<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 21:19:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at St. Jude Children&#8217;s Research&#160;Hospital</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-st-jude-childrens-research-hospital/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Memphis, TN Thank you, Ashley, clearly you were called to your profession and your story is such a good reminder that small acts of kindness can really save us when we’re going through the hardest times. And now you’re paying that kindness forward for today’s patients. Thank you for that. It’s wonderful to be back&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Memphis, TN</p>



<p>Thank you, Ashley, clearly you were called to your profession and your story is such a good reminder that small acts of kindness can really save us when we’re going through the hardest times. And now you’re paying that kindness forward for today’s patients. Thank you for that.</p>



<p>It’s wonderful to be back in Tennessee, but especially here at St. Jude.</p>



<p>Like most Americans I’ve known the work of this world-renowned institution, but to see just how special this place is firsthand is simply breathtaking. You all think of everything! And, your research is saving lives.</p>



<p>Marlo, thank you for welcoming us today. It is my honor to stand with you and truly celebrate your father’s legacy.</p>



<p>Congressman Cohen, Mayors Strickland and Harris, and our dear friend, Joyce, thank you for being with us.</p>



<p>Before I begin, I want to say that our hearts are with the families in New Orleans who have been hurt by the storms earlier this week. Please keep those families in your prayers.</p>



<p>Parents—we would do anything to keep our children safe.</p>



<p>That’s why one of the hardest parts of a cancer diagnosis is the paralyzing sense of helplessness.</p>



<p>But here at St. Jude, hearing about so many cutting-edge approaches to this disease, we are reminded that we aren’t helpless. In fact, we’re living in a time of incredible possibility.</p>



<p>Dr. Downing, thank you for showing me around—I’m inspired by the work that happens here.</p>



<p>We can end cancer as we know it. That’s what the Cancer Moonshot is all about.</p>



<p>It’s about listening to patients and survivors and their families, and finding new ways to ease the burden they face.</p>



<p>It’s about delivering new, effective treatments, including for childhood cancers, that turn a diagnosis from a moment of devastation into hope.</p>



<p>And it’s about bringing the brightest minds and fiercest hearts to the table, to learn, and collaborate, and discover together.</p>



<p>St. Jude understands that, and you support the entire family through this process.</p>



<p>With world-class care at no cost, and a tireless commitment to researching treatments and cures for childhood cancers, you have saved countless young lives. You offer healing and hope, care and community, a place of refuge for those facing the worst.</p>



<p>Like all of us, my heart has ached watching videos of Ukraine. The unthinkable bombing of a maternity ward. The theatre sheltering families, turned to debris and dust. Parents weeping over their children’s broken bodies in the streets.</p>



<p>The senselessness of it all is staggering.</p>



<p>That’s why Joe is working night and day to bring the world together to support Ukraine—with diplomacy and crippling sanctions against Russia. In fact, yesterday he attended a NATO Summit to discuss the defense of our Allies.</p>



<p>And today, he’s in Poland, where he met with our troops and humanitarian partners, seeing our efforts on the ground, and learning more about what we, and others, can do to support the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>As part of our support, Joe announced yesterday that the U.S. will welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians and others fleeing Russia’s aggression.</p>



<p>But when I learned that St. Jude was working with hospitals in Europe to bring some of the Ukrainian children with cancer and their families here—I felt so proud and I wanted join you in welcoming them. We stand with Ukraine and we’re praying for their families.</p>



<p>So thank you to St. Jude and everyone who helped bring these children to safety.</p>



<p>We often hear that the measure of a society is how we treat our most vulnerable members. We know that we have a responsibility to care for children. But anyone who has held a tiny life—who has looked into those saucer eyes and felt impossibly strong fingers wrap around your own—knows that it is so much more than an obligation.</p>



<p>It is a joy, a gift – the honor of a lifetime.</p>



<p>And, not just our children—but all children. Because inside each one is a world of possibility, of hope, of all the better tomorrows we pray will come.</p>



<p>We owe them an end to cancer as we know it. We owe them safety and health.</p>



<p>We owe them happiness and joy—the chance to be a kid.</p>



<p>Together, we can give them that.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Andrzej Duda of Poland in Briefing on the Humanitarian Efforts for&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/25/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-in-briefing-on-the-humanitarian-efforts-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 18:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rzeszów-Jasionka Airport    Rzeszów, Poland 4:48 P.M. CET PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Madam Ambassador, thank you very much.  And, Mr. President, thanks for the welcome.  Thanks for having us here.  And to &#8212; and we sent you our best.  We sent you Brzezinski as our ambassador, and I’m glad he’s here as well. And, you know, as you and I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rzeszów-Jasionka Airport<br>    Rzeszów, Poland</p>



<p>4:48 P.M. CET<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Madam Ambassador, thank you very much.  And, Mr. President, thanks for the welcome.  Thanks for having us here.  And to &#8212; and we sent you our best.  We sent you Brzezinski as our ambassador, and I’m glad he’s here as well.<br> <br>And, you know, as you and I have spoken before, Mr. Ambassador &#8212; excuse me, Mr. President &#8212; the single-most important thing that we can do from the outset is keep the democracies united in our opposition and our effort to curtail<br>the devastation that is occurring at the hands of a man who, quite frankly, I think is a war criminal.  And I think it will meet the legal definition of that as well.<br> <br>But I want to thank everyone for &#8212; and I think it’s been a surprise &#8212; about how we’ve all stayed together across the board.  The most severe punishing sanctions in the history of the world &#8212; economic sanctions &#8212; have been imposed.  And there&#8217;s more that will come.<br> <br>But, you know, there&#8217;s still an awful lot of suffering.  I, like many of you, in the past have been through refugee camps all around the world, literally, and seen the devastation as a consequence of people who were abandoned and &#8212; in war-ravaged regions of the world, whether it&#8217;s in the Middle East, or Africa, or wherever. <br> <br>I mean, it&#8217;s just devastating to see those little babies, little children, who are looking at mothers who &#8212; you don&#8217;t have to understand the language they speak &#8212; you just see in their eyes the pain.  And I mean, literally, the pain of watching their children.<br> <br>I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s anything worse for a parent than to see a child suffering &#8212; their child suffering.  I mean that sincerely.  It’s not hyperbole.  I mean it from the bottom of my heart.<br> <br>And so what you, the humanitarian community, are doing is of such enormous consequence.<br> <br>Brother, this is what we say we&#8217;re about.  This is what we say that our obligations are.  But you&#8217;re living up to it.  We&#8217;re doing it every day, all of you who are sitting at this table.<br> <br>And so, you know, I&#8217;m here in Poland to see firsthand the humanitarian crisis.  And quite frankly, part of my disappointment is that I can&#8217;t see it firsthand, like I have in other places &#8212; they will not let me, understandably; I guess it would cross the border &#8212; and take a look at what’s going on in Ukraine. <br> <br>But, you know, I’m eager to hear from you, the humanitarian community, about what you see, what you’re doing, and where you think we go from here &#8212; because you’re doing it every day.<br> <br>As has been pointed out, 10 million people have been displaced thus far; 3.8 million people to other countries, including more than a million children.  And according to the U.N., there are thousands of civilian casualties, 12 million in need of assistance, but hundreds of thousands &#8212; hundreds of thousands of people who are being cut off from help by Russian forces and are in &#8212; besieged in places like Mariupol.  I mean, it’s not stopping.  It’s like something out of a science fiction movie.  You turn on the television and see what these towns look like, and the cities. <br> <br>And I want to thank each one of you and your organizations.  Excuse me.  (Takes sip of a drink.)  When I was visiting our troops, they had pizza pie with hot peppers on it.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>But, you know, you’re helping millions of people &#8212; millions of people.  And we must &#8212; have to continue to scale up that assistance and coordinate it closely with the government of Ukraine, which is really &#8212; I think even you Poles, who know Ukraine so well, have to be a little bit surprised at how what &#8212; how much courage and capacity for resiliency of the Ukrainian people.  When you see a 30-year-old woman standing there in front of a tank with a rifle &#8212; I mean, talk about what happened in Tiananmen Square; that’s Tiananmen Square squared.  <br> <br>And, look, the &#8212; whether it&#8217;s food or a blanket or cash or the care for medical teams that we send in, or child welfare specialists, they need it now.  They need it as rapidly as we can get it there.<br> <br>And so, yesterday I announced, on behalf of the American people, we’re prepared to provide another 1 billion, as the Ambassador pointed out &#8212; 1 billion dollars for those who fled and those who are affected around the world as a consequence of the negative impact of this war on food security. <br> <br>The bad news is they’re &#8212; been the breadbasket of the world, Ukraine and Russia.  But we, the United States, are going to do our part because we’re the third-largest producer of wheat in the world.  And our Canadian friends are going to do the same thing.  But we&#8217;re going to try very hard.<br> <br>But in the meantime, the suffering that is taking place now is at your doorstep.  You&#8217;re the ones who are risking, in some cases, your lives and risking all you know to try to help.  And the American people are proud to support your efforts.  <br> <br>And today, I want to hear from all of you.  The problem is I know they&#8217;re going to tell me I have to get on the plane, and I’m going to have to leave.  But I have a lot of questions because I &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; I learned a great deal from you and your counterparts as I’ve traveled the world in the last 30 years. <br> <br>And so, I&#8217;m honored that President Duda is here today.  And I’m joined by Secretary Blinken &#8212; he’s an old friend, as well as my Secretary of State; and our USID &#8212; USAID Administrator, Samantha Powers, who, like my sister &#8212; whatever I say, she says, “It&#8217;s not enough.”  “It&#8217;s not enough.  I don&#8217;t get to do more.”  And this is a workhorse. <br> <br>So &#8212; but now going to turn it back to her so we can get to the question-and-answer period.<br> <br>ADMINISTRATOR POWER:  Thank you so much.  Thank you, Mr. President. <br> <br>President Duda, I’d love &#8212; if you’d like to say a few words.  And before you do though, just &#8212; I think, on the behalf of the entire humanitarian community, we just want to extend our thanks to you for the way that you and the Polish people have opened your borders, your hearts, your homes.  The generosity and the show of solidarity has been breathtaking.  Thank you so much, sir.  Over to you. <br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  Thank you very much, Madam Ambassador.<br> <br>Excellency, Mr. President; Mr. Secretary; Madam Ambassador; Polish and American friends: Please, if you can take these electronic devices and use it &#8212; channel two is English &#8212; because I would like to speak in my mother tongue, Polish.<br> <br>(As interpreted.)  Your Excellency, Mr. President; dear American and Polish friends; ladies and gentlemen: Thank you so much to you, Mr. President, and to the whole U.S. delegation for coming to Poland.  But first and foremost, thank you for coming here to Rzeszów, to the region of Podkarpackie, which is very close &#8212; which is located directly to the Polish-Ukrainian border. <br> <br>Thank you for coming to the place where this influx of refugees to Poland is the biggest.  Your presence here, Mr. President, first of all, sends a very big sign of unity.  This is a huge sign of support and Euro-Atlantic unity &#8212; unity with my country, with Poland.  It demonstrates great friendship between Poland and the United States, and a very profound alliance. <br> <br>This is an evidence of great support and care for our mutual relations, but also &#8212; a thing of importance to me &#8212; it is a sign and a message that you care about the security of Poland. <br> <br>Today, Mr. President, you met with U.S. soldiers who are deployed here and who watch over our security.  They also help in this very difficult work, which is receiving millions of refugees who are crossing the border to our country right now.  But first and foremost, they are guarding the security of the Polish border and guarding the security also of the entire Euro-Atlantic community of the whole of NATO &#8212; because, today, the eastern flank of NATO &#8212; and I do not hesitate to say this; I also said it yesterday at NATO summit &#8212; this is a front line today, the eastern flank. <br> <br>I&#8217;m very happy to have you here, Mr. President, because as I said, your presence here sends a great signal and evidence of unity &#8212; unity within NATO.  It demonstrates a huge support and also a big significance attached by the United States to the stability and world peace, to reinstating the peace where difficult situations are happening in places where somebody resorts to acts of aggression against other democratic and free nations, as it is happening today against Ukraine where the Russian aggression, unfortunately, happening for a month now is effect.<br> <br>But your presence, Mr. President, here today in the city of Rzeszów is also a great sign of support to us &#8212; support in terms of humanitarian assistance, which today is provided to the refugees from Ukraine, but also it is provided to us Poles who are receiving guests &#8212; because this is the name we want to apply to them.  We do not call them “refugees.”  They are our guests, our brothers, our neighbors from Ukraine who today are in a very difficult situation where 12 million people have fled their houses by the war, by the Russian attacks.  More than 3.5 million have already fled abroad.  They crossed different borders, but first and foremost, they have crossed the border with Poland.<br> <br>Today, we have got 2.5 million people in Poland, and the number is growing all the time.  So, the number &#8212; exceeding 2 million right now &#8212; is still growing.  And all signs are that if the Russian aggression continues, those numbers will continue to grow.  <br> <br>So, first and foremost, this &#8212; it gives me an opportunity to extend my gratitude to you, Mr. President, to our guests from the United States, but also to the NGOs, both from my country &#8212; starting from the organizations which are present here at this table today &#8212; but also, I want to express my gratitude to all NGOs &#8212; Polish NGOs who are involved. <br> <br>But also, I would like to thank the U.S. organizations.  A big number of them is already present in Poland, and a lot of them sends assistance to our country.  And in this context, I&#8217;m so much grateful to you, Mr. President, for your support.  <br> <br>But also, I would like to ask you to convey my personal words of thanks to the First Lady of the United States, to Mrs. Jill Biden &#8212; your spouse, Mr. President.  And please convey very heartfelt greetings from my wife to your wife.  Both ladies had a conversation a couple of days ago.  My wife gave an account of the situation in Poland.  Both ladies exchanged their views on the possibilities of help.  Then my wife paid a visit to the United States.  And from the United States, she brought &#8212; in order to support Ukraine; in order to support Ukraine hospitals and also centers here in Poland, which treats children from Ukraine, also wounded children from Ukraine &#8212; she brought from the United States a number of medical equipment and medicines from the United States. <br> <br>So, thank you so much for this very swift assistance.  Thank you so much.  And please convey these words of greetings and these words of thanks to your wife.  And also, please convey very heartfelt wishes from my wife to your wife.  <br> <br>So, ladies and gentlemen, this presents a huge challenge.  This assistance is something unprecedented, because within a couple of weeks, more than 2 million people have come to our country.  We have never experienced anything like that throughout our history.  This is the first time.<br> <br>But I would also like to thank all my compatriots who have opened their hearts and opened their houses, who have welcomed refugees &#8212; but as I said, first and foremost, our neighbors, our brothers from Ukraine &#8212; who are in a difficult position today, who are in need today.  And all of us want to help them so much.  They are staying in private houses, and they&#8217;re staying in different facilities.  Very often, these people are very much affected by the war &#8212; wounded persons, ill persons.  Many of them have undergone mental trauma after the experiences they had. <br> <br>Recently we have received people without any belongings to Poland.  They fled from bombs.  So the situation is extremely difficult.  That is why we are so much thankful for any help and assistance, because this is what we very much need today.  <br> <br>On our part, we are doing everything we can with huge dedication and devotion.  NGOs have also demonstrated huge dedication.  Also volunteers, firefighters.  So there is a lot of assistance from NGOs, from churches &#8212; Catholic church, but also other churches in our country and religious communities. <br> <br>There is a lot of support offered from all different sides, also from abroad.  And once again, we&#8217;re so much grateful for that.  This presents a huge challenge to us, but it is also a huge challenge to the whole free world as we understand it, and we all have to live up to it. <br> <br>Once again, thank you for this visit.  And I&#8217;m so happy and delighted with the conversation that we can have.  All the authorities in Poland are involved in providing assistance.  It&#8217;s not only the government, NGOs, and volunteers, but also local governments.  <br> <br>Tomorrow, Mr. President, you will meet refugees in Warsaw.  But also, the Prime Minister of the Polish government will be present there, Mr. Mateusz Morawiecki.  The Mayor of Warsaw, Mr. Rafał Trzaskowski, will be there.  And they will share with you, sir, all the activities that are being conducted in Poland in order to live up to this difficult situation, in order to solve the problem.<br> <br>So, once again, we are delighted with the visit you are paying here, sir, and a very warm welcome to our country. <br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I&#8217;m going to get in real trouble if I don&#8217;t &#8212; I forgot to say something: My wife sends her best as well.  She also went to St. Jude&#8217;s Hospital, which is a cancer hospital in the United States, to see those young Ukrainian children who were brought over seeking serious, serious help with the cancers they have.  And she said to give her best to your wife.  That&#8217;s why she&#8217;s not with me today.  She’s out west doing that.  So, thank you.  Thank you for saving me.<br> <br>ADMINISTRATOR POWER:  (Laughs.)  Thank you, Mr. President.  And thank you, President Duda, so much.  If I may just ask now the media to leave the room &#8212; thank you so much for being &#8212; so we can commence our discussion on the humanitarian circumstances.  Thank you so much.<br> <br>(The press departs.)<br> <br>5:04 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden During Visit with Service Members of the 82nd Airborne&#160;Division</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/25/remarks-by-president-biden-during-visit-with-service-members-of-the-82nd-airborne-division/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 17:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[G2A ArenaRzeszów, Poland 4:07 P.M. CET &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Mr. Secretary.&#160; Don&#8217;t jump.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; You guys are used to jumping.&#160; Don&#8217;t jump. Anyway, thanks for letting me come and say hello to you all.&#160; You know, I&#8217;ve been saying this a long time &#8212; and the people who travel with me know that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">G2A Arena<br>Rzeszów, Poland</p>



<p>4:07 P.M. CET</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Secretary.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t jump.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You guys are used to jumping.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t jump.</p>



<p>Anyway, thanks for letting me come and say hello to you all.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;ve been saying this a long time &#8212; and the people who travel with me know that because I was a senator for 36 years, the Foreign Relations Committee, traveled around the world, and 8 years as Vice President, and now President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, a couple things: First of all, thank you. You represent 1 percent of the American people.&nbsp; None of you have to be here.&nbsp; You all decided to be here for your country.&nbsp; Every one of you volunteered.&nbsp; Every single one of you stepped up.&nbsp; And the rest of the 99 percent of the rest of the country, including me, owes you and owes you big, number one.</p>



<p>Number two, you know, we’re a unique country in many ways.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re the only country &#8212; the only country in the world not based &#8212; organized based on geography or ethnicity or religion or race or anything else; we&#8217;re based on an idea.&nbsp; Literally the only country in the world based on an idea that we hold these truths to be self-evident, that all women and men are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sounds corny, but it’s the truth of who we are.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never lived up to it, but we never walked away from it.&nbsp; And the rest of the world looks to us.&nbsp; Because, you know, we not only lead by the example of our power, but by the power of our example.&nbsp; And your generation combines both.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The rest of the world looks at you and sees who you are.&nbsp; They see you are a multi-ethnic group of Americans that are, in fact, together and united into one so- &#8212; resolve: to defend your country and to help those who need help.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why you&#8217;re here.</p>



<p>I spent a lot of time in Ukraine when I was a senator and Vice President.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken to the Rada in the days when they, in fact, didn&#8217;t have what you&#8217;d call a democracy, and was there in the Maidan when the former leader had to take off and head into Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; so, you know, with the Ukrainian people &#8212; Ukrainian people have a lot of backbone.&nbsp; They have a lot of guts.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re observing it.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t mean just their military, which is &#8212; we&#8217;ve been training since back when they &#8212; Russia moved into the &#8212; in the southeast &#8212; southeast Ukraine &#8212; but also the average citizen.&nbsp; Look at how they&#8217;re stepping up.&nbsp; Look at how they&#8217;re stepping up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;re going to see when you&#8217;re there.&nbsp; And you &#8212; some &#8212; some of you have been there.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to see &#8212; you&#8217;re going to see women, young people standing &#8212; standing the middle of &#8212; in front of a damn tank, just saying, “I&#8217;m not leaving.&nbsp; I&#8217;m holding my ground.”&nbsp; They&#8217;re incredible.&nbsp; But they take a lot of inspiration from us.</p>



<p>And, you know, the woman who just died &#8212; the Secretary of State &#8212; used to have an expression.&nbsp; She said, “We are the essential nation.”&nbsp; It sounds like a bit of a hyperbole, but the truth of the matter is you are the organizing principle around which the rest of the world is &#8212; the free world is moving.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re in the midst of &#8212; and I don&#8217;t want to sound too philosophic here &#8212; but you&#8217;re in the midst of a fight between democracies and oligarchs.&nbsp; Xi Jinping &#8212; who I&#8217;ve spent more time with, they tell me, than any other world leader &#8212; points out to me that he believes, in China, that democracies can&#8217;t succeed in the 21st century.&nbsp; The reason is things are moving so fast, change is happening so quickly that democracies require consensus and we can&#8217;t put together consensus as quickly as autocrats can.</p>



<p>So what&#8217;s at stake &#8212; not just in what we&#8217;re doing here in Ukraine to try to help the Ukrainian people and keep the massacre from continuing &#8212; but beyond that, what&#8217;s at stake is: What&#8217;s &#8212; what&#8217;s &#8212; what are your kids and grandkids going to look like in terms of their &#8212; their freedom?&nbsp; What&#8217;s happening?&nbsp; The last 10 years, there have been fewer democracies that have been formed than we&#8217;ve lost in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is &#8212; what you&#8217;re engaged in is much more than just whether or not you can alleviate the pain and suffering of the people of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re in a new phase &#8212; your generation.&nbsp; We&#8217;re at an inflection point.&nbsp; About every four or five generations, there comes along a change &#8212; a fundamental change takes place.&nbsp; The world ain’t going to be the same &#8212; not because of Ukraine, but &#8212; not going to be the same 10, 15 years from now in terms of our organizational structures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the question is: Who is going to prevail?&nbsp; Are democracies going to prevail on the &#8212; and the values we share?&nbsp; Or are autocracies going to prevail?&nbsp; And that&#8217;s really what’s at stake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what you&#8217;re doing is consequential &#8212; really consequential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I said to the group in the dining room &#8212; you call it the chow, mess hall &#8212; the fact of the matter is that you are the finest &#8212; this is not hyperbole &#8212; you are the finest fighting force in the history of the world.&nbsp; Let me say it again: the finest fighting force in the history of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Part of the reason is you&#8217;ve had to fight so much for the last 20 years.&nbsp; It’s for real.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not many generations &#8212; you know, the Greatest Generation was my father&#8217;s generation, your grandparents’ generation &#8212; World War Two generation.&nbsp; But nobody &#8212; no other generation has had to be in a battle, have your buddy blown up, wipe the blood off the HMMWV, and get back in and saddle up and go for another six months.</p>



<p>The second time I&#8217;ve flew in &#8212; I’ve been in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan about 40 times &#8212; 30-something times &#8212; 38 times.&nbsp; And every time I&#8217;d go in, I&#8217;d see &#8212; like the last time I flew in &#8212; and I flew in on the &#8212; I went up in the cockpit.&nbsp; I was landing Bagram.&nbsp; And I &#8212; there were six people who came up with the cargo, basically &#8212; was what I was flying.&nbsp; And I said, “How many of you is this tour first tour of duty?”&nbsp; Not one person raised their hand.&nbsp; “Second tour?”&nbsp; Not one person.&nbsp; “Third tour of duty?”&nbsp; Three.&nbsp; “Fourth?”&nbsp; One.&nbsp; “Fifth one and sixth one?”&nbsp; That’s never happened before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One thing to go in and be in the middle of a battle, go home, and get sent back again.&nbsp; And so, one of the things that I’ve said &#8212; and I’ve gotten in trouble for saying it, but not anymore &#8212; I’ve been saying it since I got elected: We have a sacred obligation &#8212; only one obligation in this government.&nbsp; We have a lot of obligations to the elderly, the poor, children, et cetera, but only one sacred obligation: to equip those that we send to war and to care for them and their families when they come home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you all are amazing group of women and men, and I just want to thank you for your service.&nbsp; As your Commander-in-Chief, I mean it from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I said, it&#8217;s not new to me.&nbsp; I &#8212; my son spent a year in Iraq.&nbsp; He spent six months in Kosovo.&nbsp; He won the Bronze Star, the Conspicuous Service Medal, and other awards.&nbsp; Proudest thing he ever did was put that uniform on.</p>



<p>Like many of you, he didn’t have to go either.&nbsp; He was the Attorney General of the State of Delaware and in the Delaware National Guard.&nbsp; And what happened was, when his unit was going to be sent overseas, he had to go to Washington to get a &#8212; an equivalent of a dispensation because you either had to be federal property or state property.&nbsp; He was the Attorney General of the state; he had to give up the office in order to be able to go with his troops.</p>



<p>The point is that there are hundreds of thousands of people like my son, like all of you.&nbsp; So thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s not only what you&#8217;re doing to help the Ukrainian people, it&#8217;s not only what you&#8217;re doing to help Europe begin to gain &#8212; regain its confidence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reason why, when the general &#8212; when the Secretary of State asked me if I’d send another 12,000 troops along to the United States, I said, “Yeah” &#8212; from the United States &#8212; we have 100,000 American forces here in Europe; we haven&#8217;t had that long, long time &#8212; because we are the organizing principle for the rest of the world.</p>



<p>And I said, “We’ve sent the best &#8212; the best available in America.”&nbsp; And that&#8217;s all of you women and men.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I&#8217;m here.&nbsp; I came for one simple, basic reason &#8212; not a joke: to say thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you for your service.&nbsp; Thank you for who you are.&nbsp; And thank you for what you&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>And as my grandfather would say every time I walked out of his house &#8212; he’d yell at me, “Joey” &#8212; in Scranton &#8212; he said, “Keep the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandmother &#8212; my grandmother would yell, all kidding aside &#8212; this is serious &#8212; she’d yell, “No, spread it.”&nbsp; You&#8217;re spreading the faith.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you all and keep you safe.&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p> 4:16 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake&#160;Sullivan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/25/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-rzeszow-poland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 17:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49732</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Rzeszów, Poland 1:23 P.M. CET MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello. MR. SULLIVAN:&#160; Hey, guys.&#160; Hello.&#160; How are you? MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello.&#160; We have Jake Sullivan here.&#160; He&#8217;s going to talk a little bit about the President&#8217;s trip to Poland and our announcement today &#8212; our energy announcement &#8212; and then also take&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Rzeszów, Poland</p>



<p>1:23 P.M. CET</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; How are you?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; We have Jake Sullivan here.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to talk a little bit about the President&#8217;s trip to Poland and our announcement today &#8212; our energy announcement &#8212; and then also take some Q&amp;A.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll follow up with any other questions you might have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jake.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, of course, you guys heard from the President and President von der Leyen earlier today on a new U.S.-EU energy framework that accomplishes two basic purposes: one, to help the EU reduce its dependence on Russian gas; and then two, to help it reduce its dependence on gas overall.&nbsp; And as part of that, we&#8217;re committing to make available up to 15 billion cubic meters additional LNG this year through a variety of different means.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then the Europeans will be working on building out their infrastructure to be able to accept up to 50 billion cubic meters &#8212; between now and 2030, per year &#8212; additional LNG flows from the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The basic notion here is that while we&#8217;re making this clean energy transition and putting in place all of the tools and infrastructure necessary to have an economy powered by clean and renewable energy, while gas is still a substantial part of the energy mix, we want to make sure that the Europeans do not have to source that gas from Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;ll get to work immediately on that in 2022, and then we&#8217;ll build year by year between now and 2030, even as we make the far-reaching investments necessary for the clean energy transition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;ll be a joint task force established between the White House and the presidency of the European Commission to implement this basic approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, of course, they also spoke about an agreement on an updated framework for transatlantic data flows to ensure data privacy and security, and to protect those flows which form the foundation of a $7.1 trillion economic relationship between the U.S. and the EU.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this <a>agreement in principle </a>that was reached today really puts us in a position to ensure that American technology firms &#8212; big firms, yes, but especially small- and medium-sized firms &#8212; will be protected as we go forward and can fully and safely operate within the context of the U.S.-EU economic &#8212; transatlantic economic relationship.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s what we did this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, we&#8217;re off to Rzeszów, Poland.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rzeszów.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Say it again.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rzeszów.&nbsp; I just spent three weeks there.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Rzeszów, Poland &#8212; thank you &#8212; where the President will have the opportunity to meet with his Administrator of the USAID, Samantha Power, and a range of different humanitarian experts and leaders who will give him a briefing on the humanitarian assistance efforts both into and around Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, the President announced that the United States is committed to provide an additional billion dollars in humanitarian assistance to help the people of Ukraine &#8212; those who are still inside the country and those who have been displaced by the conflict.&nbsp; And he will be able to talk through with a range of different humanitarian leaders and experts, both from the region and from the international community, as well as the U.S. government experts who are playing a key role in this &#8212; how the efforts are going so far and what further steps need to be taken to make sure that we&#8217;re investing those dollars as wisely as possible.</p>



<p>He will also have the chance to visit with troops from the 82nd Airborne Division, who have been deployed to Poland to reassure our NATO Ally and to deter further aggression on the eastern flank.&nbsp; And he will also get a briefing from the commanders of those units who will have the chance to lay out for him the various tasks and missions that the American troops stationed at the airfield here have been undertaking and continue to undertake.</p>



<p>We have 10,500 troops in Poland as part of 100,000 strong U.S. force contingent across the continent as a whole.&nbsp; And a significant number of those forces here in Poland were FLOT forward &#8212; brigade combat team, tactical aviation, a Stryker unit &#8212; to ensure that we have robust deterrence and assurance in the face of Russian aggression and to fulfill the President&#8217;s commitment that we’ll defend every inch of NATO territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll go on from Rzeszów to Warsaw.&nbsp; And tomorrow, the President will meet with President Duda of Poland.&nbsp; He will also have the opportunity to meet with Ukrainian refugees and with American humanitarians who are there trying to help feed and respond to the material needs of the refugee population in Warsaw.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he will give a major address tomorrow that will speak to the stakes of this moment, the urgency of the challenge that lies ahead, what the conflict in Ukraine means for the world, and why it is so important that the free world sustain unity and resolve in the face of Russian aggression.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll also talk about the context and history of this conflict and where he sees it going from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that will be a significant speech that he delivers tomorrow afternoon, before we get on the plane to come home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think that covers the waterfront for now, although I reserve the right to revise and extend my remarks as necessary.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, President Zelenskyy said he thinks Russia wants to invade other Eastern European countries. &nbsp;Is that an assessment that the administration shares &#8212; that other countries in Eastern Europe are at risk?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we do believe that Russian aggression in Ukraine shows a willingness by the Russians to disregard international borders and to disregard the basic rules of the road of the international community that have been built and sustained over the course of seven decades.</p>



<p>So the President has been very explicit that part of the reason he&#8217;s sent forces forward to the Baltic states, to Poland, to Romania and he&#8217;s supported the setup of these four battle groups in the southern countries of NATO&#8217;s eastern flank is because it is important in this moment to send a clear message to Russia that the United States and NATO will defend every inch of NATO territory, and to deter any thinking that Putin might have about further Russian aggression into NATO.</p>



<p>In addition, the fact that Russian forces have mobilized in Belarus and that Belarus has changed its constitution to allow for more flexibility of the stationing of Russian troops and capabilities on its soil, that too has a significant impact, particularly on our NATO Allies in the Baltics and in Poland.</p>



<p>And so the combination of Russia&#8217;s brutal war in Ukraine and the change in the physical military relationship between Russia and Belarus does mean, from the President&#8217;s perspective, that the United States and NATO need to show strength and resolve in terms of the forces and capabilities postured along the eastern flank.</p>



<p>And you will see that in living color at this stop today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, President Biden, at the press conference yesterday, said that if Russia uses chemical weapons in Ukraine, the United States and NATO will respond in kind, which would seem to imply using chemical weapons back.&nbsp; Is that what he meant by “in kind”?&nbsp; Or what was he trying to say there?</p>



<p>MS. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; And you heard him in another answer say we’ll respond accordingly &#8212; meaning, you know, we will select the form and nature of our response based on the nature of the action Russia takes, and we’ll do so in coordination with our Allies.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve communicated to the Russians, as the President said publicly a couple of weeks ago, that there will be a severe price if Russia uses chemical weapons.</p>



<p>And I won&#8217;t go beyond that other than to say the United States has no intention of using chemical weapons, period, under any circumstances.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just briefly following &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on that &#8212; on nuclear weapons: With Russia threatening to use nuclear weapons, does the President consider that a red line?&nbsp; And how would the U.S. respond?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, again, I will just say, with respect to any use of weapons of mass destruction &#8212; nuclear, chemical, biological &#8212; Russia would pay a severe price for the use of those weapons, as the President has previously said.&nbsp; We have spoken to our Allies.&nbsp; We have done contingency planning within our own government.&nbsp; And we have communicated directly to the Russians.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to speak further to it here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On off-ramp for Putin here, was there a consensus &#8212; a consensus of what that may look like, what strategies to get him there?&nbsp; Anything you can say about those particular discussions?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; From my perspective, “off-ramp” is the wrong concept &#8212; because, of course, this was a war Putin chose to wage; it&#8217;s a war Putin could choose to stop.&nbsp; At any moment, he could pull his forces back, he could end the bombardment of cities and civilians.</p>



<p>Now, there is a diplomatic process underway.&nbsp; That process is being conducted directly between the Ukrainians and the Russians.&nbsp; And you have some communication between European allies, like France and Germany, as well as partners like Israel, directly with the Russians.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States is not directly participating in those negotiations, but we&#8217;re staying in close contact with our Ukrainian counterparts and with those other countries that are talking to both sides.</p>



<p>The President was very clear yesterday that, ultimately, any diplomatic agreement is one that Ukraine itself will have to determine for itself, and the United States is not going to push or pressure Ukraine into any particular outcome.</p>



<p>The last thing I would say is that, from our perspective, our role right now is to ensure that as long as Putin keeps pushing forward, that Ukraine has tools and capabilities to be able to effectively defend itself.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where our focus is.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on the liquid natural gas, on the 15 billion cubic centimeter &#8212; or cubic meters, excuse me &#8212; that are supposed to go this year, how much of that supply is already secured or needs to be secured?&nbsp; And how much of that would be coming from the U.S. versus other countries?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, I&#8217;m not sure exactly what you mean by “already secured” versus “needs to be secured,” because this will play out over the course of the year.&nbsp; So there haven&#8217;t been contracts signed for every one of those, if that&#8217;s what you mean by “secured.”</p>



<p>But we believe that we&#8217;ve identified the sources to be able to hit that target.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a combination of what the U.S. can do directly.&nbsp; For example, on March 16th, we approved the expansion of the number of countries that could receive gas from some of our terminals, number one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, we have already, over the course of the past couple of months, effectively engaged in a cargo diversion strategy to move cargo that’s destined for other countries to go to Europe.&nbsp; And we will be able to continue that over the course of the year.</p>



<p>And then, number three, the President himself has personally engaged with some other gas suppliers, including Qatar, who have been able to step up.</p>



<p>So, when you put all of those pieces together, we feel quite confident that we&#8217;ll hit our mark.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the G20, really quickly.&nbsp; On the G20 &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, (inaudible) what your response would be?&nbsp; To Ashley’s question, you said you didn’t want to say what the response would be.&nbsp; It would &#8212; you know, you&#8217;d respond.&nbsp; But was there a consensus among allies at the meetings this week as to what the response would be just among yourselves?&nbsp; Did you guys decide what that would be if Russia used chemical and biological weapons?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I would say this was a important topic of conversation at the summit, and it continues at working levels in the military, on the diplomatic side, and among the presidents’ and prime ministers’ offices.&nbsp; We are working through contingency planning for a range of different scenarios.</p>



<p>It is difficult to give precision to these kinds of hypotheticals because, of course, the form of use, the location of use, the context of use all have a bearing on the specificity of the response.</p>



<p>But in broad terms, I believe that there is convergence around the fundamental nature of how the Alliance would respond to these issues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a response to the latest statement from Ukraine that the bombing of the theater in Mariupol killed hundreds of civilians.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We all have a very deeply human response to what happened in the bombing of that theater, which is just absolute shock and horror, particularly given the fact that it was so clearly a civilian target that the Russians were striking and that they did so with such brazen disregard for the lives of innocent people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of a more formal response or analysis of the specific number, we&#8217;ve just seen that statement, and we&#8217;re in touch with Ukrainians, but I don’t have anything further to add.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, in the past, you guys have said that, you know, a cyberattack on border countries from Russia &#8212; NATO Allies would have to figure out if that counts &#8212; if that invokes Article 5.&nbsp; Was there discussion of that yesterday?&nbsp; And was there any sort of decision made on that front?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There has been no invocation of Article 5 at this point.&nbsp; You know, if a country suffers a cyberattack and calls for a collective response from the Alliance &#8212; and I hasten to note: The invocation of Article 5 and the application of a collective response doesn&#8217;t necessarily have to be a military response; it could take a number of forms, including helping that country remediate the problem, helping them build resilience against ongoing attacks, or taking a variety of cost-imposition measures against the attacker.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But ultimately, it comes down to the country under attack, probably first invoking Article 4 &#8212; consultations to discuss the collective response &#8212; and then making a determination as to whether to invoke Article 5, to ask the Alliance to come together to respond as one.&nbsp; That has not happened yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden said yesterday that Putin should be kicked out of the G20 &#8212; or Russia, more specifically.&nbsp; What efforts are underway to make that a reality?&nbsp; Is that possible?</p>



<p>And there was also mention that their economy, based on the sanctions, are now below that threshold anyway.&nbsp; So, what is the implication of that determination on their G20 status?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, the President very clearly expressed his view that, you know, Russia should not be a member in good standing of the G20, given what they&#8217;ve done.&nbsp; He also noted that Indonesia, as the chair, may have a different view.&nbsp; And he offered an alternative, which was having Ukraine be able to participate in the G20 meetings this year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we will be discussing with the other G20 members, including Indonesia.&nbsp; And the President was clear in his remarks that we want to be respectful of the views of the chair in terms of how to think about us going forward.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll be talking to them.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be talking to other partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll just leave it at what the President said yesterday, which I thought was quite clear, straightforward, and, frankly, logical: that at this moment in time, it just can&#8217;t be business as usual with Russia in the G20.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On China, what &#8212; on China, what was agreed to among the Allies about, like, what the message should be to them and how you&#8217;re going to coordinate that?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the administration&#8217;s view at this moment of how &#8212; of whether they&#8217;re leaning toward aiding the Russians at this point?&nbsp; Or have they &#8212; are you seeing signs that they&#8217;re backing away from doing so?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I would refer you &#8212; I rarely get to just cite paragraphs in NATO communiqués, but I would refer you to paragraph eight in the NATO statement out yesterday.&nbsp; And I do so because it was an unusual &#8212; an unusually direct statement, message to China from the Alliance, stating what the Allies agreed in the room, which is, collectively, we&#8217;re going to speak with one voice in saying to China that they should not provide military or other forms of assistance to Russia in the prosecution of its brutal war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And all of the Allies agreed to carry that message individually, as well as speaking collectively on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President also had the opportunity to coordinate with both President Michel and President von der Leyen of the European Union in advance of their April 1st summit, and to talk to the 27 at the EU on this topic.&nbsp; And there was broad agreement about sending that very clear message to Beijing about the implications and consequences of such support.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re all on the same page, and you&#8217;ll see that play out.</p>



<p>On the question of what we&#8217;re seeing: It remains true today what I told you two days ago, which is that since the President&#8217;s call with Xi Jinping, since my meeting with Yang Jiechi in Rome, we have not seen the Chinese move forward with the provision of military equipment to Russia.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s something we continue to watch every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, back on chemical weapons briefly: I&#8217;m not asking for a specific, but throughout this invasion, the U.S. has been very clear that we would not want to &#8212; or that you guys would not want to take steps that would be viewed as a direct escalation or confrontation with Russia.&nbsp; If Russia were to use chemical weapons, would that general view and philosophy change?&nbsp; Would the U.S. be more willing to get into a direct military confrontation with Russia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think that is an excellent effort at getting me to say something substantially different on this question than I’ve said so far.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, really, the key point here is that we&#8217;ve had the opportunity to speak directly to the Russians about the use of chemical weapons &#8212; the potential use of chemical weapons.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had the opportunity to coordinate with our Allies.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had the opportunity to get organized internally.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been clear publicly that Russia would pay a severe price.&nbsp; And beyond that, I&#8217;m not going to speak further to the issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is something that, right after the conflict began, I personally tasked the stand-up of a new tiger team that would look at a range of contingencies &#8212; this being a prominent one of those contingencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we feel like we have made considerable efforts to put ourselves in a position to respond effectively.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to preview the nature of that response.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question about the escalation of responses.&nbsp; When &#8212; you know, is the administration concerned that they&#8217;re running out of sanctions that they could put on Russia that would still have a significant impact?&nbsp; You know, the U.S. has already done so much in the way of sanctions.&nbsp; Are there other ways to go up the escalatory ladder besides military conflict that the U.S. still has?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And actually, to follow up on that, is there any concern that these sanctions and these tough measures could have the opposite intended &#8212; intention and backfire, and cause the population to actually, you know, get behind Putin if they feel that they&#8217;re being put upon by the U.S. and the EU and NATO?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Certainly the Russian leadership is going to aggressively make the case to their public that, you know, the poor, innocent government of Russia has just been economically attacked by the West, and they will use their very considerable propaganda machine to push that line.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But at the end of the day, the Russian people are going to ask the more fundamental question of why this happened and how this happened.&nbsp; And we believe that, at the end of the day, they will be able to connect the dots.&nbsp; And the same will be true up and down the Russian government: that this is &#8212; these are costs that President Putin has brought on himself and his country and his economy and his defense industrial base because of his completely unjustified and unprovoked decision to go to war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we do think the sanctions will increasingly have the effect of pressuring and constraining the Russian economy, the Russian war machine in ways that will shape their thinking as they go forward.&nbsp; And that will undermine their capacity to play an aggressive role in the world, as they have done over the course of the past many years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of additional steps that we can take, we believe that, of course, there are additional measures to tighten the screws on sanctions, and we will be constantly reviewing those.</p>



<p>This point about enforcement, though, I think is really central.&nbsp; Because in the period ahead, Russia&#8217;s main focus, from an economic perspective, is going to be to figure out how they can get around, over, or under the sanctions that have been imposed.&nbsp; And blocking off those pathways is going to be vital to producing the kinds of cost-imposition effects and vital to shaping the thinking in the Kremlin.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s really going to be our focus in the near term.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, yes, we believe that we still retain the capacity to impose additional costs on Russia that are not strictly military costs.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak to the timing of the North Korean missile launch?&nbsp; The President obviously was here overseas making the case.&nbsp; Any evidence to suggest the timing was not coincidental?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; You know, we &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) believe otherwise?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We took the somewhat unusual step of putting out a statement several days ago from the Biden administration describing these two earlier tests &#8212; I believe one was on February 28th, and the other was on March 4th, although I might have those dates slightly off &#8212; as being testing the capabilities of an ICBM, which North Korea itself did not advertise but our intelligence community determined and then we declassified that information.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In that statement, we warned that there would be more ICBM tests, and that&#8217;s what happened here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We see this as part of a pattern of testing and provocation from North Korea that is &#8212; has played out over the course of the past months and will continue to play out.&nbsp; We think there is likely more in store, and we don&#8217;t see any particular indication that this test went on this day for this reason.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Indeed, some of what is, you know, maybe driving the tempo of the testing relates to the badly failed tests that occurred just a few days ago.&nbsp; But most of the decision-making on their nuclear and testing program occurs within the context of the Korean Peninsula and the North Korean view of its security situation, not what&#8217;s happening with President Biden&#8217;s travel schedule.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake on the Iran deal, now that it seems to be on its back, what can the U.S. do and what will the U.S. do to make sure that Iran doesn&#8217;t get a nuclear weapon and to get Russia on board with that program?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I wouldn&#8217;t accept the characterization “on its back.”&nbsp; I would say that we have made substantial progress in resolving a significant number of the issues that would be necessary for us to come back into the deal on a compliance-for-compliance basis.&nbsp; There still are issues left.&nbsp; There still is work to be done.&nbsp; But we are still seeking a diplomatic outcome here that puts Iran’s nuclear program back in a box.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, if diplomacy doesn&#8217;t succeed, then we will work very closely with our international partners to increase the pressure on Iran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would just point out that the difference between the Biden administration&#8217;s approach on Iran policy and the previous administration&#8217;s approach on Iran policy is that we do have the capacity to marshal and muster the support of key allies, particularly in Europe, that were divided from the United States on the Iran issue throughout the previous administration.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the sanctions, you spoke about the importance of enforcing them.&nbsp; How much are secondary sanctions going to play into that?&nbsp; And, I guess, is the administration preparing to issue secondary sanctions on third parties who might be violating the ones already in place?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we have a number of tools to ensure compliance, and one of those tools is the designation of individuals or entities in third-party jurisdictions who are not complying with U.S. sanctions or who are undertaking</p>



<p>systematic efforts to weaken or evade them.&nbsp; And those tools are, at this point, well understood by companies and countries around the world.&nbsp; And we won&#8217;t &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re prepared to use them if it becomes necessary to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect the peacekeeping proposal to be part of the discussions with President Duda?&nbsp; And after yesterday&#8217;s discussions, is there any openness to it from the President’s side?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There was not any kind of detailed discussion of that proposal yesterday.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know, candidly, whether President Duda will raise it.&nbsp; If he does, the President will listen to him.&nbsp; But we still are seeking to understand greater details about what exactly they have in mind, because we don&#8217;t have great clarity on that.&nbsp; And until we get those details, there&#8217;s not much more I can add.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s going on with the jets?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the update with the jets?&nbsp; Are the jets coming?&nbsp; Is there a plan for the jets?&nbsp; Is that plan dead in the water?&nbsp; Was that part of negotiations this week &#8212; getting jets into Ukraine in some form?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got no update on the jets for you today.&nbsp; Nothing has fundamentally changed from our perspective since I think maybe you or one of the rest of you asked that question two days ago.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll leave it at that for now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any update on the anti-air systems like the S-300?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Only that the United States is working actively with allies in Europe and partners even further afield to get sophisticated anti-air capabilities to the Ukrainians.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to speak about specific countries or specific systems because that work is underway and, of course, I want to protect the efficiency and effectiveness of that work to actually get those systems where they need to be.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of President Zelenskyy’s demands, he made some specific demands for tanks, for anti-ship missiles.&nbsp; What was your official answer to him?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, we are in conversation with the Ukrainians and with our allies about coastal defense and anti- ship capabilities that we could provide.&nbsp; There are some operational complexities associated with that, but that is a vector, an area where we are trying to make rapid progress.</p>



<p>The &#8212; we heard his request for tanks, among other things. He has not &#8212; the Ukrainians have not yet specifically come to the United State, as far as I understand, on the tanks issue; they&#8217;ve gone to some other countries.</p>



<p>So, you know, we&#8217;ll stay in consultation with them on all of these different kinds of systems and try to make a determination about what we can source, what&#8217;s going to be effective, and what the cost-benefit analysis of the supply of any given system is.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some of these weapons are supplied overland through NATO countries.&nbsp; Is the administration concerned that Russia would try to bomb these convoys before they enter Ukraine &#8212; in a NATO country?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We are doing contingency planning for the possibility that Russia chooses to strike NATO territory in that context or in any other context.&nbsp; And the President has been about as clear as one can be about his absolute determination to respond decisively alongside the other members of our Alliance if Russia attacks NATO.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can you share any behind-the-scenes color, details of what the President is doing, how he is preparing for the address you mentioned on Saturday, even what he&#8217;s eating? Just anything a little inter- &#8212; like a little &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; But, I mean, interesting color.&nbsp; This has all been fascinating, but specifically in a color way.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m so bad at that because I, like, only &#8212; they &#8212; I get out of my hermetically sealed container to execute on the policy issues and then get back in, and I&#8217;m not sure what people eat or drink.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, like, has he been writing out the speech long?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No, so &#8212; so, let&#8217;s see.&nbsp; I mean, look, first, I would just say President Biden &#8212; and you can see this; you could see it in the press conference yesterday &#8212; he just believes passionately in NATO, in the transatlantic relationship.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the end of his remarks yesterday to the European Union, after some back-and-forth, he gave just a &#8212; there&#8217;s no other word for it than impassioned statement about the depth of his personal conviction for the transatlantic alliance and the transatlantic community, and the &#8212; both its past, its present, and its future.</p>



<p>And so I would say he sleeps way less on these kinds of trips than maybe other trips because he&#8217;s just going, going, going &#8212; like, wants to talk to the next leader; you know, take the next briefing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we&#8217;ve been covering this incredibly broad range of stuff.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So he was monitoring the negotiations on closing out Privacy Shield at the same time that he was working through the details of how many billion cubic meters we&#8217;re committing this year, at the same time as we&#8217;re talking about coastal defense capabilities to Ukraine, at the same time that we&#8217;re dealing with food security and wheat prices.</p>



<p>So, on this trip, it&#8217;s been a kind of remarkable mix of having a bunch of subject-matter experts further up in the cabin here doing, like, speed dating with the President on, you know, every topic under the sun.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I don&#8217;t mean to, like, denigrate the substance of it by calling it “speed dating,” but you get the &#8212; you get the image &#8212; like, working through all these different things.&nbsp; And he &#8212; think he&#8217;s probably taken every meal he&#8217;s eaten so far here over a briefing.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Like, he&#8217;s not sitting alone eating; he&#8217;s eating while someone is going through some element of this trip with him.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s the best I can do for color today.&nbsp; (Laughter.) But I will try to improve upon it in the future.&nbsp; How about that?&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) a lot of political issues.&nbsp; You know, the President’s approval ratings have taken a dive.&nbsp; There&#8217;s challenge with preserving democracy at home.&nbsp; Is the administration concerned that some of these things are undermining his ability to work with allies on these issues and, you know, marshaling support if people are concerned about the political backing that he has domestically?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s interesting: We have not seen that at all.&nbsp; And, of course, I would say that in any event, but I actually really mean it today.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>They&#8217;re just &#8212; this &#8212; the fact that the President a week ago could say, “Let&#8217;s get the 30 Allies together.&nbsp; Let me go sit with the 27 leaders of the European Union.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get the G7, including Prime Minister Kishida coming over from Tokyo.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s all get in one set of rooms on one day and have this out, and have everyone there energized, listening first and foremost to the President, and then rallying together” &#8212; the story of the unity on this throughout has been a story of the President&#8217;s personal leadership, of American leadership, and of the deep credibility that he has with these leaders.&nbsp; And that has been, from my perspective, unqualified.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would just make one comment that the President said yesterday that I think is really important for you all to think about as we go forward, which is: Part of the reason that he decided that we needed to do this is because, the early weeks, unity can be carried forward by momentum and inertia and adrenaline, but this could go on for quite some time.&nbsp; And to sustain that unity as costs rise, as the tragedy unfolds, that&#8217;s hard work.&nbsp; And the President wanted to get everyone together to say, “We&#8217;ve got to do that work.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I’m not saying that the unity has been built and it’ll just be there for good.&nbsp; But the rate limiter on that unity is not anything to do with the President’s, you know, domestic circumstances.&nbsp; The rate limiter is just: This is a tough sit<a>uation, and it takes an American President coming over to really try to drive this forward to keep the ball rolling and keep us all very tightly aligned and united.</a></p>



<p>So, I’ll &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) on oil prices.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, I think you may need to run.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The last.&nbsp; There was a strate- &#8212; a lot of coordination among allies on oil &#8212; strategic releases, things like that.&nbsp; Did those ideas come back up again?&nbsp; And should we expect some action on that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, they came back up.&nbsp; They came back up in particularly the G7 meeting.&nbsp; That was a major topic of conversation.&nbsp; The question of what tools we have at our disposal to deal with global oil prices.</p>



<p>And without getting ahead of the administration, we are looking at various actions we could take.&nbsp; And I’ll leave it at that for now.&nbsp; But this was not just about talking, it was about thinking about the steps we can take in the period ahead.&nbsp; But I will not steal the thunder of the administration on that issue.</p>



<p>So, thank you, guys.&nbsp; Appreciate (inaudible).</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Wow.&nbsp; That was great.&nbsp; All right, guys, hold on.&nbsp; It’s getting super bumpy.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re landing in about five minutes.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, we’re at time?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m out of questions.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Duncan, you’re out of questions?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we just ask you something just about the ceasefire in Ethiopia and how &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just don’t have anything for you on that.&nbsp; I’m happy to check with the team, but I don’t have anything specifically on the ceasefire in Ethiopia.&nbsp; Clearly, that’s something that we’re monitoring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; See you on the ground.</p>



<p>     1:58 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Council Spokesperson Emily Horne on Quad Senior Cyber Group&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/statement-by-national-security-council-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-quad-senior-cyber-group-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 15:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Australia, India, Japan and the United&#160;States recognize the need for improving cybersecurity in an increasingly digital world with sophisticated cyber threats. Improvements are particularly&#160;important in delivering the essential services of life, health and livelihood that are provided by critical infrastructure. To deliver on the Prime Ministers’ of Australia, India and Japan and the President of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Australia, India, Japan and the United&nbsp;States recognize the need for improving cybersecurity in an increasingly digital world with sophisticated cyber threats. Improvements are particularly&nbsp;important in delivering the essential services of life, health and livelihood that are provided by critical infrastructure.</p>



<p>To deliver on the Prime Ministers’ of Australia, India and Japan and the President of the United States’ vision for a free, open and resilient Indo-Pacific, this week the Quad Senior Cyber Group met in Sydney for two productive days of discussions on opportunities to extend our cybersecurity cooperation and uplift cyber resilience and critical infrastructure protection in our region.&nbsp;This meeting resulted in a work plan to further collaboration between the members, and with partners and industry in the region to address our common challenges. The group will report back to Leaders through the established Quad processes.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and European Commission Announce Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy&#160;Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/fact-sheet-united-states-and-european-commission-announce-trans-atlantic-data-privacy-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 15:07:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and the European Commission have committed to a new Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework, which will foster trans-Atlantic data flows and address the concerns raised by the Court of Justice of the European Union when it struck down in 2020 the Commission’s adequacy decision underlying the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield framework. &#160; This Framework&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and the European Commission have committed to a new Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework, which will foster trans-Atlantic data flows and address the concerns raised by the Court of Justice of the European Union when it struck down in 2020 the Commission’s adequacy decision underlying the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield framework. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This Framework will reestablish an important legal mechanism for transfers of EU personal data to the United States. The United States has committed to implement new safeguards to ensure that signals intelligence activities are necessary and proportionate in the pursuit of defined national security objectives, which will ensure the privacy of EU personal data and to create a new mechanism for EU individuals to seek redress if they believe they are unlawfully targeted by signals intelligence activities. This deal in principle reflects the strength of the enduring U.S.-EU relationship, as we continue to deepen our partnership based on our shared democratic values.</p>



<p>This Framework will provide vital benefits to citizens on both sides of the Atlantic. For EU individuals, the deal includes new, high-standard commitments regarding the protection of personal data. For citizens and companies on both sides of the Atlantic, the deal will enable the continued flow of data that underpins more than $1 trillion in cross-border commerce every year, and will enable businesses of all sizes to compete in each other’s markets. It is the culmination of more than a year of detailed negotiations between the EU and the U.S. following the 2020 decision by the Court of Justice of the European Union ruling that the prior EU-U.S. framework , known as Privacy Shield, &nbsp;did not satisfy EU legal requirements.</p>



<p>The new Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework underscores our shared commitment to privacy, data protection, the rule of law, and our collective security as well as our mutual recognition of the importance of trans-Atlantic data flows to our respective citizens, economies, and societies.&nbsp; Data flows are critical to the trans-Atlantic economic relationship and for all companies large and small across all sectors of the economy. In fact, more data flows between the United States and Europe than anywhere else in the world, enabling the $7.1 trillion U.S.-EU economic relationship.</p>



<p>By ensuring a durable and reliable legal basis for data flows, the new Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework will underpin an inclusive and competitive digital economy and lay the foundation for further economic cooperation. It addresses the Court of Justice of the European Union’s <em>Schrems II</em> decision concerning U.S, law governing signals intelligence activities. Under the Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework, the United States has made unprecedented commitments to:</p>



<ul><li>Strengthen the privacy and civil liberties safeguards governing U.S. signals intelligence activities;</li><li>Establish a new redress mechanism with independent and binding authority; and</li><li>Enhance its existing rigorous and layered oversight of signals intelligence activities.</li></ul>



<p>For example, the new Framework ensures that:</p>



<ul><li>Signals intelligence collection may be undertaken only where necessary to advance legitimate national security objectives, and must not disproportionately impact the protection of individual privacy and civil liberties;<br></li><li>EU individuals may seek redress from a new multi-layer redress mechanism that includes an independent Data Protection Review Court that would consist of individuals chosen from outside the U.S. Government who would have full authority to adjudicate claims and direct remedial measures as needed; and<br></li><li>U.S. intelligence agencies will adopt procedures to ensure effective oversight of new privacy and civil liberties standards.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Participating companies and organizations that take advantage of the Framework to legally protect data flows will continue to be required to adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles, including the requirement to self-certify their adherence to the Principles through the U.S. Department of Commerce. EU individuals will continue to have access to multiple avenues of recourse to resolve complaints about participating organizations, including through alternative dispute resolution and binding arbitration.</p>



<p>These new policies will be implemented by the U.S. intelligence community in a way to effectively protect its citizens, and those of its allies and partners, consistent with the high-standard protections offered under this Framework.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The teams of the U.S. government and the European Commission will now continue their cooperation with a view to translate this arrangement into legal documents that will need to be adopted on both sides to put in place this new Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework. For that purpose, these U.S. commitments will be included in an Executive Order that will form the basis of the Commission’s assessment in its future adequacy decision.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United&#160;States and European Commission Joint Statement on Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy&#160;Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/united-states-and-european-commission-joint-statement-on-trans-atlantic-data-privacy-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 15:04:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and the European Commission announce that they have agreed in principle on a new Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework, which will foster trans-Atlantic data flows and address the concerns raised by the Court of Justice of the European Union in the Schrems II decision of July 2020.&#160; The new Framework marks an unprecedented&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and the European Commission announce that they have agreed in principle on a new Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework, which will foster trans-Atlantic data flows and address the concerns raised by the Court of Justice of the European Union in the <em>Schrems II</em> decision of July 2020.&nbsp;<br><br>The new Framework marks an unprecedented commitment on the U.S. side to implement reforms that will strengthen the privacy and civil liberties protections applicable to U.S. signals intelligence activities. &nbsp;Under the Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework, the United States is to put in place new safeguards to ensure that signals surveillance activities are necessary and proportionate in the pursuit of defined national security objectives, establish a two-level independent redress mechanism with binding authority to direct remedial measures, and enhance rigorous and layered oversight of signals intelligence activities to ensure compliance with limitations on surveillance activities.<br><br>The Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework reflects more than a year of detailed negotiations between the U.S. and E.U. led by Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo and Commissioner for Justice Didier Reynders. It will provide a durable basis for trans-Atlantic data flows, which are critical to protecting citizens’ rights and enabling trans-Atlantic commerce in all sectors of the economy, including for small and medium enterprises.&nbsp; By advancing cross-border data flows, the new framework will promote an inclusive digital economy in which all people can participate and in which companies of all sizes from all of our countries can thrive.&nbsp;<br><br>The announcement is another demonstration of the strength of the U.S.-EU relationship, in that we continue to deepen our partnership as a community of democracies to ensure both security and respect for privacy and to enable economic opportunities for our companies and citizens.&nbsp; The new Framework will facilitate further U.S.-EU cooperation, including through the Trade and Technology Council and through multilateral fora, such as the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, on digital policies.<br><br>The teams of the U.S. Government and the European Commission will now continue their cooperation with a view to translate this arrangement into legal documents that will need to be adopted on both sides to put in place this new Trans-Atlantic Data Privacy Framework. For that purpose, these U.S. commitments will be included in an Executive Order that will form the basis of the Commission’s assessment in its future adequacy decision.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki Announcing President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of&#160;Singapore</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-announcing-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-lee-hsien-loong-of-singapore/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday March 29th, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore to the White House. The two Leaders will reaffirm the importance of the U.S.-Singapore Strategic Partnership. The President will review efforts to ensure a free and open Indo-Pacific and discuss Russia’s unjustified war against Ukraine with the Prime Minister. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday March 29<sup>th</sup>, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore to the White House. The two Leaders will reaffirm the importance of the U.S.-Singapore Strategic Partnership. The President will review efforts to ensure a free and open Indo-Pacific and discuss Russia’s unjustified war against Ukraine with the Prime Minister. The President also looks forward to deepening cooperation on a range of shared interests, including upholding freedom of the seas, advancing supply chain resiliency, addressing the crisis in Burma, and fighting climate change.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on the U.S. and the European Commission’s Task Force to Reduce Europe’s Dependence on Russian Fossil&#160;Fuels</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/25/background-press-call-on-the-u-s-and-the-european-commissions-task-force-to-reduce-europes-dependence-on-russian-fossil-fuels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 13:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49711</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:45 A.M. CET MODERATOR:&#160; Thanks so much for joining us, and I appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility.&#160; This call is going to be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&#160; Not for your reporting but just for your knowledge, on this call we have [senior administration officials]. As we said in invite for this call,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:45 A.M. CET<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much for joining us, and I appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility.&nbsp; This call is going to be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; Not for your reporting but just for your knowledge, on this call we have [senior administration officials].<br><br>As we said in invite for this call, this call will be embargoed until the call concludes.&nbsp; And you all have received a factsheet on this earlier in the morning, as well.&nbsp; And as usual, we’ll have some time for questions afterwards.&nbsp;<br><br>But with that, I will turn it over to [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to say a few things about the energy agreement and then also the new transatlantic data privacy and security agreement as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So first, on energy: Today, President Biden and President von der Leyen are ushering in a new era of energy security for Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>As you all know, Putin’s war has highlighted an urgent need to reduce our dependence, Europe’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels.&nbsp; It’s very clear that Putin is continuing to use energy as a weapon to coerce and destabilize Europe.&nbsp; The task force we’re announcing today will hit hard at his ability to do this in the near term, and we’re working toward eliminating his ability to do so in the future.<br><br>So, the strategy that we’re announcing today to address the near term is to reduce demand for fossil fuels &#8212; natural gas in particular &#8212; and also filling in for natural gas that would have come from Russia in the very near term to avoid people getting cold this winter and next winter before clean energy is deployed at scale.<br><br>The President knows, and we’ve discussed at length, that the true path to energy security runs through clean energy.&nbsp; So that’s the second part of this agreement.&nbsp; The first part is getting Europe off Russian gas.&nbsp; The second part is getting Europe off gas altogether.&nbsp; And he’s committed to reducing our dependence on fossil fuels and reaping the climate, environmental, economic, and energy security benefits of moving decisively down that path.<br><br>With respect to the enhanced Privacy Shield agreement &#8212; you know, this trip has been all about unity.&nbsp; And when you have the unity that&#8217;s been forged between the U.S. and Europe, it creates a lot of trust and goodwill, and you can settle &#8212; you can settle issues that have been nagging at the relationship.&nbsp; And we did so with the Boeing-Airbus dispute &#8212; resolving that last summer, in June.&nbsp; We did so as well by lifting steel and aluminum tariffs in November.&nbsp; And this is another example of coming together on standards, on writing the rules of the road for data flows between Europe and the U.S.&nbsp; I mean, these data flows underpin the $7 trillion of commerce that takes place between the U.S. and the European Union.&nbsp;<br><br>And based on our shared &#8212; the shared importance we place on privacy, data protection, and rule of law, we&#8217;ve come together and we’ve now settled a dispute that&#8217;s been going on for over a year.&nbsp; Another example of why unity matters.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to forge our partnership even closer.<br><br>I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to say more about the energy deal.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; So today we announced a task force that will be led out of the White House and the Office of the President of the European Commission to support the EU’s objective to end its dependence on Russian fossil fuels as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>[Senior administration official] mentioned the two lines of effort, and I want to underscore that both lines of effort focus on ensuring that the task force is working to ensure European energy security in the near term while also recognizing that a rapid clean-energy transition to renewable energy, and including energy efficiency, are key tools that we will need to avoid these shocks in the future, while advancing our shared climate objectives.<br><br>The task force and international partners will target additional LNG volumes to Europe of at least 15 bcm this year, with expected increases going forward.<br><br>The task force will also simultaneously focus on reducing overall gas demand, in line with our shared climate and clean energy objectives.&nbsp; This includes engaging with key stakeholders, including from the private sector, to target immediate reductions in gas demand that can be achieved through ramping up energy efficiency measures and accelerating renewable energy development and deployment.<br><br>The REPowerEU plan, developed by the European Commission and released on March 8th to phase out of their dependence of Russian fossil fuels well before 2030, estimates that many of these measures can produce even greater savings in the near term.<br><br>According to their estimate &#8212; their estimate is that energy savings in homes alone can save at least 15.5 bcm by the end of this year.&nbsp; And they estimate that accelerating wind and solar deployments and by frontloading that can replace about 20 bcm by the end of this year &#8212; with their goal of saving over 170 bcm a year by 2030 through the plans the EU made before the invasion, such as Fit for 55.<br><br>So we &#8212; as we support our European partners in the face of Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified war of choice, we’re also strengthening their ability to meet their long-term objectives.<br><br>So with that, we’ll turn it over and take some questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; With that, why don’t we start with Mike Shear with the New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi guys.&nbsp; Thanks for having the call.&nbsp; I guess I wanted to clarify &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen it reported this morning that this is a deal for the U.S. to provide 15 billion bcm to Europe.&nbsp; I just want to clarify, it&#8217;s not that the U.S. has that amount that it will sell to the EU or ship to the EU, but rather that it&#8217;s coming from &#8212; it&#8217;s an effort to find that amount from other countries.&nbsp;<br><br>And just as a sort of corollary to that: Isn&#8217;t it the case that the U.S. and many of the other nations around the world are already running full tilt?&nbsp; And so, how do you find that amount of LNG when the U.S. and many of the other providers don&#8217;t seem to have that kind of excess volume &#8212; at least right now?&nbsp; How do you find that in the short run?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Mike.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to start.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], please feel free to add in.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, Mike, we have close to doubled our LNG exports to Europe over the past three to four months.&nbsp; But we also arranged, over the course of the winter months, a number of swaps from our partners all over the world, particularly in Asia, to supply more LNG to Europe during its winter, particularly given its low inventory and storage levels this year.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re going to continue those efforts throughout 2022 &#8212; that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re committing to do &#8212; to hit the 15 bcm target.&nbsp;<br><br>And so this will involve a lot of diplomacy.&nbsp; We&#8217;re confident after talking with our partners, both in Asia but also in other parts of the world, that we can continue to hit that number.&nbsp; Basically, it continues at the rate at which we provided and arranged for LNG to be delivered to Europe through the past few months.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a continuation of the effort.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, over time, what Europe is doing is it&#8217;s committing to stable demand for U.S. LNG &#8212; 50 bcm &#8212; basically to execute on its goal of reducing energy dependence on Russia and removing it altogether before the end of this decade.&nbsp; And that will involve a lot of commitments by Europe to build the LNG import infrastructure, the distributional needs, the storage needs in order to transport that LNG to places where they have a real need to have gas.&nbsp; Gas imports rise over time to replace Russian imports.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to do so, as [senior administration official] said, in a way that advances our clean energy goals.<br><br>So the LNG import terminals and the pipelines can be built in a way that facilitate the use of renewable energy that could be retrofitted for hydrogen, and that&#8217;s going to be a big part of the second part of the strategy here &#8212; is getting us off gas altogether, particularly in Europe.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Kayla Tausche with CNBC.<br><br>Kayla, you there?&nbsp; We can&#8217;t hear you.&nbsp; All right, you know, we will come back to you.<br><br>Next, why don&#8217;t we go to Jarrett Renshaw with Reuters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for taking the call.&nbsp; Just &#8212; can you just clarify the additional volume part?&nbsp; Are we talking &#8212; is there an “all in” number here that the U.S. is committing (inaudible), a preexisting number plus the 15?&nbsp; So if we can get some clarification on that, that would be great.<br><br>And secondly, on the one hand, you&#8217;re talking about increased production, more natural gas flowing out of the U.S., and also at same time, looking to stop it flowing and stop the production of natural gas.&nbsp; What incentive do U.S. companies have to build out this infrastructure &#8212; U.S. natural gas companies?&nbsp; Wouldn&#8217;t they just &#8212; if the policy is to essentially shut them down at some point, what&#8217;s their incentive, given the length of these supply contracts that are needed to fund the infrastructure?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Good questions.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to start on this?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Happy to.<br><br>So, let me clarify: On &#8212; there is not an aggregate number.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; This is about &#8212; this is looking at &#8212; the Europeans actually do have an aggregate number, which is to reduce their reliance on Russian gas by the end &#8212; by well before 2030.&nbsp; And so, in the joint statement, they put 27 &#8212; “by 2027” is the target that they want to reduce that by.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s really their goal.&nbsp; That&#8217;s about &#8212; 155 bcm total is what they used from Russia in 2021.&nbsp; And so my understanding is that that&#8217;s their aggregate number, globally, that Europe is looking to aim to do.<br><br>And so the U.S. is trying to do our part and contribute to that.&nbsp; And as the President von der Leyen said today, 50 bcm &#8212; and also according to the International Energy Agency &#8212; that&#8217;s about a third of what they get from Russia today.<br><br>Regarding the question about the reducing gas demand, I should clarify that point.&nbsp; So, on that point, what we&#8217;re talking about are measures to reduce the demand for gas in the European system.&nbsp; Europe has identified things such as smart thermostats, or turning down your &#8212; degree of your home by one degree can save about 10 bcm.&nbsp; They&#8217;re looking at things like accelerating solar and wind deployment that reduce the demand for gas in the system.<br><br>The joint statement that we released today &#8212; we&#8217;ll be releasing today &#8212; talk about the infrastructure that will be built by the Europeans, on the European side, to be clean and renewable hydrogen-ready.&nbsp; That’s an example of where gas continues to move to Europe, but it&#8217;s done in a way that then contributes clean and renewable hydrogen in the future.<br><br>And so, again, these are the signals we&#8217;re trying to send to the marketplace about the role that gas plays going forward in the future.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about turning off the gas completely in the near term; it&#8217;s about making sure that it is low carbon, that the greenhouse gas intensity of the carbon and the gas over time is decreasing, aligned with our net-zero goals.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you look at technology that&#8217;s out there today, as well as we&#8217;re investing in both at home and overseas &#8212; like carbon capture, utilization, and storage &#8212; these are technologies that help reduce the carbon intensity of gas going forward and into Europe to be aligned with their strategy.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And just to add on a bit, Jarrett: On the first part of your question, if you look at what Russia currently ships to the EU in terms of LNG, it is about 15 bcm.&nbsp; Now, the pipes gas, as [senior administration official] referenced, is much larger; it&#8217;s 155 billion cubic meters.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in 2022 &#8212; you can think of why 15 &#8212; that’s the additional LNG we&#8217;re going to provide to Europe, and the idea is to get them off of Russian LNG in the very, very short term.&nbsp;<br><br>But then over time &#8212; your question was along the lines of, “What are you going to do with the infrastructure that&#8217;s built to supply additional gas?”&nbsp; And here, the important point to realize: These are not going to be stranded assets.&nbsp; The infrastructure that&#8217;s built in Europe &#8212; for example, in the distribution and the storage capacity, and even the powering of these LNG import facilities &#8212; the goal here is to build those facilities and build that infrastructure using renewable energy, using pipelines that could be used for hydrogen.&nbsp; And so, these aren&#8217;t going to be stranded assets; they&#8217;re going to be used for the clean energy infrastructure (inaudible) over time, well beyond 2030.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s try Kayla with CNBC again.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi guys.&nbsp; Can you hear me now?&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yep, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Sorry about that before.&nbsp; If the European demand remains stable, what is your understanding of how your plans to replace the remaining 100 billion-or-so cubic meters that it currently gets from Russia?&nbsp;<br><br>And just to put a finer point on it, exactly how much does the administration expect U.S. producers to increase drilling and fracking by, for the next decade, to meet this goal?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry, I couldn&#8217;t &#8212; I couldn&#8217;t hear that, Kayla.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; [senior administration official], I don&#8217;t &#8212; maybe it came through more clearly on your side.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Kayla, was your question &#8212; I think I caught some of it.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in terms of the additional 100 bcm of the 155, I would, you know, sort of direct you to the REPowerEU plan that they put out on March 8th, where they walk through a series of gas diversification measures, how they would electrify Europe, and how they would transform their industry, and to reach that &#8212; that full amount.&nbsp; And they have timeframes for that.&nbsp; And again, 2027, I believe, is their &#8212; is how they&#8217;re trying to pull that “by 2030” target forward.<br><br>But it&#8217;s everything from boosting biomethane, boosting the hydrogen production that’ll take place in (inaudible) by 2030, looking at solar rooftops, heat pump rollouts, frontloading wind and solar, and looking at EUI efforts around energy efficiency.&nbsp; And they did some of that add-up and aggregation to get to those volumes and those numbers.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s also where you see the European Commission talking about today, looking at an EU mechanism of pooling to ensure that they can fill storage, that they can ensure that they can work with member states around import infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>You saw Germany announced, I think about two weeks ago, that they&#8217;re looking to build two more import terminals, and they&#8217;re looking, I think, at a floating storage regasification unit in the near term for that.&nbsp;<br><br>So those are some measures on the hundred that I think that was your question.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of your question regarding what are we asking of U.S. production, I would &#8212; there, I would just take a look at what we have already permitted in the United States, what is already under construction.&nbsp; And this is really about where the market wants to take it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why hearing from the European Union today that they&#8217;re looking to work with their member states to ensure a stable demand of a specific volume through 2030 is really important to send a signal of where we&#8217;ve already permitted.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s various numbers out there, but there is a significant amount of volume of new production capacity from the United States that has already been permitted by the Department of Energy and others for build-out.&nbsp; And we also have two active facilities already under construction that&#8217;ll be probably ready by 2024, 2025.&nbsp;<br><br>So when you think about new volumes of production, I’d take a look at what we&#8217;ve already permitted and what&#8217;s already under construction.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And, you know, in our discussions &#8212; just to add on to [senior administration official]’s answer &#8212; in our discussions with the Europeans, you know, Russian gas has been very cheap for a long time, but it&#8217;s also quite obvious that it&#8217;s very risky.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, Europe wants to manage its risks in a better way, really with a portfolio approach.&nbsp; The U.S. is now the biggest supplier of LNG, so we&#8217;ll be a big part of it, but there&#8217;ll be other suppliers too.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve been working with producers of LNG across the world.&nbsp;<br><br>The point here is to replace an unreliable supplier of LNG with a much more reliable and secure partner in the U.S.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next, let’s go to Josh Wingrove from Bloomberg.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; And, you know, bear with us who &#8212; those of us who&#8217;ve been in the travel pool &#8212; in a fuzzy period of sleep.&nbsp; So, let me just make some clarity on this.&nbsp; Of the 15, how much of that do you think will come from the U.S., number one?&nbsp;<br><br>Number two, [senior administration official], you just mentioned the two existing facilities under production.&nbsp; Do you believe the U.S. needs more export facilities on top of that to service this goal and this vision?&nbsp; Or does the existing expansion and plan sort of meet that target?&nbsp;<br><br>And of the 15, if we don&#8217;t know how much is coming from the U.S., can we say how much is coming from Asia, for instance?&nbsp;<br><br>And, [senior administration official], we don&#8217;t really have a factsheet yet on what this data deal is.&nbsp; Can you tell us anything of what the terms of it &#8212; you know, what it&#8217;ll change for the U.S. or what it will change for Europe?&nbsp; Like, what was the &#8212; what is the deal itself?&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to take the first, and I&#8217;ll address the second question from Josh?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, of course.&nbsp; So, on the 15 &#8212; again, can&#8217;t speak to exactly where that 15 is coming from.&nbsp; (Inaudible) an active conversation among multiple parties, and again, where the market is looking to move those existing volumes.&nbsp; And so, you know, whether or not it&#8217;s a U.S. cargo or an Asian cargo, what have you, we don&#8217;t have those specifics to share with you today.&nbsp;<br><br>On your second question around U.S. exports and what&#8217;s under construction and what&#8217;s already in production today &#8212; and I&#8217;m trying to find the final number, and we’ll have to get back to you with it.&nbsp; But by my last check, we already &#8212; you know, again, what&#8217;s permitted for export terminals for construction today will get us to, I believe &#8212; and again, I don&#8217;t have the current number &#8212; but it&#8217;ll certainly be sufficient to meet the 50 demand coming out of Europe today &#8212; or by 2030.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I would say on that: Again, there&#8217;s a plentiful amount of export capacity looking to come online in the near future.&nbsp; And, really, what they&#8217;re looking is to reach final investment decision, or FID.<br><br>Over to you, [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; On the second question, Josh, I mean, the problem we&#8217;ve been trying to solve for over a year now is that the European Court of Justice invalidated the previous so- called Privacy Shield, which allowed for data flow from Europe to the U.S.&nbsp;<br><br>And a couple of the primary concerns that have been raised involved potential surveillance of European consumers by our intelligence agencies.&nbsp; And so, that and a few other issues related to privacy and security were at the crux of the negotiations over the past year.&nbsp;<br><br>And without an agreement that dealt with the Court of Justice &#8212; the European Court of Justice’s issues with the previous Privacy Shield, it put at risk the data flow that takes place between our two economies.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s an especially big problem for small businesses and medium-sized businesses that can&#8217;t easily come up with a contract that provides comfort for those companies that are doing business in Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>And it really threatened &#8212; I mean, in today&#8217;s age, the digital flows between the U.S and Europe are so large that it really threatened a significant chunk of our trading relationship.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we&#8217;ve now come to an agreement on how to deal with Europe’s concerns.&nbsp; And it really is based on a shared understanding of what privacy means in terms of data flow, what security should look like, what the rule of law &#8212; how it should operate.&nbsp; And that was really the basis on which we found compromise.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a really big deal, especially for small and midsize businesses that were at risk of losing their &#8212; losing their revenue flow from Europe.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next, let’s go to Tyler Pager with the Washington Post.&nbsp; And this is probably our last question because I think our speakers have to run to some other engagements.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And I had to jump on a little late, so I apologize if this question has already been asked.&nbsp; But in the factsheet, it says that, “This will also be done on the understanding that prices should reflect long-term market fundamentals and stability of supply and demand.”&nbsp; We had heard from some EU officials some grumbling about how much the European Union will have to pay.&nbsp; Has there been an agreement on pricing, either for this year or moving into the future?&nbsp; Any more detail you can provide on that?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, I mean &#8212; so the reference there is making the point that spot prices are really high right now.&nbsp; And so, the agreement is not to lock in those spot prices indefinitely, because those prices can change, and ideally they move lower as supplies go up.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s referencing long-term supply and demand fundamentals; that we shouldn&#8217;t just be looking to spot prices to strike a long-term agreement, which is what this is.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s the intuition.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Well, thanks again, everyone, for joining today.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, this call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until the call concludes, which will be momentarily.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks again for joining, everybody.&nbsp; And talk to you all soon.&nbsp;<br><br>11:08 A.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen in Joint Press&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/25/remarks-by-president-biden-and-european-commission-president-ursula-von-der-leyen-in-joint-press-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10:05 A.M. CET PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today I’m proud to once again be standing together with President von der Leyen as we announce a new groundbreaking initiative between the European Union and the United States.&#160;First, we’re coming together to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian energy.&#160; Putin has issued Russia’s energy resources to coerce and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>10:05 A.M. CET</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today I’m proud to once again be standing together with President von der Leyen as we announce a new groundbreaking initiative between the European Union and the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, we’re coming together to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian energy.&nbsp; Putin has issued Russia’s energy resources to coerce and manipulate its neighbors.&nbsp; That’s how he’s used it.&nbsp; He’s used the profits to drive his war machine.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that’s why, earlier this month, I announced the United States would ban all imports of Russian energy to make it clear that the American people would not be part of subsidizing Putin’s brutal, unjustified war against the people of Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the time, I noted that we were able to take those steps when others could not because the United States is a net energy exporter of energy, with a strong domestic industry.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the United States welcomed the European Union’s powerful statement earlier this month committing to rapidly reduce its dependence on Russian gas.</p>



<p>Today we’ve agreed on a joint game plan toward that goal while accelerating our progress toward a secure clean energy future.<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative focuses on two core issues: One, helping Europe reduce its dependency on Russian gas as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And, secondly, reducing Europe’s demand for gas overall.<br>&nbsp;<br>To address the first point, the United States, together with our international partners, they’re going to &#8212; we’re going to work to ensure an additional 15 &#8212; one-five &#8212; 15 billion cubic meters of liquified natural gas &#8212; LNG &#8212; for Europe this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as the EU works to discontinue buying Russian gas well before 2030, it will also work to ensure additional EU market demand for 50 billion cubic meters of LNG from the United States annually by 2030.<br>&nbsp;<br>To accomplish this, the European Commission is going to work with the member states to store gas across the continent, to build more infrastructure to receive LNG, and to take steps to increase the efficiency of gas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This build-out &#8212; this build-out will occur in a way that consists &#8212; is consistent with, not in conflict with, the zero &#8212; net-zero climate goal we &#8212; that we’re shooting for.&nbsp; It’s going to take some time to adjust gas supply chains and infrastructure as is built the last decade &#8212; for the last decade.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we’re going to have to make sure the families in Europe can get through this winter and the next while we’re building an infrastructure for a diversified, resilient, and clean energy future.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, this crisis also presents an opportunity.&nbsp; It’s a catalyst &#8212; a catalyst that will drive the investments we need to double-down on our clean energy goals and accelerate progress toward our net-zero emissions future.<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s what the second part of this initiative is all about.<br>&nbsp;<br>The United States and the European Union are going to work together to take concrete measures to reduce dependence on natural gas &#8212; period &#8212; and to maximize the available &#8212; the avail- &#8212; the availability and use of renewable energy. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re going to accelerate widespread adoption of energy-efficient technologies and equipment, like smart thermostats, the work &#8212; that work to &#8212; and work to electrify heating systems all across Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re going to invest in innovative solutions and technologies to make the switch from fossil fuels.<br>&nbsp;<br>And together, we’ll advance the use of clean and renewable hydrogen to reduce our carbon emissions.<br>&nbsp;<br>This &#8212; these steps will increase energy security, economic security, and national security.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re going to stand up a joint task force to implement these changes and drive progress that will be co-chaired by representatives from the White House and the President of the European Union’s team &#8212; Commission’s team.<br>&nbsp;<br>Madam President, I know &#8212; I know that eliminating Russian gas will have costs for Europe.&nbsp; But it’s not only the right thing to do from a moral standpoint, it’s going to put us on a much stronger strategic footing.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’m proud to announce that we’ve also reached another major breakthrough in transatlantic data flows.&nbsp; Privacy and security are key elements of my digital agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>And today, we’ve agreed to unprecedented protections for data privacy and security for our citizens.<br>&nbsp;<br>This new agreement will enhance the Privacy Shield Framework; promote growth and innovation in Europe and the United States; and help companies, both small and large, compete in the digital economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just as we did when we resolved the Boeing-Airbus dispute and lifted the steel and aluminum tariffs, the United States and the EU are finding creative, new approaches to knit our economies and our people closer together, grounded on shared values.<br>&nbsp;<br>This framework underscores our shared commitment to privacy, to data protection, and to the rule of law.&nbsp; And it’s going to allow the European Commission to once again authorize<br>transatlantic data flows that help facilitate $7.1 trillion in economic relationships with the EU.<br>&nbsp;<br>So thank you again, Madam President, for your personal friendship, for your partnership, and above all, your leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>All of this is bringing the European Union and the United States even closer together, and that’s a win for all of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I thank you all, and I’m now going to yield the podium to the President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me pull this out.&nbsp; (Pulls out the step stool.)&nbsp; Got to earn my salary here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Is it out enough?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Mr. President, Dear Joe, your presence here in Brussels this week &#8212; at the NATO summit, at the G7, and at our European Council &#8212; sends a very powerful message to the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>The transatlantic partnership stands stronger and more united than ever.&nbsp; And we are determined to stand up against Russia’s brutal war.&nbsp; This war will be a strategic failure for Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our cooperation on the four successive waves of sanctions against Russia has been extraordinary and exceptional.&nbsp; The sanctions are now working their way deep into the Russian system, draining Putin’s resources to finance this atrocious war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our work on sanctions also shows that when we act together, we’re stronger and we really can make a difference.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are continuing to reinforce our cooperation in many strategic ways: on humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine; on energy; on fighting the threats against our democracies; on solving outstanding issues in the EU-U.S. cooperation, including in data protec- &#8212; protection and privacy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In a world faced with disorder, our transatlantic unity upholds fundamental values and rules that our citizens believe in.&nbsp; Let me focus first on refugees.<br>&nbsp;<br>Until now, around three and a half million people have left Ukraine, half of them children.&nbsp; Every second refugee is a child.&nbsp; And the numbers will keep rising.&nbsp; So, together, we are mobilizing massive resources to support those displaced by the conflict, be it in Ukraine or in the neighboring countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Just this week, for example, I announced that the European Union will allocate an extra 3.4 billion euros for this purpose, and more will come.&nbsp; This demonstrates our deep support for Ukraine and its citizens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to tell the American people how grateful Europe is for their unwavering support.&nbsp; This support also extends to strengthening Europe&#8217;s energy security and independence from Russian fossil fuels.&nbsp; As you know, we aim to reduce this dependency on Russian fossil fuels and to get rid of it.&nbsp; And this can only be achieved through, of course, first of all, investment in renewables, but also through additional gas supplies, including LNG deliveries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we want, as Europeans, to diversify away from Russia, towards suppliers that we trust, that are friends, and that are reliable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And therefore, the U.S. commitment to provide the European Union with additional at least 15 billion cubic meters of LNG this year is a big step in this direction because this will replace the LNG supply we currently receive from Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>And looking ahead, the United States and Europe will ensure stable demand and supply for additional at least 50 billion cubic meter of U.S. LNG until 2030.&nbsp; And if we look at that, this amount, 50 bcm per year, is replacing one third already of the Russian gas going to Europe today.&nbsp; So, we are right in &#8212; on track now to diversify away from Russian gas and towards our friends’ and partners’ reliable and trustworthy suppliers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We need to secure our supplies not just for next winter but also for the years ahead.&nbsp; And this is a &#8212; an important, a big starting point to do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our partnership aims to sustain us through this war, to work on our independence from Russian fossil fuels, but it also focuses on building a greener future with climate neutrality.&nbsp; We will work together also with our energy-intensive industry.&nbsp; And the good news is that the infrastructure that we use for gas today can be used for clean hydrogen in the future.&nbsp; So, this investment we are doing right now is also an investment in the decarbonizing of our economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>The cooperation shows the power of our democracies.&nbsp; I particularly welcome that we will step up our respective action on strengthening democracies, the rule of law, the freedom of media in the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we also need to continue adapting our own democracies to a changing world.&nbsp; This is particularly true when it comes to digitalization, in which the protection of personal data and privacy has become so crucial.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And therefore, I&#8217;m very pleased that we have found an agreement in principle on a new framework for transatlantic data flows.&nbsp; This will enable predictable and trustworthy data flows between the EU and U.S., safeguarding privacy and civil liberties.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I really want to thank Commissioner Reynders and Secretary Raimondo for their tireless efforts over the past month to finish a balanced and effective solution.&nbsp; This is another step in our &#8212; strengthening our partnership.&nbsp; We managed to balance security and the right to privacy and data protection.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Mr. President, Dear Joe: Putin is trying to turn back the clock to another era &#8212; an era of brutal use of force, of power politics, of spheres of influence, and internal repression.&nbsp; I am confident he will fail.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are working together to forge a peaceful, prosperous, and sustainable future.&nbsp; And I know we will succeed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you very much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>10:18 A.M. CET&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
