<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 21:41:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration’ Monkeypox Outbreak&#160;Response</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-monkeypox-outbreak-response/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56448</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For years, the United States has invested in research on monkeypox and in tools to effectively respond to the disease. Monkeypox is a virus that is generally spread through close or intimate contact, with symptoms that include a rash and fever. It is much less transmissible than fast-spreading respiratory diseases like COVID-19, and this outbreak&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For years, the United States has invested in research on monkeypox and in tools to effectively respond to the disease. Monkeypox is a virus that is generally spread through close or intimate contact, with symptoms that include a rash and fever. It is much less transmissible than fast-spreading respiratory diseases like COVID-19, and this outbreak has not caused any deaths in the United States. &nbsp;The virus, however, is spreading in the United States and globally, and requires a comprehensive response from federal, state, local, and international governments and communities. Since the first United States case was confirmed on May 18, President Biden has taken critical actions to make vaccines, testing, and treatments available to those who need them as part of its whole-of-government monkeypox outbreak response.</p>



<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration announced the first phase of its national monkeypox vaccine strategy, a critical part of its monkeypox outbreak response. The vaccine strategy will help immediately address the spread of the virus by providing vaccines across the country to individuals at high risk. This phase of the strategy aims to rapidly deploy vaccines in the most affected communities and mitigate the spread of the disease.</p>



<p>This announcement is a critical component of the Administration’s broader public health response, which includes rapidly scaling up and decentralizing testing alongside continued provider education and community engagement across the country. The Administration’s monkeypox outbreak response is also informed by the multiple times over the last twenty years that the United States has effectively responded to the virus. The United States government’s response is coordinated by the National Security Council Directorate on Global Health Security and Biodefense – more commonly known as the White House Pandemic Office – which President Biden restored on day one of his presidency, in collaboration with the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).</p>



<p>Collectively, the Administration’s efforts aim to <strong>expand vaccination for individuals at risk</strong> and <strong>make testing more convenient for healthcare providers and patients across the country</strong>. The Biden-Harris Administration remains committed to working with urgency to detect more cases, protect those at risk, and respond rapidly to the outbreak.</p>



<p><strong>Scaling and Delivering Vaccines to Mitigate New Infections</strong>: Thanks to prior investments in health security and the nation’s prior experience responding to the monkeypox virus, the United States has effective vaccines and treatments that can be used against monkeypox. To date, HHS has received requests from 32 states and jurisdictions, deploying over 9,000 doses of vaccine and 300 courses of antiviral smallpox treatments. <strong>With today’s national monkeypox vaccine strategy, the United States is significantly expanding deployment of vaccines</strong><strong>, allocating 296,000 doses over the coming weeks, 56,000 of which will be allocated immediately. Over the coming months a combined 1.6 million additional doses will become available.</strong></p>



<p><strong>Making Testing Easier</strong>: The new national monkeypox vaccine strategy builds on the Administration’s efforts to make testing more widely available and easier to access. On day one of this outbreak, providers had access to a high-quality, FDA-cleared test to detect monkeypox. The CDC has since scaled testing capacity to 78 sites in 48 states, primarily at state public health laboratories, with spare capacity to conduct nearly 10,000 tests per week nationwide. <strong>Last week, CDC </strong><a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/06/22/hhs-expanding-monkeypox-testing-capacity-five-commercial-laboratory-companies.html"><strong>began shipping&nbsp; tests to five commercial laboratory companies</strong></a><strong>, including some of the nation’s largest reference laboratories, to further increase monkeypox testing capacity and access in every community. </strong><strong>This action will dramatically improve convenience for patients and health care providers across the nation.</strong></p>



<p><strong>Activating Community Leaders and Stakeholders</strong>: The response to monkeypox requires a whole-of-society effort between federal, state, territorial, and local governments and communities. The Biden-Harris Administration is communicating with healthcare providers, public health officials, and affected communities on a daily basis to share information on what the virus is, how to treat it, and which communities are most at risk. The Administration is also sharing information on how to access testing, treatments, and vaccines, and how to prevent transmission with local, government, and community leaders in geographies and communities where transmission rates have been the highest. The Administration is grateful for the leadership and activism of advocates in the LGBTQI+ community who have thus far been most affected and have quickly mobilized to promote information and awareness.</p>



<p><strong><u>The </u></strong><strong><u>Biden-Harris Administration is</u></strong> <strong><u>providing vaccines to protect high-risk groups across America.</u></strong></p>



<p>As part of the monkeypox outbreak response, the Biden-Harris Administration is launching a national strategy to provide vaccines for monkeypox for individuals at higher risk of exposure. The strategy aims to mitigate the spread of the virus in communities where transmission has been the highest and with populations most at risk. This plan distributes the two-dose <a href="https://www.fda.gov/vaccines-blood-biologics/jynneos">JYNNEOS</a> vaccine, which the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved for protection against smallpox and monkeypox in individuals 18 years and older determined to be at high risk for smallpox or monkeypox infection. States will be offered an equitable allotment based on cases and proportion of the population at risk for severe disease from monkeypox, and the federal government will partner with state, local, and territorial governments in deploying the vaccines.</p>



<p>The goal of the initial phase of the strategy is to slow the spread of the disease. HHS will immediately allocate 56,000 vaccine doses currently in the Strategic National Stockpile to states and territories across the country, prioritizing jurisdictions with the highest number of cases and population at risk. To date, vaccines have been provided only to those who have a confirmed monkeypox exposure. With these doses, CDC is recommending that vaccines be provided to individuals with confirmed monkeypox exposures and presumed exposures. This includes those who had close physical contact with someone diagnosed with monkeypox, those who know their sexual partner was diagnosed with monkeypox, and men who have sex with men who have recently had multiple sex partners in a venue where there was known to be monkeypox or in an area where monkeypox is spreading.</p>



<p>In the coming weeks, HHS expects to receive an additional 240,000 vaccines, which will be made available to a broader population of individuals at risk. HHS will hold another 60,000 vaccines in reserve.</p>



<p>As additional doses are received from the manufacturer, HHS will make them available to jurisdictions to expand availability to the vaccine for individuals with elevated risk. HHS is increasing the availability of doses by leveraging its long-standing partnership with the manufacturer of JYNNEOS to expand vaccine supply and by accelerating completion and shipment of doses to the United States. &nbsp;HHS expects more than 750,000 doses to be made available over the summer. An additional 500,000 doses will undergo completion, inspection, and release throughout the fall, totaling 1.6 million doses available this year.</p>



<p>To supplement the supply of JYNNEOS, states and territories may also request a second vaccine, <a href="https://www.fda.gov/vaccines-blood-biologics/vaccines/acam2000">ACAM2000</a>. ACAM2000 is FDA-approved for protection against smallpox, caused by the variola virus. ACAM2000 is also believed to confer protection against monkeypox, and is available under an expanded access investigational new drug protocol sponsored by CDC for vaccination of individuals at risk of monkeypox infection. However, ACAM2000 <a href="https://www.fda.gov/vaccines-blood-biologics/vaccines/acam2000-smallpox-vaccine-questions-and-answers">carries greater risk of certain serious side effects</a> than JYNNEOS and cannot be provided to individuals who are immunocompromised or who have heart disease. The CDC will work with state, territorial, and local health departments requesting the ACAM2000 vaccine to ensure that individuals are fully informed on the benefits and the risks before receiving the vaccine.</p>



<p>HHS will work closely with local and state partners and health providers to continuously evolve and strengthen its vaccine strategy to ensure that vaccines are being made available to communities most at risk and where transmission has been highest.</p>



<p><strong><u>The Administration is expanding testing supply and availability.</u></strong></p>



<p>Last week, CDC began shipping its FDA-cleared orthopox test to five major commercial laboratory companies to rapidly increase monkeypox testing access across the country. This action will dramatically expand testing capacity nationwide and convenience for patients and health care providers. These laboratories will begin to come on board for testing in early July and increase capacity through the month.</p>



<p>This expansion reflects the latest, most significant increase in testing accessibility, building on the capacities already available within the Laboratory Response Network (LRN). CDC has worked with the LRN to increase public health testing capacity by more than 50% since the start of the outbreak, increasing testing capacity from 6,000 tests per week to approximately 10,000 test per week. This network continues to provide spare testing capacity to jurisdictions across the country. CDC is working with state, territorial, and local health departments to make the monkeypox testing process more accessible to health care providers.</p>



<p>To further expand access to testing early in the outbreak, CDC published its protocol from their <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/monkeypox/lab-personnel/lab-procedures.html">FDA-cleared test</a> on June 9, 2022 for any laboratory to test for monkeypox. The FDA is exercising enforcement discretion regarding CDC’s tests, which permits the use of tests beyond the current network. FDA has also authorized the use of additional reagents and automation to increase the capacity of laboratories using the CDC test.</p>



<p>Since the start of the monkeypox outbreak, the number of days from average symptom onset to test has decreased by approximately 35%, enabling patients to more quickly learn their diagnosis, access care, and prevent spread to others. The expansion of testing aims to facilitate further reductions in the gap between symptom onset and test result, maximizing access to treatment and vaccines for patients and high-risk contacts early in the course of disease.</p>



<p><strong><u>The Administration has launched a robust community and stakeholder engagement strategy.</u></strong></p>



<p>The most effective response to infectious disease outbreaks is a community-based response. The Biden-Harris Administration is communicating with healthcare providers, public health officials, and communities on a daily basis to raise awareness of the monkeypox outbreak and educate the public and local and community leaders about what the virus is, how it is transmitted, and which populations are most at risk of the virus. As part of its robust engagement strategy, the Administration is facilitating access to vaccines, treatments, and tests. The Administration will also continue to engage directly with leaders and stakeholders in the LGBTQI+ community to work together to prevent and combat stigma and bias, and promote testing and vaccine access and health equity for LGBTQI+ communities. Through its comprehensive stakeholder engagement strategy, the Administration is also creating a critical feedback loop &#8211; learning from the experiences of those most at risk and responding based on their insights and needs.</p>



<p>HHS has provided a range of public health information to inform providers and high-risk communities, including:</p>



<ul><li>Updating and expanding the monkeypox case definition by June 1<sup>st</sup> to encourage health care providers to consider testing for all rashes with clinical suspicion for monkeypox;</li><li>Releasing emergency information on May 20<sup>th</sup> and June 14<sup>th</sup> covering clinical testing, treatment, contact tracing, and other topics to health providers, sexual and community health centers, and public health officials across the nation;</li><li>Providing over 570 case consultations to healthcare providers and health departments;</li><li>Clarifying how to transport and dispose of medical waste that allowed healthcare facilities and waste management companies to operate confidently and safely; and,</li><li>Regularly speaking with global, community, clinical, and public health stakeholders to solve challenges and answer questions.</li></ul>



<p>HHS and CDC will continue to engage with the public and communities most impacted and at risk on a daily basis throughout the response.</p>



<p><strong><u>The Administration is leading efforts to combat monkeypox globally</u></strong></p>



<p>There is no domestic-only response to a global outbreak. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to combatting monkeypox in the United States and around the world, including in countries where it has been historically endemic. The United States has also supported international efforts to combat monkeypox in endemic countries for years, including in Nigeria and the Democratic Republic of the Congo. The Biden-Harris Administration is dedicated to assisting endemic and non-endemic countries combat their outbreaks and is exploring options to further support the international response.</p>



<p>The Administration is also developing key U.S. monkeypox research and evidence priorities, led by the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, to drive efforts to improve our arsenal of medical countermeasures, strengthen real-time monitoring, enhance our understanding of the monkeypox virus, and energize the broader U.S. and global scientific community around urgent monkeypox research and evidence challenges.</p>



<p>The Biden Administration has been responding to the outbreak since the first domestic case was identified with urgency, humility, and transparency, adapting our approach as we learn more about how this virus is spreading. It will continue to ensure a whole-of-government response to the monkeypox outbreak moving forward, and will lead the government in adapting our response as the situation develops.</p>



<p>To learn more about monkeypox, signs and symptoms, treatments, and prevention, please visit the CDC page <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/poxvirus/monkeypox/index.html">here.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Biden on Trilateral Agreement Between Turkey, Finland, and&#160;Sweden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/statement-by-president-biden-on-trilateral-agreement-between-turkey-finland-and-sweden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 21:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I congratulate Turkey, Finland and Sweden on signing a trilateral memorandum, which paves the way for Allies to invite Finland and Sweden to join NATO at the Madrid Summit. When I welcomed President Niinistö and Prime Minister Andersson to the White House last month, I told them that the United States strongly supports their membership.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I congratulate Turkey, Finland and Sweden on signing a trilateral memorandum, which paves the way for Allies to invite Finland and Sweden to join NATO at the Madrid Summit. When I welcomed President Niinistö and Prime Minister Andersson to the White House last month, I told them that the United States strongly supports their membership. Finland and Sweden are strong democracies with highly capable militaries. Their membership will strengthen NATO’s collective security and benefit the entire Transatlantic Alliance. I look forward to working with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg, our Allies, and with Congress to ensure that we can quickly welcome them into our Alliance. As we begin this historic NATO Summit in Madrid, our Alliance is stronger, more united and more resolute than ever.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Attorneys General Nessel of Michigan and Ellison of Minnesota on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-attorneys-general-nessel-of-michigan-and-ellison-of-minnesota-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 21:04:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Stacey Grigsby, Deputy White House Counsel, met with Attorneys General Dana Nessel of Michigan and Keith Ellison of Minnesota to discuss efforts underway in key states to protect reproductive rights. Vice President Harris later joined the meeting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Stacey Grigsby, Deputy White House Counsel, met with Attorneys General Dana Nessel of Michigan and Keith Ellison of Minnesota to discuss efforts underway in key states to protect reproductive rights. Vice President Harris later joined the meeting and reaffirmed the Administration’s commitment to fighting for reproductive rights. The Vice President discussed the pivotal role that Attorneys General play in safeguarding the rights of the people of their states, and she encouraged them to continue to use their authority to defend reproductive rights and freedoms.</p>



<p>Both Attorneys General have taken significant action to protect access to abortion. Attorney General Nessel pledged not to deploy state resources to enforce Michigan’s 1931 abortion ban, a relic of an era before <em>Roe</em> was decided. On June 21, Attorney General Ellison reassured Minnesotans and the people of every state that no one will be prosecuted in Minnesota for seeking, helping someone else seek, or providing an abortion that is legal in Minnesota.</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials thanked the Attorneys General for their efforts to protect reproductive rights, and committed to working together in the months ahead to protect a woman’s right to make decisions about her own body. Today’s conversation followed a meeting Vice President Harris <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-state-attorneys-general-on-reproductive-rights/">convened</a> with seven Attorneys General last week to discuss reproductive rights.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and King Felipe VI of the Kingdom of Spain Before Bilateral Meeting &#124; Madrid,&#160;Spain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/28/remarks-by-president-biden-and-king-felipe-vi-of-the-kingdom-of-spain-before-bilateral-meeting-madrid-spain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 19:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Palace of MoncloaMadrid, Spain 6:02 P.M. CEST KING FELIPE VI:&#160; Mr. President, welcome.&#160; Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.&#160; (Speaks Spanish.)&#160; (No translation provided.)&#160; Mr. President, as I said earlier on when I welcomed you at the Torrejón Air Force Base, it is truly a wel- &#8212; a pleasure to welcome you to Spain, to our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Palace of Moncloa<br>Madrid, Spain</p>



<p>6:02 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>KING FELIPE VI:&nbsp; Mr. President, welcome.&nbsp; Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Speaks Spanish.)&nbsp; (No translation provided.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, as I said earlier on when I welcomed you at the Torrejón Air Force Base, it is truly a wel- &#8212; a pleasure to welcome you to Spain, to our nation&#8217;s capital, Madrid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve had the opportunity actually to meet on previous occasions, in our previous capacities as well.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>KING FELIPE VI:&nbsp; And I always treasure those opportunities in my memory.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve had chances to talk about things in the past, and I really look forward to that on this occasion as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Kingdom of Spain and the United States of America share profound historical and cultural ties &#8212; we all know that inside out &#8212; and we&#8217;re very proud of them.</p>



<p>But more importantly, we share common values and principles that are, today, the foundation of a rich and wide-ranging relationship and a sincere friendship which we highly value and which we want to continue strengthening every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden and his delegation, with Secretary Blinken ahead of it &#8212; to which will also extend a warm welcome &#8212; are visiting us to attend a very important NATO Summit here in Madrid.&nbsp; This is without &#8212; without a doubt an especially relevant summit, one in which the Allied countries must continue to show unity and determination to defend our freedom and our democratic values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, Queen Letizia and I, our government, the Spanish people are all delighted to have you here with us, together with your delegation and together with your wife, the First Lady, Dr. Jill Biden.&nbsp; And we wish you a very happy, albeit short, stay in Madrid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you very much.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Well, thank you your Majesty.&nbsp; There’s an old expression in a little town in Delaware called Claymont, Delaware, a little steel town.&nbsp; And they say, “We’re like poor relatives.&nbsp; We show up when we’re invited and we stay longer than we should.”&nbsp; So, be careful.&nbsp; We may not go back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>KING FELIPE VI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; This is my second opportunity to be in this magnificent facility.&nbsp; And it’s &#8212; the royal palace is just incredible.</p>



<p>And notwithstanding the magni- &#8212; the majesty of this palace, we do have &#8212; share the same values.&nbsp; As a matter of fact, some suggest we wouldn’t be an independent country were not for you guys some years ago.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I’ve travelled to Madrid as Vice President.&nbsp; And, quite frankly, it’s wonderful to return here again to discuss the consequences of what particularly is happening today in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is &#8212; we’re at a moment of historical &#8212; an inflection point in American &#8212; in world history.&nbsp; Things are changing.&nbsp; They’re changing drastically not only in terms of the politics of the world, but everything from pandemic diseases to dealing with &#8212; dealing with everything from climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I want to thank you for hosting this NATO meeting because it’s been 40 years &#8212; 40 years now you’ve all been members of NATO.&nbsp; And we’re all better off for it.&nbsp; All of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, NATO is united and as united and galvanized as, I believe, it’s ever been.&nbsp; And we’re ready to face the threats of Russian aggression because, quite frankly, there’s no choice.&nbsp; It’s been a &#8212; the most significant abuse of power since World War Two and an invasion of that many people under another country in Europe.&nbsp; Some people thought that was not likely to happen again, but it did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we responded.&nbsp; We responded in unison.&nbsp; And when we agreed we were going to respond, we acknowledged there was going to be some costs to our people.&nbsp; They were going to &#8212; in us im- &#8212; our imposition of sanctions on Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But our people have stood together.&nbsp; They stood up and they’ve stood strong.&nbsp; And, you know, as I told President Sánchez, who I met with a moment ago, that &#8212; I want to thank you, your Highness, for &#8212; for the support of the Spanish people &#8212; and not only as it relates to what is going on in Europe and &#8212; but what&#8217;s happening in North Africa, as well as Latin America.&nbsp; The help and support and the &#8212; the input has been extremely valuable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I tell people that the idea &#8212; we&#8217;ve always &#8212; we&#8217;ve had great migration flows into the United States over the years.&nbsp; We’re &#8212; we’re a nation of immigrants.&nbsp; But an interesting statistic, your Highness, that &#8212; I think it’s 24 out of every 100 students in grade 1 through 12 in America speaks Spanish &#8212; speaks Spanish as their original language.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the future of my country depends considerably on the assimilation of a population that is going to have all the same values that we possess and have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And your help in Latin America is also extremely important and I look forward to &#8212; from here to &#8212; and Europe to Latin America to &#8212; to the Caribbean to Africa.&nbsp; The partnership between our countries is going to determine a good large part how well things look 10 years from now and 15 years from now.</p>



<p>So we have to stay together.&nbsp; The &#8212; the unity is important.&nbsp; And I think we’re off to a very, very good start demonstrating the power of democracies in the second quarter of the 21st century, because there is &#8212; there is a contest between autocracies and democracies, and we have to succeed.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m confident we will with your help.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>6:09 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Pedro Sánchez of the Kingdom of Spain Before Bilateral Meeting &#124; Madrid,&#160;Spain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/28/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-pedro-sanchez-of-the-kingdom-of-spain-before-bilateral-meeting-madrid-spain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 18:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Palace of MoncloaMadrid, Spain 5:23 P.M. CEST PRESIDENT SÁNCHEZ:&#160; Good afternoon, and welcome to Madrid.&#160; I would like to &#8212; to start by thanking President Biden for coming to Spain to participate in the Madrid NATO Summit.&#160; I&#8217;m also very, very glad to welcome you in the Moncloa Palace in your first visit as President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Palace of Moncloa<br>Madrid, Spain</p>



<p>5:23 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT SÁNCHEZ:&nbsp; Good afternoon, and welcome to Madrid.&nbsp; I would like to &#8212; to start by thanking President Biden for coming to Spain to participate in the Madrid NATO Summit.&nbsp; I&#8217;m also very, very glad to welcome you in the Moncloa Palace in your first visit as President of the United States.</p>



<p>(Speaks Spanish.)&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Spain and the U.S. are allies.&nbsp; We are strategic partners.&nbsp; We are friends.&nbsp; We are linked together by strong historical bonds and strong partnership in many topics.</p>



<p>Moreover, we share that desire to promote the principles of freedom, democracy, human rights, gender equality, and the state of law.&nbsp; And after over 20 years since the declaration that was signed by the Secretary of State Madeleine Albright and the then-Foreign Affairs Minister of Spain Josep Piqué in 2001, there&#8217;s obviously been numerous changes that have affected transatlantic relations and relations between Spain and the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is, dear Mr. President, why I&#8217;m so happy to announce this new joint declaration between the U.S. and Spain, which will help to strengthen the relations between Spain and the U.S.</p>



<p>In this declaration, we are doing a lot of different things.&nbsp; First of all, we are reinforcing our support for a rules-based international order.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s very important to say that today here in Madrid as a consequence of the holding of the NATO Summit here because Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine is a clear violation of international law, a direct attack on our shared values, and it demonstrates the need to redouble our efforts to support that rules-based international order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And one of the main consequences of Putin’s war has actually been the revitalization of the transatlantic Alliance.&nbsp; When Europe&#8217;s security was at stake, what every Ally has done, including Spain, has been to respond decisively, reinforcing our eastern flank while recognizing the threats that come from the southern flank and, therefore, the importance for the Alliance to develop everything that&#8217;s been called the “Alliance 360 strategy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Spain has practically, dear Mr. President, doubled its military presence in Latvia with the recent deployment this very week of an anti-air defense system in the Lielvarde Air Force Base.&nbsp; The Spanish contingent in Latvia is now 592.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re also taking part in the Baltic air police patrols.&nbsp; Our Navy ships are maintaining their presence in the Alliance’s permanent forces.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, in total, Spain is participating with its deployments in five NATO missions with a total of 1,471 forces deployed.</p>



<p>And in this context in which we&#8217;re dealing, I think, with the biggest challenge to peace in Europe since the end of the Cold War, today the U.S. and Spain have committed to strengthen our cooperation in the areas of defense and security. </p>



<p>Specifically, we have spoken about the U.S.’s interest in increasing its presence in Rota’s Navy Base in order to strengthen the Alliance&#8217;s collective security. </p>



<p>And on the other hand, and as is set down in the joint declaration, we have agreed to strengthen the bonds between us in the areas of justice, cybersecurity, energy security &#8212; and, by the way, I&#8217;m very grateful to the U.S. government and the whole of the U.S. for all that LPG that we are receiving in Spain &#8212; and also the management of immigration flows, everything that has to do with climate change, technology, and digital transformation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in this update of this joint declaration that was signed back in 2001, we are expanding and reinforcing our bilateral relations.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also, of course, aware of the importance of the trade relations between our economies.&nbsp; And in our respective national recovery plans, we see an excellent opportunity for U.S. companies in Spain and Spanish companies in the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in that context, I would like to thank President Biden for his role in redefining the transatlantic trade relations, which, over the last year, have been able to resolve past differences and embark on a much more positive track &#8212; forgetting that past and looking towards the future with hope.</p>



<p>We also agree on the importance of promoting a positive agenda in Latin America, a region which &#8212; in the most part, a region with shared values.&nbsp; And together, we will be able to better defend a rules-based international order.</p>



<p>Together, we&#8217;ve also discussed the increasing challenges of a very important region for Spain and Europe, which is the Sahel; also the role of China in the current geopolitical context, which will be discussed in the NATO Summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we will continue to work together in multilateral fora, like the U.N. and the G20, in order to promote a coordinated response to all the global challenges we have, including climate emergency, food security, or the architecture of global health after the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>So, overall, this visit, dear Mr. President, has been a significant turning point in the bilateral relations between our two countries.</p>



<p>(Speaks English.)&nbsp; Allow me to finish by thanking you for your leadership.&nbsp; We are pleased to have the U.S. back on the side of multilateralism.&nbsp; The Madrid NATO Summit will start tomorrow and the decisions that we will take will reinforce our transatlantic bond.&nbsp; You can count on Spain as a solid ally and friend.</p>



<p>Thank you very much, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Pedro.&nbsp; You can count on us as well.&nbsp; And, you know, thank you for welcoming me today here and for hosting the NATO Summit in Madrid.&nbsp; And we have a &#8212; we had a very warm and personal discussion upstairs.&nbsp; And one of the things I look forward to is having an hour together before we begin the whole conference.</p>



<p>You know, we&#8217;re marking 40 years &#8212; 40 years since Spain joined NATO in becoming an indispensable Ally.&nbsp; And today, we&#8217;re standing together to defend our shared security &#8212; and I emphasize shared security; strengthen our transatlantic alliance; and meet the challenge we face today and in the future.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the things we&#8217;re going to be talking about in this meeting this week.</p>



<p>And as President Sánchez and I want to talk to you &#8212; thank you for Spain&#8217;s hospitality for U.S. service members and their families stationed here in Spain.</p>



<p>Mr. President, you&#8217;re hosting a truly historic summit and the key moment in our Alliance when Russia&#8217;s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine was &#8212; shattered peace in Europe and shattered every norm since World War Two that’s has been in place.&nbsp; And I want to thank you personally &#8212; you &#8212; for your leadership.</p>



<p>Transatlantic unity has been and will continue to be the greatest strength in our response to Russia &#8212; transatlantic security.&nbsp; We&#8217;re standing as one to support Ukraine and to enhance our own deterrence and defense capabilities.</p>



<p>And as I said before the war started: If Putin attacked Ukraine, United States would enhance our force posture Europe and respond to the reality of a new European security environment.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, we &#8212; we surged additional U.S. forces to Europe to bolster our Alliance in response to Russia&#8217;s aggressive actions.&nbsp; And for months, we&#8217;ve been consulting closely on additional steps the United States will take alongside our Allies, who are also stepping up and strengthening our selective and collective security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, the new commitments will constitute an impressive display of Allied unity and resolve and NATO&#8217;s 360-degree approach to our security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m looking forward to discussing all of this during the summit.&nbsp; But, Mr. President, you and I discussed today: We&#8217;re going to work on an agreement to increase the number of U.S. naval destroyers stationed at Spain&#8217;s Rota Naval Base, which will also enhance the bilateral defensive relationship between Spain and the United States.&nbsp; We expect that to occur much sooner than later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I welcome the steps that Spain has taken in solidarity with our Allies that we’re facing heightened threats on their borders, including sending additional capabilities you referenced to Latvia.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll be laying out additional steps the United States is going to take with our NATO colleagues as our &#8212; in our summit tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the bottom line is this: Together, the Alliance is threatening [sic] its posture &#8212; is dealing with the threats and strengthening our posture against the threats from the east and challenges from the south.  NATO is focused on all directions and domains: land, air, and sea. </p>



<p>And, Mr. President, we also discussed how the United States and Spain and other Allies are keeping needed weapons and equipment flowing to Ukraine so they &#8212; they&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re standing up in ways that I don&#8217;t think anyone anticipated, showing enormous bravery, enormous resolve.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re continuing to tighten sanctions on Russia as well.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re providing assistance to the government and the people of Ukraine as they respond to this unprovoked assault on their lives and their democracies.&nbsp; Sometimes, I think Putin&#8217;s objective is just to literally change the entire culture, wipe out the culture of Ukraine &#8212; the kinds of actions he&#8217;s taking.</p>



<p>And I want to particularly thank you, Mr. President, and the people of Spain for the support you&#8217;ve shown in welcoming more than 140,000 Ukrainian citizens refuge here in Spain. That&#8217;s remarkable and a testament to your people.&nbsp; And it’s a testament to the spirit and resolve of not only the Spanish people, but of your leadership and to stand up for what is right at a moment of crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our shared democratic values, together with our long history of friendship, make Spain and the United States strong partners on all the issues that we face together.&nbsp; In the Western Hemisphere, Spain and the United States are working together with other countries in the Latin and Caribbean areas to reinforce democratic institutions, strengthen the rule of law, spread economic prosperity, and advanced transformative approaches to manage migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re looking to do more together in Africa as well to promote stability and economic growth.&nbsp; And we reaffirmed our joint commitment today to continue to work together on the biggest challenges that affect the people all around the world, from COVID-19 to climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re releasing a Joint Declaration that reaffirms our shared values, reflects the full breadth of our cooperation.&nbsp; And we have asked our teams to follow up on the substance of the Joint Declaration so they become known to everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, thank you, again, Pedro, for your friendship and your close partnership.&nbsp; And we had a good discussion today, and I&#8217;m looking forward to continue good discussions for the remainder of this conference.&nbsp; But thank you for your hospitality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>5:35 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Bilateral Meeting between President Joe&#160;Biden and President Andrés Manuel López Obrador of&#160;Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-bilateral-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-president-andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-of-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 17:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 12, President Joe Biden will host Andrés Manuel López Obrador, President of Mexico, for a bilateral meeting at the White House.  The First Lady of the United States Jill Biden will also host Ms. Beatriz Gutierrez Müller, First Lady of Mexico.  The leaders will discuss their efforts to address global challenges, such as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 12, President Joe Biden will host Andrés Manuel López Obrador, President of Mexico, for a bilateral meeting at the White House.  The First Lady of the United States Jill Biden will also host Ms. Beatriz Gutierrez Müller, First Lady of Mexico.  The leaders will discuss their efforts to address global challenges, such as food security, and discuss joint competitiveness initiatives, such as work being undertaken in the U.S.-Mexico High-Level Economic Dialogue.  They also plan to discuss their visions for North America, cooperation on migration, joint development efforts in Central America, security, climate and energy, and global issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Declaration Between the Kingdom of Spain and the United&#160;States of&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/joint-declaration-between-the-kingdom-of-spain-and-the-united-states-of-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 15:52:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Spain and the United States are Allies, strategic partners, and friends. Our bilateral relationship is based on deep historical ties, shared democratic values, and a common vision for addressing global challenges. Spain and the United States are committed to upholding peace and security, protecting the planet’s climate for future generations, promoting democracy and human rights,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Spain and the United States are Allies, strategic partners, and friends. Our bilateral relationship is based on deep historical ties, shared democratic values, and a common vision for addressing global challenges. Spain and the United States are committed to upholding peace and security, protecting the planet’s climate for future generations, promoting democracy and human rights, and enhancing economic prosperity around the world. To affirm our commitment to working closely together to advance these goals, the President of the Government of Spain, Pedro Sánchez Pérez Castejón, and the President of the United States of America, Joseph R. Biden, Jr., on the occasion of President Biden’s visit to Spain on June 28-30, 2022, have reached the following understandings:</p>



<p><strong>Reinforcing multilateral responses to transatlantic and global challenges<br><br></strong>1.&nbsp;Spain and the United States condemn Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of choice against Ukraine, which has fundamentally altered the global strategic environment. This aggression constitutes the most direct threat to transatlantic security and global stability since the end of the Cold War. Russia’s actions also threaten the food security of some of the most vulnerable people around the world. Spain and the United States intend to continue working together, along and with other partners and allies, including the rest of the EU and the G7, to support the government and the people of Ukraine and to hold Russia accountable for its violations of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, including gross violations of international law by targeting civilians with violence, and conflict-related sexual violence. Spain and the United States also reiterate their strong support for Ukraine’s determination to choose its own future.</p>



<p>2.&nbsp;Spain and the United States are committed to defending the rules-based international order, which has been the foundation for preserving our security and advancing our prosperity over the past seven decades. We are fully committed to the goals of the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. We intend to strengthen international and multilateral institutions to promote strong, sustainable, and inclusive economic growth, defend democratic governance, and advance solutions to global challenges.&nbsp; We stand united in our determination to address challenges to that international order.&nbsp; In this regard we continue to encourage China to uphold its commitments within the rules-based international order, to contribute to international security, and to cooperate in the provision of global public goods, including on climate change, biodiversity and gender equality.</p>



<p><strong>Strengthening defense cooperation<br><br></strong>3. The United States and Spain recognize the central importance of the NATO Alliance in ensuring transatlantic peace and security. As NATO Allies for 40 years, Spain and the United States are steadfastly committed to providing NATO with ready forces and capabilities, strengthening their transatlantic ties, and ensuring a 360-degree approach to security, particularly by enhancing the relationship with mutual partners, such as the European Union. The Madrid Summit hosted by Spain will ensure that NATO is united behind a new Strategic Concept guiding the Alliance’s approach towards strategic competitors and transnational threats, and that NATO’s military and political activities are resourced to address a more dangerous security environment.</p>



<p>4.&nbsp;Spain and the United States underline their commitment to the U.S.-Spain Agreement on Defense Cooperation signed in 1988, which, together with the shared use of Spain’s bases in Rota and Morón, is an essential piece of the bilateral defense cooperation between the two countries. Spain and the United States intend to expand their defense cooperation through the permanent stationing of additional U.S. naval vessels in Rota. The two countries intend to hold regular meetings within the framework of the bilateral High-Level Defense Group to strengthen defense cooperation.</p>



<p><strong>Defending democracy, human rights, and gender equality<br><br></strong>5. Spain and the United States share the fundamental values ​​of support for freedom, equity and equality, democracy, and the rule of law. Both countries reaffirm their commitment to a foreign policy guided by the defense of human rights, especially the rights of women and vulnerable populations, such as people living in poverty, members of racially or ethnically marginalized groups, LGBTQI+ persons, members of religious minority groups, persons with disabilities, refugees, migrants, internally displaced persons, older adults, children, gender non-conforming persons, and trafficking victims.<br><br>6. The United States and Spain underscore the importance of promoting gender equity and equality globally. Both countries intend to work together to promote policies and initiatives that advance the rights of women and girls, including through the Women, Peace, and Security agenda. &nbsp;As underscored during this Summit for Democracy Year of Action, they are committed to cooperation in strengthening democratic governance and the protection and promotion of human rights throughout the world, particularly with the countries of Latin America and the Caribbean where the United States and Spain both have deep and enduring affiliations.</p>



<p><strong>Intensifying collaboration on justice and security issues<br></strong><br>7. The United States and Spain intend to maintain and build upon their strong law enforcement cooperation, including with respect to extradition and mutual legal assistance. They plan to reinforce their collaboration in the fight against terrorism, cybercrime, drug trafficking, and trafficking in persons. They intend to strengthen cybersecurity cooperation to increase national resilience to cyber-attacks, promote responsible state behavior in cyberspace, and counter malicious cyber activity from nation states and criminal actors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>8. The United States and Spain will continue to work together to strengthen counterterrorism cooperation at the bilateral level and internationally. They also will work to curb the abuse of new information and communication technologies by terrorists, violent extremists, and authoritarian regimes.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Promoting safe, orderly, and regular migration<br></strong><br>9. Both countries intend to collaborate on a comprehensive approach in the management of irregular migration flows, ensuring the just and humane treatment of migrants. Both countries also plan to coordinate efforts to address the root causes of irregular migration and work to strengthen legal pathways, with a particular focus on the countries of Latin America and the Caribbean. &nbsp;Spain and the United States likewise recognize the importance of ongoing cooperation in response to the challenges of irregular migration in the North Africa region.</p>



<p><strong>Fighting climate change and increasing energy security<br></strong><br>10. Spain and the United States recognize that the climate crisis is one of the most serious challenges of our time. Both countries stress the urgent need to increase global climate action to ensure that deep reductions in global greenhouse gas emissions are achieved by 2030 and reach net zero by 2050. In this light, they commit to pursuing a climate-smart recovery that strengthens biodiversity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>11. Both countries are committed to developing joint strategies to boost climate action in low and middle-income countries and sectoral strategies to accelerate the deployment of clean and renewable energy and the promotion of just transition to decarbonized and circular economies. They recognize the need to reach the Paris Agreement goals, including to accelerate global efforts to make financial flows consistent with low greenhouse gas emissions and climate resilient development. &nbsp;Both countries also underscore the importance of making continued progress towards the collective goal to mobilize annually 100 billion U.S. dollars for climate action in developing countries. They recognize the urgency of addressing methane in line with the Global Methane Pledge, improving adaptation to the impacts of climate change, and promoting a climate resilient development, especially in the most vulnerable countries.</p>



<p>12. The United States and Spain stress the importance of joint action to improve Europe’s energy security and reduce dependence on Russian fossil fuels. Both countries are committed to collaboration to increase the geographical diversification of energy sources, especially natural gas, to promote renewable energies and develop new vectors such as offshore wind-power and renewable hydrogen, to deploy smart technologies that promote energy efficiency, and to secure supply chains for the critical minerals essential to the energy transition.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding cooperation in commercial and economic matters<br></strong><br>13. Spain and the United States are committed to strengthening the rules-based multilateral trade system to ensure fair competition and legal certainty. Both countries are committed to promoting the development of trade and investment, including entrepreneurship, small- and medium-sized businesses, and innovation as the basis for strong, sustainable, inclusive economic growth that creates quality employment in both countries and incorporates diverse and excluded groups, while ensuring adequate protection for digital economy workers. They are committed to transatlantic cooperation to resolve trade, economic and technological differences; promote energy security and sustainability; and build resilient supply chains that are transparent, secure, sustainable, and diverse. They are committed to ending the race to the bottom on corporate taxation through the swift implementation of the OECD/G20 Inclusive Framework’s Two-Pillar Solution.</p>



<p><strong>Boosting digital, scientific, and technological cooperation<br></strong><br>14. The United States and Spain defend a digital transformation based on a shared respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms and democratic values, on reducing the digital divide, on preventing and addressing the disproportionate effects of online forms of violence and abuse on women, children, and other marginalized groups, and on the implementation of mechanisms to safeguard these principles. They express the importance of coordinating actions to mitigate security risks in the digital environment, especially the importance of working with trusted suppliers, and cooperating in defining and utilizing international standards, including open standards, and best practices that contribute to reliable and secure digitalization. They express their commitment to cooperation initiatives in the transatlantic framework, such as the EU-U.S. Trade and Technology Council, as a tool for addressing challenges in the trade, economic and technological sphere.</p>



<p>15. Spain and the United States intend to continue promoting joint science, space, and innovation initiatives carried out by research organizations, universities, and private companies in all fields of space and science, including through scientific-technological initiatives of the European Union. Spain and the United States plan to encourage industrial initiatives to enhance open strategic autonomy, especially in critical raw materials.</p>



<p>16. Both countries aim to intensify cultural and educational exchanges through bilateral programs such as the Fulbright Program, the Spain-USA Foundation, and the U.S.-Spain Council.</p>



<p><strong>Strengthening political cooperation&nbsp;<br></strong><br>17. Spain and the United States intend to continue high-level consultations between the two governments. The Spanish Minister of Foreign Affairs, European Union and Cooperation and the U.S. Secretary of State intend to continue their regular political consultations, and the Spanish Secretary of State for Foreign and Global Affairs and the U.S. Deputy Secretary of State intend to continue their regular contact. In addition, regular region- and issue-focused meetings should take place on topics of mutual interest to include Latin America and the Caribbean, the Maghreb, the Sahel, China and the Indo-Pacific, Russia, multilateral affairs, migration, science and technology, and cybersecurity.</p>



<p><strong>Looking to the future<br></strong><br>18. In the spirit of this joint declaration, Spain and the United States intend to continue strengthening their bilateral relations, expanding on these understandings as needed. As Spain prepares for its presidency of the Council of the European Union in the second half of 2023, the two countries intend to prioritize cooperation on foreign policy, security, defense, and economic issues as they relate to the EU. &nbsp;Spain and the United States look forward to working together to meet the challenges of the twenty-first century and to seizing opportunities for deepening their cooperation so that it provides security and prosperity to citizens on both sides of the Atlantic.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Tragic Loss of Life in San Antonio,&#160;Texas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-tragic-loss-of-life-in-san-antonio-texas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 15:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56414</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The tragic loss of life in San Antonio, Texas that took place yesterday is horrifying and heartbreaking.  Our prayers are with those who lost their lives, their loved ones, as well as those still fighting for their lives. As always, I am grateful for the swift work of all of the Federal, state, and local&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The tragic loss of life in San Antonio, Texas that took place yesterday is horrifying and heartbreaking.  Our prayers are with those who lost their lives, their loved ones, as well as those still fighting for their lives. As always, I am grateful for the swift work of all of the Federal, state, and local first responders.</p>



<p>While we are still learning all the facts about what happened and the Department of Homeland Security has the lead for the investigation, initial reports are that this tragedy was caused by smugglers or human traffickers who have no regard for the lives they endanger and exploit to make a profit.</p>



<p>This incident underscores the need to go after the multi-billion dollar criminal smuggling industry preying on migrants and leading to far too many innocent deaths. In Los Angeles two weeks ago, I announced that the United States has launched a first-of-its kind anti-smuggling campaign with our regional partners.  In the first three months, we have made over 2,400 arrests, and that work will only intensify in the months ahead.  </p>



<p>Exploiting vulnerable individuals for profit is shameful, as is political grandstanding around tragedy, and my Administration will continue to do everything possible to stop human smugglers and traffickers from taking advantage of people who are seeking to enter the United States between ports of entry.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Madrid,&#160;Spain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/28/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-madrid-spain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 14:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Madrid, Spain 2:10 P.M. CEST MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Okay, well, welcome to our second leg of the trip, heading to Spain, Madrid, specifically.&#160; Jake Sullivan here, our National Security Advisor &#8212; the President&#8217;s National Security Advisor &#8212; is going to give us a little bit lay of the land for NATO&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Madrid, Spain</p>



<p>2:10 P.M. CEST<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, well, welcome to our second leg of the trip, heading to Spain, Madrid, specifically.&nbsp; Jake Sullivan here, our National Security Advisor &#8212; the President&#8217;s National Security Advisor &#8212; is going to give us a little bit lay of the land for NATO and answer any of your questions.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jake.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; We&#8217;re obviously on our way to Madrid for what we expect will be a historic NATO Summit at a time of war in Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NATO today is more united, determined, and purposeful than it&#8217;s been at any point in modern memory.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s in no small part because of the intense diplomacy and leadership that President Biden has invested over the course of the past few months, including hosting a virtual NATO Summit immediately after Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine in February and then calling for an emergency summit in Brussels a month later.</p>



<p>So, NATO leaders will now have had three opportunities since the start of the war to get together, once virtually and now twice in person.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, obviously, Ukraine will be top of mind with Russia’s ongoing brutality most recently on display with this gruesome and horrific attack on the shopping center yesterday.</p>



<p>And then, NATO Allies will have the opportunity to talk about capabilities and other forms of military assistance they&#8217;ll be providing to Ukraine on an ongoing basis in the coming days and months.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ll also have an opportunity to reaffirm their determination to remain united for as long as it takes to ensure a sovereign and independent Ukraine and that Russia pays a severe price for its wanton aggression against Ukraine.</p>



<p>More broadly, this summit will provide an opportunity to set the strategic direction for the Alliance for the coming years.&nbsp; And one of the things that will be a significant outcome of the summit will be a new Strategic Concept.&nbsp; The last Strategic Concept was agreed among Allies in 2010, 12 years ago.&nbsp; So this is the first NATO Summit to produce a new Strategic Concept since then.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That Strategic Concept described Russia as a strategic partner and did not refer to China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Strategic Concept will describe in stark terms the threat that Russia poses and the way in which it has shattered peace in Europe.&nbsp; It will speak very directly and in a clear-eyed way to the multifaceted challenge posed by the People&#8217;s Republic of China.&nbsp; And it will also address modern and emerging threats, cyber and emerging technologies, hybrid warfare, the growing national security implications of climate change, and of course, the evolving threat of terrorism, which has changed over the course of the 20 years since the Alliance went into Afghanistan back in 2001.</p>



<p>In addition to the Strategic Concept, which will be agreed and adopted by leaders, the Alliance will also agree on specific targets for increased common funding for NATO, for its various budgets, to ensure that all of the strategic lines of effort that are captured in that Strategic Concept are fully resourced and that NATO has the funding that is required for it to be able to actually carry out its activities.</p>



<p>One note on that: In addition to the deliverable of common funding at the summit, what will be on display is a marked increase in national contributions by countries to the point where we anticipate, at this summit, you will see that a strong majority of NATO Allies will be either at the 2 percent Wales benchmark or on track to meet it by 2024, which is a &#8212; just over the course of the past 18 months, a substantial shift in the intensity and commitment of NATO Allies in terms of putting their money where their mouth is.</p>



<p>Germany, obviously, made a historic announcement earlier this year; other countries have followed suit.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re seeing a real commitment across the board for countries to actually make the contributions to national capabilities necessary for the Alliance to be very strong.</p>



<p>The other area where we expect to see a significant, indeed historic, set of deliverables is on the issue of force posture.&nbsp; The President said before the war started that if Putin invaded Ukraine, the United States and NATO would enhance its force posture on the eastern flank, not just for the duration of the crisis, but to address the long-term change in the strategic reality that that would present.</p>



<p>And in this summit, you will see the Alliance follow through on that commitment and the United States follow through on that commitment.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see a number of countries making commitments to increase their defense contributions to the eastern flank of the Alliance, with a special emphasis on the Balkan &#8212; the Baltics, but also other eastern flank allies as well.</p>



<p>And the United States will be making specific announcements tomorrow on land, sea, and air of additional force posture commitments over the long term, beyond the duration of this crisis, however long it goes on.</p>



<p>One of those announcements, which the President will lay out today when he meets with the Spanish President, will be an increase in the number of destroyers based at Rota, Spain, from four to six destroyers.&nbsp; Those will help increase the United States’ and NATO&#8217;s maritime presence and all the relevant maritime domains in the Euro-Atlantic area.&nbsp; But that will be just the first of several specific announcements, the rest of which we will lay out for you all tomorrow, on the first day of the NATO Summit.</p>



<p>And we think by the end of the summit, what you will see is a more robust, more effective, more combat-credible, more capable, and more determined force posture to take account of a more acute and aggravated Russian threat, not just because of what they&#8217;ve done in Ukraine, but also because of the way in which they have changed their posture vis-à-vis Belarus, which has an impact on many of our Allies, especially our Baltic Allies.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ll go into more specifics on that set of announcements tomorrow.&nbsp; But that, we believe, will be a very important part of the outcome of this summit.</p>



<p>Final thing to put on the table is: In addition to the meeting of 30 leaders tomorrow morning &#8212; the 30 Allies &#8212; there will be an afternoon session with partners, and it will display the strong partnership that Finland and Sweden have already shown as NATO partners.&nbsp; But Allies, including the United States, will have the chance to lift up and lend their voice to &#8212; their voice of support to Finland and Sweden joining the Alliance.&nbsp; And we will continue to work with Turkey to address their concerns so that Finland and Sweden can ultimately become members of NATO and help contribute in an even more direct way to the security of the Euro-Atlantic area and to the NATO Alliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will also have four Asia Pacific partners for the first time ever at a NATO summit.&nbsp; This is consistent with President Biden&#8217;s very strong view and central premise that the linkage in security between the Indo-Pacific and the Euro-Atlantic is only deepening.&nbsp; And so, the ties between allies in the two theaters have to deepen as well, not because NATO is going to go be fighting wars in the Pacific but because there is an interconnection between the robustness and vitality of our Asia-Pacific alliances and our Euro-Atlantic alliances.&nbsp; And so Japan, Korea, Australia, and New Zealand will all be present.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President, tomorrow, will have the opportunity to host a trilateral meeting with the President of Korea and the Prime Minister of Japan.&nbsp; This will be the first trilateral leaders-level meeting that we&#8217;ve had in some time among the leaders of these three countries.&nbsp; And it will be mainly focused on the continuing threat from the DPRK, particularly after an extended period of intense testing and other provocative activities that the &#8212; that the North Koreans have undertaken.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in the session more broadly, he&#8217;ll have the opportunity to talk with our Indo-Pacific partners and the NATO Alliance about the China challenge and the ways in which it increasingly is a relevant factor for the NATO Alliance, as will be reflected in the Strategic Concept.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ll stop there, and happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, just on NATO accession: President Erdoğan said that the President asked him for a meeting either tonight or tomorrow.&nbsp; Are they going to have a &#8212; sort of a formal engagement?&nbsp; And does the President now see a direct role for the United States in brokering NATO accessions for Finland and Sweden?&nbsp; And are there U.S. inducements that could help sort of sweeten the deal or grease the wheels for Turkey here?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The Secretary General of NATO has taken the lead &#8212; appropriately and correctly &#8212; in working with Finland and Sweden on the one hand and Turkey on the other hand to find a way forward that addresses Turkey’s concerns and ultimately delivers Finland and Sweden&#8217;s entry into the Alliance.&nbsp; We believe that is how it should be and how it will remain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States is not going to supplant the Secretary General or take on a brokering role in this.&nbsp; Rather, we&#8217;re going to do what many other Allies have done, which is indicate publicly and privately that we believe it is in the interest of the Alliance to get this done.&nbsp; And we also believe that Finland and Sweden have taken significant steps forward in terms of addressing Turkey&#8217;s concerns.&nbsp; We also believe and are confident that, ultimately, they will become members of the Alliance and that Turkey&#8217;s concerns will be fully addressed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of a bilateral meeting: We do expect, at some point tomorrow, President Erdoğan and President Biden have the chance to talk.&nbsp; What the modalities of that will be precisely are still being worked out.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not a fixed time or &#8212; or framework for the meeting, but they&#8217;ll have a chance to spend some time together to focus mainly on the strategic issues between the U.S. and Turkey and regional issues that are relevant to the two countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, the issue of Finland and Sweden will come up but we don&#8217;t anticipate that that&#8217;s going to be the central focus of the President&#8217;s meeting with President Erdoğan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on force posture: You mentioned persistent presence on the eastern flank.&nbsp; Is that going to be permanent basing?&nbsp; Because obviously there’s the NATO-Russia agreement from the late ‘90s.&nbsp; There’s agreement or commitment not to have permanent &#8212; permanent seems to be a bit of a (inaudible).&nbsp; Does the U.S. believe NATO is bound by that commitment to Russia from 25 years ago not to have permanent basing on its &#8212; on its borders?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I am not going to get ahead of our announcement tomorrow.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just say to you: Stay tuned in terms of the elements that will be part of that, which will involve additional forces on the eastern flank in a steady state.&nbsp; But to the particular question on rotational, permanent, et cetera: Stay tuned.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question that is not about NATO but is relevant to this week.&nbsp; Brittney Griner faces a trial in Russia.&nbsp; What is the Biden administration doing to help her, to get her home?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the involvement?&nbsp; And do you have any update on how she&#8217;s doing?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, Brittney Griner is wrongfully detained, unjustly detained, and we have made that clear as an official determination of the U.S. government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, the Russian government should release her and allow her to be returned and reunited with her family and come home safe and sound.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, both myself and Secretary Blinken have had the opportunity, just in the last few days, to speak with her &#8212; with her wife, Cherelle, and to convey our very deep sympathy, to convey that, you know, we just can&#8217;t even begin to imagine what the family must be going through, what Brittney &#8212; what Brittney must be going through.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States government is actively engaged in trying to resolve this case and get Brittney home.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into the details of what that means because these are sensitive matters.&nbsp; But I will tell you it has the fullest attention of the President and every senior member of his national security and diplomatic team.&nbsp; And we are actively working to find a resolution to this case, and will continue to do so without rest until we get Brittney safely home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also are trying to work actively to return all unjustly detained Americans and hostages being held overseas, whether that be in Iran or Afghanistan or Russia or Venezuela or China or elsewhere.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, President Zelenskyy has made clear that he wants this war to draw to a close by the end of this year and believes that Ukraine, by the winter, can regain the territory it has currently lost by Russia.&nbsp; What does the U.S. think of that assessment?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we discussed this a little bit yesterday with the pool.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want to characterize President Zelenskyy’s words.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let him speak for himself publicly on this matter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would just say that at the &#8212; at multiple levels &#8212; diplomatic, military to military, and President to President &#8212; we&#8217;ve had very deep and detailed discussions with the Ukrainians about their plans, about how they intend to proceed, both in terms of trying to halt Russian advances in the east and, ultimately, take back territory in the south and other places.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re communicating with them our analysis and assessment of those plans.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing so privately.&nbsp; But, in general,</p>



<p>we believe that it is the Ukrainians who should be setting the course of the objectives in the war, and the United States and our Allies and partners who should be supplying them with the capabilities to be able to achieve those objectives.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re focused on, and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; And that will continue in the days and weeks ahead, including through the recent delivery of the HIMARS that we believe are now being used to good effect on the battlefield.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, I wanted to ask you about the oil price cap discussions.&nbsp; The French pushed for that to be not just referencing Russia but also other countries in the world, including the United States?&nbsp; Can you say a word about that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And can you &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sorry &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; so that &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; including the United States?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, just to sort of have it be a broader initiative by the G7 rather than just focused solely on Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I wanted to ask you: You know, Prime Minister Modi was there.&nbsp; Were there discussions with him about India&#8217;s purchases of Russian oil?&nbsp; And &#8212; or do you see any kind of progress on that front?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, what ministers have now been tasked with by the leaders is to work on the specifics of how a price cap would actually work.&nbsp; One aspect of that, of course, is intensive engagement with key consuming countries.&nbsp; India is one of those countries.&nbsp; That engagement has begun.&nbsp; We have begun talks with India about how a price cap would work and what the implications of it would be.&nbsp; And I will leave it at that because, of course, those are ongoing diplomatic discussions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did the President speak with Prime Minister Modi about this issue specifically?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President did not speak with Prime Minister Modi about this yesterday, but at senior levels of the U.S. government, we had communications with the Indians yesterday.&nbsp; Before it goes to leader-to-leader level, we need to work through the details with their team at basically the Cabinet level, which is where it is right now.&nbsp; And then, if necessary, it can be elevated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the trilat that you&#8217;re doing tomorrow or &#8212; tomorrow, right? &#8212; Janet Yellen &#8212; Secretary Yellen is going to be going to Korea as well, as part of her Asia trip, including the G20.&nbsp; Are you &#8212; do you see any scope to be moving toward additional sanctions on North Korea?&nbsp; And would that even be effective in terms of their nuclear testing program?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We actually have kept up a tempo of sanctions over the course of the 18 months.&nbsp; And we are constantly looking for new targets, especially because North Korea adjusts its methods of acquiring revenue constantly.&nbsp; And so we need to constantly be looking for ways to cut off those new sources of revenue.&nbsp; And that is something that will be a matter of real consultation between Secretary Yellen and the financial watchdogs in North Korea &#8212; in South Korea. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And the President will have the opportunity with President Yoon and Prime Minister Kishida to discuss what we can do on the economic pressure side, particularly when it comes to depriving the North of hard currency that they use to fund their nuclear and missile programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on China and the Strategic Concept, can you talk a little bit more about the language, what it will say vis-à-vis Taiwan?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, the G7 leaders have just also had, you know, a large portion of their statement about China, saying they&#8217;re calling on Beijing to press Russia to stop their aggression.&nbsp; What exactly do the G7 leaders want?&nbsp; Do they want more public pressure?&nbsp; Do they want anything public?&nbsp; What have you guys agreed on to have Xi Jinping weigh in there?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, first, the &#8212; for us, the number-one priority with respect to China, when it comes to the war in Ukraine, is that China not become militarily supportive of Russia through the provision of equipment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two is that they not engage in wholesale or systematic undermining or evasion of U.S. sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on both of those, thus far, we have not seen China act in a way inconsistent with those two principles and certainly not at scale with respect to the economic relationship.&nbsp; So we want to see that continue.</p>



<p>In addition, as you noted, in the G7 statement, the leaders want to communicate to the PRC that the PRC, if it seeks to act as a responsible global player, should be using its relationship with and influence with Moscow.&nbsp; Whether that takes place publicly or privately is less relevant to us than that Xi Jinping communicate to Putin that what Russia is doing through this invasion and through this brutal war is having ripple effects through the world that is causing harm in the global south and elsewhere, and that the responsibility for that lies at the feet of the Russian government.&nbsp; And the fastest way to stop those negative ripple effects would be for Russia to stop the war.</p>



<p>So, yes, we believe that China cannot evade responsibility, given its relationship with Russia, for speaking more clearly to them.&nbsp; You know, from my perspective, that happening privately as opposed to publicly, it would be just fine if it produced a positive result.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, there was a video that came out yesterday from the G7 where President Macron is talking to both President Biden and yourself about Saudi Arabia &#8212; the fact that they&#8217;re almost at maximum capacity and can&#8217;t produce that much more oil.&nbsp; Does that change the President&#8217;s thinking at all going into his trip next month?&nbsp; And did any other leaders approach him about his trip to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to characterize President Macron’s comments yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with respect to the question of his discussions with other leaders, he spoke with President Macron about the trip.&nbsp; I &#8212; he spoke with a couple of other leaders about the trip as well, not focused on or confined to the energy piece, but the broader strategic dynamic at play and the need, particularly in light of Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine, for the United States, the G7, and the West to continue robust and effective engagement with our partners across the Middle East to include the GCC, as well as Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt, all of whom the President will see when he goes &#8212; when he goes to Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>And then, of course, he talked about Israel and the Israeli-Palestinian conflict as well with some of the leaders.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to characterize President Macron’s comments or, you know, either the content of them or the &#8212; this particular notion about Saudi Arabia and its spare capacity.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Caracas, there&#8217;s a report that, you know, we &#8212; or you&#8217;ve confirmed that senior administration officials went to Caracas.&nbsp; You mentioned freeing Americans there.&nbsp; What else can happen in terms of oil prices, particularly with an eye to the really bad financial inflation issues facing the United States?&nbsp; Are you asking for any kind of specific efforts or measures by Venezuela on the oil front?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; What we have said consistently is that we will only provide sanctions relief in return for concrete progress at the negotiating table.&nbsp; A few weeks ago, we gave a very specific license, and removed a few days ago a sanction, as part of an effort to get the talks in Mexico City back up and running effectively and with the support of the opposition.</p>



<p>A next step, in terms of further licenses, would have to be connected to progress &#8212; tangible progress at the negotiating table.&nbsp; We regard that as possible, but we want to see it actually happen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, there’s a report of a meeting in Sharm el-Sheikh a couple of weeks ago that the U.S. helped organize with leaders from Israel, Saudi Arabia, other regional partners in trying to counter the air threat or &#8212; from &#8212; missile threat from Iran.&nbsp; Can you confirm that?&nbsp; And is that a deliverable you&#8217;re eyeing for the next trip in a couple weeks?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;d refer you to CENTCOM on that particular report.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not looking for a specific missile defense deliverable on the trip, although deeper integration and deeper cooperation among all the countries of the region against the Iranian threat, including the Iranian missile threat, is a real priority of this administration, and we expect to continue to move the ball down the field on that, including during the President&#8217;s trip.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I go back to China again?&nbsp; The G7 also commented on China&#8217;s coercive non-market practices.&nbsp; The Biden administration &#8212; you know, this is not really anything new, but you guys have essentially been ready to go on your own investigation.&nbsp; What is the holdup here?&nbsp; And is the holdup at all related to your efforts in trying to get Xi Jinping to pressure Moscow on the war?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; The short answer and the unequivocal answer is “no.”&nbsp; There&#8217;s no connection between our conversations with China on the Ukraine war &#8212; Russia’s war in Ukraine and the issue of tariffs and a potential set of steps the United States would take on &#8212; vis-à-vis China trade.</p>



<p>You know, I&#8217;ve said to you guys before and the President has said this is something he&#8217;s looking at, he&#8217;s analyzing; there&#8217;s a lot of different elements to it.&nbsp; And the President wants to be sure that he&#8217;s put together the right approach before he moves out with it.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think he feels that there is a particular deadline for it.&nbsp; Getting it right is more important than just doing it fast, despite the fact that I know it is leaving all of you guys to have to ask the question week after week.</p>



<p>From our perspective, it’s something we&#8217;re looking at, the President continues to look at.&nbsp; When he has a decision to make, he&#8217;ll make the decision and we’ll move forward from there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more on Is- &#8212; on the Belarus.&nbsp; The Russians have said they&#8217;re going to supply the Iskander missiles to Belarus, which are nuclear capable.&nbsp; I’m wondering if that is a particular concern to you and whether that changes the dynamic to know that there are these nuclear &#8212; will be these nuclear-capable missiles in both Kaliningrad and Belarus.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The most important thing to us is what actually happens on the ground, not the theater between Putin and Lukashenko.&nbsp; And this was another one of those instances where they have this made-for-TV conversation that involve not just the Iskanders, but also whether there would be the provision of strategic bombers.&nbsp; And Putin said, “I will withhold those.”</p>



<p>So, will there be Iskander missiles for the long term?&nbsp; Putin says “yes,” but let&#8217;s see.&nbsp; Will there be strategic bombers in Belarus for the long term?&nbsp; Putin says “no,” but we&#8217;ll see.</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re going to watch and see what actually happens.&nbsp; And, of course, if Russian military deployments, including nuclear deployments in Belarus, occur and are sustained, that is a matter of concern for the entire NATO Alliance, it is a matter of concern for the United States, and it is something that we will take into account as we think about our own force posture.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one last one.&nbsp; Russia today released a bunch of new sanctions on U.S. officials, including the First Lady.&nbsp; I was wondering if you had any immediate reaction to that, just given that it seems to be a targeted effort to punish the President’s spouse.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I have no reaction to that other than it just goes to show you that the Russian capacity for these kinds of cynical moves is basically bottomless, so it probably shouldn&#8217;t come as a surprise to any of us that they would do something like this.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, are you going to stick around?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a topper, but whatever &#8212; what do you guys want to talk about?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us about what the White House&#8217;s reaction is to this incident in San Antonio with the migrants found in the truck and if this points to a larger problem on the border?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It’s devastating.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re closely monitoring the absolutely horrific and heartbreaking reports out of San Antonio, Texas.&nbsp; And I can tell you the President has been briefed and is going to continue to be regularly updated.</p>



<p>Our prayers are with those who tragically lost their lives, their loved ones, as well as those still fighting for their lives.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also grateful for the swift work of federal, state, and local first responders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Secretary Mayorkas said, “Far too many lives have been lost…[to] this dangerous journey.”&nbsp; We will continue to take action to disrupt human smuggling networks, which have no regard for lives.&nbsp; They explo- &#8212; exploit and endanger in order to make a profit.</p>



<p>As you know, the Department of Homeland Security is closely handling this and watching this as well.&nbsp; So, any specifics, I would refer you to them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Republican lawmakers blame the President and his policies for the &#8212; for that loss of life.&nbsp; I was wondering if you have any response to that.&nbsp; And does the President believe that the continued sort of &#8212; you know, his inability to lift border protections by those two federal court orders may have contributed to this tragedy?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, 46 people died &#8212; right? &#8212; in the state of Texas, and so &#8212; and others, as I just mentioned, are still fighting for their lives.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re still learning their names.&nbsp; Their families are still learning they lost loved ones, as when a tragic situation normally happens.&nbsp; We&#8217;re focused on them, on the facts, and holding the human <s>strugglers</s> [smugglers] who endangered vulnerable individual &#8212; individuals for profits accountable.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re &#8212; and we&#8217;re focused on continuing our historic actions to disrupt dangerous smuggling networks, including through a new anti-smuggling campaign that just in the first two months resulted in over 1,800 arrests.&nbsp; But the fact of the matter is the border is closed, which is in part why you see people trying to make this dangerous journey using smuggling networks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, our hearts go out to the families at this time.&nbsp; We are going to stay focused on the facts and making sure that we hold these smugglers accountable.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be our focus.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So on the Roe v. Wade situation, there&#8217;s &#8212; you know, have been calls for &#8212; I think we talked about this the other day about, you know, building some kind of facilities on federal lands.&nbsp; Are you any further along in terms of exploring those options?&nbsp; And would it be a possibility to come to some agreement with Tribes to use Tribal lands?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So with this proposal &#8212; we understand the proposal is well intentioned, but here&#8217;s the thing: It could actually put women and providers at risk.&nbsp; And importantly, in states where abortion is now illegal, women and providers who are not federal employees &#8212; as you look at the federal lands &#8212; could be &#8212; potentially be prosecuted.&nbsp; And so, this is &#8212; as we understand why they would put forward this proposal, there&#8217;s actually dangerous ramifications to doing this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you can’t offer sanct- &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that’s a no?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can’t offer sanctuary on federal property?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any more to share on that.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, this is &#8212; as we have mentioned, we&#8217;re looking at some &#8212; we’re looking at an array of other options.</p>



<p>We mentioned &#8212; the President on Friday, as you know, spoke to two first steps &#8212; concrete first steps that we believe will help women get the help that they need to make their decisions for themselves, the he- &#8212; for their healthcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just don&#8217;t have anything else to share &#8212; anything specific on that, but wanted to lay out what that proposal actually meant and so that you have the full breadth of the &#8212; of the meaning of what it would be to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the President is on this trip right now.&nbsp; Vice President Harris is doing interviews about the decision and about administrative action.&nbsp; You have Cabinet members making public statements.&nbsp; When is the public going to hear from the President again on this?&nbsp; Does he think that the Vice President is a better message on this &#8212; messenger on this than he is?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, it has nothing to do with the &#8212; with who&#8217;s the best messenger.&nbsp; He&#8217;s the President of the United States, right?&nbsp; When the President speaks, people listen and it &#8212; and it goes far and wide and it carries weight, obviously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As he spoke on Friday &#8212; the reason why he went out and spoke two hours after the decision was made is because he wanted to make sure he spoke directly to the American people, and he spoke in a very forceful way.&nbsp; He understands the devastation and how stunning this decision was, and he wanted to show that he was using his executive authority to act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you&#8217;re going to hear from the President, because this is &#8212; this is def- &#8212; to show how important this is, you&#8217;re going to hear from the President &#8212; not just from the President, but also the Vice President, his Cabinet secretaries.&nbsp; They have made an announcement in the last couple of days on how they&#8217;re moving forward with the two concrete steps that he&#8217;s taken.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re going to hear from the Vice President, which all makes sense in this moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like, this is a &#8212; you know, as I said, this is stunning, this is devastating, this is going to cause really terrible consequences for so many people &#8212; women across the country.</p>



<p>And the President on Friday was very clear.&nbsp; He said you &#8212; he said Congress has to act.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to do these two &#8212; first two initial steps; Congress needs to act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the way that we&#8217;re going to codify Roe is to make sure that it&#8217;s the law of the land, and there&#8217;s no executive action that&#8217;s going to make it law of the land.&nbsp; And if we can&#8217;t do that &#8212; if Congress won&#8217;t do that, then, you know, Americans have to make their voices very clear at the ballot box.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he going to get out on the road and make that case in &#8212; like, next week?&nbsp; Or when can people expect to hear him making that argument?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I just mentioned this is incredibly important to the President.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to talk about this, continue to look at what other options are available to make sure that women are able to have the healthcare that they need.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212; last one, I guess &#8212; on the January 6th Committee scheduling a surprise hearing today: Is the President going to be watching that?&nbsp; Or is he interested in seeing what the committee has to present on such &#8212; on such short notice?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, we&#8217;re headed to NATO.&nbsp; We’re hopefully going to land very shortly in Spain &#8212; Madrid, Spain &#8212; where the President is going to do, as we&#8217;ve talked about, leader-to-leader conversation on some important agenda, important issues for the &#8212; for the NATO members as we go into this for the next couple of days.</p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;ve been very, very clear.&nbsp; You know, January 6th, was a &#8212; was a dark, dark day in our democracy.&nbsp; It was not just an attack on our democracy, an attack on our law enforcement.&nbsp; And he believes, we believe that it is important for the American public to watch and to see and to learn exactly what happened on that day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we support the January 6th Select Committee.&nbsp; We have full confidence in them.&nbsp; And we just need to make sure that we get to the bottom of exactly the details of what happened on that day.</p>



<p>All right?&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>2:45 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Catalyzes more than $700 Million in Private Sector Commitments to Make EV Charging More Affordable and&#160;Accessible</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-catalyzes-more-than-700-million-in-private-sector-commitments-to-make-ev-charging-more-affordable-and-accessible/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Record-Breaking Private U.S. Investments to Help Build 250,000 Chargers Per Year, Create More Than 2,000 JobsToday, the Biden-Harris Administration is highlighting how President Biden’s leadership on electric vehicles is catalyzing more than $700 million in investments from the private sector that will increase our domestic capacity to manufacture more than 250,000 new electric vehicle (EV)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>Record-Breaking Private U.S. Investments to Help Build 250,000 Chargers Per Year, Create More Than 2,000 Jobs</em><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is highlighting how President Biden’s leadership on electric vehicles is catalyzing more than $700 million in investments from the private sector that will increase our domestic capacity to manufacture more than 250,000 new electric vehicle (EV) chargers each year, add at least 2,000 good-paying jobs, and make EV charging more affordable, accessible, and equitable. The historic private investments will follow the $7.5 billion from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to build a national network of EV chargers, enabling convenient and uniform charging at home, work, and across the country.<br><br>President Biden’s vison, leadership and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law have positioned the United States to lead the electric future and make it in America. The President <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">united</a> automakers and autoworkers around an ambitious target for 50% of new vehicles sold in 2030 to be electric, passed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-proposes-new-standards-for-national-electric-vehicle-charging-network/">build a national network of chargers</a> for a seamless charging experience, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-catalyzing-americas-clean-energy-economy-through-federal-sustainability/">activated</a> the federal government’s purchasing power to procure more zero-emission vehicles by 2027 and 100% zero-emission vehicles by 2035. The President’s actions will make EV charging convenient, reliable, and affordable for all Americans, including when driving long distances.<br><br>Today’s announcements demonstrate how the President is catalyzing private investment to boost our domestic manufacturing capacity, enabling America to create a national network of chargers and create thousands of new high-quality, union jobs building, installing, and maintaining it. Today, the auto industry renaissance continues as the private sector steps up to invest in American-made charging across the country.<br><br><strong><u>KEY INDUSTRY INVESTMENTS</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Electrify America</strong>, a leading network of fast chargers, today announced a new investment of $450 million into its charging network by Siemens, a global technology and electrification leader, and Volkswagen Group. These investments will support the rapid deployment of up to 10,000 ultra-fast chargers at 1,800 charging stations, more than the number of high-power chargers available in the United States today.<br></li><li><strong>Siemens </strong>is on track to build one million EV chargers over the next four years by investing more than $250 million in the U.S. in the past six months, including expansions of its Grand Prairie, TX and Pomona, CA manufacturing sites. Siemens has created 500 new, good-quality, union manufacturing jobs across the U.S to support critical power and EV charging infrastructure. And, they announced a $25 million minority stake investment in a US-based wireless charging company. Siemens has a new manufacturing facility coming online later this year and is introducing a new Buy America-compliant AC charger this fall.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>ADDITIONAL INDUSTRY ACTIONS</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>ABB E-mobility </strong>is adding 125 jobs across its operations this year alone, including at two new facilities. In Sugarland, Texas, they are opening a training center where ABB will provide authorized service partners with hands on training for servicing and maintaining EV chargers. In Southern California, ABB E-mobility is opening a product development and research facility where it will design, develop, and test EV chargers for the U.S. market.<br></li><li><strong>ChargePoint</strong>, a leading EV charging network, is expanding its partnership with SMTC Corporation to expand DCFC production, establish a manufacturing line for Level 2 chargers at their Milpitas, CA, facility, and create approximately 250 new manufacturing jobs. The expanded facility will be able to produce 10,000 DCFC dispensers and 10,000 Level 2 chargers by 2026.<br></li><li><strong>FLO, </strong>a North American EV charging network operator and smart charging solutions provider, announced a $3 million investment in its first U.S. assembly facility located in Auburn Hills, Michigan earlier this month. By 2028, the facility will produce upwards of 30,000 Buy America compliant charging stations and fast chargers annually, create upwards of 730 jobs, and bolster Michigan’s economy by $76 million.<br></li><li><strong>Tesla</strong> is making <em>investments at its Gigafactory in Buffalo, New York</em> to support the deployment of new fast charging stations to add to its fast-charging network. More than 1,600 employees work at Giga New York producing the Tesla Solar Roof and Supercharger stations, which are capable of charging vehicles up to 250 kW. Tesla is expanding production capacity of power electronics components that convert alternating current to direct current, charging cabinets, posts and cables. Later this year, Tesla will begin production of new Supercharger equipment that will enable non-Tesla EV drivers in North America to use Tesla Superchargers.<br></li><li><strong>Tritium</strong>, who previously <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-ensuring-future-is-made-in-america/">announced</a> a Tennessee EV charger manufacturing facility at a White House event with President Biden, is accelerating its production schedule to manufacture DC fast chargers in the third quarter of 2022. They also plan to build their first Buy America chargers in early 2023. This facility will create more than 500 local jobs and will be capable of producing up to 30,000 fast charger units per year.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>WORKFORCE DEVELOPMMENT AND EQUITY</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>IBEW</strong>, as part of the Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-launches-the-talent-pipeline-challenge-supporting-employer-investments-in-equitable-workforce-development-for-infrastructure-jobs/">Talent Pipeline Challenge,</a> pledged to train 10,000 of their members through the Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP) by this August. Philanthropies, including the Hewlett Foundation, committed a total of $250,000 to support women and workers of color training for the EVITP-certification – with an emphasis on geographic diversity.  <br></li><li><strong>ChargePoint </strong>recently partnered with the National Electrical Contractors Association (NECA) to prepare its nearly 4,000-member companies, all of which are IBEW unionized, to install EV charging infrastructure quickly and professionally in advance of the release of NEVI funding to States.<br></li><li><strong>Volta</strong>, a national owner operated ad-driven EV charging provider, expanded its &#8220;Charging for All&#8221; initiative, a multimillion-dollar commitment to ramp up equitable planning and charging investment. They will use PredictEV, a planning intelligence platform, to extend services to any state or city looking to maximize impact of public investment, while also delivering free media-space to State Departments of Transportation to ensure inclusive engagement.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
