<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:55:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces 11 Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/president-biden-announces-11-key-nominations-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 11 individuals to serve in key roles: Biniam Gebre, Nominee for Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, Office of Management and Budget Andrew Fois, Nominee for Chair of the Administrative Conference of the United States Susan Tsui Grundmann, Nominee for Member of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 11 individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Biniam Gebre, Nominee for Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Andrew Fois, Nominee for Chair of the Administrative Conference of the United States</li><li>Susan Tsui Grundmann, Nominee for Member of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</li><li>Kurt Rumsfeld, Nominee for General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</li><li>Javier Saade, Nominee for Chair of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</li><li>Dana Bilyeu, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</li><li>Leona Bridges, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</li><li>Stacey Olivares, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</li><li>Kathy Im, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</li><li>Tom Rothman, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</li><li>Elizabeth Sembler, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Biniam Gebre, Nominee for Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, Office of Management and Budget</u></strong></p>



<p>Biniam Gebre is a Senior Managing Director at Accenture and Head of Management Consulting for Accenture Federal Services. He has spent the past two decades helping dozens of organizations within both the public sector and private sector address management, operational, and technology issues ranging from agriculture to banking to artificial intelligence. He served in the Obama-Biden administration at the Department of Housing and Urban Development, where he focused on access to credit for low-income families, FHA’s financial health, and revitalizing public housing properties.</p>



<p>Gebre came to the United States as a refugee at the age of nine and grew up in public housing and on government assistance. He graduated with Highest Honors from Williams College, where he earned a B.A. in Chemistry and was a Goldwater Scholar. He also earned an M.B.A in Finance and Economics from Northwestern University. Gebre sits on the Board of Pathfinder International.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Andrew Fois, Nominee for Chair of the Administrative Conference of the United States</u></strong></p>



<p>Andrew Fois is an attorney with a 36-year legal career in public service, the non-profit sector, and private practice. He is an Attorney Advisor in the Office of Legislative Affairs in the Administrative Office of U.S. Courts. Prior to that position, he was the Deputy Attorney General for Public Safety in the Office of the Attorney General for Washington, D.C.&nbsp; In 2020, Mr. Fois was appointed by the Mayor to the D.C. Clemency Board.&nbsp; He has served at the Department of Justice on three occasions in five positions, including the Assistant Attorney General for Legislative Affairs and Assistant United States Attorney for the District of Columbia, where he prosecuted hundreds of cases.&nbsp; His experience on Capitol Hill includes service as the Chief Counsel of the House Judiciary Committee’s Subcommittee on Crime.&nbsp; He has worked for the National Crime Prevention Council as a solo practitioner and as a partner in the Venable law firm.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Fois also serves on the board of directors of the Catholic Coalition for Special Education.&nbsp; He has previously served on the boards of the Washington Regional Alcohol Program and the National Association of Children of Addiction. He served as Chairman of the D.C. Commission on Motor Vehicle Theft Prevention and the D.C. Coalition against Drugs and Violence.&nbsp; He has been a frequent author, legal adjunct professor and commentator on radio and television.&nbsp; He is active in his parish as a lector and Eucharistic Minister and was a founding member of the disabilities ministry and a member of the parish council.&nbsp; Mr. Fois earned his J.D. from the Georgetown University Law Center and his B.A. from Georgetown University.&nbsp; He also holds a master’s degree in American Government from the University of Essex in the U.K.&nbsp; He lives in Washington, D.C. with his wife and has two adult sons.</p>



<p><strong><u>Susan Tsui Grundmann, Nominee for Member of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</u></strong></p>



<p>Susan Tsui Grundmann currently serves as the Executive Director and Chief Operating Officer of the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights, where she oversees the administrative dispute resolution process and provides education to both employing offices and labor unions that represent employees in the legislative branch.&nbsp; Previously, she was nominated by President Obama to serve as a Member and Chairman of the MSPB.</p>



<p>Ms. Grundmann has served as General Counsel to the National Federation of Federal Employees (NFFE), which represents 100,000 Federal workers nationwide and is affiliated with the International Association of Machinist and Aerospace Workers. At NFFE, she successfully litigated cases in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia and the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia. She represented NFFE and the United Department of Defense Workers Coalition, which consists of 36 labor unions, and served on the Coalition’s litigation team in a coordinated response to proposed personnel changes at the Department of Defense (DoD). In addition to DoD employees, Ms. Grundmann represented employees in the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture, Passport Service, Veterans Administration, General Services Administration, and some 25 additional Federal agencies.</p>



<p>From 2003 to 2009, she was a regular instructor on Federal sector labor and employment law at the William W. Winpisinger Education and Technology Center in Hollywood, Maryland. Prior to joining NFFE, Ms. Grundmann served as General Counsel to the National Air Traffic Controllers Association. She began her legal career as a law clerk to the judges of the Nineteenth Judicial Circuit of Virginia, and later worked in both private practice and at the Sheet Metal Workers’ National Pension Fund. Chairman Grundmann earned her undergraduate degree at American University and her law degree at Georgetown University Law Center.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kurt Rumsfeld, Nominee for General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</u></strong></p>



<p>Kurt Rumsfeld is currently the Chief Counsel to Ernie DuBester, the Chairman of the Federal Labor Relations Authority.&nbsp; From September 2013 through February 2019, Mr. Rumsfeld served as the Assistant General Counsel for Operations and Legal Policy for the FLRA’s Office of General Counsel.&nbsp; His responsibilities in that role included assisting the General Counsel and Deputy General Counsel in managing the OGC’s regional operations and providing legal advice pertaining to the administration of the FLRA’s governing Statute.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before joining the FLRA, Mr. Rumsfeld practiced labor and employment law with a private law firm for over 17 years, and he began his career in labor law as an attorney-advisor with the U.S. Department of Labor.&nbsp;Mr. Rumsfeld received his B.A. in political science from Williams College, and his law degree from Northeastern University Law School.&nbsp; He also has an LL.M degree in Labor and Employment Law from Georgetown University Law Center.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Javier Saade, Nominee for Chair of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Javier E. Saade is a principled leader with three decades of broad experience as an investor, board member, founder, operating executive and economic policymaker. He served on the Biden Transition’s Agency Review Team for the Department of Treasury and served as Associate Administrator of Investment &amp; Innovation of the U.S. Small Business Administration during the Obama Administration. He led programs that, since their inception, have invested over $120 billion in hundreds of thousands of American small businesses that have created millions of jobs. Javier also served in the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commissions’ Advisory Committee on Small and Emerging Companies.</p>



<p>Javier is Managing Partner of Impact Master Holdings and Venture Partner at Fenway Summer. He has served on several corporate and non-profit boards. Prior to public service, he spent over twenty years in finance, management and advisory roles at organizations that include McKinsey &amp; Company, Booz Allen &amp; Hamilton, Bridgewater Associates and Abbott Laboratories. He holds an MBA from Harvard Business School, an MS in Operations &amp; Technology from Illinois Institute of Technology, and a BS in Industrial Management from Purdue University.</p>



<p>Javier grew up in Puerto Rico and resides with his family in Washington, DC.</p>



<p><strong><u>Dana Bilyeu, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Dana Bilyeu is the Executive Director of the National Association of State Retirement Administrators (NASRA) and has been in that role since 2013. Before joining NASRA, she served as the Executive Officer of the Public Employees&#8217; Retirement System of Nevada (2003 &#8211; 2013). As Executive Officer, she was responsible for all aspects of fund management, including analysis of plan funding, investment oversight, operational and strategic planning, and fiduciary and governance issues. Prior to her appointment as the Executive Officer, Ms. Bilyeu served eight years as the Operations Officer for the System, overseeing benefit administration, including survivor, disability, and retirement programs. Before joining Nevada PERS, Ms. Bilyeu was the System&#8217;s general counsel in the Office of the Nevada Attorney General, representing the System in benefits litigation, contracts analysis, board governance and fiduciary issues.</p>



<p>Ms. Bilyeu is in her second term on the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board (FRTIB). Ms. Bilyeu also served as a member of the Social Security Advisory Board from 2007 through 2010. The Advisory Board is an independent, bipartisan board created by Congress and appointed by the President and the Congress to advise the President, the Congress, and the Commissioner of Social Security on matters related to Social Security and Supplemental Security Income programs.</p>



<p>Ms. Bilyeu is a public employee board member of the International Foundation of Employee Benefit Plans and also serves as a board member for the National Institute on Retirement Security. She received her juris doctor from California Western School of Law and her bachelor’s degree from the University of Arizona.</p>



<p><strong><u>Leona Bridges, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Leona M. Bridges is a Commissioner for the San Francisco Employees’ Retirement System, where she serves as chair of the deferred compensation committee. She is a former Director for the Municipal Transportation Agency and Commissioner for the San Francisco Parking Authority of the City &amp; County of San Francisco, where she continues to serve on the Bond Oversight Committee. For more than two decades, Ms. Bridges was a Managing Director at Barclays Global Investors (acquired by BlackRock in 2009), becoming the world’s largest asset manager of combined assets. During her career in the financial services industry, she focused on asset management as it related to global securities lending/trading, collateral management, custody services, client service, and business development. Additionally, she was responsible for establishing and maintaining civic and community relationships.</p>



<p>Ms. Bridges holds an MBA from Golden Gate University Ageno School of Business and a Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration from San Francisco State University. She established an endowed scholarship in the College of Business to support economically and educationally disadvantaged students at San Francisco State University. Ms. Bridges serves on various community and non-profit boards. She is the recipient of many professional, community, and prestigious national awards.</p>



<p><strong><u>Stacey Olivares, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Stacie Olivares is on the board of directors of the Mission Advancement Corporation (NYSE: MACC) as its Audit Committee Chair, the Kroll Bond Rating Agency (KBRA), and CalPERS. At the nexus of capital markets, technology, and policy, Olivares works to expand markets, optimize returns, and democratize capital to advance environmental, social, and governance (ESG) and diversity, equity, and inclusion outcomes in our global economy. She is one of the few Latina Chief Investment Officers in the United States.</p>



<p>Olivares was the Chief Investment Officer of Lendistry, a fintech small business lender, from 2019 through 2020, and senior advisor on blockchain and impact investment to the world’s four-largest insurance market from 2018 to 2019. Earlier, Stacie led ESG investments as the Chief Investment Officer of COIN, a $29 billion ESG investment fund of the insurance industry, from 2011 through 2018, and as an ESG-focused portfolio manager at Morgan Stanley from 2008 through 2011. She entered capital markets with a global lens after leading the State of California’s economic advisory board from 2002 to 2007 and advancing global licensing and business development for Palm, Inc., from 2000 to 2002. Olivares serves on the advisory board of SUMA Wealth and on the board of directors of the University of California at Berkeley, College of Letters &amp; Science, the Hispanic Heritage Foundation, and the Latino Community Foundation. She holds a bachelor’s degree in economics from the University of California at Berkeley and a master’s degree in business and government from Harvard University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kathy Im, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</u></strong></p>



<p>Kathy Im is the Director of Journalism and Media at the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation. She manages a $25 million annual portfolio that is best known for supporting public media, nonprofit journalism, and documentary storytelling. During Im’s tenure, the program has deepened and expanded its investments in the creation, dissemination, and amplification of accurate, just, and inclusive news and narratives across three areas of media &#8212; professional nonprofit reporting, nonfiction multimedia storytelling, and participatory civic media &#8212; with the goal of informing, engaging, and activating Americans to build a more equitable future.</p>



<p>Im is a recognized leader in philanthropy and media. She is a member of the Board of Jurors for the Peabody Awards, a member of the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, and a former board member of Media Impact Funders, the Center for Asian American Media, and Asian Americans/Pacific Islanders in Philanthropy. She is the author of several editorials and essays about press freedom, diversity in media and journalism, and the connection between media and democracy. Kathy earned her Master’s in Public Policy from the Harris School of Public Policy Studies at the University of Chicago, where she is currently a member of the Harris Council, which advises the Dean. She earned her Bachelor’s in Government Studies from Smith College. Im lives in Chicago with her husband, Young B. Im, and their three children.</p>



<p><strong><u>Tom Rothman, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</u></strong></p>



<p>Tom Rothman, one of the global media sector’s most experienced executives, is Chairman and CEO of Sony Pictures Entertainment’s Motion Picture Group. Chairman since 2015, he oversees all of the studio’s worldwide businesses, including historic Columbia Pictures. Previously, Rothman served as Chairman and CEO of Fox Filmed Entertainment, having spent 17 years in various positions at 20th CenturyFox, including founding Fox Searchlight Pictures.&nbsp; Earlier in his career, Rothman was President of Worldwide Production for the Samuel Goldwyn Company and Executive Vice President for Columbia Pictures.&nbsp; Before joining Columbia, Rothman was a partner at the New York law firm Frankfurt, Kurnit, Klein and Selz, having clerked on the Second Circuit Court of Appeals.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since 2013, Rothman has served on the Board of Directors of Booking Holdings Inc., the world’s largest online travel agency. He is a member of the National Council on the Arts and has received The Corwin Award for Human Relations from the American Jewish Committee.&nbsp; He is a member of the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences and serves on multiple non-profit boards.&nbsp; Rothman received lifetime achievement recognitions from the Producers Guild of America and the IFP East, and Columbia University honored him with the Arthur B. Krim Award for outstanding leadership.&nbsp; He graduated magna cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa, from Brown University in 1976 and from Columbia Law School in 1980 as a two-time James Kent Scholar, the school’s highest academic honor.</p>



<p><strong><u>Elizabeth Sembler, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</u></strong></p>



<p>Elizabeth Sembler of Seminole, Florida is a retired Jewish educator and school administrator.&nbsp; She most recently served as the director of engagement at Congregation B’nai Israel in St. Petersburg, Florida. Ms. Sembler has previously served on the board of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, appointed by Presidents George W. Bush and Barack Obama. She served as chair of the board from 2014-16. She has served on the board of Tampa, Florida public television station WEDU-TV since 1993 and was the chair of its board from 2001-2003. From 2006-2008, she served on the board of the America’s Public Television Stations (APTS), a nonprofit group that supports the continued growth and development of a strong and financially sound noncommercial television service.</p>



<p>Ms. Sembler co-chairs the board of advisors of the Davidson Graduate School of Education at the Jewish Theological Seminary in New York, New York, and serves on the board of directors and is past board chair of the Academy Prep Center of St. Petersburg in Florida, a privately funded middle school for students qualifying for needs-based scholarships. She serves as vice chair of the board of directors of the Florida Orchestra, and recently joined the boards of Congregation B’nai Israel in St. Petersburg, the Institute for Strategic Policy Solutions at St. Petersburg College, and the Tampa Orlando Pinellas [TOP] Jewish Foundation in Tampa, FL.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Intent to Nominate Nine Foreign Policy and National Security&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/president-biden-announces-intent-to-nominate-nine-foreign-policy-and-national-security-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve in key roles promoting U.S. foreign policy and national security: Mark Brzezinski, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Poland Elizabeth Anne Noseworthy Fitzsimmons, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve in key roles promoting U.S. foreign policy and national security:</p>



<ul><li>Mark Brzezinski, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Poland</li><li>Elizabeth Anne Noseworthy Fitzsimmons, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Togolese Republic</li><li>Rebecca Eliza Gonzales, Nominee for Director of the Office of Foreign Missions, with the rank of Ambassador, Department of State</li><li>Brian Wesley Shukan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Benin</li><li>David John Young, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Malawi</li><li>Adriana Kugler, Nominee for U.S. Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</li><li>Oren Whyche-Shaw, Nominee for U.S. Director of the African Development Bank</li><li>Corey Hinderstein, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Department of Energy</li><li>David Honey, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary for Research and Engineering, Department of Defense</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Mark Brzezinski, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Poland</u></strong></p>



<p>Mark Brzezinski is founder and principal of Brzezinski Strategies LLC. Previously, he was Managing Director at Makena Capital Management, where he focused on responding to the growing demand for environmentally and socially responsible investment portfolios. Prior to Makena, Brzezinski served as the first Executive Director of the White House&#8217;s Arctic Executive Steering Committee and before that was the U.S. Ambassador to Sweden between 2011-2015.&nbsp; Earlier, Brzezinski was a partner at McGuireWoods LLP in Washington, D.C. From 1999 to 2001, he served on President Clinton&#8217;s National Security Council, first as a Director for Russia and Eurasia, and then as a Director for the Balkans.&nbsp; He was a Fulbright Scholar in Poland and is the author of “The Struggle for Constitutionalism in Poland.” He is a member of both the Council on Foreign Relations and the Trilateral Commission.</p>



<p>Brzezinski received a BA from Dartmouth College, a JD from the University of Virginia, and a PhD in Political Science from Oxford University. His foreign languages are Polish and French. He was awarded the Royal Order of the Polar Star by the King of Sweden and is a recipient of the Commander’s Cross of the Order of Merit of the Republic of Poland.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Elizabeth Anne Noseworthy Fitzsimmons, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Togolese Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Elizabeth Anne Noseworthy Fitzsimmons, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of African Affairs.&nbsp; From 2018-2021, she served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Central Africa and Public Diplomacy.&nbsp; Prior to that, she was Acting Deputy Spokesperson for the Department.&nbsp; Previous assignments include Deputy Executive Secretary to Secretaries Kerry and Tillerson, Senior Advisor at the Foreign Service Institute, Deputy Assistant Secretary for Public Diplomacy in the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs, and the Office of the Special Representative for Afghanistan and Pakistan.&nbsp; Fitzsimmons has served overseas in Taiwan, Hong Kong, Cambodia, India and Bulgaria.&nbsp; She has also worked in the State Department’s Operations Center and as Deputy Director of the State Department’s Executive Secretariat.&nbsp; She earned a B.A. from the University of Virginia.&nbsp; Fitzsimmons speaks Bulgarian, French and Chinese.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rebecca Eliza Gonzales, Nominee for Director of the Office of Foreign Missions, with the rank of Ambassador, Department of State</u></strong></p>



<p>Rebecca Gonzales, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the U.S. Ambassador to the Kingdom of Lesotho.&nbsp; Previously, she served as the Chief of Staff in the Bureau of Administration at the Department of State.&nbsp; She also served as the Deputy Executive Director of the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs; as Deputy Management Counselor at the U.S.&nbsp; Embassy in Pretoria, South Africa; Management Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Gaborone, Botswana; and Special Assistant in the Office of the Under Secretary for Management at the Department of State.&nbsp; Other assignments for Ambassador Gonzales include service in the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs and at U.S. embassies in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia; New Delhi, India; Bogota, Colombia; and Athens, Greece.&nbsp; Ambassador Gonzales earned a B.A. and an M.B.A. from The George Washington University and an M.S. from the Dwight D. Eisenhower School for National Security and Resource Strategy at Fort McNair, Washington, D.C.&nbsp; She speaks Spanish and Greek.</p>



<p><strong><u>Brian Wesley Shukan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Benin</u></strong></p>



<p>Brian W. Shukan, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Chargé d’Affaires a.i. and Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Khartoum, Sudan.&nbsp; He previously served as Director of the Office of the Special Envoy for Sudan and South Sudan at the Department of State.&nbsp; Shukan also served as Chargé d’Affaires a.i. and Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Port-au-Prince, Haiti, and as Principal Officer at the U.S. Consulate General in Casablanca, Morocco. His other overseas experience includes service at the U.S. embassies in Ghana, Iraq, Saudi Arabia, Luxembourg and Benin.&nbsp; Shukan is the recipient of numerous awards, including the James V. Forrestal Award for Excellence in Strategy and Force Planning at the U.S. Naval War College.&nbsp; He earned a Bachelors Degree from the University of Wisconsin-Madison, a J.D. from Washington University in St. Louis, Missouri, and an M.A. with distinction from the U.S. Naval War College.&nbsp; He speaks French and Arabic.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>David John Young, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Malawi</u></strong></p>



<p>David Young, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as Chargé d’Affaires, a.i. at the U.S. Embassy in Lusaka, Zambia.&nbsp; Previously he served as Chargé d’Affaires, a.i. at the U.S. Embassy in Pretoria, South Africa and Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Abuja, Nigeria. &nbsp;Prior to that, he was Deputy Director, Office of the Special Envoy for Sudan &amp; South Sudan, and he also served as Executive Assistant to the Under Secretary for Democracy and Global Affairs at the State Department.&nbsp; Among his other assignments, Young was a Pearson Fellow; a Public Affairs Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Guatemala; and Director, Office of International Religious Freedom in the Bureau of Democracy and Human Rights at the State Department. Young earned his B.A. degree in journalism from the University of Missouri; a Diploma from Trinity College, University of Dublin; and Master degrees in divinity and international relations from Boston University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Adriana Kugler, Nominee for </u></strong>U.S. Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development<strong><u> </u></strong>Dr. Adriana Kugler is a Full Professor at the McCourt School of Public Policy at Georgetown University. Dr. Kugler was Chief Economist at the U.S. Department of Labor under the Obama-Biden Administration between 2011 and 2013. Dr. Kugler served as Vice Provost for Faculty at Georgetown University between 2013 and 2016. Dr. Kugler was a member of the Board on Science, Technology and Economic Policy (STEP) of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine and served in the Technical Advisory Committee of the Bureau of Labor Statistics. Dr. Kugler was Chair and Chair-elect of the Business and Economics Statistics Section of the American Statistical Association in 2020 and 2019, respectively. She was an elected member of the Executive Committee of the European Association of Labor Economists and of the Executive Committee of the Latin American and Caribbean Economic Association.</p>



<p>Dr. Kugler completed her Ph.D. from the University of California at Berkeley and obtained a B.A. in Economics and Political Science from McGill University with first class honors. Dr. Kugler graduated high school in the public schools in Montgomery County, Maryland. She is married to Ignacio Donoso; they have two children − Daniel and Mireille.</p>



<p><strong><u>Oren Whyche-Shaw, Nominee for U.S. Director of the African Development Bank</u></strong></p>



<p>Until retirement in July 2020, Oren E. Whyche-Shaw was Deputy Assistant Administrator for the Africa Bureau and the Coordinator for President Obama’s Partnership in Growth and the Trade Africa Initiative at the U.S. Agency for International Development in Washington, DC. &nbsp;Prior to joining USAID in 2011, Ms. Whyche-Shaw served as the Director for the Office of African Nations and as Senior Advisor in the Multilateral Development Bank Office of the Department of Treasury.</p>



<p>Ms. Whyche-Shaw holds a Bachelor of Science degree in Theoretical Mathematics and French from Capital University in Columbus, OH. As the first Citibank Fellow, she received a master&#8217;s degree in Finance, Money and Financial Markets, and International Business from Columbia University’s Business School. Ms. Whyche-Shaw served as the Senior Special Advisor to the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission when selected as a White House Fellow in 1983. Ms. Whyche-Shaw has lived and worked internationally in more than 50 countries in over 30 years.</p>



<p><strong><u>Corey Hinderstein, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Department of Energy</u></strong></p>



<p>Corey Hinderstein is vice president of International Fuel Cycle Strategies at the Nuclear Threat Initiative based in Washington, DC, where she focuses on international nuclear fuel cycle and nonproliferation policy, global nuclear security, and arms control and nonproliferation monitoring and verification. From February 2015 through November 2017, Ms. Hinderstein was senior coordinator for nuclear security and nonproliferation policy affairs at the Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation office of the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA), U.S. Department of Energy (DOE). At NNSA, she led the DOE’s preparations for the 2016 Nuclear Security Summit and worked on other projects related to nuclear security and illicit trafficking, Iran’s nuclear program, and international monitoring and verification. Prior to her service at DOE, Ms. Hinderstein had been with NTI since 2006 and earlier was deputy director of the Institute for Science and International Security.</p>



<p>Ms. Hinderstein is a past president and Fellow of the Institute of Nuclear Materials Management (INMM) and serves on the board of directors for the World Institute for Nuclear Security. She also has served in advisory capacities for multiple national laboratories and has published widely on nuclear nonproliferation, verification and monitoring and nuclear security. Ms. Hinderstein graduated from Clark University in Worcester, MA where she was elected to Phi Beta Kappa.</p>



<p><strong><u>David Honey, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary for Research and Engineering, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. David Honey is a Special Assistant to the Director of the Defense Advanced Projects Agency (DARPA), where he helps guide collaborations with other agencies. In an earlier DARPA tour, he served as a Program Manager, Deputy Office Director, and Office Director. Dr. Honey previously served as the Director of Science and Technology in the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research in the Department of Defense, and as senior vice president of a small business.</p>



<p>Dr. Honey is a retired U.S. Air Force officer who began his military career as a pilot and later transitioned into research and development. He holds a Doctorate from Syracuse University, Master of Science degrees from the University of Arizona and the Air Force Institute of Technology and a Bachelor of Science from the Rochester Institute of Technology.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Jamie L. Harpootlian, of South Carolina, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Slovenia. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Chavonda J. Jacobs-Young, of Georgia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Research, Education, and Economics, vice Catherine E. Woteki. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; John F. Plumb, of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jamie L. Harpootlian, of South Carolina, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Slovenia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Chavonda J. Jacobs-Young, of Georgia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Research, Education, and Economics, vice Catherine E. Woteki.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; John F. Plumb, of New York, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>     Jennifer Clyburn Reed, of South Carolina, to be Federal Cochairperson of the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission.  (New Position)</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, August 4,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/04/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-august-4-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:52 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; Happy Wednesday.&#160; I have a couple of notes for you at the top.&#160;Today, Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marcia Fudge released a statement committing to do everything in HUD’s power to stop evictions for families with HUD assistance or families who rent in housing that is insured&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:52 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Happy Wednesday.&nbsp; I have a couple of notes for you at the top.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marcia Fudge released a statement committing to do everything in HUD’s power to stop evictions for families with HUD assistance or families who rent in housing that is insured by the Federal Housing Administration.&nbsp; This is part of delivering on what the President announced &#8212; or we announced in our statement just a couple of days ago.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And while the Emergency Rental Assistance funds are in the hands of state and local governments, one of the critical roles that the administration can continue to play is to act as a leading hub to convene states and cities and to share best practices, as we have done at two major eviction prevention summits.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this morning, Treasury published examples of simplified forms that are being used effectively by Emergency Rental Assistance programs around the country.&nbsp; I think Ebony may have asked a version of this yesterday &#8212; a question about this.&nbsp; But Treasury has repeatedly discouraged undue documentation burdens that limit access for eligible families and is sharing these example forms to make it easier for state and local governments to put that into practice.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Places that have are seeing results.&nbsp; I mentioned Virginia yesterday, but, as an example, Virginia is the second-highest nationwide distributor of ERA funds in the nation and has given out $223 million to tenants and landlords in need.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Virginia followed Treasury&#8217;s guidance to eliminate documentation burdens that slow down application processing for eligible families.&nbsp; And the state was able to significantly cut down application processing times by streamlining what is often the most time-consuming part of the eligibility verification and a barrier for people applying.<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is a process that we&#8217;re trying to share best practices, and the Treasury Department is trying to simplify these forms to make it easier for families.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I mentioned yesterday, we&#8217;re going to continue to highlight what the bipartisan infrastructure deal will mean for families across the country, as we will digitally as well.&nbsp; Right now, there are up to 10 million homes with lead service lines and pipes.&nbsp; Children in up to 400,000 schools and childcare facilities are at risk of exposure to lead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For kids, high exposure to lead can negatively affect academic performance and can lead to cardiovascular disease later in life.&nbsp; And the President clearly thinks that&#8217;s unacceptable, as do a number of members of Congress.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the deal makes the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history, replacing all the nation&#8217;s lead pipes and service lines, from rural towns to struggling cities.&nbsp; The deal invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I wanted to also take a moment to recognize the passing of Pentagon Force Protection Officer George Gonzalez, who was tragically killed yesterday in the line of duty.&nbsp; His life was one of service, a veteran of both the police and the military.&nbsp; He served the Federal Bureau of Prisons, the Transportation Security Administration, and the United States Army where he was awarded the Army Commendation Medal for his service in Iraq.&nbsp; He lost his life protecting those who protect the nation.&nbsp; We mourn his loss and offer condolences to his family.<br>&nbsp;<br>Two more short notes &#8212; hopefully helpful.&nbsp; This morning at the White House, as part of our ongoing efforts to every &#8212; to do everything we can and engage everyone we can to encourage vaccinations, Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy and members of the White House COVID-19 Response Team convened a historic gathering of all living, former U.S. Surgeon Generals, including Dr. Antonia Novello, Dr. Joycelyn Elders, Dr. David Satcher, Dr. Richard Carmona, Dr. Regina Benjamin, and Dr. Jerome Adams.<br>&nbsp;<br>These esteemed public health leaders who served under both Republican and Democratic Presidents discussed the importance of ensuring that communities of color, those hardest hit by the virus have the information and access they need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; And they discussed how we can work together, of course, moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last point for all of you: The President spoke &#8212; or called, I should say &#8212; Shontel Brown last night and extended his congratulations to her.&nbsp; He is focused on delivering for the people of Ohio and across the country, as is she.&nbsp; We know his agenda, including investi- &#8212; investing in our country&#8217;s infrastructure; helping grow our economy, creating good-paying, middle-class jobs is broadly popular with the American people.&nbsp;&nbsp; He&#8217;s laser focused on delivering.&nbsp; More Democrats means more ability to deliver on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know you were up way too early this morning, based on my television.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been waiting to do that joke all week.<br>&nbsp;<br>Here we are.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I appreciate the pun, Jen.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>A few questions all on the same topic &#8212; short ones, perhaps.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, the President said Governor Cuomo should resign.&nbsp; The governor has not done so.&nbsp; Has the President called the governor?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has anyone from the White House called the governor or the governor’s staff?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not that I&#8217;m aware of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When was the last time the President and Governor Cuomo spoke?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to check on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s two more on this.&nbsp; If the governor refuses to resign, does the President want to see him impeached and removed from office?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President made clear yesterday that Governor Cuomo should resign, and believes &#8212; and I believe we should start with that.&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously a process that&#8217;s going to proceed, and leaders in New York spoke to that yesterday.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll leave it to them to speak to that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the President believes Governor Cuomo should do the right thing: resign and leave space for future leadership in New York.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then there&#8217;s been a lot of discussion in here, including from the President, in recent days, about the vital role that governors play in the nation’s COVID response.&nbsp; In this period, while Governor Cuomo is still in office, does the President have confidence in him leading New York State&#8217;s response to the pandemic?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, again, the President made clear, because of the abhorrent allegations that were made public yesterday, that it is time for Governor Cuomo to resign.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, we do not want the people of New York to be impacted in a negative way, as they&#8217;re working to fight COVID.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to work with the administration in New York, with leaders in New York, to continue to fight COVID.&nbsp; That will continue.&nbsp; And obviously, if leadership changes in the state, we will work with a different leader.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Can you walk us through what changed from Monday to Tuesday, when it comes to the eviction ban?&nbsp; On Monday, Gene Sperling stood here and said the CDC has been unable to find the legal authority for even new targeted eviction moratoriums.&nbsp; There are many people across the administration who said the same thing.&nbsp; And yet, the CDC did just that yesterday.&nbsp; So what changed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to take a step back a little bit before that, to Sunday, when we were engaged &#8212; the administration, the White House was engaged directly with the CDC, at the direction of the President, to ask them to look into what legal options, if any &#8212; if any existed &#8212; there were to extend the eviction moratorium.<br>&nbsp;<br>That process was underway for a couple of days.&nbsp; The announcement yesterday was a reflection of exactly that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And when we put out a statement on Monday, right before Gene Sperling came out to the briefing, right before we came out to talk with all of you, that also made clear in there that at that time they had not yet found a legal pathway forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What was announced yesterday was not an extension of the existing moratorium, which was, of course, national; it was a more limited moratorium that was going to be impacting and helping areas that were hardest hit by COVID.&nbsp; So, different than the last moratorium.&nbsp; That was also reflected in the statement that we issued on Monday, that that was the President&#8217;s ask &#8212; to look into a more limited moratorium.<br>&nbsp;<br>They did that.&nbsp; They &#8212; and yesterday&#8217;s announcement was a reflection of that process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, what&#8217;s your message to progressives who say they&#8217;re worried that President Biden&#8217;s concerns about the constitutionality of this move will end up being a self-fulfilling prophecy and motivate opponents to go ahead and file suit now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I would first say the President shares their desire, their commitment, and their interest in keeping renters and people in their homes, and that is exactly why he took the step of asking the CDC to look into what legal pathways forward there were.&nbsp; And yesterday&#8217;s announcement was a reflection of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t control the courts; we don&#8217;t know what they will do.&nbsp; We are all aware of the Supreme Court decision at the end of June and what was outlined in their decision at the end of June.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is also going to be a temporary &#8212; temporary solution regardless, and a longer-term solution will require legislative action.&nbsp; But his message to anyone who’s been a passionate advocate is that he shares their concern, he shares their commitment.&nbsp; He wants renters to be able to stay in their home, and that&#8217;s why we took this step over the last few days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on one other topic, if you don’t mind.&nbsp; I know that the President has asked the Defense Secretary to look into the possibility of making the COVID vaccine mandatory for servicemembers, but according to the U.S. Code, it’s actually the President who has to grant a waiver to the military to make vaccines mandatory.&nbsp; Has he granted that waiver yet?&nbsp; And if not, does he plan to do so?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President is looking for a recommendation from the Secretary of Defense.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t been made yet.&nbsp; And when &#8212; if and when that is made, I would expect he would respond accordingly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The earlier moratorium used the same legal justification that the new one is using, which, in layman&#8217;s terms, is about preventing the spread of disease if you evict people at a time of pandemic.&nbsp; So the only real difference is narrowing location, but the rationale is the same.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, after the President was clear that it wasn&#8217;t legal, Gene Sperling was clear that it wasn&#8217;t legal, is this a “roll the dice and see if it gets challenged” position from an administration that may be doing something it knows is not on legal standing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President would not have supported moving forward with any action where he wasn&#8217;t &#8212; didn&#8217;t feel there was legal standing and legal support.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We obviously don&#8217;t control what the courts do.&nbsp; And we have, of course, seen what the Supreme Court decided and how they ruled, which was not related to public health &#8212; as you well know, Kelly &#8212; and was related to the relationship between the landlord and the renter.<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is different in that it is more targeted, it is focused on counties with higher substantial case rates to protect renters, and the CDC ultimately decided to adopt it.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that the conditions have changed.&nbsp; The rise of the Delta variant, especially in communities where there are large numbers of unvaccinated individuals, where there are growing case numbers, is certainly something that has raised the alarm for us, it has raised the alarm for members of Congress, and it has certainly added to the need to take this additional step.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We were in the event with Dr. Murthy earlier, and he talked about the likelihood that boosters would eventually be required.&nbsp; For Americans who are sort of taking it on their &#8212; themselves and trying to seek out a third shot, what is the administration&#8217;s view of those who are trying to, you know, &#8220;self-boost,&#8221; for lack of a better term?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ve never heard that term before, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I am &#8212; it&#8217;s interesting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, I would say that what we&#8217;ve been conveying to officials around the country who have implemented this in some places is that this is not in alignment with the guidance of the public health &#8212; of public health officials, whether that is the CDC or the FDA.&nbsp; And we are certainly in touch with local officials on that matter and conveying exactly that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also, at the same time, are prepared if the FDA decides that they are going to recommend a booster.&nbsp; That is why we ordered the number of doses we did order several months ago, because we are like Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts and always want to be prepared.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re prepared for that, but it is not what the FDA and the CDC are recommending, and we are conveying that directly to officials.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a major push here recently to protect tenants from being evicted right now.&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t more being done to help the landlords who are struggling to pay their bills because they&#8217;re not being paid?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, actually, the landlords can benefit from exactly the same emergency rental assistance that renters can benefit from.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, right now, as we understand it, many states are not distributing that money.&nbsp; The Washington Post says that this measure could drive thousands of minor landlords to bankruptcy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s exactly why &#8212; and I&#8217;m happy to have you as a partner in this effort &#8212; we are trying to advocate for states, localities to get this money out.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no reason it&#8217;s not going out to landlords, to renters; no reason that people who are eligible are not benefiting.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve seen a number of states &#8212; red states and blue states &#8212; do this very effectively.&nbsp; Texas is an example I used yesterday.&nbsp; Virginia is one I highlighted today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is why we&#8217;re doing as much of this outreach and engagement as we&#8217;re doing, and simplifying forms, making it easier for people to understand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on immigration, it&#8217;s been almost four months since the President told migrants, &#8220;Don&#8217;t come.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t leave your town.&#8221;&nbsp; Almost two months since the Vice President went to Central America to say, &#8220;Do not come.&#8221;&nbsp; But people are coming in record numbers.&nbsp; Does the President think his immigration plan is working?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President continues to convey to anyone, as you&#8217;ve said, who wants to come to the United States: Now is not the time to come.&nbsp; It is not the time to come and try to go through irregular migration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We want to have an effective process where you can apply for asylum, where you can apply for legal status.&nbsp; We have increased our investment in areas like the Central American Minors Program, allowing people to apply from within country so they are not making that dangerous trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s more that needs to be done.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also instituted a number of additional steps recently, including expedited removals, to move people out of the country more quickly.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s a &#8212; we&#8217;re still at work on improving a process and improving a system that was very broken when we took office.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the message to migrants is the same, even though they are coming &#8212; a 21-year high, 210,000 encounters at the border last month?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And I would also note the number of people who were &#8212; who were removed from the border, which is an important part of the context, which is almost half of that number.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he&#8217;s saying, &#8220;Don&#8217;t come.&#8221;&nbsp; And they&#8217;re coming.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there are a number of factors, as you well know, that are happening in these countries.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working to address those as well, and the Vice President is leading those efforts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t expect that to be a switch, but addressing root causes in these countries &#8212; corruption, economic downturn, people are fleeing a range of challenges, persecution &#8212; those are issues we need to address at the same time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Sort of a housekeeping question.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given the status of COVID and the Delta variant, what is the status on the permanent pick for an FDA commissioner?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update for you.&nbsp; Obviously, the President would love to have a permanent pick in place and wants to nominate the right person, but I don&#8217;t have an update on the timeline for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what&#8217;s taking so long?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s not going to get &#8212; he&#8217;s not going to expedite it if he does not &#8212; has not identified the right person to nominate quite yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Governor Cuomo issue: If this is potentially such a stain on the party, the President &#8212; as the leader of this party &#8212; why not pick up the phone and ask him to resign at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President was pretty clear publicly; he asked him to resign yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No plans to call him, though?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; no plans to call him to preview, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jeff.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, sort of picking up on Kelly’s question: The WHO today called on countries basically to put a halt on booster shots of the COVID vaccine.&nbsp; I know that&#8217;s not the policy yet of the United States, but it does appear as though we&#8217;re moving in that direction &#8212; at least for people who are immunocompromised.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House reaction to his call to put that off until at least the end of September so that poorer countries can get more vaccine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Jeff, we feel that it&#8217;s a false choice and that we can do both.&nbsp; We announced just yesterday that we hit an important milestone of over 110 million vaccines donated to the world.&nbsp; That is more than any other country has shared, combined.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also made clear that that is the beginning, and we also started to donate the 500 million doses of Pfizer we&#8217;ve purchased.&nbsp; We will start to donate those later this month.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ve taken action on the global level far more than any country around the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re asking the global community to also step up.&nbsp; We saw some action at the G7; more needs to happen.&nbsp; But we believe we can do both.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also, in this country, have enough supply to ensure that every American has access to a vaccine.&nbsp; We will have enough supply to ensure.&nbsp; If the FDA decides that boosters are recommended for a portion of the population, to provide those as well.&nbsp; We believe we can do both, and we don&#8217;t need to make that choice.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; On a separate topic, is the White House tracking the case of the Belarus Olympian who was forced to go to the airport and then ended up going to Austria instead of back to her own country?&nbsp; And is the U.S. providing any assistance to her or anyone else from the Belarusian team?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are aware of the case.&nbsp; I would have to check if there&#8217;s direct assistance.&nbsp; The State Department may be the best source for that, but I will check with them and see if there&#8217;s anything to provide to all of you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who inside the administration signed off on the legality of what the CDC proposed yesterday?&nbsp; Is that the CDC&#8217;s lawyers, the Justice Department?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The CDC’s lawyers, as well as our Counsel&#8217;s Office &#8212; yes.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of the Department of Justice&#8217;s engagement, but of course, that might make sense.&nbsp; I would have to check on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, you know, the President alluded yesterday to &#8212; &#8220;Look, if this gets struck down in court, if nothing else, it buys time for the federal funds from the state level to be kicked out and disbursed.&#8221;&nbsp; How much of that was a driving force behind the decision to move forward with this?&nbsp; Like, “We need to figure out some way to buy time as states figure this out.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s just go ahead with this.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President would not have supported moving forward if he did not support the legal justification.&nbsp; He is old school in that way.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would tell you that regardless of what is decided by any court &#8212; if anything is decided by any court &#8212; this is not a permanent solution.&nbsp; It is extended through the beginning of October.&nbsp; And I think you&#8217;ve seen that recognition by a range of members of Congress and leaders and advocates who have been so passionately talking about the need to extend the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; It would require legislative action.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The other piece of this that I know we keep talking about but is really a solution here, and that&#8217;s why we keep talking about it, is getting this money out to states and localities.&nbsp; This is really about money &#8212; right?&nbsp;&#8212; and funding.&nbsp; And all these states and localities have money to extend the moratorium in their states by a month or two months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There have been challenges that are understandable, including the fact that there&#8217;s no federal infrastructure for distributing this money.&nbsp; The states are doing it on their own.&nbsp; There are challenges where even well-meaning landlords and others are trying to figure out how to accept applications.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re working through those challenges, but that is a solution for the short term, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve talked about it and why we&#8217;ve spent so much time investing in that as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more quick one.&nbsp; The President was very sharp on just, kind of, his perspective on Republican governors put &#8212; or blocked, I guess, specific potential public health options, and echoed something you said yesterday in a very sharp tone: Either you&#8217;re with it or move out the way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Is that an intentional shift?&nbsp; What&#8217;s driving kind of a very sharp tone in regards to these specific actions by Republican governors?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me be also clear that, as the President said yesterday, the vast majority of leaders &#8212; and as I&#8217;ve said too &#8212; continue to step up and do the right thing.&nbsp; People like Governor Hutchinson have been traveling their state, hearing from their communities, and answering questions about the vaccine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re also in constant communication with our nation&#8217;s governor.&nbsp; So even as we called out steps that &#8212; and he called out steps that we felt should’ve been taken by the governors of Florida and Texas &#8212; we&#8217;re in touch with those offices about providing additional assistance and seeing if we can figure out what their needs are and how we can help meet them.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we had our first FEMA team on the ground in West Virginia just days after entering government.&nbsp; Right now, our Surge Response Teams are working hand in hand with the hardest-hit states that are not traditionally blue and Democratic states &#8212; Arkansas, Missouri, Louisiana &#8212; focusing on everything from contact tracing, technical expertise, and vaccine confidence.<br>&nbsp;<br>But at the same time, that wasn&#8217;t an evaluation &#8212; a partisan evaluation or assessment; that was an assessment of what isn&#8217;t happening that would help protect people&#8217;s lives and save people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; And there are leaders who are not stepping up and are getting in the way of the American people &#8212; companies and others &#8212; who are trying to save lives and stop the spread of Delta.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are going to keep calling that out.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not meant to be partisan.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not meant to be political.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just meant to convey that more action is needed in some parts of the country, even where there are many states where positive action is being taken.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, you mentioned that the new moratorium is a targeted one and not one that&#8217;s nationwide as justification of why this is &#8212; meets the legal threshold.&nbsp; But Gene Sperling, earlier, actually pointed out &#8212; he said, “To date, the CDC Director and her team have been unable to find legal authority, even for a more targeted eviction moratorium that would [just] focus…on counties with higher rates of COVID spread.”&nbsp; So I&#8217;m trying to just pinpoint what exactly is different than what they were looking at then that makes this now a &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That was also in our statement.&nbsp; We said, “to date,” and we looked at all the &#8212; and we were continuing to look at all of the legal authorities and options, as were the lawyers at the CDC and our lawyers, to see what we felt was legally viable.&nbsp; That process was a couple-day process.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t concluded on Monday when Gene Sperling came to the briefing room.&nbsp; Yesterday it concluded, and of course, they made the announcement as a result.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more question. &nbsp;What is the White House doing to push forward the nomination of David Chipman at the ATF?&nbsp; The vote could hinge on the vote of Senator Angus King, in Maine, who has been pushed by the local Maine sportsman groups and national gun rights advocates.&nbsp; Has the White House reached out specifically to Senator King on this issue?&nbsp; And is the White House fully committed to Chipman, or might it go with a different nominee at some point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to read out private conversations with members of Congress, but I will tell you that we knew this wouldn&#8217;t be easy.&nbsp; ATF hasn&#8217;t had a confirmed director in six years and only one confirmed director since the position became Senate-confirmable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;ve been eyes wide open into the challenge from the beginning.&nbsp; But we are disappointed by the fact that many Republicans are moving in lockstep to try to hold up his nomination and handcuff the chief federal law enforcement agency tasked with fighting gun crimes.&nbsp; It speaks volumes to their complete refusal to tackle the spike in crime we&#8217;ve seen over the last 18 months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is someone who has 25 years in distinguished service to our country as an ATF agent.&nbsp; He has the exact set of skills and experience we need to revitalize the bureau&#8217;s work to crack down on gun trafficking, keep guns out of the hands of criminals.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So certainly, yes, we stand by his strong qualifications and nomination.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m just going to jump around and then I’ll come back.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; In the middle.&nbsp; In the middle.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Question on &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, oh, sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead, right there.&nbsp; In the middle, right there.&nbsp; In the middle.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I’m trying to get to people I haven&#8217;t gotten to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I appreciate it.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; And then right in front of you.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; You&#8217;re good.&nbsp; You&#8217;re good.&nbsp; It&#8217;s fine.&nbsp; We can do everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infrastructure, when you talk to local officials about this, they&#8217;re really excited about the possibilities of what might happen, but they can&#8217;t say with any certainty what they&#8217;re actually going receive and what they&#8217;re actually going to be able to do.&nbsp; So as this bill advances, you know, what would you say to folks who are wondering how much of these big pots of money are actually coming to our community?&nbsp; And how quickly, assuming it passes, might they find out and see those benefits?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, one, we have put out state-by-state factsheets.&nbsp; And if different businesses or communities haven&#8217;t seen those, we&#8217;re happy to provide them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is true that, as is true with any piece of legislation, there are components of these &#8212; the project funding that would be through grants and some through applications that &#8212; where communities will have to apply for funding.&nbsp; Obviously, it would be in our interest to get that going as quickly as possible, and the Department of Transportation and others will implement that.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have been pretty clear about benefits that will help every community: replacing lead pipes, making sure people have access to broadband, making a historic investment in climate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know people are asking &#8212; and I think you&#8217;re asking specifically about people who are &#8212; who want to know if their specific bridge is going to be repaired.&nbsp; Some of that will be through grant funding; some of it will be through, you know, funding that will be designated in the piece of &#8212; in the bill. But, you know, it will, of course, take a little bit of time to implement, but we&#8217;ll be eager to get that done as quickly as the bill is signed into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, two questions &#8212; one about gun violence.&nbsp; And you just alluded to efforts to combat gun violence.&nbsp; The White House has recently touted these strike forces that are going into a few cities, talking about that.&nbsp; Are there any plans to expand that?&nbsp; Kansas City, for example, has had 91 homicides this year, most of them gun related.&nbsp; And how do these DOJ efforts differ from the ones that were going on in the Trump administration when there was a lot of ballyhooed effort about going into cities to fight crime?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not as familiar nor can I speak to the Trump administration efforts.&nbsp; What I can tell you is that the Department of Justice identified these five or six cities where officials from our team, who are experts, could work in lockstep to help crack down on gun trafficking and preventing guns from getting into the hands of people who shouldn&#8217;t have them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we will see.&nbsp; It&#8217;s early stages of the process.&nbsp; We will see what the success looks like.&nbsp; We&#8217;re quite hopeful.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of whether they have intention or plans to expand, I would point you to the Department of Justice and see what they have to say about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my question on evictions is: What role did Congresswoman Bush&#8217;s protests play?&nbsp; A number of Democratic leaders were giving her a lot of credit for raising the issue.&nbsp; I know the Vice President spoke to her Monday.&nbsp; What role did that play in the ultimate decision of the White House to move forward with the new order?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think anyone could hear Congresswoman Bush&#8217;s own personal story and experience and see her advocacy and her passion, and not be moved by that.&nbsp; I know a number of members of Congress were moved by that as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I will tell you is that the President had a number of calls with Speaker Pelosi over the weekend.&nbsp; Her advocacy, her commitment to looking to see &#8212; kicking every tire, just to go back to the analogy of yesterday &#8212; to see what was possible is something that was certainly impactful and influential with the President.&nbsp; But I would just reiterate that the President called for the extension of the moratorium&nbsp;&nbsp;back in January. &nbsp;CDC extended it three times. &nbsp;We also have spoken to this over the course of the past several months, and we&#8217;ve been in close touch with a range of members of Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, absolutely, the passion, the advocacy of a number of members is something that I think everybody watched closely, but I think it&#8217;s important to note that we all share the same objective and have from the beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a while, so I&#8217;m hoping to ask you two questions if that’s all right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First about the coronavirus pandemic, and then about &#8212; a follow-up to Governor Cuomo, the report on him.<br>&nbsp;<br>On COVID-19, former President Trump has called for China to pay the United States more than $10 trillion in reparations as a result of letting the coronavirus escape Wuhan and infect other countries causing, of course, 600,000 American deaths and economic devastation.&nbsp; President Biden hasn&#8217;t called for reparations from China.&nbsp; Does he support them?&nbsp; Does he think that China should pay us financially for what it has allowed to spread?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our policy hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, is he open to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Did you have another question?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; In a follow-up to the report on Governor Cuomo’s sexual harassment, a lot of men in politics have been accused of sexual harassment.&nbsp; President Biden was accused by female Secret Service agents of skinny dipping in front of them, offending them, according to former Washington Post reporter Ronald Kessler, who&#8217;s an author as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>His former Senate aide, Tara Reade, accused him of sexual assault.&nbsp; The Washington Post and The New York Times published multiple accounts of women who objected to the way President Biden touched them.&nbsp; Should there be an independent investigation of allegations into the President as there was into Governor Cuomo?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, the President has been clear and outspoken about the importance of women being respected and having their voices heard and being allowed to tell their stories and people treating them with respect.&nbsp; That has long been his policy, continues to be his policy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That &#8212; those were &#8212; that was heavily litigated during the campaign.&nbsp; I understand you&#8217;re eager to come back to it, but I don&#8217;t have anything further other than to repeat that he has called for the governor to resign.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If and when the Senate passes the bipartisan infrastructure deal, would President Biden like to see the House come immediately back into session, or is he okay waiting until the recess ends at the beginning of next month?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He certainly is going to be guided and be talking regularly with Speaker Pelosi about what she recommends and what she thinks is the best path forward looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you guys have said you guys are not going to return to lockdowns.&nbsp; Now, is that based just on current COVID conditions or &#8212; Dr. Fauci, today, in an interview warned that he is worried about a potentially worse variant that could more effect vaccinated people.&nbsp; So, is the guidance on lockdowns just based on current conditions or is that just a &#8212; and could change &#8212; or is it forever more are there not going to be lockdowns?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think Dr. Fauci and Dr. Collins have both spoken to this in recent days.&nbsp; And what they have conveyed and what it&#8217;s based on is the fact that we have made a significant amount of progress in the past six months &#8212; even as we are fighting the Delta variant, the most transmissible variant we have seen &#8212; and that includes 70 percent of the American people getting their first shot &#8212; 160 &#8212; more than 162 million Americans at this point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s progress.&nbsp; That ensures that a lot of communities are going to have a great deal of protection, and we&#8217;re in a different place than we were when there was the period of lockdown, so it&#8217;s a reflection of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Katie.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; The President, sort of, dismissed a question yesterday about whether he would call Governor DeSantis to discuss the situation on the ground in Florida.&nbsp; Does he feel that there is no point in personally reaching out to leaders in Texas and Florida?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, just to give you an understanding of how this works: Our team, led by COVID Coordinator Jeff Zients, is in touch with all of the governors and is &#8212; we are working closely with the Florida &#8212; Florida public health officials and the governor&#8217;s team to see if we can send a team down there to help address their needs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that is ongoing.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean we aren&#8217;t going to call out when we think there&#8217;s more steps that can be taken, but that&#8217;s an ongoing process, and we&#8217;re hopeful about making progress there moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And the President had a meeting earlier today about preventing future pandemics.&nbsp; Can you give us a readout on what he heard or discussed?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the administration learning about &#8212; about that issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the President&#8217;s view is that, even as we&#8217;re fighting the pandemic and we&#8217;re continuing to fight it, we need to do everything we can to prepare for future pandemics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That means making sure we have the funding we need, and we&#8217;re headed toward a historic number in this infrastructure bill on that front, but also making sure that he engages with our nation&#8217;s top scientists and experts &#8212; and Dr. Lander is certainly one of them &#8212; about how we should prepare, how we should think about preparing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it is part of an ongoing discussion and ongoing focus that we can&#8217;t keep our eye off of that, even as we&#8217;re fighting the current pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So does the President feel strongly that that funding should be preserved in the reconciliation package?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He feels confident there&#8217;s going to be a historic amount of funding in the reconciliation package and is pleased to see that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To go back to Cori Bush for a second, can I just confirm or ask: Did the President himself personally ever speak with Representative Bush?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe so, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And in terms of vaccines, what does the White House &#8212; or what does the administration intend to do to get other countries to step up and meet some of those vaccination goals?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know it was a part of the discussion at the G7, and there was a significant announcement made by G7 countries about their contribution to the global effort.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an important step forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think you&#8217;ve also seen international public health experts convey that we&#8217;re going to need 10 million &#8212; 10 billion, 11 billion &#8212; more doses than we currently have in the global community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think our effort is going to be continuing to make this a front-and-center discussion at global engagements, at global meetings, whether it&#8217;s UNGA or the G20 or meetings we will have in the future, because it is going to require all of the richest countries in the world, including the United States, to step up, to increase vaccine donations, to increase manufacturing capacity.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think it&#8217;s more about making it front and center in the global agenda, which the President is indicating he will intend to do &#8212; continue to do moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just two questions, Jen.&nbsp; The President &#8212; we know President Biden has called on Cuomo to resign &#8212; Governor Cuomo &#8212; but in the meantime, does the White House intend to strip him of his leadership position on those biweekly governor COVID calls?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure when the next one is scheduled.&nbsp; But again, I would convey that our objective is not to hurt the people of New York in the fight against COVID.&nbsp; If he is no longer the governor of New York, which is certainly what the President made clear of his &#8212; is his preference, then we will engage with other people.&nbsp; But we are not going to take steps to hurt the people of New York in the fight against COVID.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a second question.&nbsp; Should renters be prepared for the eviction moratorium to end for good on October 3rd?&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s thinking on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it really depends on whether there is legislative action or not.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more question on the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; I’ll approach it this way: The President may support the legal justification, but he also publicly gave voice to doubts about the constitutionality.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House&#8217;s message then to Americans who heard what happened yesterday, heard what was said at this podium on Monday, can’t square the two, and are now disappointed that the President is signaling that he doesn&#8217;t respect the rule of law.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure there are Americans evaluating it to that degree; maybe there are some of you have talked to, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; What the President has &#8212; his message to the American people, especially those who are concerned about losing their homes, being kicked out of their homes, is that he&#8217;s going to do everything in his power to make sure they can stay in their homes as long as possible.&nbsp; That is not just an extension of the eviction moratorium &#8212; which, obviously, a step was taken yesterday; it is also about using every tool at our disposal to get this money out.<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, states have the funding to extend the eviction moratorium in their own states.&nbsp; That&#8217;s because there was funding in the American Rescue Plan to get that done.&nbsp; So that includes asking his team, members of his Cabinet, whether it&#8217;s &#8212; whether it&#8217;s Secretary Fudge, who obviously made an announcement today, or the Department of Treasury, who made an announcement about the simplification of forms &#8212; that this is a priority, that they are to use all resources at their disposal to make sure they&#8217;re communicating with Americans, that we&#8217;re making it easy to get this funding out because that&#8217;s the overall objective.<br>&nbsp;<br>The overall objective is not about one tool; it is about keeping people in their homes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the President is a lawyer; spent 36 years in the Senate, was chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, eight years as Vice President, half a year as President.&nbsp; He speaks often about democracy versus autocracy.&nbsp; He&#8217;s issuing or overseeing this order from the CDC in the face of doubts about its constitutionality, which he seemed to echo yesterday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If there&#8217;s no inconsistency here, the President is &#8212; I mean, there are many people out there who say that the President is essentially not giving voice to the ethic that he campaigned on.&nbsp; He didn’t call Congress back.&nbsp;&nbsp; He asked Congress to act; it didn&#8217;t.&nbsp; How do you square all that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know I&#8217;m going to ask you who&#8217;s saying that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, there are plenty of people who are saying it.&nbsp; They are not just Republicans.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, I&#8217;ll leave that to others to figure out.&nbsp; But I think what&#8217;s important to note here is that the President would not have moved forward with a step where he didn&#8217;t feel comfortable and confident in the legal justification.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is also a reality that there are legal steps that have been taken by the Supreme Court in the last few months, and we have spoken to that publicly.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to hide from that.&nbsp; But he asked the CDC and his legal experts to look at what is possible.&nbsp; This is a narrow, targeted moratorium that is different from the national moratorium; it&#8217;s not an extension of that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a different moratorium, from a policy and legal standpoint.&nbsp; So, he felt comfortable in the justification and the legal approach to this effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A quick follow-up on that, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Uh-huh, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;You mentioned that the President is &#8220;old school,&#8221; and Steve noted that the President spent a significant amount of time in the Senate and is also a lawyer. &nbsp;When &#8212; what was the moment that the President became certain that he was on solid legal standing to move forward with this extension? &nbsp;And what was the argument &#8212; specific legal argument that won out and changed his mind? &nbsp;Because yesterday he seemed to be weighing the two &#8212; the two options.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, as I&#8217;ve been discussing, the justification from the legal team is that this is a different moratorium.&nbsp; It&#8217;s narrow.&nbsp; It&#8217;s targeted at the highest &#8212; at the areas highest impacted.&nbsp; It is not an extension of the national moratorium that was struck down just six weeks ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is the sense here that, you know, this is temporary, it&#8217;s still an open question about the constitutionality, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is temporary.&nbsp; It was extended until Oct- &#8212; or October 3rd.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, so it&#8217;s still a question of whether or not it&#8217;s constitutional but it&#8217;s worth it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t say that.&nbsp; I would &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know, but is that the sentiment?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He would not have advocated for and supported moving forward with something if he was not comfortable with the legal justification.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me just go around.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead to the middle here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two quick questions.&nbsp; First, I was hoping you could preview a little bit the President&#8217;s meeting tomorrow with the AAPI leaders.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just curious what they&#8217;ll be discussing and why you chose to invite them to the White House this week.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Well, I should have had more of a preview for you, but I will tell you that the President looks forward to meeting with leaders of the AAPI community tomorrow.&nbsp; They will discuss a range of topics including, of course, economic investment; the fight against COVID; voting rights, which is certainly an issue that is of great importance to a range of communities who have been quite active on this issue; and, obviously, continuing discrimination that members of the AAPI community experience.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve also &#8212; proud of the number of nominees from the AAPI community that we have put forward for a range of important jobs in the administration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But those are some of the topics on his agenda, and I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll come ready with a number of topics they also want to discuss.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one, quickly, just on COVID.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President, yesterday, was asked whether he thinks more cities and states should follow New York City&#8217;s lead and institute rules, you know, essentially requiring people to &#8212; who have been vaccinated to go to their restaurants and stuff like that.&nbsp; And he said, &#8220;I do,&#8221; but then he later seemed to suggest maybe it should fall more on those businesses.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I was just hoping you could clarify: Does the President &#8212; would he urge, you know, cities and states to follow New York City&#8217;s lead?&nbsp; Or does he feel that it&#8217;s more, sort of, a private-sector matter, where businesses should be the ones, you know, taking the lead on this type of thing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, both.&nbsp; I mean, there are steps that are going to be taken by localities.&nbsp; There will be steps taken by businesses.&nbsp; The President supports local efforts to keep communities safe; they&#8217;re going to be different from community to community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our view is that any verification program should meet a few standards: accessibility &#8212; it needs to be free and available in paper and digital formats; it should be secure and private; nondiscriminatory, given equity is at the center of our agenda.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But he does &#8212; we know &#8212; we will see more local communities do more and more things in this space, including verification and employee mandates that will incentivize vaccinations.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re encouraged and supportive of innovative steps at the local level.<br>&nbsp;<br>I just want to jump around.&nbsp; Go ahead, to the back.&nbsp; Yeah, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;ll go after.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Give &#8212; go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; One on Quad.&nbsp; Earlier this year, during the virtual summit, Quad countries decided on vaccine production.&nbsp; Has the President set a deadline or timeline for when these vaccines will be produced for the rest of the world?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe there&#8217;s a deadline that has been set.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; Let me see if there&#8217;s anything more specific.<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, working with the Quad on COVID vaccines is an important part of our &#8212; oh, let me see.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you for the question because I was like, I know something more on this.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our Quad partnership is on track to help produce at least 1 billion doses of COVID vaccines in India for the Asia region by the end of 2022.&nbsp; So, that is the timeline.&nbsp; Obviously, more &#8212; hopefully more sooner rather than later, but that&#8217;s the timeline for the work with the Quad.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My other question is about the kids of legal immigrants.&nbsp; Because of the aging-out process, many of them feel that they will be deported back to a country where they have never lived.&nbsp; Some of them have been moving around the city, meeting the congressmen, at the White House as well.&nbsp; One of them, at least, has met the President in Pennsylvania.&nbsp; Has the President given any assurance to these kids that, instead of focusing on their studies, they&#8217;ve &#8212; they are now right to focusing on (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; For DACA recipients?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The legal immigrants &#8212; kids of legal immigrants, not the DACA recipients.&nbsp; Because the aging-out process, they might be forced to go back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll have to check.&nbsp; Obviously, taking steps to ensure we are providing a legal pathway to citizenship, and especially for kids who came into this country, as you referenced, you know, innocently with their family members.&nbsp; But I will see if there&#8217;s anything new to report on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask about a different moratorium &#8212; the payments of student loans &#8212; that expires at the end of September.&nbsp; What is the White House doing, at this point, to get ready for that date and figure out next steps?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any preview for you on what determination will be made on that front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any information on how you&#8217;re preparing?&nbsp; I mean, we got to the point of the moratorium that we&#8217;ve been talking about earlier, where you&#8217;re at the date. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are you doing between now and that date?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are certainly well aware of the date, well aware of the impact.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview in terms of a decision.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I wanted to ask one more question about the Justice Department.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The slot for Solicitor General is still open.&nbsp; With<br>the Supreme Court ending &#8212; first session ending several months ago, at this point, and going into some cases that I&#8217;m sure the administration really cares about, where are you at on picking someone?&nbsp; And what are you doing to get ready for that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you on any personnel announcements or decisions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Shelby.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about a Harris Poll released this week that indicates the majority of Americans believe&nbsp;the worst of the pandemic is still ahead.&nbsp; And this is a big change from a few weeks ago.&nbsp; And so this is despite, as you said, 70 percent of Americans being vaccinated and CDC data showing that the vaccine is protecting vaccinated Americans from serious illness.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, why is the American public so panicked?&nbsp; And is the White House concerned at all that it&#8217;s fueled this dramatic shift in public sentiment?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That we have fueled it?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, through &#8212; you know, like returning the mask recommendations for vaccinated Americans.&nbsp; Is there &#8212; is it concerned at all?&nbsp; What can it point to as a reason for Americans &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t really taken a close look at this poll.<br>&nbsp;<br>What I will tell you is that a poll before this &#8212; I believe it was a CBS poll &#8212; showed that more vaccinated Americans were concerned about the rise of Delta than unvaccinated.&nbsp; So, it was &#8212; that was even prior to the mask guidance putting &#8212; being put in place.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly, as people see, you know, the rise in cases in certain communities &#8212; unvaccinated communities &#8212; of course that&#8217;s concerning.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp; But we also believe that it is our responsibility to provide accurate public health information and also make clear to people the impact of being vaccinated and the fact that the vaccines are doing exactly what they should do, which is protect the vast majority of people from serious illness and hospitalization.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, yes, we are &#8212; we know that it is a &#8212; it is a challenge.&nbsp; And fighting a pandemic and communicating about it is a challenge.&nbsp; But certainly, that&#8217;s why we do as many briefings as we do, why we come out here every day as we do, and why we’ll continue to allow our public health guidance to be &#8212; to be in the lead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, on infrastructure: The House Speaker is still saying that the reconciliation bill and the infrastructure bill should be connected.&nbsp; Which bill would the President like to see on his desk first: the bipartisan infrastructure bill or the reconciliation bill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President looks forward to signing both into law, and he&#8217;s eager to do that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve certainly made progress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ll also note that, on the reconciliation package &#8212; which I know we haven&#8217;t talked about a lot because the infrastructure bill has been front and center &#8212; but in the meantime, behind the scenes &#8212; which is, by the way, where most of the work happens in places like the White House &#8212; our legislative affairs team has had over 375 meetings and calls with members and senior congressional staff about just the reconciliation package.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there&#8217;s no preference from the President whether he wants to see the reconciliation first?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to stay in close coordination and rely on the guidance and leadership of Leader Schumer and Speaker Pelosi.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how does &#8212; as the leader of the Democratic Party, how does he get House Speaker Pelosi on the same page that they&#8217;re not connected?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think the President has been clear that he wants to sign both into law.&nbsp; We&#8217;re encouraged by the movement of the infrastructure package forward.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been doing a lot of work behind the scenes, and the President will continue to advocate for, publicly, the reconciliation package, given how important his Build Back Better agenda is to him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re told you have a hard out shortly.&nbsp; Just one or two more.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President made an announcement on Lebanon recovery today.&nbsp; Can you outline that for us?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, give us a sense &#8212; given the fact this is the one-year anniversary of that blast that devastated Beirut,<br>how important is Lebanon&#8217;s political and economic stability to the United States, given the crisis it’s in right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; It’s very important.&nbsp; On behalf of the country, the President sent his deepest condolences to all those who were injured, lost loved ones, and still struggle to recover from the trauma from the catastrophic explosion at the Port of Beirut one year ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, we actually did a video from him that we&#8217;re happy to provide to anyone who is interested.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also recognize that the people of Lebanon have suffered more over the past year because of avoidable political and economic crises.<br>&nbsp;<br>So what we announced today is &#8212; we &#8212; nearly $100 million in new humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; That is on top of the almost $560 million in humanitarian aid that we have provided to Lebanon over the last two years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We recognize the important role Lebanon has played in the region, as you referenced, and also their role in hosting over 1 million Syrian refugees for a number of years.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re quite proud of our longstanding support for the Lebanese people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President urges his fellow leaders in capitals around the world to also step up their support for the Lebanese people.&nbsp; No amount of outside assistance, of course, will be enough to repair the pain from the blast just last year.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Nikki, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Are there any plans for the President to hold a press conference before he goes to the beach?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect he might take some questions at some point, but no plans for a formal press conference.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got a lot going on here, as you all know.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, also any chance that Team USA might be visiting post-Olympics?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I hope so.&nbsp; They&#8217;re invited.&nbsp; I&#8217;m inviting them here to my house &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; anywhere you want to come.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I hope so.&nbsp; I have nothing to pre- &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything on the schedule, but certainly that&#8217;s a tradition and the President is probably as obsessed with the Olympics as I am, if not more, so I expect there&#8217;ll be an invitation at some point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we have to wrap it up to &#8212; thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Have a great day.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:41 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with the Bucharest Nine&#160;Ambassadors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-the-bucharest-nine-ambassadors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 19:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with ambassadors from the Bucharest Nine (B9) group of NATO’s eastern flank Allies to consult on U.S. policies and activities of interest to the region.&#160; Mr. Sullivan briefed the ambassadors on our approach &#160;to energy security in Central Europe, including measures the Biden Administration is taking with partners&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with ambassadors from the Bucharest Nine (B9) group of NATO’s eastern flank Allies to consult on U.S. policies and activities of interest to the region.&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan briefed the ambassadors on our approach &nbsp;to energy security in Central Europe, including measures the Biden Administration is taking with partners to address the risks of the Nord Stream 2 pipeline. He also previewed the upcoming visit of President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine, discussed shared concerns about Belarus, and provided an update on U.S. engagement with Russia. &nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Ukrainian&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-ukrainian-officials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 19:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Head of Presidential Administration Andriy Yermak and Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba of Ukraine. They discussed the upcoming visit of President Zelenskyy to Washington on August 30, which will highlight the breadth and depth of the U.S.-Ukraine strategic partnership. They reviewed our robust agenda for cooperation on Kyiv’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Head of Presidential Administration Andriy Yermak and Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba of Ukraine. They discussed the upcoming visit of President Zelenskyy to Washington on August 30, which will highlight the breadth and depth of the U.S.-Ukraine strategic partnership. They reviewed our robust agenda for cooperation on Kyiv’s defense challenges, energy security needs, and governance and anti-corruption reforms, as well as our common approach to human rights and democracy in the region. Mr. Sullivan underscored the United States’ unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and Euro-Atlantic aspirations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White&#160;House Releases State Fact Sheets Highlighting the Impact of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act&#160;Nationwide</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/white-house-releases-state-fact-sheets-highlighting-the-impact-of-the-infrastructure-investment-and-jobs-act-nationwide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 18:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House released state fact sheets that highlight the nationwide impact of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act, the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. The fact sheets highlight how the historic legislation will deliver for states and territories across the country to repair roads and bridges,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House released state fact sheets that highlight the nationwide impact of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act, the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century.</p>



<p>The fact sheets highlight how the historic legislation will deliver for states and territories across the country to repair roads and bridges, improve transportation options, build a network of EV chargers to accelerate the adoption of EVs and help connect every American to reliable high-speed internet.</p>



<p>In the coming days and weeks, more state by state data will show the impact of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act on our drinking water infrastructure, power infrastructure, airports, resiliency and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Individual fact sheets for each of the 50 states, the District of Columbia and Puerto Rico are linked below.</p>



<p><strong>Fact Sheets by State/Territory:</strong><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/ALABAMA_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Alabama</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/ALASKA_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Alaska</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/ARIZONA_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Arizona</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/ARKANSAS_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Arkansas</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CALIFORNIA_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">California</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COLORADO_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Colorado</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/CONNECTICUT_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Connecticut</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/DELAWARE_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Delaware</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/FLORIDA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Florida</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/GEORGIA_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Georgia</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/HAWAII_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Hawaii</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IDAHO_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Idaho</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/ILLINOIS_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Illinois</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/INDIANA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Indiana</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/IOWA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Iowa</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/KANSAS_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Kansas</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/KENTUCKY_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Kentucky</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/LOUISIANA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Louisiana</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/MAINE_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Maine</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/MARYLAND_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Maryland</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/MASSACHUSETTS_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Massachusetts</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/MICHIGAN_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Michigan</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/MINNESOTA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Minnesota</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/MISSISSIPPI_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Mississippi</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/MISSOURI_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Missouri</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/MONTANA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Montana</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NEBRASKA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Nebraska</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NEVADA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Nevada</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NEW-HAMPSHIRE_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">New Hampshire</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NEW-JERSEY_The-Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">New Jersey</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NEW-MEXICO_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">New Mexico</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NEW-YORK_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">New York</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NORTH-CAROLINA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">North Carolina</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/NORTH-DAKOTA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">North Dakota</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/OHIO_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Ohio</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/OKLAHOMA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Oklahoma</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/OREGON_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Oregon</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PENNSYLVANIA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Pennsylvania</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/PUERTO-RICO_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Puerto Rico</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/RHODE-ISLAND_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Rhode Island</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SOUTH-CAROLINA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">South Carolina</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/SOUTH-DAKOTA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">South Dakota</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/TENNESSEE_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Tennessee</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/TEXAS_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Texas</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/UTAH_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Utah</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/VERMONT_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Vermont</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/VIRGINIA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Virginia</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WASHINGTON_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Washington</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WEST-VIRGINIA_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">West Virginia</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WISCONSIN_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Wisconsin</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WYOMING_Infrastructure-Investment-and-Jobs-Act-State-Fact-Sheet.pdf">Wyoming</a><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Top 10 Programs in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act That You May Not Have Heard&#160;About</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/03/fact-sheet-top-10-programs-in-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-investment-and-jobs-act-that-you-may-not-have-heard-about/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Weatherization: Two-thirds of low-income U.S. households have high energy burdens, meaning they spend more than 6 percent of their income on utility bills. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal will invest a historic $3.5 billion in the Weatherization Assistance Program, reducing energy costs for more than 700,000 low-income households by increasing the energy efficiency of their homes,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<ol><li><strong>Weatherization: </strong>Two-thirds of low-income U.S. households have high energy burdens, meaning they spend more than 6 percent of their income on utility bills. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal will invest a historic $3.5 billion in the Weatherization Assistance Program, reducing energy costs for more than 700,000 low-income households by increasing the energy efficiency of their homes, while ensuring health and safety and creating jobs.<br></li><li><strong>Wildfires:</strong> One estimate found that 4.5 million homes in the United States are at risk of wildfire. The bill invests $8 billion in wildfire risk reduction by providing funding for community wildfire defense grants, mechanical thinning, controlled burns, the Collaborative Forest Restoration Program, and firefighting resources.<br></li><li><strong>Floods: </strong>The cost of flood damage was approximately $17 billion annually in the last decade, and is expected to increase significantly due climate-related extreme weather and rising sea levels. The bill invests $12 billion in flood mitigation, including funding for FEMA flood mitigation grants, making infrastructure investments to increase coastal resilience, and improving mapping and data so that households and businesses can better protect themselves from future flood events.<br></li><li><strong>Brownfields and superfund</strong>: 26% of Black Americans and 29% of Hispanic Americans live within 3 miles of a Superfund site, a higher percentage than for Americans overall. Proximity to a Superfund site can lead to elevated levels of lead in children’s blood. The deal invests $5 billion in addressing legacy pollution at these sites, creating good-paying union jobs and advancing economic and environmental justice.<br></li><li><strong>Natural gas wells and coal mines: </strong>In thousands of rural and urban communities around the country, hundreds of thousands of former industrial and energy sites, including orphan wells and abandoned land mines, are now idle – sources of blight and pollution. The deal invests $16 billion in creating good-paying union jobs capping these wells and mines.<br></li><li><strong>Pipeline safety:</strong> More than 20,000 miles of cast iron pipelines—much of which was installed in the 1800’s and early 1900’s—transports natural gas underneath communities in the U.S. This infrastructure, which is prone to leaks and fugitive methane emissions, is mostly located in disadvantaged areas including older cities like Philadelphia, Detroit, Baltimore, New York, and St. Louis.&nbsp; Since 2010, the U.S. has experienced thousands of pipeline incidents, resulting in hundreds of injuries and deaths, tens of thousands of evacuations, and more than $4 billion in damages. The bill includes $1 billion for the “Natural Gas Distribution Infrastructure Safety and Modernization Grant Program” to modernize natural gas distribution pipelines, reducing incidents and fatalities, and avoiding economic losses.<br></li><li><strong>Battery manufacturing: </strong>Today, the U.S. relies heavily on importing advanced battery components from abroad, exposing the nation to supply chain vulnerabilities that threaten to disrupt the availability and cost of these technologies, as well as the workforce that manufactures them. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal will invest $6B to spur U.S. advanced battery processing, manufacturing, and recycling, creating good-paying jobs and enabling American manufacturers to win the 21<sup>st</sup> century. &nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Safe Streets:</strong> Over 36,000 Americans died in motor vehicle crashes in 2019, including over 6,200 pedestrians and about 850 bicyclists. The United States has one of the highest traffic fatality rates in the industrialized world, double the rate in Canada and quadruple that in Europe. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal includes $5 billion for a first-of-its kind “Safe Streets for All” program to fund state and local “vision zero” plans and other improvements to reduce crashes and fatalities, especially for the most vulnerable of roadways users.<br></li><li><strong>Transit station ADA program: </strong>More than 30 years after the passage of the Americans with Disabilities Act, nearly 1,000 transit stations are still not fully accessible, which prevents millions of older Americans and individuals with disabilities from fully enjoying public transit. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal includes a total of $2 billion for transit ADA, including $1.75 billion for All Stations Accessibility and $250 million for Enhanced Mobility for Seniors and Individuals with Disabilities. These programs will remove barriers to transportation service and expand transportation mobility options for Americans across the country.<br></li><li><strong>Cybersecurity: </strong>The recent cybersecurity breaches of federal government data systems, critical infrastructure, and American businesses underscore the importance and urgency of strengthening U.S. cybersecurity capabilities. The bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act will invest about $2 billion to modernize and secure federal, state, and local IT and networks; protect critical infrastructure and utilities; and support public or private entities as they respond to and recover from significant cyberattacks and breaches.</li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Fighting the COVID-&#8288;19&#160;Pandemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/03/remarks-by-president-biden-on-fighting-the-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 22:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25871</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[4:29 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Last week, I laid out what we need to do to beat the COVID-19 vi- &#8212; pandemic and the challenges posed by the Delta variant. This is a very different variant than what we’ve dealt with previously.&#160; It’s highly transmissible, and it’s causing a new wave of cases.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>4:29 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Last week, I laid out what we need to do to beat the COVID-19 vi- &#8212; pandemic and the challenges posed by the Delta variant.<br><br>This is a very different variant than what we’ve dealt with previously.&nbsp; It’s highly transmissible, and it’s causing a new wave of cases.&nbsp; It accounts for over 80 percent of all COVID-19 cases in the United States today.&nbsp; Experts tell us that we’re going to see these cases rise in the weeks ahead &#8212; a largely preventable tragedy that will get worse before it gets better.<br><br>What’s different about this surge from previous ones is we have the tools to prevent this rise in cases from shutting down<br>our businesses, our schools, our society, as we saw what happened last year.<br><br>And while cases are on the rise, it’s important to note we&#8217;ve not seen a comparable rise in hospitalizations or deaths in most areas of the country.<br><br>That’s because 165 million Americans are fully vaccinated, including 80 percent of the most vulnerable Americans &#8212; our seniors.<br><br>The best line of defense against the Delta vac- &#8212; the virus is the vaccine.&nbsp; It&#8217;s as simple as that.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; The vaccine.<br><br>I want to be crystal clear about what’s happening in the country today: We have a pandemic of the unvaccinated.<br><br>Now, I know there’s a lot of misinformation out there, so here are the facts: If you&#8217;re vaccinated, you are highly unlikely to get COVID-19.&nbsp; And even if you do, the chances are you won’t show any symptoms; and if you do, they’ll most likely be very mild.<br><br>Vaccinated people almost never are hospitalized with COVID-19.&nbsp; In fact, according to one recent study, 95 percent of overall COVID-19 hospitalizations are among those not fully vaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And the data shows that virtually all the cases, hospitalizations, and deaths due to COVID-19 are from the unvaccinated population.<br><br>Last month, a study showed that over 99 percent of COVID-19 deaths have among &#8212; have been among the unvaccinated people.&nbsp; Ninety-nine percent.<br><br>That means, if you’re unvaccinated, you are much more likely to, one, get COVID-19; two, get hospitalized; and, three, die if you get it.&nbsp;<br><br>This is a tragedy.&nbsp; People are dying and will die who don’t have to die.&nbsp; The data is absolutely clear: As I&#8217;ve said, we have a pandemic of the unvaccinated.<br><br>Think of it this way: A hundred and ninety-one million Americans have gotten at least one shot, including 70 percent of adults over the age of 18.&nbsp; A hundred and sixty-five million Americans are fully vaccinated, but about ninety million Americans are eligible for vaccines and still haven’t gotten their first shot.<br><br>You know, I think there&#8217;s a clear link between the lowest-vaccinated &#8212; I know &#8212; I don&#8217;t think, actually &#8212; the lowest-vaccinated states and the states with the highest case rates.<br><br>This past week, the most vaccinated state in America,<br>Vermont, has seen just five new cases &#8212; five &#8212; per day of COVID-19 for every 100,000 people who live in that state.&nbsp; That means, on any given day, only 30 people in the entire state of Vermont got COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Nearby Maine, which has vaccinated almost 80 percent of their adults, has seen just six new cases per 100,000.&nbsp;<br><br>But the states with the lowest vaccination rates are seeing 10 to 20 times as many new cases per 100,000 people.&nbsp; It’s moving like wildfire through the unvaccinated community.&nbsp; And it’s heartbreaking, particularly because it’s preventable.<br><br>That’s why we’re doing everything we can to get more people vaccinated.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re seeing real results.<br><br>In the past two weeks, we have seen a 55 percent increase in the average number of new people getting vaccinated every day.<br><br>In the last seven days alone, nearly 3 million Americans have gotten their first shot.&nbsp; That’s the highest seven-day total in a month.<br><br>Importantly, over the past two weeks, the eight states with the highest current case rates have seen a doubling of the number of people newly vaccinated each day.&nbsp; The message is getting through, apparently.<br><br>Louisiana has seen a 212 percent increase in the average number of newly vaccinated people in that state per day, going from 3,600 to over 11,000 people vaccinated per day.<br><br>Arkansas is up 99 percent.&nbsp; Mississippi is up 125 percent.&nbsp; Alabama is up 186 percent &#8212; going from 3,200 to 9,150 people vaccinated per day.&nbsp; This will make a big difference.<br><br>These are encouraging signs.&nbsp; We have to continue our aggressive efforts to vaccinate the unvaccinated.<br><br>Last week, I announced additional steps to incentivize Americans to get vaccinated, including calling on states to offer $100 for anyone willing to step up and get a vaccination shot.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, and already Minnesota and New Mexico have done that.&nbsp; And North Carolina announced its 100-day incentive &#8212; its $100 incentive today.<br><br>Places that have offered the hundred thou- &#8212; the hundred thousand &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; the hundred dollars &#8212; that’d be really good.&nbsp; I’d go back and get vaccinated three times. &nbsp;(Laughter.) But all kidding aside, offered the $100 to get vaccination have seen an uptick of 25 percent of daily vaccination rates.<br><br>We also announced that small- and medium-sized businesses will be fully reimbursed for offering paid time off for their employees to get vaccinated and for them to take a child or a parent to get vaccinated.<br><br>And I announced some tough, sometimes unpopular steps to keep people safe and our economy strong.&nbsp; All federal workers must report their vaccination status or be subject to strict requirements.&nbsp; Any federal worker who does not attest to their vaccination status or is not vaccinated will be required to mask no matter where they work, test one to twice a week, socially distance, and generally will not be allowed to travel for work.<br><br>I directed my administration to take steps to apply similar standards to all federal contractors.&nbsp; If you want to do business with the federal government, get your workers vaccinated.<br><br>And I also directed the Pentagon to look at adding COVID-19 to the list of vaccinations that are required for our troops because others are required.<br><br>I approved the Department of Veterans Affairs to require doctors, nurses, and other healthcare workers who care for our veterans to be vaccinated.<br><br>And the good news is that now many are following the federal government’s lead.&nbsp; In the past several days, states and local officials have come out to impose similar vaccination mandates.<br><br>And the private sector is stepping up as well.&nbsp; Even Fox has vaccination requirements.&nbsp; I want to thank Walmart, Google, Netflix, Disney, Tyson Foods for their recent actions requiring vaccination for employees.<br><br>Look, I know this isn’t easy, but I will have their backs and the backs of other private and public sector leaders if they take such steps.<br><br>But others have declined to step up.&nbsp; I find it disappointing.&nbsp; And worst of all, some state officials are passing laws or signing orders that forbid people from doing the right thing.&nbsp;<br><br>As of now, seven states not only ban mask mandates, but also ban them in their school districts, even for young children who cannot get vaccinated.&nbsp; Some states have even banned businesses and universities from requiring workers and students to be masked or vaccinated.<br><br>And the most extreme of those measures is like the one in Texas that say state universities or community colleges could be fined if it allows a teacher to ask her unvaccinated students to wear a mask.&nbsp;<br><br>What are we doing?<br><br>COVID-19 is a national challenge, and we must come together &#8212; we have to come together &#8212; all of us together, as a country, to solve it.<br><br>Make no mistake: The les- &#8212; the exc- &#8212; ex- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; the escalation of cases is particularly concentrated in states with low vaccination rates.&nbsp; Just two states, Florida and Texas, account for one third of all new COVID-19 cases in the entire country.&nbsp; Just two states.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we need leadership from everyone.&nbsp; And if some governors aren’t willing to do the right thing to beat this pandemic, then they should allow businesses&nbsp;and universities who want to do the right thing to be able to do it.&nbsp;<br><br>I say to these governors, “Please, help.”&nbsp; But if you aren’t going to help, at least get out of the way of the people who are trying to do the right thing.&nbsp; Use your power to save lives.<br><br>I’ve made it our first and top priority to have a vaccine available for every single American from the day I got elected.&nbsp; That was my priority.&nbsp; And let me be clear: We have a supply for every single American, and that will never change.<br><br>At the same time, it’s also in our national interest to share some of our vaccines with the world, which gets me to the second thing I want to discuss today.<br><br>From the beginning of my presidency, I’ve been very clear-eyed that we need to attack this virus globally, not just at home, because it’s in America’s self-interest to do so.<br><br>The virus knows no boundaries.&nbsp; You can’t build a wall high enough to keep it out.&nbsp; There is no wall high enough or ocean wide enough to keep us safe from a vaccination in other &#8212; from the COVID-19 in other countries.<br><br>In fact, just like the original virus that caused COVID-19, the Delta variant came from abroad.&nbsp; As long as the virus continue to rage outs- &#8212; rage outside the United States, potentially more dangerous variants could arrive at our shores again.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we know that COVID-19 in other countries stifles economic growth, disrupts supply chains, risks instability and weakness of governments.&nbsp; And as we’ve seen in the United States, the key to growing economies is to vaccinate people.&nbsp;<br><br>So just as the American economy is recovering, it’s in all of our interests to have global &#8212; the global economy begin to recover as well.&nbsp;<br><br>This is about our values.&nbsp; We value inherent dignity of all people &#8212; the inherent dignity of everyone.&nbsp; In times of trouble, Americans reach out to offer a helping hand.&nbsp; That’s who we are.<br><br>And I’ve said before: In this fight against COVID-19, the United States is committed to be the arsenal of vaccines, just as we were the arsenal of democracy during World War Two.<br><br>And we’re backing up that commitment.&nbsp; We have contributed more than any other nation to COVAX &#8212; the collective global efforts delivering COVID-19 vaccines across the world.<br><br>We have supported manufacturing efforts abroad through our partnerships with Japan, India, Australia –- known as “the Quad.”<br><br>During my trip to Europe in June, I announced that the United States would purchase a groundbreaking 500 million doses of Pfizer and then donate them &#8212; those doses &#8212; nearly &#8212; to nearly a hundred low- and middle-income countries who don’t have the vaccine.&nbsp; Those doses will start to ship at the end of this month.&nbsp;<br><br>We also announced that we’d donate 80 million doses of our own vaccine to supply the world, which has already begun.&nbsp;<br><br>And today, I have an important update.&nbsp; We’ve already exceeded 80 million doses that have been &#8212; gone out.&nbsp; As of today, the United States has shipped over 110 million doses of U.S. vaccines to 65 countries that are among the hardest hit in the world.<br><br>Let me say it again: As of today, we have shipped over 110 million doses to 65 nations.<br><br>According to the United Nations, this is more than the donations of all 24 countries that have donated any vaccine to other countries, including China and Russia &#8212; all those nations combined.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These vaccine donations from America are free.&nbsp; We’re not selling them.&nbsp; There are no demands, no conditions, no coercion attached.&nbsp; And there is no favoritism and no strings attached.&nbsp; We’re doing this to save lives and to end this pandemic.&nbsp; That’s it.<br><br>In fact, we’re donating vaccines to countries that have real issues &#8212; we have real issues with.<br><br>And we’ll continue to give tens of millions of the doses away across the summer and work to increase U.S. manufacturing and manufacturing of vaccines around the world as well.<br><br>And it’s not just vaccines.&nbsp; We are continuing to provide<br>countries with &#8212; in need &#8212; with more testing, protective equipment, and personnel to stem the surge of the virus.&nbsp; We’ve done it in India and elsewhere.<br><br>Let me close with this.&nbsp; I’ve said before: In the race for the 21st century between democracies and autocracies, we need to prove that democracies can deliver.&nbsp;<br><br>And the democracies of the world are looking to America to lead again &#8212; in two ways.&nbsp; First, to demonstrate we can control this virus at home.&nbsp; And second, to show we can help address it around the world.<br><br>Vaccinate America and help vaccinate the world &#8212; that’s how we’re about to beat this thing.<br><br>We’re always going to have enough doses for every American who wants one.&nbsp; Our work in donating vaccines to the world is about America following through on our promises and delivering what we say we’ll deliver.<br><br>It’s showing how American science and technology, American businesses and academia, and our government can all work together.<br><br>Above all, it’s proving democracies can deliver and, yet again, that America is back leading the world &#8212; not by the example of our power, but by the power of our example.<br><br>We still have a lot of work to do.&nbsp; So if you’re unvaccinated, please, please, please get the shot.&nbsp;<br><br>But just don’t take it from me.&nbsp; Just read the news.&nbsp; Listen to the voices of the unvaccinated patients in the hospital.&nbsp; They are <s>spending</s> [sending] the most powerful message to their families and everyone around the world &#8212; a powerful message to everybody.&nbsp; As they’re lying in bed, many dying from COVID-19, they’re asking, “Doc, can I get the vaccine?”&nbsp; The doctors have to look them in the eye and say, “No, sorry.&nbsp; It&#8217;s too late.”<br><br>Right now, too many people are dying or watching a loved one dying and saying, “If I just got vaccinated.&nbsp; If I just…”<br><br>Folks, this is isn’t about politics.&nbsp; The virus doesn’t care if you’re a Democrat or a Republican.&nbsp; This is about life and death.&nbsp; Life and death.<br><br>I can’t say it any more plainly than this: The vaccine saves lives, and it could save yours or your child’s.<br>You know, I know we can do this.&nbsp; We’re the United States of America.&nbsp; We’re prepared like never before.&nbsp; We have the tools and the resources to save lives at home and around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>This is who we are.&nbsp; This is what we do.&nbsp; This is why there&#8217;s no nation like us on Earth.<br><br>God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’ll take a few questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, I have a question for you on coronavirus, but first I&#8217;d like to start with the news of the day &#8212; given, back in March, you said that if the investigation confirmed the allegations against Governor Cuomo, then he should resign.&nbsp; So, will you now call on him to resign, given the investigators said the 11 women were credible?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I stand by that statement.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you now calling on him to resign?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if he doesn&#8217;t resign, do you believe he should be impeached and removed from office?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s take one thing at a time here.&nbsp; I think he should resign.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I understand that the state legislature may decide to impeach.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that for a fact; I&#8217;ve not read all that data.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And he&#8217;s using a photo of you embracing him in his self-defense to say that these are commonplace kind of embraces that he made in the allegations against him.&nbsp; Do you condone that?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to flyspeck this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure there are some embraces that were totally innocent, but app- &#8212; apparently, the Attorney General decided there were things that weren’t.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on coronavirus, if I could ask you a question about the evictions.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Why don’t you come up and take the platform?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>On the evictions and the moratorium that lapsed on Saturday night: What is your strategy to prevent potentially millions of people from being evicted from their homes, given what we are told your administration is considering &#8212; a targeted moratorium &#8212; is likely to face legal challenges?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Any call for a moratorium based on the Supreme Court recent decision is likely to face obstacles.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve indicated to the CDC I&#8217;d like them to look at other alternatives than the one that is in pow- &#8212; in existence, which the Court has declared they&#8217;re not going to allow to continue.&nbsp; And the CDC will have something to announce to you in the next hour to two hours.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, on overseas coronavirus vaccines: Should other high-income countries follow the lead of the United States and increase donations to low- and middle-income countries?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think those countries that have been able to cover their population and have the ability to provide either dollars and/or vaccine for the 100 or so na- &#8212; poor nations that need help should do so.&nbsp; We had that discussion at the G7.&nbsp; A number of those countries said they were going to do that.&nbsp; Some have followed through.&nbsp;<br><br>The point I was making is, though, I&#8217;ve kept the commitment &#8212; we&#8217;ve kept the commitment that we would do what we said, which is more than all the rest of the countries combined thus far.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you believe that Governor DeSantis and Governor Abbott are personally making decisions that are harming their own citizens?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I believe the results of their decisions are not good for their constituents.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s clear to me and to most of the medical experts that the decisions being made, like not allowing mask mandates in school and the like, are bad health policy &#8212; bad health policy.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, I have a question about something that you just said.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure you do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You just said there is no wall high enough and no ocean wide enough to protect us from the virus.&nbsp; So what is the thinking behind letting untested and unvaccinated migrants cross the southern border into U.S. cities in record numbers?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; There is &#8212; what we&#8217;re doing &#8212; we have not withdrawn the order that is sometimes critical &#8212; criticized &#8212; saying that unvaccinated people should be &#8212; go back across the border.&nbsp;<br><br>But unaccompanied children is a different story, because there&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s the most humane thing to do is to test them and to treat them and not send them back alone.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, have you spoken with Governor Cuomo today?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I have not.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one other question on the virus.&nbsp; You just said we have &#8212; we have to continue our aggressive efforts to get the unvaccinated vaccinated.&nbsp; Other countries have found a lot of success in requiring vaccines in public places.&nbsp; New York City just announced today that they’ll require vaccines for restaurants and gyms.&nbsp; Do you think more cities and states should institute rules like that?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And are you going to publicly call on them?&nbsp; Should they institute a vaccine passport-type system, or it&#8217;s up to each city and state to figure that out on their own?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; What did you say?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think that they should institute a vaccine passport-type system or some sort of verification to use public spaces?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think they need to do that.&nbsp; I think they just need to give the authority of those restaurants or businesses to say, “In order to come in, you have to give proof that you&#8217;ve been vaccinated or you can&#8217;t come in.”<br><br>I’ll take a couple more.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President can I ask you about news of the day &#8212; one more on Governor Cuomo?&nbsp; You&#8217;re calling for him to resign now.&nbsp; My question is: Do you think he should be prosecuted?&nbsp; And what is your message to the women who have now accused him of sexually harassing them and abusing them?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, what I said was: If the investigation of the Attorney General concluded that the allegations were correct, that &#8212; back in March &#8212; that I would recommend he resign.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I&#8217;m doing today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve not read the report.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know the detail of it.&nbsp; All I know is the end result.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, a question on COVID, if I could, really quickly.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; Can you explain a little bit more why it took so long to have a possible eviction moratorium be put into place?&nbsp; There was &#8212; there are people &#8212; this expired on Saturday.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering &#8212; there are folks who are saying it took too long for this to happen.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, the courts made it clear that the existing moratorium was not constitutional; it wouldn&#8217;t stand.&nbsp; And they made that clear back in, I guess, July 15th or July 18th.&nbsp;<br><br>In the meantime, what I&#8217;ve been pushing for and calling for is we have billions of dollars that were given to states to provide for rent and utilities for those people who can&#8217;t afford to stay in their homes because they can&#8217;t &#8212; an apartment &#8212; they can&#8217;t pay their rent.&nbsp; And so, we’re urging them to distribute those funds to the landlords.&nbsp; I believe that would take care of the vast majority of what needs to be done to keep people in their &#8212; in their ho- &#8212; in their apartments now.&nbsp;<br><br>And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re working on.&nbsp; Some states have done it and some communities have, but they have not.&nbsp; The money is there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not &#8212; we don&#8217;t have to send it out.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been sent out to the states and counties &#8212; billions of dollars &#8212; for the express purpose of providing for back rent and rent for the people who are in the middle of this crisis.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s there; that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re pushing now.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been pushing that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the immediate thing to do.<br><br>I’ll take one more question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you so much.&nbsp; There was an expectation that you would be announcing new vaccines to the world today &#8212; a new &#8212; other than the ones you promised.&nbsp; Are you ready to send more vaccines to the world?&nbsp;<br><br>And there is a delegation from the White House going to Brazil tomorrow.&nbsp; Are they bringing more vaccines?&nbsp; Are they announcing more vaccines to Brazil?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No &#8212; are they announcing more vaccines overall?<br><br>Q&nbsp; &nbsp; Overall.&nbsp; And then to Brazil &#8212; for the delegation coming to Brazil tomorrow &#8212; will you be bringing vaccines?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The answer is: I don&#8217;t know whether the delegation going physically has vaccines with them.&nbsp; We have provided vaccines to &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are they bringing the announcement?&nbsp; Are they announcing there?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, no, there’s a need for several billion doses around the world.&nbsp; We have committed to over a half a billion doses.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re trying to provide for more and provide for the capacity of countries like India to be able to produce the vaccine themselves.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re helping them do that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing now.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re trying to &#8212; we’re &#8212; and, by the way, it&#8217;s free.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not charging anybody anything.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re trying to do as much as we possibly can.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, we’re learning that your administration is about to announce a new partial eviction moratorium, COVID related.&nbsp; Can you tell us any more about that?&nbsp; And are you sure it&#8217;s going to pass Supreme Court muster?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The answer is twofold.&nbsp; One, I’ve sought out constitutional scholars to determine what is the best possibility that would come from executive action, or the CDC’s judgment, what could they do that was most likely to pass muster, constitutionally.<br><br>The bulk of the constitutional scholarship says that it&#8217;s not likely to pass constitutional muster.&nbsp; Number one.&nbsp; But there are several key scholars who think that it may and it&#8217;s worth the effort.&nbsp; But the present &#8212; you could not &#8212; the Court has already ruled on the present eviction moratorium.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think what you&#8217;re going to see, and I &#8212; look, I want to make it clear: I told you I would not tell the Justice Department or the medical experts, the scientists what they should say or do.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t want to get ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>The CDC has to make the &#8212; I asked the CDC to go back and consider other options that may be available to them.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to hear from them what those other options are.<br><br>I have been informed they&#8217;re about to make a judgment as to potential other options.&nbsp; Whether that option will pass constitutional measure with this administration, I can&#8217;t tell you.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; There are a few scholars who say it will and others who say it&#8217;s not likely to.&nbsp;<br><br>But, at a minimum, by the time it gets litigated, it will probably give some additional time while we&#8217;re getting that $45 billion out to people who are, in fact, behind in the rent and don&#8217;t have the money.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why it was passed in &#8212; in the act that we passed in the beginning of my administration, and it went to the states.&nbsp;<br><br>We were under the impression that the states were moving this money out relatively rapidly.&nbsp; So, for example, if I&#8217;m in an apartment &#8212; if you&#8217;re in an apartment, and you&#8217;re behind on four- or five-month’s rent, and let&#8217;s say your rent is $2,000 a month &#8212; I&#8217;m just making this up out of the blue &#8212; and you&#8217;re behind, you need $10,000 to catch up.&nbsp; Hardly anybody has that $10,000.&nbsp; But there is money that the states have that can give to the landlord that $10,000 to the back rent.&nbsp;<br><br>The future rent, it’s unlikely &#8212; at least the hope is, since they have been made whole to that point &#8212; that they&#8217;d be inclined &#8212; because the economy is growing &#8212; inclined not to throw someone out in the street; keep that person &#8212; no guarantee &#8212; keep that person in the apartment, keep these kids in the same school district, and count on being able to have the opportunity for that &#8212; that person to be able &#8212; who may now be employed &#8212; to pay their rent.<br><br>But in the meantime, I&#8217;ve asked, isn’t there any safety valve we can put in?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s the one I explained to you.&nbsp; Again, CDC will announce that and the details of exactly how it works.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not telling &#8212; I told them I want them to take a look.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t tell them what they had to do.&nbsp;<br><br>And my hope is, it’s going to be a new moratorium that in some way &#8212; and I&#8217;m not going to announce it now; I’ll let them announce it &#8212; in some way covers close to 90 percent of the American people who are renters.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s all I can tell you now.<br><br>Thank you very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not 100 percent?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the difference?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because it’s a &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; let them explain that to you.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; I don’t want to get too far ahead.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, is COVAX doing enough to get shots in arms?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not call Governor DeSantis, Mr. President?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; To say “happy birthday”?&nbsp; What?&nbsp; I mean &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To deliver the message that you seem to be delivering today about “get out of the way.”<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He knows the message.&nbsp; He knows the message.&nbsp; We had a little discussion when I was down there.&nbsp; He knows the message.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did he say to you in that discussion?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; See you all later.<br><br>5:00 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act Creates Good-Paying Jobs and Supports&#160;Workers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/03/fact-sheet-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-investment-and-jobs-act-creates-good-paying-jobs-and-supports-workers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The deal reached by President Biden and the bipartisan group of Senators makes a once-in-a-generation investment in our infrastructure and will create good-paying union jobs repairing our roads and bridges, replacing lead pipes, and building energy transmission lines. It invests in clean energy manufacturing and zero-emission vehicles ensuring that the jobs in the clean energy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The deal reached by President Biden and the bipartisan group of Senators makes a once-in-a-generation investment in our infrastructure and will create good-paying union jobs repairing our roads and bridges, replacing lead pipes, and building energy transmission lines. It invests in clean energy manufacturing and zero-emission vehicles ensuring that the jobs in the clean energy industry are good-paying, quality American jobs. The deal ensures that all taxpayer-funded infrastructure projects use materials made in America.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act will create good jobs for workers across the country, including workers in rural areas, hard-hit energy workers, historically disadvantaged workers, and workers in distressed areas. This historic investment will accelerate the economic recovery, put Americans back to work, and boost wages for workers across the country.</p>



<p>The legislation will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Create millions of good-paying jobs.</strong>&nbsp;With the President’s Build Back Better agenda, the investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act will add, on average, around 2 million jobs per year over the course of the decade, accelerating America’s path to full employment while bringing workers who have been left behind into the labor force.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Protect critical labor standards on construction projects.&nbsp;</strong>The overwhelming majority of the funds in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act will be subject to Davis-Bacon requirements, which ensure that contractors pay workers on construction projects a fair, prevailing wage so that local wages, labor markets, and workers won’t be undercut. These requirements will protect wages for millions of workers, grow the economy, and support good-paying, union jobs.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Grow wages in the clean energy industry.</strong>&nbsp;President Biden committed to ensuring that the new jobs created in the clean energy industry—solar, wind, carbon capture, energy transmission—would be good-paying, union jobs. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act extends prevailing wage protections to all energy infrastructure provisions, including the construction of EV charging stations on highways and in communities, ensuring that these critical jobs come with good wages and benefits and support local unions.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Put pipefitters to work making communities safer.</strong>&nbsp;The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act will put pipefitters to work across the country with an historic investment in our water infrastructure, including funding to replace all of the nation’s lead water pipes. It also invests $1 billion to modernize and repair natural gas distribution pipelines, creating good-paying jobs while fighting the climate crisis by reducing methane emissions, as well as making our communities safer.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Buy America.&nbsp;</strong>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act lives up to the President’s commitment to ensure that the future is made in America by American workers. The legislation includes a comprehensive Buy America provision to ensure that all taxpayer-funded infrastructure and public works projects are built with American iron, steel, manufactured products, and construction materials. This will create good-paying manufacturing jobs here at home and further the President’s commitment to revitalizing the domestic industrial base.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Protect and support transit workers</strong>. The agreement provides unprecedented support for transportation&nbsp;workers who have worked tirelessly on the frontlines of the pandemic. The legislation includes new provisions to prevent operator assaults built on collective bargaining and labor-management collaboration, so that no transit worker should fear for their safety just for doing their job. And it provides over $300 million in grant funding to train transit workers on the zero-emission vehicles of the future, including through registered apprenticeships and other joint labor-management training programs.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Support auto workers</strong>. Auto workers and good, union auto manufacturing jobs are the backbone of communities across the country. As the country transitions to zero-emission vehicles, the President committed to building those vehicles and their components here in the United States. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act invests in grants to support battery and battery component manufacturing, manufacturing facilities, and retooling and retrofitting of existing facilities. It also invests in good-paying jobs building a nationwide network of electric vehicle charging infrastructure along highway corridors, which will accelerate the adoption of electric vehicles to address the climate crisis and support domestic manufacturing jobs.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Invest in coal and energy communities</strong>. America’s coal miners and energy workers have powered this country for more than a century. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act invests in places impacted by shifting energy markets, including directing billions of dollars for advanced energy manufacturing facilities and clean energy demonstration projects to communities where coal mines or power plants have been shut down. The legislation also invests $21 billion in environmental remediation, creating good-paying union jobs in hard-hit energy communities cleaning up superfund and brownfield sites, reclaiming abandoned mines, and capping orphaned gas wells.</li></ul>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act is just one part of President Biden’s plan to create and support good-paying, union jobs and deliver workers the dignity and rights they are owed. The President’s Build Back Better plan will pair job creation efforts with workforce development programs, invest in child care and long-term care and the care workers that enable others to go to work, provide national paid family and medical leave, ensure federal agencies have the necessary resources to protect workers, and invest in other efforts to create good, union jobs.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
