<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 15:06:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Op-Ed: Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh on Supporting the Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders Community</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2021/06/04/op-ed-deputy-national-security-advisor-daleep-singh-on-supporting-the-asian-americans-and-pacific-islanders-community/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 15:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By: Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh My story is the story of so many other Indian Americans. In search of a better life for their kids – and maybe a bit of adventure for themselves &#8211; my parents left India for America in the 1970s. I was born in Maryland, spent a few years&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>By: Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>My story is the story of so many other Indian Americans. In search of a better life for their kids – and maybe a bit of adventure for themselves &#8211; my parents left India for America in the 1970s. I was born in Maryland, spent a few years in Chicago, and settled in North Carolina when I was about seven years old.</p>



<p>I’ve always described my childhood as a happy one. Surrounded by a loving family, I felt like I was part of something bigger than myself, and that my life meant something to those around me. I also felt enormous pride and gratitude in being an American – having the freedom to find and become my authentic self, and the opportunity to dream big, even if in my case these were mostly athletic delusions.</p>



<p>At a young age, I also knew that we were different. I remember on the first day we arrived in Raleigh, our apartment was filled with unopened boxes. But instead of unpacking, my parents grabbed the phone book, found three Indian-sounding last names, and invited them over for dinner. All of them arrived within hours and, from that point on, we probably shared at least one weekend meal within the Indian community until I went away for college.</p>



<p>As I got older, I began to understand how much these gatherings meant. Like anyone else, my parents wanted a space where their traditions and beliefs were accepted, and that hadn’t always been their experience. When he first moved to the U.S., my dad &#8211; a turbaned Sikh &#8211; was told by his boss: if he wanted to keep his job, he’d need to fit in better. So that’s what my dad did – he sacrificed part of his identity to provide for his family. Meanwhile, my mom worked for the Raleigh city government, and I’ll never forget her coming home in tears after her boss openly bragged that he was a member of the KKK. He made sure to remind her of that throughout her years of dedicated but painful service in Raleigh city government.</p>



<p>I also wanted to feel accepted, but for that to happen as a kid it sometimes involved compromises that I now regret. I remember feeling dread in middle school whenever we’d have a substitute teacher, knowing they would butcher my name, and giving the whole class a good laugh at my expense. Sometimes I thought the solution was to just own it, so I’d speak during class with a thick Indian accent. When I think about that now, I’m ashamed. I made a joke out of my family’s background to deal with my own insecurity about being different.<br>Fast forwarding to the past few years, the rise in hateful attacks against Asian Americans and other communities of color made me realize that I was still carrying a lot of memories – painful ones – that felt heavier over the years. I’d almost forgotten the humiliation of getting beat up on the back of an elementary school bus for being the “dirty brown kid with smelly food,” or what it felt like to get told I couldn’t go on a date with someone in high school because I’m brown.</p>



<p>Much of the reason I’d been able to let these memories go was my deeply held belief that things were getting better when it came to race; that my kids would grow up in a different way. So I’ll admit, the slow progress and setbacks left me angry at times. I suspect many in the Indian American community feel the same way: we’re tired of watching the past repeat itself, and we’re exhausted from being quiet.</p>



<p>But to make change, we first have to recognize that we can all do better, myself included. That means being real about my own privilege as an Indian American from a middle-class household. I’m not at risk of being stopped and frisked. My wife and I don’t have to teach our kids how to survive if they get pulled over by the police. For those of us who’ve faced prejudice, we also need to check own our bias, and see our own privileges, if we’re going to do better.</p>



<p>It also means we need to speak out and do our part if we’re going to be seen as 100%, full-fledged, just-like-you citizens. As an Asian American, I’m deeply humbled and honored to have the privilege of serving in President Biden’s administration at a defining moment in our country’s history, while being a part of the most diverse administration ever assembled. My experience serving our country bears no resemblance to my mom’s days in Raleigh city government, but her experience back then, and recent violence toward Asian Americans, are a constant reminder to me about the responsibility I have of representing and standing up for the AAPI community every day in this job.</p>



<p>My role at the White House is to help create a self-reinforcing dynamic between domestic renewal, American leadership abroad, and national security. Part of domestic renewal has to do with economics: creating sustained and inclusive growth in jobs and wages, boosting the resilience of our critical supply chains, and strengthening our innovative edge. Another part of domestic renewal involves healing the wounds of racial injustice and coming together as a society to deliver on American’s unmatched promise. I don’t have direct policy responsibility in this area, but it’s central to what President Biden is trying to deliver, and a big reason why I’m here.</p>



<p>As a final thought, I want to use this platform to send love and support to my sisters and brothers in the Sikh community who have been a particular target of harassment, racism, and violence in recent years. I stand with them today and always.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, June 3, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/03/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-june-3-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 23:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:56 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; All right.&#160; I have a couple of items for all of you at the top, and some charts.&#160; We love charts in here.&#160;&#160;In today&#8217;s encouraging report, initial claims for unemployment insurance fell to their lowest level and below 400,000 for the first time since the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:56 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; I have a couple of items for all of you at the top, and some charts.&nbsp; We love charts in here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In today&#8217;s encouraging report, initial claims for unemployment insurance fell to their lowest level and below 400,000 for the first time since the pandemic hit.&nbsp; This is just the latest evidence that President Biden&#8217;s economic strategy and vaccination plans are working.&nbsp; While weekly data can be volatile, since taking office, average claims have fallen by about 50 percent, which you can see in this chart, over the course of time, and by more than 100,000 in last &#8212; in the last month alone.<br>&nbsp;<br>And earlier this week, the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development &#8212; the OECD, as it&#8217;s commonly known &#8212; one of the leading bodies in analyzing economic growth around the world, increased their projection for U.S. economic growth this year to 6.9 percent due to the strength of the American Rescue Plan and our pandemic response to get Americans vaccinated and lift our economy out of the crises that we inherited.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, the United States is the only major industrialized nation to have its growth projection through 2025 revised upward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also learned earlier this week that manufacturing activity in May was near its highest level in more than 15 years.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; I also wanted to note, which many of you saw this morning, that our Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber, Anne Neuberger, who&#8217;s been here a couple of times, released an open memo to corporate executives and business leaders urging them to take immediate steps to address the threat of ransomware.&nbsp; Obviously, this is in light of the attack this week &#8212; the ransomware attack this week, and the one from just a few weeks ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The federal government, under the leadership of President Biden, has been stepping up to strengthen the nation&#8217;s defenses against cyberattacks, but we can&#8217;t do it alone.&nbsp; Business leaders have a responsibility to strengthen their cyber defenses to protect the American public and our economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The most important takeaway from the recent spate of ransomware attacks on the United States, Ireland, and Germany, and organizations &#8212; other organizations around the world, is that companies that view ransomware as a threat to their core business operations, rather than a simple risk of data theft, will react and recover more effectively.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our Deputy National Security Advisor laid out a small number of highly impactful steps that private-sector companies can take to harden their cybersecurity.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve outlined them here.&nbsp; And again, it was in the memo that she put out just this morning, and that&#8217;s something we will encourage &#8212; continue to encourage companies to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally &#8212; lots of news out there this morning &#8212; as you all know &#8212; and many of you were probably on this call &#8212; Jeff Zients and Jake Sullivan announced the President&#8217;s strategy for global vaccine sharing and their allocation plan for the first 25 million doses to be shared globally.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, just a couple of highlights from that:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, having successfully secured enough vaccine supply for Americans, we’re donating excess &#8212; donating surplus U.S. vaccine supply and encouraging other countries with surplus supplies to do the same.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He’s announced &#8212; the President has announced a U.S. commitment to sharing a total of 80 million doses by the end of June.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s 25 million doses that will go out as soon as possible, very quickly.&nbsp; A number of those are going to even go out as soon as today.&nbsp; And that is five times the number of doses any other country has committed to sharing and 13 percent of the total vaccines produced by the United States by the end of this month.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, we&#8217;re working with vaccine manufacturers to vastly increase vaccine supply for the rest of the world in a way that can also create jobs here at home.&nbsp; So that &#8212; so we have all these manufacturers who have facilities that will enable us to continue to produce additional supply, even beyond, so that we can provide that to the rest of the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>We will also work with our partner nations and pharmaceutical companies and other manufacturers to create the kind of global vaccine production and manufacturing capacity and capabilities that can not only help the world beat this pandemic, but also helps prepare the world to respond to future threats.<br>&nbsp;<br>A couple of additional highlights: One, our approach today was rooted in a couple of considerations.&nbsp; One, ensuring vaccines are delivered in a way that is efficient and equitable and follows the latest science and public health data.&nbsp; Two, providing vaccines for populations across different regions and those most at risk, as well as the nations experiencing surges, high burdens of disease, or low vaccination rates.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, the President &#8212; as the President said, we will not use our vaccine supply and the doses we&#8217;re sharing with the world to secure favors from other countries, and that’s a value from the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, we announced that we&#8217;re sharing at least 75 percent of these vaccines, which is approximately 19 million, through COVAX, which will &#8212; of the 25 million, I should say, that are going out &#8212; through COVAX, which will facilitate equitable distribution to reach those most at risk.&nbsp; So, approximately 6 million for Latin America and the Caribbean; 7 million for South and Southeast Asia; 5 million with the African Union and Africa CDC.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re sharing 25 percent of these vaccines with countries with immediate needs and to help surges around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>As final determinations are made about additional supply and where it&#8217;s going, we will provide that to all of you, but wanted to convey how we&#8217;d be approaching this and where the initial set of supply is going.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; I hope everyone had a snack.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Alex, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; With the news that the Trump Justice Department sought the records of more journalists, this time from the New York Times, can you talk a bit about Biden’s pledge that the practice won’t continue under his Justice Department?&nbsp; Can you speak to, in particular, how can the President keep that promise while also making good on his pledge to uphold the independence of the Justice Department?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me &#8212; for those of you who didn&#8217;t follow as closely what Alex referenced, although I bet many of you did, this is the third announcement by the Department of Justice of attaining records of journalists during the last year of the Trump administration &#8212; so, something they&#8217;re projecting publicly that happened during the last year of the Trump administration.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve also indicated that this is the last.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you noted, Alex, the President has made clear that, on his watch, freedom of press will be protected.&nbsp; He laid out core principles several weeks ago, because this is something that he is personally passionate about, and he has a long record with respect to protecting the rights of journalists.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as he&#8217;s always been emphatic about &#8212; he was always alarmed by the way the former administration, the Trump administration, abused their power in some cases.&nbsp; And the career, nonpartisan, civil servants often were doing their work with great professionalism and honor and were put in a difficult position.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I will say that he&#8217;s always felt that it&#8217;s important, as is evident by his words he shared just a few weeks ago, that we should always be refining and improving our approaches to how we approach this issue and any other issue.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of a specific policy moving forward, but it&#8217;s something that he is &#8212; that&#8217;s, kind of, his principles he will approach this from, moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you said the White House had not spoken to the DOJ about this particular issue.&nbsp; Was it just a suggestion to the DOJ?&nbsp; I mean, how is this going to become codified?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, obviously, the President spoke to it himself publicly, and we&#8217;re in touch at the appropriate layers of the White House and the Department of Justice.&nbsp; And &#8212; but certainly this is the position of the President of the United States &#8212; what principles he wants to abide by as President, and he conveyed that publicly, so it wasn&#8217;t exactly in secret.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And then, on infrastructure: President Biden tried to give Republicans an alternative to funding infrastructure.&nbsp; He suggested a 15 percent minimum tax, rather than a hike in the corporate tax rates.&nbsp; So, can you talk a little bit about how this informs his broader vision?&nbsp; Is this a change to his broader vision on infrastructure? &nbsp;And is he basically proposing that no profitable corporations should be able to avoid taxes?&nbsp; Is that the, sort of, founding principle of that proposal?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, on the last one, that&#8217;s absolutely a principle.&nbsp; I will note &#8212; and I know this was a lengthy factsheet at the time &#8212; but the “book minimum tax,” which is the 15 percent minimum tax, was actually in the American Jobs Plan as one of the payfor components.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So what happened over the last couple of days and also in the meeting yesterday is that the President did a thorough review of all of the tax reforms he&#8217;s proposed &#8212; many of them on the campaign.&nbsp; So he talked about this on the campaign.&nbsp; It was in the American Jobs Plan as a payfor and also is reflected in our budget that we just put out last Friday.&nbsp; And he looked to see what could be a path forward with his Republican colleagues on this specific negotiation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, I think it&#8217;s important to step back and remember that what &#8212; the proposals about the American Jobs Plan is a historic investment in infrastructure, modernizing our nation&#8217;s infrastructure, becoming more competitive around the world.&nbsp; He&#8217;s proposed ways to pay for it.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Others have not exactly done the same in many capacities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a way for him to identify pieces that he&#8217;s long been a proponent of as ways where he feels it would not violate.&nbsp; This would not &#8212; this would &#8212; this should be completely acceptable to a number of Republicans who have said that they &#8212; they want to leave their bottom lines, they want to leave the 2017 tax law untouched.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I wouldn&#8217;t say it&#8217;s a new approach by the President. This is in our budget.&nbsp; It was on the campaign.&nbsp; It was in the American Jobs Plan proposal.&nbsp; He also talked, of course, about the benefit of tax enforcement and how that could be a revenue raiser.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what really should stand out at this point to people is that opposing this proposal would not &#8212; would mean not only opposing raising taxes on the wealthiest Americans who&#8217;ve done extraordinarily well during the pandemic; it would mean opposing the very enforcement of the 2017 tax law.&nbsp; It would mean maybe having the view that nobody should pay &#8212; that these 50 corporations who didn&#8217;t pay taxes shouldn&#8217;t pay any taxes at all.&nbsp; And that certainly is not the view the President has.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more quick one.&nbsp; Can you clarify the President&#8217;s position on the filibuster?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what way?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Where does he stand?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve said &#8212; I talked about it quite extensively yesterday.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to repeat it &#8212; and often.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the President’s view is that he believes that there should be a path forward for Democrats and Republicans to work together to get the job done on behalf of the American public, whether that is voting rights and ensuring that more people have access to voting rights, or whether that is moving forward on other priority items for him.<br>&nbsp;<br>He has talked, in the past, about a move back to the talking filibuster.&nbsp; It shouldn&#8217;t be so easy to invoke the filibuster; that is his view.&nbsp; But it hasn&#8217;t changed beyond that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, following up on infrastructure, quickly: The President and Senator Capito had said they aim to reconnect tomorrow.&nbsp; Is that going to be another face-to-face meeting here at the White House, or is that going to be happening virtually?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question, Monica.&nbsp; I think it could &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a definite format for you, but it certainly could happen.&nbsp; They&#8217;re just going to reconnect and engage.&nbsp; It certainly could happen on the phone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is the expectation from the White House that tomorrow Republicans will offer yet another counterproposal and that that may be the final step in the set of negotiations?&nbsp; Or do you anticipate this will go through the weekend until Monday, June 7th, as you had noted?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know everybody is excited to work through the weekend.&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to prejudge what Senator Capito will come to the table with tomorrow.&nbsp; I will leave that to her to speak to and other Republicans who have been a part of these good-faith discussions and negotiations.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note that this has been a good discussion and &#8212; good, ongoing discussion where we’ve &#8212; we’re working to find areas of agreement.&nbsp; We also feel there are a number of paths forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Next week, the House is going to be marking up the American Jobs Plan; Congressman DeFazio will be leading that effort.&nbsp; There are a number of Democrats and Republicans who have talked about working together &#8212; many of you have reported on &#8212; to come up with a proposal where they can all mutually agree on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the President is looking forward to engaging with Senator Capito tomorrow; feels they&#8217;ve had good discussions &#8212; good-faith discussions.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also going to keep options open and keep a range of paths open for how we move his ideas forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, on vaccines, how does the two-dose regimen factor into the 25 million doses?&nbsp; How many of them are Johnson &amp; Johnson?&nbsp; Or should this be viewed as something that is potentially more for 10 to 12 million people to get vaccinated given, of course, it requires two shots?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, also, what is the plan for doses that may expire this month or soon?&nbsp; What is the U.S. going to do to ensure that gets there quickly enough to ensure they can actually be viable?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, on the second question, we are going to, of course, look closely to determine that we get doses out as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And, as I noted, 25 million will be going out as quickly as we can logistically get those out the door.&nbsp; And we are going to &#8212; that&#8217;s certainly a factor as we are working to operationalize this, which is kind of a historic herculean effort to get these doses to all of the communities and countries that we have committed them to.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of Johnson &amp; Johnson, you know, of the doses that will be going out, they will be all approved doses by the FDA, of which Johnson &amp; Johnson is one of them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an exact breakdown between the three, but you&#8217;re absolutely correct that, obviously, if it&#8217;s Johnson &amp; Johnson, it would be one dose; if it&#8217;s the other two approved &#8212; Moderna and Pfizer doses &#8212; it would require two doses.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Steve.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, do you feel like you&#8217;re close to a deal on infrastructure &#8212; that you’ve significantly narrowed the gap?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, over time, we feel that all parties &#8212; of course, we have been and we certainly feel that Senator Capino [sic] &#8212; Capito and the other Republicans who&#8217;ve been a part of that have been operating in good faith.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, and negotiation &#8212; as you know, Steve, from covering a lot of these &#8212; is exactly that.&nbsp; It’s seeing how much each side can come closer to the other.&nbsp; And the President has some priorities, including ensuring that we&#8217;re investing in infrastructure of the future.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are areas that are personally important to him: making sure we&#8217;re rebuilding veterans hospitals; making sure we&#8217;re making electric vehicles a reality; charging stations, buses, et cetera.&nbsp; Some of these proposals have been in our counterproposal, on the original proposal.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, certainly, part of negotiating is coming up in numbers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has he abandoned the plan to raise the corporate tax rate to 28 percent?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that off the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; What the President believes is, one, that corporations can afford to pay a little bit more, and that&#8217;s a way that can &#8212; we can pay for a range of the bold proposals that he has put forward.&nbsp; But he also took a look at these proposals, and the &#8212; all of the tax proposals that he has put forward over time to find a way where there should be payfors that, based on their &#8212; based on their bottom lines, many of the Republican negotiators should be able to agree to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, Israel seems to be on the cusp of a new prime minister.&nbsp; What&#8217;s at stake for the United States here? Does policy change as a result of this leadership change?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will leave &#8212; which won&#8217;t be a surprise to you, Steve &#8212; the politics and the determination about political formation in Israel up to the parties there.&nbsp; Israel will remain an important strategic partner, one where we have an abiding security relationship.&nbsp; And that will continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll come back to you guys.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just to clarify: Is the President&#8217;s position that he would be willing to do away with this increase in the corporate tax rate if Republicans agreed to a minimum 15 percent corporate tax rate?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s take a step back.&nbsp; The minimum &#8212; the book minimum was in the President&#8217;s American Jobs Plan proposal as a proposed payfor.&nbsp; It was also in our budget.&nbsp; So this is not a new idea; this is a component of what he&#8217;s proposed for a payfor that he&#8217;s lifting up as a question as to whether they could agree to that, because it certainly doesn&#8217;t violate anything about the 2017 taxes.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s putting forward as an idea that he&#8217;s asking them where their point of view is.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he’s saying it could be one or the other?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, no.&nbsp; He believes that we should continue to look at raising the corporate rate; that is a way to pay for a range of ideas.&nbsp; He&#8217;s got a lot of ideas out there, a lot of bold proposals, including that aren&#8217;t a part of this infrastructure negotiation.&nbsp; And he continues to believe that corporations can pay more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the bottom line is that these proposals he&#8217;s put forward as payfors in the American Jobs Plan, including IRS enforcement &#8212; which is also in our budget, of course &#8212; and this book minimum tax are ways that, unless you think corporations shouldn&#8217;t pay any tax at all &#8212; and we&#8217;ll leave that to others to speak to &#8212; then there should be a way to find a path to agreement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how was that proposal received by Senator Capito?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll leave her &#8212; I&#8217;ll leave that to her and others to speak to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; The President said yesterday that he&#8217;s putting Vice President Harris in charge of the White House&#8217;s efforts to combat voting restrictions around the country.&nbsp; What is this effort going to look like exactly?&nbsp; What is the White House going to do to push back on bills that are making their way through state legislatures?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that the Vice President put out an extensive statement on this just two days ago.&nbsp; And she has this assignment because she asked to lead the effort on voting rights, because it&#8217;s an issue she is personally passionate about, and she wants to spend time and effort and energy working on.<br>&nbsp;<br>What she&#8217;s conveyed &#8212; the President certainly supports and agrees on &#8212; is that there&#8217;s a federal component here &#8212; continuing to push for legislation to move forward at a federal level &#8212; but there&#8217;s also an important component of working with grassroots organizations, leaders in states, and others to see how we can push back on laws that have been &#8212; that are moving toward getting approved, that make it harder to vote, and how we can use the power of the vice presidency to activate energy and engagement on these issues.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally: The FBI has been investigating Postmaster General Louis DeJoy in connection with his former business.&nbsp; Does President Biden believe that the Postmaster General should step down or be replaced?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;ll leave &#8212; he’ll let &#8212; he’ll leave the investigation and the process forward to the Department of Justice.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Going back to infrastructure: I understand that the President offered to repurpose $75 billion in unspent COVID money after there was some concern from the White House that doing that would jeopardize aid to rural hospitals in the areas where it was intended in the beginning.&nbsp; What changed in that negotiation?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, is there any more room for that, given the jobs report and the 20 states not taking enhanced federal unemployment anymore?&nbsp; Could more be taken from unemployment to dedicate to the $75 billion (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that what he&#8217;s referencing &#8212; or there might be some openness to &#8212; is pre-ARP money, which passed during the prior administration; there is a tiny, minimal amount left.&nbsp; So that’s certainly not going to pay for the majority &#8212; the vast majority of these proposals.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, I would note that a lot of this funding &#8212; as we&#8217;ve talked about before &#8212; the vast majority of this funding is allocated, and it is meant to go to, as you noted, hospitals, to firefighters, to keeping law enforcement on the job, to state and localities that have suffered during the pandemic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ve proposed alternatives to pay for these proposals, as we&#8217;ve been talking about a bit in here.&nbsp; Why wouldn&#8217;t it be a better option for companies that paid no tax to pay 15 percent? &nbsp;Which is still a lower tax rate than even was in the Trump tax package.&nbsp; Why wouldn&#8217;t it be a better proposal to invest in enforcement &#8212; IRS enforcement &#8212; something that&#8217;s supported by 84 percent of Republicans in the country?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are a range of ideas out there.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s bottom line is: He&#8217;s not going to raise taxes on people making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; He&#8217;s proposed a lot of different options that don&#8217;t cross that red line.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s looking forward to seeing what the other side has to offer.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Where did that $75 billion come from?&nbsp; What pot did it come out of?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The pre-ARP COVID funding.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then going to the emails with Dr. Fauci: There was an exchange between Dr. Collins and Dr. Fauci referencing a Fox News report, discussing it as &#8212; basically, the lab leak as a conspiracy.&nbsp; Collins denied, you know, jumping to conclusions, and he asserted that his mention of conspiracies was referring to the thought, the rumor that the virus was engineered &#8212; bioengineered as a weapon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Is that the position of the administration and their top health experts, that this was not engineered?&nbsp; Or is that still an open question and part of this review?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ve spoken to this pretty extensively from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me just say, on Dr. Fauci and his emails, he&#8217;s also spoken to this many, many times over the last &#8212; over the course of the last few days, and we&#8217;ll let him speak for himself.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s been an undeniable asset in our country&#8217;s pandemic response.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s obviously not that advantageous for me to re-litigate the substance of emails from 17 months ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve launched, based on the President&#8217;s direction, an entire internal review process to use all of the resources across government to get to the bottom of the origins.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a 100-day process, and we&#8217;ll look forward to providing more when that &#8212; or 90 days, sorry &#8212; when it&#8217;s concluded.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak at all to the Vanity Fair report about this State Department factsheet that came out five days before inauguration?&nbsp; You know &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Five days before this President’s inauguration?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Do you know if there was any crossover of that; how that was seen by this administration &#8212; the conclusions that they were trying to put out in the final days of the Trump administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;m just going to focus on our own internal review that&#8217;s going to use every resource in the federal government &#8212; whether that is our health experts, our medical experts, our national security team &#8212; to see what more we can unearth about the origins, which certainly we all want to get to the bottom of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, back on infrastructure.&nbsp; So just to be clear on this: One trillion in new spending, and the focus on the minimum tax instead of corporate tax hikes.&nbsp; Is this the President&#8217;s best and final offer to Republicans?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, I think it&#8217;s important to note we have a range of means for moving the President&#8217;s ideas and proposals forward.&nbsp; And the President is going to have a conversation with Senator Capito tomorrow.&nbsp; He&#8217;s very much looking forward to that.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will tell you, for clarity, that what he put forward would have been new spending on top of a baseline of $400 billion over five years.&nbsp; That amount of money &#8212; that would be expected to be invested in infrastructure regardless of these talks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And beyond that, I think, in terms of the payfors, we&#8217;re open to other options.&nbsp; The President is just not going to raise taxes on Americans making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; If the Republicans want to go back to raising the corporate rate as a part of this specific negotiation, we are absolutely for that, and we think that these corporations could pay more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If there are other options, great.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to go down the road of user fees or other areas that would raise taxes on the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how much of the plan does that minimum tax cover? &nbsp;Does the White House &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s in our budget.&nbsp; You can &#8212; you can take a look.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the corporate tax rate: Are you confident progressive Democrats in Congress would get behind a proposal that doesn&#8217;t include an increase in the corporate tax rate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, to be clear, the President absolutely thinks that corporations can afford to pay more, and especially &#8212; including corporations that paid zero in taxes over the last several years.&nbsp; That’s why it was in his proposal as a payfor.&nbsp; And certainly, a range of members, including progressives, are certainly well aware of what was in the President’s American Jobs Plan proposals as payfors.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the hack &#8212; the cyber hacking.&nbsp; The White House is telling businesses to take steps to prevent this.&nbsp; You know, what&#8217;s the message to Americans, to businesses that keep seeing these hacks happening?&nbsp; Would you consider enforcement? Would you consider other regulations that would try to make this, you know, stricter to prevent these cyberattacks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I will say that there has been. &nbsp;Ransomware is a global problem, as I think we &#8212; you all know.&nbsp; And we have seen these attacks &#8212; ransomware attacks, I should say &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen these attacks disrupt organizations around the world, from hospitals across Ireland, Germany, and France, to pipelines, as you all know, in the United States and banks in the United Kingdom.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These attacks have been on the rise for years because these criminal groups are able to make a profit off the backs of businesses, schools, local governments, and more.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the reasons that we&#8217;re doing our own review internally, which has the focus of four lines of effort &#8212; because we recognize this is an increasing threat; that it is a threat here, but it&#8217;s also a threat around the world, and certainly one that we&#8217;ll be discussing on the President&#8217;s trip in just two weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our focus is on the destruction of ransomware infrastructure and actors, including through close cooperation with the private sector &#8212; part of that communication; building the international coalition &#8212; hence part of the President&#8217;s trip; expanding cryptocurrency analysis to find and pursue criminal transactions; and reviewing our own ransomware policies.&nbsp; That&#8217;s ongoing &#8212; something that&#8217;s a priority to the President, and that will be a priority in the national security team.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he view the $1 trillion in new spending as the lowest he is willing to go?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here, but certainly we look forward to the President having the discussion with Senator Capito tomorrow.&nbsp; And as a reminder, there are some other lever &#8212; or some other paths that are currently happening.&nbsp; We&#8217;re days away from the House marking up the American Jobs Plan.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something a lot of Democrats in Congress are pretty excited about, as you all know.&nbsp; And also, there are, as has been evidence in much of your reporting, Democrats and Republicans who have been working together to come up, perhaps, with their own proposal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re looking forward to seeing that as well.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to keep optionality on the table, and we&#8217;ll see how the conversation goes tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So he could potentially be open to going lower than $1 trillion in new spending?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you any new bottom lines from here, but I think it&#8217;s important to note that there are a range of options moving forward.&nbsp; And certainly, his approach and his priority is making a historic investment in infrastructure, creating millions of jobs, and seeing how we can do that as quickly as possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You noted that the markup is just a few days away.&nbsp; Does he see Monday as, kind of, the deadline for any major breakthroughs on where these talks are going?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to have conversations with Democrats and Republicans about what the path forward may look like.&nbsp; And certainly it&#8217;s an important &#8212; it&#8217;s an important moment in the timeline, of course, because there will be movement then.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen Speaker Pelosi talk about how she wants to move forward with infrastructure in June.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen Senator &#8212; Leader Schumer talk about how he wants to move forward with infrastructure in July.&nbsp; Those are some realities in the timeline.&nbsp; But the President is not &#8212; we&#8217;re not here to set new deadlines; we’re going to continue those conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, just checking.&nbsp; Because the Transportation Secretary did say on Sunday that they do view Monday as a deadline for any breakthroughs on these talks.&nbsp; So President Biden does not view Monday as a deadline?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to keep our options open to see what paths we can move forward on.&nbsp; And certainly, the President is not going to accept a deal that doesn&#8217;t help create millions of jobs and make a historic investment in our nation&#8217;s infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; My last question: Before he goes abroad on his trip next week, should we expect any ambassador nominations to come from the White House?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know yet, Kaitlan.&nbsp; We will see.&nbsp; I know that there&#8217;s an interest in that, and we hope to have more soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would note that one of the processes in the ambassadorial nomination process is that countries have to agree to these selections, and so sometimes that&#8217;s part of the timeline.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that holding this up (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a holdup.&nbsp; It’s just part of the process. &nbsp;So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Annie.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In general, when so much of Biden&#8217;s agenda includes long-term things that will take a while to bear fruit, even once they’re passed &#8212; infrastructure being at the top of that list &#8212; is the White House concerned that Congress is moving slower than a snail’s pace on everything from democracy reform, to a policing bill, to these endless infrastructure talks, and that it will get harder as you get closer to the midterms for you to tackle your priorities?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, that’s not our view.&nbsp; I would say, first, the American Rescue Plan passed at a pretty rapid speed.&nbsp; That&#8217;s typically faster than most pieces of legislation, as many of you know, moves through Congress.&nbsp; I mean, not that this is necessarily our model in terms of timeline, but the Affordable Care Act took a year to move through Congress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we certainly recognize that sausage-making is messy.&nbsp; It takes some time.&nbsp; The President has talked about wanting to sign a bill into law this summer, and there is certainly appetite and interest and a commitment to moving forward on infrastructure from Speaker Pelosi, as well as Leader Schumer.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say, as it relates to police reform, we certainly know that coming together &#8212; in order to get that across the finish line, there needs to be agreement from the negotiators about what the path forward looks like.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve said they&#8217;re making progress; they&#8217;ve been encouraged by the tone of the discussions.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a positive sign to us, and we&#8217;re going to continue to support those efforts as they move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess, just, the question is: You know, how are you going to show voters who are trying to decide if Biden was an effective President, beyond the falling virus numbers, that his approach is working?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Beyond falling virus numbers?&nbsp; Beyond getting a global pandemic under control?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) voters.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, Anne &#8212; you know, from polling and from what the American people care about and are focused on &#8212; getting the pandemic under control; ensuring that we&#8217;re saving tens of thousands, if not hundreds of thousands of lives; making sure that the majority &#8212; more than 70 percent of people in this country are vaccinated so that they can return to their normal lives, which means returning to their jobs, kids returning to school, seeing friends, going to concerts, returning to life pre-pandemic &#8212; that is the number one, two, three, four, five issue on everyone&#8217;s mind.&nbsp; That has been the President&#8217;s focus from day one and absolutely how he has spent the majority of his time to date.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other question on Israel.&nbsp; Gantz was here today and met with Jake Sullivan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; His plan was to ask for a billion dollars in emergency military aid.&nbsp; Is the U.S. expected to grant &#8212; to provide those funds?&nbsp; And if so, does it have any expectation that we would get cooperation from the Israelis on rebuilding Gaza if we did?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t &#8212; I knew we were going to do a readout of that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s come out yet &#8212; the readout of the call.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It came out and it didn’t mention anything about whether or not those requests would be granted.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check and see if there&#8217;s any update on that.&nbsp; It may be that we have to consider their requests.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not sure we&#8217;ll have a rapid response, but I will check with our team and see if we have any update.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Mara.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; In terms of the voting &#8212; the ballot bills that are being introduced around the country &#8212; the President spoke out pretty strongly in Tulsa about them &#8212; other than the Vice President, as you said, working with grassroots groups, if you don&#8217;t have the votes to stop these laws in the state legislatures, and you don&#8217;t have the votes to overturn the filibuster so you could pass H.R. 1 or the John Lewis Act, what can he do other than engender a public backlash to them?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, we don&#8217;t accept that &#8212; that that&#8217;s the case.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to press for Congress to move forward with legislation on voting rights.&nbsp; We know it&#8217;s not always a straight line and that sometimes it takes time. And there needs to be discussion and negotiation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And in states, it&#8217;s not just about engaging with community organizations; we&#8217;re also talking about working with the private sector, working with voting rights groups, strengthening and uplifting efforts on voting rights nationwide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is an across-the-board effort that&#8217;s not just focused federally, it&#8217;s also focused on states.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also focused on local and grassroots organizations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly, one of the President&#8217;s lessons from having been &#8212; done this for 50 years or more is that, you know, the engagement and the activism of the American people is often the driver of change.&nbsp; And so a part of this effort is certainly to engage with that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Even though some of these bills have already been signed into law or are about to be (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, laws sometimes are meant to be changed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I have a question about the cyberattacks.&nbsp; Is this something that he would talk to Putin about?&nbsp; Is it something he thinks that Russia has some responsibility for or could do something to stop?&nbsp; Or what &#8212; how does he &#8212; what is Putin&#8217;s &#8212; where does Putin fit into these ransomware attacks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, we expect it to be a topic of discussion at the summit that is happening in just less than two weeks.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s message will be that responsible states do not harbor ransomware criminals, and responsible countries must take decisive action against these ransomware networks.&nbsp; So that will be a part of the discussion when he sees him in less than two weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just have one more quick one, just to put infrastructure to bed.&nbsp; I understand it &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s to bed.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand if &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s like brushing its teeth or something.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He&#8217;s saying &#8212; he&#8217;s saying that for infrastructure, it&#8217;s not &#8212; he can &#8212; he has so many payfors it&#8217;s not necessary to raise the corporate tax, or just enforcement and the book minimum would take care of infrastructure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Does he believe that raising the corporate tax and raising the tax on people who make more than $400,000 is still necessary to fund his other proposals like the American Families Plan?&nbsp; Or is he &#8212; or is he &#8212; does he believe that maybe this is not necessary at all?&nbsp; I&#8217;m not talking about whether you&#8217;re for it or not; I&#8217;m asking you if he still feels that those hikes are necessary for his agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He wouldn&#8217;t have proposed them and put them in his budget if he didn&#8217;t think so.&nbsp; I mean, I think there&#8217;s a math ch- &#8212; not challenge &#8212; there&#8217;s a math problem here somewhere, you know, in that the President has come down in his proposal, and what &#8212; and as we&#8217;re negotiating with Republicans on an infrastructure package.&nbsp; As you noted, Mara, there&#8217;s a range of other ideas that he has put forward that he wants to get passed into law: Child Tax Credit, universal pre-K, et cetera.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also proposed ways to pay for it.<br>&nbsp;<br>So these are components that would help pay for his proposals in this negotiation.&nbsp; But, certainly, raising the corporate rate is something &#8212; going back to what the rate was in, you know, the early days of the George W. Bush administration &#8212; is certainly something that he feels &#8212; sees as a viable payfor for many of his bold ideas.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8220;Viable payfor&#8221; or necessary to pay for it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I think it&#8217;s important to take a step back and remember this is not about &#8212; these proposals were not standalone corporate tax increases. &nbsp;These proposals were an American Jobs Plan to make historic investment in our nation&#8217;s infrastructure. They were to level the playing field and make universal pre-K eligible &#8212; you know, kids across the country eligible.<br>&nbsp;<br>So he&#8217;s proposed a range of ways to pay for it.&nbsp; Those payfors can be moved around.&nbsp; And certainly raising the corporate rate is a &#8212; is an area he feels is a viable, good, positive, essential option.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, in light of the recent ransomware attack, what is the White House guidance to private companies, the private sector about paying ransom?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our guidance continues to be &#8212; from the FBI &#8212; that companies should not pay ransom because it incentivizes these attacks on other companies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, separately on the &#8212; on a fourth stimulus check idea that is supported by dozens of Democrats in Congress.&nbsp; I know, a month ago, you said, you know, stimulus checks aren&#8217;t free, and it&#8217;s really up to Congress to decide whether to move forward on that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering, at this point, does the President support that idea?&nbsp; Or does he believe that his American Jobs and Families Plan provide enough economic assistance that a fourth stimulus wouldn&#8217;t be necessary?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as he said at the time &#8212; as I said at the time, I should say when you asked this before: The President is certainly open to a range of ideas.&nbsp; There are some who are proposing an elimination of the SALT deduction.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think I said it the right way.<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are some who are proposing making the Child Tax Credit permanent.&nbsp; There are some who are proposing additional stimulus.&nbsp; He&#8217;s happy to hear from a range of ideas on what would be most effective and what&#8217;s most important to the economy moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>But he&#8217;s also proposed what he thinks is going to be the most effective for the short term, for putting people back to work, to getting through this pivotal period of time, and also to making us more competitive over the long term.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to clarify, the President does support an extension of the family Child Tax Credit that&#8217;s going to start taking effect next month, correct?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s in &#8212; in his American Families Plan, he&#8217;s proposed an extension of the Child Tax Credit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Does the choreography of the Europe trip, having these sit-downs with allies and NATO before Putin, is this meant to effectively project President Biden as a messenger of the West, not just the U.S., when he sits down with the Russian leader?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that his commitment to attend the G7 and NATO predated the scheduling of the summit, just factually, as you all know.&nbsp; But I would certainly say thematically that what you&#8217;ll see from the President, and him talk about on this trip, is his advocacy for democracy over autocracy &#8212; domestically, here in the United States, but certainly around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he&#8217;s always felt that we are stronger when we are working with our partners and our allies &#8212; many of them are in the G7 and in NATO &#8212; and certainly discussing issues as it relates to cyberthreats, the threat of climate change, or problematic behavior from some where we have disagreements &#8212; including Russia, including China &#8212; would certainly be a part of those engagements.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would it be fair to say that that theme you&#8217;re talking about, the democracy over autocracy, is that maybe his guiding theme through that whole week?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Stay tuned.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, Eugene.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President hasn&#8217;t nominated a &#8212; someone for the top Antitrust role at the DOJ yet.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the longest since before H.W. Bush.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering if there&#8217;s a hold-up there.&nbsp; And if so, what is it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of any particular hold-up.&nbsp; And certainly, he wants to select and nominate the right people for each of these important positions.&nbsp; We can check and see if there&#8217;s any update on the timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on H.R. 40 &#8212; President Biden was obviously in Tulsa there.&nbsp; I was also there talking to some activists, and they heard from the President and they’ve heard from this White House that he is supportive of a committee to study reparations, which is what H.R. 40 would do.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he hasn&#8217;t called for Congress to pass H.R. 40 or talked about his support for the bill specifically, so I&#8217;m just curious if he supports the bill as written that just went through (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he supports a number of components of the bill, including the funding and the proposal for a study, which he feels would be the next important step forward and something that he feels would be absolutely correct in addressing this moment in history &#8212; these moments in history.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But not H.R. 40 as it stands?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more of an assessment of the legislation.&nbsp; But he, of course, supports a study of reparations and feels that would be the best next step.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I know that you don&#8217;t want to relitigate what happened when Biden wasn&#8217;t in office and when those e-mails were sent.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Uh-oh. &nbsp;That&#8217;s a setup.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Probably not.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But has anyone from your team briefed the President of what was in those FOIA&#8217;ed Fauci e-mails?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of him being briefed on the publicly reported e-mails.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, given that there were some things that Fauci said privately that contracted &#8212; contrasted with what he said publicly &#8212; whether it was masks or whether or not someone who had the virus, you know, could have immunity, or<br>you know, other questions as well &#8212; I mean, does he still have confidence in his NIH director?&nbsp; Does this change anything at all &#8212; these e-mails?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, the President and the administration feel that Dr. Fauci has played an incredible role in getting the pandemic under control, being a voice to the public throughout the course of this pandemic.&nbsp; And, again, I would reiterate a lot of these emails are from 17 months ago or more, certainly predating this administration, but some time ago in &#8212; as we look to history.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more.&nbsp; This morning, on &#8220;Morning Joe,&#8221; Anthony Fauci said that one of the ways to get transparency from the Chinese on the origins of COVID-19 was to, quote, &#8220;don&#8217;t be accusatory.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Does the President feel that the initial investigation of the origin of the virus, including that WHO survey that your team had deep concerns over &#8212; was the problem with that that it was too accusatory?&nbsp; I mean, is that a problem that this administration is being accusatory?&nbsp; Or &#8212; I mean, is this a situation where, you know, &#8220;we&#8217;re just following the evidence where it leads&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think our primary objective here has been working with the international community &#8212; rejoining the WHO, working with the international community to unite in pressing the Chinese to be transparent, to provide the underlying data so other scientists can take a look at that data, and to participate in a constructive way in the second round of &#8212; the next round &#8212; or the next phase, I should say, of the WHO investigation.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we noted at the time when we announced our own internal next step here, our 90-day review, one of the things that was happening in the timeline was the Chinese conveying that that was not their inclination.&nbsp;<br>So, I can&#8217;t assess what the impacts are.&nbsp; I can tell you what our position is and what we&#8217;ve been pressing for on the international stage.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Just about the 90-day review.&nbsp; One thing that&#8217;s not clear is: How is it that the U.S. intelligence officials knew about the workers in Wuhan lab &#8212; that they knew about them getting sick back in 2019, and then, in February, the intelligence officials were saying that they still hadn’t ruled out the possibility that the virus came from the lab? &nbsp;But the inquiry didn’t happen until late May of this month, and I&#8217;m wondering what took the U.S. so long before it launched its &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s not actually an accurate depiction of the timeline.&nbsp; The President actually asked his intelligence community to look into &#8212; to do an internal assessment, which then was presented to him in an internal meeting back in March.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, but the official &#8212; the 90-day inquiry, the one you&#8217;re describing, but the full look at this hypothesis, that was not announced publicly &#8212; I mean, people were not aware of &#8212; until May 26.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He didn’t &#8212; he didn’t decide to launch it.&nbsp; The timeline here was: He asked the intelligence team to do an internal review, an internal assessment.&nbsp; When that was done several weeks ago, he asked it to be made public &#8212; to declassify that information.&nbsp; That goes through a process.&nbsp; Sometimes it takes a couple of weeks to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>When that assessment was done, we were presented with an option for a public statement, and the President decided we wanted to do a more extensive review and tap into our lab scientists and experts, our &#8212; more of our national security team to see what more we can uncover over the course of 90 days.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, maybe I wasn&#8217;t saying it &#8212; or maybe I was saying it too specific with the dates.&nbsp; But the question &#8212; the bigger question is: What took the U.S. so long to take it seriously, when there were reports about the possibility of this virus coming from there, you know, way, way (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We completely refute that argument or notion.&nbsp; Obviously, the President asked his intelligence team to do an internal assessment, which happens all the time.&nbsp; We rarely talk about that publicly.&nbsp; We obviously took the step to declassify that, and that&#8217;s something that he did early on in his administration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, great.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Sorry, Nancy.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t mean to skip you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, that’s fine.&nbsp; Come back to (inaudible) &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned that vaccination rates are slowing down?&nbsp; And with the National Month of Action, if you do not get to that 70 percent goal, what is your plan B?&nbsp; And is there a concern that you have to throw in some more incentives in there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;re not going to prejudge our outcome here on July 4th.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we launched the Month of Action and one of the reasons why we are working with every entity that can play a constructive role here.&nbsp; Free beer &#8212; that seems to be very appealing to the public, it seems, by headlines.&nbsp; Krispy Kreme Doughnuts.&nbsp; Getting into raffles for flights.&nbsp; And a range of incentives that states are implementing.&nbsp; Many of them did not come from us, obviously.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because we recognize that, at this stage &#8212; and we always knew that the rate of vaccination would slow down because we were at a period of time &#8212; we went through a period of time where there wasn&#8217;t enough supply for the demand, and then we got to a period of time where we had more supply than the demand.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we launched a $3 billion effort to do local engagements, working with community leader leaders, clergy, other trusted voices, doctors, pediatricians.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But now we&#8217;re at a one-month &#8212; it reminds me a little bit of political campaigns where you are knocking on doors, you&#8217;re making phone calls, you&#8217;re incentivizing &#8212; all legal, of course &#8212; ways to get people to the polls.&nbsp; This is: How can we get more shots in arms?&nbsp; And we’re &#8212; we&#8217;ve welcomed the engagement from a range of &#8212; range of entities in the private sector to do exactly that.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will also say, as of yesterday, about a dozen states had met their 70 percent or higher.&nbsp; And ultimately, this is going to be up to individuals to get shots in their arms.&nbsp; We can take every creative step we possibly can take.&nbsp; We also understand we don&#8217;t have 100 percent control here, but we&#8217;re going to do everything we can from the federal government to reach that goal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He did create this initiative with Shots in the Shops within barber shops across the country.&nbsp; How are you going to work with other, you know, I guess, communities, especially in the South, where there is a concern that those vaccination rates are going down?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you&#8217;re absolutely right that we are &#8212; and they&#8217;re going down in different parts of the country, which, again, we anticipated.&nbsp; But in communities and areas where we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; the lower numbers are actually primarily under 40, and they&#8217;re more among young people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, one of the ways we focused is on how we can reach and engage with the communities that don&#8217;t have the highest percentage rate.&nbsp; People over 65: there&#8217;s a huge percentage of people who have received their first and even second doses.&nbsp; And even over 40, it&#8217;s quite a high percentage.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, what we&#8217;ve learned from our data is that local engagement, working with trusted voices.&nbsp; Maybe it&#8217;s the primary care physician that somebody has been seeing for 20 years; maybe it&#8217;s local churches where they go every Sunday or they go more than once a week.&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re working at a very local level to do this, and also working through the private sector on, kind of, some of these engagements where it could incentivize some of the communities that have not &#8212; that don&#8217;t have as high of a percentage rate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question: Does the President have an idea of when things would be quote, unquote, “back to normal,” especially with these ramping up of vaccine efforts?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you know, we obviously are guided by CDC guidance.&nbsp; But what we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; and they&#8217;ve announced over the last several weeks &#8212; is that, you know, if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you don&#8217;t have to wear a mask inside, outside, you know, going into stores.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that in &#8212; around the country, as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;re already seeing a move toward “back to normal,” but it really depends on community to community.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the other guidance that we have been providing and emphasizing &#8212; because if a community has a vaccination rate of 80 percent, they are clearly in a different place than a community that has a vaccination rate of 55 percent.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s really going to be determinations made at a very local level about what is safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Nancy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just in terms of &#8212; back to the corporate tax rate for a second.&nbsp; If it’s something that the President is willing to, you know, drop out of a potential bipartisan infrastructure deal, does the White House see it fitting in as a payfor for the American Families Plan?&nbsp; Or where else could that be slotted in?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have no shortage of ideas around here, Nancy.&nbsp; I will note that, again, he&#8217;s put forward a range of ways to pay for his big, bold ideas, including raising the corporate tax rate.&nbsp; And there are a number of components of his ideas that are not in this infrastructure negotiation right now &#8212; and you&#8217;ve referenced many of them &#8212; in the American Families Plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to predetermine what all the aligning of items will be in the future because that obviously isn&#8217;t a package that&#8217;s a part of this specific negotiation.&nbsp; But, certainly, he thinks that raising the corporate rate, ensuring &#8212; asking corporations who have &#8212; many of whom have made a big profit during the pandemic &#8212; to pay a little bit more is a very viable way to pay for ideas moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more thing on the COVID vaccination distribution.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How does the White House expect to donate 80 million doses without AstraZeneca?&nbsp; Does that mean that the J&amp;J shot will definitely be part of the distribution?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, J&amp;J has been approved by the FDA, so it would be a part &#8212; those doses would be a part of what we&#8217;re distributing, along with Moderna and Pfizer, including in this initial set of 25 million.&nbsp; AstraZeneca, as you know, we&#8217;re waiting for FDA approval to &#8212; to even approve it to go overseas.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that certainly we could utilize those doses, and they would be a part of the doses of the 80 million.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead, Alex.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, just &#8212; we&#8217;re weeks and weeks into these infrastructure negotiations, and I&#8217;m curious, what does the White House think it has to show for it?&nbsp; What do you think &#8212; what progress would you point to?&nbsp; What would you point to to show that, you know, we’re closer to a deal than when this process began?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that it may feel foreign, but the process of policymaking and negotiating can be messy and can &#8212; the sausage-making isn&#8217;t always beautiful or pretty.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re in the middle of right now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President has pledged to the American people, when he ran for office, that he would work with Democrats and Republicans to try to get important initiatives forward on behalf of the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is an example of that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re having ongoing discussions with Republicans.&nbsp; We feel that those discussions have been done in good faith.&nbsp; The President is looking forward to talking to Senator Capito tomorrow.&nbsp; We also are eager to see what proposal may be put forward by Democrats and Republicans who are talking about what they might agree on.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are a range of paths forward here, and the President remains committed to his goal of signing a bill into law &#8212; historic investment infrastructure &#8212; by the summer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Remain in Mexico Policy has ended.&nbsp; Is it still your message to immigrants coming from Central America not to come &#8212; that the border is still closed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Our message is still: “This is a dangerous time to come.”&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been clear in our assessment that the MPP program &#8212; more commonly known as Remain in Mexico &#8212; was quite problematic.&nbsp; It led to dangerous and inhumane conditions along Mexico&#8217;s northern border, in part because of the camps and the conditions at the camps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s something the President talked about, or we&#8217;ve talked about, for some time.&nbsp; And Secretary Mayorkas and DHS determined that the program does not adequately or sustainably enhance border management either.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our message continues to be: “This is not the time to come.”&nbsp; We want to have an effective immigration system in place, including asylum processing at our border.&nbsp; And that has not changed, but the &#8212; ending the “Remain in Mexico” program is something we&#8217;ve long talked about our commitment to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Brittany, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President has tasked Vice President Harris with two contentious, if not at least very-difficult-to-wrap-your-head-around, time-consuming issues in American politics: you know, immigration, the Northern Triangle, and race (inaudible) voting rights.&nbsp; It’s not just National Space Council stuff that hasn&#8217;t kicked off yet.&nbsp; Broadband, dealing with labor unions.&nbsp; Should we expect any other major additions to Vice President Harris&#8217;s portfolio in the coming months &#8212; let me say, by the end of the year?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the President is confident that the Vice President is absolutely up to the task.&nbsp; He sees her as a partner and someone who he &#8212; is playing the role of a modern-day Vice President, which is taking on challenging tasks, tasks that won&#8217;t be easy.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s certainly something he felt he did as Vice President, and he is confident that Vice President Harris will do exactly the same thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, as you know, she&#8217;s traveling to the Northern Triangle next week.&nbsp; She&#8217;s just taken on this initiative, per her request, on voting rights.&nbsp; She&#8217;s going to be active on that in the weeks ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I can&#8217;t predict what&#8217;s going to come our way or what initiatives she&#8217;ll need to take on over the months ahead, but certainly, these are two big tasks that he&#8217;s confident in her ability to lead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you said earlier that Harris had asked to take on this issue of voting rights.&nbsp; Is that how she&#8217;s &#8212; her portfolio has been determined.&nbsp; Has she been the one advocating for herself for these other assignments?&nbsp; Or has it been (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Typically a discussion.&nbsp; They have regular lunches, and they discuss areas where they know there needs to be one of them at the helm.&nbsp; And certainly, this is an area where she expressed a direct interest in.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m going to have to just wrap it up shortly, but go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just quickly, a little update on the White House cat. Is that something that is still happening here?&nbsp; Our readers are asking us a lot, so I figured I have a right to ask.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I bet.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been joking, although maybe it might be true, that we&#8217;re waiting for a bad news day for that to come out.&nbsp; If you see a tail wagging coming out of the briefing room, you&#8217;ll know something bad is about to happen.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on the cat.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a lot of interest.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the symbolic importance of the President&#8217;s meeting with the Queen at Windsor Castle in the UK?&nbsp; And also, when he sits down with Boris Johnson &#8212; there&#8217;s also a long history of meetings between American presidents and British prime ministers, but will this one be different because the UK is no longer part of the European Union?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we continue to have a Special Relationship with the United Kingdom, and I&#8217;m certain we&#8217;ll have more to preview early next week about what the trip looks like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But there&#8217;s a range of issues of mutual interest.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about some of them in this briefing &#8212; from the future of economic growth in the world, to addressing the COVID pandemic, to security issues around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So they have a range of topics they can clearly discuss, and certainly it should be seen as significant that it&#8217;s the President&#8217;s first stop on a foreign trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And this is his first meeting with the Queen.&nbsp; Is that something he&#8217;s always looked forward to?&nbsp; Does he have any kind of relationship with her?&nbsp; Obviously the first time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Who among us wouldn&#8217;t want to meet the Queen?&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more personal to read out.&nbsp; I will check and see if he has met her in the past.&nbsp; I believe he has, but let me check on that to confirm for sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They issued, of course, a graceful invitation, which he certainly accepted.&nbsp; He&#8217;s looking forward to seeing her with Dr. Biden, as well, on &#8212; a couple days into his trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In Tulsa, the President talked about the American Jobs Plan and what it does for closing the racial wealth gap.&nbsp; Does he give a cast-iron guarantee that whatever these negotiations are with Republicans, that will remain intact, there&#8217;ll be no compromise on racial equity?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Racial equity and addressing racial equity is central to the President&#8217;s initiatives, his commitments to rebuilding our economy around the country, and certainly he&#8217;s not going to give up on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m sorry, I&#8217;ve got to wrap it up for another meeting.&nbsp; Apologize.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it fair to call it a 1.4 trillion-dollar plan? &nbsp;Because it’s a &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will allow you to do the math yourself.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>1:50 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Bilateral Meeting with French National Security Advisor Emmanuel Bonne</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-bilateral-meeting-with-french-national-security-advisor-emmanuel-bonne/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 21:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met in Washington with Emmanuel Bonne, National Security Advisor to the President of France, to exchange views on a range of shared global policy issues. They talked about the upcoming G7 leaders meeting and NATO Summit. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Bonne agreed to continue coordinating on global access to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met in Washington with Emmanuel Bonne, National Security Advisor to the President of France, to exchange views on a range of shared global policy issues. They talked about the upcoming G7 leaders meeting and NATO Summit. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Bonne agreed to continue coordinating on global access to COVID-19 vaccines and supporting negotiations to address the tax challenges arising from globalization. They discussed our work to strengthen and modernize NATO, as well as counter challenges associated with malicious cyber activity such as ransomware, and terrorism. In addition, they discussed Russia, China, Iran, and the Sahel.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/president-biden-announces-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 20:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles: Paloma Adams-Allen, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources, United States Agency for International Development Isobel Coleman, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Policy and Programming, United States Agency for International Development Grant Harris, Nominee&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Paloma Adams-Allen, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Isobel Coleman, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Policy and Programming, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Grant Harris, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Industry and Analysis, Department of Commerce</li><li>Neil MacBride, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of the Treasury</li><li>Caral Spangler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Army (Financial Management and Comptroller), Department of Defense</li><li>Julieta Valls Noyes, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees, and Migration, Department of State</li><li>David Weil, Nominee for Wage and Hour Administrator, Department of Labor</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Paloma Adams-Allen, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Paloma Adams-Allen joined the Inter-American Foundation (IAF), a US agency supporting community-led development in Latin America and the Caribbean, in April 2017 as president and chief executive officer. Prior to joining the IAF, Adams-Allen was Sr. Director for global private sector partnerships initiatives at the international NGO, Winrock International. Before that, she served as deputy assistant administrator for the United States Agency for International Development&#8217;s (USAID) Latin America and Caribbean (LAC) Bureau. From 2010 to 2014, Adams-Allen served as Senior Adviser, during which she led the LAC Bureau&#8217;s public-private partnerships for development practice. She also spent a decade at the Organization of American States (OAS) in several hemispheric development policy, programming, and leadership roles. Early in her career she did short stints at the international law firm Coudert Brothers, and the advocacy organization Caribbean-Central American Action. Adams-Allen, who was born in Jamaica, spent her childhood between rural Jamaica and rural New England in the U.S. She holds a bachelor&#8217;s degree in development studies and African American studies from Brown University, a master’s in international affairs from Johns Hopkins University&#8217;s School of Advanced International Studies, and a Juris Doctorate from Georgetown University Law Center. An avid runner and gardener, Adams-Allen lives in Washington, D.C., with her husband, their puppy, and two awesome daughters.</p>



<p><strong><u>Isobel Coleman, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Policy and Programming, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Ambassador Isobel Coleman is a foreign policy and global development expert with more than 25 years of experience working in government, the private sector and non-profits.&nbsp; Most recently, she served on the Biden Transition Team, leading the review of the U.S. Mission to the United Nations. From 2014-2017, she was the U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations for Management, Reform and Special Political Affairs.&nbsp; During that time, she represented the United States in the UN General Assembly on budgetary matters and in the UN Security Council on Africa and peacekeeping issues. From 2018-2020, she was the Chief Operating Officer of GiveDirectly, an international non-profit tackling poverty by providing unconditional cash transfers to the extreme poor.</p>



<p>Previously, Dr. Coleman spent more than a decade as a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations where she directed CFR’s Women and Foreign Policy program and wrote extensively about global development and the advantages of women’s empowerment. Her writings have appeared in many publications, including The Atlantic, Foreign Policy, Foreign Affairs, The New York Times and The Washington Post. She is the author and co-author of numerous books including Pathways to Freedom: Political and Economic Lessons from Democratic Transitions (Council on Foreign Relations, 2013), and Paradise Beneath Her Feet: How Women are Transforming the Middle East (Random House, 2010). She graduated from Princeton University and earned MPhil and DPhil degrees in International Relations from Oxford University, which she attended on a Marshall Scholarship. She started her career at McKinsey &amp; Co. in New York, becoming a partner in the firm’s financial institutions group.</p>



<p><strong><u>Grant Harris, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Industry and Analysis, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Grant T. Harris is CEO of Connect Frontier LLC, a consulting firm that advises companies on doing business in emerging and frontier markets globally. Harris teaches on strategy and political risk in emerging markets as an Adjunct Professor of Global Management at Kellogg School of Management, Northwestern University, and a Lecturer at Haas School of Business, University of California, Berkeley. From 2011-2015, Harris served as Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for African Affairs at the White House. In this role, he conceived of the historic U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit, which generated $37 billion in commitments to support trade, investment, and development across Africa. Harris also initiated President Obama’s Doing Business in Africa Campaign and launched the President’s Young African Leaders Initiative. Harris was later appointed by President Obama to serve as a Member of the United States Holocaust Memorial Council.</p>



<p>Previously, Harris served as Deputy Chief of Staff and Counselor to U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Susan Rice. Earlier, Harris was an attorney at the global law firm of Cleary Gottlieb Steen &amp; Hamilton LLP, where he focused on cross-border transactions in Latin America. Harris also served in the African Affairs Directorate at the White House under President Bill Clinton and in the U.S. Mission to the United Nations under Ambassador Richard Holbrooke. Harris holds a law degree from Yale Law School, a Master’s in Public Affairs, with Distinction, from Princeton University, and a B.A., summa cum laude, from the University of California, Berkeley. Harris grew up in California.</p>



<p><strong><u>Neil MacBride, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Neil H. MacBride is a currently a litigation partner in the law firm of Davis Polk &amp; Wardwell, where he serves as head of its Washington, DC office and as co-head of the Firm’s Government Investigations Practice.&nbsp; Before entering private practice, Mr. MacBride spent extensive time as a government official on law enforcement, national security, and financial enforcement matters.&nbsp; He served in the Obama-Biden Administration, first as an Associate Deputy Attorney General for criminal enforcement in the U.S. Department of Justice and then as the United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Virginia overseeing all criminal enforcement and civil litigation on behalf of the United States.&nbsp; Mr. MacBride earlier served as Chief Counsel to then-Senator Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the Senate Judiciary Committee and as a federal prosecutor in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia.&nbsp; Mr. MacBride also served on the Biden-Harris and the Obama-Biden Transition Teams.&nbsp; Earlier in his career, Mr. MacBride served as General Counsel to the Business Software Alliance and practiced law at the Washington, DC law firm of Verner, Liipfert, Bernhard, McPherson &amp; Hand.&nbsp; He began his public service career clerking for the Honorable Henry C. Morgan, Jr. in the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A native of Oneonta, New York, MacBride graduated from the University of Virginia School of Law and Houghton College.&nbsp; He lives in Northern Virginia with his wife Christina Jackson MacBride and their three children.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Caral Spangler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Army, Financial Management and Comptroller, Department of Defense&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<p>Caral E. Spangler retired from government service in September 2020 after 39 years with the Department of Defense, serving as a career member of the Senior Executive Service in every Military Service and the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller). She began her career as a summer hire in the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Navy (Financial Management and Comptroller) and advanced during postings with the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) and as a Legislative Fellow in the office of Congressman Norman Y. Mineta (D-CA).&nbsp; Promoted to an SES in 1997, she served as the Director of the Investment Directorate within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller); the Director of the Budget Coordination Division in the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Navy (Financial Management and Comptroller (FM&amp;C); the Deputy for Budget, Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Air Force (FM&amp;C); the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Army (FM&amp;C); and retired as the Assistant Deputy Commandant, Programs and Resources (USMC).&nbsp; In these capacities, she has had oversight of every aspect of programming, budgeting, accounting, finance, financial systems, program and cost analysis in the Department of Defense. She has also served in acting capacities as the Auditor General, Department of the Navy, and as the Assistant Secretary of the Army (FM&amp;C). She was the recipient of a Presidential Meritorious Rank Award in 2015.</p>



<p>While Ms. Spangler was born in Minnesota, she spent her formative years in the Deep South, and graduated from Michigan State University with a Bachelor of Science in Economics.  She has a Master’s Degree in Public Administration from the Maxwell School at Syracuse University.  Ms. Spangler currently lives in Virginia with her husband.</p>



<p><strong><u>Julieta Valls Noyes, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees, and Migration, Department of State</u></strong></p>



<p>Julieta Valls Noyes, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister, is Deputy Director of the Department of State’s Foreign Service Institute, and a former U.S. ambassador to the Republic of Croatia.&nbsp; She previously served as a Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs in the Department of State, Deputy Executive Secretary of the Department, and as Deputy Chief of Mission and Charge d’Affaires a.i. at the U.S. Embassy to the Holy See.&nbsp; She also was Deputy Director of the Department’s Operations Center, and Director of the Office of Multilateral and Global Affairs in the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor.&nbsp; Earlier, Noyes served as Deputy Director, Office of Policy Planning and Coordination, Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, as Political Section Chief, U.S. Embassy Panama City, and as Political Officer at U.S. Embassy Madrid.&nbsp; Noyes earned a B.A. from Wellesley College, and a Master’s from the Industrial College of the Armed Forces.&nbsp; She speaks Spanish, Italian, Portuguese and French.&nbsp; Noyes is a first-generation American whose parents entered the United States as refugees.</p>



<p><strong><u>David Weil, Nominee for Wage and Hour Administrator, Department of Labor</u></strong></p>



<p>David Weil is Dean and professor at The Heller School for Social Policy and Management at Brandeis University. Prior to joining the Heller School in August 2017, he served as Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division at the United States Department of Labor under President Obama from 2014 to 2017. Weil is an internationally recognized expert in employment and labor market policy along with regulation, transparency policy, and the impacts of industry restructuring on employment, work, and business performance.</p>



<p>Dean Weil has advised government agencies at the state and federal levels as well as international organizations on employment, labor, and workplace policies. He co-founded the Transparency Policy Project at the Harvard Kennedy School of Government that examines how information disclosure can be used to improve private and public decisions. He is the author of more than 125 articles and five books including The Fissured Workplace. He has received numerous awards including the Frances Perkins Intelligence and Courage Award (2019). He holds a Bachelor of Science degree from Cornell University and Masters and Ph.D. degrees in public policy from Harvard University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/03/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 19:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  11:10 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning and thank you for joining us.&#160; Today I will begin with an update both on our domestic and global efforts to defeat COVID-19.&#160; We have here with us National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who will join me in speaking about our next steps in our global&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference </p>



<p>11:10 A.M. EDT<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning and thank you for joining us.&nbsp; Today I will begin with an update both on our domestic and global efforts to defeat COVID-19.&nbsp; We have here with us National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who will join me in speaking about our next steps in our global COVID-19 response.&nbsp; Then, Dr. Walensky will give an update on the state of the pandemic, and Dr. Fauci will discuss the latest science.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll leave some time for Q&amp;A at the end.&nbsp;<br><br>On his first full day in office, President Biden released a comprehensive strategy to marshal a whole-of-government wartime effort to defeat the pandemic.&nbsp; We have spent each and every day of the last four and a half months executing against that strategy.&nbsp; And today I want to provide an update on the progress we are making: first, on our efforts to get Americans vaccinated as quickly, efficiently, and equitably as possible; and second, on our efforts to help combat the pandemic globally.&nbsp;<br><br>Here at home, we have built a best-in-class vaccination program.&nbsp; Already 63 percent of adult Americans have received at least one shot, and 52 percent of adult Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; Already 12 states have 70 percent of adults with at least one shot.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an important milestone.&nbsp; And 28 states and the District of Columbia have fully vaccinated 50 percent or more of their adult population.&nbsp; As a result, in communities and states across the country, the pandemic is in retreat.<br><br>Since the President took office on January 20th, cases are down over 90 percent and deaths are down over 85 percent.&nbsp; Our successful vaccination program isn&#8217;t just saving tens of thousands of lives.&nbsp; It&#8217;s letting tens of millions of Americans get back to living their lives.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s fair to say that we&#8217;re far ahead of where anyone thought we would be in our fight against the virus.&nbsp; And, importantly, we have secured enough vaccine supply for all Americans.&nbsp; This is a direct result to the President taking aggressive action, including through the use of the Defense Production Act, the DPA, to mobilize the full force of U.S. vaccine manufacturing and production.<br><br>Because of those actions and the success of U.S. vaccine manufacturers, we are confident in our supply of our authorized vaccines.&nbsp; As a result, we&#8217;re removing the DPA priority ratings for AstraZeneca, Novavax, and Sanofi.&nbsp; While the manufacturers will continue to make these three vaccines, this action will allow U.S.-based companies that supply these vaccine manufacturers to make their own decisions on which orders to fulfill first.&nbsp;<br><br>For all the progress we&#8217;ve made as a country, as the President reiterated yesterday afternoon, we have millions of Americans still in need of protection and communities at risk because of low vaccination rates.&nbsp;<br><br>Here&#8217;s the bottom line: The bottom line is that if you are unvaccinated, you are still at risk of getting seriously ill or spreading the disease to others.<br><br>To help get as many people vaccinated as we can by July 4th, we&#8217;re kicking off a month of action, mobilizing an all-of- America effort, including new commitments from childcare providers across the country to provide free drop-in childcare to allow parents to get vaccinated; extended hours of local pharmacies for vaccinations, including many pharmacies that will be open 24 hours every Friday starting next week; commitments from states in the private sector to incentivize vaccinations and celebrate our progress, including free beer for everyone over the age of 21, on July 4th, courtesy of Anheuser-Busch.<br><br>And the Vice President is leading a “We Can Do This” national vaccination tour.&nbsp; This national vaccination tour to key communities across the country will help reach millions of Americans who still need protection against the virus, highlight the ease of getting vaccinated, encourage vaccination, and energize and mobilize grassroots vaccine education and outreach efforts.<br>As the days get brighter and brighter at home, we&#8217;re focused on driving progress to help the pandemic &#8212; help end the pandemic around the globe.&nbsp; It&#8217;s both the right thing to do and an important step in protecting Americans by helping to stamp out the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has committed that the U.S. will be an arsenal for vaccines, and our work on vaccine supply is guided by a three-part approach:&nbsp;<br><br>First, having successfully secured enough supply of vaccine for Americans, we are donating surplus U.S. vaccine supply and encouraging other countries with surplus supplies to do the same.&nbsp; In March, the U.S. shared over 4 million doses of our AstraZeneca vaccine supply with Canada and Mexico.&nbsp; And the President has announced a U.S. commitment to sharing a total of 80 million doses by the end of June.&nbsp; This is five times the number of doses any other country has committed to sharing.&nbsp; And these 80 million doses represent 13 percent of the total vaccines produced by the United States by the end of this month.&nbsp;<br><br>We will continue to donate additional doses across the summer months as supply becomes available.&nbsp; But at the same time, we know that won&#8217;t be sufficient.&nbsp; So the second part of our approach is working with U.S. vaccine manufacturers to vastly increase vaccine supply for the rest of the world in a way that also creates jobs here at home.&nbsp; Driven by the aggressive actions that have been taken to accelerate manufacturing and production lines in the U.S., Pfizer and Moderna have already increased their capacity to produce vaccines for the world.&nbsp;<br><br>The third part of our approach will have us work with our partner nations and pharmaceutical companies and other manufacturers to facilitate the kind of global vaccine manufacturing and production capacity and capabilities that can not only help the world beat this pandemic, but also prepares the world to respond to potential future threats.&nbsp;<br><br>Today we&#8217;re outlining our framework for sharing with the world the first 25 million doses.&nbsp; To be clear, our approach is to ensure vaccines are delivered in a way that is equitable and follows the latest science and public health data.<br><br>Across the coming weeks, the administration will move as expeditiously as possible and work through regulatory requirements and logistical details to ensure safe and secure delivery of doses.<br><br>This is certainly a complex operational challenge but one that we take on and will get done.&nbsp; In fact, less than two weeks ago, the President committed to providing one million doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to the Republic of Korea.<br><br>After making a 2,000-mile journey to California, these one million doses are being loaded into a plane that will take off to the Republic of Korea this evening, carrying hope and bringing life-saving protection to the one million South Koreans who have already signed up to get a shot.&nbsp;<br><br>This is just the beginning.&nbsp; We expect a regular cadence of shipments around the world across the next several weeks.&nbsp; And in the weeks ahead, working with the world&#8217;s democracies, we will coordinate a multilateral effort, including through the G7, to combat and end the pandemic.<br><br>Now, let me turn it over to National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan.<br><br>Jake.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; As Jeff said, today we are announcing our plan for sharing the first 25 million U.S. vaccines with the world.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to briefly outline why we are sharing them, how we plan to share them, and where we will share them.<br><br>First, our goal in sharing our vaccines is in service of ending the pandemic globally.&nbsp; Our overarching aim is to get as many safe and effective vaccines to as many people as fast as possible.&nbsp; It&#8217;s as simple as that.&nbsp; We want to save lives and thwart variants that place all of us at risk.&nbsp; But perhaps most important: This is just the right thing to do.<br><br>Thanks to the ingenuity of American scientists and the resilience and commitment of the American people, we&#8217;re in a position to help others, so we will help others.&nbsp; And as the President has said, the United States will not use its vaccines to secure favors from other countries.<br><br>Next, I want to say a little bit about how we are sharing.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve received requests from all over the world, and a number of important factors went into our decision about how to allocate these first 25 million vaccines.&nbsp; These factors included achieving global coverage, responding to surges and other specific urgent situations and public health needs, and helping as many countries as possible who requested vaccines.<br><br>We&#8217;ve also decided to prioritize helping our neighbors.&nbsp; We made the decision to share at least 75 percent of these vaccines through COVAX.&nbsp; This will maximize the number of vaccines available equitably for all countries and will facilitate sharing with those most at risk.&nbsp; And we decided to share up to 25 percent of these vaccines for immediate needs and to help with surges around the world.&nbsp; We can share these 25 percent in a flexible way.<br><br>Finally, I want to talk a little bit about where we are sharing these first 25 million doses.&nbsp; We&#8217;re sharing them in a wide range of countries within Latin America and the Caribbean; South and Southeast Asia; and across Africa, in coordination with the African Union.&nbsp;<br><br>This includes prioritizing our neighbors here in our hemisphere, including countries like Guatemala and Colombia, Peru and Ecuador, and many others.&nbsp; It respects existing regional networks for vaccine sharing, like the platform of the African Union and African Centres for Disease Control and Prevention, and the regional public health agency in the Caribbean &#8212; CARPHA.&nbsp;<br><br>These networks will help decide where to allocate needed doses in regions with low vaccination rates and to those most at risk, including healthcare workers who haven&#8217;t yet gotten their shots.<br><br>Our approach also prioritizes South and Southeast Asia, including countries like India, Nepal, the Philippines, and others that are undergoing surges right now.&nbsp; It recognizes our closest neighbors, Canada and Mexico, which received our first shared vaccines; and friends like the Republic of Korea, where our military shares a command.&nbsp;&nbsp; And it prioritizes other partners around the world, including countries with low vaccination rates or dealing with urgent present crises, like the West Bank and Gaza, Ukraine, Kosovo, Iraq, Haiti, and others.<br><br>In the days ahead, we will coordinate closely with COVAX and with countries that will receive our vaccines.&nbsp; And as Jeff has said, this is only the beginning.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has committed to sharing doses on an ongoing basis, starting with 80 million by the end of June.&nbsp; We will continue to donate from our excess supply as that supply is delivered to us.&nbsp; We will work with our international partners to get ahead of the virus, to follow the science, and to help countries in crisis.&nbsp;<br><br>We also know that this won&#8217;t be enough to end or reduce the lifespan of the pandemic, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re working with allies and partners to expand the production of vaccines and raw materials, including here at home, as Jeff described, and by building capacity around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also working with our G7 partners on a larger effort to help end the pandemic so that the world&#8217;s democracies deliver for people everywhere.&nbsp; And we will have more to say about this next week when the G7 leaders meet in the UK.<br><br>We will continue to build on our existing health and health security efforts focused on stopping the spread of COVID-19: increasing vaccination, detecting outbreaks and variants, responding rapidly to flares, and critically recovering economically here at home and around the world.&nbsp; And we will do so in a way that strengthens our global public health institutions and our ability to come together as an international community to defeat not just this pandemic, but the next one and the one after that.<br><br>As President Biden said in May, this is a unique moment in history, and it requires American leadership, American science and ingenuity, American perseverance, and the world&#8217;s democracies to step up to the plate.&nbsp; Today, I&#8217;m proud to say that that effort is underway.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Now over to Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; It&#8217;s great to be back with you today.&nbsp; As always, let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.<br><br>Yesterday, CDC reported a little over 9,300 new cases of COVID-19. &nbsp;Our seven-day average is about 15,600 cases per day. &nbsp;This represents a decrease of more than 30 percent from our prior seven-day average. &nbsp;And, more importantly, it is a 94 percent decrease from the peak of COVID-19 cases we reported in January of this year. &nbsp;<br><br>This is the type of news I like to deliver and, certainly, these data are encouraging and uplifting as we battle this pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>In other good news, the seven-day average of new hospital admissions is about 2,750.&nbsp; That is a decrease of 83 percent in hospitalizations since January 9th of this year when we peaked at a seven-day average of almost 16,500 daily hospital admissions.<br><br>We can all agree these trends are going in the right direction.&nbsp;<br><br>And, finally, the seven-day average of daily deaths has also declined to a new low of 363 per day &#8212; a decrease of more than 16 percent from the last week.&nbsp;<br><br>As the administration kicks off its national month of action in the critical month of June, I want to highlight a specific population that we were hoping will join the tens of millions who have already been vaccinated, and that is adolescents.&nbsp;<br><br>In the month leading up to the recommendations of the Pfizer COVID-19 vaccines for teens and adolescents 12 and older, CDC observed troubling data regarding the hospitalizations of adolescents with COVID-19.&nbsp; More concerning were the number of adolescents admitted to the hospital who required treatment in the intensive care unit with mechanical ventilation.&nbsp;<br><br>Tomorrow, we will publish a report on this topic with more details in CDC’s Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report.&nbsp; And it is these findings within this publication &#8212; one that demonstrates the level of severe disease, even among youth, that are preventable, that force us to redouble our motivation to get our adolescents and young adults vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Last month, FDA authorized and CDC recommended a safe and effective vaccine for COVID-19 that can be used in adolescents to prevent disease and hospitalization.&nbsp; I strongly encourage parents to get their teens vaccinated, as I did mine.&nbsp;<br><br>If parents have questions or concerns, please talk with your child&#8217;s healthcare provider, your local department of public health, or your local pharmacist.&nbsp; And, of course, until teens are fully vaccinated, they should continue to wear masks and take precautions when around others who are not vaccinated, to protect themselves, their friends, family, and community.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, thank you, and I&#8217;ll turn things over to Dr.&nbsp; Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to spend just a minute or so just updating you in the arena of selected COVID-19 therapeutics.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you can see the slide, but the first slide that said “Selected Therapeutics” is broken up into three major components &#8212; just to remind you that the work that has been done over the last many months to a year has been three separate approaches: one, to target the virus itself &#8212; and, as you could see, the number of interventions listed there.&nbsp; The other is to moderate an aberrant inflammatory response, moderating the host.&nbsp; And the other adjunctive therapies, such as anticoagulants.&nbsp;<br><br>If we can move to the next slide, which has the red circle around the third bullet, that&#8217;s what I want to bring to the attention of the audience, and that is monoclonal antibodies, two of which &#8212; the Regeneron combination and Eli Lilly combination &#8212; have already been approved for EUA.<br><br>I&#8217;ve highlighted in blue another additional antibody made by GSK and Vir.&nbsp; And if you go to the next slide, six days ago, in a preprint server, some very interesting and exciting data has been published.&nbsp; And that is: A randomized placebo-controlled phase three trial of non-hospitalized patients with mild to moderate COVID-19 who are at high risk for the progression of their disease &#8212; close to 600 people &#8212; a single 500 milligram dose of the monoclonal antibody, sotrovimab &#8212; again, by GSK and Vir &#8212; reduced the risk of hospitalization or death by 85 percent, compared with the placebo.&nbsp;<br><br>It is well-tolerated and there are no safety signals identified.&nbsp; And, importantly, in the test tube, this antibody retains activity against multiple variants.&nbsp; So, what we really have now are three options within the arena of monoclonal antibodies &#8212; something that&#8217;s important for physicians to know that there is an important option for treating people early to prevent them from going to the hospital.&nbsp;<br><br>This has been granted an EUA, so it&#8217;s available for use, and we encourage physicians to at least consider this possibility as part of your therapeutic armamentarium.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll stop there, and back to you, Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Wonderful.&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we now open it up for a few questions?&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re running very short on time, so we&#8217;ll just take a couple of questions.&nbsp; Please keep to one question and on topic.&nbsp;<br><br>First, Josh Wingrove of Bloomberg.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Can you say &#8212;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; (Inaudible) take questions.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me?&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; I can hear you, Josh.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Jeff, can you speak a little bit to which specific vaccines will be sent in the 25 million?&nbsp; I assume it&#8217;s safe to say that the AstraZeneca doses remain under review.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, I think we&#8217;re working on some technical issues, and hopefully we are able to open it up for questions soon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jeff, let me know if you can hear me, please.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; I was just wondering if you can say which vaccines in particular will be sent among the 25 million?&nbsp; I assume that the AstraZeneca doses remain under review and are not available.&nbsp; Have you decided, or sorted, which will be the 25 million?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good question, and thank you for the question.&nbsp; That is correct.&nbsp; The AstraZeneca doses &#8212; the 60 million AstraZeneca doses &#8212; are awaiting FDA concurrence.&nbsp; So, the 25 million will be comprised of the three approved &#8212; EUA-approved authorized vaccines &#8212; some combination of Johnson &amp; Johnson, Pfizer, and Moderna.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Kaitlan Collins, CNN.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Jeff.&nbsp; (Inaudible) as part of this partnership with COVAX, my question is: Does the U.S. still have a final say where the doses (inaudible) COVAX go?&nbsp; Or is it COVAX making that decision?<br><br>And then, just to follow: When will these 25 million be distributed?&nbsp; And are you still confident the remaining 55 will be out by the end of June?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, Jake, why don’t I hand it to you on the first COVAX question?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, whether the U.S. still has final say on where the vaccines go, Jeff? &nbsp;Is that &#8212; was that the question?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; The question on COVAX &#8212; do you want to handle that?&nbsp; And then, I’ll handle the second piece.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We may be having some audio issues here.&nbsp; But as I understand it, the question was whether the United States still has the final say as to where the doses go that are being shared through COVAX.&nbsp; And the answer is that the U.S., working with COVAX, has taken &#8212;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; I’m not hearing Jake.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN &#8212; COVAX has a list of countries &#8212; the doses that are allocated to each of those countries, and we, the United States, have made selections against that list in coordination with them so that we will retain the say in terms of where they go.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, in the case of the African Union &#8212; we are sharing with the African Union, who will ultimately make &#8212; be making the determinations about how to allocate within Africa.&nbsp; And in the case of the Caribbean, we’ll be working closely with CARPHA, the public health authority in the Caribbean, who will be making some of the key determinations for where the doses are allocated.<br><br>But ultimately, the United States will have the authority to say, “The doses are going here, as opposed to there.” &nbsp;But that will be done in very close consultation and partnership with COVAX and, crucially, according to COVAX’s formula, and then using the COVAX logistics capacity and delivery capacity to ensure that these doses actually translate into shots in arms that helps save people&#8217;s lives.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, on the second part of the question.&nbsp; We are already sharing (inaudible) &#8212; (audio technical difficulties) &#8212; with Korea.&nbsp; As I mentioned earlier, those doses are in flight now.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve announced plans to share about 13 percent of the vaccines produced for the U.S. by the end of June.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the most of any nation, and that&#8217;s the 80 million.&nbsp; So, over the coming weeks, we&#8217;ll work to get those doses to countries and get shots in arms as soon as possible.<br><br>As we do so, we&#8217;ll work through logistics, like medical agencies, coordinating to ensure safety and regulatory information to share supply teams to ensure that we have the necessary needles, syringes, and alcohol pads; transportation teams to ensure proper temperature storage, prevent breakage, and ensure the vaccine immediately clears customs.&nbsp; So the process to export the first 25 million is underway in coordination with foreign governments.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President has committed, as we talked about earlier, to sharing 80 million doses by the end of June, and we will deliver on the President&#8217;s commitment of 80 million doses by the end of June.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; And sorry for the technical challenges.&nbsp; Sheryl at New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks for taking my call.&nbsp; I wonder if you could be a little bit more specific about the 25 percent of the doses that you are reserving for, you know, immediate use &#8212; the flexible doses.&nbsp; Where are those doses going?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Over to Jake.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Technical difficulties persist.&nbsp; But the answer to the question of where the 25 percent of doses are going is: We will lay out, more specifically, the precise destination of those.&nbsp; The judgment we make about where those go is a combination of where there are specific urgent situations where partner countries are facing crises.&nbsp; And so, some examples of that include &#8212; a portion of those doses will go to India, which has, obviously, dealt with a surge, and we&#8217;ve seen the gripping images coming from that country.&nbsp; Some of them will go to the West Bank and Gaza, which has just, obviously, endured its own form of crisis over the course of the past month.&nbsp; And then there will be other destinations for the remaining doses, and we will lay that all out as those doses are prepared and then shipped.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; We’ll do one more question.&nbsp; To Zeke, at AP.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you all for (inaudible).&nbsp; Can you say where the doses are coming from?&nbsp; Are they coming from states’ inventory or the pool of federal supply right now (inaudible) manufacturers?&nbsp;<br><br>And then, for Jake: Can you explain how this is consistent with the President’s guidance that there would be “no strings attached” to these vaccines, that the U.S. is still maintaining ultimate say-so about where these doses go and reserving all of these (inaudible) bilateral, such as giving to allied troops rather than (inaudible).&nbsp; Why not just give it all to COVAX to be shared where it’s needed immediately?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, on the first question, the doses &#8212; the 25 million doses &#8212; are coming from the federal pool of supply.&nbsp; The doses that are at the states’ level, those states have ordered those doses and we&#8217;re working with those states to administer shots in arms so that the millions of Americans who are not getting vaccinated can get vaccinated as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>Jake, over to you.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, first and critically, the United States is not asking anything of any country to whom we&#8217;re giving doses.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not seeking to extract concessions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not extorting.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not imposing conditions, the way that other countries who are providing doses are doing.&nbsp; We are doing none of those things.&nbsp; These are doses that are being given &#8212; donated free and clear &#8212; to these countries for the sole purpose of improving the public health situation and helping end the pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>The Korea situation is unique.&nbsp; As the President said when President Moon visited, the animating purpose behind that is actually about the protection of American forces and the forces who serve alongside American forces: the Korean troops who are standing shoulder to shoulder with us in that country.&nbsp;<br><br>So it is a unique case and the kind of unique case for which we want to retain some flexibility, which is why we&#8217;re giving the majority &#8212; the 75 percent or more &#8212; of our doses through COVAX, but maintaining the capacity to allocate doses outside the COVAX formula as necessary.&nbsp; Korea is one case of that.&nbsp;<br><br>The West Bank and Gaza, as I mentioned, is another case where we&#8217;re not asking anything of the people of Gaza or the West Bank, but we feel that given what they are dealing with and the situation on the ground there, it is only right and proper and good for the United States to actually allocate some doses to that country.&nbsp; The same is true with some of the other allocations that we will make.&nbsp;<br><br>The President made a commitment to ensure that India received doses and giving them, not just an allocation under the regional portion of this, through COVAX, but an additional allocation from our discretionary portion was something that he wanted to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, the basic bottom line on this is that the United States is not doing this as some kind of back-and-forth deal, where we&#8217;re getting something for what we&#8217;re giving.&nbsp; We are giving these for a single purpose; it is the purpose of ending this pandemic.&nbsp; And we are doing so in a way consistent &#8212; we believe very strongly &#8212; with the public health requirements that will help hasten the end of the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we have time for one more question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, we&#8217;ll keep going.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s just go to Weijia from CBS.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; My question is actually for Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; As you watch this big push for vaccinations ahead of July 4th &#8212; and this morning on CBS you listed several reasons for why people may not be getting vaccinated yet &#8212; I&#8217;m wondering if you are making educated guesses or if you have any data and figures to show why some people are still holding out, especially in the South, where rates are relatively low.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Jeff, I think that Rochelle got kicked out by her computer.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, you know, I think the important thing is that all Americans have the opportunity to get vaccinated, and that means we need to make it even easier to get vaccinated; that we do answer people&#8217;s questions &#8212; people who have questions about the safety and effectiveness of the vaccine.&nbsp; And as we know, the vaccines &#8212; all three &#8212; are very effective and very safe, but we need to answer those questions.&nbsp;<br><br>The good news is confidence in the vaccines has grown across time, as people have neighbors and friends and faith leaders and doctors who have been vaccinated and advise them on their own decision.&nbsp; And the important thing here is that the most trusted messengers are local messengers, including doctors and faith leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>So we need to bring the vaccines to where people are and answer the questions that people have.&nbsp; And we are confident that more and more people will get vaccinated, leading up to the Fourth of July.&nbsp;<br><br>Should we try to do one more question, Kevin?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; I think we got to wrap up.&nbsp; But thank you, Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>11:43 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_3June2021_for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_3June2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Senior Advisor and Chief Spokesperson Symone Sanders on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Calls with Foreign Leaders on the Global Allocation Plan for the First 25 Million Doses of COVID-19 Vaccines</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-senior-advisor-and-chief-spokesperson-symone-sanders-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-calls-with-foreign-leaders-on-the-global-allocation-plan-for-the-first-25-million-doses-of-c/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala D. Harris spoke this morning to President Andres Manuel López Obrador of Mexico, President Alejandro Giammattei of Guatemala, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, and Prime Minister Keith Rowley, Chairman of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM). In four separate calls, the Vice President notified each of the leaders that the Biden-Harris Administration will begin&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala D. Harris spoke this morning to President Andres Manuel López Obrador of Mexico, President Alejandro Giammattei of Guatemala, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, and Prime Minister Keith Rowley, Chairman of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM). In four separate calls, the Vice President notified each of the leaders that the Biden-Harris Administration will begin sharing the first 25 million doses of COVID vaccines to their respective countries and others, as part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s framework for sharing at least 80 million vaccines globally by the end of June.<br><br>The Vice President reiterated that the Administration’s efforts are focused on achieving broad global coverage, responding to surges and other urgent situations and public health needs, and helping as many countries as possible who requested vaccines. The four leaders thanked the Vice President, and they agreed to continue working together to address COVID-19 and advance our mutual interests around the world.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-c/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC). I have determined that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC).<br><br>I have determined that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 of November 12, 2020 (Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), including the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the PRC and its involvement in military, intelligence, and security research and development programs, and weapons and related equipment production under the PRC&#8217;s Military-Civil Fusion strategy.  In addition, I find that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC and the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse, constitute unusual and extraordinary threats, which have their source in whole or substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and I hereby expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 to address those threats. <br><br>I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.<br>    </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">     Sincerely,<br><br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/03/executive-order-on-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.) (NEA), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.) (NEA), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code,</p>



<p>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, find that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 of November 12, 2020 (Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), including the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC) and its involvement in military, intelligence, and security research and development programs, and weapons and related equipment production under the PRC&#8217;s Military-Civil Fusion strategy. &nbsp;In addition, I find that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC and the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse constitute unusual and extraordinary threats, which have their source in whole or substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and I hereby expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 to address those threats.</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby order as follows:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">1.</span>  Sections 1 through 5 of Executive Order 13959, as amended by Executive Order 13974 of January 13, 2021 (Amending Executive Order 13959 &#8212; Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), are hereby replaced and superseded in their entirety to read as follows:</p>



<p>&#8220;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Section</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">1.</span> (a) The following activities by a United States person are prohibited: the purchase or sale of any publicly traded securities, or any publicly traded securities that are derivative of such securities or are designed to provide investment exposure to such securities, of any person listed in the Annex to this order or of any person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense:<br>          (i)   to operate or have operated in the defense and related materiel sector or the surveillance technology sector of the economy of the PRC; or<br>          (ii) to own or control, or to be owned or controlled by, directly or indirectly, a person who operates or has operated in any sector described in subsection (a)(i) of this section, or a person who is listed in the Annex to this order or who has otherwise been determined to be subject to the prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section.<br>     (b)  The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section shall take effect:<br>          (i)   beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 2, 2021, with respect to any person listed in the Annex to this order; <br>or<br>          (ii)  beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on the date that is 60 days after the date of the determination in subsection (a) of this section with respect to any person not listed in the Annex to this order.<br>     (c)  The purchase or sale of publicly traded securities described in subsection (a) of this section made solely to effect the divestment, in whole or in part, of such securities by a United States person is permitted prior to:<br>          (i)   12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 3, 2022, with respect to any person listed in the Annex to this order; or<br>          (ii)  12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on the date that is 365 days after the date of the determination in subsection (a) of this section with respect to any person not listed in the Annex to this order.<br>     (d)  The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or any license or permit granted before the date of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">2.</span>  (a)  Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>     (b)  Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">3.</span>  For the purposes of this order:<br>     (a)  the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;<br>     (b)  the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity;<br>     (c)  the term &#8220;publicly traded securities&#8221; includes any &#8220;security,&#8221; as defined in section 3(a)(10) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, Public Law 73–291 (as codified as amended at 15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(10)), denominated in any currency that trades on a securities exchange or through the method of trading that is commonly referred to as &#8220;over-the-counter,&#8221; in any jurisdiction; and<br>     (d)  the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">4.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.  The Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.  All executive departments and agencies (agencies) of the United States shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to carry out the provisions of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">5.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to submit recurring and final reports to the Congress on the national emergency declared in this order, consistent with section 401(c) of the NEA (50 U.S.C. 1641(c)) and section 204(c) of IEEPA (50 U.S.C. 1703(c)).</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">6.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense, is hereby authorized to determine that circumstances no longer warrant the application of the prohibitions in section 1(a) of this order with respect to a person listed in the Annex to this order, and to take necessary action to give effect to that determination.&#8221;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">2.</span>  The Annex to Executive Order 13959 is replaced and superseded in its entirety by the Annex to this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">3.</span>  Section 6 of Executive Order 13959 is amended to replace &#8220;Sec. 6.&#8221; with &#8220;Sec. 7.&#8221;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">4.</span>  Executive Order 13974 is hereby revoked in its entirety.  The Secretary of the Treasury and the heads of agencies shall take all necessary steps to rescind any orders or prohibitions issued prior to the date of this order implementing or enforcing Executive Order 13974 or the versions of sections 1 through 5 of Executive Order 13959 replaced and superseded by section 1 of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">5.</span>  (a)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>     (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>     (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>          (b)  This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>          (c)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">  <br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>   June 3, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><span style="text-decoration: underline">Annex</span><br>AERO ENGINE CORPORATION OF CHINA<br><br>AEROSPACE CH UAV CO., LTD<br><br>AEROSPACE COMMUNICATIONS HOLDINGS GROUP COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AEROSUN CORPORATION<br><br>ANHUI GREATWALL MILITARY INDUSTRY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIATION INDUSTRY CORPORATION OF CHINA, LTD.<br><br>AVIC AVIATION HIGH-TECHNOLOGY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC HEAVY MACHINERY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC JONHON OPTRONIC TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>AVIC SHENYANG AIRCRAFT COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC XI&#8217;AN AIRCRAFT INDUSTRY GROUP COMPANY LTD.<br><br>CHANGSHA JINGJIA MICROELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA ACADEMY OF LAUNCH VEHICLE TECHNOLOGY<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE SCIENCE AND INDUSTRY CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE TIMES ELECTRONICS CO., LTD<br><br>CHINA AVIONICS SYSTEMS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA COMMUNICATIONS CONSTRUCTION COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA COMMUNICATIONS CONSTRUCTION GROUP (LIMITED)<br><br>CHINA ELECTRONICS CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA ELECTRONICS TECHNOLOGY GROUP CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA GENERAL NUCLEAR POWER CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA MARINE INFORMATION ELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA MOBILE LIMITED<br><br>CHINA NATIONAL NUCLEAR CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA NATIONAL OFFSHORE OIL CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA NORTH INDUSTRIES GROUP CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA NUCLEAR ENGINEERING CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA RAILWAY CONSTRUCTION CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SATELLITE COMMUNICATIONS CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA SHIPBUILDING INDUSTRY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SHIPBUILDING INDUSTRY GROUP POWER COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SOUTH INDUSTRIES GROUP CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA SPACESAT CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA STATE SHIPBUILDING CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA TELECOM CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA TELECOMMUNICATIONS CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA UNICOM (HONG KONG) LIMITED<br><br>CHINA UNITED NETWORK COMMUNICATIONS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CNOOC LIMITED<br><br>COSTAR GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CSSC OFFSHORE &amp; MARINE ENGINEERING (GROUP) COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>FUJIAN TORCH ELECTRON TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>GUIZHOU SPACE APPLIANCE CO., LTD<br><br>HANGZHOU HIKVISION DIGITAL TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>HUAWEI INVESTMENT &amp; HOLDING CO., LTD.<br><br>HUAWEI TECHNOLOGIES CO., LTD.<br><br>INNER MONGOLIA FIRST MACHINERY GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>INSPUR GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>JIANGXI HONGDU AVIATION INDUSTRY CO., LTD.<br><br>NANJING PANDA ELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>NORTH NAVIGATION CONTROL TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>PANDA ELECTRONICS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>PROVEN GLORY CAPITAL LIMITED<br><br>PROVEN HONOUR CAPITAL LIMITED<br><br>SEMICONDUCTOR MANUFACTURING INTERNATIONAL CORPORATION<br><br>SHAANXI ZHONGTIAN ROCKET TECHNOLOGY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>ZHONGHANG ELECTRONIC MEASURING INSTRUMENTS COMPANY LIMITED</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People’s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-executive-order-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 17:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in E.O. 13959 of November 12, 2020 with respect to the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China (PRC). President Biden also expanded the scope of this national emergency by finding that the use&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in E.O. 13959 of November 12, 2020 with respect to the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China (PRC). President Biden also expanded the scope of this national emergency by finding that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC, as well as the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuses, constitute unusual and extraordinary threats. This E.O. allows the United States to prohibit – in a targeted and scoped manner – U.S. investments in Chinese companies that undermine the security or democratic values of the United States and our allies.<br><br>Specifically, the E.O. the President is signing today will:<br><br><strong>Solidify and strengthen a previous E.O to prohibit U.S. investments in the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China:&nbsp;</strong>This E.O. will amend E.O. 13959 by creating a sustainable and strengthened framework for imposing prohibitions on investments in Chinese defense and surveillance technology firms. The E.O. prohibits United States persons from engaging in the purchase or sale of any publicly traded securities of any person listed in the Annex to the E.O. or determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense:</p>



<ul><li>To operate or have operated in the defense and related materiel sector or the surveillance technology sector of the economy of the PRC; or</li><li>To own or control, or to be owned or controlled by, directly or indirectly, a person who operates or has operated in any sector described above, or a person who is listed in the Annex to this E.O. or who has otherwise been determined to be subject to the prohibitions in this E.O.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensure that U.S. investments are not supporting Chinese companies that undermine the security or values of the United States and our allies</strong>: This E.O. prevents U.S. investment from supporting the Chinese defense sector, while also expanding the U.S. Government’s ability to address the threat of Chinese surveillance technology firms that contribute — both inside and outside China — to the surveillance of religious or ethnic minorities or otherwise facilitate repression and serious human rights abuses. It signals that the Administration will not hesitate to prevent U.S. capital from flowing into the PRC’s defense and related materiel sector, including companies that support the PRC’s military, intelligence, and other security research and development programs; or into Chinese companies that develop or use Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse.&nbsp; Tackling these challenges head-on is consistent with the Biden Administration’s commitment to protecting core U.S. national security interests and democratic values, and the Administration will continue to update the list of PRC entities as appropriate.&nbsp; At the same time, the E.O.’s prohibitions are intentionally targeted and scoped.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>The President listed the following 59 entities as subject to the E.O.’s prohibitions. </strong>The prohibitions against the entities listed in the Annex to this E.O. shall take effect beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 2, 2021. The U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will also list these 59 entities on its new Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List (NS-CMIC List).<br><br><strong><em><u>Defense and Related Materiel Sector of the Economy of the PRC</u></em></strong><strong><em>:</em></strong><br>Aero Engine Corporation of China; Aerospace CH UAV Co., Ltd; Aerospace Communications Holdings Group Company Limited; Aerosun Corporation; Anhui Greatwall Military Industry Company Limited; Aviation Industry Corporation of China, Ltd.; AVIC Aviation High-Technology Company Limited; AVIC Heavy Machinery Company Limited; AVIC Jonhon Optronic Technology Co., Ltd.; AVIC Shenyang Aircraft Company Limited; AVIC Xi’An Aircraft Industry Group Company Ltd.; Changsha Jingjia Microelectronics Company Limited China Academy of Launch Vehicle Technology; China Aerospace Science and Industry Corporation Limited; China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation; China Aerospace Times Electronics Co., Ltd; China Avionics Systems Company Limited; China Communications Construction Company Limited; China Electronics Technology Group Corporation; China General Nuclear Power Corporation; China Marine Information Electronics Company Limited; China Mobile Communications Group Co., Ltd.; China National Nuclear Corporation; China National Offshore Oil Corporation; China North Industries Group Corporation Limited; China Nuclear Engineering Corporation Limited; China Railway Construction Corporation Limited; China Satellite Communications Co., Ltd.; China Shipbuilding Industry Company Limited; China Shipbuilding Industry Group Power Company Limited; China South Industries Group Corporation; China Spacesat Co., Ltd.; China State Shipbuilding Corporation Limited; China Telecommunications Corporation; China United Network Communications Group Co., Ltd.; Costar Group Co., Ltd.; CSSC Offshore &amp; Marine Engineering (Group) Company Limited; Fujian Torch Electron Technology Co., Ltd.; Guizhou Space Appliance Co., Ltd; Hangzhou Hikvision Digital Technology Co., Ltd.; Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd.; Inner Mongolia First Machinery Group Co., Ltd.; Inspur Group Co., Ltd.; Jiangxi Hongdu Aviation Industry Co., Ltd.; Nanjing Panda Electronics Company Limited; North Navigation Control Technology Co., Ltd.; Panda Electronics Group Co., Ltd.; Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corporation; Shaanxi Zhongtian Rocket Technology Company Limited; and Zhonghang Electronic Measuring Instruments Company Limited.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><em><u>Surveillance Technology Sector of the Economy of the PRC</u></em></strong><strong><em>:</em></strong><br>Hangzhou Hikvision Digital Technology Co., Ltd. and Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd.<br><br><strong><em><u>Own or Control, or Owned or Controlled by, Directly or Indirectly, a Person Who Operates or Has Operated in at Least One of These Two Sectors of the PRC Economy, or a Person Who Is Listed in the Annex to the E.O.:</u></em></strong><br>China Communications Construction Group (Limited); China Electronics Corporation; China Mobile Limited; China Telecom Corporation Limited; China Unicom (Hong Kong) Limited; CNOOC Limited; Huawei Investment &amp; Holding Co., Ltd.; Panda Electronics Group Co., Ltd.; Proven Glory Capital Limited; and Proven Honour Capital Limited.<br><br>For information concerning the process for seeking removal from any OFAC list, including the NS-CMIC List, please refer to OFAC’s Frequently Asked Question 897 at <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/faqs/897">https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/faqs/897</a>.&nbsp; Additional information regarding sanctions programs administered by OFAC can be found at <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/sanctions-programs-and-country-information">https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/sanctions-programs-and-country-information</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin Gantz</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-israeli-minister-of-defense-benjamin-gantz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin “Benny” Gantz to discuss recent developments in the region and continue the consultations between the United States and Israel on regional security issues. Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s right to defend itself and commitment to strengthening all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin “Benny” Gantz to discuss recent developments in the region and continue the consultations between the United States and Israel on regional security issues. Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s right to defend itself and commitment to strengthening all aspects of the U.S.-Israel security partnership, including support for the Iron Dome System. They exchanged views on the current situation in Gaza and Mr. Sullivan highlighted the importance of ensuring that immediate humanitarian aid is able to reach the people of Gaza. They also discussed their common interest in steps to enhance stability, peace, and security not just for Israelis and Palestinians, but across the entire region. They shared their concerns about the threat posed by Iran’s aggressive behavior in the Middle East and expressed their determination to counter these threats. They agreed that the United States and Israel would remain closely engaged in the weeks ahead to advance their strategic priorities in the region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
