<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 19:07:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on the President&#8217;s Actions to Tackle the Climate&#160;Crisis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/20/background-press-call-on-the-presidents-actions-to-tackle-the-climate-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 19:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:01 A.M. EDT &#160;MR. HASAN:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Thanks for joining us today.&#160; This is Abdullah from the White House. Today, we&#8217;ll be holding a background briefing on the actions the President will announce while in Somerset, Massachusetts, to tackle the climate crisis and seize the opportunity of a clean energy future. As a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:01 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;MR. HASAN:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us today.&nbsp; This is Abdullah from the White House.<br><br>Today, we&#8217;ll be holding a background briefing on the actions the President will announce while in Somerset, Massachusetts, to tackle the climate crisis and seize the opportunity of a clean energy future.<br><br>As a reminder, the call will be on background, attributable to a senior administration official.&nbsp; It will be embargoed until the start of the President&#8217;s remarks in Somerset today.<br><br>Not for reporting purposes but for your awareness, joining us for the call today is [senior administration official].&nbsp; He will deliver some remarks up top, and then we will take your questions.<br><br>Over to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; And really, really excited for an opportunity to talk to you about what the President will be laying out this afternoon in Massachusetts.<br><br>As the President, I think, has said from day one, we really face an urgent crisis in the changing climate.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something that is becoming increasingly manifest across our country, whether it&#8217;s in the wildfires or hurricanes, the extreme flooding events, or &#8212; as is front of mind for the 100 million Americans who face different forms of heat advisories and warnings around the country right now &#8212; extreme heat, which it has shattered 90 records around the country, which is driving folks to face increasingly severe health ailments, putting people in the ER, and which drives home the point that this is a clear and present danger for our country, for our health, for our economy, for our national security.&nbsp; And it demands that we take action boldly.</p>



<p><br>In addition to that recognition that what we face is a challenge, what we face is urgent, what has already been unleashed in terms of climate is devastating &#8212; in addition to making that point, making it vividly and clearly, the President will also talk about the incredible opportunity that we have if we get our act together, square our shoulders, and take on the climate crisis.<br><br>And going to Massachusetts is a great opportunity for him to lay that out in a place that really represents the playbook for what it means to tackle the climate crisis in a way that can unlock tons of opportunity for our workers, for our communities, and for our economy.<br><br>Brayton Point, where the President will speak, used to be the site of the largest coal plant in New England &#8212; 1500 megawatts, burning coal since 1963.<br><br>The President will speak to how we&#8217;ve had these sources of energy that had been critical to our economy over time and that we&#8217;re seeing a transition to clean energy.&nbsp; And if we embrace that transition, then we&#8217;ll see what&#8217;s happening at Brayton Point happening all around the country.<br><br>Today, Brayton Point is poised to be on the frontier of the clean energy transformation.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be manufacturing subsea cables that will help tie offshore wind plants into the grid.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be the place where several wind projects actually tie in to the grid, bringing clean electrons into Massachusetts and into New England from where it&#8217;s being generated off the Atlantic coast.<br><br>So, you know, I think part of what the President wants to do this afternoon is lay out that sense of urgency and the clarity around the impacts that we&#8217;re already seeing, and also to lay out the urgency and the &#8212; and his enthusiasm for tapping into the opportunity that we also have in front of us.<br><br>The other thing that you can anticipate is specific actions underneath both of those things.<br><br>First, on heat, the President will be announcing $2.3 billion in funding through the FEMA Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities Program for fiscal year 2022.<br><br>This is a program that existed prior to this administration.&nbsp; But this is the largest amount of funding under BRIC ever in the history of the country.&nbsp; And not only is it large, it is focused on helping communities build resilience to a broad set of climate impacts, including heat waves, which is particularly salient; doing it in a way that is going to support the administration&#8217;s Justice40 Initiative and make sure that we&#8217;re lifting up communities that have been disadvantaged.<br><br>And then in addition to the announcement on BRIC, the President will be talking about new guidance from the Department of Health and Human Services, which will actually allow communities, acting through the states, of course, to leverage the historic funding that the President has delivered to the LIHEAP program.&nbsp; That is the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program.&nbsp; Used to be something that helped folks deal with heating issues in the wintertime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This administration is broadening that program out, calibrating it to this new climate reality.&nbsp; And with it, states will be able to establish cooling centers, they will be able to help folks buy or lend efficient air conditioning units, help defray the costs that are incurred to keep cool during the summer for these vulnerable populations.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s immediate. &nbsp;That&#8217;s an incredibly important thing to get out there.<br><br>And then on the opportunity side, I think many of you covered when the President brought together state and local leaders, industry leaders, and union leaders together at the White House this past month to launch the Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership.&nbsp; Building on that, the President is going to the Interior Department &#8212; direct the Interior Department to propose the first wind energy areas in the Gulf of Mexico.<br><br>For those keeping score at home &#8212; you know, when we came into office, offshore wind was facing a uncertain future.&nbsp; Not only did this administration approve the first commercial wind project, Vineyard Wind &#8212; which actually is a partner in building this facility at Brayton Point &#8212; but it also opened up these wind energy areas all across the Atlantic, as far south as North Carolina; started opening up wind energy areas on the Pacific; and today we open up yet another coast and frontier in expanding offshore wind.<br><br>And at the same time, the President is also directing the Secretary of Interior to advance wind energy development in the waters off the mid- and southern Atlantic coast and off Florida&#8217;s Gulf Coast, alleviating uncertainty cast by the prior administration.<br><br>So those are some of the actions the President will announce.&nbsp; And bottom line: You know, I think this is a &#8212; this is an opportunity for the President, in part also, to just come out and provide his take on where we are on climate &#8212; on the urgency, on the opportunity.&nbsp; And, of course, he had issued a written statement last week with regard to action in Congress.&nbsp; And this is an opportunity for him to also speak to that.<br><br>So with that, maybe, Abdullah, back to you.</p>



<p><br>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to go into questions now, but just before we do, I forgot to mention at the top, we will have embargoed materials coming around shortly.&nbsp; Sorry you didn’t get them ahead of the call, but they will be coming to you soon.<br><br>With that, we&#8217;ll go ahead and take some questions.&nbsp; If you would like to ask a question, please use the “raise hand” feature at the bottom of your screen.<br><br>Again, if you&#8217;d like to ask a question, please use the “raise hand” feature at the bottom of your screen.<br><br>And for the first question, we&#8217;ll go Coral Davenport.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing the call.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], in addition to making these announcements, is he going to talk about the regulations that are currently under development at EPA, give any kind of update, any kind of timeline on those?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, are we going to see anything else later in the week?&nbsp; Karine suggested yesterday that there could be more to come.&nbsp; She said no climate emergency this week, but it potentially is still on the table.&nbsp; Will we see that?&nbsp; And will we see &#8212; I mean, will we see any other &#8212; you know, any other executive authority or orders or anything else in this space later during this week?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I think the President is going to be very clear that since Congress is not going to act on this emergency, he will.&nbsp; He is going to state it loudly, he&#8217;s going to state it clearly &#8212; what he put in his written statement last week, and that is that as President, he will use his executive powers to combat the climate crisis in the absence of additional congressional action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think he will also lay out that, in the coming days, he expects his administration to begin to announce the executive actions that his administration has developed and is developing to combat this emergency.&nbsp; So I think you will hear that from him in his &#8212; in his own words.&nbsp; And hopefully, that&#8217;s responsive to part of your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the second bit: This administration, really, almost on a daily basis, from January 21st, has been advancing climate action.&nbsp; So if you&#8217;re asking me to forecast the rest of the week, yeah, we&#8217;re going to keep taking climate action every single day because that&#8217;s been part and parcel of this administration&#8217;s focus.&nbsp; This is one of the four crises the President defined when he was inaugurated.&nbsp; And that direction has been very clear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think what he &#8212; what he has expressed and what he will express this afternoon is about accelerating that action, heightening that ambition, and using the executive powers to combat the climate crisis in the absence of additional congressional action.</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And we’ll go to Ben (inaudible) next.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, good morning.&nbsp; Can you hear me okay?&nbsp; (Cat meows.)</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; We can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; One of our cats is joining, sorry.&nbsp; Anyway, I just &#8212; not to overly parse words, but, [senior administration official], you said a moment ago that the President is going to be very clear that “since Congress is not going to act on this emergency.”&nbsp; Does that mean that the President has concluded that there is no longer any option for a reconciliation package with these large clean energy incentives and investments?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, Ben, thanks.&nbsp; Thanks for &#8212; thanks for the question.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think we can hear the cats.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But &#8212; but, I’ll &#8212; you know, I&#8217;ll restate it: The President is going to lay out what he can do, what he intends to do.&nbsp; He has very specific executive powers.&nbsp; He has leveraged executive action to date.&nbsp; He has directed his administration to look at a broad set of options for how to accelerate those actions, to how to implement that &#8212; those executive powers with the highest ambition, and that&#8217;s his focus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the rest of your question &#8212; probably there are other folks who can who can answer that better.&nbsp; And, you know, our focus is on what we can do in light of where we find ourselves between the urgency of action and the clarity of opportunity that&#8217;s in front of us.</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; All right, thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; I actually do think we are at time now &#8212; 11:15.&nbsp; So, apologies if we weren&#8217;t able to get to your question.&nbsp; Please feel free to follow up with me via email.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, again, we&#8217;ll try to get you the materials as soon as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder, the call is embargoed until the President’s &#8212; the top of the President&#8217;s remarks.&nbsp; And it is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; Thanks for joining.</p>



<p>11:15 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Executive Actions on Climate to Address Extreme Heat and Boost Offshore&#160;Wind</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/20/fact-sheetpresident-bidens-executive-actions-on-climate-to-address-extreme-heat-and-boost-offshore-wind/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Actions to Accelerate Clean Energy, Create Jobs, and Lower Costs Today, President Biden will reiterate that climate change is a clear and present danger to the United States. Since Congress is not acting on this emergency, President Biden will. In the coming weeks, President Biden will announce additional executive actions to combat this emergency.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>New Actions to Accelerate Clean Energy, Create Jobs, and Lower Costs</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden will reiterate that climate change is a clear and present danger to the United States. Since Congress is not acting on this emergency, President Biden will. In the coming weeks, President Biden will announce additional executive actions to combat this emergency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing his latest set of executive actions to turn the climate crisis into an opportunity, by creating good-paying jobs in clean energy and lowering costs for families. His actions will protect communities from climate impacts already here, including extreme heat conditions impacting more than 100 million Americans this week, and expand offshore wind opportunities and jobs in the United States.</p>



<p>The President will make the announcements at a former coal-fired power plant in Brayton Point, Massachusetts that will host a cable manufacturing facility to support the flourishing offshore wind industry – representing how the President’s leadership is accelerating the nation’s transition away from the pollution, environmental injustice, and volatile price swings of the past toward the good-paying jobs and energy security of the future.</p>



<p>President Biden’s new executive actions will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect Communities from Extreme Heat and Dangerous Climate Impacts: </strong>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) is announcing $2.3 billion in funding for its Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) program for Fiscal Year 2022— the largest BRIC investment in history, boosted by the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. This funding will help communities increase resilience to heat waves, drought, wildfires, flood, hurricanes, and other hazards by preparing before disaster strikes. BRIC is among hundreds of federal programs that the Biden-Harris Administration is transforming to support the Justice40 Initiative and prioritize delivering benefits to disadvantaged communities.<br><br></li><li><strong>Lower Cooling Costs for Communities Suffering from Extreme Heat:</strong> Today, the Department of Health and Human Services is issuing <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/policy-guidance/liheap-im-2022-06-heat-stress-flexibilities-and-resources-fy2022">guidance</a> that for the first time expands how the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP) can promote the delivery of efficient air conditioning equipment, community cooling centers, and more. In April, the Biden-Harris Administration released $385 million through LIHEAP to help families with their household energy costs, including summer cooling—part of a record $8 billion that the Administration has provided, boosted by the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expand Offshore Wind Opportunities and Jobs:</strong> The Department of the Interior is proposing the first Wind Energy Areas in the Gulf of Mexico, a historic step toward expanding offshore wind opportunities to another region of the United States. These areas cover 700,000 acres and have the potential to power over three million homes. President Biden is also directing the Secretary of the Interior to advance wind energy development in the waters off the mid- and southern Atlantic Coast and Florida’s Gulf Coast —alleviating uncertainty cast by the prior Administration. These actions follow the President’s launch of a new <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-launches-new-federal-state-offshore-wind-partnership-to-grow-american-made-clean-energy/">Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership</a> that brought together Governors to deliver more clean, affordable energy and new jobs.<br><br></li></ul>



<p>Millions of Americans feel the effects of climate change each year when their roads wash out, power goes down, homes are destroyed by wildfires, or schools get flooded. Last year alone, the United States faced 20 extreme weather and climate related disaster events with losses exceeding $1 billion each – a cumulative price tag of more than $145 billion. People of color and underserved communities are disproportionately vulnerable to the climate crisis and are more likely to experience the negative health and environmental effects of climate-related and extreme weather events. Further, the country’s critical infrastructure is at risk from climate and extreme weather.</p>



<p>President Biden will not back down from addressing this emergency. Since taking office, he has <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/climate/">mobilized his entire Administration to tackle the climate crisis</a> and secured historic clean energy and climate resilience investments in his Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. He will continue taking bold action to secure a safe, healthy, clean energy future—all while saving families money, delivering clean air and water, advancing environmental justice, and boosting American manufacturing and competitiveness.</p>



<p><strong><u>PROTECTING COMMUNITIES FROM EXTREME HEAT</u></strong></p>



<p>This summer, millions of Americans are navigating the challenges and dangers that come with extreme heat advisories and record-breaking temperatures exceeding 100 degrees Fahrenheit. The climate crisis is making heat waves more intense and frequent, taking a toll on health across the country—sending tens of thousands of Americans to the emergency room, increasing risks of heart and respiratory problems, and especially endangering our workers, children, seniors, historically underserved and overburdened communities, and people with underlying health conditions.</p>



<p>To respond, last year the Biden-Harris Administration launched a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/20/fact-sheet-biden-administration-mobilizes-to-protect-workers-and-communities-from-extreme-heat/">broad set of new initiatives</a> to  advance workplace safety, build local resilience, and address the disproportionate impacts of extreme heat. Today, the Administration is announcing additional steps and progress on:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing Record Funding to Increase Community Resilience:</strong> Last year, President Biden doubled the funding available through FEMA’s Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) program. This year, he is doubling it again, to a historic level of $2.3 billion available for states, local communities, Tribes, and territories to proactively reduce their vulnerability to heat waves, drought, wildfires, flood, hurricanes, and other hazards boosted by the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. As part of the President’s Justice40 Initiative, which set a goal of delivering 40% of the overall benefits of Federal investments in climate and clean energy to disadvantaged communities, FEMA is prioritizing communities that have long been marginalized, overburdened, and underserved.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Access to Home Air Conditioners and Community Cooling Centers: </strong>In April, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) released $385 million through LIHEAP to <a>help families with their household energy costs, including summer cooling</a>—part of a record $8 billion that the Administration has provided, boosted by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, to reduce cooling and heating costs for low-income Americans. Today, HHS is issuing <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/policy-guidance/liheap-im-2022-06-heat-stress-flexibilities-and-resources-fy2022">guidance</a> that will help states, Tribes, and territories expand how they respond to extreme heat and support vulnerable communities through LIHEAP. The guidance provides for a range of flexible options including increasing funding for cooling assistance through the American Rescue Plan; establishing community cooling centers; and purchasing, distributing, or loaning efficient air conditioning equipment, evaporative coolers and electric heat pumps—a more energy-efficient alternative for providing cooling services—to vulnerable households and individuals. HHS has also developed a <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/liheap-and-extreme-heat">LIHEAP and Extreme Heat</a> website to provide online resources including the Heat Stress Geographic Information (GIS) Dashboard to help grant recipients and stakeholders track, visualize, and respond to heat stress trends and needs across the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Enforcing Workplace Safety: </strong>Heat is a growing threat to workplace safety, especially in high-risk sectors like agriculture and construction. In April, Vice President Harris and Secretary of Labor Walsh launched the first-ever National Emphasis Program to protect millions of workers from heat illness and injuries. Since then, the Department of Labor’s Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) has <strong>already conducted</strong> <strong>564 heat-related inspections, which are focused on over 70 high-risk industries across 43 states. </strong>On days when the heat index is 80°F or higher, OSHA inspectors and compliance assistance specialists are engaging in proactive outreach and technical assistance to help stakeholders keep workers safe on the job.<br><br></li></ul>



<p>Through the Extreme Heat Interagency Working Group under the National Climate Task Force, the Administration is advancing a wide range of additional efforts, including a <a href="https://www.osha.gov/heat-exposure/rulemaking">historic OSHA rulemaking process</a> toward the first federal heat standard to protect workers, EPA support for community <a href="https://www.epa.gov/innovation/lets-talk-about-heat-challenge">communication strategies</a> to help people keep safe on the hottest days, a DHS <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/science-and-technology/news/2022/07/05/dhs-prize-winners-announced-challenge-counter-extreme-temperatures">Cooling Solutions Challenge</a> to fund innovative extreme heat responses,&nbsp; NOAA’s community-led <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news-release/noaa-and-communities-to-map-heat-inequities-in-14-us-cities-and-counties">urban heat island mapping campaign</a>, a USDA <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/managing-land/urban-forests/ucf">urban and community forestry program</a> to equitably improve heat resilience, and a new <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/climate-change-health-equity-environmental-justice/climate-change-health-equity/climate-health-outlook/index.html">HHS Climate and Health Outlook</a> to inform health professionals about extreme heat and other climate-related health hazards.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>BOOSTING THE OFFSHORE WIND INDUSTRY AND CREATING JOBS</u></strong></p>



<p>Since President Biden set a bold goal of deploying 30 gigawatts of offshore wind by 2030, the Administration has approved the first large-scale projects and new wind energy areas, held record-breaking wind auctions, and issued an action plan to accelerate permitting. The private sector is following suit with investments to expand an American-made wind energy supply chain. In 2021 alone, investors announced $2.2 billion in new supply chain funding, including commitments to develop nine major manufacturing facilities to produce the foundations, towers, cables, and blades of offshore wind turbines. Historic project labor agreements are helping to grow a diverse union workforce, create good-paying jobs, and support training programs.</p>



<p>To further expand these opportunities, today President Biden is:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Kickstarting Potential for Offshore Wind in Gulf of Mexico:</strong> Today, the Department of the Interior is announcing draft Wind Energy Areas and an accompanying draft Environmental Assessment to consider potential offshore wind power in the Gulf of Mexico. The Administration will seek public input on two potential Wind Energy Areas—one off the coast of Galveston, Texas and another off the coast of Lake Charles, Louisiana. The area for review covers over 700,000 acres, with the potential to power over three million homes with clean energy. As with prior proposals, the Administration is committed to working in partnership with stakeholders to advance offshore wind development while protecting biodiversity and promoting ocean co-use.<br><br></li><li><strong>Promoting Offshore Wind Opportunities in the Southeast:</strong> The prior Administration cast uncertainty over the future of offshore wind and other clean energy development off the coasts of Florida, Georgia, South Carolina, and North Carolina. Today, President Biden is directing the Secretary of the Interior to advance clean energy development in these federal waters—ensuring that these southeast states will be able to benefit from good-paying jobs in the burgeoning offshore wind industry.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>These actions follow the President’s announcement last month of a new <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-launches-new-federal-state-offshore-wind-partnership-to-grow-american-made-clean-energy/">Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership</a>, joining with Governors to ensure that federal and state officials are working together to build a U.S.-based supply chain, including manufacturing and shipbuilding, for the rapidly-growing offshore wind industry. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Invests in Summer Learning and Enrichment Programs to Help Students Catch&#160;Up</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-invests-in-summer-learning-and-enrichment-programs-to-help-students-catch-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First Lady Jill Biden and U.S. Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona Embark on a Multi-State Summer Learning Tour  Summer learning and enrichment programs can play a critical role in student success. From providing students opportunities to catch up academically from what they may have missed during the pandemic to providing channels for students to engage with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>First Lady Jill Biden and U.S. Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona Embark on a Multi-State Summer Learning Tour </em></p>



<p>Summer learning and enrichment programs can play a critical role in student success. From providing students opportunities to catch up academically from what they may have missed during the pandemic to providing channels for students to engage with their peers, friends, and caring adults, summer programs across the country are helping students recover and thrive. President Biden has invested significantly in expanding summer programs for students and families across the nation, because he knows it is an essential ingredient in student recovery and success. Through President Biden’s American Rescue Plan (ARP), states and districts received $122 billion to help schools reopen and help students catch up academically and access mental health supports, including by increasing summer programming. As a result, all 50 states, Washington D.C. and Puerto Rico, are investing in summer learning and enrichment offerings, providing more opportunities for students – especially those disproportionately impacted by the pandemic – to benefit academically and socially from these programs.</p>



<p>Further elevating the importance of high-quality summer learning programs, President Biden has called on schools to use American Rescue plan funds to provide high-quality summer learning programs – as well as tutoring and afterschool programs – at the scale needed to support, on average, an additional four months of learning gains in reading and math.</p>



<p>Starting today, First Lady Jill Biden and Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona embark on a tour across the country to amplify that call and highlight how the Biden-Harris Administration is helping students catch up academically through summer learning programs supported by the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p><strong>Summer learning and enrichment programming is among the top strategies school districts are using to address missed instruction – and the American Rescue Plan is funding it.</strong></p>



<p>President Biden’s American Rescue Plan provided states and districts with $122 billion to help schools reopen and help students recover academically and access the mental health supports they need. States were also required to set aside over a billion dollars in funding to invest in summer programs, because summer is an important time for students to reengage with their peers and teachers, catch up academically from missed instruction, and get the social, emotional, and mental health supports they need.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Local school districts plan to spend $27 billion of American Rescue Plan funds on academic recovery. </strong>According to a June <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/financial-trends-in-local-schools-covid-aid-spending/">analysis</a> by Future Ed, school districts across the country plan to spend $27 billion on academic recovery, second only to investments in staffing to help students recover from the pandemic and thrive. The American Rescue Plan requires districts to spend 20% of their ARP Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief (ESSER) funds on academic recovery, but according to the analysis, districts are planning to spend more than the required percentage – at least 25% &#8211; to help more students catch up academically. Districts are also planning to spend an additional 23% of their ARP funds on staffing – which will play a critical role in helping students recover academically and access the supports they need.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Summer learning is among the top strategies school districts are using to provide additional academic instruction &nbsp;</strong>The Future Ed analysis also found that summer learning and afterschool programs make up nearly a quarter of the academic recovery investments. Its analysis projects that schools plan to spend over $6 billion of their ARP ESSER funds on these types of programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>First Lady Jill Biden and Secretary Cardona will highlight summer learning and enrichment programs in Connecticut, Michigan, and Georgia.</strong></p>



<p>Today, First Lady Jill Biden and Secretary Cardona kicked off a multi-state tour highlighting ARP-funded summer learning programs that are helping students catch up academically and providing them with mental health, social, and emotional supports they need to succeed. Together Connecticut, Michigan, and Georgia received $9 billion in ARP ESSER funds to support safe school reopening and recovery and are anticipated to spend at least $2 billion dollars on academic recovery, including through summer learning and afterschool programs.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Connecticut has received $1.1 billion in ARP ESSER funds, and the state and school districts are anticipated to spend at least $275 million dollars on state and local academic recovery efforts through September 2024. </strong>The Connecticut State Department of Education launched a Summer Enrichment Grant Program to provide up to $250,000 in funds each to dozens of grant recipients that are providing and expanding summer programs this year, particularly those serving students most impacted by the pandemic. Last summer, Connecticut awarded nearly $9 &nbsp;million to grant recipients for summer programming.</li></ul>



<p>Dr. Biden and Secretary Cardona will visit a&nbsp;Horizons National summer learning program,&nbsp;held at&nbsp;Albertus Magnus College in New Haven,&nbsp;CT,&nbsp;serving&nbsp;elementary&nbsp;students from local public schools. Horizons received a $157,500 ARP grant, which is allowing the organization to expand its programming across the New Haven region to serve 1,000 students.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Because of ARP ESSER funds, public schools in Detroit, MI have been able to double the number of students in summer school this year. </strong>Detroit, MI received over $800 million in ARP ESSER funds, and the state overall received over $3.7 billion in ARP ESSER funds. The state and school districts are anticipated to spend at least $925 million dollars on academic recovery, including through summer programming. Because of ARP ESSER, Detroit was able to expand its summer enrichment offerings and doubled the number of students in summer programs this year. As a result, 8,000 students are attending summer school this year.</li></ul>



<p>Dr. Biden and Secretary Cardona will visit a Detroit Public Schools Community District summer learning program, held at Schulze Academy for Technology and Arts in Detroit, MI, serving kindergarten through 8th grade students from the school district. ARP funding has enabled thousands more students in the district to access summer programming, with a focus on enrichment opportunities including STEM and STEAM programming, arts, coding and cooking.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Georgia is granting $40 million to over 100 organizations across the state operating summer and afterschool programs. </strong>Georgia received $4.2 billion in ARP ESSER funds, roughly $1 billion of which the state and school districts are anticipated to spend on academic recovery. As part of this effort, Georgia created the Building Opportunities in Out-of-School Time (BOOST) Grant program, where the state funds grants to community-based organizations that operate summer and afterschool programs. The goal of the program is to provide evidence-based programming focused on supporting students most impacted by the pandemic and helping them recover. Georgia is granting $40 million to approximately 100-120 organizations doing this critical work across the state, funded by ARP.</li></ul>



<p>Dr. Biden and Secretary Cardona will visit a Horizons National summer learning program,&nbsp;held at the&nbsp;University of Georgia&nbsp;in Athens, GA,&nbsp;serving students from Barnett Shoals Elementary School. Horizons received a BOOST Grant of $192,500 per year for three years starting this year to provide and expand programming to more Athens youth during the summer and year-round.</p>



<p>Dr. Biden and Secretary Cardona’s tour is part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s broader commitment to addressing lost instructional time and ensuring students have the mental health supports they need to recover and thrive. Earlier this month, the Administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/05/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-national-effort-to-support-student-success/">launched</a> a national strategy to help students recover academically, with the goal of mobilizing 250,000 tutors and mentors to support students’ academic needs across the country. Tutors, mentors, and other adults in high-impact roles will play a critical role this summer and during the school year in helping students recover academically and succeed in and out of the classroom. To sign up to volunteer, or get help expanding, launching or improving high-quality programs, visit <a href="https://www.partnershipstudentsuccess.org">www.partnershipstudentsuccess.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris to the 2022 U.S.-Africa Business&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/20/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-to-the-2022-u-s-africa-business-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Recorded Video As Prepared for Delivery Greetings from Washington, D.C. I want to thank the Corporate Council on Africa, the Kingdom of Morocco, and His Majesty King Mohammed for hosting the 2022 U.S.-Africa Business Summit. I am honored to participate in this opening ceremony. President Joe Biden and I recognize the critical importance of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Recorded Video</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">As Prepared for Delivery</p>



<p>Greetings from Washington, D.C. I want to thank the Corporate Council on Africa, the Kingdom of Morocco, and His Majesty King Mohammed for hosting the 2022 U.S.-Africa Business Summit. I am honored to participate in this opening ceremony.</p>



<p>President Joe Biden and I recognize the critical importance of strengthening our relationship with countries across Africa. To that end, I will start with some very important news. President Biden and I are looking forward to welcoming leaders from across the African continent to Washington, D.C. from December 13<sup>th</sup> through the 15th, for the United States-Africa Leaders Summit.</p>



<p>This Summit will demonstrate America’s enduring commitment to our African partners, and it will be based on principles of mutual respect and shared interests and values. And a critical part of this Summit will be to bolster our economic relationship, which brings me to the importance of this gathering of public and private sector leaders in Marrakech.</p>



<p>I believe in the power of public-private —partnerships that bring together the experience and the expertise of the private sector with the mission of government to act for the public good and with the public trust, and the reach and capacity that governments can give, uniquely, to any endeavor.</p>



<p>By working together, we can unleash growth and opportunity that far exceeds what either the public or private sector can achieve on its own. And, as everyone here knows, there is so much opportunity for economic growth &#8211;in Africa and, of course, the United States—when we all collaborate and coordinate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Africa is the world’s fastest-growing continent. By 2030, the continent will have 1.7 billion people, home to one-fifth of the world’s population. The continent is also increasingly young, urban and connected. There is a growing demand for food, healthcare, education, technology, and infrastructure.</p>



<p>Yet, barriers remain: limited access to capital, the high cost of financing, and legal and regulatory bottlenecks. This is on top of the global challenges that I know are felt acutely in Africa, including recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, and food insecurity.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to working with all of you to address these issues, in furtherance of  the African Union’s Agenda 2063.</p>



<p>With regard to food insecurity, we are focused on the urgent need to increase food production and exports with and within Africa, a challenge made worse by Putin’s war in Ukraine. To this end, since last October, the United States has pledged more than $7 billion in humanitarian and food security assistance across Africa.</p>



<p>More broadly, our Administration’s goal is to promote inclusive and sustainable economic growth and development across the continent, to expand capital flows, and to promote the vibrant spirit of entrepreneurship and innovation that is so prevalent across Africa.</p>



<p>I am pleased to see the advances made in implementing the African Continental Free Trade Area and we will work with you to ensure its success.</p>



<p>The United States is committed to bring to bear all the tools at our disposal, including, development financing, grants and technical assistance, and support for legal and regulatory reforms—all to help our African partners thrive.</p>



<p>As part of this, our signature investment initiative in Africa—Prosper Africa—has convened a delegation to be with you in Marrakech. Led by Millennium Challenge Corporation CEO Alice Albright, it includes officials from 10 U.S. government departments and agencies. It also includes a group of investors who collectively manage more than a trillion dollars in assets.</p>



<p>Over the coming days, our delegation will discuss with you a range of issues. This includes work to advance our new global infrastructure initiative, and our work to mobilize hundreds of billions of dollars for high-quality, sustainable infrastructure investment.</p>



<p>It also includes our effort to expand Power Africa, one of our largest public-private partnerships in the world—this work will increase access to electricity, support a just energy transition, and more.</p>



<p>This week’s convening is very important. When everyone is at the table, we are better able to collaborate, coordinate, and identify new opportunities. So, I wish you a productive Summit in Marrakech.</p>



<p>This work will benefit United States-African business ties and diplomatic ties. And most importantly, it will benefit both the people of Africa and the people of the United States.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications John&#160;Kirby</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/20/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-nsc-coordinator-for-strategic-communications-john-kirby-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:31 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello.&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Okay, so today we are joined by John Kirby, NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications.&#160; Kirby is here to share an update on Russia’s activities in Ukraine and answer a few questions.&#160; So, Kirby, the floor is yours. MR. KIRBY:&#160; Thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:31 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Okay, so today we are joined by John Kirby, NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications.&nbsp; Kirby is here to share an update on Russia’s activities in Ukraine and answer a few questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Kirby, the floor is yours.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; So I wanted to let you know that we have information today, including from downgraded intelligence that we’re able to share with you, about how Russia is laying the groundwork to annex Ukrainian territory that it controls, in direct violation of Ukraine’s sovereignty.</p>



<p>We’re seeing ample evidence in the intelligence and in the public domain that Russia intends to try to annex additional Ukrainian territory.&nbsp; Russia is beginning to roll out a version of what you could call an “annexation playbook,” very similar to the one we saw in 2014.</p>



<p>Already, Russia is installing illegitimate proxy officials in areas of Ukraine that are under its control.&nbsp; And we know their next moves.&nbsp; First, these proxy officials will arrange sham referenda on joining Russia.&nbsp; Then, Russia will use those sham referenda as a basis to try to claim annexation of sovereign Ukrainian territory.</p>



<p>The Russian government is reviewing detailed plans to purportedly annex a number of regions in Ukraine, including Kherson,<strong> </strong>Zaporizhzhia, all of Donetsk and Luhansk Oblasts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia is attempting to set the conditions on the ground by seeking to establish branches of Russian banks, to establish the ruble as the default currency in these areas, and to sabotage civilian Internet access.</p>



<p>Russia’s security services continue to target Ukrainians that they believe to be associated with resistance activities.&nbsp; In Kherson, for example, Russia is taking control of broadcasting towers, establishing loyalist security forces, replacing telecommunications infrastructure, forcing residents to apply for Russian citizenship, and issuing Russian passports.</p>



<p>Russia is also installing loyalists in areas of Ukraine that it controls, including a man named Sergei Yeliseyev, a former Russian intelligence officer who has been put in charge of Kherson.&nbsp; Figures like Yeliseyev are Russian bureaucrats with absolutely no connection to Ukraine.&nbsp; No connection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Kremlin has not disclosed the timeline for the referenda, but Russian proxies in these territories claim they will take place later this year, possibly in conjunction with Russia’s September regional elections.</p>



<p>So what are the implications?&nbsp; At the start of the year, Russia told the world that it was not planning to invade Ukraine, and now we’re expected to believe that they&#8217;re not going to plan to annex Ukrainian territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Annexation by force would be a gross violation of the U.N. Charter, and we will not allow it to go unchallenged or unpunished.</p>



<p>We will continue to provide Ukraine with historic levels of security assistance.</p>



<p>Later this week, the administration will announce the next Presidential Drawdown package of weapons and equipment for Ukraine.  It’ll be the 16th such drawdown to support Ukraine since the President took office.</p>



<p>That package will include more HIMARS &#8212; that’s Highly Mobile <s>Advanced</s> [Artillery] Rocket Systems &#8212; which the Ukrainians have been using very effectively to make a difference on the battlefield.&nbsp; And it’ll also include some additional rounds of Multiple Launch Rocket Systems and artillery ammunition.</p>



<p>We’re also going to continue to expose Russian plans so the world knows that any purported annexation is premeditated, illegal, and illegitimate.&nbsp; And we are sanctioning the Russia-installed puppets and proxies in areas of Ukraine that are under Russian control.&nbsp; For example, just last month, we sanctioned the illegitimate Russian-installed mayor of Melitopol, as well as the chairperson and deputy chairpersons of the so-called government of the DNR.</p>



<p>So what next?&nbsp; If Russia nevertheless proceeds with their annexation plans, we are going to respond swiftly and severely and in lockstep with our allies and partners.</p>



<p>Russia will face additional sanctions and become even more of a global pariah than it is now.&nbsp; We will never recognize any purportedly annexed territory as belonging to Russia.&nbsp; We will support accountability efforts for forced deportations, prosecutions of oppositionists, and other gross human rights abuses carried out by Russia.</p>



<p>And we would remind Mr. Putin that, over time, it may prove unable to hold this territory.&nbsp; It’s not a given.&nbsp; The Ukrainian territo- &#8212; the Ukrainian military will work to retake that territory, and the Ukrainian people will resist Russian control and seek to drive Russia out as they have been doing the last five months.</p>



<p>Russia already made a grave mistake with this invasion.&nbsp; It’s achieved none of their strategic objectives.&nbsp; When they invaded Ukraine, only 4 of the 192 other members of the U.N. took Moscow’s side.&nbsp; So the international community, we’re convinced, will continue to stand up for state sovereignty.&nbsp; Any sham efforts to legitimize an illegal land grab will only make things worse for Russia.&nbsp; And we’re going to help make sure of that.</p>



<p>And one other item before I start taking some questions: Today we announced a series of actions the Biden-Harris administration has taken to expand the toolkit that the U.S. government uses to deter and disrupt hostage takings and wrongful detentions &#8212; I think you may have seen this out there &#8212; that&#8217;ll help bring Americans home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This morning, the President signed an executive order that provides expanded tools to help bring our citizens home.&nbsp; Specifically, it authorizes agencies to impose costs and consequences, including financial sanctions and visa bans on governments and non-state actors and those that provide them with the material support who are involved in hostage takings or wrongful detentions.</p>



<p>The State Department is also introducing a new risk indicator to their travel advisories to inform U.S. citizens about the risk of wrongful detention by a foreign government in six countries that have regularly engaged in this practice.&nbsp; This new indicator joins the existing “K” indicator.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s a “D” indicator, the new one.&nbsp; The “K” indicator, that in- &#8212; that covers the risk of kidnapping and hostage taking by non-state actors, as well as a range of other existing risk indicators for a country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These actions demonstrate President Biden&#8217;s unwavering commitment to bringing home U.S. nationals held hostage and wrongfully detained, and to try to help prevent more Americans and their families from having to go through this kind of terrible ordeal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So with that, I’ll take questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, John.&nbsp; Given what you&#8217;ve said about Russians anne- &#8212; Russia&#8217;s annexation plans, what is the U.S. assessment of President Putin&#8217;s visit to Iran and why he was willing to take such an unusual and risky trip at this time to meet with the Supreme Leader?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll let Mr. Putin speak for why he decided to go at this particular time.&nbsp; But I would say three things about this trip:</p>



<p>One, it shows the degree to which Mr. Putin and Russia are increasingly isolated.&nbsp; Now they have to turn to Iran for help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Two, it shows the degree to which his own defense industrial base is having a hard time keeping up with his unprovoked war in Ukraine.&nbsp; We already know that in respect to precision-guided munitions and advanced systems, tanks, even aircraft, he&#8217;s having trouble &#8212; particularly with the micro-electronics &#8212; because of the sanctions and the export controls.&nbsp; And we already know that even without that, his defense industrial base is challenged because of the rate of operation, the pace of operations in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then the third thing I think this indicates is the degree to which he has absolutely no intention of stopping the war and sitting down in good faith and negotiate a settlement with Mr. Zelenskyy.&nbsp; He has every intention quite the contrary, because now he wants to go buy several hundred UAVs to continue to prosecute this illegal war and to continue to kill Ukrainians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, and what does the U.S. know about the meeting that President Putin had in Iran with Turkish leader Erdoğan and what it could mean for reinstating Ukrainian grain exports?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let them speak to their meetings.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know what was on the agenda for that.&nbsp; We are mindful of the talks that have been ongoing between Turkey, Russia, and Ukraine about grain exports, and we hope for progress in those talks. But we&#8217;re clear-eyed about it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re clear-eyed about Russia&#8217;s ambitions here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re clear-eyed about the fact that there&#8217;s basically a blockade in the Black Sea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So while we certainly welcome Mr. Erdoğan’s leadership in here &#8212; and the President has thanked him for that leadership &#8212; we&#8217;ve trying to come up with a negotiated solution here to get the grain out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s unfortunate that he even has to have those talks, because there&#8217;s a blockade that Russia could stop today. They can take their ships out of the Black Sea.&nbsp; They could let that grain go and alleviate a lot of food security problems not just in Europe, but in the Middle East, in Africa, or elsewhere around the world.</p>



<p>So, again, we&#8217;re hopeful that there can be some sort of arrangement to get that grain out of there, but &#8212; but we&#8217;re not looking at it through rose-colored glasses in terms of the success that they&#8217;ll ultimately be able to achieve.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The only thing I&#8217;d add to that is: It&#8217;s good to see Ukraine at the table in these discussions, and that &#8212; that&#8217;s as it should be.&nbsp; Ukraine absolutely has to be part of whatever solution is solved, and their economy can&#8217;t suffer any more than it already has as a result of Russian blockade activity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s got to the back.&nbsp; Janne, Phil.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; And let me get my pen.&nbsp; I dropped it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Because often, when you ask me questions &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; &#8212; I have to write them down.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s okay.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t be nervous, okay?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Oh, no. &nbsp;I am always nervous when you&#8217;re called on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Next time I know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, John.&nbsp; I have two questions on &#8212; one Ukraine and one Russia.&nbsp; The Ukraine recently announced that diplomatic severance with North Korea.&nbsp; And meanwhile, Russia announced that it will be sending North Korean workers to rebuild Donbas in Ukraine.&nbsp; What is your comment?&nbsp; Or is it a violation of U.N. Security Council sanctions?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not an expert enough on sanctions to know whether these actions are violations of resolutions.&nbsp; But again, it just shows the degree to which Mr. Putin remains isolated.&nbsp; Now he&#8217;s got to turn to North Korea, you know, and he&#8217;s got to turn to Iran here, rather than just doing the right thing to begin with and ending the war.</p>



<p>And eventually, there&#8217;s going to be reconstruction of Ukraine.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s going to be for the Ukrainians to decide, Janne &#8212; not the Russians, not the North Koreans, not anybody else but President Zelenskyy and the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to get to decide how they reconstruct their country after this war.&nbsp; And obviously, and you’ve heard the President talk about this, we&#8217;re going to be there to support them through that process.</p>



<p>The goal right now &#8212; and we can&#8217;t forget what it is right now, as I &#8212; well, I mentioned it in my opening statement &#8212; is to continue to help Ukraine defend itself against this aggression inside their country, making sure that Mr. Zelenskyy and the Ukrainian Armed Forces have what they need to continue to fight back and to reclaim their sovereignty.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what matters right now.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Phil.&nbsp; And then we’ll come back (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to ask you, sir, a question about some of the comments that the President made when he was in Spain last month.&nbsp; But before that, rewinding to some of your statements moments ago, you said that Russia, over time, may prove unable to hold the territory that they&#8217;re annexing.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: What does that mean in terms of the U.S. commitment to Ukraine?&nbsp; Are we talking about, you know, backing some sort of military operation for the Ukrainians to take back territory that was taken from them?&nbsp; Or is that a more general statement about diplomatic pressure?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no change to our policy with respect to helping Ukraine defend itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, we help provide them the training that they need with some of these advanced systems and the systems themselves.&nbsp; And I would remind you that it&#8217;s not just the United States; some 50 other countries.&nbsp; In fact, Secretary Austin is going to be holding yet another iteration of the Ukraine Contact Group this week, and I suspect you&#8217;ll see additional international contributions to Ukrainian security assistance.</p>



<p>And we give that material to them; we give them the training if they need it.&nbsp; Mr. Zelenskyy and his chain of command, they determine how they&#8217;re going to use it.&nbsp; And we have seen over the last, it&#8217;s hard to believe, five months &#8212; but five months &#8212; where the Ukrainians, sometimes all in the same day, will be on the defensive in some areas and on the offensive in others.&nbsp; And we have seen, just in the last week or two, both of that, depending on where you&#8217;re at.</p>



<p>The Ukrainians are certainly &#8212; they have a right not only to defend themselves, but they absolutely have a right to go on the counter-offensive inside their own country against Russian forces.</p>



<p>Now, where and when they do that, how they do that, and what systems they use, that&#8217;s for them to decide.&nbsp; Our job, again, is to make sure they&#8217;ve got the tools and the training to be able to defend themselves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then my second question: President Biden announced last month that he was going to be sending two more destroyers to Rota, Spain.&nbsp; I think the number is going from four to six.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I guess I&#8217;m wondering: You know, why is the President sending these warships to the Mediterranean to defend the Spanish coast there &#8212; I mean, this is a country that spends about 1 percent of its GDP on total defense &#8212; when there seems to be an increasingly serious threat in the Indo-Pacific from China?&nbsp; I mean, shouldn&#8217;t Spain step up?&nbsp; Shouldn&#8217;t the Italians or French, you know, patrol their own waters so that we can have a free hand on the other side of the world?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; This is one of the very few questions I&#8217;ll probably ever get that are right down my lane.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I knew you were coming today.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I &#8212; and I served as a young officer in the Med on a couple of different deployments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, so &#8212; so a home port is just where the ship stays.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean that the ship is just there to sail in the waters off of Spain. &nbsp;And so the four destroyers that we have in the Mediterranean right now, they patrol the Mediterranean, and frankly, there are times when they&#8217;ll patrol into the North Atlantic.&nbsp; It’s just &#8212; just having them in Spain is what we call forward deployed.&nbsp; It&#8217;s like we have &#8212; you know, we have an aircraft carrier and warships in Japan forward deployed.&nbsp; We have ships forward deployed into the Middle East, in &#8212; based in Bahrain.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just a place to &#8212; it shortens the time and distance to get them on station where they might need to be.</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s &#8212; this decision by the President to add two destroyers to the four that are there I think is indicative of what the President has said many times: The security environment in Europe is different now; it has changed.&nbsp; Not is changing, not will change.&nbsp; Has changed.&nbsp; And we need to meet that.</p>



<p>This is just one of many moves, and that the President spoke to in Madrid and at the G7, that were taken to improve our military posture on NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.&nbsp; And some of those moves will be permanent, in addition to the two ships, and it&#8217;s going to take a little while for them to get there, to be permanently homebased there.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not going to happen tomorrow.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re going to put a headquarters forward command element in Poland &#8212; first time ever.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make more regular the &#8212; more routine, I should say, the rotational deployments of Army land forces throughout the eastern flank as well.</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s all part and parcel of a larger effort by the United States to make sure that we are able to meet our Article 5 commitment to our NATO Allies, particularly on the eastern flank.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we’re not emphasizing one theater at the expense of another?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Oh, look, you have to do both.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m glad you followed up on that.&nbsp; I mean, we already have 60 percent of the United States Navy either in or based in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; There&#8217;s already a robust military capability in that part of the world.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s &#8212; we have no intention whatsoever of decreasing that focus and that energy there.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve heard Secretary Austin talk about China being the pacing challenge for the United States military, and that&#8217;s exactly how they&#8217;re treating it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Take a look at the budget that we just submitted for ’23, and you&#8217;ll see chapter and verse how the United States military is really trying to make sure they&#8217;re investing in the kinds of capabilities that we&#8217;re going to need in the Indo-Pacific to face that pacing challenge.</p>



<p>Look, the United States military is a global &#8212; a global power.&nbsp; And you have to be focused on all kinds of different regions and face all kinds of different threats.&nbsp; The President was just in the Middle East because that too is an important area for our national security interests.&nbsp; We can do &#8212; we can do more than one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nandita.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Quick question, just to sort of follow up on what you said about the U.S. responding to any sort of annexation attempts.&nbsp; What kind of options are available to the U.S. if you were to respond?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, I talked about that a little bit in the &#8212; in the open.&nbsp; We certainly have additional sanctions we could &#8212; we could employ.&nbsp; We could strengthen the ones that are already in place.&nbsp; We can further try to make it harder, squeeze Mr. Putin&#8217;s ability to wage war.&nbsp; Waging war is an expensive business.&nbsp; He now &#8212; his &#8212; he&#8217;s facing inflation of up to &#8212; thanks to all the international pressure, he&#8217;s already facing inflation of up to 20 percent.&nbsp; His &#8212; his imports have fallen by 40 percent.&nbsp; The Russian stock market fell by about 30 percent recently.</p>



<p>I mean, this has not been without costs, and we can &#8212; we can raise those costs on him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you expecting to do any of that in the next few days, weeks?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce today.&nbsp; We wanted to make it clear today what we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve already, as I said in my opening statement, started to exe- &#8212; to sanction some of these so-called officials.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I don&#8217;t have any new announcements to make today, but we just wanted to make very plain for the American people what we&#8217;re seeing and make it very plain to Mr. Putin that nobody is fooled by it.&nbsp; We know he&#8217;s just dusting off the old playbook from 2014.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be watching this closely.</p>



<p>Last point &#8212; and it&#8217;s important, and I know I say it all the time, but it&#8217;s not just the United States.&nbsp; The international community is wise to this as well.&nbsp; And we fully expect that our allies and partners will participate in any additional pressure put on Mr. Putin.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, John.&nbsp; I wonder if we could change topics a bit here.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve long talked about how climate change is a national security issue for the country.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you view this as a national emergency and if you believe that executive actions that will be announced are enough of a message to send to the world that the U.S. is indeed serious about climate change.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of any announcements on specific actions with respect to climate.</p>



<p>But let me take a step back.&nbsp; I mean, the Pentagon has noted not just in this administration, but even the previous one, that climate change is a national security issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Geez, Jeff, I mean, not only does it affect our infrastructure &#8212; and you&#8217;re already starting to see military bases like Norfolk Naval Base having to invest millions of dollars to try to improve their infrastructure because of rising sea levels.&nbsp; So it has an impact on our infrastructure.&nbsp; It has an impact on our readiness, because you &#8212; and you&#8217;re seeing it now, even in the wildfires, where so many National Guardsmen are being called out.&nbsp; And &#8212; and God love them for that, but they&#8217;re &#8212; those are important tasks and missions, but it takes away from other tasks and missions when it comes to defending the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s an impact on our own readiness just because our &#8212; our troops, our sailors, our Marines, our airmen, our Coast Guardsmen are being called out for &#8212; to respond to natural disasters, which are getting worse because of climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then lastly, it&#8217;s a driver of actual missions, because climate change creates instability, which creates insecurity in some places.&nbsp; And you can end up &#8212; the fighting in Syria started, really, as a result of a drought.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s a &#8212; it can actually drive military missions and force the military to become involved in places and at times where they wouldn&#8217;t have had to otherwise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, again, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President or any &#8212; any decisions he may or may not make.&nbsp; But the President believes that this is a very important issue for our own national security.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to treat it that way.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to Iran and Russia and then, if I may, one quick one on the executive order from today.&nbsp; Jake Sullivan had said last week that Iran was preparing to train Russian forces to use armed drones in Ukraine starting this month.&nbsp; Does the U.S. have an indication that those training sessions have started or that Iran has actually given those drones to Russia?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any indications that the &#8212; that the sale has actually occurred.&nbsp; And so, therefore, we wouldn&#8217;t have any indications that there&#8217;s been training done on them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I don&#8217;t want us to get lost in the details here.&nbsp; I mean, I know it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; Obviously, we wouldn&#8217;t have talked about it if it wasn&#8217;t.&nbsp; But it is an indication of how much more desperate Mr. Putin is becoming in terms of his own defense industrial base and the degree to which he wants to continue to prosecute this war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, a lot of it&#8217;s going to depend on how many does he buy, what kind of capabilities they have.&nbsp; But the Iranians have a domestic production capability of drones, and those drones have lethal capabilities.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that for ourselves in the attacks that they have &#8212; they have perpetrated in Iraq and in Syria against our own troops and against our own facilities there.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re watching this closely, and we&#8217;re taking it seriously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the executive order from today: How quickly might we see sanctions on people or countries that the U.S. considers responsible for detaining Americans wrongfully right now?&nbsp; And how might this impact or play into the cases of Brittney Griner or Paul Whelan?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any decision space here.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not my role today.&nbsp; These are additional tools that this EO gives us, including the ability to levy additional sanctions.&nbsp; So, again, I&#8217;m not going to preview anything or get ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last thing I&#8217;d say on this is that the President remains laser-focused on these cases and in constant touch with his national security team and with our Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs on all these cases, including, of course, Mr. Whelan and Mrs. Griner.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jacqui and then Franco.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; On the Iran nuclear deal talks, John, I just wanted to get your view on this.&nbsp; Wendy Sherman said last week it&#8217;s in Iran’s deal &#8212; best interest to make a deal.&nbsp; “They would get sanctions relief.&nbsp; They would improve their economy and sell their oil again, and the world needs their oil so they could get a good price for it.”&nbsp; So I&#8217;m asking: Is the White House viewing sanctions relief for Iran as a way to bring down gas prices?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; The administration is looking at a return to the JCPOA &#8212; the Iran deal &#8212; to prevent Iran from obtaining a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal.&nbsp; And you heard the President talk about this on the trip.&nbsp; No problem in the Middle East &#8212; none &#8212; gets easier to solve if Iran has a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal of the Iran deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, look, there&#8217;s a deal on the table.&nbsp; And the onus is on Iran now to decide whether they&#8217;re going to take that deal.&nbsp; If they take that deal, yes, sanctions relief will be a part of it, as it was before, before the previous administration pulled out of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the goal, the objective, the purpose is to prevent Iran from getting a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how should we understand her statement then?&nbsp; Because the President&#8217;s whole strategy when he was on his Middle East tour was to counter Iran, but her language makes it seem like maybe, you know, they&#8217;re not so bad if they bring down gas prices, which has been hurting the President in polls, obviously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, look, I mean, there&#8217;s obviously a tangential &#8212; potentially tangential benefit, should they sign into the deal and actually stop spinning their centrifuges and come into compliance and allow themselves to be back inside the most rigid inspection regime ever in an arms control agreement, which would include potentially sanctions relief, which would include obviously some economic breathing space for them to do things potentially on the oil market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, again, Jacqui, that&#8217;s not the purpose here.&nbsp; The purpose is to try to prevent them from having a nuclear weapons capability.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s all about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last question. &nbsp;On this statement from Iran that they can produce a nuclear bomb if they want to but they haven’t made that decision, it comes after Biden and the Israeli Prime Minister publicly disagreed on the best way to counter Iran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, how concerning is it that Putin is meeting with Iran right after Iran said that they can build a bomb if they want to?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;ll let those leaders speak for the timing of this visit.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re focused on is making sure Ukraine can continue to defend itself.&nbsp; And, obviously, it looks like, potentially, they&#8217;re going to have to learn to defend themselves from these Iranian drones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you saw on the trip in Middle East, the President is focused on an integrated, more stable, more secure Middle East. &nbsp;And you can&#8217;t get there, you can&#8217;t have that as an outcome if Iran builds a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re closer to it today than they were five years ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President understands that sense of urgency, which is why he wanted his team to negotiate this deal.&nbsp; And now the negotiations are complete.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re close.&nbsp; Iran just has to agree to accept that deal, come back into compliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That won&#8217;t solve all the problems.&nbsp; Not at all.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll solve &#8212; if they come back into compliance and submit to the inspections and a reduction in their stockpiles, it&#8217;ll certainly help solve the more urgent problem now of their burgeoning nuclear capability, but it won&#8217;t necessarily solve their developing ballistic missile capability, which continues to improve.&nbsp; It won&#8217;t necessarily solve their support for terrorist networks in the region.&nbsp; It won&#8217;t solve the threats to maritime security in the Gulf that we continue to see out of Iran.&nbsp; And it potentially could &#8212; you know, might make &#8212; you know, won&#8217;t solve all problems in Yemen, although we&#8217;re glad for this ceasefire.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re still going to have to stay focused on all those other issues, which is, again, why the President&#8217;s trip was so important.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Franco.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; John, first on the Russian annex, and then if I could ask a China question.&nbsp; On the Russia annexation comments that you&#8217;re making: Can you talk a little bit more about what specifically is new in the downgraded intelligence that you brought up?&nbsp; I mean, the administration has been warning about sham elections, about referendums since the spring.&nbsp; Kherson has been named in the past as possibly a place this could happen.&nbsp; So what has actually &#8212; what are you seeing that is new in the last few weeks that you did not know, before?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I have to be somewhat careful in answering the question because we&#8217;re talking about some declassified intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would &#8212; I would point you to some of the specificity in my opening comments about some of the individuals, some of the locations, and then just the modalities, I think, of how the Russians plan to pursue this in time and space.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s really about as far as I&#8217;m able to go.</p>



<p>But we know this is going to be a concerted effort here.&nbsp; And some of it is in con- &#8212; is in parallel to the incremental territorial gains that they&#8217;re making.&nbsp; And some of the designs here are a representation of the frustration that they haven&#8217;t had as much success in territorial gains as they&#8217;ve had in the past.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is this more of an incremental advancement in that &#8212; in that theory of Russia trying to annex?&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;ve just been hearing about it for a while.&nbsp; So, I mean, I&#8217;m just trying to gauge how much &#8212; how different is this than what&#8217;s been going on for a while now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; They &#8212; this is out of the playbook, and we&#8217;ve seen him do it in the past.&nbsp; I think what we&#8217;re seeing now is a more concerted, more strategic effort.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s really about as far as I can go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On China, China tariffs &#8212; you know, I asked Karine about this yesterday and talked about the efforts of the administration to kind of address that and resolve concerns that they have about what Trump did.&nbsp; Can you talk about &#8212; a little bit about where efforts to ease those tariffs is and when we might be able to &#8212; when we might see some of the things that Biden has said is expected to come out of that?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new for you today, and I certainly can&#8217;t add to what Karine said yesterday.&nbsp; The President is looking at this.&nbsp; He wants to make sure that he makes the best decisions for the American people and for the American economy.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m certainly not going to get ahead of that.&nbsp; He&#8217;s taking this very seriously, as he should.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, I’m going to take two from the back.</p>



<p>Yeah, Ed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And then (inaudible).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; So I want to ask you about oil and Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>So should we expect an announcement then from &#8212; on August 3rd &#8212; from OPEC or Saudi Arabia about increasing oil production because of the President’s visit?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I’m &#8212; I’m certainly not going to speak for OPEC.&nbsp; They get to make their decisions and speak to them.&nbsp; I would point you to what the President said when we were in Jeddah: that the discussions on energy security were quite constructive and that he expects that it’s possible that we could see some movement here in the next two to three weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; so we’re just going to watch that and see how it goes.<br><br>Important to remember, and I think he also reminded, that OPEC+3 has already increased by 50 percent &#8212; planned increases in July and August; that’s been helpful &#8212; in addition to the 1 million barrels per day that the President has released from the Strategic Reserve.<br><br>All that oil has helped stabilize the market, and the price still hovers around $100.&nbsp; That’s because the market likes stability.&nbsp; And so those additions have created that kind of breathing space for the prices on &#8212; at the pump to start &#8212; just to start to come down.</p>



<p>So we’ll see where it goes.&nbsp; The discussions both at the GCC and bilaterally with the Saudis, again, were very constructive when it comes to energy.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be watching.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on the &#8212; so I noticed, on the President&#8217;s schedule the last two days, there have been no public events.&nbsp; Is he resting after the large international trips (inaudible)?<br><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, the President has been busy.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let Karine speak to the President&#8217;s schedule.&nbsp; But the President has been quite busy.&nbsp; Just because you don&#8217;t see something necessarily on the public schedule doesn&#8217;t mean that there&#8217;s not a lot of work going on.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; The gentleman in the back there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The Senate Foreign Relations Committee just reported out the resolution regarding the admission of Finland and Sweden to NATO, and they&#8217;re likely to do that before August recess.&nbsp; Can you speak to the importance of getting that done before the August recess?<br><br>And also, is there any sort of message regarding the, I think it was 18, House Republicans who last night voted against a non-binding resolution on the admission of the countries to NATO?</p>



<p><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I would just tell you that we obviously want to see Finland and Sweden brought into the Alliance as soon as possible.&nbsp; And so we look forward to congressional action that will allow that to be the case, at least from the United States perspective.&nbsp; As you know, every Ally has to ratify; we&#8217;re not the only ones.&nbsp; But certainly, we believe it&#8217;s in our interest and it&#8217;s in the Alliance&#8217;s interest for accession of those two countries to happen as soon as possible.<br><br>These are modern militaries, militaries that we know well.&nbsp; We exercise with them, operate with them; I myself did a long, long time ago.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve got incredible modern capabilities that will absolutely help bolster NATO&#8217;s defensive capabilities and contribute significantly to the Article 5 commitment that we all sign into when we come into the Alliance.<br><br>So we&#8217;re looking forward to it. &nbsp;We urge Congress to act as quickly as possible.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Steven, last question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; John, I wanted to give you a chance to respond to the families’ reaction to the hostage and wrongful detention executive order.</p>



<p><br>The group Bring Our Families Home issued a statement saying that the order is simply the White House “taking executive action to direct itself to follow existing law.”&nbsp; The group says the President should agree to take a meeting with the families.&nbsp; Will he do that?<br><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything on the President&#8217;s schedule specifically to speak to you today.&nbsp; I would remind that the whole national security team remains committed to staying in touch with these families, and we have routine discussions with them &#8212; with all of them.&nbsp; Our Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs is in regular contact with them.<br><br>We know that they&#8217;re suffering.&nbsp; We know they&#8217;re scared.&nbsp; And we know they&#8217;re anxious.&nbsp; And we know that they want their loved ones back home, and the President wants that too.&nbsp; And this executive order will give us some additional tools in the toolbox.<br><br>Is it going to solve every problem?&nbsp; Nope.&nbsp; Every case is specific, and you got to look at each one individually and figure out what the best way is forward.&nbsp; Sometimes turning up the heat publicly is the answer.&nbsp; Sometimes turning it down is the answer.&nbsp; Sometimes, you know, sanctions could be useful. Sometimes not.<br><br>Each one is in- &#8212; each one is individual and each one is different.&nbsp; Because, you know what? &nbsp;To those families, it’s individual as well.&nbsp; They just want their loved ones home, and the President wants that too.<br><br>This EO is a useful extra set of tools that we&#8217;ll have in our toolbox to help bring that about.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, John.<br><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Appreciate it, everybody.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, John.<br><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yes, ma’am.&nbsp; Bye, bye.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;All right.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I have a few things at the top.&nbsp; Speaking of climate change: So we are closely monitoring extreme heat conditions impacting much of Europe as well as the extreme heat impacting the more than 100 million Americans who are struggling with extreme heat conditions here at home just this week alone.<br><br>The impacts of extreme weather are intensifying across the globe, including here in the United States.&nbsp; No one is immune from climate change.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why the President has been rallying the world to take the decisive action needed in this decade to tackle the climate change &#8212; the climate crisis.<br><br>It&#8217;s also why the President is committed to taking aggressive action to tackle climate change and made clear if the Senate won&#8217;t act, he will.&nbsp; In fact, as many you &#8212; as many of you have seen already today, the President will travel to Somerset, Massachusetts, tomorrow.&nbsp; While there, he will visit the future site of a manufacturing plant located at a former coal-fired power plant that will produce transmission cables for Massachusetts’s booming offshore wind industry.<br><br>The President will underscore the historic clean energy investments his Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will make in Massachusetts and announce additional actions he will take to tackle the climate crisis and secure a clean energy future.<br><br>The President ran on fighting the unprecedented economic and national security threat of climate change.&nbsp; And he has take- &#8212; he has been taking decisive action to do so since taking office.&nbsp; Tomorrow&#8217;s action will be a continuation of that work.<br><br>And I have two things, because I know folks in the room asked this question &#8212; two different questions yesterday, and I said I would get back to them.<br><br>I think, Eugene, you had a question about ACLU.&nbsp; The Department of Homeland Security is committed to complying with the law and respects the privacy and civil liberties of individuals.&nbsp; DHS employs various forms of technology to undertake the &#8212; its mission.&nbsp; This includes using tools to better investigate threats to infrastructure; traffickers of deadly opioids on the dark web; and to identify those involved in cross-border, transnational criminal organizations and terrorist activities.<br><br>And again, as I said to you yesterday, for further information, I would point you to DHS.<br><br>And I just have one more for the Marburg virus disease in Ghana.&nbsp; I have an answer &#8212; came back with an answer for you &#8212; I think this is from Simon.<br><br>Ghana reported two fatal cases of suspected hemor- &#8212; hemorrhagic fever in the Ashanti region of Ghana in early July, which tested positive for Marburg virus disease almost two weeks after presentation.&nbsp; These were the first cases ever reported from the country.&nbsp; U.S. agencies, our embassy in Accra have been in close collaboration with Ghana Health Services, World Health Organization.&nbsp; And other partners have engaged with public health working group in the country to share information.<br><br>The government of Ghana has not made any request of us, but we stand ready to assist however we can.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s that answer there for you all.<br><br>Will, you want to kick us off?</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got two things.&nbsp; It doesn’t look like we&#8217;ll be getting a climate emergency announcement this week.&nbsp; I want to make sure that’s still on the table.&nbsp; And I wanted to ask if the White House has any concerns that the President might be relying on executive action too much.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the fi- &#8212; to answer your first question &#8212; look, one thing that I just want to step back and just lay out for all of you: When &#8212; the President was one of the first in Congress, when he was a senator, to ring the bell &#8212; the alarm bell on climate crisis.<br><br>So this is an issue that has been front of mind for him.&nbsp; This is an issue that has been &#8212; when it comes to the climate crisis &#8212; a priority.&nbsp; And taking action is something that he said he will do if Congress won&#8217;t.&nbsp; And he has been taking action, as we have &#8212; as I had just stated in my opening remarks, since he&#8217;s taken &#8212; since he taken office.<br><br>So he&#8217;s going to take, as I said, additional climate actions in that vein tomorrow, and he&#8217;s going to continue.&nbsp; He’s&nbsp; not going to just stop with the actions of tomorrow.&nbsp; But I would not plan a announcement this week on national climate emergency.<br><br>Again, everything is on the table.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just not going to be this week on that decision.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On another matter, Senator Manchin is rejecting the global tax deal that Secretary Yellen negotiated with, like, 100-plus countries.&nbsp; What will happen if those countries move ahead with the deal and the U.S. doesn’t?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I have a couple of things on &#8212; a couple of points on that that I wanted to share with all of you.<br><br>So we remain committed to finalizing a global minimum tax.&nbsp; It will level the playing field, as you all know, for U.S. businesses, decrease incentives to move jobs offshore, and close loopholes that <s>cooperations</s> [corporations] have used to shift profits overseas, which will benefit American workers, businesses, taxpayers, and middle-class families.<br><br>So that is critical and that is important and why we need to do this.&nbsp; But this significant incentive for America to come into &#8212; it is &#8212; it&#8217;s significant for America to come into compliance.<br><br>Right now, other countries are pursuing legislation that would put them in compliance.&nbsp; If they act and America doesn&#8217;t, we&#8217;ll lose out on tax revenues that we could use to invest in the strength of our economy and the middle class.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s too important for our economic strength and competitiveness to finalize this agreement.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll continue to work always to get it done.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s going to be our focus, as well.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Ashley.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Two related questions on climate.&nbsp; First, why did the White House decide that tomorrow is not the day to declare a climate emergency?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, what I can say is the President is going to do everything that he can to take action.&nbsp; Again, climate &#8212; climate crisis &#8212; taking climate action is critical, it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; You heard Kirby talk about our national security &#8212; how it threatens our national security, how it threatens the economy.&nbsp; And what the President wants to continue to do is make sure that we&#8217;re lowering energy costs for the American family.&nbsp; Again, everything is on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to go into private discussions that &#8212; policy discussions or get ahead of the President at this time.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to make some announcements. &nbsp;Today, what I can say: This climate emergency is not going to happen tomorrow.&nbsp; But we have &#8212; we have &#8212; we still have it on the table.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a circle &#8212; a date circled on the calendar.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If and when it does happen, can you talk a little bit about what specific tools it would then give the administration and what specifically you would use it for and do?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, one thing that I just wanted to make clear, because some folks were asking about &#8212; about the abortion piece &#8212; the emergency abortion piece.&nbsp; So I just wanted to just lay out: So, look, we haven&#8217;t ruled out a public health emergency, as I just laid out.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re just &#8212; we&#8217;re just still moving forward with &#8212; with the options that we potentially have in front of us; everything is on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But declaring a public health emergency is very different from declaring a climate emergency.&nbsp; Each unlocks a different set of authorities and a different pot of funding.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s one way to think about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, one of the reasons I wanted to bring this up, because we&#8217;ve heard this &#8212; and so comparing one against the other as a reflection of priority would not be &#8212; would not be accurate.&nbsp; But again, it&#8217;s on the table.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t made &#8212; we haven&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything to announce at this time.&nbsp; And, you know, the President will speak more on what it is &#8212; how he wants to move forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on those differences, is it a bigger pot of money it unlocks?&nbsp; I know that was one of the concerns the administration had about the public health emergency.&nbsp; And are there any other specifics you can share about how you could use a climate declaration?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any specifics or anything to move further on what I just stated.&nbsp; But you&#8217;re right: When Jen Klein was here, just almost two weeks ago, she talked about how in the pot of money for the &#8212; for the abortion pieces, there was just tens of thousands of dollars there.&nbsp; So we &#8212; there was some feeling that we didn&#8217;t know exactly how that would work.&nbsp; But she did state that it would be still on the table and that we were still thinking through it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as far as the &#8212; what&#8217;s on the &#8212; in the climate &#8212; the climate side, I just don&#8217;t have more information to share.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there any downsides to declaring a climate national emergency?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right now, like I said, it&#8217;s not on the table for this week.&nbsp; We&#8217;re still considering it.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have the upside or the downsides of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you can imagine, and I have said, this is an important priority when it comes to getting to clean energy, when it comes to dealing with climate crisis, when it comes to taking action.&nbsp; So the President is going to continue to make sure he&#8217;s doing everything that he can to deal &#8212; of the threats of climate change.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have specifics on the pros and the cons, but it is still on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When you talk about actions for tomorrow, should we assume that he’ll be signing executive actions to announce tomorrow?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Jeff, I just don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; Again, he&#8217;s going to make some announcement &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will there be a briefing call on this later to explain what he’s doing? &nbsp;Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; There &#8212; there might be.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have one to announce.&nbsp; We normally do.&nbsp; To your point, we usually have background calls when we&#8217;re ready, and we usually invite all of you.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have one to announce.&nbsp; There might be in the next couple of hours.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to share at this point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he been involved in these meetings today?&nbsp; Or what exactly has he been doing yesterday and today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So he&#8217;s been in meetings.&nbsp; I was &#8212; I was called &#8212; I was scheduled to meet with him today in the Oval Office.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s been meeting with his senior staff.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been meeting with staff.&nbsp; I think some of you may have seen him when &#8212; when the First Lady of Ukraine was vidi- &#8212; visiting with our First Lady.&nbsp; I believe you saw &#8212; you saw him very briefly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So he&#8217;s just been very busy dealing with the issues of the American people and meeting with his staff and senior staff the last two days.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick one on the climate emergency and public health emergency.&nbsp; How concerned is the White House it may end up, sort of, angering female voters if it does sort of go ahead and announce a climate emergency ahead of a public health emergency, considering we haven’t seen such an announcement after Roe?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that why maybe the timing &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; has been moved?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t look into &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t make that into an issue.&nbsp; I &#8212; both of &#8212; both of those things are still on the table.&nbsp; We just haven&#8217;t announced them or made a decision yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I just laid out what the difference &#8212; the difference is between when you look at a public health emergency on the abortion side, when you look at public health emergency &#8212; more so on the abortion side, but the difference between the two.&nbsp; We just don&#8217;t &#8212; they&#8217;re both on the table.&nbsp; We just don&#8217;t &#8212; haven’t made an announcement on that yet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the President did say that he&#8217;s asked his administration to see if he has the authority to declare a public health emergency.&nbsp; Is there, sort of, any update on &#8212; into that work to see if he has the authority, ultimately, to declare something like that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;re looking at all options.&nbsp; Everything is on the table.&nbsp; We just haven&#8217;t made a decision on this yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The mayors of New York City and D.C. are calling for more federal resources to assist with asylum seekers who are being bused to those cities from Texas and Arizona.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve had thousands of people arriving over the past couple of weeks.&nbsp; Mayor Bowser, here in D.C., said that these people are being “tricked.”&nbsp; What federal resources is the White House preparing, if any, to deliver to these cities and other cities that are now dealing with an increase of asylum seekers?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I can tell you, Karen, that we have been in touch with both of their &#8212; both of their administrations, both of their offices.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to look into their requests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just &#8212; I don&#8217;t have further than that to share.&nbsp; But we have been in touch with Mayor Bowser&#8217;s office and we have been in touch with Mayor Adams’s office.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there could be resources that can be given to &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right now, I can tell you that FEMA is the lead agency on this.&nbsp; And so I would &#8212; I would point you to them on &#8212; on any more information or details that they can provide.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the other end of it, some advocates say that the governors of these states are using these migrants as pawns.&nbsp; Has the White House reached out to those governors and said, “Don&#8217;t send these people to these cities on the East Coast”?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, we&#8217;re in constant communication and contact with governors just across the country.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything specific to that &#8212; you know, the specific on migrants being shipped to other states.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a message from the White House about &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what they should be doing or not doing?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think we &#8212; we have &#8212; this has come up before, I believe, a couple of months ago.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; we believe it&#8217;s shameful that &#8212; that some governors are using migrants as a political tool, as a political play, when we should be making sure that we&#8217;re doing everything that we can to help &#8212; to help folks who are coming into this process in a legal way and making sure that, you know, we do this in a &#8212; in a safe &#8212; in a safe way and a respectful way.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s shameful that that is happening.</p>



<p><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The Secret Service now says that they are unable to retrieve any more emails from agents from January 5th and 6th of last year.&nbsp; Does the President believe that it&#8217;s acceptable for a law enforcement agency &#8212; a federal law enforcement agency to simply lose such critical communications that are important to an investigation?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I appreciate the question.&nbsp; This is not something that I can speak about from here.&nbsp; This is some- &#8212; this is a question that has to go to the &#8212; any information or details has to go to the U.S. Secret Service.&nbsp; I just can&#8217;t speak from that from here because it&#8217;s a &#8212; it is a active investigation.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand, but this is something the Secret Service is saying publicly that they just &#8212; you know, they didn&#8217;t back up their emails and texts properly, apparently.&nbsp; I’m just wondering: This is the agency that is tasked with protecting the President of the United States.&nbsp; Is he concerned about some gaps in the mission there?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I understand the question, and I hear the question, but we just can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t respond to it from here, from the podium.&nbsp; It’s an active investigation.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, has the President been &#8212; I know you mentioned Marburg’s disease at the top.&nbsp; Has the President been briefed on the situation with Marburg’s disease?&nbsp; And is the White House preparing any additional action?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re ready.&nbsp; We have not gotten, as I stated, any &#8212; any ask for assistance, and we are ready to assist when asked.<br><br>I would have to check in with the team to see if the President has been briefed about this particular issue.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Josh.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say what role the ongoing reconciliation talks played in the climate decision?&nbsp; For instance, is the climate emergency off the table because you&#8217;re worried it will upend the applecart in the Senate with Senator Manchin or Sen- &#8212; or others by going sort of too big, too fast?&nbsp; Can you talk about what role the (inaudible) are between what to do now on climate and what you&#8217;re still hoping to get out of Congress?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So when it comes to what&#8217;s happening on the Senate with reconciliation, I will not negotiate in public or speak to any private conversation.&nbsp; I can tell you that our teams are in regular contact with Senator Manchin and other members in the Sen- &#8212; in the Senate and in Congress, just as we do on a &#8212; on a constant &#8212; in a constant way and a constant basis.<br><br>I will say that, as I mentioned, I wouldn&#8217;t expect an announcement this week on the emergency &#8212; on the climate change emergency.&nbsp; But what I will say is that it is still on the table.&nbsp; We have not made a decision yet.<br><br>Again, this is &#8212; what we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; this action that we&#8217;re going to hear about from the President tomorrow, this is part of multiple actions that the President has already taken from the moment that he walked into office.&nbsp; This is urgent to him.&nbsp; He called the climate crisis one of the four major crisis that he had to &#8212; that he was dealing with once walking into the administration.<br><br>Again, we&#8217;re talking about national security, we&#8217;re talking about lowering energy costs, we&#8217;re talking about threats to our economy.&nbsp; All of these things are critical.&nbsp; All of these things are important.&nbsp; And he will be &#8212; continue to be steadfast in focusing on the climate crisis.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And did he not do these things &#8212; the executive actions &#8212; previously because he hoped that he would get it in the legislation?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, the President &#8212; and you&#8217;ve heard me say this, you&#8217;ve heard him say this: When it comes to the climate change provisions in reconciliation, of course he wants to see it in the rec- &#8212; in the bill.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I guess, “Why not both?” is my question.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Pardon me?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not both?&nbsp; Like, why did he hold off &#8212; he seems to have held off doing executive action waiting for the bill.&nbsp; Could he have not done &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; look, we &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; walk and chew gum?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think we could still walk and chew gum.&nbsp; No one says &#8212; again, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp; You know, the &#8212; the process in the Senate is &#8212; is happening.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak to that in public.<br><br>Look, this was an opportunity.&nbsp; The President has said that he was going to take action.&nbsp; He said &#8212; you know, he&#8217;s always said if they &#8212; the Senate won&#8217;t, he will take action.&nbsp; He is just taking another step.&nbsp; This is not the final step.&nbsp; This is part of a process that he &#8212; that you have seen him take, especially when it comes to the climate crisis.<br><br>And so, you know, I wouldn&#8217;t see this as an either/or. &nbsp;I would see this as part of what he has been trying to continue to do in playing our part in the &#8212; in the climate crisis and dealing with climate change.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, can you offer any update on the deliberations on student loan relief and what kind of timeline, if any, there is on that?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you.&nbsp; I know this is a question that comes up often in the briefing room.&nbsp; This is something that is clearly important to the President, and so as soon as we have anything to preview, we will make sure that happens.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two on China.&nbsp; China is warning that relations with the U.S. will be damaged if Speaker Pelosi visits Taiwan.&nbsp; Do you have any comment on the reports that she&#8217;s going?&nbsp; And has the White House had any communication with her office about &#8212; about this (inaudible)?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m just not going to comment on travel that the Speaker&#8217;s office itself has not announced, I believe.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the last that I&#8217;ve heard before I came to the podium.&nbsp; So we will refer you to the congressional delegation on their travel.</p>



<p>I will reiterate that the United States remain committed to our One China policy, which is set forth in the Taiwan Relations Act, as you know, the Three Joint Communiqués, and the Six Assurances.</p>



<p>This has been a consistent U.S. position for decades across multiple administrations.&nbsp; This is nothing new here.&nbsp; U.S. support for Taiwan remains rock solid, principled, and bipartisan, and is in line with our One China policy and longstanding U.S. commitments.&nbsp; But from what I understand, there has been no announcement, and I&#8217;m certainly not going to comment on her travels at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any update on when President Biden may speak or have a phone call with President Xi?&nbsp; I know that&#8217;s been talked about.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; As you know, they spoke recently &#8212; not too long ago.&nbsp; We &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said this before &#8212; we are &#8212; we are keeping the lines of communication, of dialogue, open.&nbsp; There has been staff-to-staff communications over the last several months since the last time the President spoke to President Xi.</p>



<p>I just &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on the next conversation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;re at your time, if you need be going. &nbsp;Do you want to do one more?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; I&#8217;m at my time.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go around.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Mike.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a question on the Respect for Marriage Act.&nbsp; The President, after Dobbs, said he believed the right to privacy is at risk.&nbsp; Obviously, you, yesterday, said that the administration supports this bill.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing some Republican lawmakers in the House come out in favor of it, and McConnell says he won&#8217;t preview his vote on it until it reaches the Senate.&nbsp; So do you believe that Senate passage is actually in reach?&nbsp; And what is the President doing to get it closer to that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, as you know, and I said this yesterday, this is an issue when it comes to the right to marry, loving who you want to love.&nbsp; The President has been supportive of that for many, many years, clearly before he was the President, and he has been very vocal.</p>



<p>And so, first, I want to say that he strongly supports the bill, as you heard me say yesterday.&nbsp; He&#8217;s grateful that this has bipartisan support in the House, as we&#8217;re seeing it.</p>



<p>Right now there is a SAP, a statement of administration policy, that we sent out to show &#8212; continue to show our support.</p>



<p>Look, the President is always going to continue to speak on equal rights, especially as it relates to this particular piece on LGBTQ rights, equ- &#8212; marriage equality.&nbsp; This is not something that he will not stop talking about.&nbsp; He will make sure he is very clear.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a priority for him, hence why we did the SAP.</p>



<p>But I do want to take a step back, because I know that this has bipartisan support.&nbsp; You know, the exact reason for why this bill is being voted on is because of Republicans&#8217; assault on the recognition of Americans&#8217; right to privacy, which has been recognized and upheld over decades by judges appointed by a wide range of presidents that puts us here.&nbsp; That is why the House, you know, vote &#8212; had to vote &#8212; vote for this bill, because &#8212; so that we can protect people&#8217;s rights because of what we have seen these past several weeks.</p>



<p>The judges they&#8217;ve endorsed, for example; the state legislators they work with &#8212; they have said the quiet part out loud, which is they are coming for the right to marriage.</p>



<p>Justice Thomas &#8212; as I&#8217;ve said many times before, right here in this briefing room; as the President has said &#8212; explicitly in his concurring opinion said this.&nbsp; He was very clear about this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we need this legislation and urge Congress to move as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something the vast majority of country supports &#8212; of the country supports, just like they support restoring Roe, which is a priority for the President; stopping a national ban that we&#8217;re seeing from the ultra-MAGA who wants to make sure &#8212; who wants to make a national ban when it comes to abortion.</p>



<p>So, we have to keep &#8212; continue to speak out.&nbsp; And the President is going to continue to urge for Congress to act.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just want to follow up on that question.&nbsp; Is the White House speaking to Republicans about this bill &#8212; Senate Republicans about the bill?&nbsp; Because we are starting to see even some of the Republicans in the Senate say they would be interested in passing the bill if came to them.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And so we support that.&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is something that we are grateful to see.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you guys behind the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We are grateful to see.&nbsp; Look, we have multiple conversations with members in Congress, whether it&#8217;s a Republican or a Democrat.&nbsp; This is something our office does pretty regularly &#8212; the Office of Legislative Affairs.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything specific to share on the different conversations on this.&nbsp; But certainly we are in constant touch with members of Congress and their staff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what do you have to say to climate activists who feel like President Biden isn&#8217;t being urgent enough?&nbsp; So, you know, 20 percent of the U.S. population, about 60 million people, are going to see temperatures above 100 degrees Fahrenheit over the next few days.&nbsp; They&#8217;re constantly seeing how the Supreme Court is taking some of the power away from the agencies to do that work.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re &#8212; they want to see President Biden do more and do it quick &#8212; and do it quickly.&nbsp; We talked about him possibly doing this emergency declaration and that not being on the table. &nbsp;Why not just do it if it is so urgent, as you guys said?&nbsp; What is the hold-up?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, again, he is going to take an action tomorrow.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; That’s why we&#8217;re going to Massachusetts.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; Hopefully we&#8217;ll have a background call, like we normally do, to share specifically what that looks like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, I would disagree with the characterization of your question.&nbsp; The President has been one of the first &#8212; again, first folks and member &#8212; amongst the members on the Hill when he was senator to ring the bell &#8212; to ring the alarm bell on climate crisis.</p>



<p>He has been &#8212; he has taken action.&nbsp; He has been &#8212; you know, he has said, when he walked in, that the climate crisis was one of the crises &#8212; the four crises that he had to deal with.</p>



<p>He has taken action to meet the goals &#8212; very &#8212; very big goals, if you will &#8212; that he wants this country, our country to make in order to deal with the climate &#8212; climate crisis.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll continue to do that.</p>



<p>And so, again, this is one step.&nbsp; This is a continuing step of other steps that he has taken this past year, and we&#8217;ll see more actions from this President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You&#8217;re welcome.</p>



<p>4:31 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the U.S.-Africa Leaders&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/20/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-u-s-africa-leaders-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57881</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I look forward to hosting leaders from across the African continent in Washington, DC on December 13-15, 2022, for the U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit.&#160; The Summit will demonstrate the United States’ enduring commitment to Africa, and will underscore the importance of U.S.-Africa relations and increased cooperation on shared global priorities. The U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit will build&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I look forward to hosting leaders from across the African continent in Washington, DC on December 13-15, 2022, for the U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit.&nbsp; The Summit will demonstrate the United States’ enduring commitment to Africa, and will underscore the importance of U.S.-Africa relations and increased cooperation on shared global priorities.</p>



<p>The U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit will build on our shared values to better foster new economic engagement; reinforce the U.S.-Africa commitment to democracy and human rights; mitigate the impact of COVID-19 and of future pandemics; work collaboratively to strengthen regional and global health; promote food security; advance peace and security; respond to the climate crisis; and amplify diaspora ties.</p>



<p>I look forward to working with African governments, civil society, diaspora communities across the United States, and the private sector to continue strengthening our shared vision for the future of U.S.-Africa relations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on FDA and CDC Authorizing Novavax’s COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccine for&#160;Adults</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-fda-and-cdc-authorizing-novavaxs-covid-19-vaccine-for-adults/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 23:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today is another step forward in our nation’s fight against the virus. Following an independent scientific review by the Food and Drug Administration last week and today by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Novavax’s protein-based COVID-19 vaccine for adults has been authorized. We now have four safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines available to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today is another step forward in our nation’s fight against the virus. Following an independent scientific review by the Food and Drug Administration last week and today by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Novavax’s protein-based COVID-19 vaccine for adults has been authorized. We now have four safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines available to protect Americans against serious illness, hospitalizations, and death.<br> <br>When I took office, my Administration took decisive action to fix a broken COVID-19 response and stand up a historic vaccination program that has gotten over 260 million Americans at least their first shot, and nearly 110 million people a booster shot. This unprecedented effort has already saved over 2 million American lives, but more people need to roll up their sleeves, particularly as we confront BA.5.<br> <br>The science and data are clear: vaccines continue to protect people from serious illness, hospitalizations, and death—and with BA.5 increasing infections, it is essential that people get themselves and their kids vaccinated and stay up to date on their COVID-19 vaccinations. I encourage everyone to get their booster if they are eligible. If you’re age 50 or older, or a moderately or severely immunocompromised individual, and haven’t gotten a vaccine shot this year—you should get one right away. It is free, easy, and could save your life.<br> <br>Over the past 18 months, my Administration has left no stone unturned to ensure Americans have easy and convenient access to lifesaving tools, including vaccines, treatments, tests and more. These tools work even in the face of BA.5—they protect people, keep people out of the hospital, and save lives. While we know COVID-19 isn’t over, we can manage this moment and continue to minimize COVID-19’s impact on our daily lives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s New Executive Order to Bolster Efforts to Bring Home American Hostages and Wrongful&#160;Detainees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-new-executive-order-to-bolster-efforts-to-bring-home-american-hostages-and-wrongful-detainees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference(July 18, 2022) MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thank you all for joining this evening’s NSC background call on President Biden’s new executive order to bolster efforts to bring home American hostages and wrongful detainees. As a reminder of the ground rules, this call is on background attributable to “senior administration officials” and embargoed until&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>(July 18, 2022)</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thank you all for joining this evening’s NSC background call on President Biden’s new executive order to bolster efforts to bring home American hostages and wrongful detainees.</p>



<p>As a reminder of the ground rules, this call is on background attributable to “senior administration officials” and embargoed until tomorrow morning, Tuesday, July 19th at 9:00 a.m. Eastern Standard Time.</p>



<p>For your awareness but not for your reporting, today’s speakers are [senior administration official], [senior administration official], and [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I’ll turn it over to [senior administration official], our first speaker.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much, [moderator], and thanks to everyone for joining this call.&nbsp; We are eager to share how the Biden-Harris administration is expanding the toolkit that the U.S. government uses to help bring home American hostages and wrongful detainees.</p>



<p>Foreign states that engage in the practice of wrongful detention, whether it’s for political leverage or to seek concessions from the United States, threaten the integrity of the international political system and, moreover, the safety of US nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; And the same can be said of terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or other nefarious gains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. government maintains its unwavering commitment to bringing home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained.</p>



<p>And so that is why we are proud to announce that tomorrow, President Biden will be signing a new executive order that will provide new and expanded tools to help bring our citizens home and impose costs on the culprits as well as provide greater transparency regarding the risks.</p>



<p>The new executive order is entitled “Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained U.S. Nationals Home.”&nbsp; It reaffirms the fundamental commitment of the President, of the administration to bring home those Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>The executive order draws on the 2020 Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage Taking Accountability Act.&nbsp; And just as the name itself suggests, that law is a credit to the perseverance of the Levinson family and others who have turned their family’s extraordinary hardships into constructive and meaningful action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Frankly, all of us who work on these issues are blown away by the courage and the leadership the families in these awful circumstances show in an effort to make our government and all of us better in resolving these cases.</p>



<p>The new EO builds on those efforts and the efforts of others who have worked diligently to bring the Levinson Act to fruition, and it expands and strengthens the government’s toolkit in key ways.</p>



<p>For example, this EO reinforces U.S. government efforts to support the families of Americans wrongfully detained or held hostage overseas by directing parts of the federal government to bolster their engagement with such families and their sharing of relevant information, including intelligence information, with families regarding their loved ones’ status and the government’s efforts to secure their release or their return.</p>



<p>The new executive order also authorizes departments and agencies to impose costs and consequences on those who are involved.&nbsp; That includes financial sanctions and it includes visa bans, and it can apply whether the individual subject to those costs and consequences has acted on behalf of a state or a terrorist network or some other non-state actor.</p>



<p>This EO reflects the administration’s commitment not just to the issues generally, but to the families in particular, and it has been informed by the government’s regular engagements with them and other stakeholders who have and continue to undertake important, constructive advocacy efforts on behalf of their loved ones.</p>



<p>President Biden and those across the administration will now draw on this EO to advance our efforts, and we hope to do so in active conversation with family members and outside stakeholders.</p>



<p>In addition to the EO, tomorrow, the Biden-Harris administration will introduce a new risk indicator, the “D” for wrongful detention indicator, to the State Department’s travel advisories, which exist for all countries around the world to warn Americans of risks they may face in traveling to particular destinations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This new “D” indicator will, in particular, inform American travelers of the risk of wrongful detention by a foreign government, will highlight the elevated risk that Americans face in particular countries, and provide Americans with comprehensive safety and security information to use in making informed travel decisions.</p>



<p>Its transparency will also show to governments that engage in this sort of reprehensible practice, and indeed to the world, our commitment to calling out this sort of behavior.</p>



<p>The “D” indicator joins the existing “K” for kidnapping indicator that covers the risk of kidnapping and hostage taking by non-state actors as well as a range of other existing risk indicators.</p>



<p>State Department travel advisories are continuously revised and updated based on a comprehensive review of all available safety information and ongoing developments.</p>



<p>I should emphasize here that this work to punish those responsible for this sort of behavior, to increase transparency, to share risks about hostage taking and wrongful detention, all of this is in addition to the very hard, very important work that we do with the NSC, with State Department, the FBI, and other colleagues across the government every day to resolve particular hostage and wrongful detainee matters.&nbsp; This isn’t a substitute; it’s in addition.&nbsp; And it is a way to increase transparency through the indicator, impose costs through the executive order, and overall, try to prevent the next set of families going through this horrible ordeal.</p>



<p>I’ll now turn things over to our next speaker, [senior administration official], for additional context on the new EO and its implementation.&nbsp; And then you’ll hear from our final speaker, [senior administration official], for additional information on the update to our travel advisories.</p>



<p>Over to you, [senior administration official.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official], thanks a lot for that introduction, and thanks for bringing up this topic and also for convening this call.&nbsp; I know you’ve been at this since 2015 trying to work this problem set.&nbsp; So, grateful that you’re able to bring us all together to talk about this.</p>



<p>Folks, the President is once again demonstrating his commitment to bring home U.S. nationals held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad.&nbsp; And we continue to work closely across the administration to realize this prioritized commitment.</p>



<p>The EO is critical and gives the U.S. government expanded tools to help get Americans home, including specific authority to impose sanctions on those responsible for or complicit in wrongful detentions or hostage taking of U.S. persons overseas, regardless of whether the perpetrator is a terrorist or a state actor.</p>



<p>On the new sanctions authority for which the State Department will have the lead for developing targets, our goal is to bring folks home.&nbsp; So we use the sanctions authority with a primary focus on helping to secure a loved one’s release.</p>



<p>Now, using sanctions may not always help secure someone’s release, so we will therefore be judicious and strategic in our use of this authority.&nbsp; But the families of those held know their loved one’s case best and we intend to hear from them, hear their good ideas, and listen to their recommendations.</p>



<p>At this point, I’d like to turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for dialing in today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to take this opportunity to tell you about the parallel efforts to demonstrate our focus on this issue that [senior administration official] mentioned.&nbsp; And that is that tomorrow we’re introducing a new risk indicator, the “D” indicator, to the State Department’s travel advisories to inform U.S. travelers of the risk of wrongful detention by a foreign government.&nbsp; We’re making this change to highlight the elevated risk of wrongful detention in particular countries whose governments have engaged in that practice.</p>



<p>We’re committed to providing U.S. citizens with comprehensive safety and security information about foreign countries so they can make informed travel decisions before they head overseas.</p>



<p>The United States opposes wrongful detention and the practice of using individuals as political bargaining chips everywhere.&nbsp; These practices we know represent a threat to the safety of all U.S. citizens traveling and living abroad.</p>



<p>I’m sure you’ve all heard us say many times that we as a department have no higher priority than the safety and the security of U.S. citizens overseas.&nbsp; We definitely take extremely seriously our commitment to inform U.S. citizens living and traveling abroad of potential risks.&nbsp; And our travel advice is apolitical, fact-based, and transparent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] noted, we issue travel advisories for every country around the world offering standardized levels of advice based on established risk factors.&nbsp; Our advisories are based on the risk factors that include things like crime, for which we use a “C” indicator; health, for which we use an “H”; and [senior administration official] also mentioned the “K” indicator for kidnapping or hostage taking.</p>



<p>We’re also constantly reviewing our travel advisory system in an effort to provide the most accurate and transparent information for U.S. citizens traveling overseas.</p>



<p>We consider a lot of factors in determining which indicators to incorporate into the travel advisory for each country.&nbsp; The “D” indicator may be assigned to a given country following a department determination that the detention of a U.S. national is wrongful.&nbsp; The indicator will consider the number of cases of wrongful detentions of U.S. nationals in any given country to help determine the appropriate travel advisory level.</p>



<p>We routinely update our travel advisories for all countries based on that ongoing comprehensive review of all available safety information and ongoing developments.</p>



<p>So tomorrow, the following countries will receive the “D”-risk indicator: Burma, the People’s Republic of China, Iran, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, Russia, and Venezuela.</p>



<p>So on behalf of the State Department, I want to reiterate our commitment to bringing wrongfully held U.S. nationals home and to working closely with their families to do so.</p>



<p>My colleagues and I in Consular Affairs have a really strong partnership with our colleagues in SPEHA, with [senior administration official]’s team, and we remain in regular contact with the families of those held hostage or wrongfully detained.</p>



<p>We’re really proud of our partnership with SPEHA and with the White House, and we continue to work together to ensure we’re communicating and sharing information in a way that’s useful to the families and to the American public.</p>



<p>So I’ll stop there, and I look forward to answering your questions.&nbsp; Over.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; With that, I’ll turn it back over to the moderator for question-and-answer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking the call.&nbsp; A couple questions.&nbsp; Can we expect any sanctions announcements tomorrow along with the rollout of the executive order?&nbsp; And if so, on whom?&nbsp; How long has this executive order been in process, given the Levinson Act has been passed for quite a bit of time now?</p>



<p>And then, tangentially, there’s a number of families of detainees and hostages who are coming to D.C. this week.&nbsp; Will the President meet with any or all of them?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I’m happy to take a first stab.&nbsp; My colleagues may have thoughts as well.&nbsp; But thank you, Jennifer, for the good questions.</p>



<p>So I’ll take them in order.&nbsp; There won’t be particular sanctions targets announced tomorrow with the EO, but this is a process that we want and need to be sustainable for weeks and months to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other contexts &#8212; and I’m thinking of the human rights context in particular &#8212; the development of those sorts of packages has really generated constructive, productive collaboration, not just across the federal government &#8212; and, of course, this is, by definition, a new authority and we’ll work to build the backing to utilize it &#8212; but also between government and those outside it, with a robust dialogue on the potential targets of sanctions and the information that the government at least should consider in assessing those targets.</p>



<p>So we hope that this is a project that not only gets attention and focus within the government, as it will with the President’s direction coming tomorrow, but also with so many who work so hard on these issues outside government as well.</p>



<p>The executive order has been in development for a while now.&nbsp; Bringing something to the President’s desk obviously takes care and consideration by experts across the government.&nbsp; We also have had a number of steps that have been critical to implementing the Levinson Act, which was an important step forward through legislation.&nbsp; And that has included the use of the statutorily-defined elements for wrongful detention cases, which [senior administration official] may want to say a word about, but which have been used now in an important process that runs within the State Department.</p>



<p>Finally, I can’t speak to the President’s particular schedule, but I can speak to his commitment to these issues and to the priority he places on bringing home Americans held hostage abroad and wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>This executive order is, of course, one significant piece of that but it comes in the wake of efforts to &#8212; and successful efforts &#8212; to bring home Americans from countries really across the globe: Haiti, Afghanistan, Venezuela, Burma, and elsewhere, during the course of this administration.&nbsp; And he’ll continue to track these matters at the highest levels, including with the direct engagement of National Security Council staff leadership, State Department leadership, and others.</p>



<p>But let me see if my colleagues want to chime in on any of those three questions, as well, please.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; And, Jen, I guess the only thing I would say is that, you know, [senior administration official] indicated that a lot of work goes into this to make sure that it’s pretty much perfect when it gets to the President’s desk.&nbsp; I can tell you that we’ve been working pretty hard on this.&nbsp; The meetings have been continuous since the Levinson Act was passed pretty much.</p>



<p>And the idea was that we had to get this right.&nbsp; This is not something we want to rewind in any way, shape, or form.&nbsp; So we wanted to have a tool that was useful.&nbsp; And that took a long time to try to make sure that all the stakeholders got a chance to weigh in so we could find something that was going to be useful, powerful, and going to achieve the end states that we were hoping to achieve.</p>



<p>So it took a while, but if you want to get it right, sometimes you have to invest the time, and I think that’s the case here.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Shall we go to the next question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Recently, a lot of families have criticized the administration over what they see as a lack of strategies broadly.&nbsp; I mean, looking at your executive order, it talks about bolstering engagement, information sharing.&nbsp; A lot of them have been also complaining about lack of communication at times.</p>



<p>But, I mean, can you talk a little bit &#8212; are you able to talk a little bit about broader strategy in terms of what exactly the U.S. government is doing to bring these people home?&nbsp; Do you have a blanket strategy?&nbsp; And by that, I mean, you guys have also been criticized by the families for refusing to make some swaps on certain occasions, and so has there been any change, for example, in that approach?&nbsp; I understand this has to do with DOJ as well.&nbsp; But basically, what is your response to all of those criticisms?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for the question, and I’m sure [senior administration official] will have some thoughts on this as well.&nbsp; But let me say a couple things.</p>



<p>One, anyone who’s worked on these issues for any period of time knows that strategies need to be case specific.&nbsp; They have to be informed by the intelligence and information about a particular case.&nbsp; They need to take into account country-specific facts, regional facts, and really anything we can bring to bear to leverage to get what we all ultimately want, which is an American home with his or her loved ones.</p>



<p>Families are in regular contact with [senior administration official] and his team at the State Department, as well as for hostage cases, the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell, which is an interagency body that sits at FBI, and are part of conversations not just in developing strategies but also in refining those strategies and considering when it’s time to pivot to a plan B &#8212; and there always needs to be a plan B.</p>



<p>I would just emphasize in particular that in this administration, the President has been willing to make what he himself has said publicly are tough but important calls when it means bringing home Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’ll call attention, in particular, to his willingness to do what was necessary to bring home Trevor Reed from wrongful detention in Russia.&nbsp; It is, of course, public that that involved the release of Mr. Yaroshenko, who had served a great deal of but not all of his sentence in the United States.</p>



<p>And the President, as he said in his public statement that day, was willing to take that very rare, very extraordinary, very hard step when it meant bringing home someone for whom there was a great urgency to see home and to see healthy as well.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], do you have more you want to add?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Yeah, I wouldn’t mind adding just a little bit.</p>



<p>You know, this reminds me of that saying that “the other side always gets a vote.”&nbsp; And I’m always mindful in these cases that as we work on these different strategies &#8212; and as [senior administration official] said, they’re case specific &#8212; but as we’re executing them, at the end of the day, the other side, whether it’s Russia, China, Venezuela, et cetera, they get a vote.&nbsp; In a way, they have a very strong vote in that they hold the keys to the jail cell.&nbsp; And what we often find ourselves doing is trying to strategize and organize and, frankly, work with the families to find ways that might get those keys to open up and we can bring an American home.&nbsp; At times, it can be challenging.</p>



<p>I can tell you I probably spend one to four hours a day on the phone talking to family members.&nbsp; I’m currently away from Washington, D.C.&nbsp; I’m visiting a family tonight; will spend three hours in their home talking about their case.</p>



<p>But the bottom line is that we’re trying to partner with families to find these solutions.&nbsp; We definitely work strongly within the interagency on what we call the Hostage Recovery Enterprise.&nbsp; And frankly, we also work with members of Congress; the members and their staffers; NGOs; I would say, third-party intermediaries, but also even with the media, to come up with, I guess you would say, an overarching way of getting people back.&nbsp; And I think the media has been very powerful in really just calling awareness to this topic and, at times, even holding us accountable.</p>



<p>So, grateful for the chance to talk about this.&nbsp; But, really, to get to the meat of your question, we have ongoing strategies in all this.&nbsp; We review them pretty much on a daily basis, and we’ll partner with everyone we possibly can to see if we can bring this to a successful conclusion.</p>



<p>But I can tell you one thing: that the President of the United States, and my direct report, Secretary Blinken, they are committed to getting all these cases resolved and getting this done, and at the same time, start to bring up a deterrence strategy that can raise the cost of hostage taking and wrongful detention taking to the point that it’s no longer a feasible diplomatic strategy for those who would use it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Forgive me if I didn’t hear, but I didn’t hear a response to, especially, to Jennifer’s question about whether the President would be meeting with any of the families who were in town while they were here.</p>



<p>And if you could explain: If you are going to redefine when the administration can get involved, if they could get involved sooner with people wrongfully held &#8212; if you’re moving that bar. And if you can explain why Mark Fogel is not considered wrongfully detained, because his former colleagues and friends at the Embassy Moscow tell us that his conviction is for medical marijuana, and it seems very similar to the Griner case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for the questions.&nbsp; I’ll take a first stab and, again, invite colleagues to comment.</p>



<p>On the third one, I won’t comment &#8212; I don’t think any of us will &#8212; on a particular case, but refer you to the State Department which handles by law, by the Levinson Act, designations of those unlawfully or wrongfully detained.</p>



<p>I’ll reiterate that I can’t speak for the President’s schedule but can speak for his commitment to these issues and his willingness to authorize and indeed direct, as this executive order does, the parts of his government that can do really the two things [senior administration official] has emphasized that we need to do at the same time.</p>



<p>One is resolve the current cases and bring people home and, at the same time, add to the costs for those who engage in this behavior through the executive order; add to the transparency for American travelers and for the world by the new indicator; and overall, reduce the next generation, so to speak, of cases from arising in the first place.</p>



<p>And then, in terms of the definition of a “wrongful detainee,” that is something that is set out in the Levinson Act by federal law with a number of factors that the State Department is to consider in any particular case in reaching a conclusion as to whether a given American held abroad and acknowledged as such by a foreign government should be deemed wrongfully detained.</p>



<p>So we wouldn’t be able to redefine that via executive order, but [senior administration official] and others across the State Department are day-to-day, week-to-week implementing that in some very effective and informative ways that I think take that law, and the powerful advocacy that helped to get it passed by the Levinson family and so many other families, and showing the value of having that designation and entrenched in the U.S. code, the factors that inform it.</p>



<p>But let me turn to others for anything they’d like to add as well.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, it’s [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’ll jump in.&nbsp; The wrongful termination process, I guess you can say we will pull up a case, and then it becomes ongoing research to determine whether it starts to, using the Levinson criteria, look like a wrongful detention.</p>



<p>We’ve had some cases go very fast in that we get information, and it seems like the information is self-evident, and that leads to a rather quick determination.&nbsp; We have other cases where we’re constantly bringing in information and it finally, to an extent, kind of crosses the bar and it becomes a wrongful detention but only after more information was gathered.</p>



<p>And I can tell you that we never take a case and put it away.&nbsp; Once we take a look at a case, we’re constantly trying to, like, as I say, vacuum in information, whether it’s from family members, newspaper reports, the intelligence community, to see if we can get that little extra piece of evidence that might raise it to the bar of being a wrongful detention.</p>



<p>Some cases never really rise to that level because, for some reason or not, they’re not wrongful.&nbsp; You know, we keep getting information that doesn’t quite reach the level of being recommended for determination.</p>



<p>On the Fogel case, I probably shouldn’t talk about any cases that are ongoing.&nbsp; We’ve been looking at that for a while now.&nbsp; I spent a few hours on the Fogel case just last week trying to get more information on it.&nbsp; So it’s ongoing and active; we’re looking at it.&nbsp; But I’d rather not go into any more details on specific cases.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much for addressing this call.&nbsp; And based on those comments, I’m hoping you can provide some kind of comment.&nbsp; But I mean, is there anything that you could say in regards to how these efforts would impact Brittney Griner’s case or cases like hers, or anything you can say on efforts to secure her release?&nbsp; Any positive progress, discussion of a prisoner swap, for example?&nbsp; I would appreciate anything that you can share, even in general.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Again, I’m happy to start, and then we’ll let colleagues jump in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First of all, with respect to the executive order, there are a number of ways in which it would affect cases like that, cases in the wrongful detainee category.&nbsp; The executive order directs those across the executive branch to share consistent and accurate information with the families of those who are deemed wrongfully detained to ensure that they receive support and assistance throughout the ordeal and to work with parts of our government to try to impose costs on those responsible.</p>



<p>And as I indicated, those responsible can be government officials, and it’s really quite expansive language: “foreign persons determined…to be responsible for or complicit in, to have directly or indirectly engaged in…to be responsible for ordering, controlling or otherwise directing the hostage taking of a U.S. national or the wrongful detention of a U.S. national abroad,” or to have “attempted” to do so or indeed to have been the “leader…of an entity that has engaged” in that sort of activity.</p>



<p>And so as this authority gets implemented, it will, we hope, have a couple of effects.&nbsp; One is to impose consequences on those who’ve been part of this just abominable, inhumane practice; and in so doing, to generate over time a deterrent from others becoming part of that practice, as well, whether that’s at a broad leadership level or whether that’s particular individuals who realize there can be very personalized repercussions for engaging in this sort of activity.</p>



<p>And then, with respect to the travel indicator, of course this will help increase the transparency to Americans as they think about destinations, so they can factor in the State Department’s indication that, at least as of tomorrow &#8212; and this will be reviewed, as you heard &#8212; there are six countries where the risk of being wrongfully detained, held by a foreign government in order to be exploited or used as a bargaining chip, is very real for Americans in particular.</p>



<p>Let me invite colleagues to add to that as well.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think you covered it perfectly.&nbsp; Nothing to add.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; I agree entirely.&nbsp; The one thing I would flag is that the “D” indicator is a way of increasing transparency for the U.S. public traveling.&nbsp; We have for a long time highlighted the risk of wrongful detention in certain countries, but by flagging it in this very clear way, we are hopeful that there will be fewer cases of U.S. travelers choosing to go to certain countries where this risk is greater than in others.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], my first question is for you.&nbsp; You mentioned that sanctions might not work or be applicable for every single case.&nbsp; So I’m wondering if there are particular cases or clusters of cases in which you think sanctions might be most appropriate or most relevant, or if there’s a particular impetus for this part of the EO.</p>



<p>And then, [senior administration official], this notion of sharing additional information, being transparent with families, was, of course, a signature element of Presidential Policy Directive 30, which you were obviously an instrumental player in seven years ago.&nbsp; So I’m wondering why this element is being introduced again.&nbsp; Is there a sense that that action from 2015 didn’t go far enough in sharing information?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m just kind of curious whether there’s particular aspects or element or fact that wound up leading to this new action. Thank you so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, Eric.&nbsp; It’s [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’ll jump on and then they’ll turn over to [senior administration official], if that’s okay &#8212; although I may be asking &#8212; answering part of the question that you might have directed to him.</p>



<p>I mean, the Levinson Act, essentially, in public law, asks us to look into creating a sanctioning authority and sanctioning ability.&nbsp; And in wrestling with that over almost the last year and a half, this is the road that we’ve taken, and that seems to be a pretty good one.</p>



<p>So if there’s a reason why it’s coming out now, it’s really because it’s finally done.&nbsp; And it’s something that we’ve been working on based on what we were directed to by public law.</p>



<p>In terms of whether it can be used, I mean, obviously, I might have a country or two or three that I might be thinking about, but to be honest, I want to talk to the families.&nbsp; The families follow this case, as we do.&nbsp; We follow the cases, as you can imagine.&nbsp; But the families have a particular amount of depth to each one of their cases, for obvious reasons, and we would like to, in our engagements with them, kind of see who they think might be up for the targeting process.&nbsp; And we’d like to work with them a little bit.</p>



<p>So even though I might have a country or two where I think this might be a tool that could be put into action, I think I’m going to, kind of, withhold my fire for now until we can talk to the families and build up a strategy, because I don’t want to do that &#8212; what is it called? &#8212; like, “ready, fire, aim.”&nbsp; I want to do “ready, aim, fire.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to make sure that this is integrated into our ongoing strategy and that it has impact.&nbsp; What I don’t want to do is do something where we use a pretty powerful tool but do not get the result that we want to achieve, and that’s bringing people home and then creating that deterrent effect.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], can I turn it over to you to see if you can hit some of this and his other question?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great answers.&nbsp; And I’ll just flesh out a little bit on one of them, totally consistent with what [senior administration official] has said, which is: The focus of Presidential Policy Directive 30, in many ways, not in all ways, was in hostage cases rather than detainee cases. Now, it accounted for the latter.&nbsp; It specifically assigned the role of Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs to include working diplomatic engagements for cases in which a foreign government confirms, acknowledges that it’s detained a U.S. national but our government regards such detention as unlawful or wrongful.&nbsp; That is language that, as [senior administration official] said, was then picked up by Congress in the Levinson Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And indeed, PPD 30 did take account of the fact there would need to be family engagement for those cases as well.&nbsp; It explicitly made available to the State Department the family engagement coordinator that was being built at the time at the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell.</p>



<p>But over time, the cases that are in the detainee category &#8212; the “foreign government held,” “foreign government acknowledge” category &#8212; have risen in both number and degree of difficulty.&nbsp; And that is something that Americans see every day with some of the cases that are in the headlines.</p>



<p>And so the Levinson Act took an important step forward in entrenching some of the reforms set out in PPD 30, not just for hostage cases, but also for detainee cases.&nbsp; This implements that; it takes it forward.</p>



<p>And indeed, in some ways, one key theme of both the executive order that will be announced tomorrow, as well as the “D” indicator, is that they continue to elevate the priority being placed on the “government held,” “government acknowledged” wrongful detainee cases and enhance the toolbox available to us across the government in addressing those cases, which ultimately means resolving the current ones and trying to warn about and deter future ones.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And that is all the questions that we have time for.&nbsp; [Moderator], we’ll turn it back over to you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining this call this evening.&nbsp; As a reminder of the ground rules, the call was held on background with the speakers attributable to “senior administration officials,” and it is under embargo until tomorrow morning at 9:00 a.m. Eastern.</p>



<p>Thank you very much.&nbsp; I hope everyone has a wonderful evening.</p>



<p>&nbsp;END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Message to the Congress on Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United&#160;States Nationals&#160;Home</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/message-to-the-congress-on-bolstering-efforts-to-bring-hostages-and-wrongfully-detained-united-states-nationals-home/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order declaring a national emergency with respect to hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United&#160;States nationals. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order declaring a national emergency with respect to hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United&nbsp;States nationals.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals are heinous acts that undermine the rule of law.&nbsp; Terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or other gain &#8212; as well as foreign states that engage in the practice of wrongful detention, including for political leverage or to seek concessions from the United States &#8212; threaten the integrity of&nbsp;the international political system and the safety of United&nbsp;States nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; I have determined that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 19, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United&#160;States Nationals&#160;Home</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/19/executive-order-on-bolstering-efforts-to-bring-hostages-and-wrongfully-detained-united-states-nationals-home/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-taking Accountability Act (22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.) (Levinson Act), the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-taking Accountability Act (22 U.S.C. 1741 <em>et seq.</em>) (Levinson Act), the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.) (NEA), section 212(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952 (8 U.S.C. 1182(f)), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code,</p>



<p>I, Joseph R. Biden JR., President of the United States of America, find that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals are heinous acts that undermine the rule of law. &nbsp;Terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or&nbsp;other gain &#8212; as well as foreign states that engage in the practice of wrongful detention, including for political leverage or to seek concessions from the United States &#8212; threaten the&nbsp;integrity of the international political system and the safety&nbsp;of United States nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; I&nbsp;therefore determine that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; I hereby declare a national emergency to deal with this threat.</p>



<p>The United States Government must redouble its efforts at home and with partners abroad to deter these practices and to secure the release of those held as hostages or wrongfully detained.&nbsp; Processes established under Executive Order 13698 of June 24, 2015 (Hostage Recovery Activities) and Presidential Policy Directive 30 of June 24, 2015 (U.S. Nationals Taken Hostage Abroad and Personnel Recovery Efforts) (PPD-30) have facilitated close interagency coordination on efforts to secure the safe release of United States nationals taken hostage abroad, including engagement with the families of hostages and support of diplomatic engagement with partners abroad.&nbsp; This order reinforces the roles, responsibilities, and commitments contained in those directives and seeks to ensure that &#8212; as with hostage recovery activities &#8212; interagency coordination, family engagement, and diplomatic tools are enshrined in United&nbsp;States Government efforts to secure the safe release and return of United States nationals wrongfully detained by foreign state actors.&nbsp; This order also reinforces tools to deter and to impose tangible consequences on those responsible for, or complicit in, hostage-taking or the wrongful detention of a&nbsp;United States national abroad.</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby order:</p>



<p><a><u>Section</u></a> 1.&nbsp; <a></a>Executive Order 13698 and PPD-30 shall continue to apply to United States hostage recovery activities.&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall alter the responsibilities of the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell (HRFC), the Hostage Response Group (HRG), or the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs (SPEHA), established by Executive Order 13698, with respect to hostage recovery activities under Executive Order 13698 or PPD-30.&nbsp; Nor shall this order alter the scope of PPD-30, which applies to both suspected and confirmed hostage-takings in which a United&nbsp;States national is abducted or held outside of the United&nbsp;States, as well as to other hostage-takings occurring abroad in which the United States has a national interest, but does not apply if a foreign government confirms that it has detained a United States national.</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The HRG shall, in coordination with the National Security Council&#8217;s regional directorates as appropriate, convene on a regular basis and as needed at the request of the National Security Council to work to secure the safe release of United States nationals held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The HRG, in support of the Deputies Committee of the National Security Council and consistent with the process outlined in National Security Memorandum 2 of February 4, 2021 (Renewing the National Security Council System), or any successor memorandum, shall:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;identify and recommend options and strategies to the President through the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to secure the recovery of hostages or the return of wrongfully detained United States nationals;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;coordinate the development and implementation of policies, strategies, and procedures for the recovery of hostages or the return of wrongfully detained United States nationals;</p>



<p>(iii) &nbsp;coordinate and deconflict policy guidance, strategies, and activities that potentially affect the recovery or welfare of United States nationals held hostage or the return or welfare of United States nationals wrongfully detained abroad, including reviewing proposed recovery or return options;</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;receive regular updates from the HRFC, the Office of the SPEHA, and other executive departments and agencies (agencies), as the HRG deems appropriate, on the status of United States nationals being held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad and measures being taken to effect safe releases;</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;receive regular updates from the Department of State on all new wrongful detention determinations; and</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;where higher-level guidance is required, make recommendations to the Deputies Committee of the National Security Council.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The SPEHA shall report to the Secretary of State on a regular basis and as needed to advance efforts to secure the safe release of United States nationals wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The SPEHA shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;coordinate diplomatic engagements and strategy regarding hostage and wrongful detention cases, in coordination with the HRFC and relevant agencies, as appropriate and consistent with policy guidance communicated through the HRG;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;share information, including information acquired during consular interactions and engagements, regarding wrongful detention cases with relevant agencies to facilitate close interagency coordination;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; draw on the experience and expertise of the HRFC to support efforts to return wrongfully detained United States nationals, including by providing support and assistance to the families of those wrongfully detained;</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;develop and regularly update, in coordination with relevant agencies, strategies for wrongful detention cases for review by the HRG;</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ensure, in coordination with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, that relevant agencies have access to necessary information, including intelligence information, on wrongful detention cases to inform strategies and options; and</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;share, in coordination with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, relevant information, including intelligence information, on developments in wrongful detention cases with the families of wrongfully detained United States nationals, in a timely manner, as appropriate and consistent with the protection of sources and methods.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; To ensure that the United States Government provides a&nbsp;coordinated, effective, and supportive response to wrongful detentions, the Secretary of State shall identify adequate resources to enable the SPEHA to:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ensure that all interactions by executive branch officials with the family of a wrongfully detained United States national occur in a coordinated fashion and that the family receives consistent and accurate information from the United States Government, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;provide support and assistance to wrongfully detained United States nationals and their families throughout their detention, including through coordination with the HRFC, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law; and</p>



<p>(iii) &nbsp;provide support and assistance to United States nationals upon their return to the United States from wrongful detention, including through coordination with the HRFC and the Department of Health and Human Services, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law.</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; The SPEHA, in coordination with the HRG, the HRFC, and relevant agencies, as appropriate, shall identify and recommend options and strategies to the President through the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to reduce the likelihood of United States nationals being held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad.&nbsp; The options shall seek to counter and deter hostage-takings and wrongful detentions by terrorist organizations, foreign governments, and other actors by imposing costs on those who participate in, support, or facilitate such conduct.&nbsp; The strategies shall seek to deter any effort to engage in hostage-taking or the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad through cooperation with like-minded foreign governments and organizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 5.&nbsp; The Secretary of State shall publicly or privately designate or identify officials of foreign governments who are involved, directly or indirectly, in wrongful detentions, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, including section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2022 (Division K of Public Law 117-103).</p>



<p>Sec. 6.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;All property and interests in property of the following persons that are in the United States, that hereafter come within the United States, or that are or hereafter come within the possession or control of any United States person, are blocked and may not be transferred, paid, exported, withdrawn, or otherwise dealt in:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;any foreign person determined by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Attorney General:</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; to be responsible for or complicit in, to have directly or indirectly engaged in, or to be&nbsp;responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the hostage-taking of a United States national or the wrongful detention of a United States national abroad;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; to have attempted to engage in any activity described in subsection (a)(i)(A) of this section; or</p>



<p>(C) &nbsp;to be or have been a leader or official of an entity that has engaged in, or whose members have engaged in, any of the activities described in subsections (a)(i)(A) or (a)(i)(B) of this section relating to the leader&#8217;s or official&#8217;s tenure;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; any foreign person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General:</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; to have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp; any activity described in subsection (a)(i)(A) of this section; or</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; to be owned, controlled, or directed by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order; or</p>



<p>(C)&nbsp; to have attempted to engage in any activity described in subsection (a)(ii)(A) of this section.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or any license or permit granted prior to the date of this order.<a></a></p>



<p>Sec. 7.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The unrestricted immigrant and nonimmigrant entry into the United States of noncitizens determined to meet one or more of the criteria set forth in section 6(a) of this order would be detrimental to the interests of the United States, and the entry of such persons into the United States, as immigrants or nonimmigrants, is hereby suspended, except when the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, determines that the person&#8217;s entry would not be contrary to the interests of the United States, including when the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, so determines, based on a recommendation of the Attorney General, that the person&#8217;s entry would further important United States law enforcement objectives.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretary of State shall implement this authority as it applies to visas pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, may establish.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Secretary of Homeland Security shall implement this order as it applies to the entry of noncitizens pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may establish.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; Such persons shall be treated by this section in the same manner as persons covered by section 1 of Proclamation 8693 of July 24, 2011 (Suspension of Entry of Aliens Subject to United Nations Security Council Travel Bans and International Emergency Economic Powers Act Sanctions).</p>



<p>Sec. 8.&nbsp; <a></a><a></a>I hereby determine that the making of donations of the types of articles specified in section 203(b)(2) of IEEPA (50 U.S.C. 1702(b)(2)) by, to, or for the benefit of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order would seriously impair my ability to deal with the national emergency declared in this order, and I hereby prohibit such donations as provided by section 6 of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 9.&nbsp; <a></a>(a)&nbsp; Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p>Sec. 10.&nbsp; For those persons whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order who might have a constitutional presence in the United States, I find that because of the ability to transfer funds or other assets instantaneously, prior notice to such persons of measures to be&nbsp;taken pursuant to this order would render those measures ineffectual.&nbsp; I therefore determine that for these measures to be effective in addressing the national emergency declared in this order, there need be no prior notice of a listing or determination made pursuant to section 6 of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 11.  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.  The Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.  All agencies of the United States Government shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to carry out the provisions of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 12.&nbsp; <a></a>Nothing in this order shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the United States Government by employees, grantees, or contractors thereof.</p>



<p>Sec. 13.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to submit recurring and final reports to the Congress on the national emergency declared in this order, consistent with section 401(c) of the NEA (50 U.S.C. 1642(c)) and section 204(c) of IEEPA (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1703(c)).</p>



<p>Sec. 14.&nbsp; For purposes of this order:&nbsp;</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; the term &#8220;foreign person&#8221; means any citizen or national of a foreign state (including any such individual who is also a citizen or national of the United States, provided such individual does not reside in the United States) or any entity not organized solely under the laws of the United States or existing solely in the United States;</p>



<p>(c)  the term &#8220;hostage-taking&#8221; has the same meaning as provided in PPD-30, which is the unlawful abduction or holding of a person or persons against their will in order to compel a third person or governmental organization to do or to abstain from doing any act as a condition for the release of the person detained;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; the term &#8220;noncitizen&#8221; means any person who is not a citizen or noncitizen national of the United States;</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity;</p>



<p>(f)&nbsp; the term &#8220;United States national&#8221; means:</p>



<p>(i)   a &#8220;national of the United States&#8221; as defined in 8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22) or 8 U.S.C. 1408; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; a lawful permanent resident with significant ties to the United States;</p>



<p>(g)&nbsp; the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States; and</p>



<p>(h)  the term &#8220;wrongful detention&#8221; means a detention that the Secretary of State has determined to be wrongful consistent with section 302(a) of the Levinson Act.</p>



<p>Sec. 15.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of&nbsp;Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 19, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
