<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 22:07:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Air Force Two&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/15/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-air-force-two-departure-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 22:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53298</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George’s County, Maryland THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hi.&#160; So, we are &#8212; I&#8217;m leading a delegation on behalf of the President and our administration to express our condolences.&#160; The United States takes quite seriously the strength of our relationship and partnership with UAE.&#160; And we are going there, then, to express our condolences,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Joint Base Andrews<br><em>Prince George’s County, Maryland</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; So, we are &#8212; I&#8217;m leading a delegation on behalf of the President and our administration to express our condolences.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States takes quite seriously the strength of our relationship and partnership with UAE.&nbsp; And we are going there, then, to express our condolences, but also as an expression of our commitment to the strength of that relationship and continuing to strengthen that relationship.<br><br>I&#8217;ll speak also about what happened in Buffalo.&nbsp; It&#8217;s horrendous.&nbsp; It&#8217;s horrendous.&nbsp; In our country, we have to recognize that we may very well be experiencing an epidemic of hate towards so many Americans that is wrong.&nbsp; It is taking on a level of violence &#8212; in the case of what happened in Buffalo, and we&#8217;ve seen it in other places in our country.&nbsp; And we all must speak out against it.<br><br>Hate against any one of us, we should interpret as being hate against all of us, as a nation.&nbsp; We are a nation that prides ourselves on our diversity as an element of our strength.&nbsp; And to see what has happened yesterday &#8212;<br><br>An 86-year-old grandmother who had just been taking care of her husband in a nursing home, was just going to get some groceries.<br><br>A security guard who dedicated his life as a law enforcement officer and was known in the community to be one of the kindest, most gentle people, who showed extraordinary heroism.<br><br>I think we all have to know that this is something that we have to not only speak about, but we&#8217;ve got to do everything in our power as a nation to stop it &#8212; to stop it.&nbsp; There&#8217;s too much at stake that we should be working at and thinking about, not hating one another.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at the National Peace Officers’ Memorial&#160;Service</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-national-peace-officers-memorial-service/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 21:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. CapitolWashington, D.C. 12:28 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  President Yoes; Auxiliary President Hennie; Auxiliary President Lehmann; and Director and good friend Jimmy Pasco &#8212; we&#8217;ve worked together a long time: Thank you for inviting me to join you today and for the service you&#8217;ve extended to this nation.  I’d also like to thank the Attorney&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">U.S. Capitol<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>12:28 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  President Yoes; Auxiliary President Hennie; Auxiliary President Lehmann; and Director and good friend Jimmy Pasco &#8212; we&#8217;ve worked together a long time: Thank you for inviting me to join you today and for the service you&#8217;ve extended to this nation. <br><br>I’d also like to thank the Attorney General &#8212; General Garland; Attorney General Gupta; Homeland Security Secretary Mayorkas; and the Directors of the FBI and Secret Service;  Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms; the U.S.  Marshalls Service; U.S. Capitol Police &#8212; all for being here, but for your leadership. <br><br>We’re also joined by my long-time friends, Senator Patrick Leahy and House Majority Leader Steny Hoyer. <br><br>Before I begin, let me say a word about yesterday’s mass shooting in Buffalo, New York.  A lone gunman, armed with weapons of war and a hate-filled soul, shot and killed 10 innocent people in cold blood at a grocery story on Saturday afternoon. <br><br>Jill and I, like all of you, pray for the victims and their families and a devastated community.<br><br>I’ve been receiving updates from my team at the White House that’s in close contact with the Justice Department.  We&#8217;re still gathering the facts, but already the Justice Department has stated publicly that it is investigating the matter as a hate crime, a racially motivated act of white supremacy and violent extremism.  <br><br>As they do, we must all work together to address the hate that remains a stain on the soul of America.  Our hearts are heavy once again, but our resolve must never, ever waver.  <br><br>No one understands this more than the people sitting in front of me &#8212; moms, dads, children, family members &#8212; about how those folks in Buffalo feel today when they got the call.  They&#8217;re pulled into &#8212; it&#8217;s as if you get pulled into a black hole in your chest and there&#8217;s no way out.<br><br>Jill and I know &#8212; we know no memorial, no gestures can fill the void in the hearts they have now or that you &#8212; you who have lost someone feel as well.<br><br>Being here today and hearing the name of your husband, wife, father, mother, son, daughter, brother, sister brings it all back as if you just got that phone call 10 minutes ago.<br><br>The American people, we owe you.  You know, you (inaudible) down the street, you&#8217;re normal families, all neighbors.  And every day, you worry and you worry you&#8217;d get that phone call when they pinned on that shield.  And now you look at an empty chair.<br><br>Although I didn’t personally know your husbands, wives, sons, daughters, brothers, sisters, I knew them.  They were the first ones to run into help when everyone else ran away when we were kids, when we were young men and women.  Even in grade school, they&#8217;d jump in when someone else was threatened or being bullied, regardless of the odds.<br><br>Think about it.  It was part of their DNA.  They didn&#8217;t think about it in terms of serving and protecting and defending, but that&#8217;s what they did.  They served even before they put on that shield.  They protected.  And they were there.<br><br>Being a police officer is not just what they did.  It’s who they were.<br><br>I was telling the president of this organization, I grew up in a neighborhood where you became a cop, a firefighter, or a priest.  I wasn&#8217;t qualified for any of them, so here I am.  (Laughter.)  <br><br>But all kidding aside, we expect so much from our law enforcement officers today.  This is a different world we&#8217;re in.  Just in the last several years, it&#8217;s so much more complicated.  The job is complicated.   <br><br>Yet we expect so much more of all of you.  We expect you to be drug counselors for the 100,000 overdose deaths that took place this year &#8212; 100,000.  <br><br>We expect you to counsel those who speak to a couple in the midst of a violent confrontation of a husband and wife, man and woman.  So many of you are &#8212; literally and figuratively get caught in the crossfire.  You&#8217;re not trained psychologists; you&#8217;re law enforcement officers.<br><br>We expect you to be everything.  We expect everything of you.  Being a cop today is a heck of a lot harder than it’s ever been.  COVID-19 &#8212; one million deaths in America, leaving behind, the estimates indicate, nine significant family members or others who also look at that empty chair at the kitchen table.  So many kids left behind because of COVID and schools closing down.<br><br>You engage in longer shifts.  The strain and stress of it all is why I continue to be so committed to do more, do better to keep you safe, to keep our communities safe, and to build trust and respect that everyone deserves, particularly all of you.<br><br>We should focus on and fund the things we know that work, like crime prevention and community policing.  Not one cop in a car, but two walking the street.  Cops who walk the beat, who know the neighborhood, who can restore trust and safety. <br><br>Folks, the answer is not to abandon the streets.  It’s not to choose between safety and equal justice.  And we should agree: It’s not to defund the police.  It’s to fund the police.  Fund them with the resources, the training &#8212; (applause) &#8212; they need to protect our communities and themselves and restore trust among the police and the people. <br><br>My dad used to say &#8212; when someone would say, &#8220;Let me tell you what I value, Joe.&#8221;  He&#8217;d look at them and say, &#8220;Don’t tell me what you…&#8221;  My dad was a well-read, high-school-educated man who was a graceful man.  He&#8217;d say, &#8220;Don&#8217;t tell me what you value.  Show me your budget, and I will tell you what you value.&#8221;<br><br>Well, here’s what I value.  As soon as I came to office, we inherited a raging pandemic, with only 2 million people vaccinated.  We needed to rebuild our economy and restore public safety.  <br><br>We understood the risk that communities could face with rising violence during the pandemic and at a time when state and local budgets were shrinking because they didn&#8217;t have the tax base.  They were having to lay off cops, firefighters, teachers.  They were under tremendous strain.<br><br>So, we made sure we passed a thing called the American Rescue Plan, providing historic $350 billion directly to the cities and counties and states and Tribes so they didn&#8217;t have to lay off law enforcement.  They could keep the cops on the job and fight to keep communities safe. <br><br>And it’s working.  More than 300 communities, from big cities to small towns, are using more than $10 billion of American Rescue Plan funds for violence prevention and public safety this year &#8212; building new police training facilities; recruiting, which is getting harder; hiring; and giving policemen a raise; partnering with the federal, state, and local community groups to reduce gun violence; investing in community interventions that use trusted community members to work directly with people who are most likely to commit gun crimes or become the victims of gun crimes and intervene before it’s too late. <br><br>My mother used to say, &#8220;Out of everything bad, something good will come if you look hard enough for it.&#8221;  Well, we&#8217;re looking hard to determine why and what we can do to prevent that law enforcement officer being put in the middle.<br><br>I’m encouraging every mayor, governor to use the American resource money they have, and they have it now.  You spend it now &#8212; this summer, when crime historically spikes.<br><br>And this Rescue funding for police is part of a comprehensive strategy to combat violence in America.  I&#8217;ve laid out this plan to all the police agencies, and they&#8217;re taking a good look at it.<br><br>With my budget last year, we increased funding for state and local law enforcement by almost &#8212; well, not almost &#8212; 29 percent.  That included significant investment in Community Oriented Policing Services &#8212; the “COPS” program designed to build legitimacy and trust in communities, to address violent crime, to combat hate and extremism. </p>



<p>My budget for next year doubles the investment in community policing &#8212; $<s>573</s>&nbsp;[537] million, the most in over a decade.&nbsp;&nbsp;And on top of that, it includes $30 billion in new mandatory investments in law enforcement and crime prevention.&nbsp;<br><br>During my State of the Union Address, I announced what I called a Unity Agenda that brings the country together to address the big challenges we face.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And one of those included ending the opioid edemic [sic] &#8212; epidemic and addressing the mental health crisis.&nbsp; So many, young and old, because of this pandemic, need help.&nbsp; And having a problem &#8212; a mental problem &#8212; is no different that breaking your arm or your leg.&nbsp; You need invest in systems that provide adequate healthcare, counseling drug treatment, prevention, housing, education, and other social services to those that need it most.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, in most places, you serve your time in prison, you get a bus ticket and 25 bucks, and you end up under the same bridge you got arrested under the first time.&nbsp; They should have access to education and housing.&nbsp; Give them a chance to move beyond where they were.<br><br>And I’m committed to investing in mental health services so we have more school counselors, psychologists, and social workers working alongside you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, we have to do more to protect our officers’ mental health and emotional well-being.&nbsp; Suicide was the second-highest cause of death for law enforcement officers in 2021, surpassed only by COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Last November, I signed laws that extended critical peer counseling and mental health resources for officers, expanded elibilit- &#8212; eligibility for benefits for first responders who were disabled in the line of duty.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not unusual.&nbsp;<br><br>We wonder &#8212; we were talking briefly about the impact on the &#8212; post-traumatic stress.&nbsp; How many police officers have, multiple times, been put in line and had to do things that they didn&#8217;t have to &#8212; think they&#8217;d have to do?<br><br>We recognize it with our military.&nbsp; More people continue to die from post-traumatic stress at home than die in any wars that are going on now &#8212; 20 a week.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; We face up to it and help these folks &#8212; everyone.<br><br>There are other areas we need to continue to work on together.&nbsp; Forty percent of all the calls that result in an officer’s death are calls to intervene in a domestic violence dispute.&nbsp; Let me say it again: Forty percent.<br><br>You expect officers to have degrees in psychology?&nbsp; Do we expect them to have things that are beyond the capacity of any PhD or doc or anybody else?<br><br>That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important to get reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act, providing critical resources for law enforcement.<br><br>And I want to acknowledge law enforcement’s constructive role in trying to reach an agreement on meaningful policing legislation in Congress.&nbsp; We haven’t gotten there yet, but we must get there to strengthen public trust and public safety.&nbsp;<br><br>2021 was one of the strongest years on record when it comes to federal support delivered to state and local law enforcement.&nbsp; But while these are important steps, there&#8217;s much more work to be done.&nbsp; I’m committed to being your partner, as I always have.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me close with this.&nbsp; Jill and I know how it is when there&#8217;s a memorial service for our son, who won the Bronze Star and Conspicuous Service Medal in Iraq.&nbsp; We were proud, but we also &#8212; it&#8217;s bittersweet, because you remember everything.<br><br>I want to thank the families that are here.&nbsp; It really takes courage to show up, because everything comes back.&nbsp; Everything comes back.<br><br>A short walk from here at the National Law Enforcement Memorial, there is a quote engraved on the wall.&nbsp; And the quote goes, &#8220;It is not how these officers died that made them heroes, it is how they lived.&#8221;<br><br>To the families, Jill and I &#8212; we have some idea how hard it is.&nbsp; But I promise you: The day will come when the memory of your loved one &#8212; you open that closet door and you smell the scent, or you go by that park you used to walk in, or you hear that song.&nbsp; The day will come when it will bring a smile to your lips before it brings a tear to your eyes.&nbsp; And through your pain and your will to find a purpose worthy of how they lived, you&#8217;ll get through it.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s nothing easy about it.<br><br>Our hope and prayer is that we as a nation find that purpose as well.&nbsp; May the souls of those who you loved and those with whom you served rest in peace and rise in glory.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our police and our troops.&nbsp; God bless you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>12:46 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the United Arab Emirates to Pay Respects Upon the Death of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan, President of the United Arab&#160;Emirates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/15/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-united-arab-emirates-to-pay-respects-upon-the-death-of-his-highness-sheikh-khalifa-bin-zayed-al-nahyan-president/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential&#160;Delegation to&#160;Abu Dhabi,&#160;United Arab Emirates,&#160;to&#160;pay respects upon the death of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed&#160;Al&#160;Nahyan, President of the United Arab Emirates, on May&#160;16, 2022. &#160; The Honorable&#160;Kamala Harris,&#160;Vice President of the United States&#160;of America,&#160;will lead the delegation. Members of the Presidential Delegation: Mr.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential&nbsp;Delegation to&nbsp;Abu Dhabi,&nbsp;United Arab Emirates,&nbsp;to&nbsp;pay respects upon the death of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed&nbsp;Al&nbsp;Nahyan, President of the United Arab Emirates, on May&nbsp;16, 2022. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The Honorable&nbsp;Kamala Harris,&nbsp;Vice President of the United States&nbsp;of America,&nbsp;will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</strong></p>



<p>Mr. Sean Murphy,&nbsp;Chargé&nbsp;d’Affaires&nbsp;ad interim, U.S. Embassy Abu Dhabi</p>



<p>The Honorable&nbsp;Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States</p>



<p>The Honorable Lloyd&nbsp;J.&nbsp;Austin&nbsp;III, Secretary of Defense of the United States</p>



<p>The Honorable John F. Kerry, Special Presidential Envoy for Climate</p>



<p>The Honorable Philip Gordon, Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor to the Vice President</p>



<p>The Honorable William Burns, Director of the Central Intelligence Agency</p>



<p>The Honorable Brett McGurk, Deputy Assistant to the President and&nbsp;Coordinator for the Middle East and North Africa, National Security Council</p>



<p>The Honorable Barbara Leaf, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for the Middle East and North Africa, National Security Council</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Harris on Mass Shooting in Buffalo, New York&#160;</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/15/statement-by-vice-president-harris-on-mass-shooting-in-buffalo-new-york/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 16:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today our hearts are broken and we grieve for the victims of the horrific act of gun violence in Buffalo and for their families and friends.  The Second Gentleman and I are praying for all those who knew and lost love ones.  Law enforcement is proceeding with its investigation, but what is clear is that we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today our hearts are broken and we grieve for the victims of the horrific act of gun violence in Buffalo and for their families and friends.  The Second Gentleman and I are praying for all those who knew and lost love ones. <br> <br>Law enforcement is proceeding with its investigation, but what is clear is that we are seeing an epidemic of hate across our country that has been evidenced by acts of violence and intolerance.  We must call it out and condemn it. Racially-motivated hate crimes or acts of violent extremism are harms against all of us, and we must do everything we can to ensure that our communities are safe from such acts. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Mass Shooting in Buffalo, New&#160;York</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/14/statement-by-president-biden-on-mass-shooting-in-buffalo-new-york/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 03:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tonight, we grieve for the families of ten people whose lives were senselessly taken and everyone who is suffering the physical and emotional wounds of this horrific shooting. We are grateful for the bravery of members of law enforcement and other first responders who took immediate action to try to protect and save lives. The First Lady and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tonight, we grieve for the families of ten people whose lives were senselessly taken and everyone who is suffering the physical and emotional wounds of this horrific shooting. We are grateful for the bravery of members of law enforcement and other first responders who took immediate action to try to protect and save lives. The First Lady and I are praying for the victims and their families, and hearts all across this country are with the people of Buffalo.</p>



<p>We still need to learn more about the motivation for today’s shooting as law enforcement does its work, but we don’t need anything else to state a clear moral truth: A racially motivated hate crime is abhorrent to the very fabric of this nation. Any act of domestic terrorism, including an act perpetrated in the name of a repugnant white nationalist ideology, is antithetical to everything we stand for in America. Hate must have no safe harbor. We must do everything in our power to end hate-fueled domestic terrorism.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Kirsten Allen on the Vice President’s Travel to United Arab Emirates&#160;</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/14/statement-by-press-secretary-kirsten-allen-on-the-vice-presidents-travel-to-united-arab-emirates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 16:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53273</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris will travel to Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates on May 16 to lead a Presidential Delegation and offer condolences on behalf of the Biden-Harris Administration and the American people on the passing of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan. She will meet with His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris will travel to Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates on May 16 to lead a Presidential Delegation and offer condolences on behalf of the Biden-Harris Administration and the American people on the passing of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan. She will meet with His Highness Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, President of the United Arab Emirates. In addition to honoring the memory and the legacy of Sheikh Khalifa, the Vice President will underscore the strength of the partnership between our countries and our desire to further deepen our ties in the coming months and years.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan election as President of the United Arab&#160;Emirates </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/14/statement-by-president-biden-on-sheikh-mohammed-bin-zayed-al-nahyan-election-as-president-of-the-united-arab-emirates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 15:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I congratulate my long-time friend Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan on his election as President of the United Arab Emirates.  As I told Sheikh Mohammed yesterday during our phone call, the United States is determined to honor the memory of the late president Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan by continuing to strengthen the strategic partnership between our countries over the coming months and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I congratulate my long-time friend Sheikh Mohammed bin Zayed Al Nahyan on his election as President of the United Arab Emirates.  As I told Sheikh Mohammed yesterday during our phone call, the United States is determined to honor the memory of the late president Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan by continuing to strengthen the strategic partnership between our countries over the coming months and years. The UAE is an essential partner of the United States.  Sheikh Mohammed, whom I met with several times as Vice President when he was the Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi, has long been at the forefront of building this partnership. I look forward to working with Sheikh Mohammed to build from this extraordinary foundation to further strengthen the bonds between our countries and peoples. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ASEAN-U.S. Special Summit 2022, Joint Vision&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/asean-u-s-special-summit-2022-joint-vision-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 01:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WE,&#160;the Member States of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and the United States gather on the occasion of the ASEAN-U.S. Special Summit, the first-ever to be held in Washington, D.C., on 12-13 May 2022. EMPHASIZING&#160;the importance of adhering to key principles, shared values and norms enshrined in the Charter of the United Nations,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><strong>WE</strong>,&nbsp;the Member States of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) and the United States gather on the occasion of the ASEAN-U.S. Special Summit, the first-ever to be held in Washington, D.C., on 12-13 May 2022.<br><br><strong>EMPHASIZING</strong>&nbsp;the importance of adhering to key principles, shared values and norms enshrined in the Charter of the United Nations, the ASEAN Charter, the Declaration on Zone of Peace, Freedom and Neutrality (ZOPFAN), the Treaty of Amity and Cooperation in Southeast Asia (TAC), the 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), the Treaty on the Southeast Asia Nuclear Weapon-Free Zone (SEANWFZ) and the ASEAN Outlook on&nbsp;the&nbsp;Indo-Pacific (AOIP);&nbsp;<br><br><strong>EMPHASIZING&nbsp;</strong>the importance of creating a peaceful environment for further enhancing cooperation and strengthening the existing bonds of friendship among our countries in keeping with the principles of equality, partnership, consultation, and mutual respect, guided by the principles of the East Asia Summit (EAS) Declaration on the Principles for Mutually Beneficial Relations (Bali Principles);&nbsp;<br><br><strong>RECOGNIZING</strong>&nbsp;that our cooperation has long been indispensable to ASEAN, to the United States, and to the broader international community, beginning with our first dialogue, in Manila in 1977, and growing with the United States’ signing of the Treaty of Amity and Cooperation in Southeast Asia; with the establishment of a U.S. Mission to ASEAN, in Jakarta; and with the founding of the ASEAN-U.S. Summit;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>NOTING</strong>&nbsp;that both the AOIP and the Indo-Pacific Strategy of the United States share relevant fundamental principles in promoting an open, inclusive, and rules-based regional architecture, in which ASEAN is central, alongside partners who share in these goals;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>REAFFIRMING</strong>&nbsp;our shared commitment to strengthen and build more comprehensive ASEAN-U.S. Dialogue Relations, which have long been indispensable to ASEAN and the United States, as well as the broader region and the international community, in order&nbsp;to continue promoting and maintaining peace, security, stability and prosperity in the region; to ensure that relations remain adaptable to meet new challenges; and to appropriately cooperate in international and regional fora of which&nbsp;ASEAN Member States and the United States are members.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>FURTHER REAFFIRMING</strong>&nbsp;our shared commitment to maintaining and promoting peace, security and stability in the region, as well as to the peaceful resolution of disputes, including full respect for legal and diplomatic processes, without resorting to the threat or use of force, in accordance with international law.&nbsp;<br><br><br><strong>WE HEREBY DECLARE:&nbsp;</strong><br><br>As we celebrate the 45<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;anniversary of ASEAN-U.S. Dialogue Relations in 2022, we commit to establish an ASEAN-U.S. Comprehensive Strategic Partnership that is meaningful, substantive, and mutually beneficial at the 10<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;ASEAN-U.S. Summit in November 2022. We look forward to the early completion of the necessary process.<br><br><strong>Fighting the COVID-19 pandemic, building better health security, and recovering together&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>We&nbsp;support ASEAN’s pandemic recovery&nbsp;and health security&nbsp;efforts&nbsp;by&nbsp;strengthening&nbsp;regional and national health systems and capabilities, such as through&nbsp;the ASEAN-U.S. Health Futures initiative,&nbsp;and commit to adequate,&nbsp;stronger and sustainable global financing for pandemic prevention, preparedness, and response, including supporting ongoing efforts with the World Bank and the World Health Organization. In welcoming support extended by ASEAN Dialogue Partners through various initiatives, including the Quad Vaccine Partnership,&nbsp;we remain committed to&nbsp;facilitating&nbsp;equitable&nbsp;access to safe, affordable and quality medicine&nbsp;and health services. We are also committed to expanding&nbsp;local and regional sustainable manufacturing&nbsp;capacity&nbsp;of essential medical products, including through&nbsp;transfer of knowledge&nbsp;on voluntary and mutually agreed terms&nbsp;and provision of technical assistance.&nbsp;We are committed to investing in and strengthening health systems through Universal Health Coverage, in particular primary health care and access to&nbsp;essential&nbsp;health services, and expanding and training the health workforce as strong foundations for regional and global health and health security.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Strengthening Economic Ties and Connectivity&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>We are committed to continuing to advance&nbsp;stronger, more&nbsp;equitable, more inclusive&nbsp;economicgrowth&nbsp;and sustainable development,&nbsp;including through the implementation of the ASEAN-U.S. Trade and Investment Framework&nbsp;Arrangement&nbsp;and Expanded Economic Engagement Initiatives Workplan,&nbsp;and through the vital economic participation of the U.S. in the region.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We are committed to working to meet the region’s infrastructure needs by&nbsp;catalyzing&nbsp;investment in high-standard,&nbsp;transparent, low-carbon&nbsp;and climate-resilient infrastructure projects that advance&nbsp;inclusive&nbsp;and sustainable economic growth&nbsp;that meet&nbsp;applicable international labor standards and environmental protections.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We are committed to continuing to cooperate to promote&nbsp;trade and investment&nbsp;and facilitating resilient global&nbsp;supply chains and seamless regional connectivity, including for essential goods such as medical supplies, medicines, vaccines, food and agricultural products, commodities, high-tech products, and other essential supplies and services, contributing to sustainable economic recovery and resilience in the region.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We seek to deepen our collaboration on transport connectivity, including air, land, maritime, and transport facilitation program to advance sustainable infrastructure development and support emerging technologies, including electric vehicles.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We remain committed to and invested in prosperity and development in ASEAN and the United States.&nbsp;We will actively partner in the discussions to strengthen regional and global governance systems, and we look forward to further strengthening cooperation including through relevant initiatives or frameworks&nbsp;of the United States or ASEAN.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We are committed to improving cybersecurity capabilities, promoting digital literacy and inclusion, and strengthening frameworks and policies that foster efficiency, innovation, communication, safe and&nbsp;equitable use of the internet&nbsp;and economic prosperity while exchanging views and experiences on cyber threats and on regulatory framework and technical standards that protect personal data in light of emerging technologies and their vulnerabilities.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Promoting Maritime Cooperation&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>We note the United Nations General Assembly Resolution A/RES/75/239 emphasizing in the Preamble, the universal and unified character of the 1982 UNCLOS, and reaffirming that the Convention sets out the legal framework within which all activities in the oceans and seas must be carried out and is of strategic importance as the basis for national, regional and global action and cooperation in the marine sector, and that its integrity needs to be maintained.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We are committed to advancing our cooperation in the&nbsp;maritime domain&nbsp;through ASEAN-led mechanisms. We plan to forge new ties as well as to promote cooperation and coordination among our relevant agencies, including maritime law enforcement agencies, to collaborate to improve maritime domain awareness, search and&nbsp;rescue, maritime security,&nbsp;and to curb illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing through sharing of information, best practices and expertise,&nbsp;as well as technical assistance,&nbsp;which will complement, and not duplicate the existing mechanisms. We also commit to continuing efforts to protect, restore, and sustainably manage the marine environment.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We are dedicated to maintaining peace, security, and stability in the region, and to ensuring maritime security and safety,&nbsp;as well as&nbsp;freedom of navigation and overflight and other lawful uses of the seas as described in the 1982 UNCLOS,&nbsp;and unimpeded lawful maritime commerce as well as non-militarization and self-restraint in the conduct of activities.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We recognise&nbsp;the&nbsp;benefits of having the South China Sea as a sea of peace, stability, and prosperity. We emphasise the importance of practical measures that could reduce tensions and the risk of accidents, misunderstandings, and miscalculation. We stressed the importance of undertaking confidence building and preventive measures to enhance, among others, trust and confidence amongst parties. We further reaffirmed the need to pursue peaceful resolution of disputes in accordance with universally recognized principles of international law, including the 1982 UNCLOS.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We underscored the importance of the full and effective implementation of the 2002 Declaration on the Conduct of Parties in the South China Sea (DOC) in its entirety. We emphasized the need to maintain and promote an environment conducive to the Code of Conduct in the South China Sea (COC) negotiations. We welcome further progress towards the early conclusion of an effective and substantive COC consistent with international law, including the 1982 UNCLOS.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enhancing People-to-people connectivity&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>We are committed to investing in human capital development, empowering youth and vulnerable or&nbsp;marginalized&nbsp;groups, and strengthening the connections between our peoples, among others, support for English language, digital skills, Technical and Vocational Education and Training (TVET) and&nbsp;Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math (STEM)&nbsp;trainings in the region, including through the Billion Futures Program and the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative (YSEALI).<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We commit to working with partners, including companies and universities, to increase access to education while fostering collaboration and exchanges among our students and workers. Furthermore, we are committed to empowering women&nbsp;and girls&nbsp;and&nbsp;promoting gender&nbsp;equity and&nbsp;equality&nbsp;through enhanced engagement in ASEAN-led mechanisms, including through support for ASEAN’s gender programs and initiatives. We also commit to advancing the rights of persons with disabilities through supporting implementation of the ASEAN Enabling Masterplan on Mainstreaming the Rights of Persons with Disabilities.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Sub-regional Development&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>We are committed to supporting ASEAN Centrality and unity in promoting ASEAN’s sub-regional development.&nbsp;We further commit to promoting the stability, peace, prosperity, and sustainable development of the Mekong sub-region through shared initiatives under the Mekong-U.S. Partnership (MUSP), which complements the Friends of the Mekong, and supports the implementation of the Master Plan on ASEAN Connectivity (MPAC) 2025 and the Initiative for ASEAN Integration (IAI) Work Plan IV (2021-2025).&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We support ASEAN’s efforts in promoting equitable development, including in the fields of energy transition,&nbsp;transportation,&nbsp;environmental protection, regional resources management, and water data sharing in accordance with the Mekong River Commission’s Procedures for Data and Information Exchange and Sharing (PDIES), by aligning sub-regional growth with the comprehensive development of ASEAN, and to promote complementarity and synergy among ASEAN, MUSP and other existing Mekong cooperation mechanisms.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Leveraging Technologies and Promoting Innovation&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>We are committed to further exploring cooperation in areas of mutual benefit such as smart manufacturing, blockchain applications, trade facilitation,&nbsp;digital connectivity, digitalisation and e-commerce&nbsp;of MSMEs, e-services, digital financial services and regional payment connectivity,new and emerging technologies in line with relevant ASEAN agreements and frameworks, as well as increase technical assistance for ASEAN Member States to promote innovation<strong>,&nbsp;</strong>and capacity building on digital skills.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We commit to support the development of ASEAN’s digital infrastructure, to promote the development of peaceful, secure, open, interoperable, reliable,&nbsp;inclusive,&nbsp;and resilient Information and Communications Technology (ICT) ecosystems and 5G networks, and explore ways to strengthen cooperation on digital economy, smart,&nbsp;sustainable&nbsp;city development and emerging technologies,&nbsp;including through the U.S.-ASEAN Smart Cities Partnership (USASCP).&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We are committed to enhancing collaboration in biotechnology, smart farming,&nbsp;both precision agriculture and&nbsp;climate-smart agriculture (CSA), food science, meteorology, microelectronics, marine science, energy, and space.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Addressing Climate Change&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>We are further committed to working together to advance our respective&nbsp;nationally determined contributions (NDC).&nbsp;We affirm the key role that sub-national actors play in advancing climate action, and intend to collaborate together in the clean energy transition, including through financing and technology.&nbsp;We recognize the importance&nbsp;of taking strong action to reduce methane emissions globally, including through efforts underway such as the Global Methane Pledge.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We are committed to intensifying our partnership to bolster ASEAN’s capacity to&nbsp;enhancedisaster&nbsp;resiliency&nbsp;and adapt to the effects of climate change, such as rising sea levels, more frequent flooding, drought and other extreme weather events, heightened risk of water-energy-food insecurity, and ever-more-destructive storms.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We resolve to enhance energy transition and resilience in&nbsp;&nbsp;an inclusive and just manner&nbsp;through the facilitation of clean and renewable energy development,&nbsp;the promotion of public-private collaboration to address transition financing needs, including through blended finance,&nbsp;and the deployment of advanced and emerging low-carbon energy technologies in&nbsp;supporting increased access to energy services and&nbsp;&nbsp;energy security, including ongoing&nbsp;efforts, such as elements of&nbsp;the ASEAN Plan of Action for Energy Cooperation (APAEC) that support the acceleration of energy transition and strengthening of energy resilience in ASEAN, particularly the ASEAN Power Grid.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We resolve to work together to conserve ASEAN’s rich biodiversity and its natural capital, including through preventing,&nbsp;halting&nbsp;and reversing deforestation, and&nbsp;the degradation of ecosystems,&nbsp;as well as the restoration of&nbsp;critical ecosystems including&nbsp;forests,&nbsp;and wetlands, coastal and marine ecosystems, and the continued collaboration with the ASEAN Centre for Biodiversity (ACB).&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Preserving Peace, Building Trust&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>We support ASEAN’s efforts to preserve the Southeast Asian region as a Nuclear Weapon-Free Zone and free of all other weapons of mass destruction, as enshrined in the Treaty on the Southeast Asia Nuclear Weapon-Free Zone (SEANWFZ Treaty) and the ASEAN Charter&nbsp;tostrengthen the nuclear non-proliferation regime, and to nuclear disarmament as stipulated in Article VI of the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (NPT),&nbsp;and peaceful uses of nuclear energy as set forth in NPT Article IV. We remain committed to universalization of the IAEA additional protocol, and&nbsp;support full implementation of the Convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production, Stockpiling and Use of Chemical Weapons and on their Destruction (CWC) and the Convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production, and Stockpiling of Bacteriological (Biological) and Toxin Weapons and on their Destruction (BTWC).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We reaffirm a shared commitment to the goal of the complete denuclearization and the establishment of a permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp;We continue to call on the DPRK to fully comply with the relevant&nbsp;UN Security Council resolutions, taking into account the international community’s call for diplomacy and in the interest of maintaining peace and security in the region.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>We remain deeply concerned over the crisis in Myanmar.&nbsp;We&nbsp;highlight&nbsp;Myanmar’s commitment to the&nbsp;ASEAN&nbsp;Five-Point Consensus&nbsp;during&nbsp;&nbsp;the ASEAN Leaders’ Meeting on 24 April 2021 and&nbsp;urge&nbsp;the timely and complete implementation of the Five-Point Consensus. We will continue to support ASEAN’s efforts to facilitate a peaceful solution in the interest of the people of Myanmar, including through the work of the Special Envoy of the ASEAN&nbsp;Chair on Myanmar,in building confidence and trust with full access to all parties concerned, and effective delivery of humanitarian assistance to the people of Myanmar, including those&nbsp;who are the most in need, without discrimination. We&nbsp;reiterate our commitment to peace and stability in the region and&nbsp;continue to call for the immediate cessation of violence in Myanmar and for the release of&nbsp;allpolitical detainees, including foreigners. We will redouble our collective efforts towards a peaceful solution in Myanmar that also reflects&nbsp;a&nbsp;continued commitment to human rights and fundamental freedoms, as outlined in the ASEAN Charter.&nbsp;We welcome close coordination between the Special Envoy of the ASEAN Chair on Myanmar and the Special Envoy of the UN Secretary-General on Myanmar to ensure synergy in this important endeavor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>With regard to Ukraine, as for all nations, we continue to reaffirm our respect for sovereignty, political independence, and territorial integrity. We reiterate our call for compliance with the UN Charter and international law. We underline the importance of an immediate cessation of hostilities and creating an enabling environment for peaceful resolution. We support the efforts of the UN Secretary-General in the search for a peaceful solution. We also call for the facilitation of rapid, safe and unhindered access to humanitarian assistance for those in need in Ukraine, and for the protection of civilians, humanitarian personnel, and persons in vulnerable situations.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>As we proceed with implementation of this ambitious agenda in the coming months and years, we look forward to reaching a new level of cooperation and partnership and task our Ministers to coordinate the implementation of this Joint Vision Statement.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at the U.S.-ASEAN Special&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/13/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-u-s-asean-special-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 01:20:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State DepartmentWashington, D.C. 4:16 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, thank you.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; My whole name.&#160; Thank you all very much.&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I said last night &#8212; let me reiterate: It&#8217;s been wonderful, wonderful to host you all in the first-ever U.S-ASEAN Summit in Washington, D.C.&#160; And besides, Mr. President, the food wasn&#8217;t bad.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Department<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>4:16 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; My whole name.&nbsp; Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I said last night &#8212; let me reiterate: It&#8217;s been wonderful, wonderful to host you all in the first-ever U.S-ASEAN Summit in Washington, D.C.&nbsp;<br><br>And besides, Mr. President, the food wasn&#8217;t bad.&nbsp; It was pretty good.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t had &#8212; been ha- &#8212; been able to have, essentially, state dinners in a long time because of COVID.&nbsp; But thank you all for being there.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re not only celebrating 45 years of partnership and friendship between ASEAN and the United States, we&#8217;re launching a new era &#8212; a new era in U.S.-ASEAN relations.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me thank Prime Minister Hun Sen and &#8212; for the 22 &#8212; as the 2022 ASEAN Chair.&nbsp;<br><br>And President Widodo, I want to thank you as well &#8212; the Country Coordinator for ASEAN and U.S. Dialogue Relations &#8212; and &#8212; and for all the hard work to make this summit, I believe &#8212; I hope you believe &#8212; a success.<br><br>Over the past two days, we&#8217;ve spent time with members of &#8211;you &#8212; you&#8217;ve spent time with members of Congress, the American business community.&nbsp; You just finished a good session with the Vice President.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve met with a number of our Cabinet members.&nbsp; And I wanted you to be as exposed as you could and understand there&#8217;s enthusiasm &#8212; that it&#8217;s not just at the President&#8217;s level and the Vice President’s level, but throughout the entire administration &#8212; for this relationship and &#8212; and bettering it.<br><br>You know, discussions have covered a broad range of critical issues, including working together to keep the fight against COVID under control and to take climate action.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And by the way, I see Secretary Kerry down there.&nbsp; And, John, thanks for letting me into your old house.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;&nbsp;John has forgotten about &#8212; more about, in my view, the needs we have for climate security than anyone that I know.&nbsp;&nbsp;Thanks, John, for being here.&nbsp; I want to talk about that a little bit as we go into this here &#8212; in this &#8212; the rest of the day.<br><br>Discussions have covered a broad range of critical issues, including working together to keep up the fight against COVID-19; to take climate action and pursue a clean energy future; build a sustainable, high-standard infrastructure; and to expand access to education; enhance maritime cooperation.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and the breadth of our discussions reflect just how vital the Indo-Pacific and ASEAN region are to the United States of America, from our perspective.<br><br>And a great deal of history &#8212; the great deal of history of our world in the next 50 years is going to be written and the ASEAN countries and our relationship with you is the future in the coming years and decades.&nbsp;<br><br>The ASEAN centrality is the very heart of my administration’s strategy in pursuing the future we all want to see.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp;<br><br>The &#8212; the Indo-Pacific is an Indo-Pacific that is free and open, stable and prosperous, and resilient and secure.&nbsp; It’s what we&#8217;re all seeking.&nbsp;&nbsp;And that&#8217;s why I asked [Vice] President Harris to travel to the region last August.&nbsp;&nbsp;And that&#8217;s why, last October, at our virtual summit, I announced $100 million to support &#8212; for programs to strengthen U.S.-ASEAN cooperation.&nbsp;<br><br>And today, I&#8217;m announcing another $150 million of initiatives to deepen U.S.-ASEAN relations and achieve more &#8212; our &#8212; even better our shared objectives from the Coast Guard to climate change to &#8212; to modern infrastructure.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a whole range of things that we have to work on.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m also proud to announce that I have nominated one of my closest advisors to be U.S. Ambassador to ASEAN: Yohannes Abraham.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve already all seen him.&nbsp; But, Yohannes, you got to come back once in a while and say hi to us.<br><br>Yohannes served as the Chief of Staff of the National Security Council since the first day of my administration.&nbsp; And so, this is a fellow who I&#8217;m a little concerned to send in because he knows how I think.&nbsp; You know, I mean, he knows so much about me, I&#8217;m a little worried.&nbsp;<br><br>But all kidding aside, he is &#8212; I think you&#8217;re going to find him completely knowledgeable and he speaks for &#8212; will speak for me and speak for my administration.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Yohannes is &#8212; I wish him luck.&nbsp; He&#8217;s a &#8212; he&#8217;s the key reason why I think we &#8212; this summit has been the success it has.&nbsp; I presume to believe you believe as I do: It has been a success thus far.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll be a trusted representative and &#8212; to continue deepening this critical partnership among all of us.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re committed to a future where the rules and norms that have made possible so much growth and prosperity and stability in the Indo-Pacific are upheld and strengthened, including respect for the rule of law and for human rights.<br><br>This is something that benefits all one billion of the people who live in our countries, from the United States and all of you.&nbsp; And as we look around the world &#8212; all the challenges we&#8217;re facing &#8212; the ASEAN-U.S. partnership is critical, I think, to meeting the moment we find ourselves in history right now.<br><br>And so, let me thank you again for making the journey to Washington to celebrate the enduring friendship we share and to look ahead at all that I believe &#8212; we all believe &#8212; we can accomplish together and how much more we can do.<br><br>We’ll continue to elevate this partnership and strengthen our cooperation and to make a better, safer, and more prosperous world for all our children.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br><br>4:22 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden Highlighting State and Local Leaders Who Are Investing American Rescue Plan&#160;Funding</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/13/remarks-by-president-biden-highlighting-state-and-local-leaders-who-are-investing-american-rescue-plan-funding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 23:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3:26 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, folks.&#160; I &#8212; I&#8217;m flanked by real protection here. (Laughter.)&#160; Thank you all for being here.&#160; And I want to &#8212; I want to thank the Attorney General, Merrick Garland, who is standing behind me, for joining us today.&#160; He&#8217;s doing an incredible job as our Attorney General.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>3:26 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, folks.&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;m flanked by real protection here. (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you all for being here.&nbsp; And I want to &#8212; I want to thank the Attorney General, Merrick Garland, who is standing behind me, for joining us today.&nbsp; He&#8217;s doing an incredible job as our Attorney General.</p>



<p>I just met with this remarkable group of local officials and police chiefs standing alongside me here.&nbsp; We wanted to talk about what they&#8217;re doing to reduce violence and to keep our community safe, and how more communities can follow their lead to reduce crime and ensure public safety as we &#8212; as we head into the summer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I&#8217;ve worked on these issues for a long time &#8212; when I was a United States senator and as Vice President.&nbsp; So &#8212; so this group of leaders &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; representing big cities and rural counties &#8212; we &#8212; we actually know what works.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We all agreed, as I&#8217;ve said from the outset, that the answer is not to defund the police.&nbsp; The answer is to fund the police with the resources and training they need to protect our communities, investing in crime prevention and accountable community police officers who’ll walk the beat, know the neighborhood, and who can restore trust and safety in the neighborhoods.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it is.</p>



<p>When you know who owns a local liquor store, know who the pastor of the church is, know &#8212; it makes a big difference when you know the community.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been my approach from day one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we designed the American Rescue Plan not only to beat the pandemic, but to rebuild our economy, but to restore public safety.&nbsp; And we understood the challenge from the beginning.</p>



<p>Communities were facing a rising tide of violence that coincided with this pandemic we went through over the last two years.&nbsp; And it was happening at a time when state and local budgets were under tremendous strain.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because of the pandemic, so many people laid off, their revenue was not coming in.&nbsp; They were firing everyone from police officers to school teachers to first responders.</p>



<p>But before the American Rescue Plan, these bu- &#8212; their budgets were in deep distress in the states and localities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One study sounded before &#8212; found that before the Rescue Plan was passed, 27 percent of the mayors in America were having to cut &#8212; make deep cuts and layoffs in law enforcement as well as other areas.&nbsp; So we made sure that the American Rescue Plan provided substantial resources to keep that from happening.</p>



<p>Through the law, we provided $350 billion &#8212; let me say that again &#8212; $350 billion directly &#8212; not to the legislatures &#8212; directly to cities, counties, and states independently of one another &#8212; money that could be used to hire back police officers, to invest in proven strategies like community violence interruption and prevention programs, and to keep their cities and counties safe, and ease the burden on law enforcement.</p>



<p>Because of that funding, states and cities were able to add back 460,000 jobs, including police officers, in addition to firefighters, educators, and other critically important roles.</p>



<p>And, by the way, not a single remember- &#8212; not a single Republican member of Congress voted for the money for law enforcement, public safety, to stabilize these &#8212; and to stabilize these budgets &#8212; not a single one &#8212; for the states, the cities, and the counties.&nbsp; Not one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think we&#8217;re finding they&#8217;re showing up now because they&#8217;re realizing this is going to make a difference and beginning to make a difference.</p>



<p>Across the country, state and local leaders answered the call.&nbsp; And already, more than one &#8212; more than $10 billion of the American Rescue Plan funds have been committed to violence prevention and public safety across America.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, in &#8212; 2021 was one of the strongest years on record when it comes to federal support delivered directly to state and local governments to address and prevent crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, standing here with me today, leading the way in Detroit, my buddy &#8212; and he is my buddy, because you may remember, those of you that have been reporting from the White House for a while, that Barack Obama said to me when I was Vice President, “Go fix Detroit.”&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Spent &#8212; and the poor guy, he spent a lot &#8212; where were you, Mike?</p>



<p>MAYOR DUGGAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m still here.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I spent a lot of time with this guy &#8212; Mayor Mike Duggan &#8212; and Police Chief James White.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Are &#8212; they&#8217;re using these ARP funds to modernize police training facilities, to invest in retention of police officers, gun violence prevention efforts, gunshot detection technology.</p>



<p>In Tulsa, Mayor G.T. &#8212; excuse me &#8212;&nbsp;<s>Byrnum</s>&nbsp;[Bynum] is using the Rescue Plan funds to help recruit police officers and training for &#8212; bonus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Put your hand up when &#8212; so we know who we&#8217;re talking about here.</p>



<p>MAYOR BYNUM:&nbsp; Yes, sir.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; There you are.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I &#8212; in Kansas City, Mayor Q &#8212; known as “Mayor Q” &#8212; Quinton Lucas and police officer Joe &#8212; Joe Mabin are here.&nbsp; They used the ARP funds to avoid cuts and layoffs that would have threatened public safety in their city.&nbsp; And they put $12 million into their Violent Crimes Division and &#8212; while freeing up resources to begin hiring 150 new police officers.<br><br>In Baton Rouge &#8212; Baton Rouge, Louisiana, Police Chief Murphy Pearl [sic] &#8212; Paul &#8212; excuse me &#8212; is using ARP funds to purchase 200 additional patrol cars while investing $3 million to implement a proven strategy to reduce gun violence in communities, to produce prevention programs.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Tampa, Mayor Jane Castor and Mayor &#8212; and the Police Chief, Mary O&#8217;Connor, they&#8217;re using ARP funds to modernize the city&#8217;s fire prevention capacity, including with new fire vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Toledo, Ohio, Mayor Wade is using the ARP funds not only to avoid layoffs, but to add 100 police officers in the next few years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Mercer County, Pennsylvania &#8212; a county I know &#8212; largely rural, where the largest town is home of 16,000 people &#8212; the County Commissioner is here &#8212; Timothy McGonigle.&nbsp; Timmy was &#8212; well, I shouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I &#8212; excuse me &#8212; I was going to call you &#8212; excuse me for calling you Timmy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>COMMISIONER MCGONIGLE:&nbsp; No, they all call me that.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve always called you &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;</p>



<p>We were talking about I grew up with Michael McGonigle &#8212; was one hell of an athlete.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And anyway, but Tim is using that $12 million of ARP funds to install a county-wide radio system, connecting 911, police, fire, ambulance services for the first time.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to make a big difference in terms of the public safety writ large.</p>



<p>And in Houston, Mayor Sylvester Turner, who I’ve spent some time with, and Troy Finner, the &#8212; who is the police chief, they&#8217;re using ARP funds to improve medical health services &#8212; mental health services, excuse me &#8212; domestic violence and response efforts.&nbsp; Because they’ve realized that when there&#8217;s a domestic violence problem, it&#8217;s not always necessary to send a cop with a gun.&nbsp; You have to send someone who can talk people through things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; and funding a community re-entry program and police overtime pay so an additional 125 officers can be present in areas where violent crime occurs most frequently.</p>



<p>And across the country, more than 300 communities are engaged in the &#8212; efforts like these.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve said it before and I&#8217;ll say it again.&nbsp; To every governor, every mayor, every county official, the need is clear, my message is clear: Send &#8212; spend this money now that you have.&nbsp; Use these funds we made available to you to prioritize public safety.&nbsp; Do it quickly, before the summer, when crime rates typically surge.&nbsp; Taking action today is going to save lives tomorrow.&nbsp; So, use the money.&nbsp; Hire the police officers.&nbsp; Build up your emergency response systems.&nbsp; Invest in proven solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have a &#8212; we have an expert here with us who is one of the best &#8212; who&#8217;s best at those solutions, Reggie Moore.&nbsp; Reggie is heading up a new comprehensive statewide violence prevention program in the state of Wisconsin &#8212; a program that&#8217;s grounded in what&#8217;s known as community violence intervention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Community violence intervention is about using tested messages, community leaders, community members to directly work with people who are the most likely to commit gun crimes or become victims of those gun crimes.&nbsp; And it works.&nbsp; They intervene before it&#8217;s too late, with public health and safety approaches that work.</p>



<p>And your governor, Governor Evers, has invested $100 million in the Rescue Plan to expand these efforts across the state of Wisconsin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thanks for everything you&#8217;re doing, Reggie.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; And more and more states and communities are going to do the same thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need more of these programs.&nbsp; And we need states and communities to invest in things like jobs and training for young people, summer programs, drug treatment and mental health programs, housing, criminal justice reform, reentry support for people coming home from &#8212; after incarceration.</p>



<p>As I said in the Cabinet Room, you know, the idea that when you get let out of prison after serving your time you get 25 bucks and a bus ticket, and you&#8217;re going to end up under the same bridge you came from &#8212; from before.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you should be entitled, if you&#8217;ve served your time, to everything from Pell Grants to food &#8212; to food stamps, the whole &#8212; the whole deal, to be able to take advantage of changing your life.&nbsp; And my administration is investing in those elements.</p>



<p>The cities, the counties, and the states should be doing the same thing with the money they have because they are demonstrated ways to reduce crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bottom line is this: Across the board, we&#8217;re making sure that communities have the resources available to them that they&#8217;ve never had before so they don’t have to make tough choices between and among doing these things &#8212; reduce violence and ensure safety.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s up to the cities, the towns, and the counties to spend the money and spend it now.&nbsp; It&#8217;s there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been appropriated.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We know the challenges we&#8217;re facing as we head into this summer.&nbsp; We need to meet those challenges with a sense of urgency, which this group is doing.<br><br>Local leaders across the country, including the folks that are here today, are demonstrating exactly what works with innovative efforts and proven strategies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Every single community in America should join them.&nbsp; And as you do, I want every governor, mayor, and county official to know: My administration will continue to have your back.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Let&#8217;s get this done and get it done now.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank you all.&nbsp; God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br><a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you support Finland joining NATO?&nbsp;&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you condemn the Israeli police force in Jerusalem?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you support Finland joining NATO, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If you ask me something about what I just spoke about, I&#8217;m happy to answer your question.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think you need to invest more money in police across the nation?&nbsp; Would you push for more investment?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; We have plenty out there.&nbsp; The thing is that the governors have to loosen it up, make it available.&nbsp; Mayors have to make it available.&nbsp; It&#8217;s there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a question.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You had a question, sir.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My question is: Do you condemn the police force in Israel for their actions at the funeral of the Palestinian-American journalist?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know all the detail, but I know it has to be investigated.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know all the detail.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, would you go to support reporters, sir?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I can, I&#8217;ll ask you &#8212; I’ll ask you two.&nbsp; First, about what we&#8217;re doing here, if you can, about &#8212; there are some concerns about leniency of prosecutors right now &#8212; what you have in terms of leverage to help enforce them, doing more to hold criminals accountable.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And separately, your concerns, if you have any, on bail reform.<br><br>And then I have a separate one, if I can just allow it.&nbsp; A lot of parents are watching about baby formula.&nbsp; Do you have a message to those parents that you can share while they&#8217;re listening?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, three questions.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll answer the baby formula question because, all of a sudden, it&#8217;s on the front page of every newspaper.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s important that it &#8212; I &#8212; be responded to.<br><br>But, look, with regard to the leniency of prosecutors, that has, on balance, not been the biggest problem &#8212; the leniency of prosecutors.&nbsp; In the past, the hardest (inaudible) have been the intensity of prosecutors, people getting long sentences for crimes that are &#8212; anyway.<br><br>And so, and my &#8212; and bail reform &#8212; I think bail reform and the negative side of bail reform is vastly overrated.&nbsp; The idea that if you have no ability to make bail because you&#8217;re poor, it should relate to the severity of the crime and what you &#8212; what the problem is related that you&#8217;re accused of.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>With regard to the issue of formula, we&#8217;ve done three things.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I know Jen Psaki spoke to this today.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Number one, we&#8217;re releasing guidance today to all the states of the possible flexibilities in the WIC program &#8212; the Women, Infant, Children program &#8212; because they&#8217;re very, sort of, strict guidelines that when you walk in, if you have a WIC, you can go and purchase a certain amount of formula, but you can&#8217;t purchase more of it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The problem is the packaging issues are becoming a difficulty.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;ve &#8212; changing it so that the WIC program &#8212; you can buy what&#8217;s on the shelf so that they’re not as &#8212; as &#8212; it&#8217;s the top issue raised with me.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So the flexibility to have formula in stock should not depend on whether you have it packaged exactly what meets the requirement for that &#8212; that &#8212; for people on &#8212; on the WIC program.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Secondly, the FDA just issued a statement we worked on.&nbsp; I was on the telephone.&nbsp; And, by the way, that &#8212; on the WIC program &#8212; when I spoke to Walmart and I spoke to the major distributors for an hour or so yesterday or the day before &#8212; I can&#8217;t remember &#8212; they wanted to have this flexibility because they didn&#8217;t want to be violating the law.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Secondly, they &#8212; the top issue for retailers raised with me &#8212; secondly, the FDA just issued a statement about importation &#8212; importation of formula from abroad.&nbsp; The FDA has been looking at the &#8212; will be working with manufacturers to facilitate the incorporation of formulas from abroad that, in fact &#8212; in places like Europe, where we can get more product on U.S. shelves.&nbsp; That&#8217;s underway.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we&#8217;re going to be, in a matter of weeks or less, getting significantly more formula on shelves.&nbsp; And the FDA is also going to ensure we can import and still maintain the sa- &#8212; the high safety standards.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And the third thing that is &#8212; there&#8217;s more to say about each of these, but the third major thing we&#8217;re doing is that patien- &#8212; finally, any parent who has a serious question about where they &#8212; the particular formula they need &#8212; because there are very different formulas; some are very precise.&nbsp; And if they not &#8212; they don&#8217;t get the exact right formula, the impact on the child is extremely negative.&nbsp; We have set up a &#8212; a system whereby you can contact HHS.&nbsp; You can go to www.HHS.gov/formula.&nbsp;<br><br>They just launched this website to help parents find resources, obtain formulas, including contact with companies and food banks and health providers that, in fact, may have access to the particular formula they need.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This is a process.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working on it very, very hard.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing more urgent we&#8217;re working on than that right now.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re going to be making some significant progress very shortly.<br><br>All the way in the back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, Republicans have said that your administration should have anticipated this baby formula shortage before.&nbsp; Are you satisfied with your administration&#8217;s response so far?&nbsp; And some of the steps that you and your administration are taking now, including loosening these import requirements next week, should you have taken those steps sooner, before parents got to these shelves and couldn&#8217;t find formula?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If we&#8217;d been better mind readers, I guess we could have, but we moved as quickly as the problem became apparent to us.&nbsp; And we have to move with caution as well as speed, because we got to make sure what we&#8217;re getting is, in fact, first-rate product.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the FDA has to go through the process.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Mr. President, I&#8217;m so sorry to take you to so far.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to ask you a question about Africa, because, recently, you send your Deputy Secretary of State to Africa.&nbsp; She visit three countries: Gabon, Angola, and South Africa.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, in Angola, she spoke with President Lourenço.&nbsp; And when she gave her report to the media, she said that she&#8217;s been seeing in Angola many progress in terms of human rights, fighting corruption, and also better business environment for the Americans investor.&nbsp; Are you aware of what is going on in Angola, Mr. President?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m aware.&nbsp; However, I&#8217;m waiting for her report.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been on the phone with the President of South Africa at length on those same issues.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve been on &#8212; on the phone and been in contact with other African leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is a need for a significant increase in focusing on human rights and not abusing human rights.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s also a need for us to &#8212; what we&#8217;re doing is trying to figure out how can we help African countries accommodate the changes they have to make in terms of the &#8212; their &#8212; to deal with their environmental problems, as well as dealing with infrastructure problems.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I convinced the G7 to agree that we would put together a program where we would &#8212; the advanced economic nations of the world would provide the kind of resources, without any strings attached, to increase environmental capacity as well as dealing with other problems in African nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s a billion people.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re working very hard to try to get hold of that.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m only going to keep them standing here another few minutes.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; No worries, Mr. President.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’ll make it quick.&nbsp; Mr. President, I just want to ask you &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They &#8212; they came for the press conference.&nbsp; Right, guys?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; I appreciate your time.&nbsp; I just want to ask you: What further executive action are you considering to do police reform?&nbsp; We know that&#8217;s pretty much stalled in Congress right now.<br><br>And I also want to ask you another question, if I can, on foreign relations.&nbsp; You spoke with both of the leaders of Sweden and Finland today.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your message to President Putin after those &#8212; essentially those threats that he gave, at least to Finland?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; With regard to the second question: I&#8217;m not going to go into the detail of my private conversations with the President of Sweden and Finland, except that we had a good conversation, and they expressed their interest and desires relating to security.&nbsp; And there will be more to report on that shortly.<br><br>With regard to &#8212; the first question was what again?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What additional action are you considering on police reform?&nbsp; And we know your administration is working on (inaudible).<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What I&#8217;ve done by executive order is done what I can, insisting that &#8212; on police reform &#8212; for federal officers, no chokeholds, no no-knock warrants, et cetera.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to continue.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But one of the things I&#8217;ve decided to do &#8212; the best way to get the reform done as quickly as possible is to go local and to make sure we invest in the police departments of local and county and city police departments.&nbsp; Because one of the things we talked about in the Cabinet Room is that I don&#8217;t know any cop who likes a bad cop.&nbsp; I mean that sincerely.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I grew up in a neighborhood in Claymont where you became a cop, a firefighter, or a priest.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; I had &#8212; the guys I know in the police forces, the last thing they want is a bad cop &#8212; a bully, a thug &#8212; being on the force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the idea that somehow there&#8217;s this overwhelming desire to protect a bad cop &#8212; it’s the leadership&#8217;s role to make sure they find them, get rid of them, and if they violate a crime, prosecute them.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all so very, very much.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>3:47 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
