<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 19:07:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Consumer Price Index (CPI) in&#160;May</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/statement-by-president-biden-on-consumer-price-index-cpi-in-may/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 17:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s report underscores why I have made fighting inflation my top economic priority. While it is good to see critical “core” inflation moderating, it is not coming down as sharply and as quickly as we must see. Putin’s Price Hike hit hard in May here and around the world: high gas prices at the pump,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s report underscores why I have made fighting inflation my top economic priority. While it is good to see critical “core” inflation moderating, it is not coming down as sharply and as quickly as we must see. Putin’s Price Hike hit hard in May here and around the world: high gas prices at the pump, energy, and food prices accounted for around half of the monthly price increases, and gas pump prices are up by $2 a gallon in many places since Russian troops began to threaten Ukraine. Even as we continue our work to defend freedom in Ukraine, we must do more—and quickly—to get prices down here in the United States.</p>



<p>My Administration will continue to do everything we can to lower prices for the American people. Congress must act urgently as well. I call on Congress to pass a bill to cut shipping costs this month, and get it to my desk, so we can lower the price of goods. And, I call on Congress to pass legislation to cut costs for families like energy bills and prescription drugs. The deficit has come down more under my watch as President than at any time in history, but if Congress would pass tax reform to make the wealthiest Americans and big corporations pay their fair share, we could reduce this inflationary pressure even more. These are the most significant things Congress can do to help families now and complement the Federal Reserve’s efforts to bring inflation down.</p>



<p>Prices at the pump are a major part of inflation, and the war in Ukraine is a major cause of that. The United States is on track to produce a record amount of oil next year, and I am working with the industry to accelerate this output. But it is also important that the oil and gas and refining industries in this country not use the challenge created by the war in Ukraine as a reason to make things worse for families with excessive profit taking or price hikes.</p>



<p>We all have work to do to get inflation down. What will not help is the plan by some Republicans in Congress to raise taxes on the middle class and working families. That would be a step in the wrong direction, and I strongly oppose it.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Sixth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/president-biden-announces-sixth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 16:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Delta Air Lines will carry more than 3.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula&#160; Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration has arranged the sixth Operation Fly Formula flight. Delta Air Lines will transport Kendamil formula free of charge from Heathrow Airport in London to Logan Airport in Boston and Detroit Metro&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Delta Air Lines will carry more than 3.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration has arranged the sixth Operation Fly Formula flight. Delta Air Lines will transport Kendamil formula free of charge from Heathrow Airport in London to Logan Airport in Boston and Detroit Metro Airport between June 20 and June 24.</p>



<p>These Operation Fly Formula flights donated by Delta will contain more than 212,000 pounds or approximately 3.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula and will begin shipping on June 20.</p>



<p>The Kendamil Organic and Classic formula, made available through Operation Fly Formula, will be distributed and available for purchase at select U.S. retailers nationwide, as well as online. The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is exercising enforcement discretion so that Kendamil can import infant formula under the Kendamil brand. Kendamil will export up to at least 2 million cans of Kendamil infant formula – the equivalent of at least 54 million 8-ounce bottles to the United States. Parents can learn more about Kendamil infant formula at&nbsp;<a href="https://kendamil.com/">https://kendamil.com/</a>&nbsp;and visit the United States website at&nbsp;<a href="https://us.kendamil.com/">https://us.kendamil.com/</a>&nbsp;for updates and information on retail locations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the importation of safe infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards so it can get to store shelves faster. Yesterday, Operation Fly Formula flights landed in Texas with 1.6 million bottle equivalents of Nestlé NAN SupremePro Stage 1 infant formula, and the first shipment of 3.7 million bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula landed in Virginia aboard a donated United Airlines flight.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Flag Day And National Flag Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/10/a-proclamation-on-flag-day-and-national-flag-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 15:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; On June 14, 1777, the Continental Congress passed a resolution adopting a flag for our new Nation &#8212; the United&#160;States of America.&#160; The resolution specified 13 alternating red and white stripes with 13 stars on a blue field.&#160; The stars represented the colonies that declared independence, and in the years since, they have grown&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On June 14, 1777, the Continental Congress passed a resolution adopting a flag for our new Nation &#8212; the United&nbsp;States of America.&nbsp; The resolution specified 13 alternating red and white stripes with 13 stars on a blue field.&nbsp; The stars represented the colonies that declared independence, and in the years since, they have grown into 50 United States which comprise our great country today.&nbsp; For centuries, mariners looked to the stars to guide them across the seas, just as Americans and people across the globe look to our flag as a guiding symbol of freedom, opportunity, and hope. &nbsp;On Flag Day and during National Flag Week, we celebrate the journey of progress represented in our banner and pay tribute to the inspiration it gives Americans at home and abroad.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our flag belongs to all Americans, and its red, white, and blue colors are woven into a rich tapestry of different cultures, backgrounds, and beliefs which connects us and honors our shared history. &nbsp;Old Glory has flown around the world in times of war and in times of peace. &nbsp;It has traveled to the Moon and to Mars. &nbsp;It has sailed on ships and flown on planes. &nbsp;It waves high above the White House, courthouses, post offices, schools, and homes across the Nation, and also above our embassies and military bases overseas &#8212; an enduring beacon of democracy.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; From the Revolutionary War to the modern age, American Service members have fought bravely under the symbol of our flag, and those who give the last full measure of devotion are wrapped in its broad stripes and bright stars as they are laid to rest.&nbsp; We honor those who serve our country in uniform and pay homage to those who have made that ultimate sacrifice.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every day, the American Flag instills pride &#8212; reminding us of the ideals upon which our Nation was founded and the values for which we stand. &nbsp;As we pledge our allegiance to the Star-Spangled Banner, and the legacy it holds in our history, let us continue the work of perfecting our Union so that, together, we can deliver the promise of America for all Americans. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To commemorate the adoption of our flag, the Congress, by joint resolution approved August 3, 1949, as amended (63 Stat. 492), designated June 14 of each year as &#8220;Flag Day&#8221; and requested the President issue an annual proclamation calling for its observance and for the display of the flag of the United States on all Federal Government buildings.&nbsp; The Congress also requested, by joint resolution approved June 9, 1966, as amended (80 Stat. 194), that the President issue annually a proclamation designating the week in which June 14 occurs as &#8220;National Flag Week&#8221; and calling upon all citizens of the United States to display the flag during that week.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim June 14, 2022, as Flag Day, and the week starting June 12, 2022, as National Flag Week.&nbsp; I direct the appropriate officials to display the flag on all Federal Government buildings during this week, and I urge all Americans to observe Flag Day and National Flag Week by displaying the flag and honoring all of our brave service members and revering those who gave their last full measure of devotion defending our freedoms. &nbsp;I encourage the people of the United States to observe with pride and all due ceremony those days from Flag Day through Independence Day, set aside by the Congress (89 Stat. 211), as a time to honor the American spirit, to celebrate our history and the foundational values we strive to uphold, and to publicly recite the Pledge of Allegiance to the Flag of the United States of America.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this tenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: The Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection U.S. Government and Foreign Partner&#160;Deliverables</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/fact-sheet-the-los-angeles-declaration-on-migration-and-protection-u-s-government-and-foreign-partner-deliverables/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 14:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden joins leaders from across the Western Hemisphere to present the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection at the Summit of the Americas. The Declaration seeks to mobilize the entire region around bold actions that will transform our approach to managing migration in the Americas. The Declaration is organized around four key&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden joins leaders from across the Western Hemisphere to present the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection at the Summit of the Americas. The Declaration seeks to mobilize the entire region around bold actions that will transform our approach to managing migration in the Americas. The Declaration is organized around four key pillars: (1) stability and assistance for communities; (2) expansion of legal pathways; (3) humane migration management; and (4) coordinated emergency response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In preparation for the Summit, the United States and other countries in the region developed a suite of bold new migration-related deliverables.</p>



<p><strong>Pillar I: Stability and Assistance for Communities</strong></p>



<p>Addressing the unprecedented migration crisis in the region requires us to rethink how we view multilateral development finance and how we manage the strains on our economies. Globally, International Financial Institutions (IFIs) and development assistance have been directed to poor and low-income countries, designations which no longer apply to most of Latin America and the Caribbean. The need for economic stabilization and support is particularly important in countries housing the more than six million refugees and migrants.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Belize will implement in August 2022 a program to regularize Central American and CARICOM migrants</strong> who have been living illegally in the country for a specified time.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Colombia’s leadership in responding to Venezuelan migrants and refugees with forward-leaning policies based on solidarity, humanitarian relief, and protection:</strong> Colombia reaffirms its commitment to fully implement its announcement of temporary protected status for displaced Venezuelan migrants and refugees in its territory. As of June 10, it has granted regularization documents to over 1.2 million individuals, allowing them to work legally, access public and private services, integrate successfully, and contribute to Colombia’s economy and society. Colombia further reaffirms its commitment to grant regularization permits to 1.5M Venezuelan migrants and refugees in total, by the end of August 2022.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Costa Rica commits to plan for a renewal of the special temporary complementary protection category scheme for migrants from Venezuela, Nicaragua, and Cuba</strong>, that have arrived prior to March 2020, contingent on obtaining necessary financial resources, and to convene an international task force to secure additional direct support and financial resources to support its implementation.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ecuador issued an executive decree that creates a path to a regular migration status for Venezuelans who entered the country regularly via an official port of entry, but who are currently out of status.</strong> This process includes unaccompanied or separated migrant children and a migration amnesty. It contemplates the provision of identification documents for the regularization process, taking into account the current difficulties facing Venezuelan citizens. It intends to expand this process to include all Venezuelans.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will provide additional U.S. support for a crisis response mechanism on migration</strong>. Working with Congress, we will provide an additional <a href="https://www.state.gov/support-to-the-global-concessional-finance-facility-gcff/">$25 million</a> to the Global Concessional Financing Facility (GCFF) housed at the World Bank to prioritize countries in Latin America such as Ecuador and Costa Rica in their newly announced regularization programs for displaced migrant and refugee populations residing within their respective countries. &nbsp;The new funding would support registration processes, the extension of social services, integration programs, and would benefit host communities that have generously opened their doors to the most vulnerable.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will announce $314 million in new PRM and USAID funding for stabilization efforts in the Americas.</strong> <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/jun-10-2022-united-states-announces-more-314-million-new-stabilization-efforts-venezuela">USAID</a> and the <a href="https://www.state.gov/additional-314-million-for-u-s-humanitarian-response-to-the-venezuela-regional-crisis/">State Department</a>’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) will announce more than $314 million in new funding for humanitarian and development assistance for refugees and vulnerable migrants across the hemisphere. This includes support for&nbsp;socio-economic integration and humanitarian aid for Venezuelans in 17 countries of the region.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Pillar II: Legal Pathways and Protection</strong></p>



<p>Expanding legal pathways for protection and opportunity is at the heart of efforts to humanely address irregular migration in the Americas. The goal is to <em>change the way</em> people migrate. Countries in the region have strategically pegged priority legal pathway programs with the primary reasons for migrating: (1) jobs; (2) protection; and (3) family reunification.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Canada’s resettlement and complementary pathways initiative:</strong> Canada is welcoming record numbers of refugees and in line with Canada’s immigration levels plans.&nbsp;As part of these growing efforts, Canada will increase refugee resettlement from the Americas and aims to welcome up to 4,000 individuals by 2028, providing durable solutions to a number of refugees in the region. Canada recognizes the important support of the UNHCR and the IOM in the region. Canada will also look to promote its regular pathways in the region to help provide opportunities including to those in vulnerable situations. For example, Canada will advance a promotion and recruitment efforts related to its Francophone Immigration Program which may offer opportunities to French speaking newcomers such as Haitians with skills and experience, some of which may gave have been displaced due to the pandemic.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Canada is addressing root causes and</strong> <strong>investing&nbsp;$26.9 million, in 2022-2023, in additional funding toward migration- and protection-related capacity building in the Americas.</strong> This funding is supporting projects across Latin America and the Caribbean focused on supporting the socio-economic and labour market integration of refugees and migrants; improving border and migration management systems; contributing to the safeguarding of migrants, refugees and host communities’ rights; advancing gender equality and inclusive economic growth; and preventing and tackling migrant smuggling and trafficking in persons.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Canada expects to welcome more than 50,000 agricultural workers from Mexico, Guatemala and the Caribbean in 2022.</strong> Canada is a strong supporter of labour mobility and continues to actively promote regular pathways for migration, including temporary foreign worker programs that respond to employer labour needs, to address our labour market gaps and as alternatives to irregular migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Guatemala approves new legislation to promote legal labor migration programs.</strong>&nbsp;On June 1, the Government of Guatemala approved new legislation to incentivize fair recruitment and expand legal pathways for its citizens. The legislation exempts airline tickets from value-added and departure taxes for those traveling for temporary work abroad contracts obtained through the Ministry of Labor.&nbsp; The new initiative is part of a broader set of Guatemalan programs and policies to expand access to labor migration programs, ensure ethical recruitment, and promote legal protections for Guatemalan workers.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Mexico will expand the existing Border Worker Card program to include 10,000 to 20,000 additional beneficiaries.</strong> This program allows greater labor mobility to meet employer needs in Mexico, promote economic development in Central America, and provide an alternative to irregular migration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp;<strong>Mexico will launch a new temporary labor program providing work opportunities in Mexico for 15,000 to 20,000 workers from Guatemala per year.</strong> &nbsp;The Government of Mexico aims to expand eligibility for that program to include Honduras and El Salvador in the medium-term.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Mexico will integrate 20,000 recognized refugees into the Mexican labor market over the next three years.</strong> With the support of UNHCR, the program would connect individuals with legal status as recognized refugees in Mexico to work opportunities in regions with labor shortages. A joint initiative with UNHCR, the private sector and the Mexican Government, both refugees and firms will benefit from successful integration into Mexico&#8217;s formal labor market.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will launch the development of a $65 million U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) pilot program to support U.S. farmers hiring agricultural workers under the H-2A program.&nbsp;</strong>In collaboration with other agencies, <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/06/10/us-department-agriculture-invest-65-million-pilot-program">USDA</a> is exploring a multi-year pilot program funded by the President’s American Rescue Plan to provide grants to agricultural employers that hire farmworkers from Northern Central American countries under the seasonal H-2A visa program and agree to additional protections to benefit both U.S. and H-2A workers. The pilot will promote the resiliency of our food and agricultural supply chain and three major Administration priorities: (1) driving U.S. economic recovery by addressing current labor shortages in agriculture; (2) reducing irregular migration through the expansion of legal pathways; and (3) improving working conditions for U.S. and migrant agricultural workers. USDA will enter into a cooperative agreement with the United Farm Workers of America (UFW), which will work with relevant stakeholders, including farmers, farmworkers, farmworker advocates and unions, to ensure that the agency benefits from a wide range of views in designing this program.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will provide 11,500 H-2B nonagricultural seasonal worker visas for nationals of Northern Central America and Haiti. </strong>To address labor shortages in key sectors of the U.S. economy and reduce irregular migration, the <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/03/31/dhs-and-dol-supplement-h-2b-cap-additional-visas-second-half-fiscal-year-2022">Department of Homeland Security</a> (DHS) and Department of Labor (DOL) made an additional 11,500 H-2B visas available in late May. These visas are dedicated for nationals of the Northern Central America countries and Haiti for this fiscal year. This is combined with new employer oversight provisions.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will roll out new Fair Recruitment Practices Guidance for Temporary Migrant Workers with the cooperation of major employers, including Walmart.</strong> As the United States and various other countries expand temporary worker programs in the Western Hemisphere, President Biden recognizes the importance of safeguarding against exploitation of workers. This is why his Administration will issue first-of-its-kind “<a href="http://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/ilab/ilab20220610">Guidance on Fair Recruitment Practices for Temporary Workers</a>.” The guidance promotes best practices for governments seeking to increase participation in the H-2 visa programs and employers relying on these programs. The United States has also mobilized the support of major U.S. retailer Walmart, which notes the importance of H-2A migrant workers to U.S. agriculture and that the fair recruitment guidance aligns with the company’s own expectations around responsible recruitment.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will commit to resettle 20,000 refugees from the Americas during Fiscal Years 2023 to 2024.</strong> This represents a three-fold increase from this year and reflects the Biden Administration’s strong commitment to welcoming refugees. The protection needs are significant in the Western Hemisphere. More than 5 million Venezuelans have been displaced in the Americas, and hundreds of thousands more people from other countries across Latin America and the Caribbean are also displaced [across borders]. As the United States scales up its resettlement operations in the Americas, we call on other governments to do the same.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will increase resettlement of Haitian refugees.</strong> Reflecting the President’s commitment to support the people of Haiti, the United States also commits to receiving an increased number of referrals to the <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-refugee-admissions-program/">U.S. Refugee Admissions Program</a> for Haitians. The United States encourages other governments to join us in strengthening legal pathways for protection and opportunity for Haitians and other displaced populations in the Americas.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will resume and increase participation in the Haitian Family Reunification Parole Program.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Homeland Security will announce the resumption of the Haitian Family Reunification Parole&nbsp;Program, which&nbsp;allows certain eligible U.S. citizens and lawful permanent residents to apply for parole for their family members in Haiti. Additionally, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services will take steps to increase participation in the program by reducing barriers to access.&nbsp;New invitations to apply under the program are anticipated to be issued in early fall 2022. &nbsp;Concurrently, the Department of State will increase efforts to process Haitian immigrant visas and reduce the existing backlog.&nbsp;State&nbsp;is in the process&nbsp;of assessing options to augment&nbsp;consular adjudicator staffing in Embassy Port-au-Prince and review additional operational efficiencies to decrease the immigrant visa backlog for Haitians.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will resume the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program.</strong> Last month, the United States announced the resumption of operations for the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program (CFRP). CFRP provides a safe, orderly pathway to the United States for certain Cuban beneficiaries of approved family-based immigrant petitions. <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-dhs-resumes-cuban-family-reunification-parole-cfrp-program-and-haitian">DHS</a> will resume processing cases this summer, work with the Department of State to begin interviews in Cuba by early fall, and build capacity to consider and process approved applicants, thus contributing to migration accord targets over the next two years.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Observer States</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Spain will double the number of labor pathways for Hondurans</strong> to participate in Spain’s circular migration programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Pillar III: Humane Border Management</strong></p>



<p>Securing borders with humane border management policies and practices is essential to reducing irregular migration and collaboratively managing migration across the hemisphere. The focus moving forward should be on: 1) humane border enforcement; 2) return of migrants lacking protection needs or other legal basis to remain; 3) facilitating returns to countries of most recent residence or origin; 4) support for assisted voluntary returns; and 5) strengthened bilateral and regional law enforcement information sharing and cooperation to combat migrant smuggling and human trafficking.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will announce a multilateral “Sting Operation” to disrupt human smuggling networks across the Hemisphere.</strong> The President will announce a first of its kind campaign, unprecedented in scale, to disrupt and dismantle smuggling networks in Latin America. In the last two months, the United States, led by <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-dhs-leads-first-its-kind-campaign-unprecedented-scale-foil-human">DHS</a>, has surged over 1,300 personnel throughout the region and invested over $50 million to support these activities. Through the end of May, efforts have produced approximately 20,000 total disruption actions including arrests and prosecutions, seizures of property such as houses and vehicles used to hide and smuggle people, and criminal investigations. DHS assesses that this has led to 900 fewer migrants arriving at the Southwest border each day, and we are just getting started. The U.S. will seek to expand efforts with other governments in the region to improve information sharing, build capacity, and advance criminal investigations.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will improve the efficiency and fairness of asylum at the border.</strong> In late May, <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/05/26/fact-sheet-implementation-credible-fear-and-asylum-processing-interim-final-rule">DHS</a> and Department of Justice began implementing a new process that improves and expedites processing of asylum claims made by noncitizens subject to expedited removal, to ensure that those who are eligible for asylum are granted relief quickly, and those who are not are promptly removed. The new process is a further step toward a more functional and sensible asylum system that reduces the caseload in immigration courts while also providing individuals with a prompt and fair decision in their case. DHS is phasing in the implementation of this rule and when fully implemented, the rule will shorten the administrative process from several years to just several months.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing the Summit of the Americas Migration Deliverables and&#160;Accomplishments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/10/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-the-summit-of-the-americas-migration-deliverables-and-accomplishments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 5:05 P.M. PDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you so much.&#160;&#160; And hi, everyone.&#160; I appreciate you all tuning in.&#160; Before we get started, I just wanted to set the ground rules and remind you all that this call is on background, embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern.&#160; We hope to have a factsheet for you sometime&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>5:05 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;&nbsp; And hi, everyone.&nbsp; I appreciate you all tuning in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before we get started, I just wanted to set the ground rules and remind you all that this call is on background, embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern.&nbsp; We hope to have a factsheet for you sometime tonight, if not the declaration language, to make sure that you guys have enough context.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you may attribute the contents of the call to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll kick it over to my colleague, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thank you so much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thank you all for joining us this evening.&nbsp; We’re excited to be able to talk to you about the Los Angeles Declaration that the President will be presenting tomorrow with other heads of state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So just to provide some background: The Western Hemisphere, as a region, is undergoing historic and unprecedented rates of irregular migration.&nbsp; Nearly every country has been impacted.&nbsp; And that is why President Biden is pursuing bold and concrete action to address hemispheric responsibility for the migration challenge the region is facing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, President Biden, alongside fellow heads of state, will announce a regional partnership to address historic migration flows affecting every country in the region.</p>



<p>President Biden is asking all governments along the migratory route to establish and fortify asylum processing in each of their respective countries while more effectively enforcing their borders, conducting screenings, and removing those individuals who do not qualify for asylum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection is centered around responsibility sharing and economic support for countries that have been most impacted by refugee and migration flows.&nbsp; It sets forth a framework for a coordinated and predictable way for states to manage migration, and focuses on four main pillars: stability and assistance for communities, legal pathways, humane border management, and coordinated emergency response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a historic moment for our country.&nbsp; No prior administration has so assertively engaged to the region to secure concrete commitments to share responsibility and act to address this regional challenge.&nbsp; And no U.S. President has stood in solidarity with Canada, the countries of Latin America, and the Caribbean in this way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to take a moment to share a few of the bold new migration-related deliverables that will be shared tomorrow.</p>



<p>Under the declaration, governments will commit to collectively expand temporary worker programs to address labor shortages while reducing irregular migration.&nbsp; We see this as a true win-win for countries such as the United States, Canada, and Mexico, and other countries across the Western Hemisphere that are facing massive labor shortages.</p>



<p>It will also open, expand, and reinforce other legal channels for migration &#8212; including refugee resettlement, family unification &#8212; which will also help address critical labor shortages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will surge support for countries that are hosting large refugee and migrant populations, and combat and root out human smuggling networks that prey on the most vulnerable in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, President Biden will announce an ambitious package of new actions to combat irregular migration in a humane and sustainable way.&nbsp; For instance:</p>



<p>Jobs.&nbsp; We’ll strengthen the U.S. economy by addressing labor shortages, again, through the expansion of labor migration pathways, while strengthening protections for workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under stability and assistance, we’ll surge support to refugee- and migrant-hosting countries to stabilize populations and reduce secondary flows towards our southern border.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Refugees.&nbsp; We’ll demonstrate U.S. leadership in refugee response through our new and ambitious resettlement and funding commitments.</p>



<p>And law enforcement.&nbsp; Announcing a first-of-its-kind and unprecedented-in-scale campaign to disrupt and dismantle human smuggling networks across Latin America.</p>



<p>And last, support for Haiti.&nbsp; We will announce deliverables to help the people of Haiti, in light of the deteriorating security and humanitarian situation in the country.</p>



<p>The Los Angeles Declaration demonstrates the commitment of the entire region to step up collectively to address the challenges of historic levels of migration.&nbsp; Many countries across the region have already been absorbing millions of immigrants, migrants, and refugees, and it&#8217;s time that we work together to address this challenge.</p>



<p>Tomorrow&#8217;s announcement is a major step forward towards solving the unprecedented irregular migration challenge in the region and along our border while also focusing resources to modernize immigration and temporary worker programs to address labor shortages that are driving up prices.</p>



<p>I look forward to taking your questions.&nbsp; And back to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; I guess my main question is: How is the U.S. hoping to ensure that countries who take part in this declaration actually follow through on the commitments that you just outlined, especially the commitment around making sure that folks who don&#8217;t qualify for asylum are returned to their home country, especially folks who are able to come to the U.S. and who are not able to establish a legal basis to remain here?&nbsp;</p>



<p>How are you hoping to make sure those countries actually follow through on that commitment?&nbsp; Are you providing them anything in return?&nbsp; Or can you explain that for me, please?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, thanks so much for the question.&nbsp; And this is, I think &#8212; you know, it&#8217;ll be an ongoing dialogue.&nbsp; I think that the process of developing the declaration really helps to bring us together to work &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s been a lot of work over the course of months, at all levels, to develop the text and to come up &#8212; you know, develop consensus around these ideas.</p>



<p>And so, but this is just the beginning.&nbsp; You will see, I think, tomorrow, not only the U.S. but many countries making concrete commitments around these four pillars that I mentioned, including the one that you just highlighted about strengthening asylum systems, cross-screening people that enter one border, repatriating people that don&#8217;t qualify.&nbsp; This is really critical.&nbsp; But actions are the most important thing.</p>



<p>So I think you will see the United States continue to engage actively with all of these countries.&nbsp; We will lead by example, but we will certainly expect that all countries do their part.&nbsp; This is &#8212; you know, at its heart, at its core &#8212; is about responsibility sharing.</p>



<p>And so, we will continue to provide support to countries that are really making a strong effort to build their asylum capacity.&nbsp; There&#8217;s many countries in the region that are doing that.&nbsp; And through the State Department, we provide a lot of support, and we will continue to do so.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much.&nbsp; Can you provide more details about the support for Haiti that&#8217;s going to be announced tomorrow?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President, but that’s just to say that I think we recognize that &#8212; you know, the need to expand legal pathways for &#8212; just in general, but also specifically countries where we&#8217;re seeing high outflows that are directly related to humanitarian situations and security situations.</p>



<p>And so, I think the goal here is to provide legal channels so that folks don&#8217;t have to take irregular means to get to safety or to reunite with family.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the pillar on expanding things like temporary worker programs and family reunification.&nbsp; I think, at least in the United States, that would require congressional action, and that&#8217;s something that the Biden administration already supports.&nbsp; So, what in the declaration is going to meaningfully change the situation for the United States, which as we know is taking in the vast majority of migrants in the Western Hemisphere?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We would absolutely love to see Congress act on this.&nbsp; I think we see that there&#8217;s a real opportunity to expand legal channels for migration, and that &#8212; that would be good for our economy, good for the United States, but it would also directly have an impact on reducing irregular migration.</p>



<p>We will do everything we can within our executive authority.&nbsp; So, you know, I think you&#8217;ve already seen in the last year and a half the Biden administration do everything that we can to expand access to the H-2A and H-2B program.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen a huge uptick in the number of people that have been able to access that program and have come on temporary work visas from Central America by the &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve done the supplemental for H-2Bs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have done a lot of work &#8212; USAID, in particular &#8212; on the ground to help build the capacity of the labor ministries in the three northern Central American countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then we&#8217;ve done a lot to, you know, make sure that employers are aware of how the program works and to better match workers in countries like Central America with, you know, employers that are that are seeking &#8212; that are facing labor shortages.</p>



<p>So, I think what you&#8217;ll see tomorrow are additional efforts to try to support employers in the U.S. to more easily bring in workers from the region.&nbsp; And, you know, other ways that that we&#8217;ve &#8212; coupled with worker protections &#8212; strengthening worker protections, as that&#8217;s been sort of a really important thing for us that we&#8217;re not only expanding access to work visas, but also addressing longstanding exploitation that exists in those programs.</p>



<p>So, again, we&#8217;re doing everything we can and it&#8217;s something that I think a lot of other countries are looking to do as well.</p>



<p>We will not be the only country tomorrow to announce ways in which we&#8217;re seeking to expand labor pathways.&nbsp; But you make a great point that without congressional action, there&#8217;s only so much we can do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, thank you for doing this tonight.&nbsp; My question is: Does the administration trust the government of Ariel Henry to do what it should with the deliverables for Haiti?</p>



<p>And also, we&#8217;ve been getting questions from Haitian migrants about whether the administration would consider extending TPS for them.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; All I can say is that, you know, our deliverables tomorrow are focused on providing opportunities for the people of Haiti.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this call.&nbsp; I am wondering if you can tell us: Is every country in the Western Hemisphere expected to sign?&nbsp; What about the countries that are not present?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t expect every country to sign.&nbsp; And we &#8212; as we were &#8212; as we were developing the declaration and engaging with countries in the hemisphere, we were prioritizing countries that are most impacted by migration and refugee flows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, as the President has pointed out, there&#8217;s countries in the region &#8212; we&#8217;re certainly not the only one.&nbsp; And there are some countries that have been particularly impacted by the Venezuelan outflows, the Nicaraguan outflows.&nbsp; A country, you know, like Costa Rica and Panama, you know, 9, 10 percent of their population are made up of immigrants and refugees.</p>



<p>So, you know, there&#8217;s certain countries that, I think, feel the pain and recognize the value in coming together, working on responsibility sharing, and advancing &#8212; exploring new tools that we can employ to better bring the situation under control.</p>



<p>So those &#8212; we’ve sought to build consensus among those states.&nbsp; And, of course, we opened it up to any other country that wanted to join us, but we were &#8212; we were never seeking to have all countries in the Western Hemi- &#8212; we didn&#8217;t expect to have all countries in the Western Hemisphere sign.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I had a question about screening people for asylum.&nbsp; If I understand you correctly, you&#8217;re hoping that other countries screen people at their border.&nbsp; Is it sort of the hope that fewer people reach the United States border and apply for asylum once they get there?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The goal really is &#8212; I keep on saying &#8212; it&#8217;s responsibility sharing.&nbsp; You know, we want &#8212; we don’t &#8212; we want all countries to enforce their own immigration laws.&nbsp; We want those that enter international borders to have the opportunity to be screened for asylum or other forms of protection or immigration relief.&nbsp; And we want those who’d be qualified to be returned to their home country.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s (inaudible) three, four, five borders to access (inaudible).&nbsp; And we really do expect all countries to (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; So, how many countries do you expect to sign the declaration?&nbsp; And will we see concrete numbers assigned to each country whether it’s in (inaudible)?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We’ll be able to provide you more details on all that tomorrow.&nbsp; I think you will be pleased to see a long list of deliverables from the countries that adopt the declaration.&nbsp; You know, this is really important to the President that this not be a statement of principles &#8212; that countries come forward with something to put on the table, just as we will be doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, I think there’ll be a very ambitious and concrete slate of deliverables.&nbsp; And we look forward to sharing that with you very soon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; I mean, I think I just want to second some of the questions have already been asked.&nbsp; If you all can provide any additional details on what these deliverables might look like, how many countries are signing on to the declaration, and even how many countries have agreed to provide these kinds of deliverables that we can include in our stories ahead of tomorrow&#8217;s announcement, that would be really helpful.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; One piece that I realize I haven’t spoken about that might be of interest to all of you is &#8212; and this connects to the economic agenda that the President laid out on the first day of the summit, on Wednesday &#8212; is we’re really looking at ways in which we can provide more support to middle-income countries in the Western Hemisphere that are hosting large refugee and migrant populations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think they see that this is a region that has a long tradition of solidarity, welcoming one&#8217;s neighbors, but, you know, the impact of COVID and now the Russian aggression in Ukraine &#8212; we&#8217;re seeing countries &#8212; it&#8217;s a lot harder for countries to be welcoming and to host.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s why we have seen, I think, a real uptick in secondary movements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, one thing that you will see tomorrow are &#8212; (audio drop) &#8212; are really strained under the weight of welcoming, you know &#8212;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; [Senior administration official]?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; hundreds of thousands, if not millions, of additional, you know, migrants and refugees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, work that we&#8217;ll do with the International &#8212; you know, the Inter-American Development Bank and World Bank, and other donors to provide more new sources of financing for these countries.&nbsp; And financing that will support not only the refugees and migrants, but the host communities themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s one more &#8212; one other area beyond what I briefed before where I think you&#8217;ll see that&#8217;s providing some specifics tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Just a follow-up to some of the questions that were already asked here.&nbsp; How much were the governments of Mexico and Guatemala involved in or consulted with in drafting the declaration?&nbsp; And does the administration still have faith that their commitment to this is solid, despite their absence at the summit?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I can say that we have very strong bilateral cooperation with both Guatemala and Honduras on migration.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve been &#8212; we&#8217;ve engaged with them quite a bit in the development of the declaration and have welcomed their support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everyone for joining, again.</p>



<p>And sorry, we are moving, so the call dropped a few minutes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just as a reminder, this call is under 5:00 a.m. embargo.&nbsp; And we hope to share a draft embargo factsheet shortly.</p>



<p>Talk soon.&nbsp; Bye.</p>



<p>5:25 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Welcoming Heads of State and Government for a Dinner as Part of the Ninth Summit of the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-welcoming-heads-of-state-and-government-for-a-dinner-as-part-of-the-ninth-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 03:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Getty VillaLos Angeles, California 7:54 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, folks, welcome.&#160; Welcome, again, to dinner.&#160; And Jill and I have been trying to keep from the press the fact that this is our private home.&#160; (Laughter.) I just learned an awful lot about &#8212; anyway, I&#8217;ll tell you about it later &#8212; from the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Getty Villa<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>7:54 P.M. PDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, folks, welcome.&nbsp; Welcome, again, to dinner.&nbsp; And Jill and I have been trying to keep from the press the fact that this is our private home.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>I just learned an awful lot about &#8212; anyway, I&#8217;ll tell you about it later &#8212; from the &#8212;<br><br>But, welcome.&nbsp; And, you know, I thought today was a good day.&nbsp; And I used to always kid Barack &#8212; President Obama.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d always say to him, “All politics is personal,” meaning that it makes a difference when you get to know someone.&nbsp; Whether you agree or not, it makes a difference to look in their eyes and understand a little bit more what&#8217;s in their heart.<br><br>And I thought today was a very good day.&nbsp; We disagreed on some things, but I found that on the central issues that we talked about, relating to everything from democracy to the notion &#8212; the specific notions of &#8212; from healthcare to the environment, all the things we talked about &#8212; there&#8217;s overwhelming agreement.<br><br>And &#8212; and I think that &#8212; that &#8212; I hope that getting to know one another better will make it easier to accomplish what we all want done.&nbsp; Because, you know, it is all personal.&nbsp; And all the people we represent, it matters to them deeply that we get it right.<br><br>And so, I&#8217;d like to welcome you all.&nbsp; And enjoy the meal.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>And the press &#8212; (applause) &#8212; they tell me you&#8217;re welcome to go swimming in the pond if you&#8217;d like.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Thank you.</p>



<p>7:55 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Jair Bolsonaro of&#160;Brazil</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-jair-bolsonaro-of-brazil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 02:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and President Jair Messias Bolsonaro met today to reaffirm the strategic importance of the relationship between the United States and Brazil—two of the world&#8217;s largest democracies. At a moment when the globe is facing a cascade of crises, from Russia’s war in Ukraine to global warming and pandemic recovery, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and President Jair Messias Bolsonaro met today to reaffirm the strategic importance of the relationship between the United States and Brazil—two of the world&#8217;s largest democracies. At a moment when the globe is facing a cascade of crises, from Russia’s war in Ukraine to global warming and pandemic recovery, the partnership between the United States and Brazil is vital to international efforts to address the climate crisis, and ensure peace. The Leaders pledged to continue their ongoing collaboration on trade and commercial matters, including through U.S. support for Brazil&#8217;s OECD candidacy. President Biden and President Bolsonaro also discussed how our countries must work together to facilitate sustainable development in the larger Amazon Basin to dramatically reduce deforestation, coordinate closely at the UN Security Council over Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine, and support democratic renewal.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Jair Bolsonaro of Brazil Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-jair-bolsonaro-of-brazil-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 01:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Convention CenterLos Angeles, California 4:00 P.M. PDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Great to see you.&#160; And I want to say that I was fortunate enough to visit your magnificent country &#8211;(knocking at the door) &#8212; somebody is trying to get in &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; your magnificent country on three different occasions, including for the World&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles Convention Center<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>4:00 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Great to see you.&nbsp; And I want to say that I was fortunate enough to visit your magnificent country &#8211;(knocking at the door) &#8212; somebody is trying to get in &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; your magnificent country on three different occasions, including for the World Cup in 2014.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I also walked in the &#8212; in the festival in Rio.&nbsp; And I &#8212; Brazil is a wonderful place, magnificent people, and &#8212; because of the vibrant, inclusive democracy and your strong electoral institutions.</p>



<p>Our nations are linked by deeply rooted shared values that unlocks incredible opportunities for both our nations, in my view, so &#8212; driving an equitable, inclusive global economic recovery, and raising our climate ambitions, and a whole range of things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you have &#8212; you’ve made some real sacrifices as a country in the way you&#8217;ve tried to protect the Amazon, which is a great carbon sink in the world.&nbsp; And I think the rest of the world should be participating in helping you finance being able to preserve as much as you can.&nbsp; It seems like it&#8217;s an international responsibility because we all benefit from it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the principal driver of our relationship is a connection between our people.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m anxious to hear what&#8217;s on your mind and talk about what you &#8212; whatever you want to talk about.&nbsp; I’m &#8212; I&#8217;d like to listen as well as raise a few issues that are of, I think, mutual interest to us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, welcome, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BOLSONARO:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Mr. President &#8211;President Biden, it gives me great pleasure, once again, to visit your country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have a great deal in common, such as, for example, our shared love for freedom, democracy.&nbsp; We also share the same values.&nbsp; And we want, ultimately, the very wellbeing of our peoples and peace worldwide.</p>



<p>Brazil is a gigantic country whose territory is as vast as &#8212; can be one of the largest countries in the world.&nbsp; We also have many riches very much in the heart &#8212; heartland of Brazil.&nbsp; Our Amazon region, which is larger than Western Europe by comparison, endowed with incalculable riches, wealth, and biodiversity, as well as mineral wealth, drinking water resources, and also a source of oxygen.</p>



<p>At times, we feel threatened in our sovereignty in that region of the country, but the fact is that Brazil does very well preserve its territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as much as two thirds of the Brazilian territory are fully preserved.&nbsp; More than 85 &#8212; that&#8217;s eight-five &#8212; percent of the Brazilian Amazonian region are preserved.&nbsp; Our environmental legislation is very strict, and we do all we possibly can to enforce it and comply with it to ensure the overall wellbeing of our nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Currently, Brazil presents itself to the world as a very concrete reality in the eyes of the world at large.&nbsp; In the near future, we may become the world&#8217;s largest exporter of clean energy by means of green hydrogen exports.</p>



<p>We also have other matters or issues of interest on the agenda &#8212; such as, for example, the fact that Brazil currently feeds more than 1 billion people worldwide with our state-of-the-art agriculture and highly mechanized agricultural practices and using unmatched technology anywhere in the world.</p>



<p>The world today, I dare say, depends &#8212; and largely depends on Brazil for its very survival.</p>



<p>The environmental agenda: Yes, we do recognize our challenges, but we &#8212; yes, we do our utmost.&nbsp; We do all we can to, of course, meet our needs, to foster our interests, and why not also, of course, accommodate the will of the world at large?&nbsp; But as I said before, we stand as an example in the eyes of the world when it comes to the environmental agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to food security and clean energy and also with regards to the environmental agenda &#8212; in addition to these topics, Brazil remains a huge country &#8212; a giant &#8212; and presents herself to the world as a solution for many of the current problems.</p>



<p>We are tremendously interested in drawing closer and closer ties with the United States.&nbsp; We have experienced almost 200 years of good partnership in our history.&nbsp; A few times, here and there, we may have distanced from each other due to perhaps ideological issues.&nbsp; But I am quite certain that with the advent of my administration, our both administrations have never had such a great opportunity, given the many affinities or shared areas of interest we have.</p>



<p>This year, we will be having elections in Brazil &#8212; in Brazil.&nbsp; And we do wish to have honest, clean, transparent, auditable, reliable elections so that there&#8217;ll be no shadow of a doubt whatsoever following the elections.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m quite certain that the elections will very much be carried out in this democratic spirit.</p>



<p>I came to office through democracy.&nbsp; And I am quite certain that when I leave office, it will also be through democratic means.</p>



<p>Brazil and the United States have all it takes to seal our trade relations, thus materializing a north-south axis of relations.&nbsp; Because other countries can work in a complementary fashion mutually, and we have the wherewithal &#8212; we have all it takes to become increasingly integrated nations and countries and serve as an example for the world.</p>



<p>Furthermore, Brazil, of course, still depends or relies on other countries in certain matters.&nbsp; We have always taken a balanced approach to these matters.&nbsp; We want peace in the world, and we will do everything for peace to be achieved.</p>



<p>We do regret the ongoing conflicts.&nbsp; But then again, I have a country to manage.&nbsp; I have a country to administer before me. And given our reliance on certain foreign players, we have to be cautious &#8212; always cautious, because the consequences following the pandemic and the mistaken policy, in my view, of “stay at home and we’ll take care of the economy later on,” further worsened by a war that currently takes place 10,000 kilometers away from Brazil &#8212; the economic consequences in effect are harmful and felt by all of us &#8212; and, in Brazil, especially harmful towards the more vulnerable segments of the population, who have to face inflation in foodstuffs as well as in energy prices.</p>



<p>So, Mr. President &#8212; President Biden, we remain fully available to cooperate towards building a way out of this episode that we, of course, never wish had happened between Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; We intend and we support and we pray that we will find a way out from the current situation as soon as possible so that not only Brazil, but the world at large can go back to normalcy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s essentially what I had to convey to you by way of introduction, dear colleague and head of this nation, as we bear in mind the wellbeing of our peoples.</p>



<p>Thank you so much for the opportunity, Mr. President, for holding this bilateral session and meeting with you.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>4:09 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Opening Plenary Session of the Ninth Summit of the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-opening-plenary-session-of-the-ninth-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 23:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Convention CenterLos Angeles, California 2:37 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Please &#8212; please, sit down.&#160; Well, welcome again to the ninth Summit of the Americas.&#160; A lot of hard work has gone into this summit, and a lot of strong and constructive diplomacy so far, I believe.&#160; We brought together diverse&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles Convention Center<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>2:37 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Please &#8212; please, sit down.&nbsp; Well, welcome again to the ninth Summit of the Americas.&nbsp; A lot of hard work has gone into this summit, and a lot of strong and constructive diplomacy so far, I believe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We brought together diverse voices and stakeholders and <s>development</s> [developed] an ambition agenda and &#8212; agenda for action to address the issues that matter most to the future of our region.&nbsp; They’re not all the same concerns, in some &#8212; one sense.&nbsp; In another sense, they’re all incredibly intertwined.</p>



<p>I’m incredibly honored to be hosting all of you here in Los Angeles.</p>



<p>My administration and the proposals that we’re eager to discuss with you were &#8212; we wanted to begin to talk about today &#8212; proposals that I think are a far cry from what we saw from our previous American administration.&nbsp; But equally important, we &#8212; the Vice President and I &#8212; we want to listen, hear all of you &#8212; what you think we should we be doing.</p>



<p>The next few days, we have an opportunity to find ways we can do better for all of our people by working together.&nbsp; And I emphasize “together.”&nbsp; Together.&nbsp; That’s what our people expect of us.&nbsp; And it’s our duty to show them the power of democracies to deliver when democracies work together.</p>



<p>The United States stands ready to work in partnership with all of you &#8212; governments, institutions, civil societies, young leaders of tomorrow.&nbsp; And I invite my fellow heads of state and heads of government of the Americas to join me in adopting concrete hemispheric commitments that are going to advance our efforts to build a more sustainable, resilient, and equitable future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With our Action Plan on Health and Resilience, we’re going to help our region recover from COVID-19, while strengthening health systems, improving our ability to respond to future health emergencies by investing in health workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new Americas Health Corps will train 500,000 public health and medical professionals in the region over the next five years.&nbsp; The United States is going to fund this together with the Pan American Health Organization so when the next pandemic hits, which it will, we’ll be ready and trained healthcare workers to administer the vaccines and the needed care, which we don’t have now.&nbsp; And it won’t cost your countries anything.</p>



<p>Through our efforts to strengthen the clean energy economy in the Americas, we’re committing to just &#8212; not just an energy transition but to make communities that have been historically marginalized are able to share equally in the gains, with equitable access to both good-paying jobs we’ll create and the affordable clean energy that will be made available.</p>



<p>I’m going to continue to work, just as I did when I was Vice President with Barack Obama, to promote trade and investment in clean energy, including using the United States International Development Finance Corporation, to help countries that need assistance to access financing and to help the region reach ambitious renewable energy goals by 2030.</p>



<p>By adopting the Inter-American Action Plan on Democratic Governance, we will &#8212; we’re going to commit our nations to making real the promise of the Inter-American Democratic Charter.&nbsp; And sometimes we forget what it says.&nbsp; It says: inclusive democratic governance, transparency and accountability, protections for human rights of all people, respect for the rule of law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on all these issues and more, the United States is making critical commitments to demonstrate our enduring investment in our shared future &#8212; and to address our shared concerns, because they are shared.</p>



<p>Last night, I announced the Americas Partnership [for] Economic Prosperity plan to drive equitable economic recovery and invest in working families throughout the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I rolled out a new partnership and collaboration with the Caribbean countries to address climate change.&nbsp; I just spent a little time with the Caribbean leaders.&nbsp; We have to go back and do a lot more and hear directly about their concerns and discuss all the ways we can move together, as they pointed out to me just an hour ago, with a sense of urgency &#8212; not years, not months, but soon.&nbsp; Soon.</p>



<p>We’re making good on our commitment to vaccinate the Americas against COVID-19, building more than &#8212; going to be more than 65 million doses that we’ve already donated to the region.</p>



<p>Over the next few days, we’re also announcing more than $645 million in new lifesaving assistance to address food insecurity in the region and increase the ability to respond to disasters, as well as historic refugee and migration flows.</p>



<p>Each one of our countries has been impacted by unprecedented migration, and I believe it’s our shared responsibility to meet this challenge.&nbsp; And I emphasize “shared.”</p>



<p>Tomorrow, a number us will join &#8212; a number of us will join in announcing the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection.&nbsp; This will bring our nations together around a transformative new approach to invest in the region solutions that enhance stability, to increase opportunities for safe and orderly migration, to crack down on the criminals and human traffickers who prey on desperate people,&nbsp;and coordinate specific, concrete actions to secure our borders and resolve the shared challenges.</p>



<p>And tomorrow, I’ll be speaking more to this and laying out our commitments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bottom line is this: The Western Hemisphere is home for all of us.&nbsp; Back in 2013, when I was Vice President to Barack Obama, he asked me to lead our engagement with the region.&nbsp; And I said we should be talking about the hemisphere and I made a speech back then, saying the hemisphere &#8212; we should look at it as a “middle-class, secure, democratic” hemisphere &#8212; from Chile &#8212; “from Canada to Chile and everywhere in between.”</p>



<p>Over the past decade, our region has changed.&nbsp; The challenges we faced have changed.&nbsp; And so, our policies and our solutions have to change as well.</p>



<p>But I want to be very clear: My fundamental view and my approach to the hemisphere has not changed.&nbsp; I still believe what I said then, and I hope that you do too.&nbsp; There is no reason why the Western Hemisphere can’t be the most forward-looking, most democratic, most prosperous, most peaceful, secure region in the world.&nbsp; We have unlimited potential.&nbsp; We have enormous resources and a democratic spirit that stands for freedom and opportunity for everybody.</p>



<p>And no matter what else is happening in the world, the Americas will always be a priority for the United States of America.</p>



<p>So, thank you again for being part of this summit.&nbsp; We have a busy few days and incredible opportunities ahead of us.&nbsp; So, let’s get to work.</p>



<p>And I’m now supposed to hush up and sit down, and we’re going to have a conversation.&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, Mr. President.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The plenary session begins.)</p>



<p>(The plenary session concludes.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll be very brief.&nbsp; I want to thank you again for participating in the summit.</p>



<p>I think we’re off to a strong start.&nbsp; I heard a lot of important ideas raised.&nbsp; And notwithstanding some of the disagreements relating to participation, on the substantive matters what I heard was almost unity &#8212; uniformity: rational migration policy, doing something about the need to provide access to recovery and funding, a situation where we concluded that we must work on the environment and climate change, and so many other things.</p>



<p>And there’s no reason why the Western Hemisphere can’t be the most forward-looking, most democratic, most open and peaceful secure region in the world.</p>



<p>We can lead the world and &#8212; with the potential that exists in our people and our values.&nbsp; And so, the way we achieve that vision, I think, is by working together.&nbsp; And that’s what we’re doing these last couple of days.&nbsp; It’s going to take a challenge that’s &#8212; impacts on all of us &#8212; and to unlock the opportunities and the benefits that are available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But notwithstanding the disagreements, think back to what we heard today.&nbsp; We heard almost total agreement on the substantive things that we should be doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let’s get down to real specifics in the next couple days as to what those substantive things are, how they’re implemented, who implements them, how we agree on them, what differences we have on them, so we get down to as &#8212; as the expression in English goes, “to brass tacks.”&nbsp; There’s probably a better Spanish or other phrase for it than mine.&nbsp; But get down to really what’s at stake so we can solve some serious problems.</p>



<p>Thank you all, and enjoy the rest of the day.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:47 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces Commitments to Advance Food Security in the Western&#160;Hemisphere</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-commitments-to-advance-food-security-in-the-western-hemisphere/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55223</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A year of rising energy and fuel prices, disruptions from the global pandemic, climate change, and the impact of Putin’s unprovoked war in Ukraine, are challenging food prices across the world and in the Western Hemisphere. Many of our neighbors rely significantly on imports for food and are particularly vulnerable to rising food costs. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>A year of rising energy and fuel prices, disruptions from the global pandemic, climate change, and the impact of Putin’s unprovoked war in Ukraine, are challenging food prices across the world and in the Western Hemisphere. Many of our neighbors rely significantly on imports for food and are particularly vulnerable to rising food costs. The region is experiencing the highest spike in food prices in a generation.<br><br>At the Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles, the President is bringing together key partners to address this crisis and announcing $331 million for humanitarian assistance, food security assistance, and disaster risk reduction assistance&#8211; out of the $645 million total, that includes support for refugee and migrant populations.<br><br>The number of people facing severe food insecurity in Latin America and the Caribbean (LAC) doubled from 2014 to 2020 to more than 90 million people. Venezuela’s humanitarian, economic, and political crises have left approximately one-third of Venezuela’s population food-insecure and brought child malnutrition rates to emergency levels, with as many as 50% of children under five showing signs of malnutrition. In Honduras, the World Food Program reported that in late 2021, the number of people facing food insecurity had nearly doubled in just one year, due largely to the COVID-19 pandemic and the impact of Hurricanes Eta and Iota. And, we must address food insecurity in the region in order to advance our cooperative efforts on migration and climate smart economic reform.<br><br>The United States is expanding investments in key social safety nets to help reduce poverty and food shocks in the region and to contributing more funding for humanitarian and food security needs that will improve the quality of life for peoples across the region. The United States is a leader in the global campaign to improve food security, from our work last month as chair of the Global Food Security Call to Action Ministerial meeting, to our pledges at the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-commit-to-end-hunger-and-malnutrition-and-build-sustainable-resilient-food-systems/">UN Food Systems Summit</a> and the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/07/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-plans-for-11-billion-to-end-malnutrition-at-global-nutrition-summit/">2021 Tokyo Nutrition for Growth Summit</a>, and our recent assumption of the co-chairmanship of the Global Agricultural and Food Security Program (GAFSP). We are working closely with the International Financial Institutions to accelerate the response to food insecurity in key areas including: (i) supporting vulnerable people; (ii) promoting open trade; (iii) mitigating fertilizer shortages; (iv) supporting food production now; and (v) investing in climate-resilient agriculture for the future. We also welcome the prompt implementation of commitments outlined in the International Financial Institution (IFI) Action Plan to Address Food Insecurity.  <br><br><strong>Joint Declaration of Agriculture Exporters</strong>: One-third of the world’s food is produced in the Americas, and the current global food crisis is an opportunity and responsibility for the region to step up to supply a greater share of the world’s commodities. The United States will commit during the Summit to work together to increase food production for export, increase fertilizer production and transportation, and to improve agriculture efficiency through technical solutions and information exchanges.<br><br><strong>Food Security and Humanitarian Assistance</strong>: The Administration is announcing approximately $331 million in assistance to support food security needs and to provide humanitarian assistance across the hemisphere.  This contribution will complement the United States’ existing commitment to providing life-saving humanitarian assistance, responding to acute food insecurity, and advancing capacity-building activities that bolster disaster preparedness and response across LAC, including by developing early warning systems and providing technical assistance to first responders and community-based risk management entities. Through USAID partners, the United States continues to prioritize food as well as water and sanitation, shelter, protection services and basic health care for vulnerable populations in Haiti.  In Central America, USAID is delivering emergency food, livelihood, and protection assistance, particularly in El Salvador, Honduras, Guatemala.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
