<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 12:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Catalyzes more than $700 Million in Private Sector Commitments to Make EV Charging More Affordable and&#160;Accessible</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-catalyzes-more-than-700-million-in-private-sector-commitments-to-make-ev-charging-more-affordable-and-accessible/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 12:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Record-Breaking Private U.S. Investments to Help Build 250,000 Chargers Per Year, Create More Than 2,000 JobsToday, the Biden-Harris Administration is highlighting how President Biden’s leadership on electric vehicles is catalyzing more than $700 million in investments from the private sector that will increase our domestic capacity to manufacture more than 250,000 new electric vehicle (EV)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>Record-Breaking Private U.S. Investments to Help Build 250,000 Chargers Per Year, Create More Than 2,000 Jobs</em><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is highlighting how President Biden’s leadership on electric vehicles is catalyzing more than $700 million in investments from the private sector that will increase our domestic capacity to manufacture more than 250,000 new electric vehicle (EV) chargers each year, add at least 2,000 good-paying jobs, and make EV charging more affordable, accessible, and equitable. The historic private investments will follow the $7.5 billion from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to build a national network of EV chargers, enabling convenient and uniform charging at home, work, and across the country.<br><br>President Biden’s vison, leadership and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law have positioned the United States to lead the electric future and make it in America. The President <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">united</a> automakers and autoworkers around an ambitious target for 50% of new vehicles sold in 2030 to be electric, passed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-proposes-new-standards-for-national-electric-vehicle-charging-network/">build a national network of chargers</a> for a seamless charging experience, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-catalyzing-americas-clean-energy-economy-through-federal-sustainability/">activated</a> the federal government’s purchasing power to procure more zero-emission vehicles by 2027 and 100% zero-emission vehicles by 2035. The President’s actions will make EV charging convenient, reliable, and affordable for all Americans, including when driving long distances.<br><br>Today’s announcements demonstrate how the President is catalyzing private investment to boost our domestic manufacturing capacity, enabling America to create a national network of chargers and create thousands of new high-quality, union jobs building, installing, and maintaining it. Today, the auto industry renaissance continues as the private sector steps up to invest in American-made charging across the country.<br><br><strong><u>KEY INDUSTRY INVESTMENTS</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Electrify America</strong>, a leading network of fast chargers, today announced a new investment of $450 million into its charging network by Siemens, a global technology and electrification leader, and Volkswagen Group. These investments will support the rapid deployment of up to 10,000 ultra-fast chargers at 1,800 charging stations, more than the number of high-power chargers available in the United States today.<br></li><li><strong>Siemens </strong>is on track to build one million EV chargers over the next four years by investing more than $250 million in the U.S. in the past six months, including expansions of its Grand Prairie, TX and Pomona, CA manufacturing sites. Siemens has created 500 new, good-quality, union manufacturing jobs across the U.S to support critical power and EV charging infrastructure. And, they announced a $25 million minority stake investment in a US-based wireless charging company. Siemens has a new manufacturing facility coming online later this year and is introducing a new Buy America-compliant AC charger this fall.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>ADDITIONAL INDUSTRY ACTIONS</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>ABB E-mobility </strong>is adding 125 jobs across its operations this year alone, including at two new facilities. In Sugarland, Texas, they are opening a training center where ABB will provide authorized service partners with hands on training for servicing and maintaining EV chargers. In Southern California, ABB E-mobility is opening a product development and research facility where it will design, develop, and test EV chargers for the U.S. market.<br></li><li><strong>ChargePoint</strong>, a leading EV charging network, is expanding its partnership with SMTC Corporation to expand DCFC production, establish a manufacturing line for Level 2 chargers at their Milpitas, CA, facility, and create approximately 250 new manufacturing jobs. The expanded facility will be able to produce 10,000 DCFC dispensers and 10,000 Level 2 chargers by 2026.<br></li><li><strong>FLO, </strong>a North American EV charging network operator and smart charging solutions provider, announced a $3 million investment in its first U.S. assembly facility located in Auburn Hills, Michigan earlier this month. By 2028, the facility will produce upwards of 30,000 Buy America compliant charging stations and fast chargers annually, create upwards of 730 jobs, and bolster Michigan’s economy by $76 million.<br></li><li><strong>Tesla</strong> is making <em>investments at its Gigafactory in Buffalo, New York</em> to support the deployment of new fast charging stations to add to its fast-charging network. More than 1,600 employees work at Giga New York producing the Tesla Solar Roof and Supercharger stations, which are capable of charging vehicles up to 250 kW. Tesla is expanding production capacity of power electronics components that convert alternating current to direct current, charging cabinets, posts and cables. Later this year, Tesla will begin production of new Supercharger equipment that will enable non-Tesla EV drivers in North America to use Tesla Superchargers.<br></li><li><strong>Tritium</strong>, who previously <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-ensuring-future-is-made-in-america/">announced</a> a Tennessee EV charger manufacturing facility at a White House event with President Biden, is accelerating its production schedule to manufacture DC fast chargers in the third quarter of 2022. They also plan to build their first Buy America chargers in early 2023. This facility will create more than 500 local jobs and will be capable of producing up to 30,000 fast charger units per year.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>WORKFORCE DEVELOPMMENT AND EQUITY</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>IBEW</strong>, as part of the Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-launches-the-talent-pipeline-challenge-supporting-employer-investments-in-equitable-workforce-development-for-infrastructure-jobs/">Talent Pipeline Challenge,</a> pledged to train 10,000 of their members through the Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP) by this August. Philanthropies, including the Hewlett Foundation, committed a total of $250,000 to support women and workers of color training for the EVITP-certification – with an emphasis on geographic diversity.  <br></li><li><strong>ChargePoint </strong>recently partnered with the National Electrical Contractors Association (NECA) to prepare its nearly 4,000-member companies, all of which are IBEW unionized, to install EV charging infrastructure quickly and professionally in advance of the release of NEVI funding to States.<br></li><li><strong>Volta</strong>, a national owner operated ad-driven EV charging provider, expanded its &#8220;Charging for All&#8221; initiative, a multimillion-dollar commitment to ramp up equitable planning and charging investment. They will use PredictEV, a planning intelligence platform, to extend services to any state or city looking to maximize impact of public investment, while also delivering free media-space to State Departments of Transportation to ensure inclusive engagement.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Third Day in&#160;Europe</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/28/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-president-bidens-third-day-in-europe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56408</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[9:10 A.M. CEST&#160;MODERATOR:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; It’s [moderator].&#160; We&#8217;ll go ahead and get started.&#160; I know the time is limited. So this call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&#160; And for your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker today is [senior administration official].&#160; We just have a couple of things at the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>9:10 A.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; It’s [moderator].&nbsp; We&#8217;ll go ahead and get started.&nbsp; I know the time is limited.</p>



<p>So this call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And for your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker today is [senior administration official].&nbsp; We just have a couple of things at the top.&nbsp; And then, hopefully, we can take some questions and go from there.</p>



<p>And then, as a reminder, after the G7 ends, we&#8217;re going to head to Madrid for NATO, and Jake and Karine are going to be gaggling on the record on the plane then as well.</p>



<p>So, [senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [moderator], and thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; I’ll keep this short and take a few questions.</p>



<p>A couple of notes up at the top on some new commitments being made and then happy to hear from you.</p>



<p>First, the G7 will commit to contribute up to $5 billion to address global food security, over half of which will come from the United States.&nbsp; President Biden will commit $2.76 billion in additional U.S. government funding to support efforts in over 47 countries and regional organizations.</p>



<p>Of that $2.76 billion, $2 billion will go to help save lives through direct humanitarian interventions, and $760 million of that will be for sustainable near-term and medium-term food assistance to help enhance the resilience and productivity of food systems around the world, particularly in vulnerable regions.</p>



<p>Obviously, Putin’s actions have been at the core and the thing from which you can draw a direct line to all of the vulnerability that we’re seeing around the world, in terms of food security.</p>



<p>His actions have strangled food and agriculture production, have used food as a weapon of war, including through the destruction of agricultural storage, processing, and testing facilities; the theft of grain and farm equipment; and the effective blockade of Black Sea ports.</p>



<p>Estimates suggest that up to 40 million people could be pushed into poverty in 2022 as a result of Putin’s war in Ukraine and its secondary effects, most especially around food security around the globe.&nbsp; This is just one piece of our efforts, and we are committed to do everything we can both as the United States and the G7 to work with partners around the world to address this.</p>



<p>Secondly, the G7 has also had very productive set of conversations on China and other 21st century challenges.&nbsp; Some examples, I think, you’ll see in the communiqué when it’s released today.</p>



<p>One, you’ll see leaders release a collective statement, which is unprecedented in the context of the G7, acknowledging the harms caused by China’s non-transparent, market-distorting industrial directives.&nbsp; The leaders will commit to working together to develop a coordinated approach to remedy China’s non-market practices to help ensure a level playing field for businesses and workers.</p>



<p>Leaders will also speak to China’s role in leaving, in particular, low- and middle-income countries in debt traps.&nbsp; That’s also a first for the G7.</p>



<p>And the G7 will commit to accelerate progress to tackle forced labor, with the goal of removing all forms of forced labor from global supply chains, including state-sponsored forced labor, such as in Xinjiang.&nbsp; We will commit to take further measures to strengthen cooperation, including through increased transparency and other measures to address forced labor globally.</p>



<p>The final G7 communiqué will be out later today, around the time the President heads to Spain for NATO.&nbsp; A consistent theme that will carry over from the G7 to NATO is our commitment not just to the transatlantic alliance but also to our focus on the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>We believe that these two are linked, as you saw with Japan at the G7 launching the infrastructure partnership, joining our aggressive sanctions, and the G7 coming together to call out harmful practices of China that impact Europe and the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>President Biden looks forward to seeing Indo-Pacific leaders at NATO for the first time, including when he will attend a trilateral meeting with President Yoon of the Republic of Korea and Prime Minister Kishida of Japan to follow up on their conversations in Seoul and Tokyo last month and confer on issues related to the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea.</p>



<p>There will be a lot more to come on the NATO trip.&nbsp; And I’m happy now to take a few questions.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; If anyone has any questions, could you please raise your hand?</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Let’s go to Shannon Pettypiece from NBC, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; On the food security announcement &#8212; just real quick &#8212; over what time period is that funding for?&nbsp; And where would that money be coming from?</p>



<p>And also around the food issue, have there been any discussions among the leaders about trying to get the grain out of Ukraine using, like, an intermediary country?&nbsp; I know there was talk about that before the meeting.&nbsp; Has that come up &#8212; like any proposed ideas about getting the grain stuck in Ukraine out?<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, with respect to the commitment from the United States and the President, that $2.76 billion comes from the second Ukraine supplemental.&nbsp; That is money that will be allocated and delivered before the end of this fiscal year.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s new money.&nbsp; It&#8217;s meant for immediate action.&nbsp; And those are new commitments from the United States to address the food security challenge.</p>



<p>To your second point, obviously, getting grain out of Ukraine to global markets is at the very top of the list of priorities that leaders have, with respect to addressing the food security challenge.</p>



<p>Obviously, Ukraine is a extremely important global grain producer and exporter, and the shortfalls in global markets as a result of Ukraine&#8217;s grain not being on global markets, and indeed those pressures even becoming more acute as Ukraine reaches harvest season, are, if anything, increasing the focus that G7 leaders have on this issue.</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s fair to say that leaders were focused on discussing a range of approaches to addressing the issue of how to get &#8212; how to facilitate Ukraine&#8217;s grain to global markets.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything specific to add in terms of particular pathways or routes and assessments of them.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s do Paolo Mastrolilli, please.&nbsp; Can you ask your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thank you very much for the briefing.&nbsp; I would like to ask if after the price cap on oil is the U.S. willing to consider also a price cap for Russian natural gas?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So the U.S. focus has been on oil.&nbsp; You know, I think that our belief is that this is a step that G7 leaders can take right now to get aligned around a set of objectives that&#8217;s going to both limit Putin&#8217;s revenues and squeeze the resources that he has to wage war and, secondly, to increase stability and the security of supply in global oil markets.</p>



<p>Leaders &#8212; I think you&#8217;ll see in the communiqué later today &#8212; are going to task ministers to work urgently towards developing &#8212; consulting with third countries and the private sector in an effort to develop a price cap around oil.&nbsp; And we look forward to the work that ministers do urgently in the days, weeks ahead.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, let&#8217;s do our last question to Jessica Ni, please.&nbsp; Could you ask your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Last year, the communiqué had some language on peace and security in Taiwan Strait.&nbsp; Just wondering, would there be the same this year?&nbsp; And also, about the language on China, can we expect it to be stronger than last year or just about the same?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for that question.&nbsp; I think that you will see very similar language in this year&#8217;s communiqué around the Indo-Pacific, including the Taiwan Strait. And secondly, with respect to the language on China, the economic practices, forced-labor practices, debt sustainability and China&#8217;s role in hampering efforts to enhance debt sustainability for lower-income countries, I think you&#8217;re going to see material steps forward across each of those dimensions versus the G7 statement last year, which was unprecedented in its own right by virtue of calling out China&#8217;s economic behavior for the first time at the G7 level.</p>



<p>So, yeah, I expect, across each of those dimensions relative to last year, to see some steps forward.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder: call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the embargo lifts after this call ends.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>9:20 A.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden and G7 Leaders Announce Further Efforts to Counter Putin’s Attack on Food&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-g7-leaders-announce-further-efforts-to-counter-putins-attack-on-food-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 09:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration is Driving a Multi-Pronged Response to Global Food Security Crisis President Biden and G7 leaders will announce that they will contribute over $4.5 billion to address global food security, over half of which will come from the United States. President Biden will announce $2.76 billion in additional U.S. Government funding commitments to help&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration is Driving a Multi-Pronged Response to Global Food Security Crisis</em></p>



<p>President Biden and G7 leaders will announce that they will contribute over $4.5 billion to address global food security, over half of which will come from the United States. President Biden will announce $2.76 billion in additional U.S. Government funding commitments to help protect the world’s most vulnerable populations and mitigate the impacts of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified war in Ukraine on growing food insecurity and malnutrition. These new investments will support efforts in&nbsp;over&nbsp;47&nbsp;countries and&nbsp;regional&nbsp;organizations, to support regional plans to address increasing needs.</p>



<p>Vladimir Putin’s actions have strangled food and agriculture production and have used food as a weapon of war, including through the destruction of agricultural storage, processing, and testing facilities; theft of grain and farm equipment; and the effective blockade of Black Sea ports Russia’s choice to attack food supplies and production have an impact on markets, storage, production, and ultimately negatively impact consumers around the globe. Putin’s aggression in Ukraine, combined with the impacts from COVID-19, increasing conflict, high prices for fuel and fertilizer, have combined to devastate already fragile global food security and nutrition. Millions of people living far from the conflict face an increased risk of poverty, hunger, and malnutrition as a result of Putin’s war. Estimates suggest that up to 40 million more people could be pushed into poverty in 2022 as a result of Putin’s war in Ukraine and its secondary effects.<br><br>While the entire globe will continue to be affected by Russia’s actions, the&nbsp;most immediate needs will present in the&nbsp;Horn of Africa,&nbsp;the most immediate humanitarian assistance related to food security crisis is in the Horn of Africa, as it experiences a record-setting fourth straight season of drought, that may lead to famine. As many as 20 million people may face the threat of starvation by the end of the year. The prolonged drought is also having dire nutrition impacts, putting children at severe risk of malnutrition and in need of treatment.<br><br>To address and mitigate further impacts on global food security, the U.S. Government will continuing life-saving food assistance to address these growing needs and leverage additional financial commitments. Of the newly announced commitment of an additional $2.76 billion in humanitarian and economic assistance appropriated in May, $2 billion will be to help save lives through emergency interventions and $760 million will be for sustainable near-term food assistance to help mitigate further increases in poverty, hunger, and malnutrition in vulnerable countries impacted by high prices of food, fertilizer, and fuel. &nbsp;<br><br><strong>The U.S. government’s multi-pronged response to combat global food insecurity includes:</strong><br><br><strong><em>Global Humanitarian Assistance</em></strong><br>Since the start of Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine in February, the United States has provided $2.8 billion to scale up emergency food operations in countries impacted by the food security crisis<em>.</em> In addition to this funding, the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) is committing another $2 billion in international disaster assistance (IDA) funds for emergency humanitarian needs over the next three months. These funds include direct food assistance, as well as related health, nutrition, protection, and water, sanitation and hygiene services, in countries with high levels of acute food insecurity, reliance on Russian or Ukrainian imports, and vulnerability to price shocks, and will support countries hosting refugee populations.<br><br><strong><em>Global Development Assistance</em></strong><br>As we continue to address acute humanitarian needs, the U.S. government will continue to strengthen food systems and mitigate medium-term impacts on food security. The U.S. Government is investing $760 million to combat the effects of high food, fuel, and fertilizer prices &#8211; now being driven up by Putin’s war &#8211; in those countries that need it most.</p>



<ul><li>The United States, through USAID, will program $640 million to support bilateral targeted agriculture and food security programs to strengthen agricultural capacity and resilience in more than 40 of the most vulnerable countries ­– Ukraine, as well as across 24 countries and regions in Africa, 10 countries in Asia, 6 countries and regional presence in Latin American and the Caribbean, and 6 countries in the Middle East. These investments will tackle urgent global fertilizer shortages, purchase resilient seeds, mitigate price shortages for fertilizer, scale-up social safety nets for families suffering from hunger and malnutrition, and avert food and humanitarian crises in the most vulnerable countries. &nbsp;These solutions will be tailored to mitigate specific needs within specific contexts, driven by local solutions that can be scaled for maximum impact.<br></li><li>The United States will also undertake multilateral efforts to protect livelihoods and nutrition and help vulnerable countries build their resilience to shocks, including food price volatility, supply chain issues, climate impacts, and other stresses beyond the immediate term. Specifically, in working with Congress, the United States will provide $120 million to the following efforts:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Support for the African Development Bank’s (AfDB) African Emergency Food Production Facility (AEFPF) to increase the production of climate-adapted wheat, corn, rice, and soybeans over the next four growing seasons in Africa.<br></li><li>Support for the International Fund for Agricultural Development’s (IFAD) Crisis Response Initiative (CRI) to help protect livelihoods and build resilience in rural communities.<br></li><li>Support for the Africa Adaptation Initiative (AAI) to develop a pipeline of bankable projects in Africa, to leverage private equity.<br></li><li>Support for the Africa Risk Capacity (ARC) Africa Disaster Risk Financing Programme (ADRiFi) to help African governments to respond to food system shocks by increasing access to risk insurance products.<br></li><li>A fertilizer efficiency and innovation program to enhance the efficiency of fertilizer use in countries where fertilizer tends to be overapplied.<br></li><li>Support for the UN Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) will fund soil mapping spanning multiple countries to provide information allowing for wiser water usage, greater fertilizer conservation, and improved climate resilience impacts.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Expansion of Feed the Future</em></strong><br>Feed the Future (FTF), the U.S. government’s flagship global food security initiative led by USAID, is expanding its global footprint in eight new target countries from 12 to 20 target countries, in Africa that were also most vulnerable to the impacts of Russia’s war in Ukraine. The new target countries are the Democratic Republic of the Congo, Liberia, Madagascar, Malawi, Mozambique, Rwanda, Tanzania, and Zambia. This expansion of Feed the Future countries delivers on President Biden’s $5 billion commitment in September 2021 to end global hunger, malnutrition and build sustainable, resilient food systems abroad.<br><br>The U.S. government currently invests $2 billion per year through Feed the Future, which builds on existing technical expertise, programs and partners in more than 35 countries. In these countries, the U.S. government investments pave the way for further investments from the private sector, donors and local governments.<br><br><strong><em>Global Agriculture and Food Security Program (GAFSP)</em></strong><br>The United States through the U.S. Treasury, continues to exercise leadership in the Global Agriculture and Food Security Program (GAFSP) – a $2 billion multilateral financing mechanism that has helped the world’s poorest countries increase investments in agriculture and food security. The United States is contributing $155 million to support projects that raise agricultural productivity, link farmers to markets, improve livelihoods, reduce vulnerability, and enhance resilience to shocks. The United States is also newly serving as Co-Chair of the GAFSP Steering Committee. In this leadership position, the United States will help deepen and accelerate GAFSP’s response to the food security crisis.<br><br><strong>USG Leadership in Driving Global Action</strong><br>From the beginning, the United States has been at the forefront of global efforts to confront this crisis.</p>



<ul><li>The Department of the Treasury is also providing $500 million to the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD), which will help support the EBRD’s Resilience and Livelihood Framework.&nbsp; This package of investments, expected to reach €2 billion over the next two years, will support businesses and public services across all sectors affected by the war in Ukraine and neighboring countries.&nbsp; The funding will support Ukraine’s energy and food security needs; investing in improvements in municipal infrastructure to provide energy, water and wastewater services, and other needs, and supporting internally displaced persons.&nbsp; The United States contribution is helping to mobilize an additional $500 million in support from other donors.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br></li><li>In April, the Biden-Harris Administration announced that the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) and USAID took the extraordinary step to draw down the full balance of the Bill Emerson Humanitarian Trust (BEHT) as part of an effort to provide $670 million in food assistance to countries in need as a result of Putin’s unprovoked further invasion of Ukraine. USDA will provide $388 million in additional funding through the Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) to cover ocean freight transportation, inland transport, internal transport, shipping and handling, and other associated costs. USAID will use the BEHT’s $282 million to procure U.S. food commodities to bolster existing emergency food operations in six countries facing severe food insecurity: Ethiopia, Kenya, Somalia, Sudan, South Sudan, and Yemen.<br></li><li>In May, the United States chaired a Global Food Security Call to Action Ministerial and launched the Roadmap for Global Food Security &#8211; endorsed by 94 countries &#8211; which affirms a commitment to act with urgency, at scale, and in concert to respond to the urgent food security and nutrition needs of millions of people in vulnerable situations around the world. Ninety-four countries have endorsed the Roadmap and committed to provide immediate humanitarian assistance, build resilience of those in vulnerable situations, support social protection and safety nets, and strengthen sustainable, resilient, and inclusive food systems in line with the objectives of the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development and its Sustainable Development Goals, and the objectives of the 2021 UN Food Systems Summit. The United States also convened the UN Security Council during its May presidency to underscore the intersection of food insecurity and conflict, particularly in the context of Russia’s war in Ukraine, and to urge the international community to action.<br></li><li>In June, the United States, in coordination with partners, raised awareness of growing food insecurity at the World Trade Organization (WTO) 12th Ministerial Conference. Key outcomes included: a Ministerial Declaration on the Emergency Response to Food Insecurity, in which WTO Members committed to take concrete steps to facilitate trade and improve the functioning and long-term resilience of global markets for food and agriculture; and a Ministerial Decision in which Members agreed to exempt World Food Programme food purchases from export restrictions and prohibitions.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The United&#160;States Continues to Strengthen Cooperation with G7 on 21st Century Challenges, including those Posed by the People’s Republic of China&#160;(PRC)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/fact-sheet-the-united-states-continues-to-strengthen-cooperation-with-g7-on-21st-century-challenges-including-those-posed-by-the-peoples-republic-of-china-prc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 09:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today President Biden met with G7 leaders to&#160;strengthen&#160;our cooperation on economic issues, cyberspace and quantum, and&#160;other 21st&#160;century&#160;challenges, including those&#160;posed by China&#160;to our workers, companies, and national security.&#160;The G7, representing over 50% of the world economy, is demonstrating that it is among the most potent institutions in the world today, with like-minded democracies solving problems. &#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today President Biden met with G7 leaders to&nbsp;strengthen&nbsp;our cooperation on economic issues, cyberspace and quantum, and&nbsp;other 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century&nbsp;challenges, including those&nbsp;posed by China&nbsp;to our workers, companies, and national security.&nbsp;The G7, representing over 50% of the world economy, is demonstrating that it is among the most potent institutions in the world today, with like-minded democracies solving problems. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Committing to a unified approach to confront China’s unfair economic practices</strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;The G7 will release collective, unprecedented language acknowledging the harms caused by the People’s Republic of China’s (PRC) non-transparent, market-distorting industrial directives. They will commit to working together to develop a coordinated approach to remedy the PRC’s non-market policies and practices to ensure a level playing field for businesses and workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Elevating supply chain resilience</strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;The G7 will share insights and best practices to identify, monitor, and minimize vulnerabilities and logistic bottlenecks in advance of supply chain shocks, as well as coordinate on long-term risk that undermine global security and stability. The G7 will make a commitment to&nbsp;intensify&nbsp;development of&nbsp;responsible, sustainable, and transparent&nbsp;critical minerals supply chains and establish a forward strategy that takes into account processing, refining and recycling.</p>



<p><strong>Cooperating on Cyber and Quantum&nbsp;</strong><strong>Technolog</strong><strong>y:</strong>&nbsp;The G7 will make a commitment to intensify and elevate our cyber cooperation; working with our close partners to achieveaccountability and increasing stability and security in cyberspace. The G7 will also commit to new cooperation to deploy quantum resistant cryptography with the goal of ensuring secure interoperability between ICT systems and fostering growth in the digital economy.</p>



<p><strong>Advancing</strong><strong>&nbsp;Trade and Technology Council standards for democratic, market-oriented approaches to trade</strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;The G7 will include a commitment to&nbsp;standards in technology, trade and innovation&nbsp;that represent our values as G7 partners compete with China.&nbsp;Through fora, such as the&nbsp;U.S.-EU&nbsp;Trade and Technology Council, we will demonstrate to the world how democratic and market-oriented approaches to trade, technology, and innovation can improve the lives of our citizens and be a force for greater prosperity. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Improving the multilateral framework for debt restructuring</strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;The G7 will underscore its commitment to successfully implementing the G20 Common Framework for Debt Treatments beyond the Debt Service Suspension Initiative. The G7 will urge all relevant creditors, including non-Paris Club countries – such as China – and private creditors, to contribute constructively to the necessary debt treatments as requested. The G7 will also reaffirm its commitment to promoting transparency across all debtors and creditors for improved debt sustainability.</p>



<p><strong>Committing to tackle f</strong><strong>orced&nbsp;</strong><strong>l</strong><strong>abor</strong><strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;</strong><strong>upholding</strong><strong>&nbsp;human rights</strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;The G7&nbsp;will&nbsp;condemn&nbsp;a range of human rights abuses occurring globally, including abuses linked to&nbsp;Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine,&nbsp;the&nbsp;PRC’s repression in Xinjiang and Tibet,the military coup in Burma,&nbsp;and&nbsp;ongoing suppression of freedom in Iran.&nbsp;&nbsp;The G7&nbsp;will&nbsp;also&nbsp;commitd&nbsp;to&nbsp;accelerate progress to&nbsp;tackle forced labor,&nbsp;with the goal of removing all forms of forced labor from global supply chains, including state-sponsored forced labor, such as in Xinjiang. G7 countries&nbsp;committed&nbsp;to take&nbsp;further&nbsp;measures to strengthen cooperation, including through increased transparency and business risk advisories, and other measures to address forced labor globally.As one important example of action to combat forced labor in the PRC, the United States is implementing the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act, which President Biden signed into law in December 2021.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Reaffirming the Importance of Democratic Resilience:</strong>  The G7 Leaders – along with the leaders of Argentina, India, Indonesia, Senegal, and South Africa – released a <a href="https://www.g7germany.de/resource/blob/974430/2057608/61edf594f5ca30fb7b2ae4b79d16f1e6/2022-06-27-g7-resilient-democracies-statement-data.pdf?download=1">statement</a> on Democratic Resilience, affirming the importance of strengthening resilience to authoritarian threats within our own democracies and around the world. This Statement will amplify the shared democratic values across G7 countries; condemn Russia’s invasion of Ukraine as an attack on democracy; affirm the importance of civil society and independent media; and outline how G7 members will strengthen actions in response to rising foreign threats related to illicit finance and corruption, foreign malign influence, and transnational repression.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Erdogan of&#160;Turkey</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-erdogan-of-turkey/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 09:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke by phone today with President Recep Tayyip Erdogan of Turkey. President Biden noted he looks forward to seeing President Erdogan at the NATO Summit in Madrid where leaders will discuss the consequences of Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine for Transatlantic security and other threats to the Alliance such as terrorism,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke by phone today with President Recep Tayyip Erdogan of Turkey. President Biden noted he looks forward to seeing President Erdogan at the NATO Summit in Madrid where leaders will discuss the consequences of Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine for Transatlantic security and other threats to the Alliance such as terrorism, as well as take historic decisions to strengthen the Alliance&#8217;s collective defense and security. <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Macky Sall of&#160;Senegal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-macky-sall-of-senegal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 06:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the G7 Summit, President Biden met with President Macky Sall of Senegal. Senegal is the current chair of the African Union, and the two presidents discussed the impact of Putin’s war against Ukraine on food security in Africa. President Biden discussed the coming G7 announcement on further efforts to support food security. The two also discussed the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>At the G7 Summit, President Biden met with President Macky Sall of Senegal. Senegal is the current chair of the African Union, and the two presidents discussed the impact of Putin’s war against Ukraine on food security in Africa. President Biden discussed the coming G7 announcement on further efforts to support food security. The two also discussed the G7 Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment which includes a new flagship project to invest in a new industrial-scale vaccine manufacturing facility in Senegal which will have the potential to produce hundreds of millions of doses of vaccines annually for COVID-19 and other diseases.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden to Award Medal of&#160;Honor</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/president-biden-to-award-medal-of-honor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 21:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 5, 2022, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will award the Medal of Honor to four U.S. Army Soldiers who fought in the Vietnam War:&#160; Staff Sergeant Edward N. Kaneshiro (posthumous), Specialist Five Dwight W. Birdwell, Specialist Five Dennis M. Fujii, and retired Major John J. Duffy.&#160; &#160;&#160; Staff Sergeant Edward N. Kaneshiro will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 5, 2022, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will award the Medal of Honor to four U.S. Army Soldiers who fought in the Vietnam War:&nbsp; Staff Sergeant Edward N. Kaneshiro (posthumous), Specialist Five Dwight W. Birdwell, Specialist Five Dennis M. Fujii, and retired Major John J. Duffy.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Staff Sergeant Edward N. Kaneshiro will receive the Medal of Honor posthumously for acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving as an infantry squad leader with Troop C, 1st Squadron, 9th Cavalry, 1st Cavalry Division, near Phu Huu 2, Kim Son Valley, Republic of Vietnam, on Dec. 1, 1966.&nbsp; Staff Sergeant Kaneshiro and his team entered the village of Phu Huu 2 while on a search and destroy mission and were attacked by North Vietnamese.&nbsp; Staff Sergeant Kaneshiro destroyed one enemy group with rifle fire and two others with grenades, which enabled the orderly extrication and reorganization of the platoon and ultimately led to a successful withdrawal from the village.&nbsp; He served in Vietnam between July 18, 1966, until his death on March 6, 1967, as a result of a hostile gunshot wound.<br><br>Specialist Five Dwight W. Birdwell will receive the Medal of Honor for acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving with Troop C, 3rd Squadron, 4th Cavalry, 25th Infantry Division, in the Republic of Vietnam on January 31, 1968.&nbsp; That day, a large enemy element initiated an assault on the Tan Son Nhut Airbase near Saigon.&nbsp; They disabled or destroyed many of the unit’s vehicles and incapacitated Specialist Five Birdwell&#8217;s tank commander.&nbsp; Under heavy enemy small-arms fire, Specialist Five Birdwell moved the tank commander to safety and fired the tank&#8217;s weapons at the enemy force.&nbsp; Afterwards, he dismounted and continued fighting until receiving enemy fire to his face and torso.&nbsp; He refused evacuation and led a small group of defenders to disrupt the enemy assault until reinforcements arrived.&nbsp; He then aided in evacuating the wounded until he was ordered to seek attention for his own wounds.&nbsp; He was honorably discharged on December 29, 1968, and today practices law in Oklahoma City.<br><br>Specialist Five Dennis M. Fujii will receive the Medal of Honor for acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving as crew chief aboard a helicopter ambulance during rescue operations in Laos and the Republic of Vietnam from February 18 &#8211; 22, 1971.&nbsp; During a mission to evacuate seriously wounded Vietnamese military personnel, Specialist Five Fujii&#8217;s medevac helicopter took on enemy fire and was forced to crash land.&nbsp; Although injured, he waved off a rescue from another helicopter and remained behind as the only American on the battlefield.&nbsp; During that night and the next day, although wounded, he administered first aid to allied casualties. On the night of February 19, he called in American helicopter gunships to assist in repelling an enemy attack.&nbsp; For more than 17 hours, he repeatedly exposed himself to hostile fire as he left the security of his entrenchment to better observe enemy troop positions and to direct air strikes against them until an American helicopter could attempt to airlift him from the area.&nbsp; Upon completion of his tour, he joined the Army Reserve and today resides in Hawaii.<br><br>Major John J. Duffy will receive the Medal of Honor for acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving as the senior advisor to the 11th Airborne Battalion, 2nd Brigade, Airborne Division, Army of the Republic of Vietnam, from April 14 &#8211; 15, 1972.&nbsp; Two days earlier, the commander of the 11th Airborne Battalion had been killed, the battalion command post destroyed, and Major Duffy was twice wounded.&nbsp; He refused to be evacuated.&nbsp; In the morning hours of April 14, after a failed effort to establish a landing zone for resupply aircraft, he moved close to enemy anti-aircraft positions to call in airstrikes and was wounded again, but still refused evacuation. &nbsp;In the late afternoon, the enemy began a ground assault from all sides, and Major Duffy moved from position to position to adjust fire, spot targets for artillery and direct gunship fire.&nbsp; In the early morning of April 15, after an enemy ambush, he led evacuees, many of whom were seriously wounded, to an evacuation area, where he directed gunship fire on enemy positions and marked a landing zone for the helicopters. Only after ensuring all evacuees were aboard, did he board as well, assisting a wounded friendly foreign soldier and administering aid to a wounded helicopter door gunner. Major Duffy&#8217;s service included three tours in Vietnam in a myriad of Special Forces assignments.&nbsp; He retired from the Army on May 31, 1977, and currently lives in Santa Cruz, California.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ABOUT THE MEDAL OF HONOR</strong>:<br><br>The Medal of Honor is awarded to members of the armed forces who distinguish themselves conspicuously by gallantry and intrepidity at the risk of their own lives above and beyond the call of duty while:</p>



<ul><li>engaged in an action against an enemy of the United States;</li><li>engaged in military operations involving conflict with an opposing foreign force; or</li><li>serving with friendly foreign forces engaged in an armed conflict against an opposing armed force in which the United States is not a belligerent party.</li></ul>



<p>The meritorious conduct must involve great personal bravery or self-sacrifice so conspicuous as to clearly distinguish the individual above his or her comrades and must have involved risk of life.&nbsp; There must be incontestable proof of the performance of the meritorious conduct, and each recommendation for the award must be considered on the standard of extraordinary merit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on the President&#8217;s National Security Memorandum on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated&#160;Fishing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/27/background-press-call-on-the-presidents-national-security-memorandum-on-illegal-unreported-and-unregulated-fishing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 19:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 1:42 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; We appreciate your patience with us as we’re running a few minutes behind.&#160; Today we’ll have a few speakers discuss the National Security Memorandum on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Other Harmful Practices that the President signed this morning. As a reminder, this call is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>1:42 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; We appreciate your patience with us as we’re running a few minutes behind.&nbsp; Today we’ll have a few speakers discuss the National Security Memorandum on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Other Harmful Practices that the President signed this morning.</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” but the embargo has now been moved up to the conclusion of this call.</p>



<p>For your awareness, not for your reporting, the senior administration officials on this call are [senior administration official], [senior administration official], and [senior administration official].</p>



<p>With that, I will pass it off to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you all for joining for today’s call.&nbsp; Really appreciate your patience with us getting it started, and really look forward to sharing with you that, today, President Biden has signed a National Security Memorandum focused on illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing and associated labor abuses.</p>



<p>This is a great capstone to National Ocean Month.&nbsp; This is following the President’s proclamation of June to be National Ocean Month and a recognition of June 8th as World Ocean Day.</p>



<p>The White House began this month with a series of announcements of the new steps the administration is taking to conserve and restore the health and productivity of the ocean for the benefit of all Americans.&nbsp; And today is the kickoff of the U.N. Ocean Conference in Portugal, which is the time for us to really highlight the international components of our engagements around ocean conservation in particular.</p>



<p>Today, we&#8217;ll be sharing with you a bit more detail around what we&#8217;re doing to combat IUU fishing.&nbsp; Again, that&#8217;s illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>IUU fishing threatens the health and precious biodiversity of our oceans, which is also facing increasing threats posed by climate change, acidification, and human pollution.</p>



<p>Additionally, IUU fishing threatens the food security of coastal communities that may not have the capacity to combat these practices and otherwise prevent overfishing in their waters and depleting of resources.</p>



<p>IUU fishing can be interconnected with a web of other troubling security challenges and criminal activities such as trafficking in persons, forced labor, trade in illicit goods, wildlife trafficking, and other violations of law.&nbsp; Some states also encourage IUU fishing by associated vessels as a method of reinforcing unlawful maritime claims.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. is committed to combating IUU fishing globally, and the National Security Memorandum that the President signed today provides the U.S government with a defined set of actions to address the problem of IUU fishing, including IUU fishing committed by distant-water fishing fleets, and associated criminal activities, such as the use of force labor in the seafood supply chain.</p>



<p>The memorandum, as you&#8217;ll see, directs departments and agencies with a variety of engagement strategies, from increased coordination with diverse stakeholders from public and private and foreign and domestic, to address the challenges in a comprehensive, all-of-government way.&nbsp; It also uses the full range of existing conservation, labor, trade, economic, diplomatic, law enforcement, and national security authorities to address these challenges, and focuses around enhancing coordination and the use of existing tools and authorities to address the challenge of forced labor in the seafood supply chain.</p>



<p>Lastly, it also calls for increased access and diplomatic engagement around training and technical support of foreign partners to carry out engagements in combating this behavior in the fishing industry.</p>



<p>So with that, I am pleased to pass this over to my colleagues from State to share a bit more and then to NOAA.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And hello to everyone.&nbsp; My name is [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] was just mentioning, the elements related to combating IUU fishing on the National Security Memorandum that was signed today by the President include diplomatic engagements.</p>



<p>The United States is one of the largest seafood markets.&nbsp; We have one of the largest exclusive economic zones and waters under our jurisdiction in the world.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also a fishing country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we cannot combat IUU fishing alone; it is a global problem.&nbsp; It is involved in the value chain that feeds not only the U.S. market but other important markets.&nbsp; And there are a lot of countries who have been working to combat IUU fishing themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we believe that one of the most important elements of our diplomatic engagement is to combine and partner with all of the countries that are engaged in this work to make sure that we are as successful as possible in addressing IUU fishing but also the related human rights, labor problems, and environmental impacts of IUU fishing.</p>



<p>And so we are very pleased this week to take advantage of the global focus on oceans at the U.N. Ocean Conference.&nbsp; And we will be launching an IUU Fishing Action Alliance to bring together countries to commit to a pledge to take urgent action against IUU fishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will help us in the international implementation of the actions outlined in the National Security Memorandum, and it will help us capitalize on the resources and commitment of other countries, whether they&#8217;re coastal states, flag states, market states, or all of the above; and really begin to generate increased transparency in terms of fishing operations, increased accountability of fishers to the international rules or the rules of their flag authorities, and to make sure that the seafood products that are coming into the U.S. market are caught in accordance with international rules and national rules.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s one of the major actions we&#8217;ll be taking to begin immediately to bring together the diplomatic efforts necessary to ensure the National Security Memorandum is effectively implemented and does what it is intended to do.</p>



<p>So with that, I&#8217;ll turn things over to [senior administration official] to talk about some actions that NOAA will be taking as well.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>NOAA will be announcing two actions that help to achieve some of the objectives outlined in the National Security Memorandum.</p>



<p>First, today, NOAA is issuing a proposed rule which will enhance and strengthen its capabilities to combat IUU fishing and counter forced labor in the seafood supply chain by implementing several provisions under three different laws.</p>



<p>And I think the key &#8212; the key takeaway is that the &#8212;</p>



<p>what we will be able to do is we&#8217;re changing &#8212; well, we&#8217;re not changing, we are making our definition of IUU fishing consistent with that of the FAO&#8217;s, which will enable us in our comparability findings to both include forced labor and how we determine whether a country has comparable laws to ours, allowing the imports, and whether or not we identify fishing in waters under the jurisdiction of a nation without the permission of that nation or in violation of that nation&#8217;s laws and regulations.&nbsp; And so that will help us to prevent imports of those products into the United States.</p>



<p>I encourage you to look at the full spectrum of the proposed rule for a number of other provisions that are proposed here.</p>



<p>The second announcement that NOAA, together with the 21 agencies that comprise the IUU fishing interagency working group, is &#8212; we are announcing that we are finalizing a strategic &#8212; a five-year strategic plan.&nbsp; And in that strategic plan, we have identified a number of partners that we will be working directly with to combat IUU fishing on the ground.&nbsp; And those partners are Senegal, Ecuador, Panama, Taiwan, and Vietnam.</p>



<p>We’ll be doing capacity building in those countries, not because they are the primary offenders of IUU fishing, but because they have expressed a willingness to work with the United States to combat IUU fishing in their countries.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it back over to [senior administration official] and the NSC.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Keely, can you remind us how to queue up questions, please?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for the call.&nbsp; Just so I&#8217;m clear, could you maybe reiterate or be a little more specific about what the mem- &#8212; memorandum directs the agencies to do?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, as a secondary question, I wonder how much of this is due to concerns about Chinese illegal fishing.&nbsp; And, I mean, China says that it&#8217;s a responsible fishing nation, but how would you characterize China&#8217;s behavior in this area?&nbsp; And has the U.S. ever broached negotiations with China over these issues?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you for that question.&nbsp; So, with additional specificity, the NSM directs departments and agencies to work toward ending human trafficking, including forced labor and IUU fishing, while promoting sustainable use of the ocean in partnership with other nations and the private sector, and advance foreign and trade policies for the benefit of American workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And specifically, it&#8217;s asking departments and agencies to increase the coordination with diverse stakeholders, as I mentioned earlier, to use that full range of tools that I mentioned earlier to you as well, but also to do things like: investigate fishing vessels and operators suspected to be harvesting seafood with forced labor and issue with hold release orders as appropriate; to increase our engagement with key private sector and foreign partners, including by providing training and technical support to these partners; and to carry out research on labor practices in the seafood industry through Department of Labor, for instance, to coordinate more closely with the Department of Defense, the Coast Guard, and other enforcement agencies as well.</p>



<p>Specific to your question about China and our engagements there: The National Security Memorandum is not about any one specific country.&nbsp; All fishing nations, including those with distant-water fishing fleets, carry a range of flag-state responsibilities including monitoring their fleets and enforcing rules to prevent their vessels from engaging in IUU fishing.</p>



<p>It is also critical that all flag states, including the PRC, fully accept and implement their responsibilities to prevent and deter IUU fishing, and ensures sustainable conservation and management of our fishery resources.</p>



<p>The PRC is a leading contributor to IUU fishing worldwide, and it has impeded progress on the development of measures to combat IUU fishing and overfishing in international organizations.&nbsp; And the PRC has a responsibility to uphold these commitments as a flag state and actively monitor and correct the activities of fishing fleet activities in other countries’ waters &#8212; of its fleet fishing activities in other countries’ waters, including preventing its vessels from fishing outside coastal states’ license agreements or without a license to fish at all.</p>



<p>The U.S. has engaged bilaterally with the PRC to identify concerns about IUU fishing, to promote the PRC’s full implementation of flag-state responsibilities, and encourage the PRC’s improved implementation of international measures and in cooperation with agreements like the Port State Measures Agreement that now &#8212; that [senior administration official] mentioned briefly about PSMA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also call on the PRC to fulfill its pledge and actively participating in and support the international community in fighting against IU fishing.</p>



<p>Thanks so much for the question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I had just some basic nuts-and-bolts questions.&nbsp; Is this the first time there&#8217;s been a national security memo on IUU fishing?&nbsp; And I also was hoping that the representative from NOAA could explain the first measure &#8212; the first action that they&#8217;re taking today in a little bit more detail.&nbsp; It kind of was a little bit confusing to me, and maybe she could walk us through that.</p>



<p>And then, I also just wanted to know &#8212; I didn&#8217;t get a chance to read through the entire memo, but the complaint that I often hear is that there is not enough resources and not enough agents actually, you know, working on these problems inside NOAA, inside CBP to enforce the laws that already are on the books.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m wondering if there&#8217;s any commitment from the Biden administration to increase hiring of people in this field.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to start?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I can start.&nbsp; Thank you for that question.&nbsp; Let me go through the proposed rule and see if I can clarify a little bit more what I stated.</p>



<p>The proposed rule would strengthen NOAA’s ability to address IUU fishing activities when implementing the U.S. Moratorium Protection Act &#8212; a key engagement tool used to identify, consult with, and certify nations and entities whose fishing vessels are engaged in IUU fishing, bycatch of protected living marine resources, or shark catch on the high seas.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re talking about today is really focused on that first part &#8212; the fishing vessels engaged in IUU fishing.</p>



<p>Specifically, the rule proposes to broaden the scope of activities that NOAA can consider when identifying nations for IUU fishing to include, the first thing, fishing in waters under the jurisdiction of a nation without the permission of that nation or in violation of its laws and regulations.&nbsp; And the second piece is: fishing activities in waters beyond any national jurisdictions that involve the use of forced labor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, those are the key provisions that will &#8212; should the rule get finalized with those, would allow NOAA to find a country in violation of that and prevent those products from being imported into our market.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>Regarding your question on the NSM, this is the first time there’s been an NSM addressing IUU fishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And regarding resources, we have been working closely with Congress to ensure there are adequate resources directed at addressing these key issues.&nbsp; And we’ll continue to work closely with Congress on the implementation of the memorandum.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And thank you to our speakers.&nbsp; And thank you for &#8212; you all for joining.&nbsp; Apologies, we have to cut this quick at 2:00.&nbsp; But as a reminder, the embargo now lifts.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Reach out with any other questions.</p>



<p>1:59 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  President&#160;Biden Signs National Security Memorandum to Combat Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Associated Labor&#160;Abuses</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-national-security-memorandum-to-combat-illegal-unreported-and-unregulated-fishing-and-associated-labor-abuses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden signed a National Security Memorandum (NSM) to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing and related harmful fishing practices. &#160; IUU fishing is among the greatest threats to ocean health and is a significant cause of global overfishing, contributing to the collapse or decline of fisheries that are critical to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden signed a National Security Memorandum (NSM) to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing and related harmful fishing practices. &nbsp;</p>



<p>IUU fishing is among the greatest threats to ocean health and is a significant cause of global overfishing, contributing to the collapse or decline of fisheries that are critical to the economic growth, food systems, and ecosystems of numerous countries around the world.&nbsp; Distant water fishing vessels, which engage in industrial-scale fishing operations on the high seas and in waters under other states’ jurisdictions, can be significant perpetrators of IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices.&nbsp; IUU fishing often involves forced labor, human trafficking, and other crimes and human rights abuses.&nbsp; Left unchecked, IUU fishing and associated labor abuses undermine U.S. economic competitiveness, national security, fisheries sustainability, and the livelihoods and human rights of fishers around the world and will exacerbate the environmental and socioeconomic effects of climate change.</p>



<p>The Biden Administration will address IUU fishing by increasing coordination with diverse stakeholders — public and private, foreign and domestic.&nbsp; The United States Government will use the full range of existing conservation, labor, trade, economic, diplomatic, law enforcement, and national security authorities to address these challenges, including:</p>



<ul><li>Promoting labor rights, human rights, and fundamental freedoms through worker-centered trade policies and working to ensure that supply chains are free from forced labor, including by engaging with international institutions and trade partners to address forced labor and other abusive labor practices in IUU fishing;<br></li><li>Collaborating within international organizations, including regional bodies, and partnering with stakeholders from governments, civil society, and the private sector, to increase global attention on the challenges of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related abusive labor practices, such as the use of forced labor in seafood supply chains; and<br></li><li>Combatting abuses and strengthening incentives for ethical behavior in the global seafood industry, including by limiting the market for products derived from IUU fishing, forced labor, or other abusive labor practices.</li></ul>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is also taking the following actions to combat IUU fishing, which will be announced throughout this week’s U.N. Ocean Conference.</p>



<ul><li>The United States, the UK, and Canada will launch an <strong>IUU Fishing Action Alliance</strong> aimed at increasing ambition and momentum in the fight against IUU fishing, including <strong>a pledge to take urgent action</strong> to improve the monitoring, control, and surveillance of fisheries, increase transparency in fishing fleets and in the seafood market, and build new partnerships that will hold bad actors accountable.<br></li><li>The <strong>U.S. Interagency Working Group on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing</strong>, comprising 21 Federal agencies, will release its <em>National Five-Year Strategy for Combating Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing (2022-2026)</em> by the end of July.&nbsp; The strategy prioritizes the Working Group’s efforts to combat IUU fishing, curtail the global trade of IUU fish and fish products, and promote global maritime security, while working in partnership with other governments and authorities, the seafood industry, academia, and non-governmental stakeholders.&nbsp; The United States will engage with priority partners, including Ecuador, Panama, Senegal, Taiwan, and Vietnam.&nbsp; Information on the member agencies and activities of the Working Group can be found <a href="https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/national/us-interagency-working-group-iuu-fishing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here.<br></a></li><li>NOAA will also issue a <strong>proposed rule to enhance and strengthen its ability to address IUU fishing activities and combat forced labor in the seafood supply chain</strong>. &nbsp;Specifically, the rule will enhance NOAA’s ability to implement the Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing and the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act.&nbsp; The rule proposes to broaden the scope of activities that NOAA can consider when identifying nations that engage in IUU fishing to include fishing in waters under the jurisdiction of a nation, without the permission of that nation, or in violation of its laws and regulations.&nbsp; This will ensure consistency with the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization’s <em>International Plan of Action to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing</em>.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>These new actions build on President Biden’s proclamation declaring June as <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-ocean-month-2022/">National Ocean Month</a> and key <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-world-ocean-day-with-actions-to-conserve-americas-deepest-atlantic-canyon-cut-plastic-pollution-and-create-americas-first-ever-o/">announcements</a> the White House made earlier this month to conserve and restore the health and productivity of the ocean for the benefit of all Americans. &nbsp;These announcements included initiating the designation process for a new national marine sanctuary to conserve Hudson Canyon in the Atlantic Ocean, a phase out of the sale of single-use plastics in national parks and public lands, the launch of efforts to create America’s first-ever Ocean Climate Action Plan, and the launch of an initiative to center environmental justice in ocean science and technology activities and investments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The White&#160;House Announces Public Tours Will Resume A Full Operating&#160;Schedule</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/the-white-house-announces-public-tours-will-resume-a-full-operating-schedule/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will resume a full operating schedule from Tuesdays through Saturdays beginning on Tuesday, July 19, 2022. Public tours will be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Tuesdays, Wednesdays, Thursdays, Fridays, and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will resume a full operating schedule from Tuesdays through Saturdays beginning on Tuesday, July 19, 2022. Public tours will be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Tuesdays, Wednesdays, Thursdays, Fridays, and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All White House tours are free of charge. The White House tour schedule is subject to change based on inclement weather or official use<br><br><strong>Public White House Tour Requests</strong></p>



<p>Public tour requests are scheduled on a first come, first served basis and must be submitted through a Member of Congress and their Congressional Tour Coordinator. Constituents may reach your Member of Congress and Congressional Tour Coordinator through the U.S. House of Representative’s Switchboard at 202-225-3121, the U.S. Senate Switchboard at 202-224-3121, or online at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.congress.gov/members">www.congress.gov/members</a>.</p>



<p>Consistent with prior practices, public White House tour requests must be submitted a minimum of 21 days in advance and no more than 90 days in advance of the requested tour date(s). Reservations cannot be accepted for tour dates outside this 21 – 90-day window.&nbsp;Congressional Tour Coordinators will be able to submit tour requests for the full operating schedule on Monday, June 27, 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The White House will continue to closely monitor the COVID-19 situation with guidance based on recommendations from the CDC, and other public health officials and medical experts, and reserves the right to adjust availability of the public tours as necessary to adhere to the latest health guidance. Within the 10 days prior to the public tour, anyone who has tested positive for COVID-19, has had any COVID-19 symptoms, or been in close contact with someone confirmed or suspected to have COVID-19, should stay home. Face masks will be available when entering the White House complex for those who choose to wear them.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
