<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 13:52:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by White House Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the Meeting Between President Joe Biden and President Vladimir Putin of Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-president-vladimir-putin-of-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden will meet with President Putin in Geneva, Switzerland on June 16, 2021. The leaders will discuss the full range of pressing issues, as we seek to restore predictability and stability to the U.S.-Russia relationship. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden will meet with President Putin in Geneva, Switzerland on June 16, 2021. The leaders will discuss the full range of pressing issues, as we seek to restore predictability and stability to the U.S.-Russia relationship.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden During Briefing on the Atlantic Hurricane Outlook and Preparedness Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/24/remarks-by-president-biden-during-briefing-on-the-atlantic-hurricane-outlook-and-preparedness-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FEMA HeadquartersWashington, D.C. 1:44 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hey, the press.&#160; Welcome.&#160; I have a very brief opening statement here.&#160; Administrator Criswell, thanks for &#8212; thanks for hosting us.&#160; You know, I wanted a tested veteran for FEMA, and that&#8217;s exactly what I got in the new head of FEMA.&#160; I really do appreciate it.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">FEMA Headquarters<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>1:44 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hey, the press.&nbsp; Welcome.&nbsp; I have a very brief opening statement here.&nbsp;<br><br>Administrator Criswell, thanks for &#8212; thanks for hosting us.&nbsp; You know, I wanted a tested veteran for FEMA, and that&#8217;s exactly what I got in the new head of FEMA.&nbsp; I really do appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>She served as a fire safety officer &#8212; I got to turn this on &#8212; a fire safety officer in &#8212; in Iraq and Afghanistan &#8212; that qualifies for any tough job &#8212; and played a critical role at FEMA before, and &#8212; and was a leader in response to something I was deeply involved in as Vice President at the time: Superstorm Sandy.&nbsp; Thank you for all that great work.&nbsp;<br><br>Already this year, FEMA has stepped up and vaccinated America and responded to winter storms, reminding us that we can never be too prepared.&nbsp;<br><br>My administration is going to bring every resource to bear &#8212; every resource to bear every time to help American people &#8212; the American people weather emergencies.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;re going to spare no expense, no effort to keep Americans safe and respond to crises when they arise.&nbsp; And they certainly will.&nbsp;<br><br>Now it&#8217;s time to get ready for the busiest time of the year for disasters in America: hurricane season in the south and east, and the fire season out west.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m here today to make it clear that I will insist on nothing less than readiness for all of these challenges.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make sure the men and women of FEMA and our other key agencies have everything they need &#8212; everything they need, because they&#8217;ve got an incredibly difficult job.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I&#8217;m announcing that FEMA is going to make $1 billion available to the states, territories, Tribes, and rural communities through the Building Resilience Infrastructure and Communities program &#8212; the so-called BRIC program.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s going to double the funding available of la- &#8212; from last year, and it&#8217;s going to help communities, including those too often overlooked, and it&#8217;s going to invest in resilience and better protect themselves to serve for other climate events that we&#8217;re going to be facing.<br><br>Last year, as you all know, we faced the most named storms on record.&nbsp; Seven out of the thirty named storms alone claimed 86 lives and caused more than $40 billion in damage.&nbsp;<br><br>This year, NOAA is focusing on another severe season, perhaps &#8212; and God willing &#8212; not as bad as 2020, but still quite bad.&nbsp; We all know that these storms are coming.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be prepared; we have to be ready.&nbsp; We have to be ready.&nbsp;<br><br>When disaster strikes, we have to be there to protect and also help people recover.&nbsp; And so it&#8217;s about &#8212; not about red states and blue states.&nbsp; You all know that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about having people&#8217;s backs in the toughest moments that they face, ready with food, water, blankets, shelters, and more.&nbsp;<br><br>But there&#8217;s, you know, there &#8212; to be, you know, beginning this effort for 2021 is &#8212; I think we&#8217;ve learned a few lessons from last year as well.&nbsp; There&#8217;s help us &#8212; we &#8212; there, you know, being there to help clear roads, rebuild Main Streets, and so that the families can get back to their lives &#8212; that&#8217;s what FEMA does every single day.&nbsp; As my mother would say, “They’re doing God’s work.”<br><br>Today &#8212; today&#8217;s briefing is a critical reminder: We don&#8217;t have a moment to lose in preparing for 2021.&nbsp; And so, again, I want to thank you for all that you do.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m looking forward to hearing from you all.&nbsp; And I thank the press for coming in.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>1:48 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Democratic Opposition Leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-democratic-opposition-leader-svyatlana-tsikhanouskaya-of-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan spoke today with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus. Mr. Sullivan conveyed the United States’ strong support for the demands of the Belarusian people for democracy, human rights, and fundamental freedoms.  Mr. Sullivan praised the bravery and selfless sacrifice of democratic leaders like Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya, her husband, Syarhey, and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan spoke today with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus. Mr. Sullivan conveyed the United States’ strong support for the demands of the Belarusian people for democracy, human rights, and fundamental freedoms.  Mr. Sullivan praised the bravery and selfless sacrifice of democratic leaders like Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya, her husband, Syarhey, and the hundreds of other Belarusian democracy activists, independent journalists, and civil society leaders who languish in Belarusian jails as political prisoners of the Lukashenka regime.  Mr. Sullivan strongly condemned the brazen and dangerous grounding of a Ryanair flight between two EU member states on May 23 and the subsequent removal and detention of journalist Raman Pratasevich.  Mr. Sullivan cited the U.S. demand for the immediate release of Mr. Pratasevich and all political prisoners in Belarus, as well as the need for free and fair elections under OSCE observation to resolve the current crisis.  Finally, Mr. Sullivan made clear that the United States, in coordination with the EU and other allies and partners, will hold the Lukashenka regime to account.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br> ###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Simon Coveney of Ireland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-foreign-minister-simon-coveney-of-ireland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Foreign Minister Simon Coveney of Ireland to discuss our strong bilateral relations and cooperation on a number of shared global challenges.  Mr. Sullivan and Foreign Minister Coveney condemned the forced diversion of a flight between two EU member states and the subsequent removal and arrest of journalist&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Foreign Minister Simon Coveney of Ireland to discuss our strong bilateral relations and cooperation on a number of shared global challenges.  Mr. Sullivan and Foreign Minister Coveney condemned the forced diversion of a flight between two EU member states and the subsequent removal and arrest of journalist Raman Pratasevich in Minsk by the Lukashenka regime, and they agreed to remain in close touch on an appropriate response.  They also discussed Ireland’s role in addressing challenges to peace and security as a non-permanent member of the UN Security Council.  Mr. Sullivan and Foreign Minister Coveney reaffirmed their commitment to protecting the gains of the Good Friday Agreement for all communities in Northern Ireland.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Diversion of Ryanair Flight and Arrest of Journalist in Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-diversion-of-ryanair-flight-and-arrest-of-journalist-in-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Belarus’s forced diversion of a commercial Ryanair flight, traveling between two member states of the European Union, and subsequent removal and arrest of Raman Pratasevich, a Belarusian journalist traveling abroad, are a direct affront to international norms. The United States condemns in the strongest possible terms both the diversion of the plane and the subsequent&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Belarus’s forced diversion of a commercial Ryanair flight, traveling between two member states of the European Union, and subsequent removal and arrest of Raman Pratasevich, a Belarusian journalist traveling abroad, are a direct affront to international norms. The United States condemns in the strongest possible terms both the diversion of the plane and the subsequent removal and arrest of Mr. Pratasevich. This outrageous incident and the video Mr. Pratasevich appears to have made under duress are shameful assaults on both political dissent and the freedom of the press. The United States joins countries around the world in calling for his release, as well as for the release of the hundreds of political prisoners who are being unjustly detained by the Lukashenka regime.</p>



<p>I join the many calls for an international investigation to ascertain the complete facts of the case. I welcome the news that the European Union has called for targeted economic sanctions and other measures, and have asked my team to develop appropriate options to hold accountable those responsible, in close coordination with the European Union, other allies and partners, and international organizations.</p>



<p>For months, the Belarusian people have made their voices heard—demanding democracy, respect for human rights, and the preservation of fundamental freedoms. I applaud the courage and determination of Belarusians fighting for basic rights, including journalists like Raman Pratasevich and opposition leaders like Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya and her husband, Syarhey Tsikhanouski. The United States will continue to stand with the people of Belarus in their struggle.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi of Egypt</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-president-abdel-fattah-al-sisi-of-egypt-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 21:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi of Egypt. President Biden thanked Egypt for its successful diplomacy and coordination with the United States to end the recent hostilities in Israel and Gaza and ensure violence does not reoccur. The two leaders consulted on the urgent need to deliver humanitarian assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi of Egypt. President Biden thanked Egypt for its successful diplomacy and coordination with the United States to end the recent hostilities in Israel and Gaza and ensure violence does not reoccur. The two leaders consulted on the urgent need to deliver humanitarian assistance to those in need in Gaza and to support rebuilding efforts in a manner that benefits the people there and not Hamas. President Biden said he has asked Secretary of State Antony Blinken to visit the region for follow up on these urgent needs. Regarding the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam, President Biden acknowledged Egypt’s concerns about access to Nile River waters and underscored the U.S. interest in achieving a diplomatic resolution that meets the legitimate needs of Egypt, Sudan, and Ethiopia. The two leaders also discussed their commitment to upholding Libyan plans for national elections in December and the removal of all foreign military and irregular forces from Libya. They also affirmed their support for the Iraqi government’s efforts to strengthen Iraq’s full sovereignty and independence. President Biden underscored the importance of a constructive dialogue on human rights in Egypt. The two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to a strong and productive U.S.-Egypt partnership.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 1318</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2021/05/24/bill-signed-h-r-1318/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 21:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, May 24, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 1318, the &#8220;Alaska Tourism Restoration Act,&#8221; which temporarily allows foreign-flagged cruise ships to sail directly from Washington State to Alaska without having to dock in Canada first until either the date on which Canada lifts restrictions prohibiting cruise ships from docking in its waters&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, May 24, 2021, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 1318, the &#8220;Alaska Tourism Restoration Act,&#8221; which temporarily allows foreign-flagged cruise ships to sail directly from Washington State to Alaska without having to dock in Canada first until either the date on which Canada lifts restrictions prohibiting cruise ships from docking in its waters due to the COVID-19 pandemic or March 31, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden and First Lady Jill Biden Thanking National Guard Members at the End of Their Capitol Deployment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-thanking-national-guard-members-at-the-end-of-their-capitol-deployment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 21:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We want to offer our deepest thanks and enduring gratitude to the women and men of our National Guard for their service to keep the U.S. Capitol Complex secure over the past nearly five months. Since the insurrection on January 6, thousands of proud service members, from states and territories all across our Union, have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We want to offer our deepest thanks and enduring gratitude to the women and men of our National Guard for their service to keep the U.S. Capitol Complex secure over the past nearly five months. Since the insurrection on January 6, thousands of proud service members, from states and territories all across our Union, have stood watch over the citadel of our democracy. As they return now to their homes and families, we salute each of them for their commitment to country. When duty calls, our National Guard members put their lives on hold to stand as a shield and a support when their country is in need. We’ve asked so much of our Guard over the past year, not only defending our Capitol, but supporting our fight against COVID-19, responding to storm damage and wildfires, and deploying internationally to support peacekeeping missions. The Biden family is a National Guard family, and we are forever grateful and in awe of those who, like our son Beau, understand that duty and service to others is what makes us who we are as Americans. To all the National Guard members and their families who sacrifice so much for our country, like all our service members: we owe you and we will always have your backs.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Invests $1 Billion To Protect Communities, Families, and Businesses Before Disaster Strikes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/fact-sheet-biden-administration-invests-1-billion-to-protect-communities-families-and-businesses-before-disaster-strikes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Funding Builds on Efforts to Enhance Climate Change Resilience as President Biden Visits FEMA Ahead of Hurricane Season Today, President Biden will meet with members of his homeland security and climate teams at the Federal Emergency Management Agency&#8217;s (FEMA) National Response Coordination Center in Washington, D.C. to receive an update on preparations for the 2021&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Funding Builds on Efforts to Enhance Climate Change Resilience as President Biden Visits FEMA Ahead of Hurricane Season</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden will meet with members of his homeland security and climate teams at the Federal Emergency Management Agency&#8217;s (FEMA) National Response Coordination Center in Washington, D.C. to receive an update on preparations for the 2021 hurricane season. In advance of the President’s visit, the Administration is announcing it will direct $1 billion for communities, states, and Tribal governments into pre-disaster mitigation resources to prepare for extreme weather events and other disasters, and the Administration is announcing the development of <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/new-nasa-earth-systems-observatory-to-help-address-mitigate-climate-change" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">next generation climate data systems at NASA</a> to help understand and track how climate change is impacting communities.<br><br>In 2020, the United States experienced a record year for extreme weather, including an unprecedented 30 named storms in the Atlantic Basin. The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) is anticipating another above-normal hurricane season this year.<br><br>The costs of extreme weather events, in lives and economic damage, have been staggering. Last year alone, communities across the United States suffered through 22 separate weather and climate-related disasters with loses exceeding $1 billion each, shattering previous records, at a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion. This year has already wrought devastation, as unusual winter storms crossed Texas and the south.<br><br>On May 20<sup>th</sup>, NOAA released its <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/media-release/noaa-predicts-another-active-atlantic-hurricane-season">2021 Atlantic hurricane season outlook</a>. Forecasters predict a 60% chance of an above-normal season, a 30% chance of a near-normal season, and a 10% chance of a below-normal season. Additionally, forecasters expect a likely range of 13 to 20 named storms, of which six to 10 could became hurricanes.<br><br>As climate change threatens to bring more extreme events like increased floods, sea level rise, and intensifying droughts and wildfires, it is our responsibility to better prepare and support communities, families, and businesses before disaster – not just after. This includes investing in climate research to improve our understanding of these extreme weather events and our decision making on climate resilience, adaptation, and mitigation. It also means ensuring that communities have the resources they need to build resilience prior to these crises.<br><br>President Biden has elevated the importance of climate resilience on the global stage and prioritized resilience in his investment agenda, including in the American Jobs Plan and the FY22 discretionary request.<br><br><strong>NEW STEPS TO ENHANCE CLIMATE RESILIENCE</strong><br><br>Today, President Biden continued to act through a whole-of-government approach in support of climate resilience goals. The Administration is directing $1 billion in pre-disaster mitigation resources to communities, and it is announcing next generation climate data systems that will help us understand and track how climate change impacts communities.</p>



<p>Today, the Administration is announcing it will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Provide $1 billion for communities through FEMA’s Pre-Disaster Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities program. </strong>FEMA will provide $1 billion in 2021 for the Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) program, a portion of which will be targeted to disadvantaged communities. BRIC supports states, local communities, tribes, and territories in undertaking pre-disaster hazard mitigation projects, reducing the risks they face from disasters and natural hazards. This level of funding level is double the amount provided last year. The program seeks to categorically shift the federal focus from reactive disaster spending and toward research-supported, proactive investment in community resilience so that when the next hurricane, flood, or wildfire comes, communities are better prepared.<br> </li><li><strong>Develop and launch a </strong><a href="https://www.nasa.gov/press-release/new-nasa-earth-systems-observatory-to-help-address-mitigate-climate-change" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>new NASA mission concept for an Earth System Observatory.</strong> </a>As the number of extreme weather events increases due to climate change, the ability to forecast and monitor natural disasters is integral for the nation’s preparation, mitigation, and resilience. NASA’s Earth System Observatory will be a new architecture of advanced spaceborne Earth observation systems, providing the world with an unprecedented understanding of the critical interactions between Earth’s atmosphere, land, ocean, and ice processes. These processes determine how the changing climate will play out at regional and local levels, on near and long-term time scales.</li></ul>



<p><strong>CONTINUE A WHOLE-OF-GOVERNMENT APPROACH TO CLIMATE RESILIENCE</strong><br><br>Today’s action builds on the whole-of-government approach President Biden is taking to climate resilience. Resilience is a key focus area of the National Climate Task Force as they drive a number of actions to strengthen the resilience of our infrastructure, forests, coastal areas, oceans, range lands, and farm lands to drought, wildfire, heatwaves, and other climate impacts.<br><br>Examples of actions to date across the federal government include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Issuing an Executive Order on Climate-Related Financial Risk</strong>. Last week, President Biden issued an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/20/executive-order-on-climate-related-financial-risk/">Executive Order on Climate-Related Financial Risk</a>&nbsp;that will help the American people better understand how climate change can impact their financial security. It will strengthen the U.S. financial system and it will inform concrete decisions that the federal government can take to mitigate the risks of climate change. With so much at stake, this Executive Order ensures that the right rules are in place to properly analyze and mitigate these risks. That includes disclosing these risks to the public, and empowering the American people to make informed financial decisions.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Developing agency climate adaptation and resilience plans</strong>. The Administration has taken significant steps to revitalize Federal climate adaptation and resilience by initiating the development of Agency Climate Action Plans as required by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/">Executive Order 14008</a>. The Plans, which are being developed by 36 agencies, broadened the scope of relevant climate adaptation and resilience experts to include acquisitions and finance professionals and focus on integrating climate information in the management of procurement, real property, public lands and water, and financial programs for climate informed decisions.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Setting a responsible flood risk standard for the federal government.</strong>&nbsp;Through his Executive Order on Climate-Related Financial Risk, President Biden reinstated the Federal Flood Risk Management Standard to improve the resilience of American communities and federal assets against the impacts of flood damage, which is predicted to increase over time due to the effects of climate change. The Standard requires federal agencies to consider current and future flood risk when taxpayer dollars are used to build or rebuild in floodplains. Implementing guidelines offer a toolkit of flexible and practical options to implement these protections.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Investing in resilience through the American Jobs Plan and the FY22 budget.</strong>&nbsp;Resilience and adaptation are critical priorities for President Biden and his administration. Americans around the country have been feeling the effect of climate change and underinvestment in resilience. Investments to make our infrastructure more resilient are a key piece of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/31/fact-sheet-the-american-jobs-plan/">American Jobs Plan</a>&nbsp;and the President’s FY 2022 Discretionary Request. In addition to supporting the goal that every dollar spent on rebuilding our infrastructure during the Biden administration will be used to prevent, reduce and withstand the impacts of the climate crisis – the American Jobs Plan calls for $50 billion in dedicated resilience investments. The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/FY2022-Discretionary-Request.pdf">President’s FY22 Discretionary Request</a>&nbsp;also includes significant budget increases to enable incorporation of climate impacts into disaster planning and projects to ensure that the Nation is rebuilding smarter and safer for the future.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Integrating resilience into the White House Environmental Justice Advisory Council</strong>. The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/environmentaljustice/white-house-environmental-justice-advisory-council">White House Environmental Justice Advisory Council</a>&nbsp;(WHEJAC) was established by President Biden’s Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad to fulfill his and Vice President Harris’s commitment to confronting longstanding environmental injustices and ensure that historically marginalized and polluted, overburdened communities have greater input on federal policies and decisions. The WHEJAC members are to provide advice and recommendations to the Environmental Justice Interagency Council and the Chair of CEQ on a whole-of-government approach to environmental justice, including, but not limited to, climate change mitigation, resilience, and disaster management.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Establishing an Interagency Working Group to better prepare and respond to drought.&nbsp;</strong>The National Climate Task Force, as part of its whole-of-government consideration of climate issues,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/21/readout-of-the-third-national-climate-task-force-meeting/">established an Interagency Working Group to address worsening drought conditions</a>&nbsp;in the West and to support farmers, ranchers, Tribes, and communities impacted by ongoing water shortages. The Working Group is co-chaired by the Departments of the Interior and Agriculture and will build upon existing resources to help coordinate across the federal government, working in partnership with state, local, and Tribal governments to address the needs of communities suffering from drought-related impacts. DOI and USDA have already announced more than $25 million to assist farmers, ranchers and communities in the Klamath Basin to help them in the face of a severe drought.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Increasing investments in forest restoration to reduce the threat of catastrophic wildfire.&nbsp;</strong>Climate change is increasing the severity and frequency of wildfire seasons, which are transforming our Nation’s forests at an unprecedented rate, and destroying homes and businesses. The Biden-Harris Administration’s discretionary budget request provides nearly $1.7 billion for high-priority hazardous fuels and forest resilience projects at a scope and scale to meet the challenge we face, an increase of $476 million over the 2021 enacted level. This funding supports the Administration’s science-based approach to vegetation management at the Forest Service and DOI to protect watersheds, wildlife habitat, and the wildland-urban interface.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Launching a resilience focused task force at the Department of the Interior</strong>. Department of the Interior (DOI) Secretary Deb Haaland announced a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/news/secretary-haaland-establishes-climate-task-force-strengthens-scientific-integrity">new Climate Task Force</a>&nbsp;at DOI that will develop a strategy to reduce climate pollution; improve and increase adaptation and resilience to the impacts of climate change; address current and historic environmental injustice; protect public health; and conserve DOI managed lands. Its mission will include supporting the development and use of the best available science to evaluate the greenhouse gas emissions and associated climate change impacts of Federal land uses as well as opportunities to increase carbon sequestration; to predict the effects of climate change on public lands and land uses; and to assess and adopt measures to increase the resilience and adaptive capacity of public lands.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Launching a new approach to climate change adaptation and resilience at the Department of Homeland Security.</strong>&nbsp;Homeland Security Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas announced the launch of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2021/04/22/secretary-mayorkas-announces-new-dhs-commitments-address-climate-crisis-leaders">DHS Climate Change Action Group</a>, a coordinating body comprised of the Department’s senior leadership that will drive urgent action to address the climate crisis and will report directly to the Secretary. DHS also recently published a public Request for Information on how FEMA can ensure its programs advance equity and increase resilience for all – especially among those who are disproportionately at risk from the impacts of climate change.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Utilizing a Climate Assessment Tool to Analyze Climate Vulnerabilities at the Department of Defense</strong>. Climate change has been identified by the Department of Defense (DoD) as a critical national security threat and threat multiplier. As a result, DoD has undertaken assessments of the impacts that the climate crisis has on American military instillations. The DoD&nbsp;<a href="https://www.defense.gov/Newsroom/Releases/Release/Article/2581027/dod-announces-installation-climate-exposure-assessments-plan-through-the-defens/#:~:text=In%20conjunction%20with%20President%20Biden's,the%20Defense%20Climate%20Assessment%20Tool.">announced a plan</a>&nbsp;to complete climate exposure assessments on all major U.S. installations within 12 months and all major installations outside the continental U.S. within 24 months using the Defense Climate Assessment Tool (DCAT). The DCAT helps identify the climate hazards to which DoD installations are most exposed, which is the first step in addressing the potential physical harm, security impacts, and degradation in readiness resulting from global climate change.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Tracking the indicators of climate change at the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.&nbsp;</strong>For the first time in four years, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) has updated and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-relaunches-climate-indicators-website-showing-how-climate-change-impacting-peoples">relaunched its Climate Change Indicators</a>. This comprehensive resource presents compelling and clear evidence of changes to our climate reflected in rising temperatures, increased ocean acidity, sea level rise, and changing river flooding, droughts, heat waves, and wildfires, among other indicators. The long-overdue update to this crucial scientific resource shows that climate change has become even more evident, stronger, and extreme, and underscores the urgency for action on the climate crisis.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Releasing new U.S. Climate Normals at the NOAA</strong>. NOAA recently released the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news/new-us-climate-normals-are-here-what-do-they-tell-us-about-climate-change">U.S. Climate Normals</a>, a large suite of data products that provide information about typical climate conditions for thousands of locations across the United States. Normals act both as a ruler to compare today’s weather and tomorrow’s forecast, and as a predictor of conditions in the near future. These data products assist agencies and State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, communities, and businesses in preparing for and adapting to the impacts of climate change.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Investing in grid and community resilience at the Department of Energy</strong>. The Department of Energy is investing in grid resilience and energy resilience, including microgrid strategies, through research under the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/gmi/grid-modernization-initiative">Grid Modernization Initiative</a>. In partnership with the National Laboratories, the Department is developing a set of comprehensive energy resilience metrics and modeling capabilities to mitigate climate impacts to our energy infrastructure. The Department is also investing in projects that improve community resilience by deploying energy storage and microgrid technologies. In addition, for communities across the West, the Department is working with the Western Area Power Administration and Bonneville Power Administration to aggressively forecast, model and mitigate the potential impacts of severe climate-change-related droughts and fires on electricity systems.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Building climate and resilience considerations into transportation discretionary grants at the U.S. Department of Transportation.&nbsp;</strong>The U.S. Department of Transportation is incorporating climate and resilience criteria into over $2 billion in discretionary grant programs, including the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/RAISEgrants">RAISE</a>, INFRA, and Port Infrastructure Development grant programs. This will promote transportation investments that are future-proofed against extreme weather events. In addition, the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) has also issued new guidance for planning and design for highways in coastal areas.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Russian Security Council Secretary Nikolay Patrushev</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/joint-statement-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-russian-security-council-secretary-nikolay-patrushev/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 14:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and the Secretary of the Russian Security Council Nikolay Patrushev held consultations on United States-Russia relations as part of regular Security Council contacts. The meeting was a logical continuation of the recent discussions held in Reykjavik between Secretary of State Blinken and Foreign Minister Lavrov. The meeting was an important step&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and the Secretary of the Russian Security Council Nikolay Patrushev held consultations on United States-Russia relations as part of regular Security Council contacts. The meeting was a logical continuation of the recent discussions held in Reykjavik between Secretary of State Blinken and Foreign Minister Lavrov.</p>



<p>The meeting was an important step in the preparation for a planned U.S.-Russia summit, the date and location of which will be announced later.</p>



<p>The discussions were held in a constructive manner and, despite outstanding differences, allowed for a better understanding of each other’s positions.</p>



<p>A wide range of issues of mutual interest were discussed with a high priority given to the topic of strategic stability. The sides expressed confidence that mutually acceptable solutions could be found in a number of areas.</p>



<p>The sides agreed that a normalization of U.S.-Russian relations would be in the interest of both countries and contribute to global predictability and stability.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
