<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 23:39:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in Press Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/14/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 23:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATO HeadquartersBrussels, Belgium 9:28 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Before I turn to today’s meetings, I want to say a short word about our ongoing fight against COVID-19 at home. We&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the United States.  Much of the country is returning to normal, and our economic growth is leading the world,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>9:28 P.M. CEST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Before I turn to today’s meetings, I want to say a short word about our ongoing fight against COVID-19 at home.<br><br>We&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the United States.  Much of the country is returning to normal, and our economic growth is leading the world, and the number of cases and deaths are dropping dramatically.  But there&#8217;s still too many lives being lost.<br><br>We’re still averaging, in the last seven days, loss of 370 deaths per day &#8212; 370 deaths.  That’s significantly lower than at the peak of this crisis, but it’s still a real tragedy.  We’re approaching a sad milestone: almost 600,000 lost lives because of COVID-19 in America. <br><br>My heart goes out to all those who have lost a loved one.  I know that black hole that seems to consume you, that fills up your chest when you lose someone that&#8217;s close to you that you adored.<br><br>That’s why I continue to say to America: If you’ve not been vaccinated, get vaccinated.  Get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We have plenty of vaccination, plenty of sites.  We have more work to do to beat this virus, and now is not the time to let our guard down.  So, please &#8212; please get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We’ve had enough pain.  Enough pain.<br><br>Folks, I know it&#8217;s after 9:30, Brussels time &#8212; 9:30 p.m., and I&#8217;m still at NATO.  You&#8217;re all excited about that.  I know.  (Laughter.) <br><br>But I&#8217;ve had a chance to meet with several leaders recently, and I’ve had calls with others.  It&#8217;s been an incredibly productive day here. <br><br>I just finished a meeting with President Erdoğan of Turkey.  We had a positive and productive meeting, much of it one-on-one.  We had detailed discussions on how to proceed on a number of &#8212; a number of issues.  Our two countries have big agendas.  Our teams are going to continue our discussions, and I’m confident we&#8217;ll make real progress with Turkey and the United States.<br><br>But now I want to thank Secretary General Stoltenberg for leading a very successful NATO Summit today.<br><br>I had the honor of leading off the discussion today among the 30 nations, and I pointed out that we’re facing a once-in-a-century global health crisis.  At the same time, the democratic values that undergird our Alliance are under increasing pressure both internally and externally.  Russia and China are both seeking to drive a wedge in our transatlantic solidarity.  We’re seeing an increase in malicious cyber activity.<br><br>But that our Alliance is the strong foundation on which we can &#8212; our collective security and our shared prosperity can continue to be built. <br><br>And I made a point to make clear that the U.S. commitment to Article 5 of the NATO Treaty is rock solid and unshakable.  It’s a sacred commitment.<br><br>NATO &#8212; NATO stands together.  That’s how we’ve met every other threat in the past.  It’s our greatest strength as we meet our challenges of the future &#8212; and there are many. <br><br>And everyone &#8212; everyone in that room today understood the shared appreciation, quite frankly, that America is back.<br><br>We talked about Russia’s aggressive acts that pose a threat to NATO and to our collective security.<br><br>That’s why I met with the Bucharest 9 &#8212; the eastern flank allies &#8212; in advance of this summit.  And today I also met with the leaders of the three Baltic states: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.<br><br>I shared with our Allies that I will convey to Pre- &#8212; what I&#8217;ll convey to President Putin: that I’m not looking for conflict with Russia, but that we will respond if Russia continues its harmful activities and that we will not fail to defend the Transatlantic Alliance or stand up for democratic values.<br><br>As Allies, we also affirmed our continued support<br>for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.<br><br>We agreed to keep consulting closely on nuclear deterrence, arms control, and strategic stability.<br><br>And there was a strong consensus among the leaders in that meeting on Afghanistan.  Our troops are coming home, but we agreed that our diplomatic, economic, and humanitarian commitment to the Afghan people and our support for<br>the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces will endure.<br><br>And I welcomed our Allies and partners to recognize that counterterrorism &#8212; that counterterrorism efforts must continue to ensure that Afghanistan never again becomes a ca- &#8212; a safe haven for attacks on our countries, even as we take on terrorist networks in the Middle East and Africa.<br><br>And I’m deeply gratified that, as an Alliance, we adopted a far-reaching plan to make sure that NATO can meet the challenges<br>that we face today and in the future, not yesterday &#8212; the NATO 2030 agenda &#8212; and that we agreed to fully resource that agenda.<br><br>The last time NATO put together a strategic plan was back in 2010, when Russia was considered a partner and China wasn’t even mentioned.<br><br>We talked about the long-term systemic challenges that China’s activities pose to our collective security today.<br><br>We agreed to do more to enhance the resilience of our critical infrastructure around the world, including trusted telecommunications providers, supply chains, and energy networks.<br><br>We agreed to enhance our cooperation with our democratic partners in the Indo-Pacific to meet challenges that exist there.<br><br>We also endorsed a new cyber defense policy &#8212; NATO&#8217;s first in the past seven years &#8212; to improve the collective ability to defend against counter threats from state and nonstate actors against our networks and our critical infrastructure. <br><br>And we adopted a Climate Security Action Plan &#8212; which, several years ago, people thought we would never would do &#8212; for reducing emissions from NATO installations and adapting to the security risk of climate change while keeping a sharp &#8212; very sharp on our ability to deter and defend against threats.<br><br>And finally, we agreed that among the most important shared missions is renewing and strengthening the resilience of our democracies by pointing out we have to prove to the world and to our own people that democracy can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs of our people.<br><br>We have to root out corruption that siphons off our strength; guard against those who would stoke hatred and division for political gain &#8212; this phony populism; invest in strengthening the institutions that underpin and safeguard our cherished democratic values, as well as protecting the free press and independent judiciaries.  All of those run the agenda. <br><br>That&#8217;s how I’ll prove that democracy and that our Alliance can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs and the needs of our people.<br><br>This is going to be looked at 25 years from now as whether or not we stepped up to the challenge, because there&#8217;s a lot of &#8212; a lot of autocracies that are counting on them being able to move more rapidly and successfully in an ever-complicated world than democracies can.  We all concluded we&#8217;re going to prove them wrong. <br><br>And now I&#8217;m happy to take some questions. <br><br>Cecilia Vega of ABC.<br><br>Q    Thank you so much, sir.  Good evening.  You mentioned your sit-down with Vladimir Putin and Russian aggression that came up in your conversations today.  I&#8217;d like to ask you two questions, if I may, on that front.  Is it your sense, walking into this meeting, that Americans back home shouldn&#8217;t expect much in terms of an outcome?  Could you provide some specifics on what a successful meeting would look like to you?  Are there going to be specific concessions you want Putin to make?<br><br>And then, I&#8217;ll just give you my follow-up right now.  You&#8217;ve met Vladimir Putin before.  What have you learned about him that informs how you approach this sit-down with him?  And what&#8217;s your mindset walking into a meeting with a former KGB agent who you&#8217;ve said has no soul?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ll tell you all that when it&#8217;s over. <br><br>Look, I&#8217;ve been doing this a long time.  The last thing anyone would do is negotiate in front of the world press as to how he&#8217;s going to approach a critical meeting with another adversary and/or someone who could be an adversary.  It’s the last thing I&#8217;m going to do.<br><br>But I will tell you this: I’m going to make clear to President Putin that there are areas where we can cooperate, if he chooses.  And if he chooses not to cooperate and acts in a way that he has in the past, relative to cybersecurity and some other activities, then we will respond.  We will respond in kind. <br><br>There need not be &#8212; we should decide where it&#8217;s in our mutual interest, in the interest of the world, to cooperate, and see if we can do that.  And the areas where we don&#8217;t agree, make it clear what the red lines are.<br><br>I have met with him.  He&#8217;s bright.  He&#8217;s tough.  And I have found that he is a &#8212; as they say, when you used to play ball, “a worthy adversary.” <br><br>But the fact is that I will be happy to talk with you when it&#8217;s over, and not before, about what the discussion will entail.<br><br>Nancy Cordes, CBS.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  I also have two questions about Vladimir Putin.  The first is: Have any of the world leaders you&#8217;ve met with this week expressed concern that by meeting with President Putin this early in your presidency, that it&#8217;ll look like you&#8217;re rewarding him?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What&#8217;s your second question?<br><br>Q    The section &#8212; the second question is: What it will mean for the U.S.-Russia relationship if Aleksey Navalny were to die or be killed in prison.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Every world leader here, as a member of NATO, that spoke today &#8212; and most of them mentioned it &#8212; thanked me for meeting with Putin now.  Every single one that spoke.  And I think there were probably about 10 or 12 that spoke to it, saying they were happy that I did that and that I was going to do that.  And they thought it was thoroughly appropriate that I do, and I had discussions with them about &#8212; in the open &#8212; about what they thought was important from their perspective and what they thought was not important.<br><br>And so the interesting thing is, I know &#8212; and I’m not being critical of the press &#8212; I really mean this; I give you my word &#8212; but, generically, you all thought, “Was Biden meeting him too soon?”  I haven’t found a world leader who doesn’t think it’s not soon &#8212; it’s just soon enough.  Everyone that I’ve spoken to, privately and publicly. <br><br>It doesn’t mean there aren&#8217;t some out there, but it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not likely that a head of state is going to stand up in front of 29 other heads of state and say, “Boy, I&#8217;m glad you&#8217;re doing this,” in effect.  So there is a consensus.  And they thanked me for being willing to talk with them about the meeting and what I was &#8212; what I intended to do.<br><br>So, I haven&#8217;t found any reluctance.  There may be someone, but not in the open today or in the meetings I privately had as well.<br><br>And Navalny’s death would be another indication that Russia has little or no intention of abiding by basic fundamental human rights.  It would be a tragedy.  It would do nothing but hurt his relationships with the rest of the world, in my view, and with me. <br><br>Jeff Zeleny, CNN.<br><br>Q    Sir, good evening.  Thank you.  In a weekend interview, Vladimir Putin laughed at the suggestion that you had called him a &#8220;killer.”  Is that still your belief, sir, that he is a killer? <br><br>And I&#8217;ll continue the trend, if you don&#8217;t mind, of asking a second question.  Do you believe &#8212; if he does agree to cooperate, then what kind of a challenge do you find yourself in?  How would you ever trust him?  And if Ronald Reagan said “trust but verify,” what do you say to Vladimir Putin? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (Laughs.)  To answer the first question &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I’m laughing too.<br><br>They actually &#8212; I &#8212;<br><br>Q    So he is a killer?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, look, I mean, he has made clear that &#8212; the answer is: I believe he has, in the past, essentially acknowledged that he was &#8212; there were certain things that he would do or did do. <br><br>But look, when I was asked that question on air, I answered it honestly.  But it&#8217;s not much of a &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it matters a whole lot, in terms of this next meeting we&#8217;re about to have. <br><br>The second question was rela- &#8212;<br><br>Q    (Inaudible.)  How would you ever trust him?  And what is your version of &#8220;trust but verify&#8221;?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;d verify first and then trust.  In other words: Everything would have to be shown to be actually occurring.  It&#8217;s not about, you know, trusting; it&#8217;s about agreeing. <br><br>You know, when we &#8212; when you write treaties with your adversaries, you don&#8217;t say, “I trust you.”  You say, “This is what I expect, and if you violate the agreement you made then, we &#8212; the, quote, &#8216;The treaty is off.  The agreement is off.'&#8221; <br><br>And I&#8217;m hoping that &#8212; that President Putin concludes that there is some interest, in terms of his own interests, in changing the perception that the world has of him, in terms of whether or not he will engage in behavior that&#8217;s more consistent with what is considered to be appropriate behavior for a head of state.<br><br>Anne Gearan, Washington Post. <br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  Here at this meeting and earlier at the G7, you&#8217;ve said several times that America is back at Allies’ side, but a lot of those Allies are themselves pretty rattled by what happened on January 6th &#8212; an attempted overturning of your election &#8212; and they may still be alarmed by the continued hold that Donald Trump has over the Republican Party and the rise of nationalist figures like him around the world. <br><br>What do you say to those Allies, what have you been saying to them at these meetings about how the next President of the United States can keep any promises you make? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What I&#8217;m saying is them &#8212; to them is: Watch me.  I mean, I&#8217;m not saying anything, quite frankly.  I&#8217;m just going out &#8212; people, as I&#8217;ve said before, don&#8217;t doubt that I mean what I say, and they believe that I keep my commitments when I say it. <br><br>I&#8217;m not making any promises to anyone that I don&#8217;t believe are overwhelmingly likely to be kept.  I think that we&#8217;re at a moment where &#8212; I mean, let me put it this way: You may have had a different view, but I think an awful lot of people thought that my showing up at the G7 would not produce any kind of enthusiasm about American leadership and about where America was.  I would suggest that it didn&#8217;t turn out that way. <br><br>I would suggest that there is a &#8212; the leaders I&#8217;m dealing with in NATO and the G7 are leaders who know our recent history; know, generically, the character of the American people; and know where the vast center of the public stands &#8212; not Democrat, Republican &#8212; but who we are.  We&#8217;re a decent, honorable nation. <br><br>And I think that they have seen things happen, as we have, that shocked them and surprised them that could have happened.  But I think they, like I do, believe the American people are not going to sustain that kind of behavior. <br><br>And so, I &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t want to get into the &#8212; the statistics because you know that old phrase of Disraeli&#8217;s: “There&#8217;s three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.”<br><br>But I think it&#8217;s appropriate to say that the Republican Party is vastly diminished in numbers; the leadership of the Republican Party is fractured; and the Trump wing of the party is the bulk of the party, but it makes up a significant minority of the American people. <br><br>Now, we&#8217;ll see.  We’ll see.  I believe that by us standing up and saying what we believe to be the case, not engaging in the &#8212; the overwhelming hyperbole that gets engaged in by so many today, that we &#8212; I guess that old expression, “The proof of the pudding is in the eating.” <br><br>When we said &#8212; when I said I was going to deal with beating the virus and I was going to focus on that and I was going to get millions of shots in people&#8217;s arms, it wasn&#8217;t me &#8212; I just knew the American people.  I knew the kind of help I&#8217;d get from the Defense Department, from police departments, from &#8212; from the hospitals, from &#8212; from retired docs, from &#8212; I just knew.  And look how rapidly we moved. <br><br>Now, we have a group of people who were &#8212; everything from the political rejection of the notion of taking a vaccine, to people who were simply afraid of a needle and everything in between.  And we have a way to go. <br><br>But I never doubted that we would be able to generate the kind of support we got and get so many millions of people step up and get vaccinated.  So, I &#8212; I think it is a shock and surprise that what&#8217;s happened, in terms of the consequence of President Trump&#8217;s phony populism, has &#8212; has happened.  And it is disappointing that so many of my Republican colleagues in the Senate, who I know know better, have been reluctant to take on, for example, an investigation because they&#8217;re worried about being primaried. <br><br>But, at the end of the day, we&#8217;ve been through periods like this in American history before where there has been this reluctance to take a chance on your reelection because of the nature of your party&#8217;s politics at the moment. <br><br>I think this is passing.  I don&#8217;t mean easily passing.  That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that I succeed in my agenda &#8212; the agenda, whether it&#8217;s dealing with the vaccine, the economy, infrastructure.  It&#8217;s important that we demonstrate we can make progress and continue to make progress.  And I think we&#8217;re going to be able to do that.<br><br>So, as I said, the proof will be in where it is, you know, six months from now &#8212; where &#8212; where we are.  But I think you&#8217;re going to see that there&#8217;s &#8212; that, God willing, we&#8217;re going to be making progress, and there&#8217;s going to be a coalescing of a lot of Republicans, particularly younger Republicans who are coming up in the party. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And last question, Sebastian Smith of AFP.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  Ukraine wants a clear “yes” or “no” on getting into the NATO Membership Action Plan.  So, what&#8217;s your answer? <br><br>And, if I may, a second part to the same question: Well, now that Russia has invaded parts of Ukraine, does that effectively rule out Ukraine ever entering NATO, given that being in NATO would mean the U.S. and NATO having to defend Ukrainians against Russia? <br><br>Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The second question is &#8212; the answer is no. <br><br>The first question: It depends on whether they meet the criteria.  The fact is they still have to clean up corruption.  The fact is they have to meet other criteria to get into the Action Plan. <br><br>And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, school is out on that question.  It remains to be seen.  In the meantime, we will do all that we can to pu- &#8212; put Ukraine in the position to be able to continue to resist Russian physical aggression.  And it will not just depend on me whether or not we conclude that &#8212; that Ukraine can become part of NATO; it will depend on the Alliance and how they vote.<br><br>But I know, for one thing, there has to be a co- &#8212; they have to convince, and it&#8217;s not easy.  I made a speech, years ago, to the Rada saying that &#8212; that Ukraine had an opportunity to do something that&#8217;s never occurred in the history of Ukraine: actually generate a democratically elected and not corrupt &#8212; led by oligarchies in any of the regions &#8212; nation.  And I pointed out to them when I made that speech that they will go down in history as the founding fathers of Ukraine if, in fact, they do that.<br><br>They have more to do.  But that does not justify &#8212; the fact they have more to do &#8212; Russia taking aggressive action, either in the Donbas or in &#8212; on the sea, or in any part of Ukraine.  And we&#8217;re going to put Ukraine in a position to be able to maintain their physical security.<br><br>Thank you all so very much.  Sorry you&#8217;re all here so late.  Thank you very much.<br><br>9:54 P.M. CEST<br><br>NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium<br><br><br>9:28 P.M. CEST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Before I turn to today’s meetings, I want to say a short word about our ongoing fight against COVID-19 at home.<br><br>We&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the United States.  Much of the country is returning to normal, and our economic growth is leading the world, and the number of cases and deaths are dropping dramatically.  But there&#8217;s still too many lives being lost.<br><br>We’re still averaging, in the last seven days, loss of 370 deaths per day &#8212; 370 deaths.  That’s significantly lower than at the peak of this crisis, but it’s still a real tragedy.  We’re approaching a sad milestone: almost 600,000 lost lives because of COVID-19 in America. <br><br>My heart goes out to all those who have lost a loved one.  I know that black hole that seems to consume you, that fills up your chest when you lose someone that&#8217;s close to you that you adored.<br><br>That’s why I continue to say to America: If you’ve not been vaccinated, get vaccinated.  Get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We have plenty of vaccination, plenty of sites.  We have more work to do to beat this virus, and now is not the time to let our guard down.  So, please &#8212; please get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We’ve had enough pain.  Enough pain.<br><br>Folks, I know it&#8217;s after 9:30, Brussels time &#8212; 9:30 p.m., and I&#8217;m still at NATO.  You&#8217;re all excited about that.  I know.  (Laughter.) <br><br>But I&#8217;ve had a chance to meet with several leaders recently, and I’ve had calls with others.  It&#8217;s been an incredibly productive day here. <br><br>I just finished a meeting with President Erdoğan of Turkey.  We had a positive and productive meeting, much of it one-on-one.  We had detailed discussions on how to proceed on a number of &#8212; a number of issues.  Our two countries have big agendas.  Our teams are going to continue our discussions, and I’m confident we&#8217;ll make real progress with Turkey and the United States.<br><br>But now I want to thank Secretary General Stoltenberg for leading a very successful NATO Summit today.<br><br>I had the honor of leading off the discussion today among the 30 nations, and I pointed out that we’re facing a once-in-a-century global health crisis.  At the same time, the democratic values that undergird our Alliance are under increasing pressure both internally and externally.  Russia and China are both seeking to drive a wedge in our transatlantic solidarity.  We’re seeing an increase in malicious cyber activity.<br><br>But that our Alliance is the strong foundation on which we can &#8212; our collective security and our shared prosperity can continue to be built. <br><br>And I made a point to make clear that the U.S. commitment to Article 5 of the NATO Treaty is rock solid and unshakable.  It’s a sacred commitment.<br><br>NATO &#8212; NATO stands together.  That’s how we’ve met every other threat in the past.  It’s our greatest strength as we meet our challenges of the future &#8212; and there are many. <br><br>And everyone &#8212; everyone in that room today understood the shared appreciation, quite frankly, that America is back.<br><br>We talked about Russia’s aggressive acts that pose a threat to NATO and to our collective security.<br><br>That’s why I met with the Bucharest 9 &#8212; the eastern flank allies &#8212; in advance of this summit.  And today I also met with the leaders of the three Baltic states: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.<br><br>I shared with our Allies that I will convey to Pre- &#8212; what I&#8217;ll convey to President Putin: that I’m not looking for conflict with Russia, but that we will respond if Russia continues its harmful activities and that we will not fail to defend the Transatlantic Alliance or stand up for democratic values.<br><br>As Allies, we also affirmed our continued support<br>for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.<br><br>We agreed to keep consulting closely on nuclear deterrence, arms control, and strategic stability.<br><br>And there was a strong consensus among the leaders in that meeting on Afghanistan.  Our troops are coming home, but we agreed that our diplomatic, economic, and humanitarian commitment to the Afghan people and our support for<br>the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces will endure.<br><br>And I welcomed our Allies and partners to recognize that counterterrorism &#8212; that counterterrorism efforts must continue to ensure that Afghanistan never again becomes a ca- &#8212; a safe haven for attacks on our countries, even as we take on terrorist networks in the Middle East and Africa.<br><br>And I’m deeply gratified that, as an Alliance, we adopted a far-reaching plan to make sure that NATO can meet the challenges<br>that we face today and in the future, not yesterday &#8212; the NATO 2030 agenda &#8212; and that we agreed to fully resource that agenda.<br><br>The last time NATO put together a strategic plan was back in 2010, when Russia was considered a partner and China wasn’t even mentioned.<br><br>We talked about the long-term systemic challenges that China’s activities pose to our collective security today.<br><br>We agreed to do more to enhance the resilience of our critical infrastructure around the world, including trusted telecommunications providers, supply chains, and energy networks.<br><br>We agreed to enhance our cooperation with our democratic partners in the Indo-Pacific to meet challenges that exist there.<br><br>We also endorsed a new cyber defense policy &#8212; NATO&#8217;s first in the past seven years &#8212; to improve the collective ability to defend against counter threats from state and nonstate actors against our networks and our critical infrastructure. <br><br>And we adopted a Climate Security Action Plan &#8212; which, several years ago, people thought we would never would do &#8212; for reducing emissions from NATO installations and adapting to the security risk of climate change while keeping a sharp &#8212; very sharp on our ability to deter and defend against threats.<br><br>And finally, we agreed that among the most important shared missions is renewing and strengthening the resilience of our democracies by pointing out we have to prove to the world and to our own people that democracy can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs of our people.<br><br>We have to root out corruption that siphons off our strength; guard against those who would stoke hatred and division for political gain &#8212; this phony populism; invest in strengthening the institutions that underpin and safeguard our cherished democratic values, as well as protecting the free press and independent judiciaries.  All of those run the agenda. <br><br>That&#8217;s how I’ll prove that democracy and that our Alliance can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs and the needs of our people.<br><br>This is going to be looked at 25 years from now as whether or not we stepped up to the challenge, because there&#8217;s a lot of &#8212; a lot of autocracies that are counting on them being able to move more rapidly and successfully in an ever-complicated world than democracies can.  We all concluded we&#8217;re going to prove them wrong. <br><br>And now I&#8217;m happy to take some questions. <br><br>Cecilia Vega of ABC.<br><br>Q    Thank you so much, sir.  Good evening.  You mentioned your sit-down with Vladimir Putin and Russian aggression that came up in your conversations today.  I&#8217;d like to ask you two questions, if I may, on that front.  Is it your sense, walking into this meeting, that Americans back home shouldn&#8217;t expect much in terms of an outcome?  Could you provide some specifics on what a successful meeting would look like to you?  Are there going to be specific concessions you want Putin to make?<br><br>And then, I&#8217;ll just give you my follow-up right now.  You&#8217;ve met Vladimir Putin before.  What have you learned about him that informs how you approach this sit-down with him?  And what&#8217;s your mindset walking into a meeting with a former KGB agent who you&#8217;ve said has no soul?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ll tell you all that when it&#8217;s over. <br><br>Look, I&#8217;ve been doing this a long time.  The last thing anyone would do is negotiate in front of the world press as to how he&#8217;s going to approach a critical meeting with another adversary and/or someone who could be an adversary.  It’s the last thing I&#8217;m going to do.<br><br>But I will tell you this: I’m going to make clear to President Putin that there are areas where we can cooperate, if he chooses.  And if he chooses not to cooperate and acts in a way that he has in the past, relative to cybersecurity and some other activities, then we will respond.  We will respond in kind. <br><br>There need not be &#8212; we should decide where it&#8217;s in our mutual interest, in the interest of the world, to cooperate, and see if we can do that.  And the areas where we don&#8217;t agree, make it clear what the red lines are.<br><br>I have met with him.  He&#8217;s bright.  He&#8217;s tough.  And I have found that he is a &#8212; as they say, when you used to play ball, “a worthy adversary.” <br><br>But the fact is that I will be happy to talk with you when it&#8217;s over, and not before, about what the discussion will entail.<br><br>Nancy Cordes, CBS.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  I also have two questions about Vladimir Putin.  The first is: Have any of the world leaders you&#8217;ve met with this week expressed concern that by meeting with President Putin this early in your presidency, that it&#8217;ll look like you&#8217;re rewarding him?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What&#8217;s your second question?<br><br>Q    The section &#8212; the second question is: What it will mean for the U.S.-Russia relationship if Aleksey Navalny were to die or be killed in prison.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Every world leader here, as a member of NATO, that spoke today &#8212; and most of them mentioned it &#8212; thanked me for meeting with Putin now.  Every single one that spoke.  And I think there were probably about 10 or 12 that spoke to it, saying they were happy that I did that and that I was going to do that.  And they thought it was thoroughly appropriate that I do, and I had discussions with them about &#8212; in the open &#8212; about what they thought was important from their perspective and what they thought was not important.<br><br>And so the interesting thing is, I know &#8212; and I’m not being critical of the press &#8212; I really mean this; I give you my word &#8212; but, generically, you all thought, “Was Biden meeting him too soon?”  I haven’t found a world leader who doesn’t think it’s not soon &#8212; it’s just soon enough.  Everyone that I’ve spoken to, privately and publicly. <br><br>It doesn’t mean there aren&#8217;t some out there, but it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not likely that a head of state is going to stand up in front of 29 other heads of state and say, “Boy, I&#8217;m glad you&#8217;re doing this,” in effect.  So there is a consensus.  And they thanked me for being willing to talk with them about the meeting and what I was &#8212; what I intended to do.<br><br>So, I haven&#8217;t found any reluctance.  There may be someone, but not in the open today or in the meetings I privately had as well.<br><br>And Navalny’s death would be another indication that Russia has little or no intention of abiding by basic fundamental human rights.  It would be a tragedy.  It would do nothing but hurt his relationships with the rest of the world, in my view, and with me. <br><br>Jeff Zeleny, CNN.<br><br>Q    Sir, good evening.  Thank you.  In a weekend interview, Vladimir Putin laughed at the suggestion that you had called him a &#8220;killer.”  Is that still your belief, sir, that he is a killer? <br><br>And I&#8217;ll continue the trend, if you don&#8217;t mind, of asking a second question.  Do you believe &#8212; if he does agree to cooperate, then what kind of a challenge do you find yourself in?  How would you ever trust him?  And if Ronald Reagan said “trust but verify,” what do you say to Vladimir Putin? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (Laughs.)  To answer the first question &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I’m laughing too.<br><br>They actually &#8212; I &#8212;<br><br>Q    So he is a killer?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, look, I mean, he has made clear that &#8212; the answer is: I believe he has, in the past, essentially acknowledged that he was &#8212; there were certain things that he would do or did do. <br><br>But look, when I was asked that question on air, I answered it honestly.  But it&#8217;s not much of a &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it matters a whole lot, in terms of this next meeting we&#8217;re about to have. <br><br>The second question was rela- &#8212;<br><br>Q    (Inaudible.)  How would you ever trust him?  And what is your version of &#8220;trust but verify&#8221;?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;d verify first and then trust.  In other words: Everything would have to be shown to be actually occurring.  It&#8217;s not about, you know, trusting; it&#8217;s about agreeing. <br><br>You know, when we &#8212; when you write treaties with your adversaries, you don&#8217;t say, “I trust you.”  You say, “This is what I expect, and if you violate the agreement you made then, we &#8212; the, quote, &#8216;The treaty is off.  The agreement is off.'&#8221; <br><br>And I&#8217;m hoping that &#8212; that President Putin concludes that there is some interest, in terms of his own interests, in changing the perception that the world has of him, in terms of whether or not he will engage in behavior that&#8217;s more consistent with what is considered to be appropriate behavior for a head of state.<br><br>Anne Gearan, Washington Post. <br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  Here at this meeting and earlier at the G7, you&#8217;ve said several times that America is back at Allies’ side, but a lot of those Allies are themselves pretty rattled by what happened on January 6th &#8212; an attempted overturning of your election &#8212; and they may still be alarmed by the continued hold that Donald Trump has over the Republican Party and the rise of nationalist figures like him around the world. <br><br>What do you say to those Allies, what have you been saying to them at these meetings about how the next President of the United States can keep any promises you make? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What I&#8217;m saying is them &#8212; to them is: Watch me.  I mean, I&#8217;m not saying anything, quite frankly.  I&#8217;m just going out &#8212; people, as I&#8217;ve said before, don&#8217;t doubt that I mean what I say, and they believe that I keep my commitments when I say it. <br><br>I&#8217;m not making any promises to anyone that I don&#8217;t believe are overwhelmingly likely to be kept.  I think that we&#8217;re at a moment where &#8212; I mean, let me put it this way: You may have had a different view, but I think an awful lot of people thought that my showing up at the G7 would not produce any kind of enthusiasm about American leadership and about where America was.  I would suggest that it didn&#8217;t turn out that way. <br><br>I would suggest that there is a &#8212; the leaders I&#8217;m dealing with in NATO and the G7 are leaders who know our recent history; know, generically, the character of the American people; and know where the vast center of the public stands &#8212; not Democrat, Republican &#8212; but who we are.  We&#8217;re a decent, honorable nation. <br><br>And I think that they have seen things happen, as we have, that shocked them and surprised them that could have happened.  But I think they, like I do, believe the American people are not going to sustain that kind of behavior. <br><br>And so, I &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t want to get into the &#8212; the statistics because you know that old phrase of Disraeli&#8217;s: “There&#8217;s three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.”<br><br>But I think it&#8217;s appropriate to say that the Republican Party is vastly diminished in numbers; the leadership of the Republican Party is fractured; and the Trump wing of the party is the bulk of the party, but it makes up a significant minority of the American people. <br><br>Now, we&#8217;ll see.  We’ll see.  I believe that by us standing up and saying what we believe to be the case, not engaging in the &#8212; the overwhelming hyperbole that gets engaged in by so many today, that we &#8212; I guess that old expression, “The proof of the pudding is in the eating.” <br><br>When we said &#8212; when I said I was going to deal with beating the virus and I was going to focus on that and I was going to get millions of shots in people&#8217;s arms, it wasn&#8217;t me &#8212; I just knew the American people.  I knew the kind of help I&#8217;d get from the Defense Department, from police departments, from &#8212; from the hospitals, from &#8212; from retired docs, from &#8212; I just knew.  And look how rapidly we moved. <br><br>Now, we have a group of people who were &#8212; everything from the political rejection of the notion of taking a vaccine, to people who were simply afraid of a needle and everything in between.  And we have a way to go. <br><br>But I never doubted that we would be able to generate the kind of support we got and get so many millions of people step up and get vaccinated.  So, I &#8212; I think it is a shock and surprise that what&#8217;s happened, in terms of the consequence of President Trump&#8217;s phony populism, has &#8212; has happened.  And it is disappointing that so many of my Republican colleagues in the Senate, who I know know better, have been reluctant to take on, for example, an investigation because they&#8217;re worried about being primaried. <br><br>But, at the end of the day, we&#8217;ve been through periods like this in American history before where there has been this reluctance to take a chance on your reelection because of the nature of your party&#8217;s politics at the moment. <br><br>I think this is passing.  I don&#8217;t mean easily passing.  That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that I succeed in my agenda &#8212; the agenda, whether it&#8217;s dealing with the vaccine, the economy, infrastructure.  It&#8217;s important that we demonstrate we can make progress and continue to make progress.  And I think we&#8217;re going to be able to do that.<br><br>So, as I said, the proof will be in where it is, you know, six months from now &#8212; where &#8212; where we are.  But I think you&#8217;re going to see that there&#8217;s &#8212; that, God willing, we&#8217;re going to be making progress, and there&#8217;s going to be a coalescing of a lot of Republicans, particularly younger Republicans who are coming up in the party. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And last question, Sebastian Smith of AFP.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  Ukraine wants a clear “yes” or “no” on getting into the NATO Membership Action Plan.  So, what&#8217;s your answer? <br><br>And, if I may, a second part to the same question: Well, now that Russia has invaded parts of Ukraine, does that effectively rule out Ukraine ever entering NATO, given that being in NATO would mean the U.S. and NATO having to defend Ukrainians against Russia? <br><br>Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The second question is &#8212; the answer is no. <br><br>The first question: It depends on whether they meet the criteria.  The fact is they still have to clean up corruption.  The fact is they have to meet other criteria to get into the Action Plan. <br><br>And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, school is out on that question.  It remains to be seen.  In the meantime, we will do all that we can to pu- &#8212; put Ukraine in the position to be able to continue to resist Russian physical aggression.  And it will not just depend on me whether or not we conclude that &#8212; that Ukraine can become part of NATO; it will depend on the Alliance and how they vote.<br><br>But I know, for one thing, there has to be a co- &#8212; they have to convince, and it&#8217;s not easy.  I made a speech, years ago, to the Rada saying that &#8212; that Ukraine had an opportunity to do something that&#8217;s never occurred in the history of Ukraine: actually generate a democratically elected and not corrupt &#8212; led by oligarchies in any of the regions &#8212; nation.  And I pointed out to them when I made that speech that they will go down in history as the founding fathers of Ukraine if, in fact, they do that.<br><br>They have more to do.  But that does not justify &#8212; the fact they have more to do &#8212; Russia taking aggressive action, either in the Donbas or in &#8212; on the sea, or in any part of Ukraine.  And we&#8217;re going to put Ukraine in a position to be able to maintain their physical security.<br><br>Thank you all so very much.  Sorry you&#8217;re all here so late.  Thank you very much.<br><br>9:54 P.M. CEST<br><br>NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium<br><br><br>9:28 P.M. CEST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Before I turn to today’s meetings, I want to say a short word about our ongoing fight against COVID-19 at home.<br><br>We&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the United States.  Much of the country is returning to normal, and our economic growth is leading the world, and the number of cases and deaths are dropping dramatically.  But there&#8217;s still too many lives being lost.<br><br>We’re still averaging, in the last seven days, loss of 370 deaths per day &#8212; 370 deaths.  That’s significantly lower than at the peak of this crisis, but it’s still a real tragedy.  We’re approaching a sad milestone: almost 600,000 lost lives because of COVID-19 in America. <br><br>My heart goes out to all those who have lost a loved one.  I know that black hole that seems to consume you, that fills up your chest when you lose someone that&#8217;s close to you that you adored.<br><br>That’s why I continue to say to America: If you’ve not been vaccinated, get vaccinated.  Get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We have plenty of vaccination, plenty of sites.  We have more work to do to beat this virus, and now is not the time to let our guard down.  So, please &#8212; please get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We’ve had enough pain.  Enough pain.<br><br>Folks, I know it&#8217;s after 9:30, Brussels time &#8212; 9:30 p.m., and I&#8217;m still at NATO.  You&#8217;re all excited about that.  I know.  (Laughter.) <br><br>But I&#8217;ve had a chance to meet with several leaders recently, and I’ve had calls with others.  It&#8217;s been an incredibly productive day here. <br><br>I just finished a meeting with President Erdoğan of Turkey.  We had a positive and productive meeting, much of it one-on-one.  We had detailed discussions on how to proceed on a number of &#8212; a number of issues.  Our two countries have big agendas.  Our teams are going to continue our discussions, and I’m confident we&#8217;ll make real progress with Turkey and the United States.<br><br>But now I want to thank Secretary General Stoltenberg for leading a very successful NATO Summit today.<br><br>I had the honor of leading off the discussion today among the 30 nations, and I pointed out that we’re facing a once-in-a-century global health crisis.  At the same time, the democratic values that undergird our Alliance are under increasing pressure both internally and externally.  Russia and China are both seeking to drive a wedge in our transatlantic solidarity.  We’re seeing an increase in malicious cyber activity.<br><br>But that our Alliance is the strong foundation on which we can &#8212; our collective security and our shared prosperity can continue to be built. <br><br>And I made a point to make clear that the U.S. commitment to Article 5 of the NATO Treaty is rock solid and unshakable.  It’s a sacred commitment.<br><br>NATO &#8212; NATO stands together.  That’s how we’ve met every other threat in the past.  It’s our greatest strength as we meet our challenges of the future &#8212; and there are many. <br><br>And everyone &#8212; everyone in that room today understood the shared appreciation, quite frankly, that America is back.<br><br>We talked about Russia’s aggressive acts that pose a threat to NATO and to our collective security.<br><br>That’s why I met with the Bucharest 9 &#8212; the eastern flank allies &#8212; in advance of this summit.  And today I also met with the leaders of the three Baltic states: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.<br><br>I shared with our Allies that I will convey to Pre- &#8212; what I&#8217;ll convey to President Putin: that I’m not looking for conflict with Russia, but that we will respond if Russia continues its harmful activities and that we will not fail to defend the Transatlantic Alliance or stand up for democratic values.<br><br>As Allies, we also affirmed our continued support<br>for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.<br><br>We agreed to keep consulting closely on nuclear deterrence, arms control, and strategic stability.<br><br>And there was a strong consensus among the leaders in that meeting on Afghanistan.  Our troops are coming home, but we agreed that our diplomatic, economic, and humanitarian commitment to the Afghan people and our support for<br>the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces will endure.<br><br>And I welcomed our Allies and partners to recognize that counterterrorism &#8212; that counterterrorism efforts must continue to ensure that Afghanistan never again becomes a ca- &#8212; a safe haven for attacks on our countries, even as we take on terrorist networks in the Middle East and Africa.<br><br>And I’m deeply gratified that, as an Alliance, we adopted a far-reaching plan to make sure that NATO can meet the challenges<br>that we face today and in the future, not yesterday &#8212; the NATO 2030 agenda &#8212; and that we agreed to fully resource that agenda.<br><br>The last time NATO put together a strategic plan was back in 2010, when Russia was considered a partner and China wasn’t even mentioned.<br><br>We talked about the long-term systemic challenges that China’s activities pose to our collective security today.<br><br>We agreed to do more to enhance the resilience of our critical infrastructure around the world, including trusted telecommunications providers, supply chains, and energy networks.<br><br>We agreed to enhance our cooperation with our democratic partners in the Indo-Pacific to meet challenges that exist there.<br><br>We also endorsed a new cyber defense policy &#8212; NATO&#8217;s first in the past seven years &#8212; to improve the collective ability to defend against counter threats from state and nonstate actors against our networks and our critical infrastructure. <br><br>And we adopted a Climate Security Action Plan &#8212; which, several years ago, people thought we would never would do &#8212; for reducing emissions from NATO installations and adapting to the security risk of climate change while keeping a sharp &#8212; very sharp on our ability to deter and defend against threats.<br><br>And finally, we agreed that among the most important shared missions is renewing and strengthening the resilience of our democracies by pointing out we have to prove to the world and to our own people that democracy can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs of our people.<br><br>We have to root out corruption that siphons off our strength; guard against those who would stoke hatred and division for political gain &#8212; this phony populism; invest in strengthening the institutions that underpin and safeguard our cherished democratic values, as well as protecting the free press and independent judiciaries.  All of those run the agenda. <br><br>That&#8217;s how I’ll prove that democracy and that our Alliance can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs and the needs of our people.<br><br>This is going to be looked at 25 years from now as whether or not we stepped up to the challenge, because there&#8217;s a lot of &#8212; a lot of autocracies that are counting on them being able to move more rapidly and successfully in an ever-complicated world than democracies can.  We all concluded we&#8217;re going to prove them wrong. <br><br>And now I&#8217;m happy to take some questions. <br><br>Cecilia Vega of ABC.<br><br>Q    Thank you so much, sir.  Good evening.  You mentioned your sit-down with Vladimir Putin and Russian aggression that came up in your conversations today.  I&#8217;d like to ask you two questions, if I may, on that front.  Is it your sense, walking into this meeting, that Americans back home shouldn&#8217;t expect much in terms of an outcome?  Could you provide some specifics on what a successful meeting would look like to you?  Are there going to be specific concessions you want Putin to make?<br><br>And then, I&#8217;ll just give you my follow-up right now.  You&#8217;ve met Vladimir Putin before.  What have you learned about him that informs how you approach this sit-down with him?  And what&#8217;s your mindset walking into a meeting with a former KGB agent who you&#8217;ve said has no soul?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ll tell you all that when it&#8217;s over. <br><br>Look, I&#8217;ve been doing this a long time.  The last thing anyone would do is negotiate in front of the world press as to how he&#8217;s going to approach a critical meeting with another adversary and/or someone who could be an adversary.  It’s the last thing I&#8217;m going to do.<br><br>But I will tell you this: I’m going to make clear to President Putin that there are areas where we can cooperate, if he chooses.  And if he chooses not to cooperate and acts in a way that he has in the past, relative to cybersecurity and some other activities, then we will respond.  We will respond in kind. <br><br>There need not be &#8212; we should decide where it&#8217;s in our mutual interest, in the interest of the world, to cooperate, and see if we can do that.  And the areas where we don&#8217;t agree, make it clear what the red lines are.<br><br>I have met with him.  He&#8217;s bright.  He&#8217;s tough.  And I have found that he is a &#8212; as they say, when you used to play ball, “a worthy adversary.” <br><br>But the fact is that I will be happy to talk with you when it&#8217;s over, and not before, about what the discussion will entail.<br><br>Nancy Cordes, CBS.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  I also have two questions about Vladimir Putin.  The first is: Have any of the world leaders you&#8217;ve met with this week expressed concern that by meeting with President Putin this early in your presidency, that it&#8217;ll look like you&#8217;re rewarding him?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What&#8217;s your second question?<br><br>Q    The section &#8212; the second question is: What it will mean for the U.S.-Russia relationship if Aleksey Navalny were to die or be killed in prison.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Every world leader here, as a member of NATO, that spoke today &#8212; and most of them mentioned it &#8212; thanked me for meeting with Putin now.  Every single one that spoke.  And I think there were probably about 10 or 12 that spoke to it, saying they were happy that I did that and that I was going to do that.  And they thought it was thoroughly appropriate that I do, and I had discussions with them about &#8212; in the open &#8212; about what they thought was important from their perspective and what they thought was not important.<br><br>And so the interesting thing is, I know &#8212; and I’m not being critical of the press &#8212; I really mean this; I give you my word &#8212; but, generically, you all thought, “Was Biden meeting him too soon?”  I haven’t found a world leader who doesn’t think it’s not soon &#8212; it’s just soon enough.  Everyone that I’ve spoken to, privately and publicly. <br><br>It doesn’t mean there aren&#8217;t some out there, but it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not likely that a head of state is going to stand up in front of 29 other heads of state and say, “Boy, I&#8217;m glad you&#8217;re doing this,” in effect.  So there is a consensus.  And they thanked me for being willing to talk with them about the meeting and what I was &#8212; what I intended to do.<br><br>So, I haven&#8217;t found any reluctance.  There may be someone, but not in the open today or in the meetings I privately had as well.<br><br>And Navalny’s death would be another indication that Russia has little or no intention of abiding by basic fundamental human rights.  It would be a tragedy.  It would do nothing but hurt his relationships with the rest of the world, in my view, and with me. <br><br>Jeff Zeleny, CNN.<br><br>Q    Sir, good evening.  Thank you.  In a weekend interview, Vladimir Putin laughed at the suggestion that you had called him a &#8220;killer.”  Is that still your belief, sir, that he is a killer? <br><br>And I&#8217;ll continue the trend, if you don&#8217;t mind, of asking a second question.  Do you believe &#8212; if he does agree to cooperate, then what kind of a challenge do you find yourself in?  How would you ever trust him?  And if Ronald Reagan said “trust but verify,” what do you say to Vladimir Putin? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (Laughs.)  To answer the first question &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I’m laughing too.<br><br>They actually &#8212; I &#8212;<br><br>Q    So he is a killer?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, look, I mean, he has made clear that &#8212; the answer is: I believe he has, in the past, essentially acknowledged that he was &#8212; there were certain things that he would do or did do. <br><br>But look, when I was asked that question on air, I answered it honestly.  But it&#8217;s not much of a &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it matters a whole lot, in terms of this next meeting we&#8217;re about to have. <br><br>The second question was rela- &#8212;<br><br>Q    (Inaudible.)  How would you ever trust him?  And what is your version of &#8220;trust but verify&#8221;?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;d verify first and then trust.  In other words: Everything would have to be shown to be actually occurring.  It&#8217;s not about, you know, trusting; it&#8217;s about agreeing. <br><br>You know, when we &#8212; when you write treaties with your adversaries, you don&#8217;t say, “I trust you.”  You say, “This is what I expect, and if you violate the agreement you made then, we &#8212; the, quote, &#8216;The treaty is off.  The agreement is off.'&#8221; <br><br>And I&#8217;m hoping that &#8212; that President Putin concludes that there is some interest, in terms of his own interests, in changing the perception that the world has of him, in terms of whether or not he will engage in behavior that&#8217;s more consistent with what is considered to be appropriate behavior for a head of state.<br><br>Anne Gearan, Washington Post. <br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  Here at this meeting and earlier at the G7, you&#8217;ve said several times that America is back at Allies’ side, but a lot of those Allies are themselves pretty rattled by what happened on January 6th &#8212; an attempted overturning of your election &#8212; and they may still be alarmed by the continued hold that Donald Trump has over the Republican Party and the rise of nationalist figures like him around the world. <br><br>What do you say to those Allies, what have you been saying to them at these meetings about how the next President of the United States can keep any promises you make? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What I&#8217;m saying is them &#8212; to them is: Watch me.  I mean, I&#8217;m not saying anything, quite frankly.  I&#8217;m just going out &#8212; people, as I&#8217;ve said before, don&#8217;t doubt that I mean what I say, and they believe that I keep my commitments when I say it. <br><br>I&#8217;m not making any promises to anyone that I don&#8217;t believe are overwhelmingly likely to be kept.  I think that we&#8217;re at a moment where &#8212; I mean, let me put it this way: You may have had a different view, but I think an awful lot of people thought that my showing up at the G7 would not produce any kind of enthusiasm about American leadership and about where America was.  I would suggest that it didn&#8217;t turn out that way. <br><br>I would suggest that there is a &#8212; the leaders I&#8217;m dealing with in NATO and the G7 are leaders who know our recent history; know, generically, the character of the American people; and know where the vast center of the public stands &#8212; not Democrat, Republican &#8212; but who we are.  We&#8217;re a decent, honorable nation. <br><br>And I think that they have seen things happen, as we have, that shocked them and surprised them that could have happened.  But I think they, like I do, believe the American people are not going to sustain that kind of behavior. <br><br>And so, I &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t want to get into the &#8212; the statistics because you know that old phrase of Disraeli&#8217;s: “There&#8217;s three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.”<br><br>But I think it&#8217;s appropriate to say that the Republican Party is vastly diminished in numbers; the leadership of the Republican Party is fractured; and the Trump wing of the party is the bulk of the party, but it makes up a significant minority of the American people. <br><br>Now, we&#8217;ll see.  We’ll see.  I believe that by us standing up and saying what we believe to be the case, not engaging in the &#8212; the overwhelming hyperbole that gets engaged in by so many today, that we &#8212; I guess that old expression, “The proof of the pudding is in the eating.” <br><br>When we said &#8212; when I said I was going to deal with beating the virus and I was going to focus on that and I was going to get millions of shots in people&#8217;s arms, it wasn&#8217;t me &#8212; I just knew the American people.  I knew the kind of help I&#8217;d get from the Defense Department, from police departments, from &#8212; from the hospitals, from &#8212; from retired docs, from &#8212; I just knew.  And look how rapidly we moved. <br><br>Now, we have a group of people who were &#8212; everything from the political rejection of the notion of taking a vaccine, to people who were simply afraid of a needle and everything in between.  And we have a way to go. <br><br>But I never doubted that we would be able to generate the kind of support we got and get so many millions of people step up and get vaccinated.  So, I &#8212; I think it is a shock and surprise that what&#8217;s happened, in terms of the consequence of President Trump&#8217;s phony populism, has &#8212; has happened.  And it is disappointing that so many of my Republican colleagues in the Senate, who I know know better, have been reluctant to take on, for example, an investigation because they&#8217;re worried about being primaried. <br><br>But, at the end of the day, we&#8217;ve been through periods like this in American history before where there has been this reluctance to take a chance on your reelection because of the nature of your party&#8217;s politics at the moment. <br><br>I think this is passing.  I don&#8217;t mean easily passing.  That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that I succeed in my agenda &#8212; the agenda, whether it&#8217;s dealing with the vaccine, the economy, infrastructure.  It&#8217;s important that we demonstrate we can make progress and continue to make progress.  And I think we&#8217;re going to be able to do that.<br><br>So, as I said, the proof will be in where it is, you know, six months from now &#8212; where &#8212; where we are.  But I think you&#8217;re going to see that there&#8217;s &#8212; that, God willing, we&#8217;re going to be making progress, and there&#8217;s going to be a coalescing of a lot of Republicans, particularly younger Republicans who are coming up in the party. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And last question, Sebastian Smith of AFP.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  Ukraine wants a clear “yes” or “no” on getting into the NATO Membership Action Plan.  So, what&#8217;s your answer? <br><br>And, if I may, a second part to the same question: Well, now that Russia has invaded parts of Ukraine, does that effectively rule out Ukraine ever entering NATO, given that being in NATO would mean the U.S. and NATO having to defend Ukrainians against Russia? <br><br>Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The second question is &#8212; the answer is no. <br><br>The first question: It depends on whether they meet the criteria.  The fact is they still have to clean up corruption.  The fact is they have to meet other criteria to get into the Action Plan. <br><br>And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, school is out on that question.  It remains to be seen.  In the meantime, we will do all that we can to pu- &#8212; put Ukraine in the position to be able to continue to resist Russian physical aggression.  And it will not just depend on me whether or not we conclude that &#8212; that Ukraine can become part of NATO; it will depend on the Alliance and how they vote.<br><br>But I know, for one thing, there has to be a co- &#8212; they have to convince, and it&#8217;s not easy.  I made a speech, years ago, to the Rada saying that &#8212; that Ukraine had an opportunity to do something that&#8217;s never occurred in the history of Ukraine: actually generate a democratically elected and not corrupt &#8212; led by oligarchies in any of the regions &#8212; nation.  And I pointed out to them when I made that speech that they will go down in history as the founding fathers of Ukraine if, in fact, they do that.<br><br>They have more to do.  But that does not justify &#8212; the fact they have more to do &#8212; Russia taking aggressive action, either in the Donbas or in &#8212; on the sea, or in any part of Ukraine.  And we&#8217;re going to put Ukraine in a position to be able to maintain their physical security.<br><br>Thank you all so very much.  Sorry you&#8217;re all here so late.  Thank you very much.<br><br>9:54 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/14/a-proclamation-on-world-elder-abuse-awareness-day-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 18:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Older Americans make invaluable contributions to our families, our communities, and our Nation every day.&#160; But for far too many, the sacred promise of aging with dignity in America is broken by unconscionable incidents of abuse, neglect, or exploitation. &#160;On World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, Americans of all ages join the international community to raise&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Older Americans make invaluable contributions to our families, our communities, and our Nation every day.&nbsp; But for far too many, the sacred promise of aging with dignity in America is broken by unconscionable incidents of abuse, neglect, or exploitation. &nbsp;On World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, Americans of all ages join the international community to raise awareness and help bring an end to elder abuse.</p>



<p>Elder abuse can take many forms, including financial, emotional, physical, or sexual abuse, as well as exploitation and neglect.&nbsp; Every year, one in ten Americans aged 60 and older experiences abuse &#8212; and for every case of elder abuse that comes to the attention of authorities, it is estimated that 23&nbsp;cases are never brought to light.&nbsp; Since the start of the COVID-19 pandemic, we have also seen a chilling increase in hate crimes targeting Asian-Americans, many of whom have been elders.&nbsp; These attacks are shameful and deeply un-American.</p>



<p>Central to our Nation is the idea that we are all in this together, and that as Americans we owe one another a basic duty of care.&nbsp; The pandemic has both reinforced the importance of that duty and tested our capacity to meet it &#8212; the virus has exacerbated the quiet harm of social isolation among seniors around the world, a condition that makes abuse, neglect, and exploitation more likely.&nbsp; Having lost so many cherished seniors to this virus, we must recommit ourselves to fully including older Americans in our communities and systems of support.&nbsp; We&nbsp;must care for one another &#8212; and leave no one behind.</p>



<p>With over three-quarters of Americans 65 and over now fully vaccinated and more progress being made every day, the future for seniors is growing brighter and brighter.&nbsp; After a painful year, grandparents around the world are hugging their grandchildren again.&nbsp; Vaccinated seniors who were socially isolated are able to reengage with the broader community again.&nbsp; And as we begin to build back better, we are working to ensure that older Americans have greater opportunities to live with dignity, safety, independence, and social connections.</p>



<p>My Administration is committed to fulfilling that promise.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the American Rescue Plan included more than $1.4 billion in additional funding for programs that promote community living and ensure the safety and protection of older adults.&nbsp; The law also enhances the Elder Justice Act and ensures that Adult Protective Services can be used to protect the safety and dignity of all seniors.&nbsp; Additionally, the plan included new Medicaid funding to expand access to critical home and community-based health care services, and over $275 million for elder justice programs that address abuse, neglect, and exploitation.&nbsp; The American Jobs Plan and American Families Plan will further that progress, building up the care infrastructure that our economy and so many families depend on &#8212; expanding day programs for seniors, programs that bring care workers to seniors&#8217; homes to cook meals, and programs to help seniors get around their home safely and live more independently.</p>



<p>As we expand opportunities for older Americans, my Administration will also not tolerate elder abuse or hate in any&nbsp;form.&nbsp; I have instructed agencies across the Federal Government to do their part to combat elder abuse and support survivors. &nbsp;We are working to renew and strengthen the Violence Against Women Act, which also dedicates Federal funds to develop a more comprehensive approach to addressing abuse and neglect in&nbsp;later life, including through the funding of victim service providers, law enforcement, and prosecutors working to prevent and respond to domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking experienced by older adults, whether caused by a spouse, family member, caregiver, or others.&nbsp; And this year, for the first time, the Federal Government has provided funding to Adult Protective Services programs in every State and Territory to support their critical, on-the-ground work investigating abuse and connecting victims to resources. &nbsp;</p>



<p>During World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, we also recognize the individuals who dedicate themselves to preventing elder abuse.&nbsp; All across our Nation, caregivers work to help older adults stay connected to their communities while preventing elder abuse and intervening if it occurs.&nbsp; These unsung heroes include family members, Adult Protective Services workers, social service providers, nonprofit victim services organizations, long-term care ombudspersons, law enforcement officers, judges and judicial personnel, legal professionals, health care professionals, and financial professionals.</p>



<p>On World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, we stand with all older Americans, and elderly people around the world, who are victims of elder abuse, neglect, and financial exploitation, and we recommit ourselves to protecting every senior&#8217;s right to live their golden years with dignity and respect.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim June 15, 2021, as World Elder Abuse Awareness Day. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to work for elder justice by building inclusive communities that welcome people of all ages and abilities; by learning the warning signs of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation; and by challenging age-related biases.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fourteenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><br>                              JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Andrzej Duda of Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/14/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 14:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20711</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke today on the margins of the NATO Summit with President Andrzej Duda of Poland. The President reiterated his support for NATO’s strengthened defense and deterrence agenda and his resolute commitment to the defense of Allies on NATO’s eastern flank, including Poland. He discussed his plans for the upcoming summit with President Putin.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke today on the margins of the NATO Summit with President Andrzej Duda of Poland. The President reiterated his support for NATO’s strengthened defense and deterrence agenda and his resolute commitment to the defense of Allies on NATO’s eastern flank, including Poland. He discussed his plans for the upcoming summit with President Putin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg During Greeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/14/remarks-by-president-biden-and-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-during-greeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 14:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATO HeadquartersBrussels, Belgium 12:28 P.M. CEST&#160;SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&#160; Mr. President, it is great to see you again and just a week after we met in the White House.&#160; And thank you so much for your strong personal commitment and powerful leadership on the transatlantic bond on what to do together &#8212; North America and Europe.&#160;&#160;We&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>12:28 P.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; Mr. President, it is great to see you again and just a week after we met in the White House.&nbsp; And thank you so much for your strong personal commitment and powerful leadership on the transatlantic bond on what to do together &#8212; North America and Europe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We meet at a pivotal time for our Alliance.&nbsp; We will open a new chapter in our transatlantic relationship with the meeting today; address a wide range of issues, including Russia.&nbsp; And I think that the Allied leaders look forward to consulting with you ahead of the meeting with President Putin.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will address China, and we have seen the convergence of views among Allies.&nbsp; We all recognize that China&#8217;s heavy investments in military capabilities, continued coercive behavior, and their growing influence matters for our security.&nbsp; And we need to respond to that together as an Alliance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will review the NATO 2030 agenda, an ambitious agenda for the future of NATO.&nbsp; And to do all this, we need to invest more.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re doing with seven consecutive years of increased defense spending: 260 billion extra U.S. dollars across Europe and Canada.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So a strong NATO is good for Europe, but is also good for America.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s very good for America.&nbsp; It&#8217;s essential for America.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; And I know that &#8212; that no other major power has as many friends and allies as United States has in NATO.&nbsp; So I know that we can count on America and that America can count on Europe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, welcome, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; And thank you for your incredible leadership over the years.&nbsp; I really mean this: You have been incredible.&nbsp; I &#8212; quite frankly, we have competent people coming, but I wish you weren&#8217;t leaving, because &#8212; and, no, I really mean it &#8212; you have been absolutely incredible and you&#8217;ve been strong.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve been &#8212; you&#8217;ve been able to pull people together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that there is a growing recognition over the last couple of years that we have new challenges.&nbsp; And we have Russia that is not acting in a way that is consistent with what we had hoped, and &#8212; as well as China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I must say that we had as (inaudible) a number of my colleagues and our colleagues who are in the G7 have stepped up as well, in terms of the need for there to be greater coordination.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve had &#8212; but I want to make it clear: NATO is critically important for U.S. interests in and of itself.&nbsp; If there weren&#8217;t one, we&#8217;d have to invent one.&nbsp; It is &#8212; it allows America to &#8212; to conduct its business around the world in a way that never would have occurred were it not for NATO, number one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, you know, I believe &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said this my whole career and the four years I was out, when I decided to run for President again &#8212; that NATO is &#8212; Article 5, we take as a sacred obligation.&nbsp; And I constantly remind Americans that when America was attacked for the first time on its shores since what happened back in the beginning of World War Two, NATO stepped up.&nbsp; NATO stepped up and they honored Article 5.&nbsp; And I just want all of Europe to know that the United States is there.&nbsp; The United States is there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we &#8212; and we are pleased, back in Wales, the decision was made to increase spending.&nbsp; You&#8217;re right, it&#8217;s moving up.&nbsp; I guess there&#8217;s more than 10 countries that have met the goal, and others are on the way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s important, but it&#8217;s &#8212; I just want to thank you for your leadership.&nbsp; A lot of this wouldn&#8217;t happen without you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>12:32 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia, President Egils Levits of Latvia, and President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/14/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-kaja-kallas-of-estonia-president-egils-levits-of-latvia-and-president-gitanas-nauseda-of-lithuania/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 12:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia, President Egils Levits of Latvia, and President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania on the margins of the NATO Summit in Brussels. The President underscored strong U.S. support for the security of Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania, as well as the entire Baltic region.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia, President Egils Levits of Latvia, and President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania on the margins of the NATO Summit in Brussels. The President underscored strong U.S. support for the security of Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania, as well as the entire Baltic region. The four leaders committed to further strengthening our political, military, and economic partnerships, including working together through NATO to address challenges posed by Russia and China.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official On President Biden’s Engagements at NATO Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/14/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-president-bidens-engagements-at-nato-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 3:08 P.M. CEST MODERATOR: Good afternoon, everyone. [Redacted.] Our speaker is going to also provide a brief, unembargoed, on-background update of some of President Biden&#8217;s engagements today at NATO, including the President&#8217;s meeting with Baltic leaders. So, I&#8217;ll turn it over to him to kick us off on that. [Senior administration official], go&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>3:08 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>MODERATOR: Good afternoon, everyone. [Redacted.] Our speaker is going to also provide a brief, unembargoed, on-background update of some of President Biden&#8217;s engagements today at NATO, including the President&#8217;s meeting with Baltic leaders. So, I&#8217;ll turn it over to him to kick us off on that. [Senior administration official], go ahead.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks, everybody, for joining the call. And greetings from NATO headquarters, where I&#8217;ve just stepped out of the session of the leaders here at the summit that is currently ongoing.</p>



<p>President Biden has delivered his remarks a short while ago, and other leaders are now speaking. On the margins of the NATO Summit, he had the opportunity to meet with the leaders of the three Baltic countries: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania. And he got the chance to discuss with them and coordinate with them in advance of his meeting with Putin on Wednesday to talk about the threat that Russia poses to NATO&#8217;s eastern flank, to talk about common commitment to Article 5 and collective defense, to coordinate on the resilience of those states in the face of multiple dimensions of the threat posed by Russia &#8212; from cyber, to provocative military exercises on their borders, to information warfare.</p>



<p>He was able to communicate to them what he has communicated publicly, which is that the United States seeks a stable and constructive relationship with Russia, but also will respond in the face of Russia&#8217;s harmful activities and will always stand up for NATO Allies.</p>



<p>They also discussed the emerging security challenge posed by China, including in the domain of technology. And he thanked the three leaders for the steps that they have taken to support a trusted 5G platform &#8212; to not accept Huawei within their systems.</p>



<p>They also had the opportunity to confer on Belarus and, in particular, the recent egregious air piracy that occurred with respect to a flight that was actually bound for Vilnius, Lithuania. And they had the opportunity to talk more broadly about and an affirmative agenda around emerging technologies and innovation.</p>



<p>It was a constructive, warm, vigorous engagement between him and the three leaders, and a real symbol of solidarity and unity with NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.</p>



<p>In that vein, he also had the opportunity to do a brief meeting with the Presidents of Poland and Romania, who are the co-chairs of the Bucharest Nine, the same group of eastern flank Allies that he engaged with at their virtual summit a few weeks ago. He was able to speak with the two of them about his commitment to (inaudible) security; his commitment, again, to stand up in the face of the threat posed by Russia; and to let them know his intentions for the summit in Geneva on Wednesday.</p>



<p>He had a separate encounter &#8212; an engagement with President Duda of Poland, where they got to go a little bit deeper into the questions of America&#8217;s security and military cooperation and engagement with Poland and the United States&#8217; strong support for the defense of Poland and our common collective commitment to NATO.</p>



<p>He had the chance to talk to a number of other leaders as well, just very briefly &#8212; from the Prime Minister of Spain to the Prime Minister of the Netherlands &#8212; on a range of different issues &#8212; and, of course, to see his colleagues who have just come with him from Cornwall and the G7 &#8212; President Macron, Chancellor Merkel, Prime Minister Draghi, Prime Minister Johnson.</p>



<p>[Redacted.]</p>



<p>Q Thanks, [senior administration official], for doing this. I was hoping you could speak to the issue of Afghanistan and whether any of the NATO members raised concerns with Biden about the withdrawal. And then separately, I would just ask, broadly, on behalf of the media here, if we could get these bilats on the schedule or delivered to the press because we were unaware of several of them today, and also that we could get some access to them, which has been a pretty tradition &#8212; a tradition of both parties in the past. Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, on the second thing, you know, this was at the initiative of President Biden today that he wanted the opportunity to seek out key leaders, particularly on the eastern flank, to be sure he had the time &#8212; the opportunity to spend time with them, especially given the fact that for the key Western European countries, he&#8217;s just spent three days with them, and he wanted to maximize this opportunity to talk to the Poles, the Romanians, the (inaudible), et cetera. So, a lot of this was evolving in real time and there was not an effort to –- frankly, we would have loved to had &#8212; have more press access to them. But we’ll endeavor always to do better as we go forward.</p>



<p>In terms of Afghanistan, I listened –- I was in the room for the first hour of the summit and heard many of the significant troop-contributing countries speak and speak to the issue of Afghanistan. And each of them said that they ultimately agreed with the decision to come &#8212; to draw down this year. They understood that the time had come.</p>



<p>And the real focus in the room was not on the question of staying or going in 2021; the real focus was on how we work together as an Alliance to continue to provide support to the Afghan National Security Forces, the Afghan government, and the Afghan people.</p>



<p>And there is a considerable amount of practical work being done on that and strategic alignment on the desire to keep embassy presences, to maintain the necessary security to do that, and to work together as an alliance on everything from training &#8212; you know, particularly on over-the-horizon training; to counterterrorism and how we keep suppressing the terrorist threat in Afghanistan; to the provision of economic assistance in various forms to government.</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ve read some of the stories about this question of support or nonsupport for the drawdown from Afghanistan, and I&#8217;ve got to tell you that that is not the vibe in the room today. And, you know, it is &#8212; there is an incredible amount of warmth and unity around the entire agenda, including the &#8220;in together, out together&#8221; aspect of the Afghanistan drawdown.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks so much, again, everybody, for taking the time and hopping on this call. Really appreciate it.</p>



<p>3:32 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Brussels, Belgium</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/13/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-brussels-belgium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 22:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Brussels, Belgium 8:05 P.M. BST&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Thank you for joining us on Air Force One, on our trip to Brussels.&#160; And we have joining us our National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who will give us a preview of NATO, take some questions, and I&#8217;m also happy to take some once&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>8:05 P.M. BST<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you for joining us on Air Force One, on our trip to Brussels.&nbsp; And we have joining us our National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who will give us a preview of NATO, take some questions, and I&#8217;m also happy to take some once he&#8217;s done.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; President Biden is heading to Brussels for his first NATO Summit with the overriding objective of sending a clear message to Allies and adversaries alike that Article 5 is a sacred guarantee; that the United States regards NATO as the foundation for our security &#8212; not just in the Euro Atlantic, but worldwide &#8212; and that we will be there for our Allies.&nbsp; We will have their backs just as they&#8217;ve had our backs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;ll cover a range of issues during the session with the leaders, including, of course, the immediate issue of the drawdown in Afghanistan, where we&#8217;re proceeding on an in-together, out-together basis, and coordinating very closely with our Allies as we draw down our remaining forces.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He will also consult on ensuring security for an embassy presence that can continue to provide support to the Afghan National Security Forces and to the Afghan government, as well as humanitarian and civilian assistance to the Afghan people, especially to its women and girls.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He will discuss cyber as an increasingly important dimension of NATO&#8217;s work.&nbsp; NATO will finalize a national cyber &#8212; or, I&#8217;m sorry, not a &#8220;national&#8221; &#8212; will finalize a cyber defense strategy for the first time in seven years, which will upgrade the defense, political, and intelligence dimensions of cyber across the Alliance.&nbsp; That will not be a public document, but he will have the chance to consult with Allies on it.&nbsp; And in the communiqué that will be released, there will be a strong commitment to NATO&#8217;s emphasis on cyber deterrence and collective defense, as well as Article 5 applying on a case-by-case basis to cyberattacks of significance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, he will discuss the emerging challenges posed by China, not just in the Indo-Pacific but elsewhere, in terms of technology and cybersecurity and information warfare and in other regards, as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And China will feature in the communiqué really in a more robust way than we&#8217;ve ever seen before.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you repeat that?&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; Just didn’t hear the last line.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; China will feature in the communiqué in a more robust way than we&#8217;ve ever seen before.<br>&nbsp;<br>What we will see coming out of this is a commitment by leaders to a new Strategic Concept process that will result in the release of a new Strategic Concept at a NATO Summit next year, in 2022.&nbsp; The last Strategic Concept was done in 2010, and, among other things, referred to Russia as a &#8220;constructive partner,&#8221; and really didn&#8217;t talk about China at all.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s time for an update to that Strategic Concept for NATO.&nbsp; And he will consult with Allies and partners at the summit about this.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There will also be a Climate Action Plan.&nbsp; The Secretary General, with the support of the President and others, wants NATO to be the premier international security organization working on the intersection between climate and security.&nbsp; And, obviously, the climate dimension of everything &#8212; all of our militaries do and all of our security systems do &#8212; is growing and intensifying.&nbsp; And NATO will be front and center in all of that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, of course, there&#8217;s the consultation on Russia.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll have the opportunity to speak to all of the Allies about what he intends to talk to Putin about.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll do that behind closed doors.&nbsp; So, they get both to hear from him about his intentions with respect to the summit, and he gets to hear from them as well, so that he will go into Geneva with the full support and solidarity of all of our NATO Allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>He will meet on the sidelines of the summit with the Baltic presidents, who are a powerful example of democratic governance on NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.&nbsp; And he will speak with them about a range of issues, including the challenge and threat posed by Russia about issues related to cyber and emerging technology, on which they are leaders; about China and the growing challenges it poses as well; and, of course, about the recent air piracy in Belarus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he will also meet with President Erdoğan of Turkey, where they will cover the range of issues in our bilateral relationship, as well as a number of important regional issues, from Syria, to Libya, to the eastern Mediterranean.&nbsp; They will also have the chance to consult on the big powers &#8212; China and Russia &#8212; as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think I will &#8212; I will leave it at that.&nbsp; I guess I would just close by saying that if you think about the G7 as really centering on the most significant nonmilitary challenges of our time, and President Biden coming out of the G7 Summit with the democracies united behind an affirmative agenda to deal with those challenges, he heads into NATO really to focus on the security and military dimension of this.&nbsp; But that security and military dimension itself is changing, and cyber and emerging technology will play an important role in that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so by the time we&#8217;re done tomorrow, in Brussels, when you combine the G7 and NATO, it&#8217;s just a really powerful platform upon which America can conduct its foreign policy in the years ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So let me stop there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Talk about China a little bit.&nbsp; What role should NATO have in countering China?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think there are three things that I particularly focus on.&nbsp; One is that NATO has a role in information sharing about the nature of the security challenges that China poses.&nbsp; It imposes challenges to individual Allies in both common and distinct ways.&nbsp; And so, a broader, common picture of that challenge will be very important.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, of course, is that, increasingly, in the area particularly of emerging technology, China is growing much more sophisticated in its warfighting capabilities and methods, including in the nuclear sphere.&nbsp; And so, NATO has to play a role in developing interoperable capabilities to be able to deal with a challenge from China that is going beyond the region and extending much more broadly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, thirdly, NATO is, first and foremost, the center for security and military coordination and collective defense, but it is also a forum for democratic values.&nbsp; It is an alliance of democracies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, NATO speaking out powerfully about the common purpose and common strength of democracies is an important part of a collective effort to be able to meet the China challenge over the decades ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on the &#8212; at the G7, did he hear anything about the origins of COVID?&nbsp; Any intel shared with him that he didn&#8217;t know before?&nbsp; Did any of the Allies have anything new to share with him about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, they all pledged to &#8212; not only does the communiqué talk about a WHO-led phase two investigation that should take place in China and get to the bottom of things in China, including the original data that was withheld in the first study, but all of the countries also pledged that they would have their national systems try to share analysis and information in the weeks and months ahead, both with that international investigation and with each other.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think there was a common sense that we&#8217;ve all got to dig deeper ourselves, as well as supporting this international effort, and then pool our knowledge so we can get the best, most clear, most evidence-based picture of what actually happened with the outbreak of COVID.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there wasn&#8217;t consensus on whether it was lab-based or hu- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So no one &#8212; no one really knows?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on cyber, two things.&nbsp; Can you talk a little more about what invoking Article 5 might look like, in terms of a cyber incident?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then also, the President was asked today about this idea that was floated from the Kremlin about trading cyber hackers.&nbsp; Are there hackers in America who have been doing &#8212; committing cyber crimes in Russia that we should be &#8212; walk us through that really means.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, what the President was responding to in the affirmative was not the specific proposal of the exchange of cyber criminals.&nbsp; He was not saying, &#8220;I&#8217;m going to exchange cyber criminals.&#8221;&nbsp; What he was saying was that if Vladimir Putin wants to come and say, &#8220;I&#8217;m prepared to make sure that cyber criminals are held accountable,&#8221; Joe Biden is perfectly willing to show up and say cyber criminals will be held accountable in America, because they already are.&nbsp; That is something that we do &#8212; is when we know that someone is committing a cyber crime, whether against a domestic target or a foreign target, we take action against them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so to the extent what Vladimir Putin wants is a common commitment that no country &#8212; neither Russia nor the United States nor anyone else &#8212; will hyber [sic] &#8212; will harbor cyber criminals, whether ransomware attackers or otherwise, Joe Biden is all in for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s not saying he&#8217;s going to be exchanging cyber criminals with Russia.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no cyber criminals who have committed crimes in Russia that he&#8217;s looking at and thinking, &#8220;I&#8217;m going to exchange them.”&nbsp; I think that was overread or misread in the press coming out of &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s not what he said, right?&nbsp; I mean, he did &#8212; he did talk about specifically exchanging &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; If you go back and look at the transcript, I think you will actually see he didn&#8217;t talk about exchanging cyber criminals.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did he mean then?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like, “prisoner swap” &#8212; he didn&#8217;t say that.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; What’s that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He didn&#8217;t say &#8220;prisoner swap.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He didn&#8217;t say &#8220;prisoner swap.&#8221;&nbsp; What he was talking about was accountability and the idea that responsible countries should hold &#8212; should be held accountable to not harboring cyber criminals, and to bringing cyber criminals to justice.&nbsp; He&#8217;s prepared to do that in the United States.&nbsp; He&#8217;d like to see Vladimir Putin do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not about exchanges or swaps, or anything like that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Northern Ireland &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, sorry, just on cyber, really fast, and Article 5: This would be on a case-by-case basis.&nbsp; And the notion is that if someone gets hit by a massive cyberattack, and they need technical or intelligence support from another Ally to be able to deal with it, they could invoke Article 5 to be able to get that.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s being proposed tomorrow?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; That&#8217;s the concept.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; that will be in the communiqué coming out of (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on China, when you&#8217;re bringing this up with NATO, in the past it&#8217;s mostly been focused about Russia, or in more recent past, Macron has talked about concerns about the United&#8217;s focus is turning to the east, and not locally.&nbsp; How do you bring the Europeans along more?&nbsp; I mean, even in &#8212; even in the G7, in the communiqué, with forced labor, in that paragraph &#8212; correct me if I&#8217;m wrong &#8212; it does not have China in it, but it is mentioned in the communiqué.&nbsp; So how do you bring them along in these next steps, in the NATO &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I think forced labor is a great example of how we are all converging around a common strategy, and that strategy is ultimately about action.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so the communiqué doesn’t just say “forced labor” generically, it says “forced labor” with specific reference to solar, garments, and agriculture.&nbsp; And so where is the world solar made?&nbsp; What are the main products coming out of Xinjiang?&nbsp; You have cotton, you have garments, et cetera.<br>&nbsp;<br>So the basic notion in the communiqué was: Call out Xinjiang in terms of its human rights abuses and then establish a neutral principle that all democracies can stand behind.&nbsp; We are going to take concrete action and countermeasures against forced labor in these areas.&nbsp; And when you actually apply that in practice, that will have an impact on Xinjiang.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, from Joe Biden’s perspective, the idea here is not to score rhetorical points.&nbsp; The idea is to get agreement around a common set of principles and a common strategy.&nbsp; And if you go through the communiqué and look at the areas where they got that convergence, they are all the central pillars of how we believe we should be dealing with the challenge of China: supply chain resilience, technology standards, an infrastructure alternative, as well as robust, specific, explicit language on human rights and on China’s non-market practices.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>So that’s how we think about G7 and why we actually think this communiqué is a significant move forward from where the G7 has ever been before, and reflects a growing convergence that wasn&#8217;t there a few years ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But it&#8217;s also how we&#8217;re going to approach NATO.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not going to see, like, paragraphs and paragraphs about China in the communiqué.&nbsp; And the language is not going to be inflammatory.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be clear, straightforward, and direct.&nbsp; And also, we&#8217;re not going to try to over-crank the extent to which tomorrow is about China by any stretch.&nbsp; Tomorrow is about collective security and defense, and climate will be on the agenda; cyber will be on the agenda; Russia will be on the agenda; terrorism will be on the agenda; and this Afghanistan drawdown will be a significant issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, yes, China will be there in a way it hasn&#8217;t before.&nbsp; And I think President Biden&#8217;s view is: Explain how we see things in a transparent and clear way.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t try to push towards confrontation or conflict, but be prepared to try to rally allies and partners towards what is going to be tough competition in the years ahead.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s true in the security domain as it is in the economic and technological domains.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on Northern Ireland &#8212; sorry &#8212; did the President say anything in his conversations with Prime Minister Johnson about whether a U.S.-UK trade deal would be at risk if he doesn&#8217;t protect the Good Friday Agreement?&nbsp; Did he ask Boris Johnson not to renege on Brexit &#8212; on the Brexit pact?&nbsp; Or can you share a little bit about what the President told Boris Johnson about &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; All I&#8217;m going to say: They did discuss this issue.&nbsp; They had a candid discussion of it in private.&nbsp; The President naturally, and with, you know, deep sincerity, encouraged the Prime Minister to protect the Good Friday Agreement and the progress made under it.&nbsp; The specifics beyond that, I&#8217;m not going to get into.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Afghanistan, does he intend to touch on the Kabul issue and particularly the security at the airport &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; maybe with Mr. Erdoğan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) come up with a solutions (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He will discuss embassy presence with a broad range of allied embassies, and he will discuss security arrangements, specifically including with President Erdoğan.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to go into further details because those discussions are, you know, best to take place privately and with some degree of sensitivity.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, the event &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, you didn’t ask a question.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you take us inside the conversations at the G7 as much as you can, about China?&nbsp; I mean, how much convincing did it take to get everybody on board on the China language?&nbsp; And what was the, sort of, inside-the-room pitch that the President made to other world leaders on this?&nbsp; And did it look any different than what he said in public?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I guess the way that I would look at this is: This is not &#8212; it&#8217;s been framed up a bit as “Joe Biden walked in to convince everybody else on China.”&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s not quite accurate.&nbsp; Each country has its set of concerns that it emphasizes vis-à-vis China.&nbsp; And what the President sought to do was bring all of that together into a common picture of what we need to do collectively as democracies to respond.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there isn&#8217;t a &#8212; you know, whether it&#8217;s Germany or it’s Italy, or it’s France, or it’s the UK or Canada, to &#8212; on different issues, they have different levels of conviction about the depth of the challenge.&nbsp; But when you add it all up, actually, the whole became greater than the sum of its parts, because there is a broad view that China represents a significant challenge to the world&#8217;s democracies on a number of different dimensions, and that we need a common agenda that is mostly affirmative but also has elements where we are going to stand up and counter and compete.&nbsp; And words like “counter” and “compete” were words coming out of the mouths of every leader in the room, not just Joe Biden.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it wasn&#8217;t like he had to sit there and make a legal case to try to bring people around.&nbsp; I think the role that he felt he could play was to take the different perspectives and try to stitch them together into a coherent and common whole.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, honestly, from the transition &#8212; when there was fundamental questions about whether we were going to be deeply at odds with our European partners over China, and when the European Union signed on to the investment agreement with China &#8212; to today, when we released this communiqué and, at the end of this, you have seen, as I said before, a significant convergence on these issues, including to the point where that investment agreement is actually currently suspended.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, we believe where we&#8217;re sitting today is not the end of the story, but it is a good platform upon which to build.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you about the next chapter of that story?&nbsp; I mean, it seemed to go well at the G7.&nbsp; You know, everybody was friendly.&nbsp; You know, you didn&#8217;t have the tensions that you had in the &#8212; a few years ago.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the next step?&nbsp; I mean, how do you take that and go next to &#8212; whether it&#8217;s policy or concrete, how do you take what symbolism (inaudible) those relationships and move forward?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean, ultimately, actions speak louder than words, and the proof will be in the pudding for all of us, including the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I would say the metrics over the course of the next year are, number one: Can we actually get Build Back Better World off the ground with meaningful financing behind it and a real impetus?&nbsp; I believe the answer to that question is, yes, there&#8217;s real energy and enthusiasm behind it, but we got to do it.&nbsp; Can we turn the commitments on forced labor and ending overseas financing of coal into genuine outcomes by the end of this year or into early next year on forced labor?&nbsp; I believe the answer is yes, but we&#8217;re going to have to prove it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have to prove it on actually delivering these vaccines and on the broader, comprehensive COVID agenda.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So what we have is a good program of work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a program of work that reflects a common strategy.&nbsp; That is an affirmative strategy, but also has an element of ensuring we compete with a position of &#8212; from a position of strength with China.&nbsp; And now we&#8217;ve got to actually execute on it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So one year from today, at the next G7 &#8212; I&#8217;m not sure where that is.&nbsp; Do you know where the next G7 is?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know where the next one is.&nbsp; We’ll have to get back to you on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah, we’ll have to get back to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>We actually now have a metric against which to judge ourselves.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to hide from that.&nbsp; If we haven&#8217;t achieved it, I&#8217;ll move the goalposts next year.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; But for now &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; no, that’s a joke.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does “meaningful financing” look like for B3W?&nbsp; I mean, you said hundreds of millions of dollars, but there&#8217;s &#8212; sorry, hundreds of billions of dollars, but there’s a $41 trillion infrastructure gap.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a pretty big gap in your own &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean &#8212; but that&#8217;s like saying BRI is a drop in the bucket because it&#8217;s between 500 and a trillion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s true that there is infinite demand.&nbsp; But the fact is that, you know, we need to look at what are immediately bankable projects; where is there absorptive capacity; how do we get this money out the door in a way that actually is going to produce the physical or digital or health infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think, in the first few years, the idea that we&#8217;d be mobilizing this amount of money and proving out concept and building momentum will take us a long way.&nbsp; And that $40 trillion goes out &#8212; first goes out to 2035.&nbsp; And, second, we&#8217;re not going to stand here and pretend like we&#8217;re going to fill the entire $40 trillion gap.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to try and make a real dent in it between now and 15 years from now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can you clarify what the President said when he talked about there being a dilemma for Russia as it relates to Libya?&nbsp; Presumably he was referring to Syria.&nbsp; Is there more clarity?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Syria.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He meant Syria, then?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah, he did.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, there was reporting today about how when these G7 leaders work together, that there were concerns that China may be spying on these conversations.&nbsp; Can you talk about, like, what that reveals about the concerns that still exist (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think that was a garble, to be honest with you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That was a what?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A garble?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Who said &#8212; who said that?&nbsp; That was the thing about &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The cell signal around the room where the leaders was meeting was blocked at times.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was blocked to protect those conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; honestly think this was a garble.&nbsp; I think it was &#8212; like many beautiful coastal spots in America, Cornwall has spotty cell service, which I experienced&nbsp;considerably.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; like, I do not believe or know &#8212; I wasn&#8217;t in that session, so I can&#8217;t say for sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was in multiple sessions that cell service was blocked.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, no, I was in &#8212; I was in multiple sessions, and I was on my phone.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We got jammed.&nbsp; We felt like we were being jammed at one point.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think this is correct.&nbsp; I will check on it for you guys to be sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not trying to hide the ball here.&nbsp; But I was in four of the six sessions and on my phone on all of them.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t know about cell service being blocked.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did you see the statement from the Chinese &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; You look skeptical, but I&#8217;m telling you, I was sitting there &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because even one of your briefers told us on &#8212; one of the senior administration officials said that the cell &#8212; that Internet was blocked during the meetings.&nbsp; But you’re saying &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t think that was actually the exact phrasing.&nbsp; I mean, he didn’t have access at times to Internet, and is having a hard time getting access to his computer and his notes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I genuinely don’t think Internet was blocked, but I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; If it was, it was only for the sessions I wasn&#8217;t in, because I will show you the receipts of all the emails I sent.&nbsp; In fact &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The point was: We’re asking what it reflects on the Chinese relationship.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; When I was &#8212; I would frequently have to look up and make sure the President wasn&#8217;t looking back at me while I was on my phone during.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Anyway, that&#8217;s off the record.&nbsp; Just kidding.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did you see the statement from the Chinese Embassy in London saying that China would not pay attention to a group of small countries?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Which group of small countries is that?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Talking about the G7?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; That is sad.&nbsp; So, if their claim is that all of the other world&#8217;s largest economies count as small countries, then they have a massive problem of perspective.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this &#8212; is (inaudible) at G7, NATO &#8212; can you connect it to the priority of being foreign policy for the middle class?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; NATO?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, both &#8212; the G7 and NATO.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I mean, G7 &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) very strong priority (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah &#8212; so, G7, at its core, is about sustainable, equitable economic recovery that will deliver for the American middle class.&nbsp; The global minimum tax is &#8212; was one of our top priorities in terms of delivering for the American people.&nbsp; The dollars that will put in our fist to be able to invest back in workers and communities are substantial.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s one big outcome in that regard.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Even something like Build Back Better World actually interacts in a really interesting way with the American Jobs Plan, because as we invest in and develop clean energy technologies or water infrastructure that we&#8217;re building out in the United States, investing this money overseas through Build Back Better World will actually give export opportunities for American-made products and technologies.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re very mindful of that and would be proud of that as a &#8212; as a feature of Build Back Better World.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, all of the work on supply chain resilience so that we&#8217;re never again dependent on another country in a crisis and so that we have sufficient manufacturing capacity at home for critical materials, sensitive materials &#8212; that&#8217;s going to deliver jobs and economic growth for the middle class.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So those are just three &#8212; three examples.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned &#8212; you mentioned briefly Erdoğan, but could you give us a little more sense as to what the agenda is tomorrow in that &#8212; in that bilateral?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah, so they will talk about Afghanistan and, in particular, how we ensure that our embassies can stay in a safe and secure way in Afghanistan to be able to do all the things that we want to do in providing for the Afghan government and security forces and people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They will talk about Syria and humanitarian access, among other issues in the counterterrorism space.&nbsp; They will talk about the eastern Mediterranean.&nbsp; They will talk about Libya.&nbsp; They will talk about political and economic issues that are more challenging.&nbsp; And then they will &#8212; that have been challenges in our relationship, including human rights-related issues.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And they will talk about the &#8212; as I said in my opening laydown, Russia and China.&nbsp; You know, Russia, obviously, is both at odds with Turkey in some places and working with Turkey in others.&nbsp; So it&#8217;ll be an interesting chance for him to compare notes with Erdoğan before seeing Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he prepared to talk about their meetings (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The S-400s &#8212; will he bring that up as well?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, he will.&nbsp; The S-4- &#8212; yeah, the air defense system in &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; in Turkey.&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you give us any idea of what he might say on the S-400s?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m following the Biden Doctrine, and I will, you know, let him have that conversation with Erdoğan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Afghanistan interpreters who helped the U.S. military, was there any discussion amongst the Allies in any of the G7 meetings or pull-asides about what to do about &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; He spoke with several leaders &#8212; I guess not several.&nbsp; He spoke with a few leaders &#8212; particularly like the Germans, who have troops as part of the drawdown now in Afghanistan &#8212; about interpreters, translators, others who have supported not just us, but NATO and their countries about what we&#8217;re going to collectively do to make sure that we meet the obligation we have to get them out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So was there any conclusion on that?&nbsp; Is there more of a plan now than you had before going into the G7 on what to do on (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; For them, it was an opportunity at the leader level to communicate to each other and then to be able to communicate down to their systems, send a pulse through their systems.&nbsp; This is a massive priority for our President, as well as for the leaders of these other countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on ransoms, was there debate amongst the Allies at the G7 meetings about whether or not they should say something about whether to pay ransoms?&nbsp; Was that a topic of discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Not really.&nbsp; Too much to talk about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Russia, today in the news conference, (inaudible) say that there is no guarantee that he can change Vladimir Putin; Vladimir Putin is Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; Do you come into this with &#8212; like, can you &#8212; can you sort of assess the level of optimism or confidence that anything can be done to change the behavior of this man, given the experience that the President acknowledged in terms of sanctions not really having a real impact on his behavior?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think there are two fundamental elements to how we think about dealing with Russia.&nbsp; One is: Are there areas where, in our common interest, we can work together to produce outcomes that are &#8212; that work for the United States and for the American people?<br>&nbsp;<br>And the other is: How do we send a clear message about those harmful activities that we will not tolerate and to which we will respond?<br>&nbsp;<br>On the second: Of course, we can&#8217;t make guarantees about what Russia will do, but we can make pledges about what America will do, which is we will respond if those harmful activities continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the first: We will see where we get.&nbsp; There&#8217;s the question of strategic stability.&nbsp; There&#8217;s the question of Syria and humanitarian access.&nbsp; There are issues related to the Arctic.&nbsp; There are other places where it would be in our interest to find a basis to work with Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If a country attacks us by cyber, does the United States respond by cyber?&nbsp; Can the United States respond by cyber?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The way that I&#8217;ve consistently characterized our response when it &#8212; when it came to SolarWinds and to other cyberattacks of that scope and scale is that we are prepared to take responsive actions that are seen and unseen, and I&#8217;ll leave it at that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say anything more about U.S-UK travel and whether &#8212; I know that there was a working group on this, but, at the leader level, was there any discussion about opening up?&nbsp; And how soon might we see that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; They did discuss it.&nbsp; You know, the President expressed his deep understanding that the UK would love to have its citizens travel to the U.S. as soon as possible.&nbsp; But he also communicated that this ultimately is a decision for the public health experts to make according to their guidance, and that&#8217;s what the point of getting our experts together is: so that the UK experts can share all the information necessary to help hasten that decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said the U.S. can take actions that are “seen and unseen.”&nbsp; So in reaction to what the FBI has now said was crimes committed by cyber criminals within Russia, has the U.S. taken any unseen actions in that window of time since its response?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to say anything further on that except to point out that we do see a difference between SolarWinds, on the one hand, and ransomware attacks on the other hand.&nbsp; Ultimately, we don&#8217;t judge Russia &#8212; the Russian government &#8212; was responsible for the ransomware attacks, but we have said it is &#8212; it is Russia&#8217;s sovereign obligation to deal with it, and we have communicated that to them.&nbsp; And that is a continuing dialogue between our countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the President said that &#8212; what President Putin said to NBC News, he said that he had no knowledge of these ransomware attacks.&nbsp; Do you take President Putin at his word that he would have no knowledge of this in any form?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t speak to that one way or the other.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was a date set for Angela Merkel&#8217;s visit to the White House then?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do we know what that is?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; July 15.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we announced it.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;All right. &nbsp;It&#8217;s Jerome&#8217;s last trip, so &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right here.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know he’s not the President, but he&#8217;s the National Security Advisor, so we have to celebrate you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Seven years of White House, so, yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Amazing.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well, hopefully, you know, we&#8217;ll end it with &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re thinking of maybe having drinks on Monday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s do it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Monday?&nbsp; That&#8217;s tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; It&#8217;s probably a good time (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Send us the details.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Right, because the very exciting U.S.-EU Summit is the next day &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; which I know all of you guys (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All the more reason to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why we’re doing it Monday.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Anything I can do for you?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, anything on if he&#8217;s inviting the Queen to the White House?&nbsp; It seemed like he invited the Queen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he invite the Queen?&nbsp; Or was he just sort of speaking colloquially?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will have to talk with him about that.&nbsp; That wasn&#8217;t a prior planned offer.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You guys have now had a little bit of time to review the infrastructure package that the Republican &#8212; that the bipartisan group of 10 senators proposed at this point: $1.2 trillion over eight years, I think.&nbsp; Do you have any comments on it right now?&nbsp; Is it sufficient?<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>And what do you say to Democrats who say that you&#8217;re effectively wasting your time by continuing to do this without just pursuing your own policy goals?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I&#8217;ve talked to the President about this.&nbsp; He&#8217;s staying in close touch with his senior team back at the White House.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Before he left, he asked the Jobs Cabinet and members of his senior White House team, including, of course, Ron Klain, but also Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell, and others to stay closely engaged with members as they continue to discuss multiple paths forward and multiple options for getting his ideas passed into law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re still taking a look, still having conversations with these &#8212; the members of this bipartisan group.&nbsp; I would &#8212; on the second part of your question, though, I would say that the way we see it is that we&#8217;re looking to see where we can find common ground on infrastructure and on areas where there&#8217;s overlap and agreement.&nbsp; We are still moving forward with a budget process, which is another path and a simultaneous path to get a range of these ideas passed into law, as well as corporate tax reform.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in response to folks who are saying we&#8217;re delaying, we&#8217;re not.&nbsp; We&#8217;re moving on both tracks at the same time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has he talked to Manchin or Romney specifically about their infrastructure proposal?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has asked his team to stay in close touch with members &#8212; a range of members &#8212; and he has been updated by them at least once a day, sometimes twice, since he started the trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he hasn&#8217;t spoken to them directly yet, that you know of?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has not had those &#8212; he has not had those engagements on the trip.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been &#8212; he&#8217;s been busy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you pull back the curtain a little bit in advance of the Putin summit about how he is being prepared, prepped on this?&nbsp; Obviously, the National Security Advisor has been with him throughout, but, like, how does one prepare for these visits?&nbsp; Obviously, they have interactions in the past.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the First Lady said he was &#8220;overprepared.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Said he was &#8220;overprepared.&#8221;&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Well, what I think she meant by that &#8212; I also know she said &#8212; which I agree with, from having many conversations with him &#8212; is that foreign policy, national security, you know, engaging on the world stage is an area that has been a central focus of his 50 years in public life and public office.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, he, of course, has engaged with President Putin before, as you well know.&nbsp; And, you know, he certainly knows what to expect.&nbsp; His view is that this is not a meeting about trust, it&#8217;s not a meeting about friendship &#8212; it&#8217;s a meeting about figuring out where we can find common ground, and also being straightforward and candid about areas where we have concern.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, really, he has actually been spending some time preparing for each of these rounds of meetings.&nbsp; You know, as we were just talking about the G summit &#8212; the G &#8212; the G7 with Jake, there was a lot that happened during that summit, from COVID, from the cyber ransomware, China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>A lot of the discussions over the &#8212; the majority of the discussions over the last two days, on a staff level, were about the summit and those meetings.&nbsp; And the majority of meetings he&#8217;ll have tonight and tomorrow morning are about NATO.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is a very packed trip.&nbsp; And certainly he&#8217;ll spend time preparing with his team, talking about where there are opportunities to engage on the path forward with President Putin.&nbsp; But I would also just reiterate he&#8217;s been preparing for this moment for 50 years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned about vaccines not reaching 70 percent by July 4th?&nbsp; Does that say anything about divisions in America?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say: Look, at the end of the day, it is &#8212; at this point, what the government can do is we can provide the resources, we can incentivize, we can provide the funding, the vaccine supply, and work with states and localities to do everything we can &#8212; and in the private sector &#8212; to incentivize people to get shots in their arms.&nbsp; It is ultimately up to individuals to do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What you&#8217;ve seen is that a number of states have met and surpassed that goal, right?&nbsp; Many have not yet.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve started &#8212; kicked off this one-month campaign to do everything we can to reach it.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll see where we get.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got some time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, in Israel, the Knesset just approved the new coalition which would end Benjamin Netanyahu&#8217;s 12-year run, I think.&nbsp; Can the White House comment on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will have a statement shortly that should be out to all of you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President spoken to the new prime minister?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;I don&#8217;t believe he has yet, but he will soon.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll get you with the statement and a readout if that happens, whenever that happens.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What’s the President&#8217;s message to the American public about the Delta variant and how concerned they should be?&nbsp; I mean, he tweeted about it the other day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say anything more about, you know, what the administration is doing specifically to address that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, the spread of the Delta variant and the prevalence of it is one of the reasons why we are making clear to people who have not been vaccinated &#8212; specifically people under 40; it&#8217;s a big gap, as you all know, between the percentages of people over 40 versus under &#8212; of what &#8212; how high the risk is from the Delta variant.&nbsp; It spreads, it&#8217;s very transmissible, and this should be another incentive for young people to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we are working to elevate that as a concern because we want people to be aware of the risks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Great.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>8:41 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with Prime Minister Bennett of Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-prime-minister-bennett-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 20:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke today with Prime Minister Bennett to offer his warm congratulations to Prime Minister Bennett on becoming Prime Minister of the State of Israel.&#160; President Biden highlighted his decades of steadfast support for the U.S.-Israel relationship and his unwavering commitment to Israel’s security.&#160; He expressed his firm intent to deepen cooperation between the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke today with Prime Minister Bennett to offer his warm congratulations to Prime Minister Bennett on becoming Prime Minister of the State of Israel.&nbsp; President Biden highlighted his decades of steadfast support for the U.S.-Israel relationship and his unwavering commitment to Israel’s security.&nbsp; He expressed his firm intent to deepen cooperation between the United States and Israel on the many challenges and opportunities facing the region.&nbsp; The leaders agreed that they and their teams would consult closely on all matters related to regional security, including Iran.&nbsp; The President also conveyed that his administration intends to work closely with the Israeli government on efforts to advance peace, security, and prosperity for Israelis and Palestinians.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United States and G7+ Partners Will Provide More than 2 Billion Vaccines for the World</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/fact-sheet-united-states-and-g7-partners-will-provide-more-than-2-billion-vaccines-for-the-world/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 19:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and our G7 Partners are rallying to defeat COVID-19 through historic financing, donations, and capacity building, demonstrating how democracies can provide for our people and the world. This week in Cornwall, the United States and G7+ Leaders announced more than one billion safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines to accelerate global coverage. This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>The United States and our G7 Partners are rallying to defeat COVID-19 through historic financing, donations, and capacity building, demonstrating how democracies can provide for our people and the world.</em></strong></p>



<p>This week in Cornwall, the United States and G7+ Leaders announced more than one billion safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines to accelerate global coverage. This announcement means that since 2020, the G7+ has committed to financing and providing approximately 2.3 billion vaccines for the world. The United States is providing nearly half of that support and is the single largest COVID-19 vaccine donor in the world. This 2.3 billion total includes support for expanding local production capacity around the world to add more than a billion doses to the global vaccine supply by the end of 2022. &nbsp;<br><br><strong>Earlier Financing and Sharing: </strong>G7+ countries have previously committed to finance and share more than 1 billion doses.</p>



<ul><li>Since the inception of COVAX, G7+ countries have previously committed more than <strong><u>1 billion doses</u></strong> through COVAX to date in direct financing and doses.&nbsp;<br></li><li>This includes more than 330 million dose equivalents from the United States in funding for COVAX and at least 80 million U.S. vaccines donated to the world from surplus supply.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Local Vaccine Production Investments: </strong>G7+ investment in local vaccine production capacity will support at least 1 billion vaccine doses by the end of 2022.</p>



<ul><li>Through partnerships like the Quad Vaccine Partnership of the United States, India, Japan, and Australia, the G7+ is committed to expanding local production for at least<strong><u> 1 billion doses</u></strong> of safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines in 2021 and 2022.<br></li><li>The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC) is driving this effort and is also working with peer Development Finance Institutions including the International Finance Corporation, Proparco, and DEG to support vaccine manufacturing in Africa – for Africa.</li></ul>



<p><strong>This week: </strong>The G7+ agreed to provide an additional more than 1 billion doses starting summer 2021.</p>



<ul><li>This week in Cornwall, G7+ Leaders agreed to provide at least <strong><u>1 billion doses</u></strong> of safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines to accelerate global vaccine coverage, particularly for the poorest countries.<br></li><li>The United States announced its commitment to purchase and contribute to Gavi or in support of COVAX <strong>500 million doses</strong> of Pfizer BioNTech COVID-19 vaccine, with delivery beginning in August 2021, as its portion of approximately half of the overall G7+ commitment. The U.S. will allocate these doses to 92 low and lower-middle income nations around the world. <strong>This is the world’s largest-ever purchase and donation of vaccines by a single country.</strong></li></ul>



<p>The United States calls on countries to donate additional doses of safe and effective vaccines, strengthen vaccine readiness, and work with private sector partners to vaccinate the world. In addition to support for the G7+ commitment on vaccines, the United States will continue to share doses from our domestic supply as they become available.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: NATO Summit: Revitalizing the Transatlantic Alliance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/fact-sheet-nato-summit-revitalizing-the-transatlantic-alliance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The transatlantic alliance is the strong foundation on which our collective security and our shared prosperity are built.&#160; The partnership between Europe and the United States, in my view, is and must remain the cornerstone of all that we hope to accomplish in the 21st century, just as we did in the 20th century… The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>“The transatlantic alliance is the strong foundation on which our collective security and our shared prosperity are built.&nbsp; The partnership between Europe and the United States, in my view, is and must remain the cornerstone of all that we hope to accomplish in the 21<sup>st</sup> century, just as we did in the 20<sup>th</sup> century… The United States is fully committed to our NATO Alliance… we’ll keep faith with Article 5.”</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;–<em> President Biden, February 19, 2021</em></p>



<p>President Biden will participate on June 14 in the NATO Summit in Brussels that brings together the leaders of all 30 Allied nations. &nbsp;During the Summit, the President will reaffirm the enduring Transatlantic bond through NATO and underscore the United States’ ironclad commitment to Article 5 – an attack on one is an attack on all and will be met with a collective response.&nbsp; Allied leaders will launch an ambitious set of initiatives to ensure NATO continues to provide security to our citizens through 2030 and beyond.</p>



<p>The Transatlantic relationship is built on a foundation of shared democratic values.&nbsp; NATO’s strength comes not only from its military might, but also its unity and common purpose founded on respect for democracy, individual liberty, and the rule of law, as enshrined in the Washington Treaty.&nbsp; Now in its 73rd year, NATO is the most powerful and successful Alliance in history.&nbsp; NATO faced down the Communist bloc in the Cold War and today provides security for approximately one billion people in Europe and North America.&nbsp; As NATO winds down its military presence in Afghanistan after nearly 20 years, the United States and our NATO Allies and partners will continue supporting the people of Afghanistan through civilian and security assistance.&nbsp; The United States will also continue to stand shoulder to shoulder with our Allies and partners in NATO’s non-combat advisory mission in Iraq.</p>



<p>NATO played a pivotal role in coordinating the civilian response to COVID-19, airlifting hundreds of tons of critical supplies around the world and building almost 100 field hospitals, while maintaining its deterrence and defense posture.&nbsp; This assistance is saving lives and proves that defense investment and capacity building increase our nations’ resilience in the face of all kinds of crises, not only against military threats.</p>



<p><strong><u>Key Summit Outcomes</u></strong>:</p>



<p><strong>A New Strategic Concept</strong>:&nbsp; Allies will agree to revise NATO’s Strategic Concept, a framework that will guide the Alliance’s approach to the evolving strategic environment, which includes Russia’s aggressive policies and actions; challenges posed by the People’s Republic of China to our collective security, prosperity, and values; and transnational threats such as terrorism, cyber threats, and climate change. &nbsp;The new Strategic Concept will be prepared for adoption at the NATO Summit in 2022.</p>



<p><strong>Updating Cyber Defenses</strong>: Leaders will endorse a new Cyber Defense Policy for NATO that will strengthen Allied coordination to ensure the Alliance is resilient against the increasingly frequent and severe threats we face from malicious cyber activity perpetrated by state and non-state actors, including disruptive ransomware attacks against critical infrastructure.&nbsp; This updated policy will also provide strategic guidance for NATO’s political, military, and technical cyber efforts to deter, defend against, and counter the full spectrum of cyber threats.&nbsp; Leaders will also affirm the importance of defending our networks and ensuring Allies rely on trustworthy providers for next generation telecommunication networks.</p>



<p><strong>Preserving our Technological Edge</strong>:&nbsp; Leaders will affirm that NATO’s ability to ensure our common defense relies on maintaining our technological edge. &nbsp;Allies will launch a Defense Innovation Accelerator to facilitate their technological cooperation and speed the adoption of emerging technologies that will enhance the Alliance’s defense and security.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Combatting Climate Change</strong>:&nbsp; Leaders will agree to a Climate Security Action Plan and set the ambition for NATO to become the leading international organization for understanding and adapting to the impact of climate change on security. &nbsp;They will agree to reduce greenhouse gases from military activities and installations in line with national commitments under the Paris Agreement, and agree to initiate a regular high-level global climate and security dialogue.</p>



<p><strong>Strengthened Deterrence and Defense</strong>:&nbsp; Allies will commit to implementation of new military concepts and strategies that strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense posture to meet threats from Russia and elsewhere.&nbsp; NATO also continues to monitor the Russian deployments in and around Ukraine.</p>



<p><strong>Greater Sharing of Responsibility</strong>:  Non-U.S. defense spending has risen for seven consecutive years since the Wales Defense Investment Pledge adopted during the Obama-Biden Administration in 2014.  Allied leaders will recommit to the Wales Pledge in its entirety and to providing NATO with cash, capabilities, and contributions of ready forces.</p>



<p><strong>Investing in NATO:</strong>&nbsp; Allies will also commit to ensuring NATO is led, staffed, and resourced at levels necessary to deliver on the decisions taken at the Summit.&nbsp; Leaders will agree to identify the additional resources, including through NATO common funding, to enhance NATO’s ability to meet security challenges today and in the future.</p>



<p><strong>Increased Consultation and Cohesion</strong>:&nbsp; Allies will commit to enhance political coordination at NATO on all matters related to their individual and collective security.&nbsp; Leaders will also reaffirm their commitment to their common values, including individual liberty, human rights, democracy, and the rule of law.</p>



<p><strong>Stronger Societies</strong>:&nbsp; Recognizing the increasingly complex threats to our security, Allied leaders will affirm that national and collective resilience are essential for credible deterrence and defense, and vital to safeguard our societies, citizens, and shared values.&nbsp; Allied leaders will issue a Strengthened Resilience Commitment to outline future priorities, including on the security of supply chains, critical infrastructure, and energy networks, as well as preparedness for pandemics and natural disasters.</p>



<p><strong>Deeper Partnerships</strong>:&nbsp; Allies will enhance NATO’s ability to strengthen the rules-based international order by increasing dialogue and practical cooperation with the Alliance’s partners, including the European Union and those in the Indo-Pacific (Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the Republic of Korea).&nbsp; Leaders will recommit to NATO’s Open Door Policy, which provides a path to membership for any European country that shares our values and meets the necessary responsibilities and obligations.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
