<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 16:38:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Equality Act Will Provide Long Overdue Civil Rights Protections for Millions of Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/fact-sheet-the-equality-act-will-provide-long-overdue-civil-rights-protections-for-millions-of-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Freedom and equality are fundamental American values. But today, millions of Americans lack basic non-discrimination protections just because of who they are or whom they love. President Biden believes that every American must be able to live freely, openly, and safely. That’s why he continues to call on the Senate to swiftly pass the Equality&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Freedom and equality are fundamental American values. But today, millions of Americans lack basic non-discrimination protections just because of who they are or whom they love. President Biden believes that every American must be able to live freely, openly, and safely. That’s why he continues to call on the Senate to swiftly pass the Equality Act, legislation which will provide long overdue federal civil rights protections to LGBTQ+ Americans and their families, while strengthening some key civil rights laws for people of color, women, people with disabilities, and people of faith.</p>



<p><strong>Despite the progress our Nation has made towards full equality, LGBTQ+ Americans still lack full non-discrimination protections in 29 states. </strong>In the absence of a Federal non-discrimination law, more than half of all U.S. states lack laws on the book prohibiting discrimination against LGBTQ+ individuals and families. The lack of federal non-discrimination protections for LGBTQ+ people means that millions of Americans can be denied housing, education, credit and more just because of who they are or whom they love. In states across the country, LGBTQ+ Americans can get married on Sunday, and denied a rental lease on Monday.<br><br><strong>The Equality Act will provide long overdue civil rights protections on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity – ensuring LGBTQ+ Americans are finally afforded equal protection under law. </strong>The Equality Act amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to provide explicit non-discrimination protections on the basis of sex, sexual orientation, and gender identity. The bill builds on the Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>Bostock v. Clayton County </em>by making explicit that non-discrimination protections for LGBTQ+ people in employment settings apply to other areas of life.</p>



<p><strong>The Equality Act will help protect LGBTQ+ Americans who continue to report facing discrimination. </strong><a href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/press-releases/poll-lgbtq-americans-discrimination/">Studies</a> show that majority of LGBTQ+ Americans say they have personally experienced discrimination because of their sexual orientation or gender identity. Transgender Americans, especially transgender women of color, continue to face rampant discrimination in housing, employment, and in public. These types of discrimination cause LGBTQ+ Americans to face higher rates of poverty, violence, and unemployment than other Americans.</p>



<p><strong>Discrimination isn’t just wrong. It also is detrimental to the physical health and safety of LGBTQ+ Americans, especially transgender women of color.</strong>&nbsp;LGBTQ+ Americans still face discrimination when seeking medical care or visiting a doctor. In surveys, nearly 29% of transgender people in the United States say they’ve been refused medical care because of their identity, which can lead to avoidance of medical care. &nbsp;That is why the Department of Health and Human Services <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/05/10/hhs-announces-prohibition-sex-discrimination-includes-discrimination-basis-sexual-orientation-gender-identity.html">announced</a> that it is taking steps to address and prevent discrimination against LGBTQ+ Americans in healthcare settings, but Federal legislation is needed to codify these protections. Discrimination also leads to violence. Transgender women of color face epidemic levels of violence. Too often, this violence stems from institutional discrimination in healthcare settings, housing, and employment.</p>



<p><strong>Anti-LGBTQ+ discrimination also contributes to mental health inequities faced by LGBTQ+ youth. </strong><a href="https://www.thetrevorproject.org/survey-2021/?section=Introduction">75 percent</a> of LGBTQ+ youth say they’ve experienced discrimination because of their sexual orientation or gender identity. Discrimination and bullying are detrimental to the mental health of any young person, and more than half of all transgender and non-binary youth say they have seriously considered commitment suicide in the past year. To address bullying and discrimination at school, the Department of Education has <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-confirms-title-ix-protects-students-discrimination-based-sexual-orientation-and-gender-identity">announced</a> that it is taking steps to expand protections for LGBTQ+ students in our Nation’s schools, but Federal legislation is needed to codify these protections.</p>



<p><strong>The Equality Act will also expand public accommodations protections for people of color, women, and people of faith. </strong>The Equality Act would also strengthen civil rights protections for other protected groups, including people of color, women, people with disabilities, and people of faith by expanding where non-discrimination protections apply to public accommodations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with Senator Sinema</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-senator-sinema/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 16:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President spoke to Senator Sinema today to thank her again for her work on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Agreement. He reiterated his strong support for the compromise agreement, and they discussed his plan to try to build support for the Agreement among both Democrats and Republicans. The President also reiterated that he would fight to pass&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President spoke to Senator Sinema today to thank her again for her work on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Agreement. He reiterated his strong support for the compromise agreement, and they discussed his plan to try to build support for the Agreement among both Democrats and Republicans. The President also reiterated that he would fight to pass the Bipartisan Agreement, as he committed to the group. The President reiterated strong support for both the Bipartisan Infrastructure bill and a reconciliation bill containing the American Families Plan moving forward on a two-track system, as he said yesterday when meeting the press with the bipartisan group of ten Senators. These are two critical priorities to the President that he wants to see advance through the legislative process as quickly as possible, pass as quickly as possible, and be presented to him for signing as quickly as possible. The President looks forward to signing both these bills.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/president-biden-announces-u-s-special-envoy-to-advance-the-human-rights-of-lgbtqi-persons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, ahead of his remarks at the White House for Pride Month, President Joe Biden announced that he will appoint Jessica Stern to be the U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons at the Department of State – a role critical to ensuring that U.S. diplomacy and foreign assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, ahead of his remarks at the White House for Pride Month, President Joe Biden announced that he will appoint Jessica Stern to be the U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons at the Department of State – a role critical to ensuring that U.S. diplomacy and foreign assistance promote and protect the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons around the world. The Special Envoy will play a vital role in leading implementation of the Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World. At a time when the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons are increasingly threatened in all regions of the world, the Special Envoy will bring together like-minded governments, civil society organizations, corporations and international organizations to uphold &nbsp;dignity and equality for all. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Jessica Stern, United States Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons, Department of State</u></strong></p>



<p>Jessica Stern, Executive Director of OutRight Action International, is based in New York. Jessica specializes in gender, sexuality and human rights globally. At OutRight, she has supported the legal registration of LGBTIQ organizations globally, helped secure the mandate of the United Nations Independent Expert on Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity, expanded the UN General Assembly resolution to include gender identity, and co-founded the UN LGBTI Core Group. She has provided expert opinions to governments globally, regional human rights institutions, and UN mechanisms, including UN Women where she serves as a member of multiple leadership bodies. Her writing has been cited by the Indian Supreme Court in its seminal judgment decriminalizing same-sex relations and been featured in The Oxford Handbook of Women, Peace and Security (2019). She is frequently quoted by the media, including by The New York Times, Al Jazeera, The Washington Post, BBC News, and The Guardian. She is an adjunct associate professor at Columbia University’s School of International &amp; Public Affairs.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Florida Emergency Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-florida-emergency-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 04:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that an emergency exists in the State of Florida and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State and local response efforts due to the emergency conditions resulting from the Surfside Building Collapse beginning on June 24, 2021, and continuing. The President&#8217;s action authorizes the Department of Homeland Security, Federal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that an emergency exists in the State of Florida and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State and local response efforts due to the emergency conditions resulting from the Surfside Building Collapse beginning on June 24, 2021, and continuing.</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s action authorizes the Department of Homeland Security, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to coordinate all disaster relief efforts which have the purpose of alleviating the hardship and suffering caused by the emergency on the local population, and to provide appropriate assistance for required emergency measures, authorized under Title V of the Stafford Act, to save lives and to protect property and public health and safety, and to lessen or avert the threat of a catastrophe in Miami-Dade County.</p>



<p>Specifically, FEMA is authorized to identify, mobilize, and provide at its discretion, equipment and resources necessary to alleviate the impacts of the emergency.&nbsp; The Individuals and Households Program under Section 408 of the Stafford Act and assistance for debris removal and emergency protective measures, including direct federal assistance, will be provided.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Thomas J. McCool as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Highlighting the Importance of Getting Vaccinated and Kicking Off a Community Canvassing Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/24/remarks-by-president-biden-highlighting-the-importance-of-getting-vaccinated-and-kicking-off-a-community-canvassing-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 03:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22019</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Green Road Community CenterRaleigh, North Carolina 5:33 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, Raleigh.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; I &#8212; I&#8217;m going to &#8212; AUDIENCE MEMBER:&#160; (Inaudible.)&#160; (Laughter.) AUDIENCE MEMBER:&#160; We love you!&#160; (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Love you back.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Well, look, that old &#8212; I &#8212; you&#8217;re &#8212; by the way, you&#8217;re in the midst of the &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Green Road Community Center<br>Raleigh, North Carolina</p>



<p>5:33 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, Raleigh.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;m going to &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We love you!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Love you back.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Well, look, that old &#8212; I &#8212; you&#8217;re &#8212; by the way, you&#8217;re in the midst of the &#8212; you&#8217;re in the presence of a &#8212; one hell of an individual.&nbsp; I want you all to know about.&nbsp; Not me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; He&#8217;s always there when people need help, and he particularly focuses on people who are left behind: Reverend Barber.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thanks for all you do, Rev.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ive, I thank you for that introduction, you know, and for everything you&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>You know, I &#8212; I think &#8212; I thank you everyone here at the Green Road Community Center for hosting us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Governor Cooper, my good friend.&nbsp; A great governor.&nbsp; But the most important thing: He&#8217;s a man of enormous integrity, and &#8212; no, he really is.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You&#8217;re doing an incredible job; I&#8217;m lucky to have you as a partner, Gov.&nbsp; And as we &#8212; as we move along here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, you know, the main thing I want to do is start off with the way you should never start off.</p>



<p>Are they &#8212; do you have chairs out there?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, if you have a chair, sit.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t stand for me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I was getting the &#8212; I was getting to feel really guilty, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I said that a while ago, as the press will tell you. &nbsp;About a year ago, I said, &#8220;Why don&#8217;t everybody sit down?&#8221;&nbsp; And somebody in the front said, &#8220;I don&#8217;t have a damn seat.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I want to get in trouble.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; I thought you didn&#8217;t have any seats there.&nbsp; I was going to really feel guilty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, look, it&#8217;s great to be Mayor Baldwin of Raleigh and Mayor &#8212; Mayor Schewel of Durham.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And joined by a proud native son of North Carolina: the Administrator of the EPA in Washington, D.C., Michael Regan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Where are you, Michael?&nbsp; I&#8217;m always worried &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I&#8217;m always worried when I come back to North Carolina and Michael is with me that the governor is going to take him back.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I need him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, folks, he&#8217;s doing one heck of a job at EPA.&nbsp; And if you want to talk about health, think about the environment.&nbsp; Think about what&#8217;s happen &#8212; being done &#8212; what we&#8217;re changing at EPA.&nbsp; And the &#8212; it makes a big deal.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s also &#8212; it&#8217;s also out there, across the state, encouraging people to get vaccinated as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wanted to come to Raleigh to thank everyone in this room for everything you&#8217;re doing to get your community vaccinated.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; You&#8217;re saving lives.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me remind everybody: We lost 600,000 dead in America in about a year.&nbsp; That&#8217;s more than every life lost in World War One, World War Two, the Vietnam War, Iraq, Iran, across the board &#8212; Afghanistan.&nbsp; More lives lost in a year than every major war in the 20th century and the 21st century.&nbsp; And guess what, folks?&nbsp; There&#8217;ve been lives lost all around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, America, I might say &#8212; this is not &#8212; I didn&#8217;t plan on saying this, but I&#8217;m going anyway: We have an obligation in the United States of America to live up to who we are.&nbsp; America is the only &#8212; is a unique nation.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the only nation formed based on an idea &#8212; an idea, not an ethnicity, not an ideology, not a &#8212; idea: We hold these truths to be self-evident that all men and women are created equal, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, here&#8217;s the deal.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s the deal.&nbsp; There are over 100 countries in the world that have no capacity to help themselves right now.&nbsp; None.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why &#8212; I got somewhat criticized, but that&#8217;s why I&#8217;ve worked so darn hard &#8212; after being able to nail down, in the first 100 days, over 60 [600] million doses of vaccine for Americans, I went to Europe to meet what they call the &#8220;G7&#8221; and then with NATO and then with the EU.&nbsp; And I promised that the United States, in the remainder of this year and the first half of next year, is going to provide a billion doses to the rest of the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; A billion doses.</p>



<p>Half a billion of those will be done between now and January and the first half of next year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The point being: I wanted the nation to reflect what you all reflect.&nbsp; Everyone in this room, there&#8217;s everything &#8212; you &#8212; I want to thank you for all you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; But the rest of the world is in trouble as well.&nbsp; We have to look out for one another.&nbsp; We really do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what you&#8217;re doing here &#8212; going back to the United States &#8212; nonprofits directing folks to where to go; houses of worship opening on-site vaccination for congregants; my friend Reverend Barber is here, as I said, and countless faith leaders who are truly doing God&#8217;s work; college students providing rides for seniors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what&#8217;s happening in America is what America is all about.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the rest of world is looking at: Are we what we advertise ourselves to be?&nbsp; It&#8217;s because of people like you, here in Raleigh and in communities across America, that we&#8217;re going to win this fight.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look at the progress we made so far.&nbsp; Today, 66 percent of all American adults have gotten at least one shot.&nbsp; That includes 87 percent of all seniors of all colors; 75 percent of adults ages 40 and up have gotten a shot; and 70 percent of those age 30 and up.</p>



<p>Nationwide, we’re seeing the lowest number of daily cases and deaths since the first day of the pandemic.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve built equity into the heart of the vaccination program.&nbsp; I put together a vaccination team, headed by a really bright guy, and we put together a group of 23 doctors.&nbsp; And what they did was we had one doc who does nothing but deal with equity &#8212; access for people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a reason why it&#8217;s been harder to get African Americans, initially, to get vaccinated: because they&#8217;re used to be experimented on &#8212; the Tuskegee Airmen and others.&nbsp; People have memories.&nbsp; People have long memories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s awful hard, as well, to get Latinx vaccinated as well.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; They&#8217;re worried that they&#8217;ll be vaccinated and deported.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, from day one, something that Governor Cooper has been totally focused on is making sure we get as many people vaccinated, particularly people who don&#8217;t have access to healthcare usually; who don&#8217;t have ordinary &#8212; don&#8217;t have doctors or family physicians, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Seventy three percent of the shots administered at community health centers through the federal program we have and more than 58 percent of the shots administered in federally-run vaccination sites have gone to people of color.&nbsp; It makes a gigantic difference.</p>



<p>And across the nation, people of color have accounted for more than half of all the vaccinations in the last month.&nbsp; The more we close the racial gap in vaccination rates, the more lives we can save.&nbsp; And if I can &#8212; (applause).&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if I can pause for one second: That’s why I’ve called for spending billions of dollars at NIH focusing on new ways to deal with obesity, diabetes, Alzheimers, and cancer.&nbsp; Focused just on those diseases &#8212; money that private drug companies don’t have the money to invest in or the inclination to.&nbsp; Because guess what?&nbsp; In most Black communities across America and Hispanic communities, how many stores have fresh vegetables?&nbsp; How many stores have a &#8212; I’ll go down the list.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; The health condition a person enters this fight over makes a big difference as to what, in fact, is going to be able to be done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here in North Carolina, my administration provided $105 million from the emergency man- &#8212; Federal Emergency Management Agency &#8212; FEMA &#8212; to help get people vaccinated.&nbsp; Working with the governor and the mayors and county officials across the state, there are 240 personnel in the Tar Heel State just to put the needle in somebody’s arm.</p>



<p>This has been a gigantic &#8212; a gigantic logistical challenge not just in North Carolina, but all across America.&nbsp; More than 660 National Guard members have supported the COVID-19 response here in North Carolina.&nbsp; Over in Greensboro, we stood up the federal vaccination site that alone has administered 135,000 shots.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The governor and I visited one of the mobile units you’re deploying to meet people where they live.&nbsp; And as a result of these efforts statewide, case deaths are down over 90 percent in the last five months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of this is great news.&nbsp; But here’s the deal: For all the progress we’ve made as a country, hospitalizations and deaths are down drastically in places where people are getting vaccinated.&nbsp; The data couldn’t be clearer: If you’re vaccinated &#8212; if you’re vaccinated, you’re safe.&nbsp; You are still at risk of getting seriously ill or dying if you, in fact, have not been vaccinated.&nbsp; That’s just a fact.</p>



<p>And this new, dangerous variant that continues to emerge &#8212; it’s now the most common variant in America and here.&nbsp; And unvaccinated people are incredibly vulnerable.&nbsp; This is a serious concern with what experts call the “Delta” variant.&nbsp; It is not only &#8212; according to the CDC, between 10 to 20 percent of all cases in the last two weeks have been the Delta variant.</p>



<p>Dr. Fauci has made it clear &#8212; he and my wife have been traveling the country to make this case &#8212; that it’s more easily transmittable, this Delta variant, potentially deadlier, and especially dangerous for young people &#8212; for young people.&nbsp; He says its the greatest threat to our fight to beat COVID-19.</p>



<p>But the good news is, we have a solution.&nbsp; The science is clear.&nbsp; The best way to protect yourself against the virus and its variants is to be fully vaccinated.&nbsp; It works.&nbsp; It’s free.&nbsp; It’s safe.&nbsp; It’s easy.&nbsp; It’s convenient.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over 150 million Americans have gotten fully vaccinated and they’re safe and protected now, including against the Delta variant.&nbsp; They’re getting back to living their lives and spending time with their loved ones.&nbsp; But we need more people to get fully vaccinated to finish the job.&nbsp; That’s why I’m here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I called for June to be the “Month of Action” to get folks vaccinated so we can all enjoy a Fourth of July with our independence from the virus &#8212; from the virus.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’re already vaccinated, make sure your family and friends are vaccinated.&nbsp; Help them make a plan to get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’ve gotten your first shot, make sure you get your second one to be fully protected.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s a big deal.</p>



<p>And if you’re not vaccinated, don’t put it off any longer. Just do it.&nbsp; Just do it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it’s never been easier.&nbsp; It&#8217;s never been easier to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Text your Zip Code to 438829 &#8212; 438829.&nbsp; And, immediately, it will pop to find the vaccination sites closest to you.&nbsp; And hardly anyone is beyond five miles from a potential site.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Get a free ride to and from your vaccination sites.&nbsp; I want to publicly thank &#8212; when I asked for help, both Lyft or Uber said between the time &#8212; this last month to July 4th, they’ll provide a ride free to and from.&nbsp; They’ll wait and take you back home.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Thousands of pharmacies are offering no-appointment, walk-in vaccinations.&nbsp; More than 1,400 pharmacies are in North Carolina that do that.&nbsp; They’ve already administered over 2.2 million shots &#8212; these pharmacies.&nbsp; Many of them are open 24 hours on Fridays.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, go tomorrow if you’ve not gotten it done.&nbsp; Or when you’re going out, knocking on doors, tell them, “Tomorrow, 24 hours, a majority of these drugstores are open.”&nbsp; Get it done.&nbsp; Get it done.&nbsp; And they get it done at their convenience.</p>



<p>And if you still have questions, that’s okay.&nbsp; Talk to people who you know who have gotten the shot.&nbsp; That’s what you guys are out there &#8212; going to be doing, knocking on doors.&nbsp; Talk to your doctor or your health provider.&nbsp; If you don’t have one, physicians know it’s the right choice to get vaccinated to protect themselves, their patients, and their communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And listen to North Carolina’s own Dr. Kizzy Corbett, you know, from Hurdle Mills, just about an hour north from here.&nbsp; She’s a scientist at NIH that I met several weeks ago who helped develop the COVID-19 vaccine &#8212; (applause) &#8212; a vaccine that was developed after decades of research under Republican and Democratic administrations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I said, I met her earlier this year during a tour of the NIH Vaccine Research Center where this all happened.&nbsp; She’s incredible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, there is no reason to leave yourself vulnerable to the deadly virus for one single day more.&nbsp; And as they say in my church, I’m preaching to the choir, I know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But the television is recording this.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Make the case.&nbsp; Let people know getting vaccinated is not only maybe going to save their lives, but save their mother, their father, their child, their son, their daughter, their coworker.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, please, please get vaccinated.&nbsp; And let’s everyone do our part.&nbsp; Let’s everyone do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This weekend, we will be hosting another nationwide canvassing event where volunteers like you are going to knock on doors and talk to their friends and neighbors and help finish the job of getting America vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This weekend, we&#8217;ll be hosting another nationwide canvassing event where volunteers like you are going to knock on doors and talk to friends and neighbors to help finish the job of getting America vaccinated.</p>



<p>To join that effort, I say to the people watching this &#8211;because these people have already joined the effort: To join that effort, please visit WeCanDoThis.HHS.governor [sic] &#8212; .gov, excuse me &#8212; WeCanDoThis.HHS.gov.&nbsp; Sign up.&nbsp; Get involved.</p>



<p>We can do this.&nbsp; We really can do this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me close where I began.&nbsp; To all of you here today who are about to head out and canvass your communities: Thank you from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; I genuinely mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But just listen, again, to Ive &#8212; graduated from Apex Friendship High, just finished her first year in school.&nbsp; She&#8217;s been spending her summer doing door-to-door &#8212; going door to help get people vaccinated to stay safe.</p>



<p>And I’ll bet what she had to say, when asked, is what a lot of you think as well.&nbsp; She said, quote &#8212; I hope you don’t mind my repeating this, Ive &#8212; but she said, quote, “Reaching out and giving back to the community is everything.&nbsp; I like to say…I don&#8217;t dream of having a dream job or a dream career, but I dream of truly helping people in the best way I can…that&#8217;s my life goal.”</p>



<p>This can be among one of the most important things you do. I really mean it.&nbsp; And again, remember &#8212; I think you&#8217;re probably the least ones that have to remember &#8212; remember: 600,000-plus Americans have died.&nbsp; Six hundred thousand-plus Americans have died.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Delta variant &#8212; you know there&#8217;s going to be others as well.&nbsp; You know what&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to get our young people vaccinated. &nbsp;</p>



<p>So, talk to those moms when you knock on the door.&nbsp; Tell them about &#8212; tell them about why it&#8217;s so important to get their children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You may remember, I got widely criticized when I suggested we keep dropping the age of people eligible for vaccinations.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been based on the science.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t do anything based on a whim.&nbsp; The science, the tests show that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what&#8217;s going to happen here, I predict, as soon as we go from temporary approval to permanent approval &#8212; which just takes time; it&#8217;s not that its (inaudible) is there &#8212; it&#8217;s going to increase the number of people willing to move as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Ive, thank you for representing the best of us.&nbsp; Thank all of you for representing the best of us.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve all got the whole world in front of you.&nbsp; And, you know, it&#8217;s because of &#8212; it&#8217;s because of people like Ive and all of you why I have so much faith in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not being &#8212; you know, if you notice, I&#8217;ve been unfairly criticized for being optimistic.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been fairly criticized because I think we can actually pull people together.&nbsp; I ran &#8212; when I ran for President, I ran for three reasons.&nbsp; I said, one, is restore the soul of America &#8212; just basic decency, looking out for one another.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, two, because we had to rebuild the backbone of this country that had been so damaged, which is the middle class &#8212; (applause) &#8212; working-class folks and middle-class folks.&nbsp; It was about time to build the economy from the middle up and out and from the middle class up.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we have to do.</p>



<p>Folks, let&#8217;s really let this be the summer of joy and freedom.&nbsp; Let it really happen.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s celebrate the Fourth of July with the independence from the virus.&nbsp; We can get this done.&nbsp; We &#8212; no, we really can get this done, and we really can do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you know what?&nbsp; I said the third reason I was running was to unify the country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Well, folks, it&#8217;s never been as divided as it is today &#8212; never been as divided as it is today, since the Civil War.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, it’s such a waste of talent, such a waste of time.&nbsp; And the rest of the world is looking at us.&nbsp; The rest of the world is wondering whether or not can we really lead the world again.&nbsp; The last four years have been devastating to our leadership around the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m not making &#8212; but it’s true.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the way we lead: Like you always lead &#8212; those who lead better than I and others &#8212; you lead by example, and the example is twofold.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll end with this.&nbsp; One is making sure we do everything in our power to walk that extra mile, to knock on that door, to pick up the phone, to actually pull up in your own vehicle and take someone who needs to get to a vaccination site.&nbsp; Convince them.&nbsp; Let them know why it&#8217;s so important.&nbsp; Let them know.&nbsp; Because people &#8212; people respond to individual relationships, even new ones.&nbsp; “I got it.&nbsp; My brother got it.&nbsp; My sister got it.&nbsp; I took my daughter, and she got it,” et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And secondly, let the world know that when it comes down to lifesaving initiatives, no matter where they are &#8212; but they come from us &#8212; we should share them with the world &#8212; the whole world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re even giving some of these vaccines to nations that are not our friends because the people are not the ones who are not our friends &#8212; the leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, folks, there&#8217;s a lot we can do.&nbsp; As I said, I have faith in your generation.&nbsp; The reason I&#8217;m so optimistic is because you&#8217;re the most incredible generation in American history.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not being solicitous.&nbsp; Number one, you&#8217;re the least prejudiced generation in history, number one.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Number two, you volunteer than most &#8212; any other generation, including my vaulted generation of the ’60s.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You &#8212; no, I mean it.&nbsp; We are proud of what we did, but you volunteer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number three, you&#8217;re the best-educated generation in the history of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I believe our dealing with equity is only the beginning as it relates to vaccine.&nbsp; The first executive order I signed was insisting that every one of my Cabinet members focus on racial equity &#8212; (applause) &#8212; because we have a &#8212; we have a chance &#8212; we have a chance to make significant change in this country, and it&#8217;s going to come from what you guys do.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t thank you enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sorry to take so much of your time, but God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>5:57 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden After Meeting with a Bipartisan Group of Senators on Infrastructure Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/24/remarks-by-president-biden-after-meeting-with-a-bipartisan-group-of-senators-on-infrastructure-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Stakeout Location THE PRESIDENT:&#160; We had a really good meeting.&#160; And to answer your direct question, we have a deal.&#160; And I think it&#8217;s really important &#8212; we&#8217;ve all agreed &#8212; that none of us got what we &#8212; all that we wanted.&#160; I clearly didn&#8217;t get all I wanted.&#160; They gave more than, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Stakeout Location</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We had a really good meeting.&nbsp; And to answer your direct question, we have a deal.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s really important &#8212; we&#8217;ve all agreed &#8212; that none of us got what we &#8212; all that we wanted.&nbsp; I clearly didn&#8217;t get all I wanted.&nbsp; They gave more than, I think, maybe they were inclined to give in the first place.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this reminds me of the days we used to get an awful lot done up at the United States Congress.&nbsp; We actually worked with one &#8212; we had bipartisan deals.&nbsp; Bipartisan deals means compromise.<br>&nbsp;<br>One of the things that I&#8217;ve &#8212; I&#8217;ve made clear: I&#8217;ve signed on &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to let them give you the detail because &#8212; and you can ask them &#8212; and I&#8217;m &#8212; I will &#8212; I will talk to you all later, in the next hour or two.&nbsp; What- &#8212; I promise you I&#8217;m not going away.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But one of the things that we agreed on: infrastructure.&nbsp; We made serious compromises on both ends.&nbsp; There is &#8212; and they&#8217;ll &#8212; they&#8217;ll give you the numbers.&nbsp; But we did not &#8212; they did not &#8212; and I understand their position &#8212; Republicans and this group did not want to go along with my &#8212; any of my Family Plan issues &#8212; the childcare tax credits, the human infrastructure that I talk about.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that &#8212; we&#8217;ll see what happens in the reconciliation bill and the budget process &#8212; if that &#8212; if we get some compromise there.&nbsp; And if we can&#8217;t, see if I can attract all the Democrats to a position that is there.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to &#8212; they&#8217;re going to move on a dual track.&nbsp; And &#8212; and that&#8217;s all I&#8217;ll say.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I want to thank each and every one of them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been &#8212; you know, a lot of us go back a long way, where we&#8217;re used to doing one thing: Give each other our word and that&#8217;s the end.&nbsp; Nobody questions it.&nbsp; They have my word, I&#8217;ll stick with what they proposed, and they&#8217;ve given me their word as well. So, where I come from, that&#8217;s good enough for me.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m going to turn it over to the two Chairs here.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll talk to you all a little bit later.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you been briefed about the building collapse in Miami?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I have.&nbsp; I spoke with the mayor.&nbsp; I spoke with the congresswoman.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll have more to say about that as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you committed to the two-track system, Mr. President?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Pardon me?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you committed to the two-track system?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That is &#8212; there is going to be a two-track system.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And are you confident that you&#8217;re going to have all of the Democrats support it in the Senate?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let them talk to you. Okay?&nbsp; I&#8217;m not confident in anything except I trust their word.<br>&nbsp;<br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the Passing of Former President Benigno Aquino III of the Philippines</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-former-president-benigno-aquino-iii-of-the-philippines/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I extend my deepest condolences to the people of the Philippines on the death of former President Benigno “Noynoy” Aquino III. He was a valued friend and partner to the United States, and he will long be remembered for serving his country with integrity and selfless dedication. President Aquino’s steadfast commitment to advancing peace, upholding&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I extend my deepest condolences to the people of the Philippines on the death of former President Benigno “Noynoy” Aquino III. He was a valued friend and partner to the United States, and he will long be remembered for serving his country with integrity and selfless dedication. President Aquino’s steadfast commitment to advancing peace, upholding the rule of law, and driving economic growth for all Filipinos, while taking bold steps to promote the rules-based international order, leaves a remarkable legacy at home and abroad that will endure for years to come. I greatly valued our time working together, and I extend my heartfelt sympathies to his family and to all who will mourn his absence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on Police Reform Negotiations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-police-reform-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is grateful to Rep. Bass, Sen. Booker, and Sen. Scott for all of their hard work on police reform, and he looks forward to collaborating with them on the path ahead. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is grateful to Rep. Bass, Sen. Booker, and Sen. Scott for all of their hard work on police reform, and he looks forward to collaborating with them on the path ahead.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre Aboard Air Force One En Route Raleigh, North Carolina</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/24/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-raleigh-north-carolina/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Raleigh, NC 3:29 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Today, President Biden is traveling to Raleigh, North Carolina, where he will visit a mobile vaccination bus and highlight the ease of getting vaccinated, encourage vaccinations, and mobilize grassroots vaccine education and outreach efforts. The President isn’t the only one out today getting the word&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Raleigh, NC</p>



<p>3:29 P.M. EDT<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Today, President Biden is traveling to Raleigh, North Carolina, where he will visit a mobile vaccination bus and highlight the ease of getting vaccinated, encourage vaccinations, and mobilize grassroots vaccine education and outreach efforts.<br> <br>The President isn’t the only one out today getting the word out about local efforts to vaccinate more Americans today.  The Second Gentleman and Dr. Murthy are hosting a press call to highlight new ways the administration is encouraging young people to get vaccinated, including new efforts from the private sector targeting young people.<br> <br>The First Lady and Dr. Fauci are in Florida today visiting an innovative vaccine sites, including in a drive-through site and one at a hockey arena that are getting Floridians vaccinated. <br> <br>And the Vice President is meeting virtually with local community groups and members that are doing the grassroots work to encourage vaccinations across the country.<br> <br>In his remarks, the President will highlight some of the incredible work North Carolinians are doing to get their community members vaccinated, Governor Cooper’s commitment to center equity in his COVID response, and also his administration’s work to get North Carolinians vaccinated.<br> <br>The President will also remind Americans about the growing threat of the Delta variant and that the vaccines are effective against the variants. <br> <br>Okay.  Zeke, you want to &#8212; you want to kick us off?<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Karine.  First, just following up on the President’s remarks a few minutes ago: Could you clarify what the President said what &#8212; that the &#8212; the bipartisan package had to move “in tandem” with the Democrats-only package?  Is the President saying he will not, under any circumstances, sign this bipartisan agreement unless Democrat &#8212; the Democrats’ unilateral package also passes?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Well, let me just first say that the American people wanted to see a compromise.  They wanted to see a government that works for the people.  And that is what we saw today.  That’s what the President did.  And compromising means giving in some places, but also finding common ground. <br> <br>Ultimately, this does not have a gas tax in it.  It doesn’t have an electric vehicle tax.  It does not raise taxes of Americans who make more than &#8212; who make less than $400,000.  And this is a big win. <br> <br>And so, the way that the President sees this is that &#8212; we have always said that the President, in April, had two plans: the American Jobs Plan and the American Family Plan.  And he has always been clear that he intends to pass both.<br> <br>The infrastructure bill contains the core of the American Jobs Plan and the reconciliation bill will be the vehicle to pass the American Families Plan.  So, his intention is to make sure that he &#8212; we move forward with both.<br> <br>Q    But the President said before that one was &#8212; that the &#8212; the Jobs Plan necessitated the Families Plan.  Is that the case: He needs the Families Plan in order to get &#8212; in order for him to sign that bipartisan agreement?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  He&#8217;s saying that he wants to do both at the same time.  That&#8217;s what he wants to do.  He wants to make &#8212; <br> <br>Q    So it’s not a red line, though?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I &#8212; I&#8217;m going to let his words stand.  And what he is saying &#8212; that he&#8217;s not going to give up on his legislative priorities.  That&#8217;s what he said in April.  That&#8217;s what he was saying today. <br> <br>He wants to make sure that infrastructure &#8212; this investment, this historic investment &#8212; this agreement that was made today is done.  Right?  And we should be, you know, celebrating that &#8212; the fact that we got this bipartisanship. <br> <br>But he also wants to make sure that his investment in people &#8212; the &#8220;human investment,&#8221; as he has called it &#8212; is also done.  Because we have to make investments that help &#8212; that help people down the &#8212; down the line, that does generational investments, and also economic investment.<br> <br>Q    Does he still favor &#8212;<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So that’s his focus.<br> <br>Q    Sorry to cut in.<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  No, no.  It’s okay. <br> <br>Q    Sorry about that.<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Go ahead.  Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Does he still favor a corporate tax increase as part of reconciliation, now that it didn&#8217;t make the bipartisan package?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Well, the one thing I will say is that &#8212; like I said, we’re not going to raise taxes on people who make less than $400,000; that this is &#8212; this is a win.  This &#8212; there&#8217;s no gas tax.  Right?  There&#8217;s no &#8212; any kind of like taxes in that &#8212; in that regard.  And so that&#8217;s a big win. <br> <br>And so, he wanted to make sure that we do not put the burden on the American people, that these plans pay for itself, and that&#8217;s going to be the focus.  And we’ll have more, and we’ll continue to share when we have more.<br> <br>Q    He talked about the Democratic Party being a divided, but a rational party.  Is President Biden having any conversations today with Senator Sanders or any of the other members who wanted more in this bill?  What&#8217;s his outreach right now to progressives?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Well, I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any meetings to preview or conversations to preview.  As you know, he&#8217;s headed &#8212; we&#8217;re all heading to North Carolina today to focus on the importance of getting vaccinated and making sure that we lift up the work that &#8212; that&#8217;s being done in North Carolina today. <br> <br>But he has a good relationship with Senator Sanders.  They have spoken multiple times over the last 150 days or so.  And he&#8217;ll continue to have those conversations. <br> <br>As we know, the President has been all hands &#8212; &#8220;all-hands-on-deck&#8221; on this.  Right?  He&#8217;s had multiple conversations with congressional members.  He&#8217;s had them over in the Oval Office.  His staff &#8212; his senior White House staff has &#8212; this week, has been back and forth to the Capitol, having those conversations. <br> <br>So, that&#8217;s not going to end.  This is the beginning of, I think, this bipartisan structure &#8212; infrastructure framework is a first step to get to what we need to be doing for the American public, which is making sure that we invest in them and in their future.<br> <br>Q    Sure.  And President Biden said he conceded or gave up a lot in this bill, but technically he&#8217;s still going for everything else in the reconciliation bills.  Did he really give up anything?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Well, let me just say this: This historic bipartisan infrastructure framework will make life better for millions of Americans.  Right?  It will create a generation of good-paying jobs and economic growth; position the U.S. to win the 21st century, including combating the climate crisis.<br> <br>As we&#8217;ve talked about, the President is committed &#8212; again, and I&#8217;ve said this already &#8212; to the full legislation agenda, which is including the care economy, expanding childcare, additional investment in clean energy, and passing a budget resolution that enacts his legislation priorities. <br> <br>So that is his commitment.  And, as we know, when we compromise, you give up a little; you know, you give a little.<br> <br>Q    But he didn&#8217;t give up anything.  I mean, he&#8217;s going to get everything through &#8212; he wants through reconciliation. <br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  But, I mean, he said it himself: There were some things that, you know, he did give up on.  But, I think the bottom line is that, that red line that you were talking about &#8212; like that &#8212; that was the red line that was not crossed.  Right?  We didn&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;re not rising &#8212; raising taxes for people who make $400,000 &#8212; less than $400,000.  And there are no gas tax &#8212; tax on this. <br> <br>So this is a big win.  We have a bipartisanship deal.  This is something that the President, in many ways, was elected to do, because people &#8212; the American people really believed that he was able to do this, and he did.  And so we&#8217;re going to move forward on that.<br> <br>Q    Karine, about the vaccination rates and at the event today &#8212; so, given that we&#8217;re seeing the vaccination rates in the South and the West go down, but there&#8217;s some COVID cases rising in some of these states, is the White House worried that some of these July 4th celebrations might lead to, like, regional surges in the coronavirus &#8212; may become a super-spreader event? <br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  (Inaudible) every part of the country, we have seen a dramatic drop in cases.  We&#8217;ve seen a drop &#8212; dramatic drop in deaths and hospitaliz- &#8212; hospitalizations since we took office. <br> <br>For vaccinated people, as we all know, it&#8217;s safe to see friends and family with no masks, go to a concert.  You see people going out to restaurants, weddings even, vacations, or have a Fourth of July party, which is right around the corner. <br> <br>But we do see varying vaccination rates across the country.  We will continue to build trust with local messengers. <br> <br>These local leaders the President will be highlighting today are mission critical to the next phase of our work.  Like, we know when the President &#8212; as you all know, when the President travels somewhere, that local news that they get in that local community is tremendous and is incredi- &#8212; and is incredibly important. <br> <br>So we&#8217;ll continue our vaccinations program as well.  So there&#8217;s a shot &#8212; a shot waiting for people when they&#8217;re ready.  It&#8217;s never been easier to get vaccinated.  It&#8217;s free.  Right?  It&#8217;s easy to get.  We have worked really hard.  The President has worked really hard to make that happen. <br> <br>And to reiterate, we are doing everything we can to help states get more Americans vaccinated.  That&#8217;s why the President is in North Carolina today. <br> <br>Ultimately, though, this is an individual decision.  This is a personal decision.  We&#8217;ve been clear, and so is the science.  The science is very clear.  As we know, the Delta variant is contagious and more severe, but the vaccines protects against it.  So we encourage &#8212; every day we can, we start &#8212; we encourage the American people to get vaccinated.<br> <br>Q    Following up on that, at what point do you concede that the people who want to get vaccinated have been vaccinated, the people who don&#8217;t want to get vaccinated aren&#8217;t going to get vaccinated?  And then what does that next step look like?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I don&#8217;t think we concede that.  I think we have to make sure, in order to &#8212; for us to get back to normal, which we&#8217;re starting to do, we have to make sure that people are getting vaccinated.  We have to make sure that we&#8217;re working with people on the ground who are those trusted ver- &#8212; voices.  And they&#8217;re talking to their neighbors and getting their neighbors vaccinated if they haven&#8217;t been yet.  That&#8217;s the only way that we&#8217;re going to be able to also fight these variants that we&#8217;re seeing. <br> <br>So it is in &#8212; it is mission critical to make sure that we do all that we can to get people vaccinated.  That&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been doing as an administration these last 150 days.<br> <br>Q    Karine, has the President or anyone in the White House watched General Milley&#8217;s comments yesterday on critical race theory or Secretary Austin&#8217;s comments?  And what&#8217;s the administration&#8217;s view in general on what the Republicans are saying about the teaching of critical race theory?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So, let me tell you where we stand.  We &#8212; we should teach our kids the truth: America is a great country, but there have been some dark chapters in our history. <br> <br>As the President said in Tulsa, &#8220;We should know the good, the bad, everything.  That&#8217;s what a great &#8212; that&#8217;s what great nations do: They come to terms with their dark sides.&#8221;  Slavery is a part of this nation&#8217;s history, so was the brave work of Black and white Americans and putting an end to it. <br> <br>Our children should learn all of our history.  We don&#8217;t think politicians trying to score political points by banning parts of our history in our classroom is a good thing.  So we trust our teachers to teach our kids the facts and the truth. <br> <br>Q    Karine, just quickly, to follow up on Jeff&#8217;s in question.  We&#8217;ve already seen some Democrats criticize the framework that the White House and these senators came up with.  Did the White House brief other Democrats on this framework before they came out and said they agreed to it?  And what do next steps look like to make sure that the entire party is unified on the path forward that the President has laid out?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Look, like the President said outright: Today&#8217;s agreement is a crucial step forward in realizing the economic agenda for the American Jobs Plan and the fruition of hard work with both parties. <br> <br>This is, you know, the largest &#8212; he said this &#8212; the largest investment in public transportation in history.  It will connect every American to broadband, eliminate lead pipes to stop kids from drinking poisoned water, and makes critical progress on the climate crisis &#8212; including by making the largest investment in EV infrastructure in history, investment in clean power infrastructure, clean transportation infrastructure, and climate resilience. <br> <br>This is &#8212; also amounts to two thirds of the resources the President proposed in the respective jobs &#8212; American Jobs Plan categories. <br> <br>And as the President also made very clear, on dual tracks, we&#8217;re going full steam ahead for the rest of his Build Back Better Plan &#8212; this is what I was saying earlier: He&#8217;s not going to give up on his legislative agenda &#8212; working with the Senate on a budget resolution that includes a fair tax system for the middle class, human infrastructure, the American Families Plan and other essential investments.  And we&#8217;re going to keep working together with &#8212; with every segment of our party and across the aisle to get all of this done.<br> <br>So, we&#8217;re going to continue to talk to, you know, Republicans and Democrats to get this done.  As you know, this bipartisan &#8212; bipartisanship that we came together with was 10 Republicans and 10 Democrats, and so we&#8217;re going to continue that work.<br> <br>Q    Senator Schumer recommended the White House extend student loan benefits through March this week &#8212; the college student loan benefits &#8212; (inaudible), where we’re not paying back the interest.  Is that something that&#8217;s under consideration by the White House?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Let me &#8212; let me get back and talk to our team.  I don&#8217;t have any update on that right at this moment.  As you know, COVID really, really hurt many Americans, including students.  And so let me get back to you on that.  I don&#8217;t have any update.<br> <br>Q    The President is in North Carolina today, and the First Lady is in Florida.  Did the White House, you know, pick areas that are particularly under-vaccinated?  Or how did it choose to go to the states where it&#8217;s really kind of ramping up this outreach effort?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Yeah.  You know, as I said at the top, or as you just mentioned, you know, members of our administration are blitzing the country to highlight the efforts &#8212; local communities hard work to get more people vaccinated. <br> <br>You know, the local efforts are making a difference, you know?  And we &#8212; we are &#8212; this is a grassroots operation that we&#8217;ve been talking about for the past couple of weeks. <br> <br>And so this is incredibly important to have our principals out there.  Like I said earlier, when they&#8217;re there, they get that &#8212; you know, they get the local press there to lift up what they&#8217;re doing on the ground.  And everything that folks are doing on the ground is critical &#8212; is mission critical in getting people vaccinated.  And we have to continue to make sure we get the word out there and people understand why it&#8217;s so important to get vaccinated, in order to continue to get back to normal.<br> <br>Q    Karine, we have the Afghan President Ashraf Ghani’s visit to the White House tomorrow.  Can you preview what the President hopes to accomplish?  Should we expect announcements on security at the Kabul airport and other &#8212; and any updates on the timeline for withdrawal of U.S. troops from Afghanistan?<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Yeah.  So &#8212; (Air Force One experiences turbulence) &#8212; it is bumpy. <br> <br>So, this visit is a &#8212; is, first, is &#8212; is first about our ongoing commitment and support to the Afghan people and to the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces. <br> <br>As we continue to undertake our security transition, Afghanistan has experienced a significant COVID outbreak of the Delta variant, and we will be providing 3 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to the people of Afghanistan to be shipped as soon as next week, pending logistics.  We are also providing oxygen and other supplies. <br> <br>The newest COVID support, which is &#8212; which is from the tranche of the 55 million doses we announced on Monday, is distinct from the further $266 million in humanitarian assistance Secretary Blinken announced on June 4th. <br> <br>We are also continuing security assistance through DOD’s Afghan- &#8212; Afghanistan Security Forces Fund to provide financial support to the Afghan National Army National, Afghan National Police, Afghan Air Force, and Afghan Special Security Forces, including the special mission wing.<br> <br>Congress appropriated over $3 billion to ASFF in 2021, and the President has requested over $3.3 billion for 2022.<br> <br>Second, the President will emphasize the need for unity, cohesion, and for the Afghan government to focus on key challenges Afghanistan faces.<br> <br>We will welcome both President Ghani and Chairman Abdullah.  And one of the important messages we will be stressing is the need for the leaders to be a united front as they address security and other challenges.<br> <br>(Air Force One experiences turbulence.)  It&#8217;s getting bumpy here.  We&#8217;re about to land.  Here we go. <br> <br>Third, we will &#8212; third, we will emphasize our continuing diplomatic support for the peace process and for all Afghan parties to engage in good faith in that process.<br> <br>Obviously, these are significant challenges to this complex peace effort, but we believe that a negotiated political settlement is the best way to end the conflict, and we’ll continue to support those efforts.<br> <br>Since 2002, the United States has provided nearly $88 billion in security assistance; $36 billion in civilian assistance, including $787 million specifically intended to support Afghan women and girls; and nearly $3.9 billion in humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan.<br> <br>Q    Nothing on the airport that you’re expecting?  Nothing on the Kabul airport that you know?  No announcements on &#8212;<br> <br>Q    (Inaudible) Erdoğan meeting &#8212;<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So, I mean &#8212; so, as far as the security situation/assessment in general, we are seeing elevated attacks on ANDSF and Afghan government versus a year ago.  Right?  But no increase in attacks on our military or presence since February 2020.<br> <br>We assess that we had not &#8212; if we had not begun to draw down, violence would have increased against us as well after May 1st.  So, the status quo was not an option.<br> <br>So, we would also note that the &#8212; much of this is Taliban violence, but some is attributable to other groups, like ISIS-K, that were obviously not part of any negotiations or engagements, and that the Taliban is also fighting.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Karine.<br> <br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Thank you.<br> <br>3:47 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Meeting with Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond and Key Business Groups on Historic Infrastructure Investments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/readout-of-meeting-with-senior-advisor-cedric-richmond-and-key-business-groups-on-historic-infrastructure-investments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 22:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond hosted a virtual roundtable with key business groups, including those representing Black, LGBTQ+, Hispanic, AAPI, women and small business leaders. Director Richmond discussed the historic investments proposed in President Biden’s American Jobs Plan and updated business leaders on the status of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond hosted a virtual roundtable with key business groups, including those representing Black, LGBTQ+, Hispanic, AAPI, women and small business leaders. Director Richmond discussed the historic investments proposed in President Biden’s American Jobs Plan and updated business leaders on the status of the negotiations with the bipartisan group of Senators. He also reiterated the President’s commitment to not raise taxes on people making less than $400,000 a year and thanked the business leaders for their leadership and support.<br> <br>The business leaders spoke of the urgent need for investments in infrastructure, including roads, bridges, ports, seaports and broadband. They also emphasized their support for programs to help businesses recover from the economic impacts of the pandemic and expanding federal contracting opportunities for small businesses. The group discussed how access to paid leave and child care resources will support their employees and allow small businesses to better compete. The leaders reiterated the need for additional capital investment in order to create jobs and compete in the 21st century economy.<br> <br>Richmond also thanked participants for joining and said that he looks forward to continued dialogue about how the Biden &#8211; Harris Administration can continue its support for small businesses. This meeting is part of Director Richmond’s outreach to small businesses. To date, Richmond has organized nearly 150 meetings with the private sector that were attended by over 95,000 people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
