<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 22:29:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Travel to&#160;India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/29/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-travel-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50033</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 30th and 31st, Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics Daleep Singh will be in New Delhi to continue our ongoing consultations with the Government of India, and advance a range of issues in the U.S.-India economic relationship and strategic partnership. Singh will meet with Government of India officials to deepen cooperation to promote&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On March 30<sup>th</sup> and 31<sup>st</sup>, Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics Daleep Singh will be in New Delhi to continue our ongoing consultations with the Government of India, and advance a range of issues in the U.S.-India economic relationship and strategic partnership. Singh will meet with Government of India officials to deepen cooperation to promote inclusive economic growth and prosperity, and a free and open Indo-Pacific. Singh will consult closely with counterparts on the consequences of Russia’s unjustified war against Ukraine and mitigating its impact on the global economy. Singh will also discuss priorities of the Biden Administration, including the promotion of high-quality infrastructure through Build Back Better World and the development of an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Electric Vehicle and Battery Manufacturing Investments in North&#160;Carolina</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/29/statement-by-president-biden-on-electric-vehicle-and-battery-manufacturing-investments-in-north-carolina/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s announcement that the electric vehicle maker VinFast will build an electric vehicle and battery manufacturing facility in North Carolina – $4 billion to create more than 7,000 jobs and hundreds of thousands of electric vehicles and batteries – is the latest example of my economic strategy at work. It builds on recent announcements from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s announcement that the electric vehicle maker VinFast will build an electric vehicle and battery manufacturing facility in North Carolina – $4 billion to create more than 7,000 jobs and hundreds of thousands of electric vehicles and batteries – is the latest example of my economic strategy at work. It builds on recent announcements from companies like GM, Ford, and Siemens to invest in America again and create jobs.&nbsp; Our efforts to build a clean energy economy are driving companies to make more in America rebuild our supply chains here at home, and ultimately bring down costs for the American people.<br><br>Since taking office, we have implemented an industrial strategy to revitalize domestic manufacturing with create good-paying American jobs, strengthen American supply chains, and supercharge the industries of the future like electric vehicles – and we see that strategy paying off day after day. Last year, I signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to build out EV charging infrastructure and brought together the United Autoworkers and automakers at the White House to sign an executive order to get 50% electric vehicle sales share in 2030.<br><br>Congress has an opportunity with competitiveness legislation like the Bipartisan Innovation Act to double down on the progress we’ve made rebuilding our industrial base to create more good-paying jobs, make more in America – including semiconductors needed by our auto industry – and lower prices for working families.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;55</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/03/29/bill-signed-h-r-55/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 21:04:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50027</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, March 29, 2022, the President signed into law:&#160;H.R. 55, the &#8220;Emmett Till Antilynching Act,&#8221; which makes lynching a Federal hate crime.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, March 29, 2022, the President signed into law:<br>&nbsp;<br>H.R. 55, the &#8220;Emmett Till Antilynching Act,&#8221; which makes lynching a Federal hate crime.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/29/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:39:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE: Travis LeBlanc, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board for a term expiring January 29, 2028.  (Reappointment) # # #]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>Travis LeBlanc, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board for a term expiring January 29, 2028.  (Reappointment)</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore in Joint Press&#160;Statements</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/29/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-prime-minister-lee-hsien-loong-of-singapore-in-joint-press-statements/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial Office 3:19 P.M. EDT VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Okay, good afternoon, everyone.  It is my great pleasure to see you again, Mr. Prime Minister.  You and I had an extensive and wonderful visit when I was in Singapore in August.  We discussed many issues that impact our nations and the world.  And today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial Office </em></p>



<p>3:19 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Okay, good afternoon, everyone.  It is my great pleasure to see you again, Mr. Prime Minister.  You and I had an extensive and wonderful visit when I was in Singapore in August.  We discussed many issues that impact our nations and the world.  And today was a continuation of that conversation with a number of do-outs from the conversation that we originally had.</p>



<p>I must say, at the beginning, what I said to you then and today remains absolutely true: The United States is a proud member of the Indo-Pacific, and the relationship that we have with the nations in that region and with Singapore is an enduring relationship.  It is a relationship we value and we prioritize for many reasons, including the shared principle that we have about what is important in terms of world order and international norms and standards.</p>



<p>The focus of the trip in August was to do what is important and what is possible in continuing to strengthen and reaffirm the relationship that the United States has with Singapore. </p>



<p>And the importance of the relationship spans many areas, including what is in our mutual interest and our shared interest in terms of our own nations’ strength and prosperity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You and I discussed the issue of Russia and Ukraine.&nbsp; And we, in the spirit of our work together being global, discussed our support for the people of Ukraine and also the importance of acknowledging the economic costs that Singapore levied as a result of our shared concern about the advancement that Russia and the &#8212; and the aggression that Russia has taken, and the threat that it has posed to an issue that we hold dearly &#8212; and I&#8217;ll speak for the United States, and I know that we share this concern &#8212; about upholding the importance of sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>



<p>But the bigger issue is not only about what we must do to maintain and fight for, for the United States, European security, but what we must do as a matter of principle and priority for our nation in standing up to the importance of rules and norms and international rules and norms &#8212; again, in this case, as it relates to sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>



<p>During the August trip, we launched many initiatives that are about shaping the future of our nations and our world.&nbsp; And today, of course, again, is a follow-up to that conversation, including what we are doing together in the context of space.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am very pleased that as a follow-up to the discussion that you and I had in Singapore, that Singapore has signed on to the Artemis Accords, which of course is a partnership between many nations, Southeast Asia now being represented; Singapore being the fourth Southeast Asian nation to recognize what we can do together to expand international norms as it relates to all matters, including matters in space.</p>



<p>And so, we have discussed that.&nbsp; We have discussed, of course, the importance of working together on the issue of cyber, both as a security matter but also as a matter that relates to our nation&#8217;s prosperity and investment in innovation.&nbsp; And so, we have announced, and you announced with the President today, the U.S.-Singapore Cyber Dialogue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have also discussed other issues that relate to our economies and, again, prosperity of our respective nations, including the importance of collaboration on the issue of supply chains &#8212; something we talked about back in August and have discussed again today &#8212; and our commitment to moving forward together on this important work.</p>



<p>And we have discussed the importance of climate and what our nations have the ability and have the commitment to do to be leaders on this issue that threatens the security and the wellbeing of our entire globe.</p>



<p>So, with that, Mr. Prime Minister, I thank you for the visit and for our conversation.&nbsp; I look forward to many more.&nbsp; And I thank you for the friendship as well.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; Thank you, Vice President &#8212; Vice President Harris, ladies and gentlemen.&nbsp; I thank the Vice President for her very warm remarks.&nbsp; We last met in August, in Singapore, and we continued with a very good conversation this afternoon, reaffirming the longstanding and robust partnership between our two countries.</p>



<p>And we also discussed the ongoing crisis in Ukraine and reiterated our shared commitment to a stable, rules-based global order.</p>



<p>The U.S. has played an important and constructive role in the Asia Pacific for nearly eighty* years.&nbsp; Singapore has consistently supported a strong U.S. presence in the region, both through words and actions.&nbsp; And our two countries enjoy close economic relations.</p>



<p>Our U.S.-Singapore Free Trade Agreement signed in 2004, nearly 20 years ago, was the U.S.’s first FTA with an Asian country.&nbsp; Singapore is home to nearly 5,500 U.S. companies, and U.S. FDI stock in Singapore exceeds U.S. investments in China, India, and the Republic of Korea combined.</p>



<p>Singapore is also the second-largest Asian investor in the U.S.&nbsp; So, Singapore&#8217;s investment in the U.S. and U.S. exports to Singapore support more than a quarter million U.S. jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our security and defense ties go back many decades.&nbsp; We’re a major security cooperation partner of the U.S.&nbsp; Our Memorandum of Understanding on Defense Cooperation, signed in 1990 and renewed recently in 2019, provides the U.S. military with access to Singapore&#8217;s air and naval bases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vice President Harris visited the littoral combat ship USS Tulsa at our Changi Naval Base when she visited Singapore, and she could see firsthand how Singapore supports the U.S. military presence and its defense engagements in the region.</p>



<p>Singapore also has one of the largest foreign training presences in the U.S.&nbsp; We are grateful for U.S. support, for their air force training, which we conduct with detachments in Arizona and Idaho.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we continue to work together to jointly face challenges on the horizon, deepening defense cooperation in areas like cyber defense, artificial intelligence, and joint training with the F-35s.</p>



<p>The Vice President and I reviewed progress on the substantial agenda of deliverables announced on her visit last year.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve established a bilateral cyber dialogue to work together on critical infrastructure protection, data security, and sharing of best practices in support of a rules-based multilateral order in cyberspace.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re expanding the MOU between MTI and DFC to deepen collaboration in green and sustainable infrastructure projects in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as the Vice President told you, Singapore has signed the Artemis Accords, which aim to promote the peaceful, sustainable, and beneficial use of space.&nbsp; We are the first Southeast Asian country to sign on, and we had a good discussion about this because the Vice President chairs the White House National Space Council.</p>



<p>&nbsp;So I&#8217;m very glad that the Vice President and I were able to meet again to discuss ways to take our partnership to even greater heights.&nbsp; And we look forward to the next occasion to meet the Vice President once more, either in Washington or, I hope, in Singapore.</p>



<p>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you again, Mr. Prime Minister.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3:27 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore in Joint Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/29/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-lee-hsien-loong-of-singapore-in-joint-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 1:28 P.M. EDT&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Welcome back to the White House.&#160; I’m honored to welcome Prime Minister Lee to the White House today.&#160; And I’m proud &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; I’m really proud of the partnership that &#8212; between Singapore and the United States.&#160; It’s as close and as strong as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>1:28 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Welcome back to the White House.&nbsp; I’m honored to welcome Prime Minister Lee to the White House today.&nbsp; And I’m proud &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; I’m really proud of the partnership that &#8212; between Singapore and the United States.&nbsp; It’s as close and as strong as it’s ever been.<br>&nbsp;<br>And together, we’re working to uphold a rules-based order &#8212; international order, supporting the founding principles of the United Nations, and advance a future for the Indo-Pacific that is both free and open.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As we look toward the future, Prime Minister Lee and I share a commitment to ASEAN as &#8212; and its centrality in all of what we do.&nbsp; And I’m looking forward to hosting the ASEAN leaders here in Washington, D.C., for a Special Summit this spring.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also discussed a wide range of concerns for peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; That includes ensuring that all nations in the region, including China, uphold the principles that enable a free and open region.<br>&nbsp;<br>Singapore and the United States are both committed to freedom of navigation as well as the unimpeded flow of maritime commerce in the South China Sea.<br>&nbsp;<br>We shared our concerns about the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea and their destabilizing ballistic missile launches, and in clear vio- &#8212; which are clearly in violation of multiple U.N. Council resolutions &#8212; Security Council resolutions.<br>And we both urge North Korea to refrain from further provocations and return to the negotiation table for serious and sustained diplomacy.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re deeply concerned, both of us, by the continuing suffering and violence in Burma, following last year&#8217;s military coup &#8212; the coup that caused humanitarian crisis and reversed a decade of democratic and economic progress for the people of Burma.<br>&nbsp;<br>Singapore and the United States agree that the military regime must urgently implement the ASEAN Five-Point Consensus and return Burma to its path to democratic transition.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we also discussed the war in Ukraine.&nbsp; Last week, in Europe, the world saw the strong unity for a unified response and resolve among the NATO Alliance, the G7, and the European Union to answer Putin&#8217;s brutal and unjustified assault on Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, with the Prime Minister&#8217;s visit and Singapore’s strong leadership on this issue, it&#8217;s clear that Putin’s war is unacceptable to nations in every region of the world &#8212; not just Europe, but in every region of the world.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an attack on the core international principles and it &#8212; that underpin peace and security and prosperity everywhere, including in the Indo-Pacific.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, Singapore and the United States are united in sending the message to all nations &#8212; to all nations, regardless of their size or population: They are equal in the right &#8212; in their rights on the global stage.&nbsp; They have a right to sovereignty and territorial integrity and to determine their own future free from violence and intimidation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Mr. Prime Minister, our nations cooperate closely on security and counterterrorism; we have for some time.&nbsp; And we have deep commercial and economic ties.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also developed deep personal ties as well, I must acknowledge.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I &#8212; we&#8217;re going to continue to deepen our partnership and seize the opportunities to meet the challenges of the moment and to meet them together: fighting COVID-19, making sure we&#8217;re prepared for the next pandemic; increasing our climate ambitions and working to decarbonize the shipping sector; cooperating on everything from cybersecurity to space exploration; promoting a broad-based economic growth throughout the Indo-Pacific, including by working together to develop an Indo-Pacific economic framework that will drive enduring prosperity across the region.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we have a large agenda, Mr. Prime Minister &#8212; an important agenda, a shared vision that we are jointly pursuing: a free and open Indo-Pacific, an Indo-Pacific that is connected, prosperous, and more secure, and more resilient.&nbsp; And the U.S.-Singapore partnership is essential, I believe, to realize that future.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you, again, Prime Minister Lee.&nbsp; I always appreciate consulting with you.&nbsp; And as I’ve told you, both you and Singapore punch way above your weight &#8212; way above your weight.&nbsp; And I value the time we spend together, and I look forward to many more meetings.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>The floor is yours.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; Thank you, President Biden.&nbsp; Thank you for those warm remarks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden, ladies and gentlemen, I&#8217;d like to thank the President for the very warm welcome that I and my delegation have received.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We last met in Rome on the sidelines of the G20 Summit, but much has changed since those few months ago.&nbsp; Current international uncertainties and crisis underscore the need for countries to work together with close friends and partners.&nbsp; And Singapore deeply appreciates America&#8217;s commitment to engage Southeast Asia, and especially Singapore, despite the ongoing crisis in Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>We had a very good discussion with President Biden this morning.&nbsp; We reaffirmed the longstanding and multifaceted partnership between Singapore and the U.S., and our shared commitment to a stable, rules-based global order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The U.S. has played an important and constructive role in the Asia-Pacific for more than &#8212; for nearly 80 years.&nbsp; And Singapore has consistently supported a strong U.S. presence in the region through our words and actions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have substantial bilateral cooperation on economic, defense, and security issues, and also strong people-to-people ties.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Singapore is the second-largest Asian investor in the U.S., and the U.S. is the largest investor in Singapore.&nbsp; Singapore&#8217;s investments in the U.S. and U.S. exports to Singapore support over a quarter million American jobs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On the defense front, Singapore is a Major Security Cooperation Partner of the U.S. &#8212; in fact, the only country with this status.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For more than 30 years, we&#8217;ve had an MOU on defense cooperation, signed in 1990 and recently renewed in 2019, which has provided the U.S. military access to Singapore&#8217;s air and naval bases.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are also expanding our cooperation into new areas, including cybersecurity, digital economy, sustainable development, and even space.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Singapore deeply appreciates President Biden&#8217;s leadership in strengthening U.S. engagement in the region.&nbsp; We welcome his intention to host an ASEAN-U.S. Special Summit here soon.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a strong affirmation of American commitment to Southeast Asia and to ASEAN centrality.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President and I discussed the importance of the U.S. growing both its strategic and economic stakes in the Asia-Pacific.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important to advance a positive economic agenda that&#8217;s open, inclusive, up to date, and flexible.<br>&nbsp;<br>We therefore welcome America&#8217;s proposed Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, which will strengthen America&#8217;s engagement in the evolving regional economic architecture.<br>&nbsp;<br>I discussed with the President his recent visit to Europe and the ongoing crisis in Ukraine.&nbsp; Singapore is a staunch supporter of international law and the U.N. Charter, which prohibits acts of aggression against a sovereign state.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve strongly condemned the unprovoked attack by Russia on Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The sovereignty, political independence, and territorial integrity of all countries, big and small, must be respected.&nbsp; The unprovoked military invasion of a sovereign country under any pretext is unacceptable.<br>&nbsp;<br>We cannot condone any country arguing that another country&#8217;s independence is the result of historical errors and crazy decisions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I shared with President Biden the measures that Singapore has taken to constrain Russia&#8217;s capacity to conduct war against Ukraine.&nbsp; Our actions are based on principles that are fundamental to our survival and existence as an independent, sovereign nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve upheld these principles and voted in accordance with them at the U.N. in successive crisis over many decades involving different countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>The war in the Ukraine has implications for the Asia-Pacific.&nbsp; There are potential flashpoints and contentious issues in our region too, which, if not managed well, could escalate to open conflict.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Countries with interests in the region need to pursue all efforts to settle disagreements through peaceful means so that we can avoid reaching a point of no return.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s important, therefore, to keep open channels of dialogue between countries, including at the highest level.&nbsp; This will help to manage developments in order to avoid conflict and prevent misreading each other&#8217;s intentions.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also need to create inclusive constructs to bridge differences and encourage cooperation and interdependence in the Asia-Pacific &#8212; for example, the APEC Leaders’ Meeting and the proposed Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.<br>&nbsp;<br>The U.S. has enduring strategic interests in the Asia-Pacific and many friends in the region who want you to stay actively and consistently engaged.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m confident that within this regional context, Singapore&#8217;s own relationship with the U.S. will continue to grow from strength to strength.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Now, we each agreed we would take one question.&nbsp; And &#8212; I’ll &#8212; I&#8217;ll recognize someone first.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Darlene Superville, Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; What is your view of Russia&#8217;s announcement today that it will, quote, “fundamentally” scale back its military operations near Kyiv and another northern city in Ukraine?&nbsp; Do you see this as possibly the war beginning to come to an end, or do you see this as Russia trying to buy time and to recalibrate for a new military effort?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t read anything into it until I see what their actions are.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see if they follow through on what they’re suggesting.&nbsp; There are negotiations that have begun today &#8212; or not begun, continued; today: one in Turkey and others.</p>



<p>I had a meeting with the heads of state of &#8212; of four Allies in NATO: France, Germany, the United States, and &#8212; and &#8212; and Great Britain.&nbsp; And there seems to be a consensus that let&#8217;s just see what they have to offer; we&#8217;ll find out what they do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in the meantime, we&#8217;re going to continue to keep strong the sanctions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to provide the Ukrainian military with their capacity to defend themselves.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to keep a close eye on what&#8217;s going on.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; I call on Dawn Tan, Channel NewsAsia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon, Mr. President.&nbsp; Good afternoon &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; Use the mic.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; Good afternoon, Mr. President.&nbsp; And good afternoon, Prime Minister.</p>



<p>Prime Minister, you&#8217;ve advocated the benefits for the United States to develop a bipartisan consensus on Asia, that Asia depends upon a predictable U.S. policy towards the region.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>How assured are you, though, that the momentum that you&#8217;ve seen with ASEAN-U.S. engagement has the ability to move the needle on shared objectives in the Asia-Pacific towards the fundamentals that we all need to live by &#8212; peace, prosperity, and economic development?&nbsp; And, basically, how well is President Biden doing in this regard?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; I think if you put it at a very broad level, there is consensus in the United States on the direction of their policy in the Asia-Pacific that they want to engage China; that they are developing &#8212; trying to develop a stable, predictable relationship with China; and, at the same time, engaging other countries in the region not just on strategic and security issues but also on economic cooperation and trade, and other investment, and environmental and sustainability links.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;So, at the very broad level, I think the consensus is there.&nbsp; At the level of specific policies, each administration launches new initiatives.&nbsp; I&#8217;m quite convinced, having seen several administrations, that this one is completely focused on achieving something lasting in Asia.&nbsp; And we in Singapore will do our best to help to make sure that their proposals work and will take root and will continue to grow for many years to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; Thank you, President Biden.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you, gentlemen. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:42 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Prime Minister Lee of&#160;Singapore</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/29/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-prime-minister-lee-of-singapore/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 20:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris today met with Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore. Building on the Vice President’s August 2021 visit to Singapore, the leaders reviewed progress made on initiatives launched last year and agreed to further strengthen the U.S.-Singapore strategic partnership. The Vice President and the Prime Minister discussed Russia’s brutal and unjustified&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris today met with Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore. Building on the Vice President’s August 2021 visit to Singapore, the leaders reviewed progress made on initiatives launched last year and agreed to further strengthen the U.S.-Singapore strategic partnership. The Vice President and the Prime Minister discussed Russia’s brutal and unjustified war against Ukraine. The Vice President thanked the Prime Minister for Singapore’s support for Ukraine and the rules-based international order, including imposing financial sanctions and export controls on Russia. They discussed next steps in terms of implementation of these economic measures as well as the importance of support for the people of Ukraine. The Vice President underscored the enduring commitment of the United States to the Indo-Pacific region, and Southeast Asia in particular. They discussed the importance of strengthening partnerships throughout the region, including through ASEAN, to promote an Indo-Pacific that is free and open, connected, prosperous, secure, and resilient.  The Vice President welcomed Singapore becoming the first Southeast Asian nation to join the Artemis Accords and discussed with the Prime Minister our continued cooperation on space, climate, supply chains, and cybersecurity.<br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">### </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe&#160;Biden’s Call with President Macron of France, Chancellor Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Draghi of Italy, Prime Minister Johnson of the United&#160;Kingdom</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/29/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-call-with-president-macron-of-france-chancellor-scholz-of-germany-prime-minister-draghi-of-italy-prime-minister-johnson-of-the-united-kingdom-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 17:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France, Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy, and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.  The leaders affirmed their determination to continue raising costs on Russia for its brutal attacks in Ukraine, as well as to continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France, Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy, and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.  The leaders affirmed their determination to continue raising costs on Russia for its brutal attacks in Ukraine, as well as to continue supplying Ukraine with security assistance to defend itself against this unjustified and unprovoked assault.  They reviewed their efforts to provide humanitarian assistance to the millions affected by the violence, both inside Ukraine and seeking refuge in other countries, and underscored the need for humanitarian access to civilians in Mariupol. They also discussed the importance of supporting stable energy markets in light of current disruptions due to sanctions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Singapore Joint Leaders’&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/29/u-s-singapore-joint-leaders-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is honored to welcome Prime Minister of the Republic of Singapore Lee Hsien Loong to Washington, D.C. The U.S.-Singapore strategic partnership is anchored in our shared respect for the rules-based international order, adherence to international law, and the principles enshrined in the United Nations Charter – including respect for sovereignty,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is honored to welcome Prime Minister of the Republic of Singapore Lee Hsien Loong to Washington, D.C. The U.S.-Singapore strategic partnership is anchored in our shared respect for the rules-based international order, adherence to international law, and the principles enshrined in the United Nations Charter – including respect for sovereignty, the peaceful resolution of disputes, cooperation among nations, and fundamental human rights. These principles have underpinned decades of unprecedented peace and stability as well as economic and social development, in the Indo-Pacific region and around the world.<br><br>The United States and Singapore recognize that threats to the UN Charter and rules-based international order anywhere, including Russia’s unprovoked attack on Ukraine, place peace and prosperity everywhere at risk. The war in Ukraine has a negative impact on the Indo-Pacific region, which already faces many complex challenges. Taken together, the opportunities and challenges of the 21st century demand deeper cooperation between us.<br><br>The leaders welcome the enduring strength of the bilateral strategic partnership, marked by Singapore’s unique status as a Major Security Cooperation Partner, by the 5,400 U.S. companies that call Singapore home, by the countries’ close people-to-people ties, and by the series of high-level bilateral visits during the first year of the Biden-Harris Administration. The leaders resolve to further expand bilateral cooperation, taking bold new steps to drive broad-based economic growth and innovation, raise infrastructure standards in the region, address the climate crisis, promote health security, increase supply chain resilience, improve cybersecurity, ensure the long-term sustainability of outer space activities, and more. As we strengthen our partnership, we will promote a world in which all nations, large and small, can stand together as equals to tackle the most pressing challenges of our era and deliver for our people.<br><br><strong>Upholding the Rules-Based International Order</strong><br><br>President Biden reiterates the sustained and growing commitment of the United States to its allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific region, as described in the Indo-Pacific Strategy of the United States. President Biden and Prime Minister Lee reaffirm their strong support for ASEAN Centrality and the ASEAN-centered regional architecture. Prime Minister Lee welcomes President Biden’s invitation to ASEAN leaders for a historic ASEAN-U.S. Special Summit in Washington, D.C. The leaders highlight the success of the U.S.-Singapore Third Country Training Program, which has received more than 1700 officials from across ASEAN. The United States seeks cooperation with all partners who share our objectives in the Indo-Pacific region, and to that end, we welcome the Quad’s support for ASEAN Centrality, deeper economic integration, addressing of regional challenges, and promotion of an open, inclusive, stable and secure Indo-Pacific region and a rules-based order. We also welcome the enhanced engagement of European and regional partners in Southeast Asia and the broader Indo-Pacific region.<br><br>The United States and Singapore emphasize our unwavering commitment to the principles of sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity, and condemn Russia’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, which clearly violates international law, including the United Nations Charter. The United States and Singapore recognize the need to preserve a world in which borders cannot be changed by force and state-to-state relations are guided by international law. Given the unprovoked attack on Ukraine, many countries across the Atlantic and the Pacific, including the United States and Singapore, have imposed their own financial sanctions and export controls against Russian entities. The United States and Singapore will ensure the effective implementation of their respective measures. The United States and Singapore are deeply concerned about the deteriorating humanitarian crisis in and around Ukraine, and call on all parties to allow safe and unfettered passage of civilians, facilitate unhindered access to humanitarian assistance for those in need in Ukraine, protect civilians, and respect human rights.<br><br>Amid global security challenges, the United States and Singapore continue to build on our partnership to pursue our shared interests. The leaders reaffirm a shared commitment to the goal of the complete denuclearization and the establishment of a permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula. Both leaders call on the DPRK to engage in serious and sustained diplomacy and emphasize the importance of full implementation of relevant United Nations Security Council resolutions. The leaders underscore the importance of peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region and encourage the peaceful resolution of disputes. President Biden and Prime Minister Lee also reflected on the close counterterrorism partnership shared by the United States and Singapore, and Singapore’s support of the United States relocation efforts related to Afghanistan last year.<br><br>In the maritime domain, the United States and Singapore reaffirm the right of freedom of navigation and overflight and other lawful uses of the seas accorded by international law, including the 1982 United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS). We reaffirm the need to pursue peaceful resolution of disputes in accordance with international law, including UNCLOS, which sets out the legal framework within which all activities in the oceans and seas must be carried out. We respect states’ ability to conserve, sustainably develop, and effectively manage their maritime natural resources in accordance with international law, including UNCLOS. We reaffirm that all concerned parties must abide by the 2002 Declaration on the Conduct of Parties in the South China Sea, and reiterate our support for ASEAN-led efforts to develop an effective and substantive Code of Conduct for the South China Sea that upholds the legitimate rights&nbsp;and interests&nbsp;of all parties and is consistent with UNCLOS. We also affirm the importance of acting consistently with the relevant Standards and Recommended Practices of the International Civil Aviation Organization, and the relevant instruments and conventions of the International Maritime Organization.<br><br>The United States and Singapore share deep concerns about the situation in Myanmar and the challenges it poses to regional stability. We continue to call for an end to violence against civilians in Myanmar, the release of all political detainees, including State Counsellor Aung San Suu Kyi, President Win Myint and foreign detainees;&nbsp;unhindered humanitarian access;&nbsp;and for Myanmar to return to its path of democratic transition. We appreciate the constructive role played by Singapore and ASEAN in facilitating a peaceful solution in the interest of the people of Myanmar, and we call for the Myanmar military regime to urgently implement the ASEAN Five Point Consensus. We are concerned the crisis has reversed years of economic progress in Myanmar and increased the risk of illicit finance.<br><br><strong>Driving Inclusive Prosperity and Addressing Emerging Challenges</strong><br><br>President Biden and Prime Minister Lee underscore their shared commitment to promoting broad-based economic growth in the United States, in Singapore, and throughout the region. They reaffirm the close collaboration between the United States and Singapore on developing an Indo-Pacific economic framework with regional partners that will expand cooperation on trade, supply chains, clean energy, decarbonization, infrastructure, tax, and anti-corruption. They welcome Thailand’s leadership as host of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) in 2022, and look forward to the United States hosting APEC in 2023. The leaders reviewed ongoing efforts to facilitate regional trade and increase supply chain resilience and looked forward to the implementation of the U.S.-ASEAN Economic Futures initiative.<br><br>The leaders also look forward to expanding economic cooperation under the U.S.-Singapore Partnership for Growth and Innovation (PGI), which aims to secure inclusive growth for our economies and regions in new and forward-looking areas: digital economy, energy and environmental technology, advanced manufacturing, and health services. New initiatives announced under the PGI include the development of interoperable ethical Artificial Intelligence governance frameworks, and plans for a U.S. business development mission to Singapore to facilitate new business opportunities and strengthen partnerships in advanced manufacturing.<br><br>President Biden and Prime Minister Lee commit to deepening cooperation between the United States and Singapore on high quality infrastructure development in the region. To that end, the United States and Singapore renewed and expanded the MOU to deepen cooperation on infrastructure development to cover new collaborations in green and sustainable infrastructure projects in the region that address social and economic needs and promote inclusive, private sector-led growth.<br><br>The climate crisis poses an existential threat to the world. Recognizing the need to enhance ambition in this decisive decade, the United States has put forward an ambitious target to achieve a 50-52 percent reduction from 2005 levels in economy-wide net greenhouse gas pollution in 2030 and to reach net-zero greenhouse gas emissions&nbsp;by&nbsp;no later than 2050, and Singapore has announced it will raise its climate ambition to achieve net-zero emissions by or around mid-century,&nbsp;and will be making a formal revision to both its Nationally Determined Contribution and Long-Term Low-Emissions Development Strategy (LEDS) later this year after consulting closely with key stakeholders.&nbsp;We commit to strengthening the U.S.-Singapore Climate Partnership, and we look forward to working with other countries to implement the Paris Agreement.&nbsp;President Biden and Prime Minister Lee recognize that decarbonizing the shipping sector is essential to transitioning to a clean energy economy and they commit to working together to advance green shipping, including by establishing alternative bunkering infrastructure for the provision of low- and zero-carbon fuels at our ports.<br><br>The United States and Singapore highlight their shared commitment to bolstering global health security and building back better from the COVID-19 pandemic, and preparing for further pandemics and other shocks to health systems. We must work with allies and partners to strengthen and finance vaccine readiness and accelerate efforts to control COVID-19 globally, for example by working with global health organizations such as the World Health Organization, GAVI, the Vaccine Alliance, and the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations.</p>



<p>The United States and Singapore affirm the importance of ensuring that critical and emerging technologies foster an open, accessible, and secure technology ecosystem, based on mutual trust, confidence, and respect for a rules-based international order. To this end, we commit to increasing resiliency in our technology supply chains, and developing robust approaches to data governance and security, seeking consistency and interoperability where feasible. We also plan to explore R&amp;D and other collaborations, including through the PGI, in order to progress towards affordable, resilient, secure and interoperable advanced high-speed wireless communications (“NextG”) in the Indo-Pacific region.<br><br>The United States and Singapore maintain a strong and growing partnership on cybersecurity. We seek global adherence to the UN framework of responsible state behavior in cyberspace and pledge to deepen our cooperation on combating cyber threats, promoting resilience, and securing our critical infrastructure, amongst other issues. We welcome the establishment of the United States-Singapore Cyber Dialogue to cement our cross institutional linkages to jointly tackle cybersecurity issues. We will continue to jointly lead critical efforts in the International Counter Ransomware Initiative to tackle the surge in ransomware attacks worldwide.<br><br>The United States and Singapore believe in the importance of creating a safe, stable, secure, and sustainable space environment that facilitates space exploration, science, and commercial activities that benefit all of humanity. President Biden welcomes Singapore’s commitment to the Artemis Accords. President Biden and Prime Minister Lee also welcome the convening of a United States-Singapore Space Dialogue.<br><br>Today’s challenges all demand closer cooperation between us. For many decades the United States and Singapore have worked together to overcome the challenges of the day, and we will continue to do so, with determination and resolve. Together, we are deepening our strategic partnership to seize opportunities and address emerging threats. We are defending and strengthening the rules-based international order that has long supported global security and prosperity, and will continue to do so long into the future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Puerto Rico Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/29/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-puerto-rico-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 16:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and ordered Federal aid to supplement Commonwealth and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe storm, flooding, and landslides from February 4 to February 6, 2022. The President&#8217;s action makes Federal funding available to affected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and ordered Federal aid to supplement Commonwealth and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe storm, flooding, and landslides from February 4 to February 6, 2022.<br> <br>The President&#8217;s action makes Federal funding available to affected individuals in the municipalities of Cataño, Dorado, Toa Baja, Vega Alta, and Vega Baja.<br> <br>Assistance can include grants for temporary housing and home repairs, low-cost loans to cover uninsured property losses, and other programs to help individuals and business owners recover from the effects of the disaster.<br> <br>Federal funding also is available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures for the entire commonwealth.<br> <br>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Robert Little III as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas. <br> <br>Damage assessments are continuing in other areas, and more areas and additional forms of assistance may be designated after the assessments are fully completed.<br> <br>Residents and business owners who sustained losses in the designated areas can begin applying for assistance tomorrow by registering online at <a href="http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov">http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov</a> or by calling 1-800-621-FEMA (3362) or 1-800-462-7585 (TTY) for the hearing and speech impaired. The toll-free telephone numbers will operate from 7 a.m. to 10 p.m. (local time) seven days a week until further notice.  <br> <br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
