<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 16:55:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the U.S. Supreme Court Decision Upholding the Affordable Care Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/17/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-u-s-supreme-court-decision-upholding-the-affordable-care-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 16:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Affordable Care Act remains the law of the land.&#160; Today’s U.S. Supreme Court decision is a major victory for all Americans benefitting from this groundbreaking and life-changing law. It is a victory for more than 130 million Americans with pre-existing conditions and millions more who were in immediate danger of losing their health care&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Affordable Care Act remains the law of the land.&nbsp;<br><br>Today’s U.S. Supreme Court decision is a major victory for all Americans benefitting from this groundbreaking and life-changing law. It is a victory for more than 130 million Americans with pre-existing conditions and millions more who were in immediate danger of losing their health care in the midst of a once-in-a-century pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>It is a victory for every American who, prior to the Affordable Care Act, stayed up at night staring at the ceiling, wondering whether they would lose everything if they or a loved one got sick. Because of this law, they don’t have to worry about being denied coverage due to a pre-existing condition like diabetes or watching their coverage being capped during a cancer treatment. Because of the law, they are able to get free preventive screenings that can save their lives and improve their health. Today’s victory is also for all the young people who can stay on their parents’ insurance plan until they turn 26 years old, and for the millions of low-income families and people with disabilities receiving health care because their states expanded Medicaid under this law.</p>



<p>After more than a decade of attacks on the Affordable Care Act through the Congress and the courts, today’s decision – the third major challenge to the law that the U.S. Supreme Court has rejected – it is time move forward and keep building on this landmark law.<br><br>That is what we are doing thanks to the American Rescue Plan, which has lowered health care costs and expanded coverage for millions of&nbsp;Americans through the Affordable Care Act. More than 1.2 million Americans signed up for coverage under the law through a special enrollment period I established during this pandemic, which people can still sign up for through August 15<sup>th</sup>. And&nbsp;I look forward to working with the Congress to build on this law so that the American people will continue to have access to quality and affordable health care.<br><br>Today’s decision affirms that the Affordable Care Act is stronger than ever, delivers for the American people, and gets us closer to fulfilling our moral obligation to ensure that, here in America, health care is a right and not a privilege.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in a Meeting with Members of the Texas State Senate and Texas House of Representatives</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/16/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-meeting-with-members-of-the-texas-state-senate-and-texas-house-of-representatives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room  11:18 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So let me begin today by saying thank you to all of you.  You are courageous leaders and you&#8217;re American patriots.  And so, I&#8217;m very pleased to welcome you &#8212; and for many of you, welcome you back &#8212; to the White House to have yet another&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Roosevelt Room </em></p>



<p>11:18 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So let me begin today by saying thank you to all of you.  You are courageous leaders and you&#8217;re American patriots. <br><br>And so, I&#8217;m very pleased to welcome you &#8212; and for many of you, welcome you back &#8212; to the White House to have yet another very important conversation, and this time about one of the most important pillars of our democracy, which is about the fundamental right to vote.  <br><br>And when we look at what has happened in Texas, we look at what&#8217;s happening around the country, I think it&#8217;s important to remember: We talk about the right to vote, and the right to vote is a given.  All citizens have the right to vote.  Constitutionally, it is their right.<br><br>What we are seeing are examples of an attempt to interfere with that right and attempt to marginalize and take from people a right that has already been given.  We are not asking for the bestowal of a right; we are talking about the preservation of a right that is the right of citizenship.  And it&#8217;s that fundamental.  It is that fundamental. <br><br>And so, when I look at that and the fact that Americans are at risk of losing their access to their right &#8212; they still have the right, but losing access to that right &#8212; we know we have a great challenge in front of us, and therefore, a fight, which is to fight for every American’s right &#8212; meaningful right to vote.<br><br>And so that&#8217;s where we are.  And, of course, since 2013 and the gutting of Shelby &#8212; in the Shelby v. Holder case, we have seen exactly what we fear when that case came down in 2013. Because that case was an opening of a door to allow states to do what otherwise we have protected against, which is states putting in place laws that are designed, in many cases quite intentionally, to make it difficult for people to vote. <br><br>And so this is what we&#8217;ve seen over and over again, and what&#8217;s happening right now in Texas is, of course, a very clear and current example of that.  So, to the &#8212; to the point of what we must do collectively to ensure that every American retains their right to vote, our administration &#8212; President Biden and myself and our administration are here to make very clear that we will do everything in our power as an administration to lift up the voices of those who seek to preserve the right of the people to vote. <br><br>We&#8217;re not telling people how to vote.  And, frankly, this is not a Democratic or a Republican issue; this is an American issue.  This is an American issue. <br><br>When we look at these attempts to infringe on people&#8217;s access to voting, we know that it is going to impact people &#8212; Americans with disabilities, seniors, students, people of every walk of life. <br><br>When we look at these laws that are designed to interfere with poll workers &#8212; well, let&#8217;s think about that for a moment.  I have voted and been &#8212; and visited with these wonderful American volunteers, the poll workers, when I&#8217;ve gone to vote at the local elementary school, when I&#8217;ve gone to vote at the local church.  This is who we&#8217;re talking about, and interfering with them in what they are doing as part of their civic duty. <br><br>These are some of the issues that are at play.  And so, I welcome you.  I welcome you on behalf the President and myself.  As you know, he&#8217;s in Europe right now.  But we wanted to greet you here in the Roosevelt Room as an extension of the importance of the work you are doing, not only on behalf of the people of Texas, but the people of our country and our nation as a whole. <br><br>And while we will meet, we will also talk about the administration&#8217;s absolute commitment to seeing Congress &#8212; the United States Congress &#8212; pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act and to pass the For the People Act to, again, put back in place the protections that existed before and to ensure, as we go forward, that as there are new attacks on the access to the polls and voting, that we head them off in a way that ensures again that the people retain their right to vote however they choose, but unimpeded.  <br><br>So with that, I want to thank all of you, and we will talk about Senate Bill 7 and how it clearly has been written in a way that will make it difficult for people and what you all are doing as courageous leaders that, again, speak up for the people.  And that is what you are doing.  <br><br>So, thank you all, and I look forward to our discussion.  And let us begin.  Let us begin.  So, thank you. <br><br> 11:24 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement From Senior Advisor and Chief Spokesperson Symone Sanders on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with Texas State Legislators on Voting Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/16/statement-from-senior-advisor-and-chief-spokesperson-symone-sanders-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-texas-state-legislators-on-voting-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The right to vote is fundamental to our democracy—and defending that fundamental right is the most important work we can do as a nation. Today Vice President Harris met with 16 members of the Texas State Senate and Texas House of Representatives, who in May blocked passage of legislation that would have made it significantly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The right to vote is fundamental to our democracy—and defending that fundamental right is the most important work we can do as a nation. Today Vice President Harris met with 16 members of the Texas State Senate and Texas House of Representatives, who in May blocked passage of legislation that would have made it significantly harder for the people of Texas to vote. They discussed the restrictive voting measures that already exist in Texas, the measures that would have been added under Texas Senate Bill 7 (SB7), and the path forward to make voting more accessible.</p>



<p>Members spoke about the real impact and effects of denying people the right to vote – including that it could lead to denial of health care, underfunding education, and failure to prepare the state to address emergency situations such as when the state had a power outage.</p>



<p>Members also spoke about the strength of building diverse coalitions around common values such as faith, education, and economic opportunity.</p>



<p>Members thanked the Vice President for lifting up the work to protect the right to vote and to make it more accessible to all Texans – and by extension – all Americans.</p>



<p>Over the last few weeks, the Vice President has spoken with a number of local and national leaders. On Monday, the Vice President held her first meeting on the ground regarding voting rights while she was in Greenville, South Carolina. Today’s meeting continued that work. The Vice President’s work moving forward will focus on educating the American people about voting rights attacks, building a coalition to bring together Americans concerned about their right and ability to vote, advancing federal legislation, registering voters per the President&#8217;s Executive Order on March 7th, and advocating for democratic principles worldwide.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration will protect the fundamental right to vote for all Americans regardless of where they live—by working to make voting accessible for all Americans and make sure every vote is counted through a transparent process.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title> Remarks by President Biden Before Air Force One Departure </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/16/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Geneva AirportGeneva, Switzerland 8:21 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:  I owe my last question an apology.  I shouldn’t have &#8212; I shouldn’t have been such a wise guy with the last answer I gave. Anyway, thanks for being here.  And most of you have been here the whole route.  I really do think &#8212; not me, but I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Geneva Airport<br>Geneva, Switzerland</p>



<p>8:21 P.M. CEST<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I owe my last question an apology.  I shouldn’t have &#8212; I shouldn’t have been such a wise guy with the last answer I gave.<br> <br>Anyway, thanks for being here.  And most of you have been here the whole route.  I really do think &#8212; not me, but I think we, the country, has put a different face on where we&#8217;ve been and where we&#8217;re going.  And I feel good about it.  I feel &#8212;<br> <br>You know, one of things that I think, understandably, there was a good deal of skepticism about: would the G7 sign on and give America back it&#8217;s, sort of, leadership role.  I think it did.  It wasn’t me, but it meant they&#8217;re glad America is back.  They&#8217;re glad America is back, and they acted that way. <br> <br>And then, when we went to NATO, I think it was the same thing.  We had really good meetings there and real response, as well as the EU.  I didn’t get one single person &#8212; not one of the world leaders said to us anything other than thanking me for arranging a meeting with Putin.  And I thought, quite frankly, I was in a much better position to represent the West, after the previous three meetings with Putin, that &#8212; knowing that the rest of the West was behind us.  And so, I think &#8212; so I owe them all a debt of gratitude.<br> <br>Q    Mr. President, since you&#8217;re now heading home, can I just ask you briefly about two domestic issues?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not sure I can answer them, but &#8212;<br> <br>Q    If you could.  First would be this fate of the infrastructure bill.  There&#8217;s now a bipartisan group that has a new offer.  Have you had time to review it?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I haven’t seen it.  No, I &#8212; I&#8217;m not being &#8212; I honestly haven’t seen it.  I don’t know what the details are.  I know that my Chief of Staffs thinks there’s some room that there may be a means by which to get this done.  And I know that Schumer and Nancy have moved forward on a reconciliation provision as well.  So I&#8217;m still hoping we could put together the two bookends here.<br> <br>Q    And the second issue is: Yesterday &#8212; or earlier this week, Mitch McConnell said that if Republicans were to take back the Senate in 2022, he did not see a way that you could get a Supreme Court justice confirmed.  Do you have a response to that?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Uh &#8212;<br> <br>Q    This would be next year.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, I know.  I know.  The answer is: Mitch is &#8212; Mitch has been nothing but &#8220;no&#8221; for a long time.  And I&#8217;m sure he means exactly what he says, but we&#8217;ll see.<br> <br>Q    Mr. President, did you talk with President Putin about the Iran nuclear deal? <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yes.<br> <br>Q    Did you make &#8212; find a way?  What did you discuss, and did you find a way to make some progress?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  It was about how we would jointly work, and I&#8217;m not going to discuss what we discussed.<br> <br>Q    Mr. President, Kaitlan&#8217;s question that you answered at the very end there, that you came over to talk about, I think at the heart of it was this question of whether or not you seem overly optimistic, given that &#8212; what we all listened to President Putin essentially say the same, old things that he’s said forever.  He &#8212; you know, rejecting all responsibility for all that stuff. <br> <br>And I guess the question that she was trying to get, and maybe you could take another stab at it, is: What concrete evidence do you have from these three &#8212; three plus hours that suggest that any movement has been made?<br> <br>And I don’t &#8212; I don’t mean that to be &#8212; I’m not &#8212; it’s not meant to be a &#8212; (inaudible) &#8212;<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, no, no.  No.  I know, but you’re all &#8212;<br> <br>Q    &#8212; (inaudible) question.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Look, to be a good reporter, you got to be negative.  You got to have a negative view of life &#8212; okay? &#8212; it seems to me, the way you all &#8212; you never ask a positive question. <br> <br>Why, in fact, having agreement &#8212; we’ll find out.  We have an agreement to work on a major arms control agreement. <br> <br>I started on working on arms control agreements back all the way during the Cold War.  If we could do one when the Cold War, why couldn’t we do one now?  We’ll see.  We will see whether or not it happens. <br> <br>But what do you &#8212; I mean, the thing that always amazes me about the questions &#8212; and I apologize for having been short on this before.<br> <br>If you were in my position, would you say, “Well, I don’t think, man, anything is going to happen.  This is going to be really rough.  I think it’s going to really be bad”?  You’d guarantee nothing happens.  You’d guarantee nothing happens.<br> <br>And so, so far &#8212;<br> <br>Q    So, there’s a value to &#8212;<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  There’s a value to being realistic and put on an optimistic front, an optimistic face.<br> <br>Look, you all said the same thing about the, you know, what was going to happen when we had the first meeting of the &#8212; of &#8212; of the seven.  “Oh, Biden &#8212; they’re not going to &#8212; they’re not going to buy Biden’s stuff.  They’re really not really…”<br> <br>Any of you find that?  Did that happen?  Any of it?  A little bit?  Just a little sliver of it? <br> <br>When I went to meet with NATO &#8212; “Oh boy, they’re not going to be happy.  They’re all going to be against Biden meeting with Putin.  They’re not going to want that.”  Did you hear a single, solitary syllable?<br> <br>Now, what would have happen if I had said, before I went into those negotiations, “You know, I think it’s going to be really hard.  I think it’s going to be really difficult.  I’m not so optimistic about &#8212; I don’t see anybody really changing”? <br> <br>And the same way when I met with the EU.  “The EU is not going to like the way Biden is operating.” <br> <br>Q    But this is Vladimir Putin.  I mean, can you be optimistic about his change?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Sure, it’s Vladimir Putin.  But, look, it was also &#8212; I don’t want to compare him to Putin, but it was &#8212; the French President said he will never go for more money for NATO.  Guess what?  He’s agreed. <br> <br>Every &#8212; I mean, look, guys, I’m going to drive you all crazy because I know you want me to always put a negative thrust on things, particularly in public, and negotiate in public. <br> <br>I don’t have to trust somebody &#8212; we didn’t have to trust somebody to get START II.  It wasn&#8217;t a about our trust &#8212; “Well, I trust the Russians.  I can tell, man, they&#8217;re really &#8212; they&#8217;re &#8212; I can look in his eye, and they&#8217;re really very, very truthful.”  It&#8217;s not that at all. <br> <br>You have to figure out what the other guy&#8217;s self-interest is.  Their self-interest.  I don&#8217;t trust anybod- &#8212; look, I&#8217;ve got to get in the plane, but I&#8217;ll say it &#8212; you&#8217;ll hear me say this more than once.<br> <br>Q    It’s your plane.  You can go when you want.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yeah, no, but &#8212; no, but here’s the thing: Folks, I &#8212; I don&#8217;t see any benefit ever to begin a negotiation as &#8212; and, I mean, you&#8217;re the brightest people in the country.  You&#8217;re the most informed people on detail.  I&#8217;m not being solicitous; you are.  But it makes no sense for me to negotiate with you.  It makes no sense for me to tell you what I&#8217;m about to do.  It makes &#8212; not because I want to hide anything from you.  Why would I telegraph that?<br> <br>Q    Did he do anything that surprised you, sir?<br> <br>AIDE:  Sir, we need to go.  Sir, we really have to go. <br> <br>Q    Was there any moment that you were really surprised by?<br> <br>AIDE:  Sir &#8212; thank you, guys.  Thank you, guys.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, I wasn’t surprised because I was convinced that &#8212; let me choose my words.  Russia is in a very, very difficult spot right now.  They are being squeezed by China.  They want desperately to remain a major power.  You all are writing about, not illegitimately, “Biden already gave Putin what he wants: legitimacy, standing in the world stage with the President of the United States.”  They desperately want to have &#8212; be relevant. <br> <br>They have &#8212; and they don&#8217;t want to be known as, as some critics have pointed and said, you know, the &#8220;Upper Volta with nuclear weapons.&#8221;  It matters.  And I found it matters to almost every world leader &#8212; no matter where they&#8217;re from &#8212; how they&#8217;re perceived, their standing in the world.  It matters to them.  It matters to them in terms of their support at home as well. <br> <br>And so I think that there is &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to think how to shorten this so I can get in the plane. <br> <br>I&#8217;m of the view that, in the last three to five years, the world has reached a fundamental inflection point about what it&#8217;s going to look like 10 years from now.  I mean it literally.  It&#8217;s not hyperbole.  It&#8217;s not like I&#8217;m trying to pump it up.  I think it&#8217;s a genuine reality. <br> <br>And so each of the countries in &#8212; around the world, particularly those who had real power at one time or still do, are wondering: What &#8212; how do I maintain and sustain our leadership in the world?  That&#8217;s what the United States is going through right now.  How do we sustain us being the leading, the most powerful, and most democratic country in the world?  A lot is going on. <br> <br>I don&#8217;t know about you, I never anticipated, notwithstanding no matter how persuasive President Trump was, that we&#8217;d have people attacking and breaking down the doors of the United States Capitol.  I didn&#8217;t think that would happen.  I didn&#8217;t think we’d &#8212; I&#8217;d see that in my lifetime.  But it&#8217;s reinforced what I&#8217;ve always known and what I got taught by my political science professors and by the senior members of the Senate that I admired when I got there: that every generation has to re-establish the basis of its fight for democracy.  I mean, for real, literally have to do it. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ve never seen, including during &#8212; since the Civil War, such an outward assault on voting rights.  I mean, just a flat assault.  I didn&#8217;t anticipate that happening four years ago, but it&#8217;s happening now. <br> <br>So, there&#8217;s a lot at stake.  Each of the countries, we have our own concerns and problems, but we still &#8212; as long as I&#8217;m President, we are going to stick to the notion that we&#8217;re open, accountable, and transparent.  And I think that&#8217;s an important message to send the world. <br> <br>Thank you all so much.<br> <br>8:31 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in Press Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/16/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hôtel du Parc des Eaux-VivesGeneva, Switzerland 7:20 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It&#8217;s been a long day for you all.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; I know it was easy getting into the &#8212; the pre-meeting.&#160; There was no problem getting through those doors, was it &#8212; was there?&#160;&#160;Anyway, hello, everyone.&#160; Well, I’ve just finished the &#8212; the last meeting&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Hôtel du Parc des Eaux-Vives<br>Geneva, Switzerland</p>



<p>7:20 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a long day for you all.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I know it was easy getting into the &#8212; the pre-meeting.&nbsp; There was no problem getting through those doors, was it &#8212; was there?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Anyway, hello, everyone.&nbsp; Well, I’ve just finished the &#8212; the last meeting of this week&#8217;s long trip, the U.S.-Russian Summit.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I know there were a lot of hype around this meeting, but it’s pretty straightforward to me &#8212; the meeting.&nbsp; One, there is no substitute, as those of you who have covered me for a while know, for a face-to-face dialogue between leaders.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; And President Putin and I had a &#8212; share a unique responsibility to manage the relationship between two powerful and proud countries &#8212; a relationship that has to be stable and predictable.&nbsp; And it should be able to &#8212; we should be able to cooperate where it&#8217;s in our mutual interests.<br>&nbsp;<br>And where we have differences, I wanted President Putin to understand why I say what I say and why I do what I do, and how we’ll respond to specific kinds of actions that harm America&#8217;s interests.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, I told President Putin my agenda is not against Russia or anyone else; it&#8217;s for the American people: fighting COVID-19; rebuilding our economy; reestablishing our relationships around the world with our allies and friends; and protecting our people.&nbsp; That’s my responsibility as President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I also told him that no President of the United States could keep faith with the American people if they did not speak out to defend our democratic values, to stand up for the universal rights and fundamental freedoms that all men and women have, in our view.&nbsp; That’s just part of the DNA of our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, human rights is going to always be on the table, I told him.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about just going after Russia when they violate human rights; it&#8217;s about who we are.&nbsp; How could I be the President of the United States of America and not speak out against the violation of human rights?<br>&nbsp;<br>I told him that, unlike other countries, including Russia, we&#8217;re uniquely a product of an idea.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard me say this before, again and again, but I&#8217;m going to keep saying it.&nbsp; What’s that idea?&nbsp; We don&#8217;t derive our rights from the government; we possess them because we&#8217;re born &#8212; period.&nbsp; And we yield them to a government.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, at the forum, I pointed out to him that that’s why we&#8217;re going raise our concerns about cases like Aleksey Navalny.&nbsp; I made it clear to President Putin that we&#8217;ll continue to raise issues of fundamental human rights because that&#8217;s what we are, that&#8217;s who we are.&nbsp; The idea is: &#8220;We hold these truths self-evident that all men and women…&#8221;&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t lived up to it completely, but we&#8217;ve always widened the arc of commitment and included more and more people.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I raised the case of two wrongfully imprisoned American citizens: Paul Whelan and Trevor Reed.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also raised the ability of Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty to operate, and the importance of a free press and freedom of speech.<br>&nbsp;<br>I made it clear that we will not tolerate attempts to violate our democratic sovereignty or destabilize our democratic elections, and we would respond.<br>&nbsp;<br>The bottom line is, I told President Putin that we need to have some basic rules of the road that we can all abide by.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also said there are areas where there&#8217;s a mutual interest for us to cooperate, for our people &#8212; Russian and American people &#8212; but also for the benefit of the world and the security of the world.&nbsp; One of those areas is strategic stability.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You asked me many times what was I going to discuss with Putin.&nbsp; Before I came, I told you I only negotiate with the individual.&nbsp; And now I can tell you what I was intending to do all along, and that is to discuss and raise the issue of strategic stability and try to set up a mechanism whereby we dealt with it.<br>&nbsp;<br>We discussed in detail the next steps our countries need to take on arms control measures &#8212; the steps we need to take to reduce the risk of unintended conflict.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’m pleased that he agreed today to launch a bilateral strategic stability dialogue &#8212; diplomatic speak for saying, get our military experts and our &#8212; our diplomats together to work on a mechanism that can lead to control of new and dangerous and sophisticated weapons that are coming on the scene now that reduce the times of response, that raise the prospects of accidental war.&nbsp; And we went into some detail of what those weapons systems were.<br>&nbsp;<br>Another area we spent a great deal of time on was cyber and cybersecurity.&nbsp; I talked about the proposition that certain critical infrastructure should be off limits to attack &#8212; period &#8212; by cyber or any other means.&nbsp; I gave them a list, if I&#8217;m not mistaken &#8212; I don&#8217;t have it in front of me &#8212; 16 specific entities; 16 defined as critical infrastructure under U.S. policy, from the energy sector to our water systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, the principle is one thing.&nbsp; It has to be backed up by practice.&nbsp; Responsible countries need to take action against criminals who conduct ransomware activities on their territory.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we agreed to task experts in both our &#8212; both our countries to work on specific understandings about what’s off limits and to follow up on specific cases that originate in other countries &#8212; either of our countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>There is a long list of other issues we spent time on, from the urgent need to preserve and reopen the humanitarian corridors in Syria so that we can get food &#8212; just simple food and basic necessities to people who are starving to death; how to build it and how it is in the interest of both Russia and the United States to ensure that Iran &#8212; Iran &#8212; does not acquire nuclear weapons.&nbsp; We agreed to work together there because it&#8217;s as much interest &#8212; Russia&#8217;s interest as ours.&nbsp; And to how we can ensure the Arctic remains a region of cooperation rather than conflict.<br>&nbsp;<br>I caught part of President&#8217;s &#8212; Putin&#8217;s press conference, and he talked about the need for us to be able to have some kind of modus operandi where we dealt with making sure the Arctic was, in fact, a free zone.<br>&nbsp;<br>And to how we can each contribute to the shared effort of preventing a resurgence of terrorism in Afghanistan.&nbsp; It&#8217;s very much in &#8212; in the interest of Russia not to have a resurgence of terrorism in Afghanistan.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are also areas that are more challenging.&nbsp; I communicated the United States’ unwavering commitment to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We agreed to pursue diplomacy related to the Minsk Agreement.&nbsp; And I shared our concerns about Belarus.&nbsp; He didn&#8217;t disagree with what happened; he just has a different perspective of what to do about it.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I know you have a lot of questions, so let me close with this:&nbsp;It was important to meet in person so there can be no mistake about or misrepresentations about what I wanted to communicate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I did what I came to do: Number one, identify areas of practical work our two countries can do to advance our mutual interests and also benefit the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Two, communicate directly &#8212; directly &#8212; that the United States will respond to actions that impair our vital interests or those of our allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>And three, to clearly lay out our country’s priorities and our values so he heard it straight from me.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I must tell you, the tone of the entire meetings &#8212; I guess it was a total of four hours &#8212; was &#8212; was good, positive.&nbsp; There wasn’t any &#8212; any strident action taken.&nbsp; Where we disagreed &#8212; I disagreed, stated where it was.&nbsp; Where he disagreed, he stated.&nbsp; But it was not done in a hyperbolic atmosphere.&nbsp; That is too much of what’s been going on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Over this last week, I believe &#8212; I hope &#8212; the United States has shown the world that we are back, standing with our Allies. &nbsp;We rallied our fellow democracies to make concert &#8212; concerted commitments to take on the biggest challenges our world faces.<br>&nbsp;<br>And now we’ve established a clear basis on how we intend to deal with Russia and the U.S.-Russia relationship.<br>&nbsp;<br>There’s more work ahead.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not suggesting that any of this is done, but we’ve gotten a lot of business done on this trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>And before I take your questions, I want to say one last thing.&nbsp; Folks, look, this is about &#8212; this about how we move from here.&nbsp; This is &#8212; I listened to, again, a significant portion of what President Putin&#8217;s press conference was, and as he pointed out, this is about practical, straightforward, no-nonsense decisions that we have to make or not make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ll find out within the next six months to a year whether or not we actually have a strategic dialogue that matters.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll find out whether we work to deal with everything from release of people in Russian prisons or not.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll find out whether we have a cybersecurity arrangement that begins to bring some order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Because, look, the countries that most are likely to be damaged &#8212; failure to do that &#8212; are the major countries.&nbsp; For example, when I talked about the pipeline that cyber hit for $5 million &#8212; that ransomware hit in the United States, I looked at him and I said, &#8220;Well, how would you feel if ransomware took on the pipelines from your oil fields?&#8221;&nbsp; He said it would matter.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not about just our self-interest; it&#8217;s about a mutual self-interest.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll take your questions.&nbsp; And as usual, folks, they gave me a list of the people I&#8217;m going to call on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, Jonathan, Associated Press.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; U.S. intelligence has said that Russia tried to interfere in the last two presidential elections, and that Russia groups are behind hacks like SolarWinds and some of the ransomware attacks you just mentioned.&nbsp; Putin, in his news conference just now, accepted no responsibility for any misbehavior.&nbsp; Your predecessor opted not to demand that Putin stop these disruptions.&nbsp; So what is something concrete, sir, that you achieved today to prevent that from happening again?&nbsp; And what were the consequences you threatened?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;Whether I stopped it from happening again &#8212; he knows I will take action, like we did when &#8212; this last time out. &nbsp;What happened was: We, in fact, made it clear that we were not going to continue to allow this to go on. &nbsp;The end result was we ended up withdrawing &#8212; they went withdrawing ambassadors, and we closed down some of their facilities in the United States, et cetera. &nbsp;And he knows there are consequences.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, look, one of the consequences that I know &#8212; I don&#8217;t know; I shouldn&#8217;t say this; it’s unfair of me &#8212; I suspect you may all think doesn&#8217;t matter, but I&#8217;m confidence it matters to him &#8212; confident it matter to him and other world leaders of big nations: his credibility worldwide shrinks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let&#8217;s get this straight: How would it be if the United States were viewed by the rest of the world as interfering with the elections directly of other countries, and everybody knew it?&nbsp; What would it be like if we engaged in activities that he is engaged in?&nbsp; It diminishes the standing of a country that is desperately trying to make sure it maintains its standing as a major world power.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so it&#8217;s not just what I do; it&#8217;s what the actions that other countries take &#8212; in this case, Russia &#8212; that are contrary to international norms.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the price they pay.&nbsp; They are not &#8212; they are not able to dictate what happens in the world.&nbsp; There are other nations of significant consequence &#8212; i.e. the United States of America being one of them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, just a quick follow on the same theme of consequences.&nbsp; You said, just now, that you spoke to him a lot about human rights.&nbsp; What did you say would happen if opposition leader Aleksey Navalny dies?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I made it clear to him that I believe the consequences of that would be devastating for Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll go back to the same point: What do you think happens when he&#8217;s saying, &#8220;It&#8217;s not about hurting Navalny,&#8221; this &#8212; you know, all the stuff he says to rationalize the treatment of Navalny &#8212; and then he dies in prison?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I pointed out to him that it matters a great deal when a country, in fact &#8212; and they asked me why I thought that it was important to continue to have problems with the President of Syria.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;Because he&#8217;s in violation of an international norm.&nbsp; It&#8217;s called a Chemical Weapons Treaty.&nbsp; Can&#8217;t be trusted.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s about trust.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about their ability to influence other nations in a positive way.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, would you like to trade our economy for Russia&#8217;s economy?&nbsp; Would you like to trade?&nbsp; And, by the way, we talked about trade.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any problem with doing business with Russia, as long as they do it based upon international norms. It&#8217;s in our interest to see the Russian people do well economically.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a problem with that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But if they do not act according to international norms, then guess what?&nbsp; That will not &#8212; that only won&#8217;t it happen with us, it will not happen with other nations.&nbsp; And he kind of talked about that &#8212; didn&#8217;t he, today? &#8212; about how the need to reach out to other countries to invest in Russia.&nbsp; They won&#8217;t as long as they are convinced that, in fact, the violations &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, the American businessman who was in house arrest.&nbsp; And I pointed out, &#8220;You want to get American business to invest?&nbsp; Let him go.&nbsp; Change the dynamic.”&nbsp; Because American businessmen, they&#8217;re not &#8212; they’re not ready to show up.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want to hang around in Moscow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, I &#8212; look, guys, I know we make foreign policy out to be this great, great skill that somehow is, sort of, like a secret code.&nbsp; Pract- &#8212; all foreign policy is, is a logical extension of personal relationships.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the way human nature functions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And understand, when you run a country that does not abide by international norms, and yet you need those international norms to be somehow managed so that you can participate in the benefits that flow from them, it hurts you.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a satisfying answer: &#8220;Biden said he&#8217;d invade Russia.&#8221;&nbsp; You know, it is not &#8212; you know.&nbsp; By the way, that was a joke.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not true. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But my generic point is, it is &#8212; it is more complicated than that.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>David Sanger.&nbsp; I thought I saw David.&nbsp; There he is.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; In the run-up to this discussion, there’s been a lot of talk about the two countries spilling down into a Cold War.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if there was anything that you emerged from in the discussion that made you think that he &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; With your permission, I’m going to take my coat off.&nbsp; The sun is hot.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; anything that would make you think that Mr. Putin has decided to move away from his fundamental role as a disrupter, particularly a disrupter of NATO and the United States?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And if I could also just follow up on your description of how you gave him a list of critical infrastructure in the United States.&nbsp; Did you lay out very clearly what it was that the penalty would be for interfering in that critical infrastructure?&nbsp; Did you leave that vague?&nbsp; Did he respond in any way to it?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me answer your first &#8212; well, I’ll second question, first.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I pointed out to him that we have significant cyber capability.&nbsp; And he knows it.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t know exactly what it is, but it&#8217;s significant.&nbsp; And if, in fact, they violate these basic norms, we will respond with cyber.&nbsp; He knows.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the cyber way.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; In the cyber way.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, I &#8212; I think that the last thing he wants now is a Cold War.&nbsp; Without quoting him &#8212; which I don&#8217;t think is appropriate &#8212; let me ask a rhetorical question: You got a multi-thousand-mile border with China.&nbsp; China is moving ahead, hellbent on election, as they say, seeking to be the most powerful economy in the world and the largest and the most powerful military in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>You&#8217;re in a situation where your economy is struggling, you need to move it in a more aggressive way, in terms of growing it.&nbsp; And you &#8212; I don&#8217;t think he&#8217;s looking for a Cold War with the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s about a &#8212; as I said to him, I said, “Your generation and mine are about 10 years apart.&nbsp; This is not a &#8216;kumbaya&#8217; moment, as you used to say back in the &#8217;60s in the United States, like, &#8216;Let&#8217;s hug and love each other.&#8217;&nbsp; But it&#8217;s clearly not in anybody&#8217;s interest &#8212; your country’s or mine &#8212; for us to be in a situation where we&#8217;re in a new Cold War.&#8221;&nbsp; And I truly believe he thinks that &#8212; he understands that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But that does not mean he&#8217;s ready to, quote, figuratively speaking, “lay down his arms,” and say, “Come on.”&nbsp; He still, I believe, is concerned about being, quote, “encircled.”&nbsp; He still is concerned that we, in fact, are looking to take him down, et cetera.&nbsp; He still has those concerns, but I don&#8217;t think they are the driving force as to the kind of relationship he&#8217;s looking for with the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Jennifer.&nbsp; Jennifer Jacobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Is there a particular reason why the summit lasted only about three hours?&nbsp; We know you had maybe allotted four to five hours.&nbsp; Was there any reason it ran shorter?<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, did &#8212; President Putin said that there were no threats or scare tactics issued.&nbsp; Do you agree with that assessment, that there were no threats or scare tactics?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, did you touch on Afghanistan and the safe withdrawal of troops?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes, yes, and yes.&nbsp; Let me go back to the first part.<br>&nbsp;<br>The reason it didn&#8217;t go longer is: When is the last time two heads of state have spent over two hours in direct conversation across a table, going into excruciating detail?&nbsp; You may know of a time; I don&#8217;t.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t think of one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we didn&#8217;t need, as we got through, when we brought in the larger group &#8212; our defense, our intelligence, and our foreign &#8212; well, our &#8212; my foreign minister &#8212; wasn’t the foreign minister &#8212; my Secretary of State was with me the whole time &#8212; our ambassador, et cetera.&nbsp; We brought everybody in.&nbsp; We had covered so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so there was a summary done by him and by me of what we covered.&nbsp; Lavrov and Blinken talked about what we had covered.&nbsp; We raised things that required more amplification or made sure we didn&#8217;t have any misunderstandings.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so it was &#8212; it was &#8212; kind of, after two hours there, we looked at each other like, “Okay, what next?”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What is going to happen next is we&#8217;re going to be able to look back &#8212; look ahead in three to six months, and say, “Did the things we agreed to sit down and try to work out, did it work?&nbsp; Do we &#8212; are we closer to a major strategic stability talks and progress?&nbsp; Are we further along in terms of…” &#8212; and go down the line.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be the test.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not sitting here saying because the President and I agreed that we would do these things, that all of a sudden, it&#8217;s going to work.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not saying that.&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is I think there&#8217;s a genuine prospect to significantly improve relations between our two countries without us giving up a single, solitary thing based on principle and/or values.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There were no threats issued?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no, no.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; There were no threats.&nbsp; There were &#8212; as a matter of fact, I heard he quoted my mom and quoted other people today.&nbsp; There was &#8212; it was very, as we say &#8212; which will shock you, coming from me &#8212; somewhat colloquial.&nbsp; And we talked about basic, basic, fundamental things.&nbsp; There was a &#8212; it was &#8212; and you know how I am: I explain things based on personal basis.&nbsp; “What happens if,” for example.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, there are no threats, just simple assertions made.&nbsp; And no “Well, if you do that, then we&#8217;ll do this” &#8212; wasn’t anything I said.&nbsp; It was just letting him know where I stood; what I thought we could accomplish together; and what, in fact &#8212; if it was &#8212; if there were violations of American sovereignty, what would we do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you share what you asked him about Afghanistan?&nbsp; What was your particular request for Afghanistan and the U.S. troops?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, he asked us about Afghanistan.&nbsp; He said that he hopes that we&#8217;re able to maintain some peace and security, and I said, “That has a lot to do with you.”&nbsp; He indicated that he was prepared to, quote, “help” on Afghanistan &#8212; I won&#8217;t go into detail now; and help on &#8212; on Iran; and help on &#8212; and, in return, we told him what we wanted to do relative to bringing some stability and economic security or physical security to the people of Syria and Libya.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we had those discussions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yamiche.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Mr. President.&nbsp; Did you &#8212; you say that you didn&#8217;t issue any threats.&nbsp; Were there any ultimatums made when it comes to ransomware?&nbsp; And how will you measure success, especially when it comes to these working groups on Russian meddling and on cybersecurity?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, it’s going to be real easy.&nbsp; They either &#8212; for example, on cybersecurity, are we going to work out where they take action against ransomware criminals on Russian territory?&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t do it.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think they planned it, in this case.&nbsp; And they &#8212; are they going to act?&nbsp; We&#8217;ll find out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Will we commit &#8212; what can we commit to act in terms of anything affecting violating international norms that negatively affects Russia?&nbsp; What are we going to agree to do?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I think we have real opportunities to &#8212; to move.&nbsp; And I think that one of the things that I noticed when we had the larger meeting is that people who are very, very well-informed started thinking, “You know, this could be a real problem.”&nbsp; What happens if that ransomware outfit were sitting in Florida or Maine and took action, as I said, on their &#8212; their single lifeline to their economy: oil?&nbsp; That would be devastating.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re like &#8212; you could see them kind of go, &#8220;Oh, we do that,&#8221; but like, &#8220;Whoa.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s in &#8212; it&#8217;s in everybody&#8217;s interest that these things be acted on.&nbsp; We’ll see, though, what happens from these groups we put together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a quick follow-up question?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; The third one, yes.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, when President Putin was questioned today about human rights, he said the reason why he&#8217;s cracking down on opposition leaders is because he doesn&#8217;t want something like January 6th to happen in Russia.&nbsp; And he also said he doesn&#8217;t want to see groups formed like Black Lives Matter.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your response to that, please?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; My response is kind of what I communicated &#8212; that I think that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a ridiculous comparison.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one thing for literally criminals to break through cordon, go into the Capitol, kill a police officer, and be held unaccountable than it is for people objecting and marching on the Capitol and saying, “You are not allowing me to speak freely.&nbsp; You are not allowing me to do A, B, C, or D.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, they&#8217;re very different criteria.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Steve.&nbsp; Steve Holland, Reuters.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President &#8212; sorry &#8212; President Putin said he was satisfied with the answer about your comment about him being a &#8220;killer.&#8221;&nbsp; Could you give us your side on this?&nbsp; What did you tell him?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He’s satisfied.&nbsp; Why would I bring it up again?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And now that you’ve talked to him, do you believe you can trust him?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, this is not about trust; this is about self-interest and verification of self-interest.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s about.&nbsp; So, I &#8212; virtually almost &#8212; almost anyone that I would work out an agreement with that affected the American people&#8217;s interests, I don&#8217;t say, “Well, I trust you.&nbsp; No problem.&#8221;&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see what happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, as that old expression goes, “The proof of the pudding is in the eating.”&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to know shortly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Igor, Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, Mr. President.&nbsp; Hello, Mr. President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You want to go on the shade?&nbsp; You can&#8217;t &#8212; can you see?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah, yeah.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, I think you know attacks in civil society and the free &#8212; free press continue inside Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For example, Radio Free Europe &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Radio Liberty; Voice of America; Current Time TV channel, where I work, are branded foreign agents &#8212; and several other independent media.&nbsp; So, we are essentially being forced out in Russia 30 years after President Yeltsin invited us in.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My question is: After your talks with President Putin, how interested do you think he is in improving the media climate in Russia?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t put it that way, in terms of improving the climate.&nbsp; I would, in fact, put it in terms of how much interest does he have in burnishing Russia&#8217;s reputation that is not &#8212; is viewed as not being contrary to democratic principles and free speech.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s a judgment I cannot make.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not because I think he &#8212; he is interested in changing the nature of a closed society or closed government&#8217;s actions relative to what he thinks is the right of government to do what it does; it&#8217;s a very different approach.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, there&#8217;s a couple of really good biogra- &#8212; I told him I read a couple &#8212; I read most everything he&#8217;s written and the speeches he&#8217;s made.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I&#8217;ve read a couple of very good biographies, which many of you have as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think I pointed out to him that Russia had an opportunity &#8212; that brief shining moment after Gorbachev and after things began to change drastically &#8212; to actually generate a democratic government.&nbsp; But what happened was it failed and there was a great, great race among Russian intellectuals to determine what form of government would they choose and how would they choose it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And based on what I believe, Mr. Putin decided was that Russia has always been a major international power when it&#8217;s been totally united as a Russian state, not based on ideology &#8212; whether it was going back to Tsar and Commissar, straight through to the &#8212; the revolution &#8212; the Russian Revolution, and to where they are today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that it&#8217;s clear to me &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said it &#8212; that I think he decided that the way for Russia to be able to sustain itself as a great &#8212; quote, “great power” is to in fact unite the Russian people on just the strength of the government &#8212; the government controls &#8212; not necessarily ideologically, but the government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s the choice that was made.&nbsp; I think it &#8212; I &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to second guess whether it could have been fundamentally different.&nbsp; But I do think it does not lend itself to Russia maintaining itself as one of the great powers in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, one more question &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on COVID &#8212; on COVID-19, Mr. President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, could we ask you one more question, please, sir?&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; Did military response ever come up in this conversation today?&nbsp; Did you &#8212; in terms of the red lines that you laid down, is military response an option for a ransomware attack?<br>&nbsp;<br>And President Putin had called you, in his press conference, an “experienced person.”&nbsp; You famously told him he didn&#8217;t have a soul.&nbsp; Do you now have a deeper understanding of him after this meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on the military &#8212; military response, sir?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, we didn&#8217;t talk about military response.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the spirit, Mr. President, of you saying that there is no substitute for face-to-face dialogue, and also with what you said at NATO that the biggest problems right now are Russia and China &#8212; you&#8217;ve spoken many times about how you have spent perhaps more time with President Xi than any other world leader.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So is there going to become a time where you might call him, old friend to old friend, and ask him to open up China to the World Health Organization investigators who are trying to get to the bottom of COVID-19?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get something straight.&nbsp; We know each other well; we&#8217;re not old friends.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just pure business.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I guess, my question would be that you&#8217;ve said that you were going to press China.&nbsp; You signed on to the G7 communiqué that said you &#8212; the G7 were calling on China to open up to let the investigators in.&nbsp; But China basically says they don&#8217;t want to be interfered with anymore.&nbsp; So, what happens now?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The impact &#8212; the world&#8217;s attitude toward China as it develops.&nbsp; China is trying very hard to project itself as a responsible and &#8212; and a very, very forthcoming nation; that they are trying very hard to talk about how they&#8217;re taking and helping the world in terms of COVID-19 and vaccines.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re trying very hard.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, certain things you don&#8217;t have to explain to the people of the world.&nbsp; They see the results.&nbsp; Is China really actually trying to get to the bottom of this?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One thing we did discuss, as I told you, in the EU and at the G7 and with NATO: What we should be doing and what I&#8217;m going to make an effort to do is rally the world to work on what is going to be the physical mechanism available to detect, early on, the next pandemic and have a mechanism by which we can respond to it and respond to it early.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp; And we need to do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any progress on the detained Americans, sir?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did Putin say about Paul Whelan and Trevor Reed?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, what do you say to the families of the detained Americans?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, why are you so confident Russia &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The families of the detained Americans, I have hope for.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Say it again; we can&#8217;t hear you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I said the families of the detained Americans came up and we discussed it.&nbsp; We’re going to follow through with that discussion.&nbsp; I am &#8212; I am not going to walk away on that issue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why are you so confident he&#8217;ll change his behavior, Mr. President?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not confident he&#8217;ll change his behavior.&nbsp; Where the hell &#8212; what do you do all the time?&nbsp; When did I say I was confident?&nbsp; I said &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said in the next six months you&#8217;ll be able to determine &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I said &#8212; what I said was &#8212; let&#8217;s get it straight.&nbsp; I said: What will change their behavior is if the rest of world reacts to them and it diminishes their standing in the world.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not confident of anything; I&#8217;m just stating a fact.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But given his past behavior has not changed and, in that press conference, after sitting down with you for several hours, he denied any involvement in cyberattacks; he downplayed human rights abuses; he even refused to say Aleksey Navalny’s name.&nbsp; So how does that account to a constructive meeting, as President &#8212; President Putin framed it?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If you don’t understand that, you&#8217;re in the wrong business.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>7:53 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-Russia Presidential Joint Statement on Strategic Stability</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/16/u-s-russia-presidential-joint-statement-on-strategic-stability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 17:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, President of the United States of America Joseph R. Biden and President of the Russian Federation Vladimir Putin, note the United States and Russia have demonstrated that, even in periods of tension, they are able to make progress on our shared goals of ensuring predictability in the strategic sphere, reducing the risk of armed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We, President of the United States of America Joseph R. Biden and President of the Russian Federation Vladimir Putin, note the United States and Russia have demonstrated that, even in periods of tension, they are able to make progress on our shared goals of ensuring predictability in the strategic sphere, reducing the risk of armed conflicts and the threat of nuclear war.</p>



<p>The recent extension of the New START Treaty exemplifies our commitment to nuclear arms control. Today, we reaffirm the principle that a nuclear war cannot be won and must never be fought.</p>



<p>Consistent with these goals, the United States and Russia will embark together on an integrated bilateral Strategic Stability Dialogue in the near future that will be deliberate and robust. Through this Dialogue, we seek to lay the groundwork for future arms control and risk reduction measures.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on DACA Day</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-daca-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 22:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dreamers are Americans.&#160; Many have spent most of their lives in the United States.&#160; They live, study, work, and worship in our communities.&#160; They have served on the frontlines during the COVID-19 pandemic.&#160; In 2012, the Obama-Biden Administration created the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy.&#160; Since that date, DACA has allowed more than&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dreamers are Americans.&nbsp; Many have spent most of their lives in the United States.&nbsp; They live, study, work, and worship in our communities.&nbsp; They have served on the frontlines during the COVID-19 pandemic.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>In 2012, the Obama-Biden Administration created the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy.&nbsp; Since that date, DACA has allowed more than 800,000 immigrant youth who came to the United States as children to temporarily remain in our country, work lawfully, pursue their education and long for the day they could become citizens.</p>



<p>Twenty years ago, Congress introduced the first version of the bipartisan Dream Act, led by Senator Durbin (D-IL) and former Republican Senator Hatch.&nbsp; And over the years, bipartisan coalitions of lawmakers championed this bill.&nbsp; The&nbsp; American public overwhelmingly supports this legislation. But time and time again, the Senate has failed to act.</p>



<p>Only Congress can provide a permanent legislative fix to provide lasting stability for these young people and their families.  My immigration bill, the U.S. Citizenship Act, creates a pathway to citizenship for undocumented individuals in our country, including Dreamers.  In March, the House took a critical first step and passed the American Dream and Promise Act.   Congress must find a way to pass these legislative solutions and I will continue to work towards passage of legislation protecting Dreamers and creating a path to citizenship for  undocumented immigrants. These young people represent the best of America and we can’t let them down.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Guy Parmelin and Foreign Minister Ignazio Cassis of Switzerland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-guy-parmelin-and-foreign-minister-ignazio-cassis-of-switzerland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 22:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Guy Parmelin and Foreign Minister Ignazio Cassis of Switzerland.  President Biden thanked President Parmelin for hosting the U.S.-Russia Summit in Geneva on June 16, and he expressed appreciation for Switzerland’s unique historical role providing a neutral ground for diplomacy and negotiations.  The leaders discussed the strong&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Guy Parmelin and Foreign Minister Ignazio Cassis of Switzerland.  President Biden thanked President Parmelin for hosting the U.S.-Russia Summit in Geneva on June 16, and he expressed appreciation for Switzerland’s unique historical role providing a neutral ground for diplomacy and negotiations.  The leaders discussed the strong U.S.-Switzerland commercial, science and education, and security relationships.  President Biden thanked Switzerland for its 40 years of service as the U.S. Protecting Power in Iran.  He also welcomed Switzerland’s contribution to the global COVID-19 pandemic response including by hosting the Gavi vaccine alliance secretariat and its contributions to COVAX to facilitate equitable access and distribution of safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Excerpts from Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by Vice President Harris to the Brussels Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/15/excerpts-from-remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-vice-president-harris-to-the-brussels-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The truth is we face many shared challenges: The pandemic and the resulting economic uncertainty. Climate change, cyber threats, and the resulting security concerns. And, of course, the outright assault on democracy that is occurring around the globe. In the chaos of the crisis, Autocrats have become more destructive. Human rights abuses have multiplied. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The truth is we face many shared challenges: The pandemic and the resulting economic uncertainty. Climate change, cyber threats, and the resulting security concerns. And, of course, the outright assault on democracy that is occurring around the globe.</p>



<p>In the chaos of the crisis, Autocrats have become more destructive. Human rights abuses have multiplied. The rule of law that underpins our international order is under assault. Even basic truth, even basic facts, are being undermined by disinformation—chipping away at public confidence in our press and scientists, our courts and our elections.</p>



<p>I will never forget the horror and the heartbreak of January 6, 2021, when our United States Capitol, a beacon of democracy for so many, came under siege by a violent mob who refused to accept the results of a free and fair election. It is not enough to say we cannot let something like that ever happen again. We must commit and recommit our democratic principles and lead by example. We must reinforce our democratic institutions to deliver real results and instill trust.</p>



<p>There are barriers that stand in the way of doing that. Corruption is one such barrier.</p>



<p>Corruption causes the people to suffer. It stands in the way of progress. It stands in the way of hope.</p>



<p>Corruption can keep people from going to the doctor, sending their children to school, opening a small business, getting a fair trial. Corruption corrodes public trust and drives away investment. It compels migration. It causes violence. And it cannot stand. This month, we announced that for the first time ever, our Administration is designating the fight against corruption a core U.S. national security interest. Together with our allies, civil society, and the private sector, the United States will prioritize the fight against corruption to preserve democracy.</p>



<p>The fight against corruption is a fight won through accountability, through transparency. It is a fight won through strengthening the rule of law and also through the promotion of human rights.</p>



<p>Our democracies cannot be sustained when people are denied their rights, their freedom, their dignity. We must reckon with the injustices of the past and confront those that still persist.</p>



<p>A democracy&#8217;s strength depends on its ability to protect against injustice. When we make it possible for more people to fully participate, we improve communities, we improve countries, we improve our world. And that is why, wherever, whenever human rights are violated, we must stand together.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement From Senior Advisor and Chief Spokesperson Symone Sanders on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting With Immigrant Women Who Work in the Care Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/statement-from-senior-advisor-and-chief-spokesperson-symone-sanders-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-immigrant-women-who-work-in-the-care-economy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, on the ninth anniversary of the creation of the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) program, Vice President Kamala Harris met with immigrant women who work in the care economy, including two DACA recipients. U.S. Senators Bob Menendez (NJ) and Dick Durbin (IL), as well as Ai-Jen Poo and Jessica Morales Rocketto of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, on the ninth anniversary of the creation of the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) program, Vice President Kamala Harris met with immigrant women who work in the care economy, including two DACA recipients. U.S. Senators Bob Menendez (NJ) and Dick Durbin (IL), as well as Ai-Jen Poo and Jessica Morales Rocketto of the National Domestic Workers Alliance, also participated.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Vice President heard directly from two DACA recipients, Scarleth Herrera Lopez and Gloria Elizabeth Blanco; two Temporary Protected Status (TPS) recipients, Melissa Larette and Rukmani Bhattari Adhikari; and two green card holders, Yaquelin Lopez Chavez and Gilda Blanco. The women told the Vice President about the challenges they face on the frontlines during the pandemic, and how they and their loved ones have experienced the U.S. immigration system. The Vice President thanked the women for the critically important work they do, for their courage, and for sharing their personal stories with her and the group.<br>&nbsp;<br>During the conversation, the Vice President reiterated the urgent need for Congress to create a clear pathway to citizenship for Dreamers, farmworkers, and individuals with Temporary Protected Status, and she called on the U.S. Senate to pass the American Dream and Promise Act and the Farm Workforce Modernization Act. She thanked Chairman Durbin for his leadership on the American Dream and Promise Act, and Chairman Menendez for his leadership on the U.S. Citizenship Act.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###&nbsp;<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
