<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 19:07:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe&#160;Biden’s Call with President Macron of France, Chancellor Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Draghi of Italy, Prime Minister Johnson of the United&#160;Kingdom</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/21/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-call-with-president-macron-of-france-chancellor-scholz-of-germany-prime-minister-draghi-of-italy-prime-minister-johnson-of-the-united-kingdom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 19:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France, Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy, and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.  The leaders discussed their serious concerns about Russia’s brutal tactics in Ukraine, including its attacks on civilians. They underscored their continued support for Ukraine, including by providing security assistance to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France, Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy, and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.  The leaders discussed their serious concerns about Russia’s brutal tactics in Ukraine, including its attacks on civilians. They underscored their continued support for Ukraine, including by providing security assistance to the brave Ukrainians who are defending their country from Russian aggression, and humanitarian assistance to the millions of Ukrainians who have fled the violence. The leaders also reviewed recent diplomatic efforts in support of Ukraine’s effort to reach a ceasefire.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on our Nation’s&#160;Cybersecurity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/21/statement-by-president-biden-on-our-nations-cybersecurity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is a critical moment to accelerate our work to improve domestic cybersecurity and bolster our national resilience. &#160;I have previously warned about the potential that Russia could conduct malicious cyber activity against the United States, including as a response to the unprecedented economic costs we’ve imposed on Russia alongside our allies and partners. It’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This is a critical moment to accelerate our work to improve domestic cybersecurity and bolster our national resilience. &nbsp;I have previously warned about the potential that Russia could conduct malicious cyber activity against the United States, including as a response to the unprecedented economic costs we’ve imposed on Russia alongside our allies and partners. It’s part of Russia’s playbook. Today, my Administration is reiterating those warnings based on evolving intelligence that the Russian Government is exploring options for potential cyberattacks.</p>



<p>From day one, my Administration has worked to strengthen our national cyber defenses, mandating extensive cybersecurity measures for the Federal Government and those critical infrastructure sectors where we have authority to do so, and creating innovative public-private partnerships and initiatives to enhance cybersecurity across all our critical infrastructure. Congress has partnered with us on these efforts — we appreciate that Members of Congress worked across the aisle to require companies to report cyber incidents to the United States Government.</p>



<p>My Administration will continue to use every tool to deter, disrupt, and if necessary, respond to cyberattacks against critical infrastructure. But the Federal Government can’t defend against this threat alone. Most of America’s critical infrastructure is owned and operated by the private sector and critical infrastructure owners and operators must accelerate efforts to lock their digital doors. The Department of Homeland Security’s Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) has been actively working with organizations across critical infrastructure to rapidly <a href="http://www.CISA.gov/Shields-Up">share information and mitigation guidance</a> to help protect their systems and networks</p>



<p>If you have not already done so, I urge our private sector partners to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/21/fact-sheet-act-now-to-protect-against-potential-cyberattacks/">harden your cyber defenses immediately</a> by implementing the best practices we have developed together over the last year. You have the power, the capacity, and the responsibility to strengthen the cybersecurity and resilience of the critical services and technologies on which Americans rely. We need everyone to do their part to meet one of the defining threats of our time — your vigilance and urgency today can prevent or mitigate attacks tomorrow.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Act Now to Protect Against Potential&#160;Cyberattacks</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/21/fact-sheet-act-now-to-protect-against-potential-cyberattacks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49454</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris Administration has warned repeatedly about the potential for Russia to engage in malicious cyber activity against the United States in response to the unprecedented economic sanctions we have imposed.&#160; There is now evolving intelligence that Russia may be exploring options for potential cyberattacks. The Administration has prioritized strengthening cybersecurity defenses to prepare our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has warned repeatedly about the potential for Russia to engage in malicious cyber activity against the United States in response to the unprecedented economic sanctions we have imposed.&nbsp; There is now evolving intelligence that Russia may be exploring options for potential cyberattacks.</p>



<p>The Administration has prioritized strengthening cybersecurity defenses to prepare our Nation for threats since day one. President Biden’s Executive Order is modernizing the Federal Government defenses and improving the security of widely-used technology. The President has launched public-private action plans to shore up the cybersecurity of the electricity, pipeline, and water sectors and has directed Departments and Agencies to use all existing government authorities to mandate new cybersecurity and network defense measures. Internationally, the Administration brought together more than 30 allies and partners to cooperate to detect and disrupt ransomware threats, rallied G7 countries to hold accountable nations who harbor ransomware criminals, and taken steps with partners and allies to publicly attribute malicious activity.</p>



<p>We accelerated our work in November of last year as Russian President We accelerated our work in November of last year as Russian President Vladimir Putin escalated his aggression ahead of his further invasion of Ukraine with extensive briefings and advisories to U.S. businesses regarding potential threats and cybersecurity protections. The U.S. Government will continue our efforts to provide resources and tools to the private sector, including via <a href="https://www.cisa.gov/shields-up">CISA’s Shields-Up campaign</a> and we will do everything in our power to defend the Nation and respond to cyberattacks. But the reality is that much of the Nation’s critical infrastructure is owned and operated by the private sector and the private sector must act to protect the critical services on which all Americans rely.</p>



<p>We urge companies to execute the following steps with urgency:</p>



<ul><li>Mandate the use of multi-factor authentication on your systems to make it harder for attackers to get onto your system;<br></li><li>Deploy modern security tools on your computers and devices to continuously look for and mitigate threats;<br></li><li>Check with your cybersecurity professionals to make sure that your systems are patched and protected against all known vulnerabilities, and change passwords across your networks so that previously stolen credentials are useless to malicious actors;<br></li><li>Back up your data and ensure you have offline backups beyond the reach of malicious actors;<br></li><li>Run exercises and drill your emergency plans so that you are prepared to respond quickly to minimize the impact of any attack;<br></li><li>Encrypt your data so it cannot be used if it is stolen;<br></li><li>Educate your employees to common tactics that attackers will use over email or through websites, and encourage them to report if their computers or phones have shown unusual behavior, such as unusual crashes or operating very slowly; and<br></li><li>Engage proactively with your local FBI field office or CISA Regional Office to establish relationships in advance of any cyber incidents. Please encourage your IT and Security leadership to visit the websites of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cisa.gov/shields-up">CISA</a>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.fbi.gov/investigate/cyber">FBI</a>&nbsp;where they will find technical information and other useful resources.</li></ul>



<p>We also must focus on bolstering America’s cybersecurity over the long term. We encourage technology and software companies to:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Build security into your products from the ground up — “bake it in, don’t bolt it on” — to protect both your intellectual property and your customers’ privacy.<br></li><li>Develop software only on a system that is highly secure and accessible only to those actually working on a particular project.&nbsp; This will make it much harder for an intruder to jump from system to system and compromise a product or steal your intellectual property.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Use modern tools to check for known and potential vulnerabilities. Developers can fix most software vulnerabilities — if they know about them.&nbsp; There are automated tools that can review code and find most coding errors before software ships, and before a malicious actor takes advantage of them.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Software developers are responsible for all code used in their products, including open source code. Most software is built using many different components and libraries, much of which is open source.&nbsp; Make sure developers know the provenance (i.e., origin) of components they are using and have a “software bill of materials” in case one of those components is later found to have a vulnerability so you can rapidly correct it.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Implement the security practices mandated in the President’s Executive Order, <em>Improving our Nation’s Cybersecurity</em>. Pursuant to that EO, all software the U.S. government purchases is now required to meet security standards in how it is built and deployed. We encourage you to follow those practices more broadly.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Agriculture Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/21/a-proclamation-on-national-agriculture-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 15:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[     On National Agriculture Day, we recognize the invaluable contributions of American farmers, farmworkers, ranchers, fishers, foresters, and other agricultural workers, who have practiced their craft for generations and touch the lives of Americans every day.  Their tireless efforts growing crops, raising livestock, and distributing food, fuel, and fiber sustain America and the entire world.  They&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>     On National Agriculture Day, we recognize the invaluable contributions of American farmers, farmworkers, ranchers, fishers, foresters, and other agricultural workers, who have practiced their craft for generations and touch the lives of Americans every day.  Their tireless efforts growing crops, raising livestock, and distributing food, fuel, and fiber sustain America and the entire world.  They put meals on our plates, clothes on our backs, and roofs over our heads.  Along the way, America&#8217;s agricultural workers serve as stewards of the land; ensure the safety and health of animals, plants, and people; and strengthen our rural communities with economic opportunities.<br><br>     Throughout the COVID-19 pandemic, the country&#8217;s agricultural workers have stepped up and stayed resilient, adapting their operations to ensure that every family has enough food on the table.  To support their efforts and ensure a stable food supply, our pandemic economic recovery assistance supports our agricultural businesses, whose operations were among the hardest hit by market disruptions.  We are building a food system that will be more competitive, balanced, and equitable &#8212; made possible by expanded and fairer markets, investments that sharpen farmers&#8217; competitive edge, and an emphasis on more affordable, healthy food for consumers that is produced closer to home.<br><br>     My Administration is also committed to protecting farmers &#8212; including small family farms that are vital to our food system &#8212; by bolstering competition across the industry and around the world.  We are taking action to enforce antitrust laws, move agriculture products to market more expeditiously, expand new agriculture processing capacity, and strengthen our supply chain resiliency.  We are also eliminating systemic barriers that have denied underserved producers consistent, fair, and equal access to opportunities for far too long.  My Administration remains determined to advance an American agriculture sector that works for everyone.  <br><br>     National Agriculture Day also celebrates the farmers, ranchers, fishers, and foresters who adopt agricultural practices that help combat the climate crisis.  Extreme weather events, including droughts, floods, wildfires, tornadoes, hurricanes, and other climate-related disasters, have had a devastating impact on American agriculture.  My Administration is committed to helping the agriculture sector enhance its resiliency and sustainability while increasing its productivity and profitability.  By working together, we can ensure that American agriculture continues to lead the world in production, that our food supply is secure, and that our economy remains strong.<br><br>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 22, 2022, as National Agriculture Day.  I call upon all Americans to join me in recognizing and reaffirming our commitment to and appreciation for our country&#8217;s farmers, ranchers, foresters, farmworkers, and all those who work in the agriculture sector across the Nation.<br><br>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this<br>twenty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Travel to&#160;Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/20/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-travel-to-poland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 02:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to Poland following his meetings in Brussels, Belgium with our NATO Allies, G7 Leaders, and European Union Leaders to discuss international efforts to support Ukraine and impose severe and unprecedented costs on Russia for its invasion. On Friday, March 25, President Biden will travel to Warsaw, Poland, where he will hold a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to Poland following his meetings in Brussels, Belgium with our NATO Allies, G7 Leaders, and European Union Leaders to discuss international efforts to support Ukraine and impose severe and unprecedented costs on Russia for its invasion. On Friday, March 25, President Biden will travel to Warsaw, Poland, where he will hold a bilateral meeting with President Andrzej Duda. The President will discuss how the United States, alongside our Allies and partners, is responding to the humanitarian and human rights crisis that Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war on Ukraine has created.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Houthi Attack Against Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/20/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-houthi-attack-against-saudi-arabia-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 16:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We condemn the Houthi attacks over the last 48 hours against civilian infrastructure in Saudi Arabia. These attacks reportedly targeted water treatment facilities as well as oil and natural gas infrastructure. The Houthis launch these terrorist attacks with enabling by Iran, which supplies them with missile and UAV components, training, and expertise. This is done&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We condemn the Houthi attacks over the last 48 hours against civilian infrastructure in Saudi Arabia. These attacks reportedly targeted water treatment facilities as well as oil and natural gas infrastructure. The Houthis launch these terrorist attacks with enabling by Iran, which supplies them with missile and UAV components, training, and expertise. This is done in violation of UN Security Council resolutions prohibiting the import of weapons into Yemen. Saudi Arabia and the Yemeni Government have endorsed multiple UN calls for ceasefires and de-escalation over the last year. The Houthis have rejected these calls, responding instead with new offensives in Yemen and terrorist acts, such as those launched against Saudi Arabia last night. It is time to bring this war to a close, but that can only happen if the Houthis agree to cooperate with the United Nations and its envoy working on a step-by-step a process to de-escalate the conflict. The United States stands fully behind those efforts, and we will continue to fully support our partners in the defense of their territory from Houthi attacks. We call on the international community to do the same.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden Marking&#160;Nowruz</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/20/statement-by-president-joe-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-marking-nowruz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I extend our best wishes to all who are celebrating Nowruz in the United States and around the world today — including in Iran and across the Middle East, in Central and South Asia, in the Caucuses, and in Europe. The Nowruz holiday brings family and friends together around the table to give&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I extend our best wishes to all who are celebrating Nowruz in the United States and around the world today — including in Iran and across the Middle East, in Central and South Asia, in the Caucuses, and in Europe.</p>



<p>The Nowruz holiday brings family and friends together around the table to give thanks for loved ones, count our blessings, share meals and gifts, reflect on the year that has passed, and welcome the arrival of spring and the possibilities of a new season. That spirit of new beginnings and the joy of Nowruz is reflected in our own Haft-Sin table at the White House, representing our hopes for the new year. It is a recognition and celebration of the vibrant cultures and friendships of our many diaspora communities in America who make extraordinary contributions and strengthen the fabric of our nation every day. To everyone celebrating, Eid-eh Shoma Mobarak — we wish you a Happy Nowruz.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Homeland Security Advisor Dr. Liz Sherwood-Randall’s Visit to&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/19/readout-of-homeland-security-advisor-dr-liz-sherwood-randalls-visit-to-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 19:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the week of March 14, Assistant to the President for Homeland Security Dr. Liz Sherwood-Randall led an interagency delegation to Paris, France, with representatives from the Department of Defense, the Department of State, and the National Security Council.  They met with the Chief of the Military Staff of the President of the Republic Admiral Jean-Philippe Rolland&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>During the week of March 14, Assistant to the President for Homeland Security Dr. Liz Sherwood-Randall led an interagency delegation to Paris, France, with representatives from the Department of Defense, the Department of State, and the National Security Council.  They met with the Chief of the Military Staff of the President of the Republic Admiral Jean-Philippe Rolland and separately with National Intelligence and Counter-Terrorism Coordinator Laurent Nuñez to discuss global terrorism trends, counterterrorism cooperation between the United States and France, and other vital national security interests.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Homeland Security Advisor Dr. Liz Sherwood-Randall’s visit to&#160;Kosovo</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/19/readout-of-homeland-security-advisor-dr-liz-sherwood-randalls-visit-to-kosovo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 19:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the week of March 14, Assistant to the President for Homeland Security Dr. Liz Sherwood-Randall&#160;led a U.S. delegation to Pristina, Kosovo. During the visit, Dr. Sherwood-Randall met with Kosovo President Vjosa Osmani-Sadriu and Prime Minister Albin Kurti and visited Camp Liya and Camp Bondsteel. Dr. Sherwood-Randall reiterated the United States’ steadfast commitment to Kosovo’s sovereignty,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>During the week of March 14, Assistant to the President for Homeland Security Dr. Liz Sherwood-Randall&nbsp;led a U.S. delegation to Pristina, Kosovo. During the visit, Dr. Sherwood-Randall met with Kosovo President Vjosa Osmani-Sadriu and Prime Minister Albin Kurti and visited Camp Liya and Camp Bondsteel.</p>



<p><br>Dr. Sherwood-Randall reiterated the United States’ steadfast commitment to Kosovo’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and regional security, as demonstrated through U.S. enduring leadership in NATO’s Kosovo Force (KFOR) mission and substantive support for the Kosovo Security Force (KSF) as it continues its 10-year transition plan.  Dr. Sherwood-Randall expressed deep thanks to President Osmani and Prime Minister Kurti for Kosovo’s ongoing support for temporarily hosting vulnerable Afghans at Camp Liya as they transition to future homes, for Kosovo’s partnership in countering terrorism, and for Kosovo’s acts of solidarity with the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Passing of Congressman Don&#160;Young</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/19/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-congressman-don-young/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 18:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I knew Don Young for a long time. He always stayed true to who he was and the people of Alaska he represented. Tough. Loyal.&#160;A consensus builder. He was larger than life, but always focused on Alaskans’ everyday lives. As Dean of the House, he was the longest-serving House Republican in history—but cherished photos of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I knew Don Young for a long time. He always stayed true to who he was and the people of Alaska he represented. Tough. Loyal.&nbsp;A consensus builder.</p>



<p>He was larger than life, but always focused on Alaskans’ everyday lives. As Dean of the House, he was the longest-serving House Republican in history—but cherished photos of his legislation being signed into law by ten presidents, Republicans and&nbsp;Democrats.</p>



<p>There is no doubt that few legislators have left a greater mark on their state.&nbsp;Don’s legacy lives on in the infrastructure projects he delighted in steering across Alaska.&nbsp;In the&nbsp;opportunities he advanced for his constituents.&nbsp;In the&nbsp;enhanced protections for&nbsp;Native tribes he championed. His legacy will continue in the America he loved.</p>



<p>Jill and I&nbsp;send our prayers to his wife Anne, to his daughters and the entire Young family, and to the people of Alaska.</p>



<p>May God bless Don Young.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
