<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:13:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;3325</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/bill-signed-h-r-3325/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, August 5, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 3325, which provides for the award of four Congressional Gold Medals to the United States Capitol Police and those who protected the U.S. Capitol on January 6, 2021.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, August 5, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 3325, which provides for the award of four Congressional Gold Medals to the United States Capitol Police and those who protected the U.S. Capitol on January 6, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the First Interagency Task Force Meeting on Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity&#160;(PAVE)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/readout-of-the-first-interagency-task-force-meeting-on-property-appraisal-and-valuation-equity-pave/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26305</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration Launches first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals Today, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development Secretary Marcia L. Fudge and Domestic Policy Advisor Ambassador Susan Rice convened the first principal-level meeting for the Interagency Task Force on Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity (PAVE). They were joined by senior leadership from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration Launches first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals</em></p>



<p>Today, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development Secretary Marcia L. Fudge and Domestic Policy Advisor Ambassador Susan Rice convened the first principal-level meeting for the Interagency Task Force on Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity (PAVE). They were joined by senior leadership from Cabinet and independent agencies that have been invited to participate in the Task Force.</p>



<p>Task Force members discussed how current appraisal practices are a significant contributor to the disparity in housing values. The practice of comparing properties within similar neighborhoods can be a proxy for racial demographics, which leads to the perpetuation and exacerbation of the legacy of segregation and redlining. The group identified near- and long-term opportunities to advance equity in home appraisals that will help narrow the racial wealth gap and reinvest in communities that have been historically left behind. The Task Force Members will work together and consult with civil rights organizations, advocacy groups, industry, and philanthropic entities to drive change.</p>



<p>Additionally, Task Force members agreed that the scope of the Task Force will be to:</p>



<ol><li>Ensure that government oversight and industry practice further valuation equity;</li><li>Combat valuation bias through educating the consumer and training the practitioner;</li><li>Ensure equity in valuation by making available high-quality data;</li><li>Create a comprehensive approach to combating valuation bias through enforcement and other efforts.</li></ol>



<p>The Task Force is chaired by Secretary Fudge and Ambassador Rice, and includes cabinet-level leaders from executive departments and additional members from independent agencies. The Task Force will deliver a final action report within 180 days.</p>



<p>The Task Force membership is comprised of the following officials:</p>



<ul><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (co-chair)</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy (co-chair)</li><li>Director of the National Economic Council</li><li>Attorney General of the United States</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Comptroller of the Currency (OCC)</li><li>Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve</li><li>Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC)</li><li>Chairman of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)</li><li>Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration and the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council</li><li>Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB)</li><li>Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA)</li><li>Appraisal Subcommittee (ASC)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-31/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:16:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Mary Katherine Dimke, of Washington, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Washington, vice Rosanna Malouf Peterson, retiring. &#160; &#160; &#160;John P. Howard, III, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Mary Katherine Dimke, of Washington, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Washington, vice Rosanna Malouf Peterson, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;John P. Howard, III, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Judge of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals for the term of fifteen years, vice Phyllis D. Thompson, term expiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Beth Robinson, of Vermont, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Second Circuit, vice Peter W. Hall, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Charlotte N. Sweeney, of Colorado, to be United States District Judge for the District of Colorado, vice Richard Brooke Jackson, retiring.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden  on the Passing of AFL-CIO President Richard&#160;Trumka</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-afl-cio-president-richard-trumka/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I recently called Rich Trumka. It wasn’t scheduled. I just called to check in as old friends do. We started our conversation like always. He asked about Jill and the family and I asked about Barbara and theirs. And then we got to work. For Rich, work was synonymous with a word that defined his&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I recently called Rich Trumka. It wasn’t scheduled. I just called to check in as old friends do. We started our conversation like always. He asked about Jill and the family and I asked about Barbara and theirs. And then we got to work.</p>



<p>For Rich, work was synonymous with a word that defined his life: dignity. In the more than thirty years of our friendship, he was a fierce and forceful champion for the dignity of the American worker.</p>



<p>Whenever you heard him speak, you understood why. He was the American worker.</p>



<p>A son of a Pennsylvania coal miner, he grew up to be one. He became president of the United Mine Workers at just 33, and nearly thirty years later, he was elected president of the AFL-CIO. Yet no matter how far his career took him, he never forgot where he came from and the people he started with.</p>



<p>For Rich, it was always about doing right by working people – fighting for and protecting their wages, their safety, their pensions, and their ability to build a good, decent, honorable middle-class life. It was about workers improving their own lives and building worker power together. And it was about America itself. It was about the American worker being the heart of our economic might and dynamism.&nbsp; I’ve always believed that the middle class built this country and unions built the middle class. There is no doubt that Rich Trumka helped build unions all across America.</p>



<p>Perhaps the most important trait I valued in Rich is that he was never afraid to speak truth to power, even if the power was held by people he helped elect – myself included. He was always honest and fair. He was always tough and trustworthy. He was as great a friend and powerful and reliable ally as anyone could have in their corner.</p>



<p>I will miss him as will the countless workers whose lives he made better and the labor movement he led with daring vision. But I know our pain is nothing compared to what Barbara and their son Rich Jr. and their grandchildren Richard and Taylor are feeling on this day. As I told you on the phone after we heard the news, Jill and I send you our love – today and always.</p>



<p>Rich Trumka was a dear friend, a great American, and a good man.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in Meeting with Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Civil Rights&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/05/remarks-by-president-biden-in-meeting-with-asian-american-native-hawaiian-and-pacific-islander-civil-rights-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 20:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 12:15 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Let me begin by saying to the press that I&#8217;m sorry that I’m late.&#160; We just learned a very close friend passed away: Rich Trumka.&#160; And he was more than the head of the AFL-CIO.&#160; He was a good, close, personal friend.&#160; And the Vice President and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>12:15 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me begin by saying to the press that I&#8217;m sorry that I’m late.&nbsp; We just learned a very close friend passed away: Rich Trumka.&nbsp; And he was more than the head of the AFL-CIO.&nbsp; He was a good, close, personal friend.&nbsp;<br><br>And the Vice President and I were talking a little bit, and he &#8212; he was with his son and his grandsons on a camping trip, and &#8212; and at least he was with the people who adore him.&nbsp;<br><br>But I apologize for starting late.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re sorry for your loss, Mr. President.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>The Vice President and I are honored to host leaders representing the rich diversity of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander communities &#8212; many of whom I met before, some of whom I&#8217;m meeting for the first time &#8212; and I welcome again to the White House.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We have a full agenda to discuss: the pandemic, the economy, immigration, voting rights, and hate crimes.<br><br>In fact, let me start by acknowledging that on this day, in 2012, I was with another friend who&#8217;s half Sikh &#8212; he&#8217;s a Sikh.&nbsp; And we were on &#8212; dealing with the 10 people shot in a hateful act of bigotry at the Sikh temple in Oak Creek, Wisconsin.&nbsp; Seven people lost their lives that day.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we honor everyone impacted by this tragedy.&nbsp; And we think about all the pain during this pandemic, with the rise of hate crimes, harassment, bullying, and other forms of bias against Asian Americans.&nbsp; It seems not to stop.<br><br>And after the shooting in the Atlanta area, Kamala and I traveled to Atlanta, met with a group &#8212; some of whom are here &#8212; of Asian American leaders.&nbsp; The discussion was very raw.&nbsp; It was powerful.&nbsp; And a common theme was that Asian Americans feeling unsafe, unwanted, and some of you indicted feeling invisible sometimes.&nbsp;<br><br>Our message back to you was, at that moment: We see you.&nbsp; We see you.&nbsp;<br><br>A few months later, we stood here in the White House and we signed the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act into law.<br><br>It also was a powerful moment showing that we can come together &#8212; Democrat and Republican &#8212; we can come together as a nation and truly look out for one another.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, that’s why we wanted to convene this meeting to continue to strengthen our efforts because more must be done, in my view &#8212; our view.<br><br>A pandemic the AH &#8212; the AANI &#8212; -NH and PI community &#8212; I stumbled all over myself there &#8212; but has been on the frontlines from the beginning and is critical to helping us vaccinate America &#8212; not just get vaccinated but to vaccinate America.<br><br>The community is also critical in keeping the U.S. economy strong.&nbsp; In six months, we&#8217;re seeing the fastest growth at this point in any administration&#8217;s history &#8212; in no small part because of this community.&nbsp; The fastest-growing economic growth in nearly 40 years.&nbsp;<br><br>And now we have an opportunity to make historic investments in our infrastructure and in our families, and finally build an economy that deals everybody in &#8212; just doesn’t come from top down, but from the middle and the bottom up.&nbsp; And creating millions of good-paying jobs in every community, including the AANHPI community and delivering affordable childcare, paid leave, universal pre-K, as well as community college.&nbsp;<br><br>There is work to do on immigration; there’s work to do on voting rights and so much more.<br><br>On my first day in office, I signed an executive order to advance racial equity and a whole-of-government approach to address inequities and injustice in America from every agency.&nbsp;&nbsp;And this group&#8217;s input has been critical and continues to be critical to that approach.&nbsp;<br><br>And I look forward to the discussion that we&#8217;re about to have and the actions that, God willing, we’ll be able to follow.<br><br>So I want to thank you all again for being here, and we’ll get to our meeting.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>12:19 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act Advances President&#160;Biden’s Climate&#160;Agenda</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-investment-and-jobs-act-advances-president-bidens-climate-agenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 18:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last month, the President stood with Democrats and Republicans to announce the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework – which makes the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century and is an important first investment to ensure the U.S. can tackle the climate crisis. Last week, the President and Senators announced details of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Last month, the President stood with Democrats and Republicans to announce the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework – which makes the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century and is an important first investment to ensure the U.S. can tackle the climate crisis.</p>



<p>Last week, the President and Senators announced details of the historic investment, which includes historic components that will help combat climate change, advance environmental justice, and create good-paying, union jobs. From reducing greenhouse gas emissions across the transportation sector, replacing lead pipes to deliver clean drinking water, electrifying America’s power grid, and more, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal embeds key provisions that advance President Biden’s climate plan alongside his full Build Back Better Agenda.</p>



<p>President Biden promised to work across the aisle to deliver results for working families, and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal demonstrates we can come together to take key steps towards building an economy and country that is more sustainable, resilient, and just – all while creating jobs, furthering environmental justice, and addressing climate change.</p>



<p>President Biden believes we must invest in our country and our people by creating good jobs, tackling the climate crisis, and sustaining equitable economic growth for decades to come. The deal – along with his Build Back Better Agenda – will deliver progress towards this vision for working families across the country.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Modernize Public Transit and Reduce Emissions</span></strong></p>



<p>The transportation sector is the nation’s top contributor to greenhouse gas emissions, which we must reduce to ensure we meet President Biden’s goals to create a net-zero economy by 2050. And, America’s transit infrastructure has a multi-billion dollar repair backlog with more than 24,000 buses, 5,000 rail cars, 200 stations, and thousands of miles of track, signals, and power systems in need of replacement. <strong>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal makes the largest investment in public transit in history and is the largest federal investment in passenger rail since the creation of Amtrak – helping reduce greenhouse gas emissions when repairing, upgrading, and modernizing the nation’s transit infrastructure</strong>. The bill invests $105 billion in new funding to improve healthy, sustainable transportation options for millions of Americans by modernizing and expanding transit and rail networks across the country. It will replace thousands of transit vehicles, including buses, with clean, zero emission vehicles.  And, it will benefit communities of color since these households are twice as likely to take public transportation and many of these communities lack sufficient public transit options. In addition, it will help transit workers who are disproportionally workers of color. Bus and transit workers are 31% Black and 19% Hispanic, compared to 12% and 18% respectively of the workforce overall. <br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Build Up EV Infrastructure</span></strong></p>



<p>U.S. market share of plug-in electric vehicle (EV) sales is only one-third the size of the Chinese EV market. The President believes that must change. <strong>The bill invests $7.5 billion to build out the first-ever national network of EV chargers in the United States and is a critical element in the Biden-Harris Administration’s plan to accelerate the adoption of EVs to address the climate crisis and support domestic manufacturing jobs. </strong>The bill will provide funding for deployment of EV chargers along highway corridors to facilitate long-distance travel and within communities to provide convenient charging where people live, work, and shop.  Federal funding will have a particular focus on rural, disadvantaged, and hard-to-reach communities.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Electrify America’s Buses</span></strong></p>



<p>American school buses play a critical role in expanding access to education, but they are also a significant source of pollution. <strong>The deal will deliver thousands of electric school buses nationwide, including in rural communities, helping school districts across the country buy clean, American-made, zero emission buses, and replace the yellow school bus fleet for America’s children. </strong>The deal invests $5 billion in zero and low emission school buses, in addition to more than $5 billion in funding for public transit agencies to adopt low- and no-emissions buses. These investments will drive demand for American-made batteries and vehicles, creating jobs and supporting domestic manufacturing, while also removing diesel buses from some of our most vulnerable communities. In addition, they will help the more than 25 million children and thousands of bus drivers who breathe polluted air on their rides to and from school. Diesel air pollution is linked to asthma and other health problems that hurt our communities and cause students to miss school, particularly in communities of color and Tribal communities.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Reduce Emissions Across Airports, Ports, and Waterways</span></strong></p>



<p>The United States built modern aviation, but our airports lag far behind our competitors. According to some rankings, no U.S. airports rank in the top 25 of airports worldwide. Our ports and waterways need repair and reimagination too. <strong>The bill invests $17 billion in port infrastructure and $25 billion in airports to address repair and maintenance backlogs, reduce congestion and emissions near ports and airports, and drive electrification and other low-carbon technologies.</strong> Modern, resilient, and sustainable port, airport, and freight infrastructure will support U.S. competitiveness by removing bottlenecks and expediting commerce and reduce the environmental impact on neighboring communities.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Strengthen Resilience</span></strong></p>



<p>Millions of Americans feel the effects of climate change each year when their roads wash out, airport power goes down, or schools get flooded. Last year alone, the United States faced 22 extreme weather and climate-related disaster events with losses exceeding $1 billion each – a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion. People of color are more likely to live in areas most vulnerable to flooding and other climate change-related weather events. <strong>The deal makes our communities safer and our infrastructure more resilient to the impacts of climate change and cyber attacks, with an investment of roughly $50 billion.</strong> This includes funds to protect against droughts and floods, in addition to a major investment in weatherization. The bill is the largest investment in the resilience of physical and natural systems in American history.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Deliver Clean Drinking Water</span></strong></p>



<p>Currently, up to 10 million American households and 400,000 schools and child care centers lack safe drinking water. <strong>The deal’s $55 billion investment represents the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history, including dedicated funding to replace lead service lines and the dangerous chemical PFAS (per- and polyfluoroalkyl).</strong> It will replace all of the nation’s lead pipes and service lines. From rural towns to struggling cities, the deal invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal Nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Address Legacy Pollution</span></strong></p>



<p>In thousands of rural and urban communities around the country, hundreds of thousands of former industrial and energy sites are now idle – sources of blight and pollution. 26% of Black Americans and 29% of Hispanic Americans live within 3 miles of a Superfund site, a higher percentage than for Americans overall. Proximity to a Superfund site can lead to elevated levels of lead in children’s blood. <strong>The deal invests $21 billion in environmental remediation, making the largest investment in addressing the legacy pollution that harms the public health of communities and neighborhoods in American history, creating good-paying union jobs in hard-hit energy communities and advancing economic and environmental justice.</strong> The bill includes funds to clean up superfund and brownfield sites, reclaim abandoned mine land and cap orphaned gas wells.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Electrify America’s Power Infrastructure</span></strong></p>



<p>As the recent Texas power outages demonstrated, our aging electric grid needs urgent modernization. A Department of Energy study found that power outages cost the U.S. economy up to $70 billion annually. <strong>The deal’s roughly $60 billion investment is the single largest investment in clean energy transmission in American history.</strong> It upgrades our power infrastructure, including by building thousands of miles of new, resilient transmission lines to facilitate the expansion of renewable energy. It creates a new Grid Deployment Authority, invests in research and development for advanced transmission and electricity distribution technologies, and promotes smart grid technologies that deliver flexibility and resilience. It invests in demonstration projects and research hubs for next generation technologies like advanced nuclear reactors, carbon capture, and clean hydrogen.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">BUILD BACK BETTER AGENDA</span></strong></p>



<p>Tackling the climate crisis and reaching President Biden’s goal of a net-zero emissions economy by 2050 requires&nbsp;<strong>consistent action</strong><strong>and historic investments in sustainable, resilient, and equitable infrastructure</strong>&nbsp;– and this deal is a critical step towards realizing these objectives.&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>But we know there is more work to do</strong>&nbsp;– to grow our economy, create jobs, reduce climate pollution, and ensure more Americans can participate fully and equally in our economy.<br><br>In addition to the bipartisan deal, President Biden is dedicated to fulfilling his entire vision to tackle the climate crisis – which includes&nbsp;<strong>advancing his full Build Back Better Agenda&nbsp;</strong>that will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Create an energy efficiency and clean electricity standard </strong>to send a market signal that bring additional private investment off the sidelines and into modernizing America’s electric grid – a key step towards reaching President Biden’s goal of 100% clean electricity by 2035.</li><li><strong>Extend and expand clean energy and EV tax credits </strong>for businesses and consumers to spur demand for domestic manufacturing, accelerate clean energy and EV deployment, and grow our capacity to build those technologies in the U.S.</li><li><strong>Enlist a Civilian Climate Corps </strong>to put a new, diverse generation of Americans to work conserving our public lands and waters, bolster community resilience, and advance environmental justice – all while paving the way for good-paying, union jobs.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Administration Announces Additional Actions to Help Kids Go Back to School&#160;Safely</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-biden-administration-announces-additional-actions-to-help-kids-go-back-to-school-safely/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the next six weeks, more than 50 million students will head back to school, and more than 20 million students will return to undergraduate and graduate studies. For young people, getting vaccinated right away is the best way back to the things they love – like playing sports, completing their studies, and spending time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Over the next six weeks, more than 50 million students will head back to school, and more than 20 million students will return to undergraduate and graduate studies. For young people, getting vaccinated right away is the best way back to the things they love – like playing sports, completing their studies, and spending time with friends and loved ones. Today, the Biden Administration announced additional actions to get students ages 12 and above vaccinated and to ensure all students can go back to school safely this fall:<br><br>Today, the Administration is highlighting the following efforts to get more young people vaccinated:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Incorporating COVID-19 vaccination into sports physicals for student athletes this summer and fall</strong>: Today, the American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP), the American Medical Society for Sports Medicine (AMSSM), and ten other sports and medicine organizations are issuing a consensus statement to all their members urging all medical providers to ask about COVID-19 vaccine status during sports physicals, and where available to also administer the COVID-19 vaccine. Both AAP and AMSSM have issued updated guidance for physicians incorporating COVID-19 vaccination into sports physical protocols, and AAP has issued revised forms for doctors, parents, and student athletes to use to document their pre-participation examination including language on COVID-19 vaccination. The AAP estimates that approximately 60 to 70 percent of children and adolescents participate in organized sports across the country. Each year, millions of these student athletes receive a pre-participation exam, also known as a sports physical, in order to participate. This action will help elevate the importance of getting vaccinated against COVID-19 as a key part of safe competitive play. The organizations signing onto the consensus statement are:<br></li><li>American Academy of Pediatrics</li><li>American Academy of Family Physicians</li><li>American Academy of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</li><li>American College of Emergency Physicians</li><li>American College of Sports Medicine</li><li>American Medical Society for Sports Medicine</li><li>American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine</li><li>American Osteopathic Academy of Sports Medicine</li><li>National Athletic Trainers’ Association</li><li>National Federation of State High School Associations</li><li>National Collegiate Athletic Association</li><li>U.S. Olympic &amp; Paralympic Committee<br></li><li><strong>Sending pediatricians to ‘Back to School Nights’ to get communities vaccinated against COVID-19</strong>: The National Parent Teacher Association (PTA) is calling on its 22,000 local member PTAs and parent leaders nationwide to host community conversations about getting vaccinated at Back to School parent meetings this summer and fall. National PTA will partner with the American Academy of Pediatrics to deploy local pediatricians to be a part of these Back to School parent meetings, so parents can have their questions answered by doctors who know and treat their children. AAP will also produce digital materials on the vaccine and kids that parent leaders can use as they convene community conversations. Alongside other trusted partners like teachers and school nurses, pediatricians around the country have been active in showing up to parent meetings and other events this summer to talk about the vaccine and how to keep kids safe in school this fall.<br></li><li><strong>Providing schools and colleges with additional resources to host pop-up vaccine clinics as students come back to school and back to campus</strong>: In an effort to get more kids 12 and older vaccinated, last week President Biden called on school districts nationwide to host at least one pop-up vaccination clinic over the coming weeks, and the Administration directed pharmacies in the federal pharmacy program to work with school districts and colleges across the country to host vaccination clinics on-site. Today, the Administration will release additional resources to help schools host pop-up vaccine clinics, including a detailed guide for hosting school-based clinics, template letters and text messages for district and school leaders to use in sending messages home to students and families about the vaccine, resources for teachers to use in discussing the vaccine with students and their parents, and materials parent leaders can use as part of community conversations on the vaccine. The Administration also released a “Vax to School” College Checklist, detailing eight ways that colleges and universities can increase awareness of and access to the vaccine as students come back to campus – building off of the work of the nearly 900 colleges in the COVID-19 College Challenge who have committed to building vaccination rates on their campuses this summer and fall. The American Rescue Plan has provided billions of dollars that school districts and institutions of higher education can use to create awareness and build vaccine confidence, host vaccine clinics, and provide incentives such as paid time off for staff to get vaccinated.<br></li><li><strong>Launching the Back to School “Week of Action”&nbsp;with partners nationwide to get young people vaccinated: </strong>Beginning August 7th and ending August 15th, the Health and Human Services’ We Can Do This campaign and Made to Save are launching a Week of Action to encourage vaccinations for young people and support parents and schools as they get kids back to safe, in-person learning.&nbsp; The Week of Action will mobilize school districts, students, teachers, national organizations, local government leaders, businesses, social media influencers, celebrities, and thousands of volunteers to kick off the school year by encouraging young people to get vaccinated and offering accessible ways to do it in their community. More than 90 youth-based organizations, faith-based organizations, and schools are committed to hosting over 200 vaccination events focused on school and campus-based COVID-19 vaccination drives for students, their families, and their communities, with hundreds more events taking place throughout the month of August. Events will take place all over the country, including canvassing, phone banks, text banks and more. As part of the Week of Action, Second Gentleman Douglas Emhoff and Education Secretary Miguel Cardona will travel to Topeka, KS to visit a back-to-school vaccine clinic; and trainings will be provided for teachers, parents, and student organizations on how to engage young people and their families on the vaccine. To kick off the Back to School Week of Action, the Second Gentleman and National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases Director Dr. Anthony Fauci will host a virtual discussion with youth leaders who expanded access to the vaccine for young people and their communities. The Second Gentleman and Dr. Fauci will ask the young leaders about why they got involved in vaccine efforts, and how they have responded to the needs of their peers and their communities in getting more young people vaccinated. The virtual event will be livestreamed on the White House YouTube channel.<br></li></ul>



<p>Today’s announcements build on the Administration’s release earlier this week of the “Return to School Roadmap,” a resource to support students, schools, educators, and communities as they prepare to return to safe, healthy in-person learning this fall and emerge from the pandemic stronger than before. The Roadmap provides key resources and supports for students, parents, educators, and school communities to build excitement around returning to classrooms this school year and outlines how federal funding can support the safe and sustained return to in-person learning. Over the course of the next several weeks as schools reopen nationwide, the Roadmap will lay out actionable strategies to implement the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s (CDC) updated guidance for K-12 schools, so that schools can minimize transmission and sustain in-person learning all school-year long.<br><br>The Roadmap includes three “Landmark” priorities that schools, districts, and communities are encouraged to focus on to ensure all students are set up for success in the 2021-2022 school year. These include: (1) prioritizing the health and safety of students, staff, and educators, (2) building school communities and supporting students’ social, emotional, and mental health, and (3) accelerating academic achievement. As part of the Roadmap, the Department will release resources for practitioners and parents on each of these priorities, and will highlight schools and districts that are using innovative practices to address these priorities. The Department will also lift up ways that the American Rescue Plan and other federal funds can be used to address these priorities in schools and communities across the country, as well as outline additional investments from President Biden’s Build Back Better agenda that are needed to ensure our schools and communities can rebuild from the pandemic even stronger than they were before and address inequities exacerbated by the pandemic, particularly for students in underserved communities.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Deferred Enforced Departure for Certain Hong Kong&#160;Residents</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-deferred-enforced-departure-for-certain-hong-kong-residents/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. signed a memorandum directing the deferral of removal of certain Hong Kong residents who are present in the United States, giving them a temporary safe haven. This action demonstrates President Biden’s strong support for people in Hong Kong in the face of ongoing repression by the People’s Republic of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. signed a memorandum directing the deferral of removal of certain Hong Kong residents who are present in the United States, giving them a temporary safe haven. This action demonstrates President Biden’s strong support for people in Hong Kong in the face of ongoing repression by the People’s Republic of China (PRC), and makes clear we will not stand idly by as the PRC breaks its promises to Hong Kong and to the international community. Since taking office, the Biden Administration has been clear that we, alongside our allies and partners, strongly oppose the PRC’s wielding of the National Security Law to deny basic rights and freedoms, assault Hong Kong’s autonomy, and undermine its remaining democratic processes and institutions. Given the politically motivated arrests and trials, the silencing of the media, and the diminishing the space for elections and democratic opposition, we will continue to take steps in support of people in Hong Kong.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Deferred Enforced Departure for Certain Hong Kong&#160;Residents</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/memorandum-on-the-deferred-enforced-departure-for-certain-hong-kong-residents/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY SUBJECT:       Deferred Enforced Departure for Certain Hong Kong Residents The United States supports the human rights and fundamental freedoms of the residents of Hong Kong.  Recognizing the significant erosion of those rights and freedoms in Hong Kong by the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC), I am&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE                                                                                                THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY<br><br>SUBJECT:       Deferred Enforced Departure for Certain Hong Kong Residents<br><br>The United States supports the human rights and fundamental freedoms of the residents of Hong Kong.  Recognizing the significant erosion of those rights and freedoms in Hong Kong by the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC), I am directing the deferral of removal of certain Hong Kong residents who are present in the United States.<br><br>By unilaterally imposing on Hong Kong the Law of the People&#8217;s Republic of China on Safeguarding National Security in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (NSL), the PRC has undermined the enjoyment of rights and freedoms in Hong Kong, including those protected under the Basic Law and the Sino-British Joint Declaration.  Since the imposition of the NSL in June 2020, Hong Kong police have continued a campaign of politically motivated arrests, taking into custody at least 100 opposition politicians, activists, and protesters on NSL-related charges including secession, subversion, terrorist activities, and collusion with a foreign country or external elements.  Over 10,000 individuals have been arrested for other charges in connection with anti-government protests.  Over the last year, the PRC has continued its assault on Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, undermining its remaining democratic processes and institutions, imposing limits on academic freedom, and cracking down on freedom of the press.  <br><br>There are compelling foreign policy reasons to defer enforced departure for Hong Kong residents presently in the United States.  The United States is committed to a foreign policy that unites our democratic values with our foreign policy goals, which is centered on the defense of democracy and the promotion of human rights around the world.  Offering safe haven for Hong Kong residents who have been deprived of their guaranteed freedoms in Hong Kong furthers United States interests in the region.  The United States will not waver in our support of people in Hong Kong.<br><br>Pursuant to my constitutional authority to conduct the foreign relations of the United States, I have determined that it is in the foreign policy interest of the United States to defer for 18 months the removal of any Hong Kong resident subject to the conditions and exceptions provided below.<br><br>Accordingly, I hereby direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to take appropriate measures to defer for 18 months the removal of any Hong Kong resident who is present in the United States on the date of this memorandum, except for those: <br><br>(1)  who have voluntarily returned to Hong Kong or the PRC after the date of this memorandum; <br><br>(2)  who have not continuously resided in the United States since the date of this memorandum; <br><br>(3)  who are inadmissible under section 212(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) (8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)) or deportable under section 237(a)(4) of the INA (8 U.S.C. 1227(a)(4)); <br><br>(4)  who have been convicted of any felony or two or more misdemeanors committed in the United States, or who meet any of the criteria set forth in section 208(b)(2)(A) of the INA (8 U.S.C. 1158(b)(2)(A));<br><br>(5)  who are subject to extradition; <br><br>(6)  whose presence in the United States the Secretary of Homeland Security has determined is not in the interest of the United States or presents a danger to public safety; or<br><br>(7)  whose presence in the United States the Secretary of State has reasonable grounds to believe would have potentially serious adverse foreign policy consequences for the United States. <br><br>I further direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to take appropriate measures to authorize employment for noncitizens whose removal has been deferred, as provided by this memorandum, for the duration of such deferral, and to consider suspending regulatory requirements with respect to F-1 nonimmigrant students who are Hong Kong residents as the Secretary of Homeland Security determines to be appropriate.<br><br>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Sixth Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/president-biden-names-sixth-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing three new candidates for the federal bench and one new nominee to the D.C. Court of Appeals, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing three new candidates for the federal bench and one new nominee to the D.C. Court of Appeals, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, this slate includes:</p>



<ul><li>A woman currently serving as Vermont’s first openly LGBT Supreme Court justice, who would also be the first openly LGBT woman to serve on any federal circuit court.</li><li>A woman who would be the first openly LGBT federal judge in Colorado and the first openly LGBT woman to serve as a federal district court judge in any state west of the Mississippi.</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s sixth round of names for federal judicial positions, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 35.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move at an unparalleled speed with respect to judicial nominations. His first judicial nominations announcement was made faster than that of any new President in modern American history, and today’s announcement continues that trend.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>CIRCUIT COURT</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Justice Beth Robinson: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit</strong><br></span><br>Justice Beth Robinson has served as an Associate Justice on the Vermont Supreme Court since 2011. Prior to her appointment, Justice Robinson served as counsel to Vermont Governor Peter Shumlin from 2010 to 2011. From 1993 to 2010, Justice Robinson was a civil litigator in private practice at Langrock Sperry &amp; Wool where she focused on civil litigation including employment law, workers’ compensation, contract disputes, and family law.&nbsp; She also represented LGBTQ+ individuals in civil and civil rights cases, including leading the freedom to marry movement in Vermont.&nbsp; From 1990 to 1991, Justice Robinson was an associate at Skadden, Arps, Slate, Meagher &amp; Flom in Washington, D.C., focusing on white-collar criminal defense. Justice Robinson served as a law clerk for Judge David B. Sentelle on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia from 1989 to 1990.<br><br>Justice Robinson received her J.D. from the University of Chicago Law School in 1989 and her B.A. from Dartmouth College in 1986.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>DISTRICT COURTS</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Judge Mary Katherine Dimke: Nominee for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Washington</strong><br></span><br>Judge Mary Katherine Dimke has served as a U.S. Magistrate Judge for the Eastern District of Washington since 2016. Prior to becoming a judge, she was an Assistant U.S. Attorney for the Eastern District of Washington from 2012 to 2016 and for the Western District of Washington from 2008 to 2012. Judge Dimke joined the U.S. Department of Justice through its Honors Program in 2004 where she served as an attorney in the Fraud Section of the Criminal Division in Washington, D.C. until 2007. Judge Dimke served as a law clerk for Judge Richard C. Tallman on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit in Seattle, Washington from 2003 to 2004. She also served as a law clerk for Judge Alan B. Johnson on the U.S. District Court for the District of Wyoming in Cheyenne from 2002 to 2003.<br><br>Judge Dimke received her J.D. from Vanderbilt University Law School in 2002 as a member of the Order of the Coif and her B.A.,&nbsp;<em>magna cum laude</em>, from Pepperdine University in 1999.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Charlotte Sweeney: Nominee for the United States District Court for the District of Colorado</strong><br></span><br>Charlotte Sweeney is currently a partner at Sweeney &amp; Bechtold, LLC, where she has practiced since 2008. Her law practice is devoted to representing individuals in employment law cases. Ms. Sweeney was previously a partner with LaFond &amp; Sweeney, LLC from 1999 to 2008 and LaFond &amp; Bove, LLC from 1997 from 1999. Ms. Sweeney began her career as an associate with LaFond &amp; Clausen, LLC in 1995 and was named a partner at the firm in 1998.<br><br>Ms. Sweeney received her J.D. from the University of Denver College of Law in 1995 and her B.S. from California Lutheran University in 1991.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>D.C. COURT OF APPEALS</u></strong></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>John P. Howard III: Nominee for the District of Columbia Court of Appeals</strong><br></span><br>Judge John P. Howard III currently serves as an Administrative Law Judge with the District of Columbia Office of Administrative Hearings. Prior to his appointment to the bench in 2018, Judge Howard served as an Administrative Law Judge with the District of Columbia Commission on Human Rights from 2014 to 2018, where he adjudicated discrimination claims in the areas of employment, housing, education, and public accommodations. From 2012 to 2014, Judge Howard practiced law as a solo practitioner and with a small firm, where he focused on civil litigation and family law. Judge Howard was previously an associate in the D.C. office of Akin, Gump, Strauss, Hauer &amp; Feld LLP from 2011 to 2012. Judge Howard served as a law clerk for Judge Alexander Williams, Jr. on the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland, and for the Honorable David C. Simmons of the D.C. Commission on Human Rights in 2010.<br><br>Judge Howard received his J.D. from the Georgetown University Law Center in 2010 and his B.A. from Howard University in 2006.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
