<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 22:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Zelenskyy of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/21/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-zelenskyy-of-ukraine-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 22:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47585</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine to reaffirm the commitment of the United States to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.  President Biden strongly condemned Russian President Putin’s decision to purportedly recognize the “independence” of the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine. He updated President Zelenskyy on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine to reaffirm the commitment of the United States to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.  President Biden strongly condemned Russian President Putin’s decision to purportedly recognize the “independence” of the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine. He updated President Zelenskyy on the United States’ response, including our plan to issue sanctions. President Biden reiterated that the United States would respond swiftly and decisively, in lock-step with its Allies and partners, to further Russian aggression against Ukraine. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Russian Announcement on Eastern&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/21/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-russian-announcement-on-eastern-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 20:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We have anticipated a move like this from Russia and are ready to respond immediately. President Biden will soon issue an Executive Order that will prohibit new investment, trade, and financing by U.S. persons to, from, or in the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine. This E.O. will also provide authority to impose sanctions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We have anticipated a move like this from Russia and are ready to respond immediately. President Biden will soon issue an Executive Order that will prohibit new investment, trade, and financing by U.S. persons to, from, or in the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine. This E.O. will also provide authority to impose sanctions on any person determined to operate in those areas of Ukraine. The Departments of State and Treasury will have additional details shortly. We will also soon announce additional measures related to today’s blatant violation of Russia’s international commitments.</p>



<p>To be clear: these measures are separate from and would be in addition to the swift and severe economic measures we have been preparing in coordination with Allies and partners should Russia further invade Ukraine.</p>



<p>We are continuing to closely consult with Allies and partners, including Ukraine, on next steps and on Russia’s ongoing escalation along the border with Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/20/statement-from-press-secretary-jen-psaki-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 01:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the President has repeatedly made clear, we are committed to pursuing diplomacy until the moment an invasion begins. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Lavrov are scheduled to meet later this week in Europe, provided Russia does not proceed with military action. President Biden accepted in principle a meeting with President Putin following that engagement,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As the President has repeatedly made clear, we are committed to pursuing diplomacy until the moment an invasion begins. Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Lavrov are scheduled to meet later this week in Europe, provided Russia does not proceed with military action. President Biden accepted in principle a meeting with President Putin following that engagement, again, if an invasion hasn’t happened.  We are always ready for diplomacy.  We are also ready to impose swift and severe consequences should Russia instead choose war.  And currently, Russia appears to be continuing preparations for a full-scale assault on Ukraine very soon. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Emmanuel Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/20/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-emmanuel-macron-of-france-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 22:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke with President Emmanuel Macron of France today. They discussed ongoing diplomacy and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s military buildup on the borders of Ukraine. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke with President Emmanuel Macron of France today. They discussed ongoing diplomacy and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s military buildup on the borders of Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s National Security Council&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/20/readout-of-president-bidens-national-security-council-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 20:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. convened a meeting of the National Security Council to discuss the latest developments regarding Russia’s military buildup on the borders of Ukraine. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. convened a meeting of the National Security Council to discuss the latest developments regarding Russia’s military buildup on the borders of Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in Press&#160;Gaggle</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/20/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-press-gaggle-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 14:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47566</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Westin Grand MunichMunich, Germany 11:18 A.M. CEST THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, this was an important trip to be here at the Munich Security Conference &#8212; in particular this year, as I said yesterday.&#160; We are looking at a moment that is a very decisive moment on one of the bases for the Munich Security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Westin Grand Munich<br>Munich, Germany</em></p>



<p>11:18 A.M. CEST</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, this was an important trip to be here at the Munich Security Conference &#8212; in particular this year, as I said yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are looking at a moment that is a very decisive moment on one of the bases for the Munich Security Conference and certainly one of the founding reasons for NATO, which is European security and the connection and alliance between Europe and the United States.</p>



<p>This was a productive trip, in terms of the extensive bilateral meetings that we had that were in furtherance of the ongoing collaboration and partnership with our Allies. &nbsp;</p>



<p>It was important in that, as you all know, this is a moment that is very dynamic.&nbsp; If not every hour, certainly every day, there seem to be new moments of interest and also of intelligence.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we have affirmed, however &#8212; all of that being said &#8212; through these last couple of days, that this Alliance is strong &#8212; probably stronger than it was before; and &#8212; and that this Alliance has purpose and meaning founded on shared principles that are very much at play right now.&nbsp; And as I mentioned yesterday, if we think about those principles, one of the most important is about a mutual respect for sovereignty and territorial integrity, which at its essence is what is at play in terms of Russia&#8217;s posture as it relates to Ukraine.<br><br>At stake is the NATO Alliance, in terms of our unity, joining together &#8212; through, sometimes, compromise; certainly always through collaboration &#8212; to be a unified voice, especially when these very founding principles of our relationship are being compromised, if not attacked.</p>



<p>So, with that, I’ll take any questions you have.</p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; And I’ll call on folks.&nbsp; So, Nandita from Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; During your meeting with President Zelenskyy, he spoke a little bit about asking the U.S. for specific defense aid.&nbsp; Could you talk a little bit about what he asked the United States for and what the U.S. has agreed to offer?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll tell you what I think you already know: So far, we have offered &#8212; not even offered, we have &#8212; we have transferred and given $650 million in aid.&nbsp; We have also made certain loan guarantees around, in particular, $1 billion.<br><br>And that is on top of all of the work that we have done collectively through the NATO Alliance to provide support for Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything new that you are planning to offer Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, what I made clear in our meeting and &#8212; is that &#8212; again, this is a dynamic situation.&nbsp; And depending on what happens in the coming days, we will reevaluate the need that Ukraine has and our ability to support.&nbsp; And we have been doing that through the course of these many months.</p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Molly from ABC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; I wanted to ask you, first, are you going to take part in that NSC meeting &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; today?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You are going to take part in that?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then I wanted to follow up on your meeting with President Zelenskyy yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When he spoke after your meeting, he shared his frustration with countries like the U.S. who say that a attack is likely to happen in Ukraine but that you won&#8217;t put sanctions in place until that happens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You &#8212; the administration has continually said that retaining those sanctions holds on to some leverage.&nbsp; But if you believe Putin has made up his mind, what leverage do you really have?&nbsp; Why not put those sanctions in place now?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The purpose of the sanctions has always been and continues to be deterrence.&nbsp; But let&#8217;s also recognize the unique nature of the sanctions that we have outlined.</p>



<p>These are some of the greatest sanctions, if not the strongest, that we&#8217;ve ever issued.&nbsp; As I articulated yesterday, it is directed at institutions &#8212; in particular, financial institutions &#8212; and individuals, and it will exact absolute harm for the Russian economy and their government.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if Putin has made up his mind, do you feel that this threat that has been looming is really going to deter him?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Absolut- &#8212; we strongly believe &#8212; and remember also that the sanctions are a product not only of our perspective as the United States but a shared perspective among our Allies.&nbsp; And the Allied relationship is such that we have agreed that the deterrence effect of these sanctions is still a meaningful one, especially because &#8212; remember, also &#8212; we still sincerely hope that there is a diplomatic path out of this moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And within the context then of the fact that that window is still opening, altho- &#8212; open, although it is absolutely narrowing &#8212; but within the context of a diplomatic path still being open, the deterrence effect, we believe, has merit.</p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Jennifer Jacobs from Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Would you be willing to talk a little bit about how the U.S. would get out of this potential conflict with Russia?&nbsp; What is the endgame?&nbsp; How does the U.S. &#8212; after imposing some of these sanctions and possible military action, how does the U.S. disentangle from this?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I would characterize it differently.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t consider ourselves to be entangled.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re very clear of our principles and our purpose, which is to be aligned with our Allies, understanding that &#8212; I mean, listen, guys, we&#8217;re talking about the potential for war in Europe.<br><br>I mean, let&#8217;s really take a moment to understand the significance of what we&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp; It’s been over 70 years.&nbsp; And through those 70 years, as I mentioned yesterday, there has been peace and security.&nbsp; We are talking about the real possibility of war in Europe.<br><br>So our position is, for us, very clear, which is as a leader &#8212; which we have been, bringing together the Allies, working together around our collective and unified position &#8212; that we would all not just prefer, we desire, we believe it is in the best interest of all that there is a diplomatic end to this moment.&nbsp; And so where do we want this to end?&nbsp; That is where we want it to end.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What should Americans be braced for?&nbsp; What could they possibly be facing?&nbsp; The President has already said Americans will be facing some economic fallout or some hardships.&nbsp; Can you explain to Americans what exactly will they face if this happened?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; As the President talked about in his speech, we are aware that, again, when America stands for her principles and all of the things that we hold dear, it requires sometimes for us to put ourselves out there in a way that maybe we will incur some cost.&nbsp; And in this situation, that may relate to energy costs, for example.&nbsp; But we are taking very specific and appropriate, I believe, steps to mitigate what that cost might be if it happens.</p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; Let’s go to Eli at the Los Angeles Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; A question about something else that President Zelenskyy said yesterday relating to NATO.&nbsp; He seemed to question the sincerity of Allies, including the U.S., I think, in terms of a desire to admit Ukraine to NATO.&nbsp; Is there any &#8212; is there any reaction to those pretty pointed comments from the President?&nbsp; And was that something that was discussed with Chancellor Scholz and other leaders?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me start by saying I appreciate and admire President Zelenskyy’s desire to join NATO.&nbsp; And one of, again, the founding principles of NATO is that each country must have the ability &#8212; unimpaired, unimpeded &#8212; to determine their own future, both in terms of their form of government and, in this case, whether they desire to be a member of NATO.<br><br>And I&#8217;ll put that in context, because the obvious is also the point, which is that: and therefore no other country can tell anyone whether they should or should not join NATO.&nbsp; That should be their independent choice.&nbsp; That is the point of sovereignty.&nbsp; So I respect President Zelenskyy’s desire to be a member of NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NATO is a membership.&nbsp; It is about nations coming together as a group, making decisions collectively around, again, principles and what will be, then, the conditions and &#8212; and the standards of membership.&nbsp; And so that is the process.</p>



<p>It doesn&#8217;t happen overnight.  No one country can say “I want to be, and therefore I will be.”  And no one country can say &#8220;You can&#8217;t be.&#8221;  And isn&#8217;t that at the heart of the very issue we’re presented with in terms of Russia&#8217;s aggression, or stated aggression, toward Ukraine?</p>



<p>Q    Was it surprising to you, though, that he planted that flag so firmly on that issue &#8212; given that that&#8217;s obviously Putin&#8217;s main demand, is that he gets some sort of guarantee, swearing that Ukraine won&#8217;t be admitted &#8212; that Zelenskyy wants to make it clear that they do want to enter the organization?  Was that a surprise that he would come and say that at this point in this crisis?  And does that make it less likely that there&#8217;ll be some sort of diplomatic resolution?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not going to second guess President Zelenskyy’s desires for his own country.  But I will say this: Let us recognize the position he is in right now.  His country is virtually surrounded by Russian troops.  I believe he came here &#8212; this is my belief, based on just my own assessment and speculation &#8212; he came here to make a very clear point that he does not stand alone.<br></p>



<p>In fact, I told him in our meeting, “The United States stands with you.”  Because we do, as do this community of Allies and partners.</p>



<p>So I understand where he &#8212; why he came here.  And I would not second guess &#8212; I will not second guess why he spoke the words he speaks.<br></p>



<p>He&#8217;s in a position, again, where his country is virtually surrounded by what &#8212; by, I think most reasonable people would believe, hostile troops.<br></p>



<p>AIDE:  Let’s go to Aamer at The AP, please.</p>



<p>Q    Thank you, Madam Vice President.  So Daleep Singh said late last week that SWIFT sanctions probably won&#8217;t be part of the opening gambit if sanctions go forward.  Considering the administration saying early and often that you&#8217;re going to stay high &#8212; start high and stay high, how does that square?  How can you start high and stay high without SWIFT sanctions in the package?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  We&#8217;re going to take this one moment at a time in terms of what might need to happen in the future in terms of escalation.  But right now, we&#8217;ve made our position clear.</p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; And last question, let&#8217;s go to Natasha at CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering whether the U.S. has evidence that Putin has actually given the order to his subordinates to launch an attack and whether that intelligence and that evidence is shared and agreed upon by the Allies here &#8212; and that includes Zelenskyy, who has been skeptical of this kind of intelligence in the past.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; As the President has said, we believe that Putin has made his decision.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I will also say that, as part of our relationship and partnership, in &#8212; in the context of the Alliance, we do share information, certainly, because we want to make sure that we are all working with the same information when we make these very critical and meaningful decisions &#8212; the last question about sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I said it yesterday on the stage: Everybody didn&#8217;t agree at the beginning about what the consequences should be if Russia re-invades Ukraine.&nbsp; We had to meet.&nbsp; We had to discuss it.&nbsp; Because each of these nations &#8212; I mean, I spe- &#8212; I spent time &#8212; a considerable amount of time with the Chancellor of Germany yesterday.&nbsp; I &#8212; I spent time with the President of the EU yesterday.&nbsp; When we look at the significance of these sanctions, they are immense.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, all nations who are a part of this understand that we cannot take lightly or speak lightly about what we are prepared to do, because we do understand the cost we are exacting, and it is severe.<br><br>So we have had these discussions, again, through a process.&nbsp; We have arrived at this place.&nbsp; And &#8212; and back to the last question, we will, obviously, reassess depending on how the days, weeks, and months ahead roll out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you believe &#8212;</p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; Thank you all.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; But &#8212; just go on.&nbsp; You can go to the follow-up (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was just going to ask: Do you believe that the U.S. and Ukraine are now more on the same page about what the intelligence suggests than they have been in the past?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I can tell you that there has been direct communication about the intelligence, so nothing is being held back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Vice President, the Prime Minister of Italy does not agree with all of the sanctions plans.&nbsp; He said yesterday that he does not feel that energy should be sanctioned.&nbsp; Does that not undercut U.S. efforts to impose tough, painful, severe financial sanctions?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve said, this is an alliance of nations that each have their priorities and their &#8212; their individual concerns about how anything we do going forward will impact their specific country, their economy, and their security.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, I would not deny Italy from having its perspective or its list of concerns; we all do, actually.&nbsp; That has been part of this process.&nbsp; And so Italy is very much at the table in terms of these conversations about how we can do this in a way that achieves its intended purpose, which &#8212; back to the earlier point &#8212; is about deterring Russia from invading a sovereign nation.<br><br>And we all understand, including every country in Europe, what war in Europe looks like and what it can mean for the citizens of each of those countries.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 11:34 A.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Briefings on&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/19/statement-from-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-briefings-on-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 23:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden continues to monitor the evolving situation in Ukraine, and is being updated regularly about events on the ground by his national security team. They reaffirmed that Russia could launch an attack against Ukraine at any time. This afternoon, the President received an update on the Vice President&#8217;s meetings at the Munich Security Conference with President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden continues to monitor the evolving situation in Ukraine, and is being updated regularly about events on the ground by his national security team. They reaffirmed that Russia could launch an attack against Ukraine at any time.</p>



<p>This afternoon, the President received an update on the Vice President&#8217;s meetings at the Munich Security Conference with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine, European Commission President von der Leyen, NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg, leaders of the Baltic states (Prime Minister Kallas of Estonia, President Levits of Latvia, and President Nauseda of Lithuania), Chancellor Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Mitsotakis of Greece, and leaders of other Allies and partners.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, the President will convene a meeting of the National Security Council on the situation in Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and President Zelenskyy Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/19/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-zelenskyy-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 16:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47550</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Commerzbank Filiale MünchenMunich, Germany 2:12 P.M. CEST VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&#160; I&#8217;m looking forward to our conversation.&#160;As you know, this is a decisive moment in our world&#8217;s history.&#160;And this is an important meeting for that and many other reasons. I look forward, in this discussion, to hearing directly from you about the situation on the ground&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Commerzbank Filiale München<br>Munich, Germany</em></p>



<p>2:12 P.M. CEST<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking forward to our conversation.&nbsp;As you know, this is a decisive moment in our world&#8217;s history.&nbsp;And this is an important meeting for that and many other reasons.</p>



<p>I look forward, in this discussion, to hearing directly from you about the situation on the ground in Ukraine.&nbsp; I look forward to, in this way, also hearing from you about what your concerns are and also sharing with you information that we may have in a way that we will continue to work together.</p>



<p>This is also a chance for me to reiterate the position of the United States as it relates to Ukraine.&nbsp; As I have said earlier today to our allies around the world, the United States take seriously the importance of the integrity and the territorial integrity of Ukraine and your sovereignty.&nbsp; And the United States stands with Ukraine in this regard.</p>



<p>If Russia further invades your country, as I mentioned earlier today, we will impose swift and severe economic sanctions.&nbsp; We have been clear about that.&nbsp; We are also clear that we would prefer that this would be resolved in a diplomatic way, and we have remained open to a diplomatic path to resolution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, if Russia takes aggressive action against Ukraine, we are prepared to implement and to do that work in a unified way with our allies around the world.</p>



<p>Any threats to your country, we take seriously, and we have rallied our Allies and our partners to speak with one voice.&nbsp; And those voices have been reflected throughout the course of these last couple of days and before.&nbsp; So I look forward to our conversation.&nbsp; And thank you.<br><br>PRESIDENT ZELENSKYY:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; And thank you for this meeting.&nbsp; This is our first meeting, and I&#8217;m very grateful to you and to our team for having this opportunity to talk to you about the situation which is happening around our borders; about the risks and how to resolve this matter and, I do agree with you, in a peaceful and diplomatic manner, as we have been doing all eight years in a row.</p>



<p>We do clearly understand what is going on.&nbsp; This is our land, and the only thing we want is to have peace, bring the peace back to our country.</p>



<p>And in this case, we are very grateful to the United States, to you personally, to our strategic partners, and President Biden.&nbsp; We have had many meetings with the congressmen and Senate members.&nbsp; And we are grateful for the bipartisan support of the United States.</p>



<p>Today, we do need specific steps, specific support.&nbsp; We are getting support from you in supporting our defense capacity, our army.&nbsp; This is something we are prepared to discuss and continue this dialogue because this is something that we are very interested in.</p>



<p>When I say “we,” I mean not only Ukraine, because our strong army is protecting Europe and we all want to be one unified body, one world which looks into the peaceful future.</p>



<p>As regards to the sanction policy, we are grateful to you for your understanding that sanctions may bring about peaceful resolution of this matter.&nbsp; And I would like to share with you that what &#8212; how we see this, what we think the needs are, and what we think can work.</p>



<p>In any case, we believe in our own strengths and force, the support of our partners, our army.&nbsp; And thank you very much again for this meeting.</p>



<p>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2:16 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Munich Security&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/19/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-munich-security-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 12:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hotel Bayerischer HofMunich, Germany 11:45 A.M. CEST THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Good morning.&#160; Thank you, Ambassador Ischinger.&#160; And to all of the very extraordinary leaders who are here today, I thank you for the kind introduction and your years of dedicated leadership.&#160; And thank you also to Chancellor Scholz for your kind words. So,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Hotel Bayerischer Hof<br>Munich, Germany</em></p>



<p>11:45 A.M. CEST</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Thank you, Ambassador Ischinger.&nbsp; And to all of the very extraordinary leaders who are here today, I thank you for the kind introduction and your years of dedicated leadership.&nbsp; And thank you also to Chancellor Scholz for your kind words.<br><br>So, it is an honor to join all of these distinguished leaders from around the world this morning.</p>



<p>I am certain we all recognize this year’s gathering is unlike those of the recent past.&nbsp; Not since the end of the Cold War has this forum convened under such dire circumstances.<br><br>Today, as we are all well aware, the foundation of European security is under direct threat in Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>Let us remember: From the wreckage of two world wars, a consensus emerged in Europe and the United States.&nbsp; A consensus in favor of order, not chaos; security, not conflict.<br><br>So by forging relationships and bonds, forging organizations and institutions, laws and treaties, we, together, established a set of rules, norms that have governed ever since.<br><br>And Europe has enjoyed unprecedented peace, security, and prosperity through a commitment to a set of defining principles.&nbsp; The United States is equally committed to these principles: that people have a right to choose their own form of government; that nations have a right to choose their own alliances; that there are inalienable rights which governments must protect; that the rule of law should be cherished; that sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states must be respected; and that national borders should not be changed by force.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We are here in Munich, together, to reaffirm our commitment to these principles.&nbsp; These principles have brought us peace and security.&nbsp; The backbone of this, of course, is NATO &#8212; the greatest military alliance the world has ever seen.<br><br>As a defensive alliance, we have deterred acts of aggression against NATO territory for the past 75 years.&nbsp; And today, let me be clear: America’s commitment to Article 5 is ironclad.&nbsp; This commitment is sacrosanct to me, to President Biden, and to our entire nation.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, I am joined here in Munich by a bipartisan delegation from the United States Senate and the United States House of Representatives.&nbsp; They are Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; They have a wide range of political views.&nbsp; But they stand together in recognition of the value and the importance of our NATO Alliance.<br><br>Now, even in the most difficult times for our transatlantic community and even when our system has been tried and tested, we, the United States and Europe, have come together and demonstrated our strength and our unity, just as we do today &#8212; as we stand in this decisive moment, with all eyes on Ukraine.<br><br>As we have said all along, there is a playbook of Russian aggression.&nbsp; And this playbook is too familiar to us all.</p>



<p>Russia will plead ignorance and innocence, it will create false pretext for invasion, and it will amass troops and firepower in plain sight.<br><br>We now receive reports of what appears to be provocations.&nbsp; And we see Russia spreading disinformation, lies, and propaganda.<br><br>Nonetheless, in a deliberate and coordinated effort, we, together, are: one, exposing the truth and, two, speaking with a unified voice.<br><br>As President Joe Biden has made clear: The United States, our NATO Allies, and our partners have been and remain open to serious diplomacy.&nbsp; We have put concrete proposals on the table.&nbsp; We have encouraged and engaged Russia through NATO, the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe, the United Nations, and bilateral dialogues.&nbsp; We have engaged in good faith.</p>



<p>Russia continues to claim it is ready for talks while, at the same time, it narrows the avenues for diplomacy.&nbsp; Their actions simply do not match their words.<br><br>And let me be clear.&nbsp; I can say with absolute certainty: If Russia further invades Ukraine, the United States, together with our Allies and partners, will impose significant and unprecedented economic costs.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We have worked intensively with many of you in this room to ensure we are prepared to move forward with consequences.<br><br>We have prepared, together, economic measures that will be swift, severe, and united.&nbsp; We will impose far-reaching financial sanctions and export controls.&nbsp; We will target Russia’s financial institutions and key industries.&nbsp; And we will target those who are complicit and those who aid and abet this unprovoked invasion.<br><br>Make no mistake: The imposition of these sweeping and coordinated measures will inflict great damage on those who must be held accountable.&nbsp; And we will not stop with economic measures.&nbsp; We will further reinforce our NATO Allies on the eastern flank.<br><br>In fact, together we have already taken steps to strengthen our deterrence and collective defense.&nbsp; We have deployed an additional 6,000 American service members to Romania, Poland, and Germany.&nbsp; We have put another 8,500 service members in the United States on a heightened sense of readiness.<br><br>As President Biden has said, our forces will not be deployed to fight inside Ukraine, but they will defend every inch of NATO territory.<br><br>Since Russia launched its proxy war against Ukraine nearly eight years ago, the people of Ukraine have suffered immensely: nearly 14,000 people killed, more than a million displaced, and nearly 3 million in need of aid.<br><br>The United States has provided significant support to Ukraine: security assistance, humanitarian assistance, and economic assistance.&nbsp; And we will continue to support the people of Ukraine.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>I believe it is important for us &#8212; all of us &#8212; as leaders to never forget the cost of this type of aggression on human lives and livelihoods.<br><br>So, the United States, our Allies, and our partners, together, we have achieved remarkable unity.&nbsp; It is evident in our shared acknowledgment of the threats, our united response, and our determination to uphold international rules and norms.<br><br>In the face of Russian aggression, I have been reassured and heartened by the widespread agreement across the transatlantic community that these rules and norms will be defended.<br><br>And we should not lose sight of how rare it is in history to have a prolonged period of relative peace and stability.&nbsp; So, let the past few months be a reminder to us all: Defending the rules and norms, upholding our principles &#8212; this is the vital work of each generation.<br><br>In recent years, some have questioned whether the West is up to the task.&nbsp; Some have wondered whether this system can endure.&nbsp; Some have even done so on this very stage.<br><br>Indeed, the theme of this conference two years ago questioned the staying power of the West; whether or not the transatlantic community was losing its cohesion, its influence, its appeal.<br><br>So I will answer the skeptics and those seeking to test us: Today, the United States, our Allies, and our partners are closer together.&nbsp; Today, we are clear in our purpose.&nbsp; And today, we are even more confident in our vision.<br><br>Our strength must not be underestimated, because, after all, it lies in our unity.&nbsp; And as we have always shown, it takes a lot more strength to build something up than it takes to tear something down.<br><br>Thank you all.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>AMBASSADOR ISCHINGER:&nbsp; Madam Vice President, thank you so much for this great speech, which I think will be commented about and read about quite a bit in coming hours and days and weeks.</p>



<p>Before we start our conversation, let me repeat what I said before you came into the hall.&nbsp; It was in 2009, President Biden who established &#8212; having just been elected Vice President at that time &#8212; a young tradition, namely that the United States would be represented in Munich by the Vice President.</p>



<p>And he came several times.&nbsp; And I was delighted to see that even the Trump administration followed that example.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re now so happy to have you to continue this tradition.&nbsp; And I would be delighted if you can convey to the President that even if he is now no longer the Vice President, he has always a standing invitation here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, Ambassador, I will.&nbsp; And I will tell you, it is the President&#8217;s enthusiasm about the importance of this conference that led to my enthusiasm to be with you this afternoon.&nbsp; So thank you very much.<br><br>AMBASSADOR ISCHINGER:&nbsp; Now, on a slightly more serious note: A year ago, when the President appeared on our screen &#8212; actually, in this room &#8212; I was standing right here in this room when he appeared on screen and he said, and I quote, “America is back.&nbsp; The transatlantic alliance is back.”</p>



<p>Now, that was a message that was extremely well received here, even if we &#8212; not all of us knew that we would be threatened in the way that we feel threatened right now, as you just explained.</p>



<p>But as we look forward, there are lots of people here in Germany, in Europe, who asking themselves, “Okay, America is back.&nbsp; That&#8217;s great.&nbsp; But is it for good?&nbsp; Is this for good?”&nbsp; Many in Europe are fearful of a time where maybe some kind of a second Trump could be looming in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So here&#8217;s my question: What can or should we Europeans do to keep the United States engaged in Europe long term, not just today as we sit here, and even beyond the current administration?<br><br>I think that is such an important question, because we have learned over these last weeks and months that without the United States considering herself a European power, we&#8217;re actually quite powerless.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think the evidence of the point that I will make is present in this room.&nbsp; You will see there is probably one of the largest delegations from the United States Congress present today &#8212; Republicans and Democrats who, as I said earlier, you know, often don&#8217;t agree on much, but agree on this.</p>



<p>I would &#8212; I think that the heart of your question really does demand the importance of &#8212; of the perseverance and enduring nature of institutions and alliances.&nbsp; And I would say that, on that point, we are strong.</p>



<p>There is an unwavering commitment to NATO and to the Alliance, as evidenced, again, by the conversations and the unity that has resulted over the last several months where nations have come together, where the United States, we would like to believe, has been among leaders in playing a leadership role to bring together the Allies around common principles and norms, doing it in a way that has been, at its essence, about the value and the strength of diplomacy, which is about direct engagement.</p>



<p>We have counted &#8212; and the Secretary of State is here, Tony Blinken.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve counted an excess of at least 200 conversations just in the last couple of months, be it between the President and others, the Secretary of State, myself, and so on.</p>



<p>So I would say to you that the relationship is strong and that the importance of the relationship is something that we take very seriously, which is why in this historic moment, in this defining moment, potentially, the strength of the institution and the Alliance reveals itself, even if there&#8217;s been a question about that before.<br><br>AMBASSADOR ISCHINGER:  Thank you so much. <br><br>Now, another key team &#8212; key theme of our special edition with President Biden a year ago was this question, and I&#8217;d be interested in your response today.  The question was: Can democracies prove that they can still deliver better solutions to the world&#8217;s major challenges than autocracies?<br></p>



<p>There are skeptics who would probably not have a hard time finding evidence to the contrary over the past period.  What do we need, what do democracies need in order to do better and to convince our people &#8212; peoples that we can do it?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Ambassador, I think this is one of the most challenging issues of our time, which is the relative strength &#8212; the question about the relative strength, efficiency, and effectiveness of democracies versus autocracies.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to always bet on democracies.  I think all of us here share that in common.  And it is a reflection of, again, the principles that we have that include the importance of being a government that reflects the needs and desires of the people through a process that has integrity, that rejects corruption, and embraces the concepts of equality and freedom.<br><br>When we look at the challenge that we face now, in the United States &#8212; and you&#8217;re right, President Joe Biden talks a lot about this &#8212; and we take pride in the fact that the strength of a democra- &#8212; democracy, one measure of that strength will be: Does it deliver on the needs of the people?<br><br>So, for example, in the United States &#8212; again, with thanks and with great attribution to the congressional delegates that are here &#8212; we passed a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that was one of the first in generations that will deliver on the needs of the people. <br><br>So, I would say that the strength of democracies and the way that democracies will prevail, one &#8212; one measure of that will be: Does it actually deliver for the people? <br><br>But that being said, there is a duality that is always present, I believe, which is that democracy is both &#8212; it both has the characters of &#8212; characteristics of strength and fragility, meaning that it is incumbent on each of us to understand the strength of democracy to deliver for the people, but also the fragility of democracies, which is that if we are not vigilant, if we don&#8217;t fight for the principles, then they can fade. <br><br>And so, that, again, brings us to the reason that we are here today: to continuously reaffirm and rededicate ourselves as a community to the strength of democracies and the need for us to not only individually but collectively uphold its principles, its values, and its purpose.<br><br>AMBASSADOR ISCHINGER:  Thank you very much.  Now, I think I have no choice but to return to our overriding theme this weekend, which has been when Secretary Stoltenberg spoke earlier and Chancellor Scholz spoke just before you.  Of course, the central theme was &#8212; and you talked about it just a few minutes ago &#8212; was Ukraine. <br><br>So, the Biden administration, the President himself, you &#8212; you&#8217;ve all stated that you expect that there will be some kind of military action by Russia going forward.  Now, I &#8212; personally, I&#8217;ve no question about your determination to do what you announced to do. <br></p>



<p>But I think this audience would be interested in how you and the Biden administration judges our readiness.  Do you think we, Europeans, are sufficiently prepared for such a kind of worst-case scenario, which would &#8212; in my view at least, which would tend to sort of, you know, terminate the search for a durable and peaceful European security architecture?  And we&#8217;ve been working on that for more than a generation &#8212; for two generations.<br><br>So, the question is: If you could reflect a bit about how you think about this and what, conceivably, Americans and Europeans &#8212; working together &#8212; what we could do in the future even better in terms of speaking with Russia, not only about Russia. <br><br>You know, one of the things I really regret is that the Russian government decided not to come here.  I would have appreciated an opportunity to challenge them on this stage, as has been the case for many years here Munich. <br><br>So &#8212; but I think you understand my question.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, as I said in my speech, I am reassured and heartened by the work that we have collectively done over the last several months.  And it is work.  Not everyone started out in the same place in terms of a variety of issues that are on the table.  How do we define &#8220;aggression&#8221;?  What should be the consequences?  Which consequences are appropriate?  Which are we willing to pursue?  Which aren&#8217;t we willing to pursue?  So we didn&#8217;t all start out in the same place. <br><br>But through diplomacy &#8212; and again, this speaks to the strength of diplomacy &#8212; we came together and are now speaking with a unified voice.  And that voice was a function of not only dialogue, but debate, some concessions, but also a practical realization of the moment that we&#8217;re in, which is that we are looking at a sovereign nation that may very well be on the verge of being invaded yet again.<br><br>And perhaps this is a moment, as life does present us with those moments, that challenge us to ask what is our reason for being.  And I think we all know the history of NATO and its reason for being.  The spirit behind this term we use, &#8220;the transatlantic community.&#8221;  The word &#8220;community,&#8221; meaning a collection, not &#8212; a collection of individuals who see themselves as a collection than as one.  And that’s where we are now.<br><br>I don’t disagree with you that it would be nice if we were presented with other circumstances, be it at this conference or in the world, but that’s not where we are.<br><br>We remain open to diplomacy.  We have said it continuously, and our deeds, our words, and our actions have reflected that priority.</p>



<p>We believe that when you define the strength of any nation &#8212; certainly I&#8217;ll speak for the United States &#8212; we believe it is an expression of our strength to seek, as a first priority, a diplomatic resolution to any conflict.&nbsp; And I believe we&#8217;ve been clear about that.&nbsp; But yet, we are presented with this moment today.</p>



<p>And so the question is: If that diplomacy leads to a dead end &#8212; we hope it does not; I said that again in my speech today, the President said it last night &#8212; we are still open to a diplomatic resolution.&nbsp; But if it does not, we are also clear-eyed that there must be consequences.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we have clearly articulated the consequences we have in store, and they will be severe and swift.&nbsp; And they were derived through a process, again, of diplomatic discussions and engagement wherein there has been some consensus around what would be appropriate, given perhaps some predictable scenarios.</p>



<p>I think this moment speaks to, yes, a moment we would like to avoid, if it was avoidable, but it also speaks to our resolve to speak with one voice and a unified voice.</p>



<p>History has challenged us over the years in that regard.&nbsp; But I think history will show that, at this moment, we are standing strong.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>AMBASSADOR ISCHINGER:&nbsp; Madam Vice President, I can only thank you on behalf of our participants of this audience and of those who are listening from the outside for traveling over &#8212; for coming over here in these difficult circumstances with pandemic conditions.&nbsp; You know, under more normal circumstances, there would be like 600 people in this hall.&nbsp; It would be totally overcrowded.&nbsp; So thank you for doing this.&nbsp;<br>Thank you for doing this for us.&nbsp; For us here in Europe, it’s &#8212; it’s an enormously reassuring message.&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to invite all of you to offer to the Vice President of the United States a warm round of applause, if you could, please.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; 12:14 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Briefing on the Vice President&#8217;s Events in Munich,&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/18/background-press-briefing-on-the-vice-presidents-events-in-munich-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 03:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Munich, Germany AIDE:&#160; (Inaudible) on background with a senior administration official, and embargoed until the end of the conversation.&#160; And it’s just going to be [senior administration official]. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; This conversation. AIDE:&#160; Embargoed until the end of this conversation, on background with a senior administration official. So, [senior administration official] will give some opening thoughts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Munich, Germany </em></p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; (Inaudible) on background with a senior administration official, and embargoed until the end of the conversation.&nbsp; And it’s just going to be [senior administration official].<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This conversation.<br><br>AIDE:&nbsp; Embargoed until the end of this conversation, on background with a senior administration official.<br><br>So, [senior administration official] will give some opening thoughts and then happy to take questions.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, let me just sort of do a brief overview and walk you a little bit through the events of today and the plans for tomorrow.<br><br>But in the context of this overall trip &#8212; in the context of the overall trip, I think we already talked about a little bit, is that the context of this administration&#8217;s approach to this crisis and approach to our alliances and partnerships in general, which we stress was key to this administration&#8217;s foreign policy from the start.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s moments like these that they become particularly important.&nbsp;<br><br>And you&#8217;ve seen, I think in the recent weeks and days, a very deliberate, intentional, coordinated, and clear rollout on how we&#8217;re approaching this crisis.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard it multiple times from the President, from the Secretary of State, from the Secretary of Defense, and the Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>And she came here as part of that overall approach to this crisis to do a number of things: to continue the process of consulting as we continue to flesh out our response to Russia&#8217;s aggression and threats of aggression; coordinating that with our close partners in Europe who are involved in this; and delivering the message that we&#8217;ve been delivering all along to them &#8212; one of support and solidarity and commitment to some core principles, and to the Russians that we are and continue to be ready for diplomacy &#8212; and we put a lot of ideas on the table &#8212; but we&#8217;re also determined to respond as we need to respond and impose costs if they go ahead and continue with the further invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>So this is part of a real administration-wide process of consultation with our close allies.&nbsp;<br><br>So it was, in that context, fitting that her first meeting of the day was with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg.&nbsp; There are a lot of elements to our response, and they&#8217;re not only military and defensive and deterrence, but they include that.&nbsp; And NATO has been a big part of the response to Russia&#8217;s activities.&nbsp;<br><br>And she used this opportunity with the Secretary General to further coordinate how we as an Alliance of 30 countries are responding.&nbsp; And so they talked about some of what we&#8217;ve already done and some of what we might need to do in the future.&nbsp; And you know &#8212; we&#8217;ve already talked about some of the force posture adjustments we&#8217;ve made to reinforce our Allies to which we have Article 5 commitments in NATO.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve done a lot of that, including sending troops from the United States &#8212; further troops from the United States to Europe, and also what we&#8217;ve done for Ukraine, including the $650 million of defense assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>And she thanked the Secretary General for his leadership over the past eight years.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been a stalwart friend of the United States and a great leader of this Alliance and is called upon to lead at a really difficult time.&nbsp;<br><br>So they talked about Alliance unity, the way forward.&nbsp; I mentioned force posture adjustments and also the diplomacy.&nbsp; You saw that we, as recently as Secretary Blinken&#8217;s speech &#8212; either yesterday or the day before; it&#8217;s hard to even keep track &#8212; at the U.N. said that we&#8217;re still ready to meet and proposed a meeting with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov.&nbsp; NATO has done the same &#8212; the Secretary for NATO-Russia Council.&nbsp;<br><br>So this was a real opportunity to coordinate on all those fronts, diplomatic and military.&nbsp;<br><br>Following a meeting with Secretary General Stoltenberg, she met with the three leaders of the Baltic states &#8212; Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.&nbsp; It was really important for her in that meeting &#8212; for the Vice President &#8212; to underscore our enduring and unshakable commitment to NATO’s Article 5.&nbsp; These are among the Allies who are most concerned about that because they feel the threat themselves directly, and not least from the massive Russian military presence in Belarus.&nbsp; And so she reassured them that the United States means what it says when it says it&#8217;s committed to Article 5.<br><br>And they, together, discussed some of the same themes from the meeting with the NATO Secretary General &#8212; the force posture adjustments that we made, the further troops and equipment that we&#8217;ve sent to Europe to, as we&#8217;ve said many times, be ready for any contingency.<br><br>The Vice President also discussed with them the issue of costs, which we all in this Alliance agree on it, if Russia goes in further.&nbsp; And that requires coordination of economic sanctions, which has been a priority for us as well.&nbsp; These are members of the European Union, and their role in that will be important.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, finally, she had a meeting with a bipartisan delegation from Congress &#8212; I think we&#8217;ve put out some information about that already &#8212; but delegations led by Speaker Pelosi and Senators Graham and Whitehouse &#8212; bipartisan, bicameral.<br><br>The Vice President, as a sort of a tradition at the Munich Security Conference, took the opportunity to meet with them.&nbsp;&nbsp;And that was not only useful to see them and discuss some of the issues, but to demonstrate that our approach to this crisis is really a bipartisan one.&nbsp; There are plenty of divisions in Washington on plenty of issues.&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s fair to say when it comes to standing up to Russia and its aggression, we&#8217;re quite unified.&nbsp; And that was a really important message and is an important message that the Vice President here is here leading our delegation.&nbsp; And there are important members of both houses of Congress here as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Sorry to go on for so long, but maybe a couple of things about tomorrow, and then after we&#8217;ll take a few questions.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the main element of tomorrow&#8217;s program is her speech to the Munich Security Conference.&nbsp; I think, as I mentioned before, you know, you&#8217;ve heard from other senior people in this administration, starting with the President &#8212; and you&#8217;ll see, I think, her speech fit into the message that we&#8217;ve been sending from the start of this crisis: that we are preparing for either contingency, diplomacy or a response &#8212; a tough response, as necessary.&nbsp;<br><br>We have been putting the world on notice of what we&#8217;re afraid of and seeing from the Russians &#8212; these provocations that we fear that they could use as a pretext for invading Ukraine.&nbsp; And in the past hours and days, unfortunately, we have seen some of those.<br><br>The Vice President &#8212; I think you can expect her to articulate some core themes.&nbsp; And I (inaudible) get into too much detail about the speech, but she will no doubt articulate some important themes, including “strength through unity.”&nbsp; The whole point of meeting with these close Allies is that we&#8217;re stronger when we&#8217;re acting together.&nbsp;<br><br>I think she&#8217;ll underscore some of the core principles that are at stake here &#8212; you know, not least that: One country simply can&#8217;t decide it&#8217;s just going to invade another country and violate the sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; It’s a core principle of NATO and many other organizations in which we’re a part, and certainly one that we believe in and the Vice President strongly believes in.<br><br>She will make clear, as we have been making clear for days and weeks and months, that we remain, even at this late hour, open to diplomacy.&nbsp; But if the Russians reject that diplomacy that we have offered, that will be a sign that they weren&#8217;t really serious about it.<br><br>I think you can expect the Vice President to be clear about the costs that would be imposed on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been pretty clear that those (inaudible) will include significant, severe, and swift financial sanctions and export controls that will be very costly to Russia and weaken Russia.&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s, in fact, one of the core points that, regardless of what happens, we, in this Alliance, believe we will emerge stronger and Russia will emerge weaker.&nbsp;<br><br>Then, the rest of the schedule I think we discussed on the call the other day: a bilateral meeting with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine, a bilateral meeting with Chancellor Scholz of Germany.&nbsp; And then a number of other, you know, what we call “pull-asides” with a number of other leaders &#8212; world leaders in town that she will be meeting with.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have a list for you, frankly, simply because the schedule, like the world is, is in flux.&nbsp; And we haven&#8217;t set a final schedule, but you can be sure there&#8217;ll be a number of other world leaders that she’ll spend some time with &#8212; once again, because &#8212; going back to the core point that we&#8217;re stronger when we&#8217;re together, this whole trip is about coordinating with key partners.<br><br>AIDE:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Let’s open it up to questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we &#8212; you mentioned the conversations today with the Baltic leaders and commitment to Article 5.&nbsp; They also were asked for a greater U.S. presence.&nbsp; (Inaudible) pretty blunt, and I thought that the wording was strong about “we&#8217;ve lost our freedom to Russia once; we don&#8217;t want to do it again” &#8212; is what Estonia&#8217;s Prime Minister said.&nbsp;<br><br>What commitments are you guys ready to make to them? &nbsp;And in the case of Lithuania, they formally asked to go from the rotational presence to something more permanent.&nbsp; Is this just necessary at this point in the world we live in for there to be a bigger and more permanent presence on the eastern flank?<br><br>And then, secondly, on Zelenskyy, is there any concern tomorrow about him coming, even if it&#8217;s just for several hours, to be seen outside of Ukraine at such a fluid and difficult time?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first, I don’t have any new announcements on force posture in Europe beyond those that, you know, our administration has already announced.&nbsp; Because I did say that we have adjusted force posture.&nbsp; And we do that to be ready for any contingency, and that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what we remain determined to do.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know, there is already NATO force posture presence in the Baltic states: battalions announced &#8212; rotational battalions after 2014, and also Baltic Air Policing, where NATO countries help them patrol the airspace.&nbsp;<br><br>But I think you will find that our force posture &#8212; we have said: If Russia further invades Ukraine, then we will continue to look at the force posture that is necessary to make sure Article 5 is preserved, protected, and all of our countries can be defended.&nbsp;<br><br>On Zelenskyy, I don&#8217;t have anything to announce that we announced the other day.&nbsp; I think you probably saw that his spokesman put out a statement that they were considering their trip, so I can only refer you to the Ukrainians as to President Zelenskyy’s plans about being in Munich.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any concern about him coming?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; What is important is that we continue our dialogue with the Ukrainians and continue to demonstrate support for the Ukrainians.<br><br>President Biden has spoken a number of times with President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken has been in Kyiv.&nbsp; We have, as a government, engaged very closely to demonstrate our support for Ukraine in this situation.&nbsp;<br><br>And when President Zelenskyy said he was going to be in Munich, this was another opportunity to continue that dialogue.&nbsp;&nbsp;And if he&#8217;s here, the Vice President will be &#8212; it will be an important opportunity for her to engage with him.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there is no effort to ask or encourage Zelenskyy not to leave Ukraine?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s really his call.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really up to him where he feels he needs to be.&nbsp; If he&#8217;s in Munich, the Vice President will look forward to meeting with him.&nbsp; If he decides he needs to be in Ukraine, we&#8217;ll find other ways of engaging with him to keep on the dialogue that we&#8217;ve had from the start.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up also on the Lithuanian &#8212;&nbsp;I mean, that was a very public request.&nbsp; It was made very directly to Vice President Harris about the permanent troops.&nbsp; I mean, what do you &#8212; what do you make of just the fact that it&#8217;s such a public request?&nbsp; I mean, is it &#8212; is that &#8212; you mentioned things will change if there&#8217;s invasion.&nbsp; Does that mean permanent rotation is under consideration?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; What it means is that we have had and continue to have a very fruitful and, I think, satisfactory dialogue with all of our NATO partners, including &#8212; or, you might even say, especially &#8212; the Baltic states in recent weeks and months about force posture, and we’ll continue to do so.<br><br>Secretary Austin was just at the NATO defense ministerial in Brussels.&nbsp; He then went on to Poland and is going to Lithuania to continue this discussion of what is the best and right force posture for the United States and NATO in Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t have anything beyond that to say except that, obviously, we&#8217;re constantly looking at what we need to do to defend all of our NATO Allies.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know, has President Putin &#8212; has President Putin made up his mind on whether to attack or not?&nbsp; Does the U.S. believe he knows now what he&#8217;s going to do?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I think you&#8217;ve heard us be pretty clear that we don&#8217;t try to figure out what&#8217;s in his mind.&nbsp; All we can do is watch what we’re watching.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, no determination has been made yet on whether he plans to attack or not, at this point?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We can&#8217;t know what&#8217;s in his head.&nbsp; We can’t know what’s in his head.&nbsp; We just have to prepare for what &#8212; you know, we have noted what we feared could precede an invasion as being alleged provocations and what could be a pretext.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing some of those things which are a great cause for concern.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why our diplomacy that the Vice President is leading here in Munich has been intensified.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not going to guess what&#8217;s in President Putin’s mind.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of quick questions.&nbsp; President Putin obviously did a news conference earlier today in which he sort of brushed off, you know, the threat of &#8212;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;I’m sorry, what news conference?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Putin did a news conference earlier today, which you’re obviously aware of, but there he spoke about sort of how the West always finds a pretext to impose sanctions on Moscow.&nbsp; So, essentially, kind of brushing off the threat that has been sort of the cornerstone of the, you know, the U.S. strategy.&nbsp;<br><br>How concerned are you that, you know, this has kind of failed to really deter him in the past?&nbsp; Do you &#8212; do you really think that that&#8217;s going to happen this time?<br><br>And also, separately, the Russian Defense Ministry said that he&#8217;s going to oversee nuclear drills in Russia on Saturday.&nbsp; Do you consider that to be a concerning sign &#8212; a sign of escalation?&nbsp; How &#8212; you know, how are you thinking about, sort of, Putin looking at nuclear drills in Russia in this situation?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first, you know, look, obviously there are no guarantees.&nbsp; All we can do is make clear that there will be severe costs if Russia decides to further invade Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also made clear, because you alluded to him saying that &#8220;they&#8217;ve put sanctions on us before&#8221;&nbsp;&#8212; which is true; we have done for other violations &#8212; we&#8217;ve made clear that these sanctions would go well beyond anything we&#8217;ve done in the past.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve put on some significant sanctions not just in 2014 after the invasion of Ukraine and annexation of parts of southeastern Ukraine and the annexation of Crimea, but well beyond anything we&#8217;ve done since then.&nbsp;<br><br>And I mention that that will include very severe financial sanctions, coordinated with our European allies, and export controls to weaken Russia&#8217;s industrial base, defense industrial base.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we hope President Putin really takes that to heart and gets that message, because if he thinks somehow invading or occupying Ukraine will strengthen Russia, we believe we&#8217;re going to demonstrate through these actions the opposite is the case.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;re confident that this is going to act as a deterrent?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;re confident that this is going to act as a deterrent?&nbsp; Everything you have planned, in terms of export controls and sanctions, that is going to deter him this time around?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not making any predictions about it.&nbsp; I’m just describing what the thinking behind what we&#8217;re doing is.&nbsp; We&#8217;re bolstering Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;re reinforcing our NATO Allies in Europe to make sure they&#8217;re safe.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to hit Russia with very severe economic costs if it goes in, while also saying, to this day: We are ready for and prefer a different path, which is diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;m not making any predictions.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just describing what we&#8217;re conveying with the hope that it will lead the Russians to see that they are better off and we are all better off if they choose the course of diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And could you please answer my question on the nuclear drills?&nbsp; The &#8212; you know, that the Defense Ministry said is going to happen tomorrow and Putin is going to actually be overseeing them.&nbsp; Do you think that is &#8212; would you classify that as escalation?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I think &#8212; obviously, in the context like this with so many military forces deployed and lots of tensions in the region, I think it&#8217;s fair to say that adding on top of that with nuclear and other strategic exercises is escalatory and unfortunate.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, can you talk about the coordination or whatever between the Vice President and the Secretary of State?&nbsp; Are they talking?&nbsp; Are they meeting regularly?&nbsp; Are they kind of staying in their own lane and all of that stuff?<br><br>And a second question: I wonder &#8212; one of the things that President Biden did was sort of speak directly to the Russian people, you know, in some of his speeches over the last week.&nbsp; I wonder if the Vice President plans to do something similar to issue a message or (inaudible) directly to the Russian people, directly to Putin in her speech, or whenever.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the latter, I&#8217;ll leave that to the speech.&nbsp; I described some of the key themes I thought &#8212; I think you can expect her to address.&nbsp; But I won&#8217;t preempt the speech further on that particular point.&nbsp;<br><br>Although, you know, we do think it&#8217;s important &#8212; and that&#8217;s why the President embraced it &#8212; and that&#8217;s, you know, linked to this issue of costs as well, because we want the Russian people to know this is not against the Russian people.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to defend Ukraine against an invasion, and have no ill will towards the Russian people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we prefer diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>As for the Vice President and Secretary Blinken: Yes, they are in extraordinarily close contact.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve met several times today, in fact &#8212; or at least a couple of times &#8212; including a private meeting this morning to coordinate and work together on how we&#8217;re going to advance our &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Blinken.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The VP.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The Vice President and Secretary Blinken (inaudible).<br><br>And so, you know, I actually began by talking about how, we as an administration, have been rolling out a deliberate, intentional, coordinated strategy with multiple actors doing multiple things as part of the same team, and that&#8217;s what this deployment to Munich is.<br><br>I mentioned the Vice President has had and will continue to have a number of bilateral meetings with her counterparts &#8212; as mentioned, the two presidents and prime minister of the Baltic states, Chancellor Scholz, Secretary General of NATO, and President Zelenskyy.&nbsp;<br><br>And Secretary Blinken has had and will continue to have numerous contacts with his foreign minister counterparts, both bilaterally and multilaterally.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we are &#8212; you know, in the context of what I mentioned about being here and coordinating, and, you know, this is all about strength, unity, dialogue, and coordination.&nbsp; That &#8212; you know, their activities here are a core part of that approach.<br><br>But, absolutely intimately in contact with each other, including, as I mentioned, discussions throughout the day.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you share &#8212; can you share anything of what they&#8217;ve talked about or specifics, like how, specifically, does he guide her &#8212; whether it&#8217;s in a specific meeting or a specific question, or is it more as a sounding board?&nbsp; I just want to understand it better.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, they&#8217;re implementing the same strategy.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve described &#8212; we&#8217;ve all described what we&#8217;re doing here: coordinating a joint approach with Europeans on sanctions, if it comes to that; looking together with our NATO partners on force posture adjustments; and discussing our support for Ukraine, which is not just military, but the sovereign loan guarantee.&nbsp; And so, they are implementing the exact same policy set by the President, and they&#8217;re doing it together.&nbsp;<br><br>AIDE:&nbsp; We have time, folks, for two more questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the SWIFT &#8212;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Let’s go to Molly.&nbsp; She hasn’t had a chance.&nbsp; And then come back to Jennifer.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the (inaudible) reports of the Russian separatists reporting mass evacuations and signaling that there&#8217;s a possible explosion that &#8212; a lot of reports coming out of that region.&nbsp;<br><br>You talked about the Vice President being willing to talk about some of these false-flag efforts in her speech.&nbsp; How specific do you expect her to get?&nbsp; And does the United States believe that these reports of mass evacuations that we&#8217;re seeing are part of a false-flag effort that are starting and could, perhaps, lead to a full-scale invasion by Russia?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m just not sure I specifically said she would talk about that in her speech.&nbsp; If I did, maybe I misspoke, because what I was suggesting is that that has been the predicate to her speech.&nbsp; Like, she&#8217;s giving a speech at a moment when we&#8217;ve already warned that we&#8217;re going to see a potential pretext for an invasion, and we&#8217;ve already started to do that.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s like where we are at the moment she&#8217;s giving her speech.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s been important to do that in advance because we&#8217;ve seen it play out.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as for confirming &#8212; I think I mentioned the other day when we talked about this &#8212; you know, this approach of throwing spaghetti at the wall.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve alleged many, many different things, most of which we can&#8217;t confirm.&nbsp; And that is concerning because they are all potentially in that category of things that they&#8217;re going to point to.&nbsp;<br><br>So you mentioned the specific one of evacuations.&nbsp; That&#8217;s troubling, as are the allegations of shelling and missile deployments and many of the other things that they have alleged that we&#8217;re not able to confirm, which makes us worry that this is part of what we were afraid of: that they&#8217;re coming up with some pretext for using force against Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any update on the troop levels?&nbsp; You know, since the 7,000, have there been &#8212; has the administration seen any additional troops come in the last &#8212; I guess, was it &#8212; has it been 24 hours since the 7,000?&nbsp; Or 48 hours?&nbsp; Does &#8212; do the numbers continue to rise?&nbsp; Are there more signs on the border of a potential invasion? &nbsp;<br><br>And also, you mentioned about seriousness of diplomacy.&nbsp; Does the administration now feel or is it increasingly feeling that Russia is not interested in diplomacy?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first, I won&#8217;t go beyond.&nbsp; I think the President, you know, yesterday said something about, you know, upwards of 150,000 troops.&nbsp; We do &#8212; we have been clear that we are not seeing the withdrawals that they are claiming.&nbsp; In fact, the 7,000 you refer to is &#8212; not only did we not see the withdrawals, but we saw an additional 7,000, and we have not seen withdrawals (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But have you seen increases since then?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don’t have any increases to announce here.<br><br>And the second part of your question is on diplomacy?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About diplomacy.&nbsp; And does the United States &#8212; you know, Harris said it’s up to &#8212; the onus is on Russia to take diplomacy seriously.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the consideration that &#8212; does the United States now acknowledge or think that Russia is not taking it seriously &#8212; diplomacy?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The next few days will tell us a lot.&nbsp; I think you heard Secretary Blinken at the United Nations the other day make that clear that he is ready to meet his counterpart.&nbsp; NATO did the same &#8212; the NATO-Russia Council.<br><br>If Russia invades, notwithstanding our offers to continue to talk following these specific things we put on the table in terms of diplomacy, I think we would be forced by that to conclude that Russia is not ready for diplomacy.&nbsp; That would be the sign.&nbsp; But until that happens, we’re still (inaudible), because that’s a far preferable approach for everybody.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And until that happens, can you not rule out that they are not willing to find some sort of diplomatic &#8212; I mean, it seems like we’ve been in this pattern, the status quo, for a while.&nbsp; The administration is saying that, you know, they’re poised to do something at any time.&nbsp; It’s been a couple weeks.&nbsp; Things haven’t happened.&nbsp; And I guess the question is, sort of &#8212; it seems like by saying you’re not closing the door, that you are leaving some room open for them to still come to the table and do that in a substantive way.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We are.&nbsp; The space has gotten narrower and narrower over time, with the troop buildup and the rejection of some of the specific ideas we put on the table.&nbsp; But we are not ruling it out.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in terms of what Putin said today about being willing to negotiate but needing the West and the U.S. to take seriously all of their demands, obviously the sticking point with NATO on foreclosing Ukraine’s membership in NATO is not somewhere that you’re going to go.&nbsp; Do you think that this can &#8211; that there can be some kind of, you know, point of compromise here?&nbsp; Or are both sides kind of talking past one another?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We continue to be ready to test the proposition.&nbsp; When the Russians first put their ideas forward, we said that some of them were non-starters but others provided a basis for discussion, and we proposed those discussions then and we continue to propose them now.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the SWIFT financial system, Daleep Singh at the briefing did say that that probably will not be part of the initial package of sanctions.&nbsp; Can you maybe explain a little bit why?&nbsp; Why wouldn’t the SWIFT &#8212; yanking them from SWIFT be part of the initial part of the sanctions?&nbsp; Is that something the VP is still talking with folks about?&nbsp; Was it because the Allies just were not quite comfortable with it for various reasons, which are understandable?&nbsp; Or can you just explain that a little?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I won’t go beyond what Daleep said about SWIFT, but I will say that coordinating specific sanctions with the Europeans remains a core part of our approach and remains part of the diplomacy that the Vice President is doing here in Munich.&nbsp;<br><br>We believe we are already quite united and are determined to be as united as possible.&nbsp; And this is something the Vice President has already brought up and will continue to bring up with our key partners in Europe.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, just had a quick last question on Anne, during the briefing in the White House, where she attributed the cyberattack on Ukraine on Russia.&nbsp; I was just wondering if you can give us any details on how the U.S. plan &#8212; or Allies plan to sort of respond to that.&nbsp; Are you planning to retaliate?&nbsp; I mean, how do you take that from here on?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I’ll have to leave that with what Anne had already to say about it, you know, except maybe to say: Obviously, cyber is part of this (inaudible) of things that we’re concerned about.&nbsp; We have heard that and the Vice President has heard it from partners here in Europe.&nbsp; You know that the Baltic states, Estonia in particular, has been the subject of cyberattacks.&nbsp;<br><br>So the only thing I would add is to just underscore that we obviously take that seriously as a part of the things that we’re going to speak about.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it fair to say the speech has been evolving because of all these &#8212; the attacks and everything over the last few days?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; It’s fair to say that we have taken a consistent approach.&nbsp; Obviously, there’s &#8212; it’s a fluid situation and new developments, and you always take those into account when you’re doing a speech.&nbsp; But I think you’ll find that the speech fits squarely into the consistent approach that this administration has been taking for weeks and months now.&nbsp; And it’s just one more part of this important project.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
