<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:16:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility in the Federal Workforce</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/25/executive-order-on-diversity-equity-inclusion-and-accessibility-in-the-federal-workforce/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including sections 1104, 3301, and 3302 of title 5, United&#160;States Code, and in order to strengthen the Federal workforce by promoting diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, it is hereby ordered as follows: Section 1. &#160;Policy.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including sections 1104, 3301, and 3302 of title 5, United&nbsp;States Code, and in order to strengthen the Federal workforce by promoting diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Policy.&nbsp; On my first day in office, I signed Executive Order 13985 (Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government), which established that affirmatively advancing equity, civil rights, racial justice, and equal opportunity is the responsibility of the whole of our Government. &nbsp;To further advance equity within the Federal Government, this order establishes that it is the policy of my Administration to cultivate a workforce that draws from the full diversity of the Nation.</p>



<p>As the Nation&#8217;s largest employer, the Federal Government must be a model for diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, where all employees are treated with dignity and respect. &nbsp;Accordingly, the Federal Government must strengthen its ability to recruit, hire, develop, promote, and retain our Nation&#8217;s talent and remove barriers to equal opportunity. &nbsp;It must also provide resources and opportunities to strengthen and advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility across the Federal Government. &nbsp;The Federal Government should have a&nbsp;workforce that reflects the diversity of the American people. &nbsp;A growing body of evidence demonstrates that diverse, equitable, inclusive, and accessible workplaces yield higher-performing organizations.</p>



<p>Federal merit system principles include that the Federal Government&#8217;s recruitment policies should &#8220;endeavor to achieve a&nbsp;work force from all segments of society&#8221; and that &#8220;[a]ll employees and applicants for employment should receive fair and&nbsp;equitable treatment in all aspects of personnel management&#8221; (5 U.S.C. 2301(b)(1), (2)). &nbsp;As set forth in Executive Order&nbsp;13583 of August 18, 2011 (Establishing a Coordinated Government-Wide Initiative to Promote Diversity and Inclusion in&nbsp;the Federal Workforce), the Presidential Memorandum of October 5, 2016 (Promoting Diversity and Inclusion in the National Security Workforce), Executive Order 13988 of January&nbsp;20, 2021 (Preventing and Combating Discrimination on the&nbsp;Basis of Gender Identity or Sexual Orientation), the National Security Memorandum of February 4, 2021 (Revitalizing America&#8217;s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships), and Executive Order 14020 of March 8, 2021 (Establishment of the White House Gender Policy Council), the Federal Government is at its best when drawing upon all parts of society, our greatest accomplishments are achieved when diverse perspectives are brought to bear to overcome our greatest challenges, and all persons should receive equal treatment under the law.&nbsp; This order reaffirms support for, and builds upon, the procedures established by Executive Orders 13583, 13988, and 14020, the Presidential Memorandum on Promoting Diversity and Inclusion in the National Security Workforce, and the National Security Memorandum on Revitalizing America&#8217;s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships. &nbsp;This order establishes that diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility are priorities for my Administration and benefit the entire Federal Government and the Nation, and establishes additional procedures to advance these priorities across the Federal workforce.</p>



<p>Sec. 2. Definitions. For purposes of this order, in the context of the Federal workforce: &nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The term &#8220;underserved communities&#8221; refers to populations sharing a particular characteristic, as well as geographic communities, who have been systematically denied a full opportunity to participate in aspects of economic, social, and civic life. In the context of the Federal workforce, this term includes individuals who belong to communities of color, such as Black and African American, Hispanic and Latino, Native American, Alaska Native and Indigenous, Asian American, Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander, Middle Eastern, and North African persons. It also includes individuals who belong to communities that face discrimination based on sex, sexual orientation, and gender identity (including lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, gender non-conforming, and non-binary (LGBTQ+) persons); persons who face discrimination based on pregnancy or pregnancy-related conditions; parents; and caregivers. &nbsp;It also includes individuals who belong to communities that face discrimination based on their religion or disability; first-generation professionals or first-generation college students; individuals with limited English proficiency; immigrants; individuals who belong to communities that may face employment barriers based on older age or former incarceration; persons who live in rural areas; veterans and military spouses; and persons otherwise adversely affected by persistent poverty, discrimination, or inequality. Individuals may belong to more than one underserved community and face intersecting barriers.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The term &#8220;diversity&#8221; means the practice of including the many communities, identities, races, ethnicities, backgrounds, abilities, cultures, and beliefs of the American people, including underserved communities.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;The term &#8220;equity&#8221; means the consistent and systematic fair, just, and impartial treatment of all individuals, including individuals who belong to underserved communities that&nbsp;have been denied such treatment.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;The term &#8220;inclusion&#8221; means the recognition, appreciation, and use of the talents and skills of employees of&nbsp;all backgrounds.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;The term &#8220;accessibility&#8221; means the design, construction, development, and maintenance of facilities, information and communication technology, programs, and services so that all people, including people with disabilities, can fully and independently use them.&nbsp; Accessibility includes the provision of accommodations and modifications to ensure equal access to employment and participation in activities for people with disabilities, the reduction or elimination of physical and attitudinal barriers to equitable opportunities, a commitment to ensuring that people with disabilities can independently access every outward-facing and internal activity or electronic space, and the pursuit of best practices such as universal design.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;The term &#8220;agency&#8221; means any authority of the United&nbsp;States that is an &#8220;agency&#8221; under 44 U.S.C. 3502(1), other&nbsp;than one considered to be an independent regulatory agency, as defined in 44 U.S.C. 3502(5).</p>



<p>Sec. 3. &nbsp;Government-Wide Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and&nbsp;Accessibility Initiative and Strategic Plan. &nbsp;The Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) and the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) &#8212; in coordination with the Chair of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) and in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs, the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy (APDP), the Director of the National Economic Council, and the Co-Chairs of the Gender Policy Council &#8212; shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) reestablish a coordinated Government-wide initiative to promote diversity and inclusion in the Federal workforce, expand its scope to specifically include equity and accessibility, and coordinate its implementation with the provisions of Executive Order 13985 and the National Security Memorandum on Revitalizing America&#8217;s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;develop and issue a Government-wide Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility Strategic Plan (Government-wide DEIA Plan) within 150 days of the date of this order that updates the Government-wide plan required by section 2(b)(i) of Executive Order 13583. &nbsp;The Government-wide DEIA Plan shall be updated as appropriate and at a minimum every 4 years. &nbsp;The Government-wide DEIA Plan shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;define standards of success for diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility efforts based on&nbsp;leading policies and practices in the public and private sectors;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;consistent with merit system principles, identify strategies to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, and eliminate, where applicable, barriers to equity, in Federal workforce functions, including: &nbsp;recruitment; hiring; background investigation; promotion; retention; performance evaluations and awards; professional development programs; mentoring programs or sponsorship initiatives; internship, fellowship, and apprenticeship programs; employee resource group and&nbsp;affinity group programs; temporary employee details and assignments; pay and compensation policies; benefits, including health benefits, retirement benefits, and employee services and work‑life programs; disciplinary or adverse actions; reasonable accommodations for employees and applicants with disabilities; workplace policies to prevent gender-based violence (including domestic violence, stalking, and sexual violence); reasonable accommodations for employees who are members of religious minorities; and training, learning, and onboarding programs;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;include a comprehensive framework to address workplace harassment, including sexual harassment, which clearly defines the term &#8220;harassment&#8221;; outlines policies and practices to prevent, report, respond to, and investigate harassment; promotes mechanisms for employees to report misconduct; encourages bystander intervention; and addresses training, education, and monitoring to create a culture that does not tolerate harassment or other forms of discrimination or retaliation; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;promote a data-driven approach to increase transparency and accountability, which would build upon, as appropriate, the EEOC&#8217;s Management Directive 715 reporting process;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;establish an updated system for agencies to report regularly on progress in implementing Agency DEIA Strategic Plans (as described in section 4(b) of this order) and in meeting the objectives of this order. &nbsp;New reporting requirements should be aligned with ongoing reporting established by Executive Order 13985 and the National Security Memorandum on Revitalizing America&#8217;s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships. &nbsp;Agency reports on actions taken to meet the objectives of this order shall include measurement of improvements, analysis of the effectiveness of agency programs, and descriptions of lessons learned. &nbsp;The Director of OPM and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall support agencies in developing workforce policies and practices designed to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility throughout agencies by, for example, providing updated guidance and technical assistance to ensure that agencies consistently improve, evaluate, and learn from their workforce practices;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;pursue opportunities to consolidate implementation efforts and reporting requirements related to advancing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility established through related or overlapping statutory mandates, Presidential directives, and regulatory requirements; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;support, coordinate, and encourage agency efforts to&nbsp;conduct research, evaluation, and other evidence-building activities to identify leading practices, and other promising practices, for broadening participation and opportunities for advancement in Federal employment, and to assess and promote the benefits of diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility for Federal performance and operations and barriers to achieving these goals. &nbsp;Agencies should use the capabilities of their evaluation officers and chief statistical officers and requirements under the Foundations for Evidence-Based Policymaking Act of 2018, Public Law 115-435, to advance this&nbsp;goal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 4. &nbsp;Responsibilities of Executive Departments and Agencies. The head of each agency shall make advancing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility a priority component of the agency&#8217;s management agenda and agency strategic planning. &nbsp;The head of each agency shall implement the Government-wide DEIA Plan prepared pursuant to section 3 of this order and such other related guidance as issued from time to time by the Director of OPM or the Deputy Director for Management of OMB.&nbsp; In addition, the head of each agency shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;within 100 days of the date of this order, submit to&nbsp;the APDP, the Director of OPM, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB a preliminary assessment of the current state of diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in the agency&#8217;s human resources practices and workforce composition. &nbsp;In conducting such assessment, the head of each agency should:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;assess whether agency recruitment, hiring, promotion, retention, professional development, performance evaluations, pay and compensation policies, reasonable accommodations access, and training policies and practices are equitable;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;take an evidence-based and data-driven approach to determine whether and to what extent agency practices result in inequitable employment outcomes, and whether agency actions may help to overcome systemic societal and organizational barriers;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;assess the status and effects of existing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility initiatives or programs, and review the amount of institutional resources available to support human resources activities that advance the objectives outlined in section 1 of this order; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;identify areas where evidence is lacking and propose opportunities to build evidence to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility and address those gaps identified;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;within 120 days of the issuance of the Government-wide DEIA Plan, and annually thereafter, develop and submit to the&nbsp;APDP, the Director of OPM, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB an Agency Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility Strategic Plan (Agency DEIA Strategic Plan), as&nbsp;described by section 3(b) of Executive Order 13583 and as modified by this order. &nbsp;Agency DEIA Strategic Plans should identify actions to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and&nbsp;accessibility in the workforce and remove any potential barriers to diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in&nbsp;the workforce identified in the assessments described in subsection (a) of this section. &nbsp;Agency DEIA Strategic Plans should also include quarterly goals and actions to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility initiatives in the agency workforce and in the agency&#8217;s workplace culture;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;on an annual basis, report to the President on the status of the agency&#8217;s efforts to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility within the agency, and the agency&#8217;s success in implementing the Agency DEIA Strategic Plan. &nbsp;Consistent with guidance issued as part of the Government-wide DEIA Plan, the agency head shall also make available to the general public information on efforts to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in the agency&#8217;s workforce;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;oversee, and provide resources and staffing to support, the implementation of the Agency DEIA Strategic Plan;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;enhance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility within the agency, in collaboration with the agency&#8217;s senior officials and consistent with applicable law and&nbsp;merit system principles;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;seek opportunities to establish a position of chief diversity officer or diversity and inclusion officer (as distinct from an equal employment opportunity officer), with sufficient seniority to coordinate efforts to promote diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility within the agency;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(g) &nbsp;strongly consider for employment, to the extent permitted by applicable law, qualified applicants of any background who have advanced diversity, equity, inclusion, and&nbsp;accessibility in the workplace; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(h) &nbsp;in coordination with OMB, seek opportunities to ensure alignment across various organizational performance planning requirements and efforts by integrating the Agency DEIA Strategic Plan and diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility goals into broader agency strategic planning efforts described in 5 U.S.C. 306 and the agency performance planning described in 31 U.S.C. 1115.</p>



<p>Sec. 5. &nbsp;Data Collection.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall take a data-driven approach to advancing policies that promote diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility within the agency&#8217;s workforce, while protecting the privacy of employees and safeguarding all personally identifiable information and protected health information.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Using Federal standards governing the collection, use, and analysis of demographic data (such as OMB Directive No. 15 (Standards for Maintaining, Collecting, and Presenting Federal Data on Race and Ethnicity) and OMB Memorandum M-14-06 (Guidance for Providing and Using Administrative Data for Statistical Purposes)), the head of each agency shall measure demographic representation and trends related to diversity in the agency&#8217;s overall workforce composition, senior workforce composition, employment applications, hiring decisions, promotions, pay and compensation, professional development programs, and attrition rates.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;The Director of OPM,&nbsp; the Chair of the EEOC, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall review existing guidance, regulations, policies, and practices (for purposes of&nbsp;this section, &#8220;guidance&#8221;) that govern agency collection of demographic data about Federal employees, and consider issuing, modifying, or revoking such guidance in order to expand the collection of such voluntarily self-reported data and more effectively measure the representation of underserved communities in the Federal workforce. &nbsp;In revisiting or issuing any such guidance, the Director of OPM, the Chair of the EEOC, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall take steps to promote the protection of privacy and to safeguard personally identifiable information; facilitate intersectional analysis; and reduce duplicative reporting requirements. &nbsp;In considering whether to revisit or issue such guidance, the Director of OPM, the Chair of the EEOC, and the Deputy Director for Management of&nbsp;OMB shall consult with the Chief Statistician of the United&nbsp;States, the Chair of the Chief Data Officers Council, and&nbsp;the Co-Chairs of the Interagency Working Group on Equitable Data established in section 9 of Executive Order 13985.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall implement any such revised guidance issued pursuant to subsection (c) of this section to expand the collection of voluntarily self-reported demographic data. &nbsp;The head of each agency shall also take steps to ensure that data collection and analysis practices allow for the capture or presence of multiple attributes and identities to ensure an intersectional analysis.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall collect and analyze voluntarily self-reported demographic data regarding the membership of advisory committees, commissions, and boards in a&nbsp;manner consistent with applicable law, including privacy and confidentiality protections, and with statistical standards where applicable. &nbsp;For agencies that have external advisory committees, commissions, or boards to which agencies appoint members, agency heads shall pursue opportunities to increase diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility on such committees, commissions, and boards.</p>



<p>Sec<em>.</em> 6. &nbsp;Promoting Paid Internships.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; The Director of OPM and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall issue guidance to agencies and the Executive Office of the President with respect to internships and similar programs within the Federal Government, including guidance on how to:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;increase the availability of paid internships, fellowships, and apprenticeships, and reduce the practice of hiring interns, fellows, and apprentices who are unpaid;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;ensure that internships, fellowships, and apprenticeships serve as a supplement to, and not a&nbsp;substitute for, the competitive hiring process;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;ensure that internships, fellowships, and apprenticeships serve to develop individuals&#8217; talent, knowledge, and skills for careers in government service;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;improve outreach to and recruitment of individuals from underserved communities for internship, fellowship, and apprenticeship programs;&nbsp;and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ensure all interns, fellows, and apprentices with disabilities, including applicants and candidates, have a process for requesting and obtaining reasonable accommodations to support their work in the Federal Government, without regard to whether such individuals are covered by the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, Public Law 93-112.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall, as part of the annual reporting process described in section 4(c) of this order, measure and report on the agency&#8217;s progress with respect to the&nbsp;matters described in subsection (a) of this section.</p>



<p>Sec. 7. &nbsp;Partnerships and Recruitment. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), the Director of OPM, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB, in consultation with the Chair of the EEOC, shall coordinate a&nbsp;Government-wide initiative to strengthen partnerships (Partnerships Initiative) to facilitate recruitment for Federal employment opportunities of individuals who are members of underserved communities. &nbsp;To carry out the Partnerships Initiative, the Director of OSTP, the Director of OPM, and the&nbsp;Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall take steps to&nbsp;increase diversity in the Federal employment pipeline by supporting and guiding agencies in building or strengthening partnerships with Historically Black Colleges and Universities, including Historically Black Graduate Institutions; Hispanic-Serving Institutions; Tribal Colleges and Universities; Native American-serving, nontribal institutions; Asian American and Pacific Islander-serving institutions; Tribally controlled colleges and universities; Alaska Native-serving and Native Hawaiian-serving institutions; Predominantly Black Institutions; women&#8217;s colleges and universities; State vocational rehabilitation agencies that serve individuals with disabilities; disability services offices at institutions of higher education; organizations dedicated to serving veterans; public and non-profit private universities serving a high percentage of economically disadvantaged students or first-generation college or graduate students; community colleges and technical schools; and community-based organizations that are dedicated to serving and working with underserved communities, including return-to-work programs, programs that provide training and support for older adults seeking employment, programs serving formerly incarcerated individuals, centers for&nbsp;independent living, disability rights organizations, and organizations dedicated to serving LGBTQ+ individuals.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall work with the Director of OSTP, the Director of OPM, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB to make employment, internship, fellowship, and apprenticeship opportunities available through the Partnerships Initiative, and shall take steps to enhance recruitment efforts through the Partnerships Initiative, as part of the agency&#8217;s overall recruitment efforts. &nbsp;The head of each agency shall, as part of the reporting processes described in sections 3(c) and 4(c) of this order, measure and report on the agency&#8217;s progress on carrying out this subsection.</p>



<p>Sec. 8. &nbsp;Professional Development and Advancement. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Director of OPM, in consultation with the Deputy Director for Management of OMB, shall issue detailed guidance to agencies for tracking demographic data relating to participation in leadership and professional development programs and development opportunities offered or sponsored by agencies and the rate of the placement of participating employees into senior positions in agencies, in a manner consistent with privacy and confidentiality protections and statistical limitations.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall implement the guidance issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, and shall use&nbsp;demographic data relating to participation in professional development programs to identify ways to improve outreach and recruitment for professional development programs offered or&nbsp;sponsored by the agency, consistent with merit system principles. &nbsp;The head of each agency shall also address any barriers to access to or participation in such programs faced by&nbsp;members of underserved communities.</p>



<p>Sec. 9. &nbsp;Training and Learning. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The head of each&nbsp;agency shall take steps to implement or increase the availability and use of diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility training programs for employees, managers, and leadership. &nbsp;Such training programs should enable Federal employees, managers, and leaders to have knowledge of systemic and institutional racism and bias against underserved communities, be supported in building skillsets to promote respectful and inclusive workplaces and eliminate workplace harassment, have knowledge of agency accessibility practices, and have increased understanding of implicit and unconscious bias.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The Director of OPM and the Chair of the EEOC shall issue guidance and serve as a resource and repository for best practices for agencies to develop or enhance existing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility training programs.</p>



<p>Sec. 10. &nbsp;Advancing Equity for Employees with Disabilities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; As established in Executive Order 13548 of July 26, 2010 (Increasing Federal Employment of Individuals with Disabilities), the Federal Government must become a model for&nbsp;the employment of individuals with disabilities.&nbsp; Because a&nbsp;workforce that includes people with disabilities is a stronger and more effective workforce, agencies must provide an equitable, accessible, and inclusive environment for employees with disabilities.&nbsp; In order for Federal employees and applicants with disabilities to be assessed on their merits, accessible information technologies must be provided and, where needed, reasonable accommodations must be available that will allow qualified individuals with disabilities to perform the essential functions of their positions and access advancement opportunities. &nbsp;To that end, the relevant agencies shall take the actions set forth in this section.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The Secretary of Labor, the Director of OPM, the Chair of the EEOC, the Deputy Director for Management of OMB, and the Executive Director of the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board (Access Board), in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, as appropriate, shall coordinate with agencies to:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;support the Federal Government&#8217;s effort to provide people with disabilities equal employment opportunities and take affirmative actions within the&nbsp;Federal Government to ensure that agencies fully comply with applicable laws, including sections 501, 504, and 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended (29 U.S.C. 791, 794, 794d);<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;assess current practices in using Schedule A hiring authority to employ people with disabilities in&nbsp;the Federal Government, and evaluate opportunities to enhance equity in employment opportunities and financial security for employees with disabilities through different practices or guidance on the use of Schedule A hiring authority; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;ensure that:<br>(A) &nbsp;applicants and employees with disabilities have access to information about and understand their rights regarding disability self-identification;<br>(B) &nbsp;applicants and employees with disabilities have access to information about Schedule A hiring authority for individuals with disabilities;<br>(C) &nbsp;applicants and employees with disabilities have access to information about, understand their rights to, and may easily request reasonable accommodations, workplace personal assistance services, and accessible information and communication technology;<br>(D) &nbsp;the process of responding to reasonable accommodation requests is timely and efficient;<br>(E) &nbsp;the processes and procedures for appealing the denial of a reasonable accommodation request are timely and efficient; and<br>(F) &nbsp;all information and communication technology and products developed, procured, maintained, or used by Federal agencies are accessible and usable by employees with disabilities consistent with all standards and technical requirements of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;To ensure that all Federal office buildings and workplaces are accessible to employees with disabilities, the Administrator of General Services, the Director of OPM, the Deputy Director for Management of OMB, and the Executive Director of the Access Board shall work with Federal agencies to ensure that Federal buildings and leased facilities comply with the accessibility standards of the Architectural Barriers Act of 1968, Public Law 90-480, and related standards.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;Beyond existing duties to comply with the Architectural Barriers Act of 1968 and related standards, the head of each agency shall maximize the accessibility of the physical environment of the agency&#8217;s workplaces, consistent with applicable law and the availability of appropriations, so as to&nbsp;reduce the need for reasonable accommodations, and provide periodic notice to all employees that complaints concerning accessibility barriers in Federal buildings can be filed with the Access Board.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Labor shall review the use of the Workforce Recruitment Program (WRP) for college students and recent graduates with disabilities and take steps, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to expand the WRP.&nbsp; The Secretaries shall submit a report to the APDP describing any steps taken pursuant to this subsection and providing recommendations for any Presidential, administrative, or congressional actions to further expand and strengthen the program and expand job opportunities.</p>



<p>Sec. 11.&nbsp; Advancing Equity for LGBTQ+ Employees.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;As established in Executive Order 13988, it is the policy of my Administration to prevent and combat discrimination on the basis&nbsp;of gender identity or sexual orientation. &nbsp;Each Federal employee should be able to openly express their sexual orientation, gender identity, and gender expression, and have&nbsp;these identities affirmed and respected, without fear of&nbsp;discrimination, retribution, or disadvantage. &nbsp;To that end,&nbsp;the&nbsp;relevant agencies shall take the actions set forth in&nbsp;this section. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall, in coordination with the Director of OPM, ensure that existing employee support services equitably serve LGBTQ+ employees, including, as appropriate, through the provision of supportive services for transgender and&nbsp;gender non-conforming and non-binary employees who wish to&nbsp;legally, medically, or socially transition.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) To ensure that LGBTQ+ employees (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), as well as LGBTQ+ beneficiaries and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents of all Federal employees, have equitable access to healthcare and health insurance coverage:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the Director of OPM shall take actions to promote equitable healthcare coverage and services for&nbsp;enrolled LGBTQ+ employees (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), LGBTQ+&nbsp;beneficiaries, and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents, including coverage of comprehensive gender-affirming care, through the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;the Secretary of Defense shall take actions to promote equitable healthcare coverage and services for LGBTQ+ members of the uniformed services (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), LGBTQ+ beneficiaries, and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents, including coverage of comprehensive gender-affirming care, through the Military Health System.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;To ensure that LGBTQ+ employees (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), LGBTQ+ beneficiaries, and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents have equitable access to all other insurance coverage and employee benefits, the head of each agency shall, in coordination with the Director of OPM, ensure that the Federal Government equitably provides insurance coverage options and employee benefits for LGBTQ+ employees (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), LGBTQ+ beneficiaries, and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents, including long-term care insurance, sick leave, and life insurance. &nbsp;This includes ensuring that Federal benefits, programs, and services recognize the diversity of family structures.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;To ensure that all Federal employees have their respective gender identities accurately reflected and identified in the workplace:&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the head of each agency shall, in coordination with the Director of OPM, take steps to foster an inclusive environment where all employees&#8217; gender identities are respected, such as by including, where applicable, non-binary gender marker and pronoun options in Federal hiring, employment, and benefits enrollment forms;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall update, as appropriate and in consultation with any other relevant agencies, any relevant Federal employee identification standards to&nbsp;ensure that Federal systems for issuing employee identity credentials account for the needs of transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees. &nbsp;The Secretary, in coordination with any other relevant agencies, shall take steps to reduce any unnecessary administrative burden for transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees to update their names, photographs, gender markers, and pronouns on federally issued employee identity credentials, where applicable; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;the head of each agency shall, in consultation with the Director of OPM, update Federal employee identification standards to include non-binary gender markers where gender markers are required in employee systems and profiles, and shall take steps to reduce any unnecessary administrative burden for transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees to update their gender markers and pronouns in employee systems and profiles, where applicable.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;To support all Federal employees in accessing workplace facilities aligned with their gender identities, the head of each agency shall explore opportunities to expand the availability of gender non-binary facilities and restrooms in federally owned and leased workplaces.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(g) &nbsp;The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Director of OPM and the heads of agencies, shall take steps to mitigate any barriers in security clearance and background investigation processes for LGBTQ+ employees and applicants, in particular transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees and applicants.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(h) The Director of OPM shall review and update, if necessary, OPM&#8217;s 2017 Guidance Regarding the Employment of Transgender Individuals in the Federal Workplace.</p>



<p>Sec. 12. &nbsp;Pay Equity. &nbsp;Many workers continue to face racial and gender pay gaps, and pay inequity disproportionately affects women of color.&nbsp; Accordingly:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Director of OPM shall review Government-wide regulations and guidance and, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, in order to address any pay inequities and advance equal pay, consider whether to:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;work with agencies to review, and revise if necessary, job classification and compensation practices; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;prohibit agencies from seeking or relying on an applicant&#8217;s salary history during the hiring process to set pay or when setting pay for a current employee, unless salary history is raised without prompting by the applicant or employee.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency that administers a pay system other than one established under title 5 of the United States Code shall review the agency&#8217;s regulations and guidance and, as&nbsp;appropriate and consistent with applicable law, revise compensation practices in order to address any pay inequities and advance equal pay. &nbsp;Agencies should report to OPM any revisions to compensation practices made to implement this direction.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;The Director of OPM shall submit a report to the President describing any changes to Government-wide and agency-specific compensation practices recommended and adopted pursuant to this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 13.&nbsp; Expanding Employment Opportunities for Formerly Incarcerated Individuals.&nbsp; To support equal opportunity for formerly incarcerated individuals who have served their terms of incarceration and to support their ability to fully reintegrate into society and make meaningful contributions to our Nation, the Director of OPM shall evaluate the existence of any barriers that formerly incarcerated individuals face in accessing Federal employment opportunities and any effect of those barriers on the&nbsp;civil service.&nbsp; As appropriate, the Director of OPM shall also evaluate possible actions to expand Federal employment opportunities for formerly incarcerated individuals, including the establishment of a new hiring authority, and shall submit a&nbsp;report to the President containing the results of OPM&#8217;s evaluation within 120 days of the date of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 14.&nbsp; Delegation of Authority.&nbsp; The Director of OPM is hereby delegated the authority of the President under sections 3301 and 3302 of title 5, United States Code, for purposes of carrying out the Director&#8217;s responsibilities under this order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 15. &nbsp;General Provisions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;Independent agencies are strongly encouraged to comply with the provisions of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                             JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.  </p>



<p><br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>    June 25, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President Biden Signs Executive Order Advancing Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility in the Federal Government</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-advancing-diversity-equity-inclusion-and-accessibility-in-the-federal-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility (DEIA) in the Federal workforce. This Executive Order reaffirms that the United States is at its strongest when our Nation’s public servants reflect the full diversity of the American people. Even with decades of progress building a Federal workforce that looks&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility (DEIA) in the Federal workforce. This Executive Order reaffirms that the United States is at its strongest when our Nation’s public servants reflect the full diversity of the American people.</p>



<p>Even with decades of progress building a Federal workforce that looks like America, the enduring legacies of employment discrimination, systemic racism, and gender inequality are still felt today. Too many underserved communities remain under-represented in the Federal workforce, especially in positions of leadership. This Executive Order establishes an ambitious, whole-of-government initiative that will take a systematic approach to embedding DEIA in Federal hiring and employment practices.</p>



<p>When public servants reflect the communities they serve, the government is more effective and successful. That is why the Biden-Harris Administration has appointed <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/29/fact-sheet-100-days-in-biden-harris-administration-makes-history-with-presidential-appointees/">an historic number of&nbsp; diverse leaders</a>. Today’s Executive Order will help develop a Federal workforce that looks like America where qualified people from every background and walk of life have an equal opportunity to serve our Nation.</p>



<p>The Executive Order:</p>



<p><strong>Establishes a government-wide initiative to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in all parts of the Federal workforce. </strong>This initiative will be led by the Office of Personnel Management and the Office of Management and Budget, in close partnership with the White House and the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. The initiative will reinvigorate the whole-of-government approach to DEIA first established in the Obama-Biden Administration. The initiative will advance opportunity for communities that have historically faced employment discrimination and professional barriers, including: people of color; women; first-generation professionals and immigrants; individuals with disabilities; LGBTQ+ individuals; Americans who live in rural areas; older Americans who face age discrimination when seeking employment; parents and caregivers who face employment barriers; people of faith who require religious accommodations at work; individuals who were formerly incarcerated; and veterans and military spouses.</p>



<p><strong>Charges all agencies with assessing the current state of diversity, equity, inclusion and accessibility within their workforces, and developing strategic plans to eliminate any barriers to success faced by underserved employees. </strong>The Order charges all Federal agencies with reviewing within 100 days whether employees who are members of underserved communities face barriers to employment, promotion, or professional development within their workforce.</p>



<p><strong>Directs agencies to seek opportunities to establish or elevate Chief Diversity Officers within their organizations. </strong>To help ensure the coordination of DEIA initiatives across the Federal government, the Executive Order directs all agencies to look for opportunities to establish senior leaders to promote diversity and inclusion within the workforce.</p>



<p><strong>Expands diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility training throughout the Federal workforce. </strong>On his first day in office, President Biden rescinded a ban that prevented Federal employees from participating in diversity and sensitivity trainings. Today’s Executive Order builds on that by directing all Federal agencies to expand the availability of DEIA trainings for their workforce, so that Federal employees are supported in building skillsets to promote respectful and inclusive workplaces and have increased understanding of implicit and unconscious bias. These types of trainings equip public servants to best serve the American public, and the many diverse communities that make American strong.</p>



<p><strong>Addresses workplace harassment, including sexual harassment.</strong>&nbsp; Requires a government-wide, comprehensive plan to address workplace harassment, including sexual harassment.&nbsp; The plan will outline policies and practices to prevent report, respond to, and investigate harassment, and address training, education, and monitoring to create a culture that does not tolerate harassment or other forms of discrimination.</p>



<p><strong>Reduces the Federal government’s reliance on unpaid internships, which can create barriers for low-income students and first-generation professionals. </strong>The Federal government must be an engine of opportunity for Americans from every walk of life to serve our Nation through public service. But too often, unpaid Federal internships prevent hardworking and talented students and professionals from participating in Federal career advancement opportunities. The Executive Order directs key agencies to take steps to reduce the reliance on unpaid internships, fellowships, and apprenticeships to ensure that more Americans can take advantage of these opportunities.</p>



<p><strong>Advances pay equity to ensure that all public servants are fairly compensated for their work and their talents. </strong>Many workers continue to face racial and gender pay gaps, and pay inequity disproportionately affects women of color.&nbsp; The Order directs the Office of Personnel Management to review Government-wide regulations and guidance that set pay and wage standards for public servants. It also directs the Office of Personnel Management to consider taking steps to prohibit agencies from seeking or relying on an applicant&#8217;s salary history during the hiring process and compensation decisions, an important component of advancing pay equity.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Advances equity in the workplace for individuals with disabilities. </strong>The Federal government is stronger and more successful when individuals with disabilities have equal opportunities to lead at every level. In spite of decades of progress in removing barriers to employment for employees with disabilities, people with disabilities remain under-represented throughout the Federal government, and particularly in positions of leadership. The Executive Order directs the government to become a model employer for individuals with disabilities. It charges key agencies, including the Department of Labor and the U.S. Access Board, to coordinate across the Federal government to ensure that all Federal workplaces and technologies are fully accessible; improve the process for requesting reasonable accommodations; and ensure that all Federal employees understand their rights to request reasonable accommodations. The Executive Order also directs a review of Schedule A Hiring Authority for individuals with disabilities to assess opportunities to enhance employment opportunities and financial security for employees with disabilities. And the Executive Order directs the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Labor to take steps to expand the use of the Workforce Recruitment Program for college students and recent graduates with disabilities.</p>



<p><strong>Advances equity in the workplace for LGBTQ+ public servants. </strong>For too long, LGBTQ+ employees have faced discrimination and harassment in the workplace. To advance opportunity for LGBTQ+ employees in the Federal workforce, the Executive Order directs agencies to ensure that the Federal health benefits system equitably serves LGBTQ+ employees and their dependents by expanding access to comprehensive gender-affirming health care. Agencies are also directed to take steps to ensure that federal benefits like sick leave and life insurance equitably serve LGBTQ+ individuals and all families with diverse family structures.&nbsp; The Order charges all agencies to ensure that the usage of gender markers and pronouns in the Federal employment process respects transgender, gender non-conforming and non-binary employees, and directs all agencies to take steps to expand access to gender-neutral facilities inside federal workplaces. Finally, the Order charges all agencies with ensuring that their employee support services equitably serve LGBTQ+ employees, including, transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees who wish to legally, medically, or socially transition.</p>



<p><strong>Builds a more diverse pipeline into public service through new recruitment partnerships. </strong>Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Hispanic Serving Institutions, Tribal Colleges and Universities, Minority Serving Institutions, and women’s colleges are engines of opportunity and innovation in our Nation. The Executive Order charges agencies with developing new recruitment partnerships to ensure that the Federal government can recruit our Nation’s best talent.</p>



<p><strong>Expands Federal employment opportunities for formerly incarcerated individuals. </strong>Individuals with prior convictions experience must be supported in accessing employment as they fully re-enter society. The Federal government has an important role to play in supporting formerly incarcerated individuals in fully reintegrating into society and making meaningful contributions to our country. The Executive Order directs the Office of Personnel Management to assess the barriers that formerly incarcerated individuals face when seeking Federal jobs.&nbsp; The Executive Order also tasks the Office of Personnel Management with considering creating new Hiring Authorities to expand job opportunities for individuals with past convictions.</p>



<p><strong>Advances equity in professional development. </strong>The Executive Order directs agencies to improve the collection of demographic data about which employees are able to access professional development and advancement opportunities to ensure that these programs equitably serve all Federal public servants.</p>



<p><strong>Improves the collection of demographic data about the Federal workforce. </strong>The Executive Order charges key agencies with reviewing and improving guidance on the collection of demographic data about Federal employees. With improved data on the Federal government’s workforce composition, agencies will be better able to take an evidence-informed approach to reducing inequitable barriers in hiring, promotion, professional development, and retention practices.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in Bill Signing of H.R. 49 to Designate the National Pulse Memorial into Law</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/25/remarks-by-president-biden-in-bill-signing-of-h-r-49-to-designate-the-national-pulse-memorial-into-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium  1:57 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m Joe Biden.  I&#8217;m Jill&#8217;s husband.  (Laughter.)  Before I sign, let me start with a few words about what&#8217;s going on now in &#8212; in Florida.  And, you know, the people who are here, who were part of what happened that night at the Pulse nightclub and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium </p>



<p><br>1:57 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m Joe Biden.  I&#8217;m Jill&#8217;s husband.  (Laughter.) <br><br>Before I sign, let me start with a few words about what&#8217;s going on now in &#8212; in Florida.  And, you know, the people who are here, who were part of what happened that night at the Pulse nightclub and the scores that I just spoke to a moment ago &#8212; they&#8217;re online looking at this &#8212; they understand that &#8212; what it&#8217;s like to have to wait and wonder what happened. <br><br>The families &#8212; I remember going down there to the Pulse nightclub afterwards and &#8212; and wondering: &#8220;Is it my son, my daughter, my husband, someone I love &#8212; is that who got lost?&#8221;  Because you didn&#8217;t know for certain initially. <br><br>And as &#8212; as Congressman Cicilline knows, there&#8217;s nothing worse than having to wait and wonder what happened.  And I know, Val, when you were a police chief, you had to go through waiting a lot as well. <br><br>And so, I just want to say, I&#8217;ve spoken to Governor DeSantis.  And we&#8217;ve provided all the help that they have &#8212; they need.  We sent the best people from FEMA down there.  We&#8217;re going to stay with them; with the disaster declaration we made, provide for everything from housing to, God forbid, whether there&#8217;s a need for moratoria- &#8212; if there are &#8212; to &#8212; for the bodies to be placed.  Everything in between. <br><br>And &#8212; but I just &#8212; I just want to say &#8212; and I&#8217;m sure I speak for all the members of the Congress here today and all the survivors here that &#8212; that it&#8217;s a tough, tough time.  There&#8217;s so many people waiting.  &#8220;Are they alive?  Will they be &#8212; what will happen?&#8221;  And so, our heart goes out to them. <br><br>And I &#8212; to the people of Florida, I want to &#8212; I&#8217;ve spoken to Debbie Wasserman Schultz.  I&#8217;ve spoken to most of the folks down there and member &#8212; in authority.  And I promise you, the administration, the Congress &#8212; we&#8217;re doing everything possible to be of assistance now and after this occurs &#8212; after they decide exactly what the state of play is.<br><br>But I&#8217;m glad to welcome everyone here to the adjunct to the White House here, and in person and virtually: survivors and family members, victims, and the path-breaking leaders like Senator Baldwin. <br><br>Just over five years ago, the Pulse nightclub, a place of acceptance and joy, became a place of unspeakable pain and loss.  And we&#8217;ll never fully recovery, but we&#8217;ll remember.  And we have to &#8212; what we&#8217;re going to do is what the members of Congress here did, and enshrine in law &#8212; as a consequence of that law, enshrine, in perpetuity, literally a monument to the loss that occurred there, and an absolute determination that we&#8217;re going to deal with this every single, solitary day and make sure that we&#8217;re not in a position to see this happen again. <br><br>Behind me, you see, on either board there, the 49 lives lost: family members, parents, friends, veterans, students, young, Black, Asian, Latino &#8212; all fellow Americans.  And in their memory and for the countless others forever scarred is why I sign this today. <br><br>And let me say how much I appreciate it &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; the &#8212; the commitment of the members of the House and Senate to make sure that we don&#8217;t forget &#8212; that this isn&#8217;t forgotten. <br><br>Now, there&#8217;s a tradition when a bill is signed that the President gives a signing pen to each of the people who had something to do with the law or the decision being made in the first place. <br><br>I promise you, I have all the pens, but they&#8217;re in the other room.  I couldn&#8217;t figure how to sign &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; sign them all.  But don&#8217;t leave without the pen.  Okay?  All right?  All right. <br><br>REPRESENTATIVE TAKANO:  Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>REPRESENTATIVE SOTO:  Thank you, Mr. President.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (The bill is signed.) <br><br>May we never have to sign another &#8212; no President ever have to sign another monument like this.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you. <br><br>And one last thing, as I said to &#8212; to the survivors and their &#8212; those who lost folks, a little earlier, in private: You know, what the Congress has done means a great deal, and it&#8217;s important.  But it&#8217;s really hard; it brings back everything as if it happened yesterday. <br><br>And every time there&#8217;s a memorial service for our son, Beau, you know, you&#8217;re flattered.  You feel good about it.  You think it&#8217;s wonderful &#8212; the recognition.  But it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s tough.  It&#8217;s as if it happened yesterday, it happened the day before, it happened the moment you&#8217;re signing it. <br><br>So, I want to thank the folks who are here and the folks who are survivors who are on Zoom with us.  I want to thank them for their courage &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; for their courage. <br><br>But, I promise you, none of the members of Congress that are here, nor I, nor Jill are going to let up until we deal with equity across the board. <br><br>Thank you so very much.  (Applause.)<br><br>PARTICIPANT:  Thank you, Mr. President.  It means so much to us. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And you&#8217;ve got to come back and get your pens.  (Laughter.) <br><br>2:03 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, June 25, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/25/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-june-25-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:52 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi everyone.&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Hello, Jen.&#160; Good to see you.&#160;&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Good to see you.&#160; Happy Pride.&#160; Celebrating here today.&#160;Okay.&#160; I&#8217;m just going to give you a quick overview of the week ahead: On Monday, the President will welcome Israeli President Rivlin to the White House.&#160; President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:52 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, Jen.&nbsp; Good to see you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Good to see you.&nbsp; Happy Pride.&nbsp; Celebrating here today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to give you a quick overview of the week ahead: On Monday, the President will welcome Israeli President Rivlin to the White House.&nbsp; President Rivlin’s visit will highlight the enduring partnership between the United States and Israel and the deep ties between our governments and our people.&nbsp; As President Rivlin approaches the end of his term, the visit will honor the dedication he has shown to strengthening the friendship between the two countries over the course of many years.<br>&nbsp;<br>On Tuesday, the President will travel to Southwest Wisconsin with Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack to talk about growing agriculture &#8212; growing agriculture and rural economies.<br>&nbsp;<br>On Wednesday, he will convene Cabinet officials, governors from western states, and private sector partners to discuss the devastating intersection of drought, heat, and wildfires in the Western United States, and strengthening prevention, preparedness, and response efforts for this wildfire season, which is already outpacing last season alone &#8212; outpacing last season alone &#8212; sorry &#8212; the 2020 wildfire season alone burned over 10 million acres across the United States, resulting in the loss of dozens of lives and tens of billions of dollars in economic damage.&nbsp; This meeting will focus on how the federal government can most effectively protect public safety and deliver assistance to our people in times of urgent need.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, on Friday, the President will also deliver remarks on the June jobs report.<br>&nbsp;<br>Next week, even while all of this is going on &#8212; a busy week &#8212; the President will also continue to work and engage closely with members of Congress about moving his agenda forward, whether it&#8217;s the bipartisan infrastructure agreement just announced yesterday or the budget reconciliation process that&#8217;s also moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he will continue to &#8212; on his work to protect the sacred right to vote.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll hear from him next week on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re still finalizing the details, and he&#8217;s been engaged in that work through his career, so you&#8217;ll hear more from him on that next week.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note, so I don&#8217;t forget: Today is Jerome&#8217;s last day in the White House Briefing Room as a White House correspondent.&nbsp; So thank you &#8212; to your service to the public over the last several years.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>All right.&nbsp;&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we kick it off, Darlene.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Is the infrastructure agreement already stuck in a pothole?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You worked hard on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I didn&#8217;t.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I like it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Absolutely not, in our view.&nbsp; The President is continuing to, as I said &#8212; as he said yesterday, there&#8217;s work ahead.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>But yesterday was a significant moment when you saw Democrats and Republicans and the President of the United States stand outside together and say, &#8220;We&#8217;ve come to agreement to pa- &#8212; to work for &#8212; toward passing a historic investment in infrastructure, one that would have…&#8221; &#8212; I just have this handy chart up here; I thought someone might ask about this &#8212; &#8220;…would have key components that would help communities across the country.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I talked with him about this, this morning: what he was most excited about, what he&#8217;s going to continue, what his message is going to be as he continues to advocate for this bill moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>One is the significant economic impact.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to help create millions of good-paying union jobs that will also have a huge impact on low-income communities, on communities of color.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It will eliminate lead pipes to stop kids from drinking poisoned water.&nbsp; Flint, Michigan, should not be so far away that we don&#8217;t remember the impact on that community.&nbsp; This is a &#8212; part of this package will help prevent that from ever happening again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It includes the single-largest investment in environmental remediation in history.&nbsp; What does that mean?&nbsp; A lot of people at home don&#8217;t know what that means, so I&#8217;m going to explain it.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s 100 percent of what he asked for.&nbsp; It means cleaning up pollution in communities that have disproportionately borne the brunt of environmental pollution.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a capping &#8212; it also means capping wells where big oil companies left wells uncapped with methane pouring out.&nbsp; It means putting people back to work to do the work we need to do to help create a clean energy economy for the long term.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it has the largest investment in public transit in our nation&#8217;s history.&nbsp; We know this will also have an enormous impact on low-income communities &#8212; many communities of color.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll also note: There are huge components of this package that will help address the climate crisis.&nbsp; One is the first-ever &#8212; first-ever network &#8212; first time we&#8217;ve ever invested &#8211;sorry &#8212; in a network of EV charging stations across the country.&nbsp; So electric vehicles &#8212; I don&#8217;t currently own one; maybe I will in the future.&nbsp; Who knows.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It will make it easier &#8212; there will be more charging stations so people can use them across the country.&nbsp; It will have the largest investment in history in a clean energy transmission grid &#8212; something that will also help us take a huge step forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this bill also will help us &#8212; and this the piece he talked about yesterday, but he is particularly excited about &#8212; make us more competitive in the world.&nbsp; And a specific example there is making sure we are building our battery industry here in the United States to compete globally.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that&#8217;s the case he&#8217;s making, he&#8217;s going to continue to make.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question there&#8217;s work ahead, and he&#8217;s ready to roll up his sleeves and work like hell to get it done.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we&#8217;re hearing from the Hill, from a lot of senators, that &#8212; unhappiness over the President&#8217;s decision to want to do both these packages at the same time &#8212; the pairing, moving them in tandem.&nbsp; When senators agreed to this deal, was the White House upfront with them that this was the way the President wanted to proceed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, you all have heard the President say multiple times, publicly, that he wanted to &#8212; he was going to move these bills forward &#8212; wanted to move them forward in parallel paths.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That hasn&#8217;t been a secret.&nbsp; He hasn&#8217;t said it quietly.&nbsp; He hasn&#8217;t even whispered it.&nbsp; He said it very much out loud to all of you, as we have said many times from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say that the President&#8217;s view is that the public &#8212; the American people &#8212; elected him to not lead on process, but to get things done.&nbsp; The House and Senate are going to determine &#8211; the Leaders in the House and Senate are going to determine the sequencing, the timeline.&nbsp; And he looks forward to signing both pieces of legislation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other quick one.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the plan for what &#8212; will we get a statement from the President after the &#8212;&nbsp; Derek Chauvin is sentenced?&nbsp; Do you expect the President will call George Floyd&#8217;s family &#8212; be in touch with them after the sentence is announced?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question, Darlene.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any anticipat- &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you.&nbsp; I guess I should say, at this point, we&#8217;ll wait for the sentencing to come out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, he has a close personal connection with the Floyd family, and certainly I know they and we are all watching this closely.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Does the President have any plans to visit Surfside to see the devastation for himself?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, that any decision along those lines would be done in coordination and cooperation with local authorities.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know &#8212; and you all have been covering this closely &#8212; right now, we&#8217;re in a rescue-and-recovery phase of this, and there have been frequent updates from local authorities on the ground.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I don&#8217;t have any trip to preview or predict for you at this point in time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How did the Vice President choose El Paso as the location for her first trip to the border as Vice President?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I was &#8212; I was interested in that as well, so we looked into it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say that El Paso has an interesting history, as you may know, because it was the place where the former President, kind of &#8212; it was a base place of where he put in place some of his immigration policies that we felt were so problematic.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a place that has a little bit of historical connection in that regard, and it&#8217;s an opportunity to draw a bit of a contrast with what we&#8217;re trying to accomplish.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, can you give us any details about the three staffers in the Vice President&#8217;s office who are leaving?&nbsp; And what should we take from the fact that you have several key staffers who are leaving this early in the administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have any more details on the circumstances of their departure.&nbsp; As you may know, these are sometimes high &#8212; high-stress jobs, tiring jobs, exhausting jobs.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have anything more specific on their decisions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on Surfside, if I can, very quickly: Obviously, no details about whether he plans to travel there.&nbsp; Has the President now spoken to Florida Governor Ron DeSantis about the circumstances there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re working to set up a call between the President and the governor.&nbsp; That should be happening this afternoon, and we&#8217;ll give you all a readout of that when it happens.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ll wait for that readout when it happens.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President, yesterday, spoke about voting rights and what he would be doing.&nbsp; He said, &#8220;I&#8217;ll be going around the country, making the case.&#8221;&nbsp; So he announced it.&nbsp; What specifically is he doing?&nbsp; Where is he going?&nbsp; And what is that going to look like?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Stay tuned.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any specific visits to announce for you yet, but this is going to be a fight of his presidency.&nbsp; He believes that voting is a fundamental right for the American people.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to use every lever at his disposal to &#8212; to advocate for that.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll hear more from him next week as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The DOJ announcement today &#8212; that they would be filing this lawsuit against Georgia given what&#8217;s going on with their election law there &#8212; did the White House play a role in that?&nbsp; Did the President consult anybody?&nbsp; Does he have any thought on it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We did not.&nbsp; That was a &#8212; that was an announcement they made on their own.&nbsp; But it certainly is consistent with the President&#8217;s commitment to the administration and the guidance he&#8217;s given, publicly and directly, to use every lever at our disposal to ensure we are protecting the fundamental right to vote across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, on the timing of when the President is going to get out and advocate for voting rights &#8212; I mean, how soon can we see this?&nbsp; We&#8217;re hearing everyone from the Department of Justice to activists saying that this is really urgent issue.&nbsp; So how soon can we expect this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President is going to speak to all of you and to the public next week about his continuing commitment to voting rights, expanding access to voting rights &#8212; something that he&#8217;s worked on for decades, through his public career.&nbsp; And I expect he&#8217;ll have more to say then.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then you could just follow up and maybe clarify: When the President is talking about doing these two pieces of legislation in tandem, is he going to wait for both of them to land on his desk?&nbsp; What &#8212; what exactly is the timeline here?&nbsp; How does this play out?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, he believes the American people elected him to lead on getting results to put out bold ideas to the public.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what he&#8217;s done.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re going to leave it to leaders in Congress to determine the sequencing and the timeline for those pieces moving forward.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s going to use every lever at his disposal, he&#8217;s going to be involved, he&#8217;s going to roll up his sleeves, he&#8217;s going to work like hell to get these &#8212; both of these pieces of legislation done.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what does that really look like?&nbsp; Because he says that if one doesn&#8217;t come to him, he&#8217;s not going to sign the other.&nbsp; So is he going to wait for both of them to land on his desk before signing the bipartisan package, waiting for the reconciliation package to come through?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He fully expects, hopes, plans to sign both into law.&nbsp; And he will leave it to leaders in Congress to determine the timeline and the sequencing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on both on that and Darlene&#8217;s question.&nbsp; The issue Republicans seem to be having is on that specific issue: &#8220;I won&#8217;t sign it if the other one isn&#8217;t on my desk.&#8221;&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s what has them &#8212; &#8220;frazzled,&#8221; perhaps, would be the word right now &#8212; an eloquent one.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, digging in on that, if leadership decides to send you the bipartisan bill, but the reconciliation bill is not done yet, the President said yesterday, &#8220;I won&#8217;t sign it.&#8221;&nbsp; And that is the White House position on it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just take a step back here, because I think the American people are quite focused on how we&#8217;re getting work done on their behalf &#8212; less focused on the mechanics of the process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, it is up to Republicans &#8212; many of whom are the ones who have conveyed that, I think &#8212; if I&#8217;m accurate here &#8212; to decide if they are going to vote against a historic investment in infrastructure that&#8217;s going to rebuild roads and railways and bridges in their communities simply because they don&#8217;t like the mechanics of the process.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a pretty absurd argument for them to make.&nbsp; Good luck on the political front on that argument.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the President is going to continue to advocate, educate, convey to everyone directly why this needs to move forward.&nbsp; And he stands &#8212; he plans to stand exactly by the commitment he made yesterday to them, and he expects they&#8217;ll do the same.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just two more quick ones.&nbsp; You guys just released a readout with a call with Senator Sinema, who was one of the lead negotiators.&nbsp; In that readout, the President was reiterating pretty much all of the things he said when he was standing with the senators.&nbsp; Was there a need for the President to reassure Senator Sinema or was that just a normal scheduled call?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s just a reflection of the President&#8217;s commitment to stay very engaged.&nbsp; Yesterday was not the end.&nbsp; I know none of you thought that, but just to be clear: There is work ahead.&nbsp; Senator Sinema is a &#8212; was an important leader and partner on this effort to get this bipartisan bill passed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also reiterated, in that call, his desire and his commitment and interest in getting a reconciliation bill passed.&nbsp; That has a lot of his key priorities, whether it&#8217;s extending the Child Tax Credit, making universal pre-K a reality, or community college a reality for kids across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s ongoing engagement.&nbsp; He&#8217;s looking forward to signing both bills into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I just follow up on the &#8212; can I follow up &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are Republicans expected to be so enamored with the idea of sending perhaps billions of dollars into the hinterland that they&#8217;re going to be willing &#8212; you need five more Republicans, obviously &#8212; that they&#8217;re going to be willing to accept this two-track approach and, sort of, look the other way when the express train comes through on the reconciliation idea?<br>&nbsp;<br>Are they &#8212; you &#8212; you&#8217;re sounding as though you expect at least five more Republicans to be so enamored with the idea of sending out these billions of dollars to their &#8212; the constituencies, if you will.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s exactly what they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; This bill would, again, be a historic investment on our nation&#8217;s infrastructure: the largest investment in public transit in history, the largest in &#8212; since the founding of Amtrak.&nbsp; And as I&#8217;ve noted, it would expand broadband access.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not exactly a partisan issue.&nbsp; It would rebuild roads and railways and bridges in people&#8217;s communities, including Republicans.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, yes, we fully expect the American people to support this.&nbsp; We fully expect and hope we&#8217;ll have the votes to get it forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At least five?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; At least five.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, five stood &#8212; stood there yesterday and announced their support for it.&nbsp; And it is now the job of the Democratic Caucus and the Republican Caucus to vo- &#8212; go back and make the case to their &#8212; their other colleagues.&nbsp; Exactly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; House Budget Committee Chairman John Yarmuth said he doesn&#8217;t think it&#8217;s realistic to fully pay for this broader reconciliation package that contains some of the President&#8217;s other domestic priorities that you just laid out.<br>&nbsp;<br>Senator Manchin also said he doesn&#8217;t think the country can take on that much more debt.&nbsp; So does the White House still believe that both the infrastructure compromise and this other reconciliation package need to be fully paid for?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President had proposed a number of ways to pay for these packages.&nbsp; Obviously, there was agreement already on the payfors for the infrastructure bipartisan deal, which was agreed to by the five Democrats and the five Republicans who stood outside with the President just yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President also believes that raising the corporate rate back to where it was the first year of the George W. Bush administration; making &#8212; asking individuals, the top 1 percent of Americans to pay more &#8212; to pay for these historic investments, to pay for an extension of the Child Tax Credit, to make sure kids have access to universal pre-K &#8212; is something that we should do because it&#8217;s right &#8212; the right policy.&nbsp; It will also &#8212; it&#8217;s also going to help move our country forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one quick question on Afghanistan.&nbsp; Can the President declare a true end to the war if the U.S. is planning to keep 650 troops in the country to provide diplomatic security as well as several hundred additional troops to maintain security at the Kabul airport?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, again, I would say: The President was clear from the beginning that we anticipated and planned to have a diplomatic presence on the ground. &nbsp;And so he&#8217;s doing exactly that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow up on that, Jen?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Afghanistan &#8212; and then I have a follow-up on something else.&nbsp; But on Afghanistan: If we&#8217;re keeping people there, what&#8217;s the contingency if in fact the Taliban takes over the country?&nbsp; Do you have a contingency &#8212; does the administration have a contingency for that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what regard?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, what will you do?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; For the safety of our &#8212; of our men and women serving &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I understand the safety, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; in Kabul, or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand the safety of our people, but what about the safety of the country?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been there for X amount of years.&nbsp; Are we going to reinvest more people if that&#8217;s the case?&nbsp; Will there be boots on the ground?&nbsp; What exactly are &#8212; is this administration looking at if that country falls to the Taliban?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s, I think, what&#8217;s important to note, Brian: When the President made this announcement, he was very clear that if we did not pull our troops &#8212; withdraw our troops from &#8212; from Afghanistan &#8212; something that he has long talked about having an interest and a desire to do &#8212; the Taliban would have been shooting at U.S. troops again on May 1st.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a decision he had to make as President.&nbsp; So the withdrawal deadline negotiated &#8212; because of the withdrawal deadline negotiated, I should say, by the prior administration.&nbsp; So his fundamental belief is that after 20 years, it&#8217;s time to bring our troops home.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re doing that in a timely and orderly fashion, led by the Department of Defense.&nbsp; And we had to make sure we were taking steps &#8212; if we had left our troops there, they would be in harm&#8217;s way.&nbsp; That was a step we had to take.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, if the Taliban takes over, what would we do?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we have &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of or anticipate.&nbsp; We are &#8212; we have a range of capacities, including over-the-horizon capacities and capabilities that we will maintain in place.&nbsp; The President announced that at the beginning of his announcement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a follow-up &#8212; another quick follow-up.&nbsp; The other question is: Is this administration prepared for &#8212; we&#8217;ve heard rumblings from the former President and his supporters about August and the inevitability of him being reinstated.&nbsp; Is this administration prepared to meet the challenge if, in fact, they press that issue in August?&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;ve already seen an insurrection.&nbsp; What would this administration&#8217;s actions be &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; if that &#8212; if that is pressed in August?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is going &#8212; is prepared to continue to govern and lead the United States of America.&nbsp; And, of course, should there be an elevation, an escalation, you know, that is something we would certainly monitor and track as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jacqui.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;On reconciliation: Before the President made this statement yesterday, had there been any understanding between the President and the GOP senators who were negotiating that these two deals would come in tandem? &nbsp;Had the Republican senators expressed an understanding to the President that that would happen?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Jacqui, I think the point I was trying to make earlier is that it&#8217;s something the President stated publicly many times.&nbsp; And certainly, he was consistent with that case, made privately, as were our negotiating team &#8212; that he expected, anticipated these &#8212; these initiatives would move forward on a dual track.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would also note that when we say &#8220;budget reconciliation&#8221; &#8212; just to make it like in “human speak” &#8212; what we&#8217;re talking about here is a budget process that includes the American Families Plan, which is the President&#8217;s idea he proposed.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think anyone expects that he was going to walk away from his own proposals.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the Republicans had expressed an understanding &#8212; a level of understanding that that would happen?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to let &#8212; I&#8217;ll let them speak for themselves.&nbsp; But, again, the President said this, as we did, multiple times publicly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on reconciliation &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are the red lines and the must haves?&nbsp; And is the same team working with Congress &#8212; Ricchetti, Terrell, Deese &#8212; about the next steps in the reconciliation package?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, earlier this week &#8212; today&#8217;s Friday; I think it was Wednesday &#8212; we did have a number of those individuals you mentioned, as well as Susan Rice was a part of the team, and there may have been one or two other people, who went up to the Hill to talk about the budget reconciliation process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re obviously at the early stages of that.&nbsp; There&#8217;s lots to discuss and negotiate, including among Democrats.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll let that proceed in the coming weeks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then with the DOJ suing Georgia: Is this the beginning of more lawsuits against similar efforts in other states?&nbsp; Has the White House expressed any concern areas as they take on voting rights and initiatives like that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let the &#8212; the Attorney General and the Department of Justice speak to that and what their plans are.&nbsp; They probably won&#8217;t preview them, I would expect.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think it&#8217;s just a reflection of the fact that the President has conveyed his priority is using every lever at his disposal to protect the fundamental right of people in this country to vote.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, what&#8217;s your timeline for these two pieces of legislation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a new timeline to predict for you here, Steve.&nbsp; Again, we &#8212; Speaker Pelosi has been doing this a while; I don&#8217;t know that there&#8217;s anyone better.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to work with her, Leader Schumer, and others to make sure we get these bills signed into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Afghanistan meeting, is the President going to talk about a negotiated political settlement?&nbsp; Is that still possible in Afghanistan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There &#8212; a political path forward is certainly one that we continue to support.&nbsp; We have a negotiator, as you well know, who, you know, is a &#8212; is monitoring and closely engaged in that process.&nbsp; And so that is certainly ongoing and will be a part of the agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thank you.&nbsp; On Afghanistan, in terms of SIV applicants &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the President said yesterday, this would be a topic in the meeting today.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you provide clarity on what neutral locations these applicants will be moved towards?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then also, will that withdrawal include those who have already fled Afghanistan, because of a fear of retaliation, to places like Jordan or Egypt?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, so let me give you information on where we are.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s unfortunately not going to answer every single question.&nbsp; Some of this we&#8217;re not going to be able to outline for security reasons.&nbsp; But we have identified a group of SIV applicants &#8212; Special Immigrant Visa applicants &#8212; who have served as interpreters and translators, as well as other at-risk categories, who have assisted us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They will be relocated to a location outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown, by September, in order to complete the visa application process.&nbsp; So they will do it from another location.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The additional details of that I&#8217;m just not going to be able to speak to from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did you say a number though on &#8212; on how &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a number to outline for you.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s unlikely we will, because we are going to &#8212; those are the categories that we are prioritizing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that these are individuals who are already in the SIV pipeline, and so we&#8217;d under &#8212; under &#8212; and of course we&#8217;d under &#8212; undertake any relocation in full compliance with U.S. law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one &#8212; just a follow-up.&nbsp; I know I&#8217;ve asked about this a good amount, but for my colleagues as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We reported yesterday that the administration would lift Title 42 in a phased approach this summer.&nbsp; Does this summer look likely?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And here&#8217;s a new addition to that question: What will be the administration&#8217;s plan once that policy is lifted?&nbsp; Will it be centered on deterrence?&nbsp; Will it be prioritizing restoring the asylum system?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, on the second part, that, of course, we want to restore the asylum system and we want to make it more operational.&nbsp; We want to make it more humane.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a lot of work we can &#8212; we need to do after the disaster of the last four years on this front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the timeline of Title 42 &#8212; I know I keep saying this to you, and I apologize it&#8217;s the same answer &#8212; but that is a decision that will be made by the CDC.&nbsp; I have nothing to preview for you in terms of the timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Karen.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, Georgia Governor Brian Kemp today accused the President and his allies of weaponizing the Justice Department to undermine election integrity.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House reaction to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I would say: If you have such a fear of making it easier and more accessible for people to vote, then I would ask you what you&#8217;re so afraid of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House see the Justice Department as its only real way of going on offense against some of these sweeping efforts across the country to implement voting restrictions?&nbsp; That, as opposed to legislation right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, we don&#8217;t.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I mean, it is an area where, of course, the Attorney General and some of the &#8212; as you know, Kristen Clarke, Vanita Gupta &#8212; some of the highest-ranking officials in the Justice Department &#8212; the President nominated and pushed for their confirmation &#8212; have long records of advocacy, effectiveness, and work on these issues.&nbsp; So, he certainly entrusts them with the work they&#8217;re going to continue to do on this front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are going to continue to fight for, battle for, work toward federal legislation.&nbsp; I know it does not seem easy at this time.&nbsp; Hard things &#8212; we do hard things; that&#8217;s what we do here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re also going to continue to engage &#8212; and this is a &#8212; as it relates to an earlier question &#8212; with local activists, with local legislators.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve seen the Vice President do a bit of this &#8212; engage with and work with them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to &#8212; to fight this fight on many fronts.&nbsp; And certainly not &#8212; the role that the Attorney General and the Justice Department may decide to take is one, but there are a l- &#8212; a number of other ways the President, the Vice President, and our administration will be continuing to fight for voting rights.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, right in the middle.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;Today, on the anniversary of Shelby v. Holder, you have over 25 buses coming in between today and tomorrow on these Freedom Rides, being led by Black Voters Matter. &nbsp;Has anyone from the administration spoken with them? &nbsp;I know that they&#8217;re going to be holding a news conference later on today.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But have you reached out to them?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll have to talk to our outreach team and some other senior members of the team to see if they had been engaged directly with them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know off the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, when it comes to the President trying to lower crime rate in the midst of this spike, there have been many reports showing that putting money &#8212; adding more money to police departments does not necessarily correlate with lowering crime.&nbsp; Why did the President decide to do that in &#8212; or instead of attaching it within the order to having the police departments do &#8212; have some type of system where they have to do something in order to receive that type of money?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that the President &#8212; and we saw some positive steps forward just yesterday on police reform in the negotiations; that&#8217;s certainly a positive step.&nbsp; The President believes we need to do both.&nbsp; And many &#8212; most people in most communities across the country where there&#8217;s rising crime agree.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And what the President announced just a couple of days ago, was a &#8212; primarily, a plan to reduce gun violence, which he feels is a big driver of violence across the country.&nbsp; But I would say, community policing and &#8212; is something that we&#8217;ve seen as effective, rebuilding trust in communities, ensuring that law enforcement are working on behalf of communities &#8212; that&#8217;s what he was proposing funding to go towards.&nbsp; That is different than a step &#8212; as it relates to the criminal justice system.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he going to talk back about creating a police oversight commission?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think a number of activists have conveyed that that is not their pri- &#8212; their preference for the path forward.&nbsp; They want to see this legislation move forward.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen some progress on that front, so that&#8217;s where we&#8217;re going to put ba- &#8212; the basket we&#8217;re going to put our eggs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the middle.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Now that Vice President Harris is visiting the border &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; as we speak, when will President Biden visit?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you or preview for you.&nbsp; As the President has said &#8212; the Vice President said back in March, she&#8217;d be open to visiting the border.&nbsp; And if it&#8217;s constructive and moves the ball forward for the President to visit it, I&#8217;m sure he may.&nbsp; But we come with a bunch of people, as you all know.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On voting &#8212; on voting rights, I just &#8212; I just want to be clear: Are you saying that the White House had no contact with the Justice Department about this decision to move forward in Georgia?&nbsp; Is the Justice Department completely independent on this or is &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m not &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; part of a White House agenda?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a priority to the President.&nbsp; But &#8212; and, yes, of course we are wel- &#8212; allowed to know.&nbsp; But it is &#8212; I was not meaning to convey that.&nbsp; But it is a decision made by the Justice Department to move forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, clearly, a priority of the President to take action wherever we can in government to make it more accessible to vote for people across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me go to her first, then I&#8217;ll go to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; When you talk about engaging at the state level &#8212; voting rights &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what does that look like?&nbsp; Aside from travel, how will the administration be scrutinizing new laws going into place or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you saw the Department of Justice take an action today, that&#8217;s an example.&nbsp; But you&#8217;ve also seen the Vice President meet with legislators and work &#8212; and talk with them about the path forward and how we can work together to fight back against vote- &#8212; efforts to suppress the vote across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So those are two examples.&nbsp; But, also, engaging with activists.&nbsp; I will say, there are a lot of people in this building who know a lot about how to engage, educate, empower people to know what their rights are.&nbsp; We want to work with states and local authorities to do exactly that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the President will be talking about this more next week.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the administration believe that&#8217;s making a difference in Republican-controlled state legislatures?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have to see.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President of Angola, President João Lourenço, was at the United Nations this week, and his main goal there &#8212; or his main focus was to &#8212; advocating to end the arms embargo that is going on on the Central &#8212; in the Central African Republic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And President Lourenço is now the acting President of the International Conference on the Great Lakes Region.&nbsp; So he know the area.&nbsp; He have done a lot of work to bring peace and security in this region; that&#8217;s why he advocated strongly to end the embargo.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the United States wants to continue the embargo.&nbsp; Do you know what is the main reason?&nbsp; Or what &#8212; what is the interest of the United States to keep the embargo on the Central African Republic?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’d really point you to our U.N. Ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield; or the State Department for that question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just have one more &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we have to move on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any situation in which the President would sign the bipartisan infrastructure deal without an accompanying reconciliation bill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President fully expects and plans to sign both pieces of legislation into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other question &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The end of the Supreme Court term is next week.&nbsp; Does the President or the White House expect any retirements?&nbsp; And what would the message from the President be to a Justice who might be thinking about hanging up the robe?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a decision for them to make as an individual.&nbsp; And he would support whatever decision they make.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden met with financial regulators earlier this week.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if there was any discussion about buy-now-pay-later companies &#8212; so like Klarna, Affirm, Afterpay.&nbsp; These are becoming very popular in the U.S. in retail transactions.&nbsp; And Europe recently made moves a few months back to regulate them.&nbsp; Is there anything you could tell me about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve provided a readout of the meeting and what the focus of the meeting is &#8212; was &#8212; which was to provide an update on the state of the financial markets, to talk about how they can work to make credit more accessible.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything more to read out for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So no discussion &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You could certainly &#8212; you could certainly reach out to any of the regulators if they want to speak about anything they raised.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have more of a readout from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; But no discussion from the White House then &#8212; on that then?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would point you to the regulators.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more to read out from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President is meeting shortly with President Ghani and Chairman Abdullah.&nbsp; They met yesterday with the Senate&#8217;s Minority Leader.&nbsp; And after that meeting, he called for a reversal of course by this administration to avoid a Taliban takeover of Afghanistan, contending that will give rise to renewed terrorism threats to the U.S. homeland. What is your response to Senator McConnell on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would first say it’s important to take a step back and remember what we inherited.&nbsp; One, the lowest number of U.S. and partner forces in Afghanistan since the early days of the war.&nbsp; Two, an agreement between the United States and the Taliban to draw down all U.S. troops by May 1st, just three months after Inauguration Day &#8212; a very short timeline.&nbsp; And three, a military stalemate between the Taliban and Afghan forces.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s the hand we were dealt.&nbsp; The President made a decision &#8212; which is consistent with his view that this was not a winnable war &#8212; to bring the U.S. troops home, some- &#8212; after 20 years of fighting this war.&nbsp; And a big part of that decision was also around the fact that if we left our troops there, our troops would be at risk because the Taliban would be shooting at them by May 1st.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s the basis of it.&nbsp; Are there challenges to it?&nbsp; Of course.&nbsp; Will we continue to be engaged &#8212; as &#8212; as today is an &#8212; is evidence of &#8212; with the government about how we can continue to provide humanitarian security support?&nbsp; Yes, we will.&nbsp; Will we have a presence on the ground?&nbsp; Yes, we will.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But that was a decision the President made with all of those factors involved.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good to see you again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, hello, Goyal, how are you?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good to see you again.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Good to see you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick two questions, please.&nbsp; One on U.S.-India relations, of course: Prime Minister Modi has spoken with President Biden a number of times.&nbsp; And have they &#8212; at the level of moving forward U.S.-India relations now between the two of them and where vaccine is concerned &#8212; where do we stand?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, Goyal, that the &#8212; India is an incredibly important partner to the United States in the region and globally.&nbsp; And we work with India on a range of issues, as you well know &#8212; economic, strategic, security.&nbsp; And the United States certainly took a range of steps, as India was at the early stages of dealing with a rise in the pandemic, to help provide a range of assistance, and we will continue to do that moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, Goyal.&nbsp; We got to &#8212; we got &#8212; we&#8217;re going to run out of time, so I just want to get to as many people as possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on the border thing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Texas Governor Greg Abbott released a statement saying that he would have preferred the Vice President went to the Del Rio sector or the Rio Grande area.&nbsp; Any response to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>And secondly, was there any communication between the Vice President&#8217;s office that you can tell us about with the governor&#8217;s office about a potential meeting?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A meeting with the governor?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the Vice &#8212; between the Vice President and the governor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I am happy to check with them and see if there was or if that was ever a part of &#8212; of the plans.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll get back to you on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any response to his criticism about where she went today?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say the purpose of the Vice President&#8217;s visit &#8212; as we&#8217;ve outlined &#8212; was to &#8212; she&#8217;s long said she would be open to visiting the border; she&#8217;s doing that with Secretary Mayorkas, who oversees the border and has helped lead a range of progress there that we&#8217;ve seen over the last couple of months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there certainly is a connection between the important work the Vice President is doing in the Northern Triangle, where we&#8217;ve also seen a reduction in migration of unaccompanied children since March and since April.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that&#8217;s the purpose of their visit.&nbsp; In terms of direct consultation with the governor, I&#8217;m happy to check and see if there&#8217;s more I can read out for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead in the middle, in the back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll go to you, right in front of him.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the governor&#8217;s meeting with western governors next week: Can you tell us anything about which governors are invited, what we can expect to come out of that meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, specifically, the President mentioned he was surprised at just how little federal wildland firefighters were paid.&nbsp; What would the administration do about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, we could pass a federal minimum wage, which would represent a higher wage than it seems the firefighters are getting. &nbsp;But, certainly, he will continue to advocate for additional support and assistance for the men and women serving as firefighters around the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me give you a sense of the governors coming.&nbsp; So the meeting, first, will focus on how the federal government can improve wildfire preparedness and response efforts, protect public safety, and deliver assistance to our people in times of urgent need.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a former local elected official himself &#8212; maybe he will always feel that way in his heart, I think.&nbsp; He feels it&#8217;s really important to engage directly, sit with people &#8212; as you can, either remotely or in person &#8212; to really discuss what the holdups are, what the challenges are, how can we help be better partners from the federal government.&nbsp; So this is an example of that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Governor Kate Brown, Governor of Oregon; Governor of California, Gavin Newsom; Governor of New Mexico, Michelle Lujan Grisham; Governor of Wyoming, Mark Gordon; Governor of Colorado, Jared Polis; Governor of Utah, Spencer Cox; and Governor of Nevada, Steve Sisolak, will be the governors who will be in attendance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could I just confirm that Governor Little and Governor Gianforte are not invited?&nbsp; And Governor Inslee?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s the list of attendees I have.&nbsp; I can certainly check if there&#8217;s more on who or &#8212; was or wasn&#8217;t invited.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; I said I would go to right next.&nbsp; We’ll &#8212; we’ll make sure we get to you.&nbsp; I promise.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you offer more specifics about what the President and the White House will do over the next week to continue to boost support for this infrastructure bill?&nbsp; Can we expect him to be on the phone with Republicans that have expressed concerns about his comments yesterday?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You can expect, as is evidenced by the fact that he called Senator &#8212; he had a conversation with Senema- &#8212; Senator Simina &#8212; Sinema?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Ugh, Friday.&nbsp; That’s a hard one.&nbsp; Senator Sinema this morning that he, of course, be on the phone, and he will be engaging directly with members of both parties about moving his priorities forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, sometimes that&#8217;s scheduled or planned a day in advance or the day before, so I don&#8217;t have more specifics for you.&nbsp; But as they happen, we&#8217;ll read them out for you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up on that, please?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he called any of the Republican senators today?&nbsp; Obviously, you were mentioning earlier that he&#8217;s talked about this publicly, what his stance was.&nbsp; There are Republican senators that are surprised by what he said yesterday and are upset, as has been reported.&nbsp; So has he talked to them today?&nbsp; And what is he doing to sort of keep this deal intact?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think what he&#8217;s doing, Anita, is continuing to convey and provide details to the public &#8212; who care deeply about whether he&#8217;s delivering for them, less about the mechanics of the process &#8212; about why this should be a package that&#8217;s supported broadly by Democrats and Republicans across Congress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that&#8217;s what I did, certainly, at the beginning, and that&#8217;s the case he&#8217;s going to continue to make.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he call any of those senators today though?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any additional calls to read out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think &#8212; let&#8217;s see &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Jen.&nbsp; First, just following up on an earlier question.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Special Immigrant Visa population from Afghanistan: Does the United States plan to protect those translators and people who worked for Americans who have already fled Afghanistan and are in different countries currently?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, they’re individuals who are already in the SIV pipeline.&nbsp; I suppose some of them might not be.&nbsp; I can certainly &#8212; might not be still there.&nbsp; I can certainly check and see if they&#8217;re &#8212; if they&#8217;ve already departed Afghanistan, how that would apply.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then I have another question about the manatee population in Florida.&nbsp; They are dying &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That was not on my bingo card today &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but I’m happy to answer it.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, the Wall Street Journal had a good article about them this week.&nbsp; They are dying at a record pace.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;Eight hundred of them died in the last year. &nbsp;And I wanted to see if the administration believes that these animals should be relisted as endangered, and also whether anything in Biden’s infrastructure deal that he struck yesterday would continue on to help with &#8212; part of the problem is that they’re &#8212; the Florida waters are not clean.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s sort of hurting their habitat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I will say, in in all seriousness &#8212; I mean, certainly, it&#8217;s an important question, an important issue.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want the &#8212; the pro-manatee &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; people to not think I feel that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I will say that, yes, there are components of his &#8212; of his package.&nbsp; I mean, a part of this package &#8212; a big part of this package is a down payment on climate resilience, on ensuring that we are cleaning up some of the polluted areas in our country &#8212; something that is impacting a lot of communities proportionally more than others.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that is &#8212; I would have to check on sort of what that means for the Florida coast &#8212; I think you said, specifically there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of relisting them &#8212; it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I just have to talk to the &#8212; the folks &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more about Afghanistan, please.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; who would be more specific about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Nazira Karimi, Afghan journalist.&nbsp; There are many protestors &#8212; Afghan protestors &#8212; outside the White House.&nbsp; They are waiting and they have a high expectations from today&#8217;s two Presidents meeting.&nbsp; Do you have any message for them?&nbsp; Because as soon as I leave here, I go to see them and get their opinion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I would say that the &#8212; the meeting today is an opportunity to convey, from the President, that we have an ongoing commitment &#8212; we are committed to supporting the Afghan people and the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces, even as we continue to undertake a security transition.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is also going to emphasize, during this meeting, the need for unity, cohesion, and for the Afghan government to focus on the key challenges Afghanistan faces.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, as you noted, we’ll welcome both President Ghani and Chairman Abdullah.&nbsp; And one of the most important messages he will stress is that they need to have a united front as Afghanistan continues to address security and other challenges.<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, he will emphasize our continuing diplomatic support for the peace process and for all Afghan parties to engage in good faith in that process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So the bottom line that you can convey is that he&#8217;s going to discuss our enduring United States support, including through security assistance to the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces, development and humanitarian assistance to support the Afghan people, and diplomatic engagement in support of peace.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, guys.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got a &#8212; you’ve got to gather.&nbsp; Oh, I’m sorry.&nbsp; Chris.&nbsp; Chris.&nbsp; Chris.&nbsp; And then I want to go to Amna because it&#8217;s her first time too, so okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Happy Pride.&nbsp; I know we&#8217;re running short on time,&nbsp; I’m just going to smush my multiple inquiries today on the LGBT developments into one, and that is &#8212; (laughter).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Take your time; it&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; People can leave if they need to gather.&nbsp; No one is rushing you out of here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The initiatives today: How do they place in the President&#8217;s both domestic and foreign policy agenda?&nbsp; And don&#8217;t they fall short of the President signing the Equality Act into law?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, on the &#8212; well, let me start with the first one because I think that&#8217;s an important question, because what we do here and the values that we advocate for in the United States do send an important message around the world, and sometimes we forget that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, during his remarks today, the President will outline, of course, the historic step his &#8212; his administration has taken, but he will also renew his calls on the Senate to swiftly pass the Equality Act and provide overdue, explicit civil rights protections to LGBTQ people and families across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He will also speak directly to the proliferation of state-level anti-LGBTQ bill- &#8212; plus &#8212; bills, denouncing them as un-American and legislation disguised as bullying.&nbsp; And he will commend the community for their courage and bravery pushing progress forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, he will announce his appointment of Jessica Stern as the U.S. envoy to advance the human rights of LGBTQ persons at the Department of State, a role &#8212; just to make the connection here &#8212; that will be critical to advancing his agenda overseas and around the world, as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any plans for the President to visit the soon-to-be Pulse Memorial?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview in terms of travel beyond next week.&nbsp; Maybe &#8212; we don&#8217;t work too far ahead in planning around these parts, but certainly the fact that he&#8217;s signing this legislation today sends a clear message about, you know, his commitment to the LGBTQ+ community, and to commemorating what was a tragedy in our nation&#8217;s history.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Amna.&nbsp; Okay, last one.&nbsp; And then everybody can gather.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two quick ones on &#8212; the NewsHour has been in touch with Taliban spokesman Suhail Shaheen.&nbsp; Ran by him the reports of hundreds of additional U.S. forces staying beyond the withdrawal.&nbsp; This is his response: He says, “It&#8217;s a violation of the commitment and the agreement made by the U.S.&nbsp; It jeopardizes the peace process and could pave the way for continued prolonged war.”&nbsp; So what&#8217;s the White House response to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, that we have been very clear &#8212; and the President was when he made his announcement about his plans to withdraw troops &#8212; that we plan to have a diplomatic presence on the ground, including &#8212; including a security presence to protect our diplomatic presence on the ground.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that has been a part of the discussion from the beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>And beyond that, I certainly would have to talk to our national security team if there&#8217;s more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more quick one: The family of Mark Frerichs &#8212; a U.S. Navy veteran who is still held hostage in Afghanistan &#8212; is worried that as U.S. troops continue to leave, you&#8217;ve lost all leverage in any efforts to free him.&nbsp; So what&#8217;s the President&#8217;s message to his family?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President&#8217;s message is that he will continue to fight every day of his presidency to bring Americans home who are detained overseas in &#8212; whether it&#8217;s in Afghanistan or any other country around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, we will have a diplomatic presence on the ground.&nbsp; We will continue to work closely with the government, with security support, humanitarian support.&nbsp; And there needs to be continued &#8212; continued political process, ongoing negotiations.&nbsp; That will be part of the President&#8217;s message today when he meets with the leaders.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks, everyone, so much.&nbsp; Happy Friday.</p>



<p>1:35 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Continued U.S. Support for a Peaceful, Stable Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/fact-sheet-continued-u-s-support-for-a-peaceful-stable-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 21:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States continues to use its full diplomatic, economic, and assistance toolkit to support a peaceful and stable Afghanistan. Today, President Biden welcomed Afghanistan President Ashraf Ghani and Chairman of the High Council for National Reconciliation Dr. Abdullah Abdullah to the White House to discuss enduring United States support, including through security assistance to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The United States continues to use its full diplomatic, economic, and assistance toolkit to support a peaceful and stable Afghanistan.</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden welcomed Afghanistan President Ashraf Ghani and Chairman of the High Council for National Reconciliation Dr. Abdullah Abdullah to the White House to discuss enduring United States support, including through security assistance to the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces, development and humanitarian assistance to support the Afghan people, and diplomatic engagement in support of peace.<br><br>Our strong support and partnership is designed to prevent Afghanistan from ever again being used as a safe haven for terrorism; maintain Afghan stability and build self-reliance; promote economic growth; preserve social gains in education, health and women’s empowerment and the rule of law; protect the rights of women, girls, and minorities; bolster Afghan civil society; and respond to humanitarian needs.  <strong>Since 2002, the United States has provided nearly $88 billion in security assistance, $36 billion in civilian assistance, including $787 million specifically intended to support Afghan women and girls, and nearly $3.9 billion in humanitarian assistance to Afghanistan.</strong><br><br>The United States will continue to provide assistance through its enduring partnership with Afghanistan to promote a peaceful and stable future that the Afghan people want and deserve.  This includes:<br><br><strong>Providing COVID-19 vaccines to the Afghan people.</strong>  As part of our work to end the COVID-19 pandemic worldwide, and in response to a recent surge in COVID cases in Afghanistan, the United States will donate three million doses of Johnson and Johnson vaccine to the people of Afghanistan through COVAX. COVAX is working to ship those doses to Afghanistan.<br><br><strong>Providingcritical emergency medical assistance to respond to the COVID-19 crisis</strong>. USAID is also supporting Afghan efforts to respond to the critical shortfalls in oxygen and medical ventilation support by providing emergency and structural assistance. USAID has ordered over 300 oxygen cylinders and several months’ worth of ventilator consumables to be shipped to Afghanistan as quickly as possible.  Additionally, USAID plans to install oxygen plants in four hospitals that will serve smaller facilities in the surrounding areas. USAID previously announced that they are investing $3.7 million to train clinicians to manage severe cases in the five hardest hit urban cities and provide critical expertise for vaccine deployment. <br><br><strong>Providing needed assistance to help with the pandemic’s impacts. </strong>This is in addition to in the past year, the State Department and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) have provided $40 million to directly help Afghanistan respond to the COVID-19 outbreak, expedited $90 million in other COVID-related development assistance through the World Bank, and reoriented other U.S. development assistance to support Afghan efforts to deal with the pandemic’s consequences.  And, USAID recently committed $38 million in emergency COVID-19 supplemental funding to the UN World Food Program (WFP) to address the food and nutrition needs of approximately 1.2 million COVID-impacted vulnerable people in Afghanistan.  WFP will reach over a million people most affected by the economic impacts of COVID-19 with in-kind food assistance to help them meet their food needs for four months. Additionally, with this funding, WFP will reach more than 164,000 children and nearly 28,000 pregnant and lactating women with essential moderate acute malnutrition treatment.<br><br><strong>Contributing lifesaving humanitarian assistance to Afghans in need</strong>. The U.S. recently announced more than $266 million in new humanitarian assistance to address the pressing needs of an estimated 18 million people in Afghanistan, including more than 4.8 million internally displaced Afghans.  This funding will allow our partners to provide lifesaving protection, shelter, livelihood opportunities, essential health care, emergency food aid, water, sanitation, and hygiene services to respond to the needs generated by the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic.  Furthermore, this assistance will help to address protection needs for the most vulnerable Afghans.  This includes women and girls facing particular risks, including gender-based violence, as a result of decades of conflict and the pandemic.<br><br><strong>Continuing security assistance.  </strong>The Department of Defense’s Afghanistan Security Forces Fund (ASFF) will provide financial support to the Afghan National Army, Afghan National Police, Afghan Air Force and the Afghan Special Security Forces, including the Special Mission Wing.  Congress appropriated over $3 billion to ASFF in 2021 and the President has requested over $3.3 billion for 2022. <br><br><strong>Sustaining development assistance to support a secure, stable, unified, democratic, and self-reliant Afghanistan that is at peace with itself and its neighbors. </strong> As part of our commitment to invest in and support the Afghan people, the United States has recently announced an additional $300 million in civilian assistance for Afghanistan in 2021 through both the Department of State and USAID.  The President has also requested an additional $364 million in development assistance for the State Department and USAID for 2022.<br><br>This assistance demonstrates our enduring support for the Afghan people.  The funding will be targeted at sustaining the gains of the past 20 years by improving access to essential services for Afghan citizens, promoting economic growth, fighting corruption and the narcotics trade, improving health and education service delivery, supporting women’s empowerment, enhancing conflict resolution mechanisms, supporting the Afghan-led peace process and bolstering Afghan civil society.<br><br><strong>Mobilizing diplomatic support for peace and stability. </strong>The United States continues to press for a just and durable peace in Afghanistan. The United States recognizes that the best way to protect our interests and the interests of the Afghan people is through an Afghan-owned and Afghan-led negotiated settlement. Following intensive efforts by the State Department and a number of our key allies and partners, formal Afghanistan Peace Negotiations started last year for the first time since 2001. We continue to urge all Afghan parties to engage urgently and meaningfully in peace talks aimed at achieving a just and durable settlement that includes protections for the rights of all Afghans, including women and minorities.  The appointment of Mr. Jean Arnault as the United Nations Secretary General’s personal representative on Afghanistan and regional issues reflects the critical role of the United Nations in bringing together Afghan sides and regional stakeholders to end Afghanistan’s more than 40-year war.<br><br><strong>Standing with Partners in Support of the Afghan people.</strong>  Building on the broad international support for the Afghan people, the United States will encourage our partners to continue their security and development assistance, including through the Afghan National Army Trust Fund (ANATF), Law and Order Trust Fund for Afghanistan (LOTFA), and the Afghanistan Reconstruction Trust Fund (ARTF).  The United States will also work closely with other major donors to ensure continued development and humanitarian assistance to help the Afghan people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe Biden&#8217;s Call with Governor Ron DeSantis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-call-with-governor-ron-desantis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 19:11:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke this afternoon with Florida Governor Ron DeSantis to offer support after the President approved an emergency declaration for Miami-Dade County, Florida last night following the partial collapse of a residential building in Surfside, Florida. The President said his administration stands ready to provide additional resources and assistance that state and local officials&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke this afternoon with Florida Governor Ron DeSantis to offer support after the President approved an emergency declaration for Miami-Dade County, Florida last night following the partial collapse of a residential building in Surfside, Florida. The President said his administration stands ready to provide additional resources and assistance that state and local officials need. The President expressed his gratitude for the heroic first responders and search and rescue teams who are working tirelessly and whose bravery and courage have saved lives. The President also expressed his condolences to the Governor and the people of the Surfside community, sharing his grief for the families who lost loved ones in this devastating tragedy and for the families who are waiting in anguish as search and rescue efforts continue.</p>



<p><strong><u>Background:</u></strong></p>



<p>The President approved the emergency declaration shortly after receiving the request from the Governor of Florida, ordering Federal assistance be made available. The emergency declaration authorizes FEMA to coordinate disaster relief efforts, reimburse response costs, provide equipment and resources to assist with debris removal and emergency protective measures in order to try to save lives, and to provide temporary shelter and housing for those who have been displaced. FEMA has deployed an Incident Management Assistance Team to Florida to provide support for the state and two FEMA-supported search and rescue teams are involved in the response to this devastating incident. FEMA is also sending building science experts, search and rescue technical experts, and a mobile command center. Additional FEMA National Urban Search and Rescue System teams are on alert if requested. The White House and FEMA have been in close coordination with local officials throughout the past two days. The White House is continuing to monitor the situation, and the President will continue to receive regular updates from his Homeland Security team.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 49</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/25/bill-signed-h-r-49/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 19:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, June 25, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 49, which designates the Pulse Memorial located in Orlando, Florida, as the National Pulse Memorial.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, June 25, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 49, which designates the Pulse Memorial located in Orlando, Florida, as the National Pulse Memorial.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Equality Act Will Provide Long Overdue Civil Rights Protections for Millions of Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/fact-sheet-the-equality-act-will-provide-long-overdue-civil-rights-protections-for-millions-of-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Freedom and equality are fundamental American values. But today, millions of Americans lack basic non-discrimination protections just because of who they are or whom they love. President Biden believes that every American must be able to live freely, openly, and safely. That’s why he continues to call on the Senate to swiftly pass the Equality&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Freedom and equality are fundamental American values. But today, millions of Americans lack basic non-discrimination protections just because of who they are or whom they love. President Biden believes that every American must be able to live freely, openly, and safely. That’s why he continues to call on the Senate to swiftly pass the Equality Act, legislation which will provide long overdue federal civil rights protections to LGBTQ+ Americans and their families, while strengthening some key civil rights laws for people of color, women, people with disabilities, and people of faith.</p>



<p><strong>Despite the progress our Nation has made towards full equality, LGBTQ+ Americans still lack full non-discrimination protections in 29 states. </strong>In the absence of a Federal non-discrimination law, more than half of all U.S. states lack laws on the book prohibiting discrimination against LGBTQ+ individuals and families. The lack of federal non-discrimination protections for LGBTQ+ people means that millions of Americans can be denied housing, education, credit and more just because of who they are or whom they love. In states across the country, LGBTQ+ Americans can get married on Sunday, and denied a rental lease on Monday.<br><br><strong>The Equality Act will provide long overdue civil rights protections on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity – ensuring LGBTQ+ Americans are finally afforded equal protection under law. </strong>The Equality Act amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to provide explicit non-discrimination protections on the basis of sex, sexual orientation, and gender identity. The bill builds on the Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>Bostock v. Clayton County </em>by making explicit that non-discrimination protections for LGBTQ+ people in employment settings apply to other areas of life.</p>



<p><strong>The Equality Act will help protect LGBTQ+ Americans who continue to report facing discrimination. </strong><a href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/news/press-releases/poll-lgbtq-americans-discrimination/">Studies</a> show that majority of LGBTQ+ Americans say they have personally experienced discrimination because of their sexual orientation or gender identity. Transgender Americans, especially transgender women of color, continue to face rampant discrimination in housing, employment, and in public. These types of discrimination cause LGBTQ+ Americans to face higher rates of poverty, violence, and unemployment than other Americans.</p>



<p><strong>Discrimination isn’t just wrong. It also is detrimental to the physical health and safety of LGBTQ+ Americans, especially transgender women of color.</strong>&nbsp;LGBTQ+ Americans still face discrimination when seeking medical care or visiting a doctor. In surveys, nearly 29% of transgender people in the United States say they’ve been refused medical care because of their identity, which can lead to avoidance of medical care. &nbsp;That is why the Department of Health and Human Services <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/05/10/hhs-announces-prohibition-sex-discrimination-includes-discrimination-basis-sexual-orientation-gender-identity.html">announced</a> that it is taking steps to address and prevent discrimination against LGBTQ+ Americans in healthcare settings, but Federal legislation is needed to codify these protections. Discrimination also leads to violence. Transgender women of color face epidemic levels of violence. Too often, this violence stems from institutional discrimination in healthcare settings, housing, and employment.</p>



<p><strong>Anti-LGBTQ+ discrimination also contributes to mental health inequities faced by LGBTQ+ youth. </strong><a href="https://www.thetrevorproject.org/survey-2021/?section=Introduction">75 percent</a> of LGBTQ+ youth say they’ve experienced discrimination because of their sexual orientation or gender identity. Discrimination and bullying are detrimental to the mental health of any young person, and more than half of all transgender and non-binary youth say they have seriously considered commitment suicide in the past year. To address bullying and discrimination at school, the Department of Education has <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-confirms-title-ix-protects-students-discrimination-based-sexual-orientation-and-gender-identity">announced</a> that it is taking steps to expand protections for LGBTQ+ students in our Nation’s schools, but Federal legislation is needed to codify these protections.</p>



<p><strong>The Equality Act will also expand public accommodations protections for people of color, women, and people of faith. </strong>The Equality Act would also strengthen civil rights protections for other protected groups, including people of color, women, people with disabilities, and people of faith by expanding where non-discrimination protections apply to public accommodations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with Senator Sinema</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-senator-sinema/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 16:38:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President spoke to Senator Sinema today to thank her again for her work on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Agreement. He reiterated his strong support for the compromise agreement, and they discussed his plan to try to build support for the Agreement among both Democrats and Republicans. The President also reiterated that he would fight to pass&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President spoke to Senator Sinema today to thank her again for her work on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Agreement. He reiterated his strong support for the compromise agreement, and they discussed his plan to try to build support for the Agreement among both Democrats and Republicans. The President also reiterated that he would fight to pass the Bipartisan Agreement, as he committed to the group. The President reiterated strong support for both the Bipartisan Infrastructure bill and a reconciliation bill containing the American Families Plan moving forward on a two-track system, as he said yesterday when meeting the press with the bipartisan group of ten Senators. These are two critical priorities to the President that he wants to see advance through the legislative process as quickly as possible, pass as quickly as possible, and be presented to him for signing as quickly as possible. The President looks forward to signing both these bills.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/president-biden-announces-u-s-special-envoy-to-advance-the-human-rights-of-lgbtqi-persons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22007</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, ahead of his remarks at the White House for Pride Month, President Joe Biden announced that he will appoint Jessica Stern to be the U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons at the Department of State – a role critical to ensuring that U.S. diplomacy and foreign assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, ahead of his remarks at the White House for Pride Month, President Joe Biden announced that he will appoint Jessica Stern to be the U.S. Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons at the Department of State – a role critical to ensuring that U.S. diplomacy and foreign assistance promote and protect the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons around the world. The Special Envoy will play a vital role in leading implementation of the Presidential Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World. At a time when the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons are increasingly threatened in all regions of the world, the Special Envoy will bring together like-minded governments, civil society organizations, corporations and international organizations to uphold &nbsp;dignity and equality for all. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Jessica Stern, United States Special Envoy to Advance the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons, Department of State</u></strong></p>



<p>Jessica Stern, Executive Director of OutRight Action International, is based in New York. Jessica specializes in gender, sexuality and human rights globally. At OutRight, she has supported the legal registration of LGBTIQ organizations globally, helped secure the mandate of the United Nations Independent Expert on Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity, expanded the UN General Assembly resolution to include gender identity, and co-founded the UN LGBTI Core Group. She has provided expert opinions to governments globally, regional human rights institutions, and UN mechanisms, including UN Women where she serves as a member of multiple leadership bodies. Her writing has been cited by the Indian Supreme Court in its seminal judgment decriminalizing same-sex relations and been featured in The Oxford Handbook of Women, Peace and Security (2019). She is frequently quoted by the media, including by The New York Times, Al Jazeera, The Washington Post, BBC News, and The Guardian. She is an adjunct associate professor at Columbia University’s School of International &amp; Public Affairs.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
