<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 23:53:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala Harris on the For the People Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-the-for-the-people-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 23:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When we cast a ballot, we not only decide our leaders. We determine our future. The right to vote is fundamental. It gives Americans a voice in what happens in our nation—whether that is in our economy or our national security, our education system or our healthcare system. When more people have a voice, our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>When we cast a ballot, we not only decide our leaders. We determine our future.<br><br>The right to vote is fundamental. It gives Americans a voice in what happens in our nation—whether that is in our economy or our national security, our education system or our healthcare system. When more people have a voice, our democracy becomes more representative, and our nation becomes stronger.<br><br>Today, across our nation, we are witnessing unprecedented attacks on voting rights. There are unjust bills in dozens of state legislatures that would limit early voting and vote by mail and otherwise make it harder for the American people to vote. Make no mistake: While these attacks are meant to silence some Americans, the impact is felt by all Americans.<br><br>At this critical moment, the United States Senate had a critical opportunity to make voting more accessible nationwide. The For The People Act has the broad support of the American people. Yet, as Senate Democrats united around the legislation, this afternoon, Senate Republicans voted against advancing it.<br><br>The President and I are undeterred, and I know the American people are as well. Like generations before, we will not give up, we will not give in, and we will continue the fight to strengthen the right to vote. We will fortify and expand the nationwide coalition on voting rights, and promote voter engagement and registration nationwide. We will lift up leaders in the states who are working to stop anti-voter legislation, and work with leaders in Congress to advance federal legislation that will strengthen voting rights.<br><br>I want to be clear that our Administration remains determined to work with Congress to pass the For The People Act, and we will keep working with Congress to pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act.<br><br>Here is the bottom line: Our democracy is stronger when everyone participates—and it is weaker when people are denied meaningful access to participation. And that is why the right to vote is neither Democratic nor Republican. The right to vote is an American right.<br><br>It is our duty, at every opportunity, to protect and strengthen the right to vote.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the For the People Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-for-the-people-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 23:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Democrats in Congress unanimously came together to protect the sacred right to vote. In supporting the For the People Act and defending the rights of voters, they stood united for democracy. They stood against the ongoing assault of voter suppression that represents a Jim Crow era in the 21st Century. Unfortunately, a Democratic stand&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Democrats in Congress unanimously came together to protect the sacred right to vote.</p>



<p>In supporting the For the People Act and defending the rights of voters, they stood united for democracy. They stood against the ongoing assault of voter suppression that represents a Jim Crow era in the 21st Century.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, a Democratic stand to protect our democracy met a solid Republican wall of opposition. Senate Republicans opposed even a debate—even considering—legislation to protect the right to vote and our democracy.</p>



<p>It was the suppression of a bill to end voter suppression—another attack on voting rights that is sadly not unprecedented.</p>



<p>The creed “We Shall Overcome” is a longtime mainstay of the Civil Rights Movement. By coming together, Democrats took the next step forward in this continuous struggle—not just on Capitol Hill, but across the country—and a step forward to honor all those who came before us, people of all races and ages, who sacrificed and died to protect this sacred right.</p>



<p>I’ll&nbsp;have more to say on this next week. But let me be clear. This fight is far from over—far from over. I’ve been engaged in this work my whole career, and we are going to be ramping up our efforts to overcome again—for the people, for our very democracy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with FEMA and Emergency Preparedness Team on Extreme Weather Preparation and Response Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-fema-and-emergency-preparedness-team-on-extreme-weather-preparation-and-response-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 22:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met today with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, FEMA Acting Associate Administrator for Response and Recovery David Bibo, and other members of his emergency preparedness team to discuss FEMA’s ongoing efforts to prevent, prepare for and respond to extreme weather events, including hurricanes, tornadoes, extreme heat, and wildfires, as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met today with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, FEMA Acting Associate Administrator for Response and Recovery David Bibo, and other members of his emergency preparedness team to discuss FEMA’s ongoing efforts to prevent, prepare for and respond to extreme weather events, including hurricanes, tornadoes, extreme heat, and wildfires, as well as how to expedite delivery of support to communities in need of Federal help.</p>



<p>The President emphasized the importance of ensuring that the Federal government is prepared to respond quickly to a range of extreme weather scenarios and to support Americans when disasters strike.&nbsp;The President and his team also discussed how to enable communities across our country to build greater resilience in the face of extreme weather, which has been exacerbated by climate change.&nbsp;The President thanked FEMA and other frontline agencies for all they have done to respond to COVID-19 and help vaccinate Americans, and for their support in response to this year’s brutal winter storms and early fire season.</p>



<p>Next week, President Biden will convene Cabinet officials, Governors from Western States, and private sector partners to discuss the devastating intersection of drought, heat, and wildfires in the Western United States, and strengthening prevention, preparedness and response efforts this season.&nbsp;The 2020 wildfire season alone burned over 10 million acres across the United States, resulting in the loss of dozens of lives and tens of billions of dollars in economic damage.&nbsp;Next week’s meeting hosted by the President will focus on how departments and agencies across the Federal Government, in close coordination with State and local governments and the private sector, can most effectively enhance public safety and deliver assistance to our people in times of urgent need.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, June 22, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/22/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-june-22-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 21:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21641</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:13 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; So, I know some of you are going to have to leave for the pool call, which is absolutely fine.&#160; We will also keep you honest on when the President is getting ready to speak.&#160; So there are a couple of mechanics.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:13 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, I know some of you are going to have to leave for the pool call, which is absolutely fine.&nbsp; We will also keep you honest on when the President is getting ready to speak.&nbsp; So there are a couple of mechanics.&nbsp; Chris is going to be our special helper on this front today.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, a couple of items at the top.&nbsp; As you may have seen, today, the FAA &#8212; the Federal Aviation Administrator &#8212; Administration &#8212; announced it will award $8 billion in airport rescue grants from the American Rescue Plan to keep airport workers employed, construction projects going, provide rent relief to in-terminal concession companies, and help U.S. airports recover from the impacts of COVID-19.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks to the President&#8217;s successful vaccination program, America is on the move again.&nbsp; There are over three times more Americans traveling through airports now than at any time last year, and this funding will help airports ramp up operations, keep travelers safe, and workers employed.&nbsp; Hundreds of airports across the country will receive this funding, thanks to the American Rescue Plan, including airports in Philadelphia; Charleston, West Virginia; Anchorage, Alaska; Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina; Portland, Maine; and Portland, Oregon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last item for the top: It&#8217;s the first official week of summer, as you all know, and the onset of peak wildfire season.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already &#8212; we&#8217;re already experiencing extreme heat in the West, several large wildland fires, and we&#8217;ve had three named Atlantic storms &#8212; including Tropical Storm Claudette, which led to the tragic loss of life in Alabama this past weekend.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It was important to the President to meet with the FEMA Administrator and members of the Emergency Preparedness team, including the Homeland Security Advisor, to discuss the federal government&#8217;s ongoing preparedness and response efforts, as well as how FEMA supports communities in need.&nbsp; Hence, that&#8217;s what he will be doing this afternoon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Josh, why don&#8217;t you kick us off.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two subject areas.&nbsp; First, with regard to voting rights, President Biden described his 2020 campaign as a battle for the soul of America. &nbsp;What does the administration think is more important for the soul: upholding the tradition of the filibuster or getting the voting rights agenda through?&nbsp; If you had to make the choice, what is that choice?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t see it through that prism, which won&#8217;t surprise you.&nbsp; I will say that, first, the President believes that expanding access to voting, making it easier for people to vote should be a fundamental right for the American public across the country.&nbsp; And it will be a fight of his presidency long past today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I will also note &#8212; since you gave me the opportunity &#8212; that this has been a fight that he has been battling through the course of his career.&nbsp; When he was in the Senate, he fought for an extension of the Voting Rights Act.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it&#8217;s something that he, of course, talked about on the campaign trail, and he will continue to use the bully pulpit but also every lever in government to continue to advocate for moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, the President is going to meet with the FEMA Administrator this afternoon.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re seeing a lot of extreme weather and climate events.&nbsp; Researchers have an event at Columbia University this week to look at moving people out of harm&#8217;s way in order to mitigate the effects of extreme weather.&nbsp; Does this administration believe that more people need to leave the areas adversely affected by climate change in order to address the issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really interesting question, Josh.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if they&#8217;ll be talking about that during the President&#8217;s briefing this afternoon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note that, while it&#8217;s traditional for Presidents to get briefings on hurricanes and preparedness for hurricanes, it was important to him and to our team to also get a briefing on wildfires and the impacts, and also to take steps that are &#8212; to prepare for that and the impacts on local communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Whether that means moving people from their homes &#8212; it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll have to see what comes out of the briefing today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On COVID and missing the 70 percent deadline: As this White House sees it, what went wrong?&nbsp; What happened there?&nbsp; Was the goal too high, the number just not attainable?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t see it exactly like something went wrong.&nbsp; How we see it is: We set a bold, ambitious goal &#8212; something the President has done from the very beginning &#8212; and we are expected to meet that goal just a couple of weeks after July 4th.&nbsp; And, in fact, at this point, as of today, we&#8217;re going to be already at that point for people who are 30 years of age and older.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we also know, though &#8212; and we&#8217;ve learned this as we&#8217;ve been working to get the pandemic under control, take on this herculean task where there is no playbook &#8212; is that there are demographic groups and sometimes populations where it&#8217;s more difficult to reach.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that and we&#8217;ve talked about that as it related to &#8212; early on, to hesitancy we were seeing in communities of color or some more conservative communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve seen it&#8217;s been a great deal more difficult to get &#8212; to get young people between the ages of 18 and 26 vaccinated than adults who are older than that.&nbsp; Hence, we are redoubling our efforts to ensure we are targeting, we are focusing on, we are making the vaccine more accessible for those age groups.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, we are on &#8212; we are already meeting the goal of vaccinating with one dose 70 percent of Americans 30 years of age and older.&nbsp; And we are working toward meeting it for all adults as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just quickly, if I can follow up on voting rights here.&nbsp; Yesterday, you said that there&#8217;s more work to be done &#8212; among that is including engaging state legislatures.&nbsp; But the problems, as Democrats at least see it, is not problems in blue states &#8212; state legislatures; it&#8217;s Republican-controlled states where many of these decisions are already being made.&nbsp; So what leverage do you actually have?&nbsp; And what, realistically, do you think you can accomplish in some of these red states?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think the point we&#8217;ve been making is that it&#8217;s, in part, a federal approach that is needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think it&#8217;s important to remember why we&#8217;re at this point: State legislatures, as you referenced, across the country are passing a wave of anti-voter laws based on the same repeatedly disproven lies that led to an assault on our nation&#8217;s Capitol.&nbsp; They are putting these laws in place because they did not like the outcome and they&#8217;ve continued to perpetuate a lie about the outcome of the election.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What the President and what the Vice President will do is engage with voting rights groups; engage with legislatures who are supportive of expanding access to voting around the country &#8212; yes, there are &#8212; even in red states, there are many Democratic legislators or legislators who want to expand that access; empower them, work with them, support them in these efforts; and continue to fight to get legislation across the finish line on the federal level.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So this fight is not over.&nbsp; No matter the outcome today, it is going to continue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you mentioned the bully pulpit on the voting issue.&nbsp; Jamaal Bowman, a congressman, said earlier today, the President needs to be a lot more &#8220;vocal,&#8221; a lot more &#8220;out in front&#8221; on the issue.&nbsp; Do you guys believe the President has elevated this issue enough, given the seriousness that you frame it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would suggest that &#8212; that isn&#8217;t a &#8212; that is a fight &#8212; that those words are a fight against the wrong opponent.&nbsp; The President is passionate about this issue.&nbsp; He has been passionate through the course of his time in public office.&nbsp; You know, again, securing a 25-year extension of the Voting Rights Act &#8212; when, I would note, Strom Thurmond chaired the committee.&nbsp; So that was quite a time to live through.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he&#8217;s absolutely revolted by the wave of anti-voter laws based on the same repeatedly disproven lies that led to our assault &#8212; an assault on our nation&#8217;s Capitol, as I know the congressman and many others are as well.&nbsp; We share their passion.&nbsp; We share the desire to fight these efforts.&nbsp; We share the desire to fight against efforts by many Republicans to suppress the vote around the country.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean that that fight will always be easy, but he is going to stand by them in this effort.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would note that it&#8217;s not that he has &#8212; you know, it is not just about private phone calls &#8212; he&#8217;s certainly done a number of those &#8212; and private meetings &#8212; as he did with Senator Manchin yesterday to convey to him the importance to him, personally, of moving this to a debate on the floor about this important piece of legislation.&nbsp; The President has also &#8212; gave a speech in Tulsa, Oklahoma, where he gave a passionate &#8212; made a passionate case for the importance of voting rights.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also has taken action, including empowering a number of nominees at the apart- &#8212; at the Department of Justice who have been leading advocates for voting rights, pushing for their confirmation to get through.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department of Justice also just announced a few weeks ago that they are doubling their support and their financial support for enforcement of important voting laws around the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he signed a historic executive action, just several weeks ago, that puts in place a number of protections to ensure that people have the ability to vote.&nbsp; I would say that&#8217;s hardly being silent.&nbsp; That&#8217;s hardly sitting on the backbench.&nbsp; And we are &#8212; he will be standing with advocates in this fight for the foreseeable future.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; This White House is very good at setting ambitious but achievable goals.&nbsp; Did the White House believe that 70 percent was achievable when you set it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, there&#8217;s no record &#8212; there&#8217;s no playbook for this.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no record to look back and say, &#8220;These were the &#8212; these were the goals that were achieved 5 years ago or 10 years ago,&#8221; because we&#8217;re dealing with a historic pandemic.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s view is that we should set bold, ambitious goals and do everything we pas- &#8212; possibly can to achieve them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And in our view, we have &#8212; part of our objective was to return the country to normal, for people to enjoy backyard barbecues, which people across the country &#8212; millions of people will be.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have 1,000 people on the South Lawn here at the White House &#8212; frontline workers, men and women who are serving &#8212; also enjoying life back to normal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we also are honest about where we need to continue to redouble our efforts.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s among people who are 18 to 26.&nbsp; That is a small &#8212; relatively small demographic of the country, but one where there needs to be continued work.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to use every tool at our disposal to push for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what is the game plan for getting young people vaccinated in greater numbers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me give you a couple of examples of what we&#8217;re working on.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just Dr. Fauci on TikTok, though that is happening.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, Dr. Fauci has done several Q&amp;As with TikTok and Instagram influencers to answer questions, to meet people where they are, including young people, give them information they need.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>CDC&#8217;s COVID Vaccine Chat on WhatsApp is now live to help Spanish-speaking young adults get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re working with the private sector as well.&nbsp; As you all know, Microsoft is giving away Xboxes at Boys &amp; Girls Clubs.&nbsp; The College Challenge is rallying university students across the country.&nbsp; Walgreens is giving out $25 to anyone who gets vaccinated there before July 4th.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These are just a couple of examples of some of the approaches we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll build on that from there.&nbsp; What we&#8217;ve all &#8212; what we&#8217;ll also note is that we&#8217;re seeing the same challenges that we&#8217;ve seen in other groups, which is that access and making it as easy as possible is the name of the game.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, continuing to re- &#8212; to support our pharmacy program, to support our mobile vaccination units, to make this &#8212; the vaccine as accessible to young people.&nbsp; They lead busy lives; we want this to be just a &#8212; just a box they can check on their weekend to-do list.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on Phil&#8217;s question.&nbsp; You very ably went through the President&#8217;s history on voting rights and related issues, and you&#8217;ve laid out all the times he&#8217;s spoken about it. But this lectern is available to him today.&nbsp; We have not heard him talk about it.&nbsp; He has the biggest megaphone in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Aside from the Tulsa speech, just a few weeks ago?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m talking about when the vote is happening &#8212; using the President&#8217;s time.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, clearly, the President is choosing not to do that now.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Where is the President on this issue on a day when they&#8217;re voting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, that the President has spoke &#8212; spoken passionately about his commitment to expanding access to voting rights a number of times, and you will hear him speak about this again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You certainly will hear us.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll put out a statement from him at the conclusion of the vote today.&nbsp; And I expect you&#8217;ll hear from &#8212; more from him in the coming days as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On another subject, with COVID: Former FDA Commissioner Scott Gottlieb is among the voices saying he&#8217;s concerned that children who are not yet eligible to be vaccinated could be drivers of the variant, especially with school coming back and camps and all of that.&nbsp; What specifically does the administration feel needs to be done to address that issue for those not yet even eligible to be vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, as a parent of a couple kids myself who are not yet eligible to be vaccinated, I think the challenge is we need to be vigilant and abide by the CDC guidelines.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not always easy to do, and we know that.&nbsp; And that means, you know, being mindful of social distancing, being mindful of where mask wearing should be essential to keep your kids protected and keep other kids protected.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, we can&#8217;t expedite the work of the FDA.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the gold standard in science, and we want them to abide by whatever timeline works for them.&nbsp; But it does mean &#8212; which again, is challenging &#8212; abiding by the guidelines for children and those who are not yet eligible until we get to that point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You said, yesterday, the President feels a lot &#8212; a great deal of the crime we&#8217;re seeing is a result of gun violence, but the stats show it&#8217;s not just gun crimes.&nbsp; So why does the President think there&#8217;s been a 30 percent increase in car thefts in D.C., 47 percent increase in robbery in New York City, or a 98 percent increase in rapes in Atlanta?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think, if you look at a number of cities across the country, it is actually driven by gun violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>Take St. Louis: In 2021, 96 percent of homicides where the instrument is known were committed using a firearm.&nbsp; In New York City, from March 2020 to March 2021, shooting incidents have jumped 77 percent.&nbsp; The city recorded more than 1,500 shootings in 2020; 97 percent more than 777 in 2019.&nbsp; There are major cities across the country where gun violence is absolutely the driver, where it is absolutely increasing.&nbsp; And that will be a central part of what he&#8217;ll talk about when he delivers his remarks tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And given everything that is going on &#8212; with guns, without guns &#8212; does the President still think that this is the best time to end cash bail?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I have a &#8212; any new position on that for you, but I&#8217;m happy to check and see if there&#8217;s anything more to report.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So his stated position from his website, which is, basically, end cash bail &#8212; he wants to lead a national effort to end cash bail and reform the pretrial system.&nbsp; That stands?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a new position for you, but I&#8217;m happy to check for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, for people who are watching who might be worried about a rise in crime, what does the President think is a deterrent to committing a crime if there&#8217;s no cash bail in place?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me give you just a sense to the degree I can, because we&#8217;re still finalizing the specifics.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s been, one, an increase in violent crime over the last 18 months; it&#8217;s not just over the last few months.&nbsp; And actually, if you look statistically back, it&#8217;s more over the last five years or so.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So there&#8217;s an initial set of actions the President has announced to date to address gun violence.&nbsp; Back in April, strengthening regulations on ghost guns; stabilizing braces that make firearms more legal [sic] &#8212; lethal; investing money in community violence intervention programs &#8212; an investment that he thinks can be quite effective.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talked about, for decades &#8212; and I think you&#8217;ll hear him talk about more tomorrow &#8212; supporting additional funding for community policing through his budget request, and helping state and local governments keep co- &#8212; cops on the beat.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, yes, we believe that a central driver of violence is gun violence and is the use of guns.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing that statistically in a lot of areas.&nbsp; But he also believes that we need to ensure that state and local governments keep cops on the beat, that we&#8217;re supporting community policing, and that&#8217;s a key part of it as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just the last one.&nbsp; You just said, again, you guys want to &#8220;keep cops on the beat,&#8221; but there are reports that big cities are having a very difficult time recruiting officers right now.&nbsp; And there are many other reports that morale is at an all-time low in big police departments.&nbsp; So why does the President think that there&#8217;s low morale with police officers on the beat?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re the right entity to give an assessment of that.&nbsp; I&#8217;d certainly look to the police departments to give that assessment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I would say to you is that the President has never supported defunding the police.&nbsp; He&#8217;s always supported community policing programs.&nbsp; He&#8217;s supported giving funding to &#8212; to states and localities around the country, including through his American Rescue Plan, because he thinks there is an essential role to play for community policing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Andrea.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I want to ask you about infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there was the meeting earlier today.&nbsp; Can you give us a little &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s still going on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s still going on.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As far as I know.&nbsp; When I came out here, yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And are you hopeful that you&#8217;ll be able to invite those senators to the White House for a meeting with the President?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will see.&nbsp; As we do every day in democracy in action happening here, we assess what the right next step is.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as I noted yesterday, the President is encouraged by the ongoing talks and discussions that are continuing with Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve sent some &#8212; he&#8217;s asked some members of his senior team &#8212; as you noted, Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell &#8212; to go up to Capitol Hill and meet with a group of bipartisan senators.&nbsp; And once they conclude that meeting, I expect we&#8217;ll assess what the next steps are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;re getting a lot of criticism already about the paring down of the very ambitious infrastructure proposals.&nbsp; Things that are falling away are things that you&#8217;ve said are top priorities, whether it&#8217;s climate, the care economy.&nbsp; I mean, how do you &#8212; how do you anticipate dealing with and solving those priorities, spending issues, if you get to a compromise now that is, in fact, a slimmed down version of what you initially planned?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a budget reconciliation process that&#8217;s just getting underway, which we expect to be a vehicle to move a number of the President&#8217;s bold ideas forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you a question about Amazon as well?&nbsp; So the FTC is going to look at the Amazon-MGM merger.&nbsp; There&#8217;s growing criticism about the antitrust legislation that&#8217;s being put forth on the Hill.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Are you &#8212; what is your perspective about whether there is, sort of, fundamental reform needed to ensure that large companies don&#8217;t get too big?&nbsp; Do you see this as, sort of, an inflection point?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve seen companies, including Amazon, really profit enormously from the pandemic and during the pandemic, and there have been warnings even from international financial institutions.&nbsp; So do you see that there&#8217;s something sort of fundamental needed now to check the growth?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m going to be in a position to speak to it from here.&nbsp; There are legal components of this.&nbsp; I can see if there&#8217;s more we can &#8212; we can give back to you on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on the Amazon FTC review: Do you &#8212; can you just confirm any details of that review?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going be able to confirm or speak to that specifically from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President&#8217;s remarks tomorrow, just to follow up on policing and crime &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; will that detail any efforts on police reform?&nbsp; Or is that kind of unilaterally focused on crime prevention?&nbsp; And why or why not?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, there&#8217;s ongoing negotiations, as you know, on police reform.&nbsp; And the President would love to have a bill on his desk that he could sign into law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve seen progress being made, we&#8217;ve heard progress being made, and those discussions are ongoing.&nbsp; So I would expect that his &#8212; his remarks tomorrow will build on &#8212; will build on a number of the announcements that have already touched on that he&#8217;s made in the recent months, making guns &#8212; putting in place safety measures to make our streets safer, preventing the use of guns in violent crime across the country, ensuring that we can have more cops on the beat to protect communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He, obviously, is a big advocate for the benefit of community policing so we&#8217;ll build on that foundation and lay out a comprehensive strategy to address violent crime and gun violence as the &#8212; as we enter the summer months.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some advocates &#8212; criminal justice advocates have raised concern that potentially having the President raise alarm about, you know, a trend of rising crime &#8212; this crime uptick in American cities &#8212; could actually undercut efforts on police reform, especially since legislation is still being discussed, you know, in Congress.&nbsp; So is that a concern for the White House at all?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The White House has said that, you know, the administration wants to give members of Congress space to negotiate police reform, but that potentially raising alarm of this crime uptick could hurt those efforts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that the negotiations are happening between Senator Booker, Senator Scott, key &#8212; Congressman Bass.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think they&#8217;ve expressed that particular concern.&nbsp; If there&#8217;s a named person who is expressing this concern, I&#8217;m happy to speak to that.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s &#8212; those negotiations are ongoing.&nbsp; We keep them abreast of our work.<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, I think, in communities across the country who advocate and support police reform, they don&#8217;t see it as a mutually exclusive issue; neither does the President.&nbsp; We need &#8212; police reform is long outdated.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s also important to take steps to &#8212; to put in place gun safety measures, to take any &#8212; use at any lever he can as President to do exactly that, and to ensure there is appropriate funding and resources needed to ensure there&#8217;s community policing in communities across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more on FEMA &#8212; the FEMA meeting.&nbsp; Given that meeting happened today, FEMA is still involved in setting up shelters at the border.&nbsp; Since we&#8217;re going into hurricane season, as you said, is there a deadline on when FEMA will be pulled out of that process of assisting at the border?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to assess for FEMA.&nbsp; Obviously, they&#8217;ll make that assessment in coordination with the leadership at the Department of Homeland Security, but I don’t have anything to preview on the timeline for that.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been a key resource.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. &nbsp;Going back to the 70 percent goal, the CDC data says that there are 13 states that are falling way short of that 70 percent; they&#8217;re less than 55 percent.&nbsp; Four states are below 50 percent.&nbsp; Should those states get more of a focus right now and not the nationwide number, as the administration plans their strategy to get vaccinations up?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; we&#8217;re not not focusing on those states.&nbsp; I would say that, one, it&#8217;s important to note that when we give the statistics &#8212; including 87 percent of all seniors, 75 percent of people age 40 and over, 70 percent of those age 30 and over &#8212; they&#8217;re from red states and blue states and purple states, or whatever color the state may be.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our focus, from the beginning, has been continuing to redouble our efforts among demographics and groups where we need extra assistance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have taken steps to put in place 24-hour pharmacies, walk-up sites, mobile clinics, free rides.&nbsp; We have vaccines at barber shops, baseball games, NASCAR races.&nbsp; Even over the last &#8220;Month of Action,&#8221; which we&#8217;ve been doing across the country, we&#8217;ve had 15,000 events.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve attempted 1.4 million contacts or reached about 500,000 people.&nbsp; And there are thousands of volunteers in 50 states across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Ultimately, it&#8217;s going to be up to individuals to decide if they want to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there something more, though?&nbsp; You went through all of those incentives, and specifically tying those to that age group &#8212; that younger age group.&nbsp; But if there&#8217;s something that&#8217;s regional about this &#8212; if it&#8217;s Alabama, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Wyoming that are those states below 50 percent, is there something that the administration can do to get those numbers up?&nbsp; Or at this point, is this governors and states that should be doing this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s always been a partnership, and it will continue to be a partnership moving forward.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s also up to individuals to make the decision to get vaccinated.&nbsp; And what we can do from the federal government, of course, is to make it as accessible as possible; make sure we have the supply &#8212; we&#8217;ve done that long ago; make sure there are thousands and thousands of sites, vaccinators, opportunities for people to get vaccinated; incentivize it across the country. &nbsp;That&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;ve done.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note: We&#8217;re not going to stop implementing these programs on July 5th.&nbsp; We will continue to implement them as we work to get more people in the country vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, April.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I want to hit two topics: voting rights, as well as crime.<br>&nbsp;<br>You keep bringing up former President George W. Bush, in 2006, when he &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I do?&nbsp; I keep bringing him up?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you bought him up &#8212; you brought the extension up.&nbsp; You brought the extension up of voting rights, and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What &#8212; I think that happened long before (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;&nbsp; Right, but you brought it up as to &#8212; it was extended for 25 years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t bring up George W. Bush, but, go ahead, you can bring him up.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, I&#8217;m bringing him up.<br>&nbsp;<br>As someone who was here when he did it &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; he was a Republican who did it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s one of his pieces that he likes to tout when he talks about efforts in the Black community.&nbsp; What&#8217;s different with Republicans then and Republicans now when it comes to voting rights?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What&#8217;s different?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, April, what &#8212; what should raise some questions for Americans across the country is: Why would anyone want to make it more difficult to vote?&nbsp; Why wouldn&#8217;t we want to make it more accessible?&nbsp; What are they so afraid of?&nbsp; And maybe they&#8217;re more afraid now of what it would mean to have more people voting across the country than they were back then.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll have to ask them that question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, secondly, on crime: What&#8217;s different now as you&#8217;re trying to push this effort on community policing, as well as guns?&nbsp; What&#8217;s different now?&nbsp; What do you think will have the teeth to change the tide that hasn&#8217;t been changed before?&nbsp; In the coming years (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Different now &#8212; do you mean different from a different period of time &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; or different from &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, you know, community policing was in place during the Clinton years; it was taken away.&nbsp; There was conversation about it in many years prior.&nbsp; And now, you&#8217;re bringing it back again.&nbsp; So you’re bringing the issue back again.&nbsp; What teeth do you believe that will have?&nbsp; And do you believe that that could become a reality again?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, I understand different police departments can do what they want.&nbsp; But you’re trying to make an overall sweeping push for police departments across the nation to make this difference.&nbsp; What’s different now that will make this tide change?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say one difference now is that it&#8217;s become a politically charged issue, when it wasn&#8217;t historically.&nbsp; And if you look back, Community Oriented Policing Services, you know, historically had been supported by liberal Democrats; Democrats; civil rights groups, including the NAACP, and &#8212; over the course of time.&nbsp; And that has always been the case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say we&#8217;re not suggesting &#8212; the President isn&#8217;t suggesting it&#8217;s the silver bullet.&nbsp; A central part of his remarks and his &#8212; his announcement tomorrow will be about addressing gun violence, which he thinks is a significant driver in violence in our communities and cities across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, as you know, April, there are laws that were in place: the Assault Weapons Ban, others that are no longer in place.&nbsp; There are also additional guns &#8212; ghost guns and others that were not a reality just a few years ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are some laws he&#8217;d like to go back to and some that he&#8217;ll continue to work to update.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, again, what&#8217;s different now?&nbsp; I mean, you&#8217;ve got the powerful NRA.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got Republicans who &#8212; anytime you touch anything about guns, they feel like you&#8217;re taking their rights away.&nbsp; What&#8217;s different now?&nbsp; Where do you think the tide will turn on this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Are you asking me about, like, the politics of now or the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The politics and, you know, this moment in time.&nbsp; Why do you believe that you have a chance to make a dent when you didn&#8217;t &#8212; when Democrats didn&#8217;t have to do &#8212; have it before?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just say here&#8217;s how the President sees this: There&#8217;s been rising crime in cities for the last 18 months, if not before that.&nbsp; Yes, there needs to be reforms of police systems across the country; the President is a firm believer in that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But there are also steps he can take, as President of the United States, to help address and hopefully reduce that crime.&nbsp; A big part of that, in his view, is putting in place gun safety measures, using &#8212; even as Congress is not moving forward currently &#8212; using the bully pulpit, but also using levers at his disposal as President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess I’ll take another shot &#8212; stab at that, to use a phrase.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; What&#8217;s different for Joe Biden?&nbsp; Thirty years ago, he was chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, wrote a crime bill, addressed this issue.&nbsp; What has he learned since then?&nbsp; And what can we look, tomorrow, that might be the same or different?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, on the campaign: The President said that some parts of the bill worked and some areas did not work.&nbsp; There are also steps he took as senator when he introduced or supported legislation, I should say, to address the disparities in gun senten- &#8212; in drug sentencing laws.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s taken some specific actions over time in areas where he don&#8217;t &#8212;&nbsp; doesn&#8217;t think worked as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are some components of that legislation he supported at the time, including the 10-year ban on assault weapons; including the support for &#8212; for the Violence Against Women Act; and including the support for community policing programs that he has been a longtime advocate for.&nbsp; And I think you will see continuity in terms of his support for those initiatives moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said that he aims to build on the announcements he&#8217;s made.&nbsp; Is there anything we can expect to hear tomorrow that we haven&#8217;t heard before?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Stay tuned.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t tell you everything, otherwise you won&#8217;t come tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the President&#8217;s meeting with the chairman of the Federal Reserve yesterday: Did the President bring up interest rates or express his view on the direction of interest rates at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you well know, that is the purview of the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve put out their own projections, as you know, about what it looks like moving forward.&nbsp; The topic and the focus of the meeting was exactly as it was outlined in our &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he did not bring up interest rates at all?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just have no more to read out for you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on the infrastructure negotiations, do you know &#8212; has White House put anything new on the table as far as payfors?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say we&#8217;ve put a lot of different options on payfors on the table.&nbsp; And our view is there&#8217;s a fundamental question right now: Are &#8212; are Dem- &#8212; are Republicans, members of Congress, do they believe that rich people should have to pay the taxes they owe?&nbsp; Or should we increase the cost of travelers who are just trying to make it to work?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s the basic question here.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll see if they can make progress on that exact point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say who the stakeholders will &#8212; who will be at the White House tomorrow for this crime meeting?&nbsp; Can you say who&#8217;s coming?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The announcement tomorrow?&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have it in front of me, but we can venture to get it to you after the briefing.&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And this is sort of a pullback question, but why now exactly?&nbsp; Is it just because crime rates are up and the stats are out?&nbsp; Or why is this the week, of all the weeks, that the President has decided to focus on crime?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, I would say that he&#8217;s made a number of announcements over the past several months on gun violence, on putting in place gun safety measures.&nbsp; He&#8217;s made &#8212; announced in his budget his support for community policing and providing funding.&nbsp; Maybe we haven&#8217;t drawn that clear through-line for all of you, but this is a continuation of that, in his view.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Labeling it a speech about crime is certainly different than a speech about gun safety or it &#8212; this is &#8212; this is a different focus.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A central part of it will be on gun violence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m just going to continue this &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; crime spree, if you will.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A lot of analogies here that might be threatening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My colleague, Zolan, had brought up that there are activists who are very concerned that the President&#8217;s decision to highlight crime right now could undercut some of the negotiations on the Hill for police reform.&nbsp; You&#8217;d asked for the names of some of them.&nbsp; The Tampa Dream Defenders is one, the Justice Action Network is another &#8212; just so we, sort of, have that covered.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But can you address how the President is going to sort of walk that line between expressing his concern about crime without undercutting these efforts that, as you point out, have been under- &#8212; you know, have been underway for a while.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, what I was trying to get at &#8212; but thanks for bringing up the question again &#8212; is that there are negotiators that are continuing to make progress on the Hill.&nbsp; And the President supports and stands by a lot of these groups in their support and advocacy for long-overdue police reform.&nbsp; He believes that, supports it, wants to sign a bill into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>He does not feel that they are conflicting.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think you&#8217;ve heard from any of the negotiators on the Hill that they feel they are conflicting either.&nbsp; So that was the point I was trying to make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And communities across the country where they are seeing &#8212; if you&#8217;re living in St. Louis and 96 percent of homicides were done where &#8212; we know the instrument &#8212; were done using a firearm, you do want to hear more about what the President of the United States is going to do to address that.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re living in New York City, you do want to hear more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And nationwide, you know, Everytown put out some information that there were 30 &#8212; more &#8212; 30 &#8212; 3,900 additional firearm deaths and 9,278 additional firearm injuries in 2020 compared to 2019.&nbsp; That&#8217;s impacting people&#8217;s lives, people&#8217;s communities, people&#8217;s families, people&#8217;s neighbors.&nbsp; Of course they want to hear more, and he wants to share more with the American public about what he&#8217;s going to do about it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just on COVID: Just given that, you know, the country did not reach this goal of 70 percent of adults being &#8212; getting one shot, is there anything that the country cannot do?&nbsp; Is there any sort of &#8212; I mean, that was always the, sort of, benchmark for getting back to normalcy.&nbsp; And since we didn&#8217;t get there, are there things that the country cannot do because we haven&#8217;t actually achieved the goal that we were supposed to?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say it&#8217;s a goal we, here, set in the White House.&nbsp; I’m &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything you’d recommend the country not do, given that the goal was not reached?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this was always going to be community to community, right?&nbsp; When the President set this goal back in March, it was always meant to be a incentive and a driver for people to see what the benefit would be of getting vaccinated.&nbsp; And at the time, what the President said is, “If you are vaccinated, your neighbors are vaccinated, you can all have a backyard barbecue.”&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing that times about 100 by hosting 1,000 people here at the White House.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, if you&#8217;re in a community where you&#8217;re at 80 percent vaccination rate, my bet is the community is pretty closely back to normal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If you&#8217;re not in a com- &#8212; if you&#8217;re a community with a much lower vaccination rate, obviously, you&#8217;re going to make your own choices, but you&#8217;re not operating in a community where it should be back to normal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it&#8217;s always going &#8212; was always going to be local, was always going to be based on what the decisions are made, community to community &#8212; but not nationwide, no.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really dependent on where you&#8217;re living.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, because the President is in Washington, D.C., and they have got &#8212; we have got &#8212; Washington, D.C., has gone beyond their 70 percent goal, it&#8217;s okay to do (inaudible).&nbsp; It&#8217;s okay to have 1,000 people in Washington, D.C., at an event because Washington, D.C., has surpassed the 70 percent, but somewhere where it&#8217;s a 50 percent vaccination rate perhaps &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Communities are going to make their own decision.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing ever magical through science about 70 percent.&nbsp; 70 percent was a bold, ambitious goal we set to continue to drive to get more people vaccinated across the country.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not as if, if you&#8217;re 67 percent in a community, you&#8217;re at a different level of safety than 71 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>Communities are going to make their own decisions.&nbsp; And I think, at &#8212; a fundamental fact is that if you&#8217;re vaccinated, if your neighbors are vaccinated, then you&#8217;re safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; One quick &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I&#8217;m going to (inaudible) here.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Chris.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thanks.&nbsp; Can you respond to &#8212; at least a couple Republican senators and one today said that &#8212; want to have talked about signing on to this bipartisan talks right now on the Jobs Plan, that that would essentially stop momentum or stop you guys from being able to do reconciliation.&nbsp; Can you respond to that idea that they&#8217;re basically cooperating so that you can&#8217;t do the second half of your plan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s how the process works, fundamentally.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it will not stop the White House from enacting and Democrats from &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if you just &#8212; if we just go to our episode of “How a Bill Becomes a Law,” there&#8217;s a budget reconciliation process led by the budget chairman; it&#8217;s proceeding.&nbsp; It needs a certain number of votes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s different from the number of votes that are needed for other pieces of legislation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That piece of legislat- &#8212; the budget reconciliation process is proceeding.&nbsp; There&#8217;ll be discussions.&nbsp; There may even be disagreements among people within the Democratic Party about what should be included in there or not.&nbsp; There needs to be 50 votes to move that forward.&nbsp; But that process is continuing and proceeding.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But stopping the momentum for it, as well as taking the amount of time that these talks are taking that it &#8212; realistically, that it could gum up the works to get this &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; How would it gum up the works?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, this is their &#8212; this is their plan, their hope of a strategy.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sounds like they have some more explaining to do about what they mean.&nbsp; Or maybe they need to go to “How a Bill Becomes a Law,” &#8220;How Reconciliation Works.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;ll suggest that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Senator Sanders could &#8212; he could come to the Republican caucus and teach them.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll offer him.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One on foreign affairs, please?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, we have to wrap it up because I think the President is about to speak.&nbsp; But thanks so much everyone.&nbsp; Sorry it was a little short today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>1:48 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before a Meeting with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell and Homeland Security Advisor and Deputy National Security Advisor Dr. Elizabeth Sherwood-Randall</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/22/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-meeting-with-fema-administrator-deanne-criswell-and-homeland-security-advisor-and-deputy-national-security-advisor-dr-elizabeth-sherwood-randall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 21:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 2:06 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, our FEMA Director &#8212; Administrator is here today.&#160; We&#8217;re going to talk about was the sever- &#8212; severe weather patterns we&#8217;re facing which keeps &#8212; likely increase every year.&#160; And I want to make sure that we&#8217;re in a position to be able to help Americans all across&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>2:06 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, our FEMA Director &#8212; Administrator is here today.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to talk about was the sever- &#8212; severe weather patterns we&#8217;re facing which keeps &#8212; likely increase every year.&nbsp; And I want to make sure that we&#8217;re in a position to be able to help Americans all across the country and in all our jurisdictions as these severe weather incidents increase.<br>&nbsp;<br>The last few days alone, we&#8217;ve seen droughts and wildfires in the West, and we&#8217;ve seen tornadoes in Illinois, flooding in the South and the Mid-Atlantic.&nbsp; And extreme weather doesn&#8217;t confine itself, as you all know, to state lines.&nbsp; These crises require proactive federal responses.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just not just the states responding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I know that &#8212; that your team, Administrator, is going to raise &#8212; be faced with a lot of challenges this year, more than most.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not that you&#8217;re not used to it, but it&#8217;s going to &#8212; this time, it&#8217;s the whole country.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve already stepped up this year to help vaccinate the American people and respond to the (inaudible), but now we have to respond to these brutal storms &#8212; and more severe storms and fires that extend into longer seasons throughout the year.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to bring every resource to bear to be prepared to respond and to help people recover, but it&#8217;s a big job.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re making sure FEMA and other frontline agencies have what they need to continue getting the job done.&nbsp; And I insist on being ready for whatever comes our way.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is all about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re here today about.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll be hosting a meeting next week with Western governors and FEMA and the Cabinet members to prepare for heat, drought, and wildfires in the West.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I want to thank everybody for being here today.&nbsp; And let me just say one other thing.&nbsp; You know, I was talking with my staff a moment ago in the office about wildfires.&nbsp; And &#8212; and, you know, the thing I know a little bit about is the fire service.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there&#8217;s an old expression: God made man, and then he made a few firefighters.&nbsp; They are &#8212; they have the higher incidence of severe injuries than police officers do.&nbsp; They are incredibly, incredibly brave, what they do: They run to the fire.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I just realized &#8212; I didn&#8217;t realize this, I have to admit &#8212; that federal firefighters get paid $13 an hour.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to end in my administration.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a ridiculously low salary to pay federal firefighters.&nbsp; Not that many federal firefighters, but &#8212; and they &#8212; and I know you use all the resources, including state and local firefighters.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, any rate, that&#8217;s we&#8217;re going to talk about today.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be brought up to date on what we can expect this season.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And many of you have covered what&#8217;s already happened.&nbsp; And the droughts in the West is just astounding, when you take a look at it.&nbsp; Fires have already started, and flooding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re in for a tough season, but I think we&#8217;ve got to be prepared and have every resource available to make sure we&#8217;re there for the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all so very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on voting rights, is this end?&nbsp; Is it over?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:10 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Three Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/president-biden-announces-three-key-nominations-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 20:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles: David Uhlmann, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Enforcement and Compliance Assurance, Environmental Protection Agency Celeste Wallander, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Security Affairs, Department of Defense David Prouty, Nominee for Member of the National&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>David Uhlmann, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Enforcement and Compliance Assurance, Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Celeste Wallander, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Security Affairs, Department of Defense</li><li>David Prouty, Nominee for Member of the National Labor Relations Board</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>David Uhlmann, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Enforcement and Compliance Assurance, Environmental Protection Agency</u></strong></p>



<p>David M. Uhlmann is an internationally recognized expert on environmental law, leading authority on criminal enforcement of the environmental laws in the United States, and highly-regarded advocate for environmental stewardship and corporate sustainability programs. He is currently the Jeffrey F. Liss Professor from Practice and the director of the Environmental Law and Policy Program at the University of Michigan Law School. Professor Uhlmann previously served for 17 years as a federal prosecutor, including seven years as the Chief of the Environmental Crimes Section at the United States Department of Justice. In that role, he led prosecution of environmental and wildlife crimes nationwide, coordinated national legislative, policy, and training initiatives regarding criminal enforcement, and chaired the Justice Department&#8217;s Environmental Crimes Policy Committee. He earned a reputation for prosecuting polluters aggressively and fairly, presided over expansion of the environmental crimes program, and strengthened relationships with the Environmental Protection Agency, the Coast Guard, and other law enforcement partners. His work as lead prosecutor in <em>United States v. Elias</em>, a tragic knowing endangerment case that left a 20-year-old worker severely and permanently brain-damaged, is chronicled in <em>The Cyanide Canary</em>. He received numerous Justice Department and EPA awards for his precedent-setting prosecutions, including the first environmental justice criminal trial.</p>



<p>Professor Uhlmann is a fellow in the American College of Environmental Lawyers, which invited him to join their Board of Regents earlier this year. Professor Uhlmann was named a “Conservation Hero” by the Michigan League of Conservation Voters and selected by the University of Michigan to be a Distinguished Faculty Fellow in Sustainability. Professor&nbsp;Uhlmann received a J.D. from Yale Law School and a B.A. in history and political science with high honors from Swarthmore College. Following law school, he clerked for U.S. District Court Judge Marvin H. Shoob in Atlanta, Georgia. He is married to Virginia Murphy, a professor in the Residential College at the University of Michigan. They have three adult children and two grandchildren, all of whom love hiking in the northern Maine woods.</p>



<p><strong><u>Celeste Wallander, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Security Affairs, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Celeste Wallander is President and CEO of the U.S.-Russia Foundation. She served as Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Russia/Central Asia on the National Security Council (2013-2017), as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Russia/Ukraine/Eurasia (2009 to July 2012), professor at American University (2009-2013), visiting professor at Georgetown University (2006-2008), Director for Russia/Eurasia at the Center for Strategic and International Studies (2001-2006), Senior Fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations (2000- 2001), and professor of Government at Harvard (1989-2000).&nbsp; She is the author of over 80 publications on European and Eurasian security issues, focused on Russian foreign and defense strategy. She received her Ph.D. (1990), M.Phil. (1986) and M.A. (1985) degrees from Yale University, and her B.A. (1983 – summa cum laude) from Northwestern University.&nbsp; She is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations, the Atlantic Council of the United States, and the International Institute for Strategic Studies.</p>



<p><strong><u>David Prouty, Nominee for Member of the National Labor Relations Board</u></strong></p>



<p>DavidProuty&nbsp;is General Counsel of Service Employee International Union (SEIU) Local 32BJ, the largest labor union for property service workers in the country with over 175,000 members. He served as General Counsel of the Major League Baseball Players Association (MLBPA) from 2013 – 2017 and as Chief Labor Counsel of the MLBPA from 2008 – 2013. Prior to June 2008, Mr. Prouty was General Counsel of UNITE HERE, the union formed by the 2004 merger of UNITE (the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees) with HERE (the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union), and was General Counsel of UNITE from 2001 &#8211; 2004. Before serving as General Counsel of UNITE and UNITE HERE, Mr. Prouty was Southern Regional Counsel for UNITE and its predecessor union, the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU), for fifteen years and litigated many of the union’s landmark organizing cases including <em>Fieldcrest Cannon, S. Lichtenberg, Tultex </em>and<em> Kmart</em>.&nbsp; He is a Fellow of the College of Labor and Employment Lawyers; was the Union Co-Chair of the American Bar Association’s Committee on Practice and Procedure Under the National Labor Relations Act from 2007 – 2010;&nbsp;was a member of the National Labor Relations Board’s Union Advisory Panel from 1997 to 1998; and is a member of the Peggy Browning Fund’s Advisory Board. Mr. Prouty graduated from Walter Johnson High School in Bethesda, Maryland in 1976; received his AB&nbsp;<em>magna cum laude</em>&nbsp;from Bowdoin College in Brunswick, Maine in 1980; worked as a researcher and organizer for the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) from 1980 to 1983; and received his JD&nbsp;<em>cum laude</em>&nbsp;from Harvard Law School in 1986.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 18:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21615</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION&#160;SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Carlton Waterhouse, of Virginia, to be Assistant Administrator, Office of Solid Waste, Environmental Protection Agency, vice Peter C. Wright. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION&nbsp;SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Carlton Waterhouse, of Virginia, to be Assistant Administrator, Office of Solid Waste, Environmental Protection Agency, vice Peter C. Wright.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Roundtable with LGBTQ+ Advocates on the Equality Act and Achieving Full Equality for LGBTQ+ Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/21/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-lgbtq-advocates-on-the-equality-act-and-achieving-full-equality-for-lgbtq-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 01:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond, and Executive Director of the Gender Policy Council Jen Klein hosted a roundtable in the Roosevelt Room with LGBTQ+ leaders who are coordinating the national movement to pass the Equality Act. Advocates shared their perspectives on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond, and Executive Director of the Gender Policy Council Jen Klein hosted a roundtable in the Roosevelt Room with LGBTQ+ leaders who are coordinating the national movement to pass the Equality Act. Advocates shared their perspectives on the urgency and importance of Congress extending long overdue civil rights protections to LGBTQ+ Americans by passing the Equality Act and shared the efforts their organizations are undertaking to get the bill to the President’s desk.</p>



<p>During the meeting, LGBTQ+ advocates and leaders also briefed senior White House officials on the alarming increase in anti-LGBTQ+ legislation in state legislatures across the country, in particular legislation that targets transgender children. They discussed the detrimental impacts these bills are having on the health, safety, and well-being of children and families across the United States.</p>



<p>Senior White House officials expressed their gratitude for the participants’ leadership and impactful advocacy. They reiterated the President’s strong commitment to achieving full equality for every LGBTQ+ American and his calls for the Senate to quickly pass the Equality Act. Finally, they underscored that the President has the backs of LGBTQ+ Americans, especially transgender youth.</p>



<p>Participants in today’s roundtable included:</p>



<ul><li>Alphonso David, President, Human Rights Campaign</li><li>Fatima Goss Graves, President and CEO, National Women’s Law Center</li><li>Fran Hutchins, Executive Director, Equality Federation</li><li>Mara Keisling, Executive Director, National Center for Transgender Equality</li><li>Kasey Suffredini, CEO and National Campaign Director, Freedom for All Americans</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, June 21, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/21/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-june-21-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 23:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:06 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi everyone.&#160; Good morning &#8212; or good afternoon.&#160; Okay.&#160; A couple of items for all of you at the top. Today, the Biden-Harris administration has launched Child Tax Credit Awareness Day to educate the public and encourage non-filers to sign up for the largest&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:06 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi everyone.&nbsp; Good morning &#8212; or good afternoon.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; A couple of items for all of you at the top.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris administration has launched Child Tax Credit Awareness Day to educate the public and encourage non-filers to sign up for the largest Child Tax Credit in history.<br><br>The American Rescue Plan increased the Child Tax Credit to $3,000 for families whose children are between 6 and 17 years old, and $3,600 for families with children under 6 years old, and allows half of that tax credit be paid to families in advance through a monthly check or direct deposit.&nbsp;<br><br>So, starting July 15th, almost all families who have filed taxes in the last two years will receive this monthly payment automatically.&nbsp; This means most families with two young children would receive a monthly payment of $600 starting in July.&nbsp;<br><br>But we want to make sure that everybody who is eligible signs up, hence we have launched a website: ChildTaxCredit.gov &#8212; very easy to remember.&nbsp; And if anybody is not sure &#8212; maybe they haven’t filed taxes because they &#8212; they don’t &#8212; they’re not required to &#8212; they can go there and learn if they’re eligible for this incredible benefit.<br><br>Second, today, the United States &#8212; in coordination with our allies and partners in Canada, the European Union, and the United Kingdom &#8212; has taken a number of actions to impose costs on the Lukashenko regime in Belarus for a variety of egregious acts.<br><br>Last month, we said we would develop a list of targeted actions against key members of the Lukashenko regime associated with ongoing abuses of human rights and corruption, the falsification of the 2020 Election, and the forced diversion of the Ryanair flight.<br><br>Today, we are following through and holding the regime accountable.&nbsp; So, earlier today, the Department of State and the Department of Treasury designated 62 Belarusian individuals and 5 entities in response to continuing repression in Belarus.<br><br>Importantly, we did this alongside our partners and allies.&nbsp; And with these coordinated actions on both sides of the Atlantic, we are demonstrating our deep and shared concern regarding the Lukashenko regime’s activities.&nbsp;<br><br>Finally, today, the Biden-Harris administration announced the distribution list for the remaining 55 million of the 80 million doses of America’s own vaccine supply President Biden has pledged to send out globally and allocate by the end of June in service of ending the pandemic.<br><br>Already, we have sent millions of doses to the world, including 2.5 million doses that arrived in Taiwan this weekend.<br><br>And, in addition, sharing doses fr- &#8212; in addition to sharing doses from our vaccines &#8212; own vaccines supply, the Biden-Harris administration is committed to working with U.S. manufacturers to produce more vaccine doses to share with the world.&nbsp;<br><br>And we’ve purchased, as we announced last week, half &#8212; or the week before that &#8212; half a billion Pfizer doses to donate to 92 low- and middle-income countries and members of the African Union. In total, the G7 agreed to provide an additional more than 1 billion doses starting in the summer of 2020 [2021].<br><br>With that, Alex, why don’t you kick us off?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I have a few.&nbsp; The first is on that vaccine allocation.&nbsp; The President promised to distribute those 80 million by the end of the month, but he&#8217;s obviously falling short of that goal.&nbsp; So, is there any indication that the red tape in this distribution is costing lives at this point?&nbsp; Why is it taking so long?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;re committed to allo- &#8212; we&#8217;re committed allocating those doses; we&#8217;ve done exactly that.&nbsp; What we found to be the biggest challenge is not actually the supply &#8212; we have plenty of doses to share with the world &#8212; but this is a herculean logistical challenge.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen that as we&#8217;ve begun to implement.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, as we work with countries, we need to ensure that there&#8217;s &#8212; safety and regulatory information is shared.&nbsp; Some supply teams need needles, syringes, and alcohol pads.&nbsp; Transportation needs &#8212; teams need to ensure that there are proper temperature storage, prevent breakage, and ensure the vaccine immediately clears Customs.&nbsp;<br><br>So, this has not, as you all know, been done before.&nbsp; Sometimes it&#8217;s even language barriers that occur as we&#8217;re working to get these doses out to countries.&nbsp;<br><br>So we have announced today where these doses are going.&nbsp; We will continue to announce as they land on the ground and as they are being shipped.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re looking forward to doing that as quickly as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And on infrastructure, the latest compromise: You said, earlier today, the President needs to see more details.&nbsp; What details does he need to see?&nbsp; Was he not able to take a look at the package this weekend?&nbsp;<br><br>And one of the issues you&#8217;ve obviously raised are payfors.&nbsp; So, gas tax aside &#8212; that being a nonstarter &#8212; what payfors would the White House be open to?&nbsp; Specifically, some have raised potentially using leftover CARES funds or funds from the December COVID package.&nbsp; Would those be feasible?&nbsp; And do you want to see the package ultimately fully paid for?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that, you know, the President&#8217;s pledge was not to raise taxes on Americans making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; And the proposed gas tax or vehicle mileage tax would do exactly that.&nbsp; So that is a nonstarter for him.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also note, for the mathematicians in the room: That only raises $40 billion, which is a fraction of what this proposal would cost.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has proposed a range of ways to pay for this package, including ways that would not violate the red lines that Republicans have put forward.&nbsp; One of them is ensuring the highest &#8212; wealthiest individuals in this country pay what they&#8217;re supposed to pay as it relates to taxes &#8212; additional tax enforcement &#8212; which would raise a great deal more by multiples of what the gas tax would raise.&nbsp; And it would &#8212; it would fall on for &#8212; predominantly wealthy Americans and just ensure they&#8217;re paying the taxes they owe.&nbsp; So, that is an area where we feel there should be an opportunity to move forward.&nbsp;<br><br>And as it relates to details, of course, there needs to be ongoing discussion; there will be over the coming days, rapidly.&nbsp; I expect he’ll have conversations this afternoon.&nbsp; Tomorrow, we&#8217;ll read those out as those happen, provide information to all of you.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re eager to get those continued.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the White House open to using those leftover funds to fund the ultimate bill?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, there&#8217;s minimal, very small amounts that would be leftover.&nbsp; And many of those small amounts have already been allocated or they are to help small businesses, help keep cops and firefighters on the beat.&nbsp; And so we feel the best proposal that does not violate the red lines that the Republicans have put forward would be tax enforcement and some other proposals the President has already put on the table.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lastly, on voting rights: Obviously, there&#8217;s going to be a show vote on S.1. tomorrow that&#8217;s going to fail.&nbsp; So, I wanted to come back to President Biden pledging to do whatever he could.&nbsp; He said he’d use every sort of tool at his disposal to get the bill passed.&nbsp;<br><br>What has he done to get that bill passed, considering this vote is going to fail?&nbsp; And since he has pledged that, is it time for him to start calling, again, for filibuster reform more loudly?&nbsp; That’s a tool at his disposal he has not yet really pushed for.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me just give you a sense of how we see this and how the President sees it: It&#8217;s a step forward.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t expect there to be a magical 10 votes.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not suggesting that.&nbsp; But just two weeks ago, there were questions about whether Democrats would be aligned.&nbsp; We certainly hope that will be the case tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s important to remember that this has been a 60-year battle to make voting more accessible, more available to Americans across the country.&nbsp; And our effort, the President&#8217;s effort to continue that fight doesn&#8217;t stop tomorrow at all.&nbsp; This will be a fight of his presidency.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of the steps he&#8217;s taken, he&#8217;s had conversations, obviously, with members about supporting this legislation, including Senator Manchin, as you all know, over the last couple of weeks.&nbsp; And he will continue to advocate.<br><br>He&#8217;s also asked his Vice President &#8212; or, agreed with his Vice President that she will be in charge of this effort moving forward.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t stop.&nbsp; This is an important piece of it &#8212; the federal legislation.&nbsp; More work to be done.&nbsp; But it doesn&#8217;t stop with that.&nbsp; There&#8217;s work to do in the states.&nbsp; There&#8217;s work to do with voting groups.&nbsp; There&#8217;s work to do to empower and engage legislatures.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that will also be part of her effort.<br><br>As it relates to the filibuster: You know, I don&#8217;t think you have to take it from us.&nbsp; That would be Congress moving forward or making a decision.&nbsp; If the vote is unsuccessful tomorrow, it will &#8212; I &#8212; we suspect it will prompt a new conversation about the path forward, and we&#8217;ll see where that goes.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on infrastructure: You know, Senator Portman said over the weekend that he thought that dropping the gas tax and this fee on electric vehicles could be something that they could do, so long as the President puts forward ideas that do not include raising any taxes.&nbsp; Is that a potential compromise that seems feasible?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, last I checked, the proposal the President put forward in his initial proposal &#8212; that has been a part of this discussion to increase investment in tax enforcement, ensure that people who are the wealthiest are paying what they should be paying in taxes, which would raise a significantly larger amount than the gas tax &#8212; does exactly that and should meet his bar.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, to Alex&#8217;s point, do you want this bill to be fully paid for?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has proposed means of fully paying for this package, including the tax enforcement components.&nbsp; He thinks that&#8217;s a responsible thing to do.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to have discussions with members about how we can find a path forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned continuing discussion: Should we expect another in-person meeting perhaps here at the White House this week?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I suspect &#8212; you can expect that, yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just going into this week, how does the President view his role in these negotiations?&nbsp; Is he the closer?&nbsp; Is the the facilitator?&nbsp; Like what’s his approach this week to try and get this across the finish line?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I feel like there&#8217;s a baseball analogy here I really want to deliver on so my husband thinks I&#8217;m cool, but I can&#8217;t think of it.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, I think the President, having served 36 years in the Senate, he&#8217;s always going to be deeply involved.&nbsp; He&#8217;s always going to roll up his sleeves and want to know every detail of what&#8217;s being discussed, every detail of the proposal and package.&nbsp; As I &#8212; as I noted, in response to Mary&#8217;s question, I suspect he&#8217;ll have some members here over the past &#8212; over the next couple of days to have those discussions in person.&nbsp;<br><br>So I don&#8217;t know how you &#8212; I will leave it to all of you to &#8212; to characterize or give a label for that.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s ready to roll up his sleeves, ready &#8212; the O- &#8212; the door to the Oval Office is always open.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll be deeply involved and engaged in these negotiations over the coming days.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And some progressives have made the ask that if you&#8217;re going to move forward with this bipartisan package, moderate senators commit to them to supporting the reconciliation piece of this as well &#8212; the second track, if you will.&nbsp; Will the President also seek that commitment from the moderates if they do move forward on a bipartisan piece of legislation?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the President sees this as a process that is &#8212; has multiple paths forward.&nbsp; And the reconciliation process &#8212; which is already underway, being led through the budget committees in Congress &#8212; is an important component of that.&nbsp;<br><br>And a number of his priorities and his proposals that he&#8217;s put forward are not a part of this negotiation or are not a part of this discussion that&#8217;s happening in a bipartisan manner.&nbsp; So he certainly would like to see that move forward, and he will make that case to others as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one last quick one: Does he support the Manchin language on the voting rights issue?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you know, again, I think this is a compromise.&nbsp; And as that happens, as compromises happen, it means there&#8217;s a lot that you like about it &#8212; and it may not be everything you love, but he certainly sees this as a step forward.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and as Stacey Abrams said over the weekend, incremental steps forward in making voting rights more accessible, making voting more available is a good thing.&nbsp;<br><br>And he certainly is appreciative of the efforts by Senator Manchin and others to continue to make progress on voting rights, which he feels is a huge priority.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some quick follow-ups on things that have already been discussed.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, on infrastructure, the meeting that would be taking place at the White House this week: Do we have a day or people who would be attending on that yet?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s an excellent question.&nbsp; We will provide more details to you as soon as we have them.&nbsp; But I suspect it could be more than one engagement.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then on voting rights: There&#8217;s been a lot of concerns expressed about whether it&#8217;s the Manchin proposal, the two bills that have been already floating in Congress &#8212; that they actually don&#8217;t address the key issues that are being faced right now, which is local election officials being removed, being taken &#8212; their power being taken away from them.&nbsp; Is the White House going to say anything about what more needs to be done to deal with those specific issues that are happening right now?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I think that&#8217;s an important point to raise.&nbsp; You know, even if the voting rights bill was sailing across the finish line with the support of every member of Congress, there would still be more to be done.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the Vice President is going to be leading this effort.&nbsp; You&#8217;re right that some of that is protections for officials and states.&nbsp; Some of that is, frankly, pushing back on the more t- &#8212; more than 40 states where there&#8217;s legislation moving forward that makes it more difficult for people to exercise a fundamental ro- &#8212; right, which is the right to vote.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, this is not the end of our effort; this is, in some ways, the beginning.&nbsp; And there is going to be more work done by the President, by the Vice President, by the administration to expand access to voting rights.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more thing, just on the financial regulation meeting &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that’s happening in the Oval Office today.&nbsp; There were a number of issues that I didn&#8217;t see on, kind of, your readout of what was going to be discussed at that meeting.&nbsp; You know, it could be anything from the Federal Reserve&#8217;s signaling interest rate hikes to the role that meme stocks are playing in financial stability.&nbsp; Just anything &#8212; I mean, are those &#8212; are those issues going to be raised?&nbsp; And what more is going to be focused on at that?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ll provide a readout of the meeting when their meeting concludes.&nbsp; I would note that it is a routine meeting.&nbsp; And most Presidents meet with their financial regulators.&nbsp; There is, of course, a couple of items on the proactive agenda.&nbsp; And when it&#8217;s concluded, we&#8217;ll provide a readout, including the state of the country&#8217;s financial institutions, work that they&#8217;re all doing to promote financial stability, implementation updates around climate-related financial risk, agency actions on financial inclusion and access to credit.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s the proactive agenda.&nbsp; As you know, in these meetings, different topics come up.&nbsp; But this is, again, in our view, a standard and routine meeting where they&#8217;ll discuss &#8212; the focus will really be on those topics.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you expecting any decisions to come out of it?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s more of an update than it is a decision.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Back on infrastructure, aside from the gas tax, now that the President has had a chance to take a look at the bipartisan plan, what does he think of it?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’d first say that the President is encouraged that Democrats and Republicans are continuing to discuss a path forward on rebuilding our roads, our railways, and our bridges.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a positive sign.&nbsp; And this offer is nearly double what the Republican offer was just a few weeks ago.&nbsp; That&#8217;s another positive sign in the right direction.&nbsp;<br><br>He&#8217;s somebody who cares about the details, wants to have a discussion.&nbsp; And now that he&#8217;s back in the United States and &#8212; I expect he&#8217;ll do that over the coming days.&nbsp; Also stay closely in touch with Democratic leadership about the path forward.&nbsp;<br><br>But certainly, he&#8217;s encouraged by the fact that the number has increased, the investments have increased.&nbsp; Has some questions about the payfors, which I&#8217;ve noted.&nbsp; And has a red line about the gas tax and raising taxes on individuals making less than $400,000 a year.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is a $1 trillion plan big enough for him?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think we see this as a &#8212; as a one step.&nbsp; There is a reconciliation process.&nbsp; That&#8217;s ongoing.&nbsp; And that addresses and includes a number of the President&#8217;s key priorities, including making pre-K universal for kids across the country, which would increase the likelihood of graduating by more than 50 percent; making community college more accessible.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s a lot of investments and proposals the President has put forward because he thinks they&#8217;re important for our economy, for the American workforce, for our competitiveness.&nbsp; And a lot of those will be included in a budget process that&#8217;s already moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So even if this plan doesn&#8217;t end up being as big as he would like it to be, he believes there are other ways to &#8212; to get those policies enacted?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are a lot of vehicles to move his bold ideas forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Medicare, does the President support Bernie Sanders&#8217;s proposal to include dental and vision in Medicare?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I actually haven&#8217;t talked to him about this, so I don&#8217;t want to speak out of turn.&nbsp; Let me do that, and we can get you all an answer on that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally, can you describe what safeguards the administration has in place to make sure that the children of top officials don&#8217;t get preferential treatment in hiring?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me say, first, that we have the highest ethical standards of any administration in history.&nbsp; A number of ethics officials have conveyed that, and we&#8217;re proud of that.&nbsp; We have also staffed up at an unprecedented pace, and that &#8212; and this is the most diverse administration in American history. &nbsp;<br><br>So, we certainly expect that everyone will abide by those high ethics standards.&nbsp; That applies in how we operate; it also applies in how hiring is done.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Afghanistan, please.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the President back from his trip, with the kind of progress you&#8217;ve talked about that he sees on infrastructure, is he seeing this as an inflection point, in terms of urgency?&nbsp; Is his mindset at all different after being rather patient in his approach with outreach?&nbsp; How would you describe where his head is right now, concerning how quickly something can get done?&nbsp; Because there are a lot of people who are feeling like it&#8217;s taking too long, and that perhaps he has to have a more active central public role.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;d first say that, having lived through a lot of legislative battles himself, he knows that sometimes they take some time; the sausage-making takes some time.&nbsp; But to your point, he does not feel the time is unlimited.&nbsp; And he would like &#8212; it is not weeks, in his view, in terms of moving forward and seeing if there&#8217;s a bipartisan path forward.&nbsp;<br><br>So that is why he&#8217;s eager to have these meetings and discussions over the coming days in the White House and see what it looks like, see if we can address some of the questions he has about this proposal.&nbsp; And certainly, he&#8217;d like to move forward sooner rather than later.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Iran, the newly elected President has indicated that he does not wish to meet with President Biden or to engage on the components of the JCPOA.&nbsp; What is the President&#8217;s view on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t currently have diplomatic relations with Iran or any plans to meet with the lead- &#8212; at the leader level, so it&#8217;s unclear that anything has actually changed on that front.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say that the President&#8217;s view and our view is that the decisionmaker here is the Supreme Leader.&nbsp; That was the case before the election; is the case today; will be the case, probably, moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>The Iran nuclear negotiating teams just finished their six rounds of talks.&nbsp; They have not yet announced the seventh round.&nbsp; But as is typical, they&#8217;re back consulting with capitals.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re looking forward to seeing where that goes moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Peter.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On COVID-19 origins, Jake Sullivan said this week that if China does not let investigators probing the COVID origins in, they&#8217;re going to face isolation in the international community.&nbsp; So what is an example of something that the White House thinks China would care about being isolated from?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that, as you know from covering the trip, last week there was a great deal of calibration around &#8212; in the global community, among the world&#8217;s largest democracies, the world&#8217;s most important security partners, about how we were going to work together to address the rising economic power of China and concerns where we have concerns, which &#8212; the lack of transparency is certainly one of them.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think what the President and what Jake Sullivan were referring to is: The global community has taken notice, we&#8217;re going to work together to exercise the necessary pressure on China to be a participant and to provide transparent data and access in this case, and China wants to have a role in the global community and global conversations.&nbsp; And certainly, they would take note of that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, the White House&#8217;s position would be that isolation from the international community is more of a deterrent than, say, sanctions and threatening sanctions or some other form of punishment?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the point that Jake was making is that China wants to be seen as a power in the world, as a central actor in the world.&nbsp; And they &#8212; they are not looking to have the global community align against them.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on infrastructure, Bernie Sanders is pitching a reconciliation package that&#8217;s up to $6 billion.&nbsp; That includes some of the President&#8217;s other priorities &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Trillion.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry &#8212; $6 trillion.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a lot more money that way.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just here to get you the accurate info.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; If something $6 trillion dollars big makes it to the President&#8217;s desk, would he sign it or is that too big?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp; And I would also note that the President has put forward a way of paying for these proposals, including what he feels are necessary reforms to our corporate tax system and asking the individuals &#8212; the highest-income individuals, the top 1 percent, to pay more.&nbsp;<br><br>And he&#8217;s put a range of ideas out there on the table and proposals out there on the table.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have discussions with Congress about what it looks like, what Democrats are comfortable with as well.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a range of views in the Democratic Party as well, but we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, the last one, a dozen or so states have now ended the federal unemployment benefits &#8212; the extra unemployment benefits.&nbsp; A couple more states are going to do that in coming days.&nbsp; Does the White House think that the governors who are ending these extra enhanced unemployment benefits before they expire are doing the right thing or the wrong thing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have continued to implement &#8212; or are continuing to advocate to implement these unemployment benefits for the remainder of their tenure, which is just a couple of months.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t actually know, because the data doesn&#8217;t exist yet, what the impact of the implementation in these states is.<br><br>Our view is that American families &#8212; there are still millions of people out of work.&nbsp; They still need a little bit of extra assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>We also don&#8217;t think that these benefits should be never-ending.&nbsp; Hence, they&#8217;re going to expire in early September.&nbsp;<br><br>So we know governors are going to make their decisions.&nbsp; We continue to believe that, with more than 7 million people out of work, that there&#8217;s still additional assistance we should give to the American public.&nbsp;<br><br>Why don&#8217;t you go ahead.&nbsp; Af- &#8212; you said &#8220;Afghanistan.&#8221;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; My name is Nazira Azim Karimi.&nbsp; I&#8217;m an Afghan freelance journalist.&nbsp; As you know, President Ghani and Dr. Abdullah will travel on Friday to the White House to Washington and visit with President Biden.&nbsp; What will be the main topic that President Biden will discuss with both of them?<br><br>And also, Taliban continues their attack in Afghanistan even today.&nbsp; White House has any plan to invite Taliban, too, to convince them to make a ceasefire in Afghanistan?&nbsp; Because Afghan people, they are really tired &#8212; Afghan.&nbsp; And, emotionally, we are in a bad situation.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Understood.&nbsp; Well, I know that President Ghani will be here in the United States on preplanned travel to New York, I believe.&nbsp; And of course, the President looks forward to welcoming him to the White House for a meeting on Friday.&nbsp; And I expect their top of &#8212; their focus of their conversation will &#8212; to be to continue to discuss how we can work together to ensure that Afghanistan never again becomes a safe haven for terrorist groups who pose a threat to the U.S. homeland; how we can work together to continue to implement the humanitarian assistance, other assistance that the United States remains committed to, even as we work to draw down our troops.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just two questions.&nbsp; One, in the wake of the Supreme Court ruling on the NCAA and college athlete compensation, does the White House believe that there should be federal &#8212; federal rules or some kind of federal standard governing college athlete compensation?&nbsp; Or is that a decision that the administration believes should be left up to states?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; I &#8212; let me just first say, on the ruling, that our view is that, of course, NCAA student-athletes work very hard, both on the athletic field and in the classroom.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a retired one myself.&nbsp; And today&#8217;s decision recognizes that, as with all Americans, their hard work should not be exploited.&nbsp; And the President believes that everyone who works should be compensated fairly for his or her labor.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of specific regulations, it&#8217;s an excellent question.&nbsp; This is obviously a new ruling.&nbsp; I&#8217;d have to talk to our policy teams about that and where we might stand.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one on COVID-19: Based on the current projections, it does not look like the President&#8217;s July 4th target of getting 70 percent of the population at least one dose of the vaccine will be met.&nbsp;<br><br>Of course, the administration has tried to incentivize vaccinations along with corporations and other partners.&nbsp; What else can the White House do at this stage to try and change the trajectory of vaccination rates?&nbsp; And what are the concerns of missing that target in terms of the President&#8217;s desire to get back to normalcy?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say we&#8217;ve made tremendous progress in our vaccination efforts to date.&nbsp; And the ultimate goal has been to get America back to normal, as you said.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re looking forward to doing that even here at the ri- &#8212; White House.&nbsp; As you know, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;ve invited 1,000 &#8212; over 1,000 essential workers and military families to join the President on the South Lawn &#8212; and many more &#8212; with fireworks on the Mall.&nbsp;<br><br>What we&#8217;ve seen over the course of the past couple months, in terms of progress, is a massive reduction in the number of COVID cases by about 90 percent &#8212; a 95 percent reduction in the number of deaths that are down.&nbsp; That&#8217;s significant progress.<br><br>We set this bold, ambitious goal because we wanted to continue to make progress.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing exactly that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen 16 states meet it.&nbsp; What we &#8212; what we&#8217;ve seen, as we&#8217;ve dug into the data, is that there is a big gap between individuals 25 and over, and 18 to 25.&nbsp; Eight- &#8212; yes, eighteen to under twenty-five.&nbsp; That means that&#8217;s an area we need to continue to work on.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, regardless, even if we sailed past &#8212; even if we do sail past the 70 percent goal, we&#8217;re still going to be vaccinating people on July 5th, on July 7th, on July 10th.&nbsp; That is still going to be &#8212; continue to be part of our objective.&nbsp;<br><br>But as we dig into the data, we know that what we&#8217;re seeing is a lower rate among young people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s concerning, especially with the Delta variant being on the rise, as it is &#8212; which does not discriminate by age, which still could cause death, serious illness.<br><br>I expect, in the coming days, you&#8217;ll get an update from our COVID team on where we are on the data on the different categories as they dig into it.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of them.&nbsp;<br><br>But we&#8217;re going to continue to run through the tape.&nbsp; We&#8217;re also going to continue to be focused on where we can raise the rates and raise the numbers where we see there &#8212; there&#8217;s a lower uptick of vaccination.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s a fly on your head.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Oh, thank you guys.&nbsp; At least it&#8217;s not a cicada.&nbsp; I swear, those things are &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, but I do have actual questions.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; I was like, &#8220;Is there breaking news?&#8221;&nbsp; But it&#8217;s just &#8212; yeah, there you go.&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; So, I mean, talking about the voting rights vote &#8212; there&#8217;s supposed to be a test vote tomorrow.&nbsp; That is expected to fail.&nbsp; When you look at &#8212; right now, the prospects for voting rights is not very high to get something through Congress as things stand right now.&nbsp;<br><br>So what I would like to know is if you can say, specifically, what the White House plans to do if you cannot get something &#8212; some type of federal action.&nbsp; I know you said that there are a lot of other things; you look at this as the beginning of the process.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But ultimately, on an issue as fundamental as voting rights, if you cannot get federal action, what is left for the White House to do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think we accept that.&nbsp; All I&#8217;m &#8212; the point I&#8217;m making is that it&#8217;s also state action.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also, frankly, action that&#8217;s been happening from the Department of Justice, including increased funding and increased implementation across the country, which is something that the President and the Attorney General have both emphasized as a priority, and we&#8217;ve made some specific announcements about.<br><br>So, look, I think, as we look to tomorrow, what&#8217;s clear and where we &#8212; what we&#8217;re measuring, I think, is: Is the Democratic Party united?&nbsp; We weren&#8217;t, as of a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a step forward.&nbsp; If &#8212; if and when &#8212; and as I &#8212; as I will acknowledge, we don&#8217;t expect there to be a magical 10 or more Republican votes.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been clear &#8212; the Republican Party and Republicans in the Senate: They do not want to make it easier to vote.&nbsp; They do not want to make it more accessible for Americans to vote.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, where do we go from there?&nbsp; That is a conversation we&#8217;re going to have to have with leaders in Congress, with Democrats, with a range of members who also want to see advance &#8212; advances on voting rights.&nbsp; And I expect the President will engage with Senator Schumer and others on the path forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When you talk about a conversation, does &#8212; that means a conversation on the filibuster, I would think, because, like you said, there&#8217;s not the 10 votes in the Senate.&nbsp; And that being the case, what do you expect that conversation to look like?&nbsp; Are you having conversations with Senator Manchin and others about possibly making changes to the filibuster, at least when it comes to voting rights, if anything is going to get done in Congress?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say the President has &#8212; has spoken to his support for a talking filibuster in the past, and, at times, other members have as well.&nbsp; It requires a majority of &#8212; it requires 50 Democrats to support changes in the filibuster rules.&nbsp; I will allow you all to do your vote counting of where things stand there.&nbsp; I suspect it&#8217;s not just one or two individuals who are opposed to that.&nbsp;<br><br>I will note, though, as I said earlier, that if the vote is unsuccessful, I suspect &#8212; we suspect that may change the conversation on the Hill.&nbsp; We will see.&nbsp;<br><br>But I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of where things are.&nbsp; There&#8217;s going to be a vote tomorrow.&nbsp; Democrats, we suspect and hope, will be united in making voting more accessible for people across the country, making sure we&#8217;re advocating for it as a fundamental right.&nbsp;<br><br>This is an opportunity for Republicans to stand up and do the same.&nbsp; It shouldn&#8217;t be a partisan issue.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q &nbsp;Thank you, Jen. &nbsp;Two topics for you. &nbsp;The first, I wanted to ask you about crime. &nbsp;I &#8212; is that I wanted to understand: Is there a concern at the White House that there could be an increase in crime this summer with the &#8212; you know, the pandemic lifting? &nbsp;And is that concern the reason that the President is going to weigh in this week?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, the reason is that there&#8217;s been actually a rise in crime over the last five years, but really the last 18 months.&nbsp; And so, it&#8217;s an opportunity for the President to speak to what he&#8217;s going to do to help address that.&nbsp; And as we&#8217;ve seen around the country, it is a concern of many Americans &#8212; Republicans but also Democrats, too &#8212; not necessarily through a partisan lens.&nbsp; It was something the President felt was appropriate to speak to and tell the American people what he&#8217;s doing to help address.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would he be approaching this a little differently than he did, perhaps in &#8217;94, when there was another crime wave that Democrats responded to?&nbsp; Can you talk to how his approach might change?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of his comments or remarks later this week.&nbsp; But it is an area where the President feels a lot &#8212; a great deal of the crime we&#8217;re seeing is a result of gun violence.&nbsp; I &#8212; you can expect he&#8217;ll speak to that and his commitment to continuing to address gun violence and gun safety in the country.&nbsp;<br><br>And, certainly, a long time has passed since the Crime Bill in &#8217;94.&nbsp; He&#8217;s spoken himself to differences &#8212; things he would stand by, things he would &#8212; might do differently.&nbsp; But I wouldn&#8217;t see this as a response to that, as much as a conveying to the American people what he&#8217;s going to do now to help address the rise in crime we&#8217;ve seen over the last year and a half.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just wanted to follow up on Phil&#8217;s question &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; from earlier about the Manchin compromise that had been floated.&nbsp; Just &#8212; if you can talk specifically about his idea &#8212; or maybe if you could speak specifically to the administration&#8217;s position on allowing or requiring some form of voting ID when people go to the polls.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President is looking &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to go through different individual pieces of the package.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a compromise.&nbsp; The President &#8212; there are components there, of course, that I think, universally among most Democrats in the country &#8212; an extension of early voting, making Election Day a law &#8212; we would support.&nbsp; This is a step forward, should be seen as an incremental step forward.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see what&#8217;s the next step in Congress.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thank you.&nbsp; Quick one on immigration and then another topic.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been reports &#8212; Axios is reporting that the White House is eyeing the end of July for a potential timeline to lift Title 42 at the border.&nbsp; CDC is also referring to White House on this.&nbsp; Does the White House see that as a realistic timeline for potentially lifting Title 42?&nbsp; Would we be at a place where vaccines are continuing to be distributed and it would be safe enough to lift that policy?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have any new policy to announce.&nbsp; When it comes to Title 42, there&#8217;s been no change.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not, of course, going to get ahead of the CDC decision, the process involved in that &#8212; which you just touched on a lot of those components.&nbsp; But we would let them pursue that process.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would the White House prefer to allow the outcome of that policy be dictated by the current litigation that the ACLU is pursuing or would &#8212; that the administration unilaterally make a decision on that policy?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a policy process that&#8217;s ongoing.&nbsp; That&#8217;s unrelated to the litigation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then in terms of the President&#8217;s trip later on this week to North Carolina, the White House &#8212; the administration said early on that when it came to vaccine hesitancy, a big part of the strategy was relying on local physicians, local governments as well &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to kind of take that on.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s &#8212; the Vice President took a trip recently, and the First Lady is taking a trip.&nbsp; Now the President taking a trip.&nbsp; Does this mark, kind of, a shift in strategy when it comes to combating vaccine hesitancy?&nbsp; And when it comes to that specific demographic you described &#8212; younger people &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what really do you do to convince those people to take vacc- &#8212; vaccines at that point?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say: No.&nbsp; Where we&#8217;ve invested our funding is in local &#8212; empowering local, trusted voices, whether they&#8217;re doctors or clergy or civic leaders.&nbsp; That continues to be the case.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, of course, the President and the Vice President of the United States should be out there advocating for the impact, the efficacy of the vaccine, and the impact.&nbsp; And as a part of our &#8220;Month of Action&#8221; here &#8212; a month-long campaign &#8212; it&#8217;s absolutely appropriate for them to do that, in our view.&nbsp;<br><br>As it relates to young people, you know, I think we&#8217;ll use some of the same tactics we&#8217;ve deployed with a range of communities &#8212; right? &#8212; which is trusted voices; which is ensuring, you know, if a college roommate or a college &#8212; a former college classmate got the vaccine and now can go out and feel safe going out to restaurants and concerts.&nbsp; That&#8217;s pretty effective, maybe even more so than the President of the United States appearing in their local newspaper.&nbsp; That will continue to be an area we invest.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also continued to make it as accessible as humanly possible.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something we can do from the federal government.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that as a barrier in the past.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made progress.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that as a barrier.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to do that as it relates to young people.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re also incentivizing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, it&#8217;s okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Okay, two questions.&nbsp; The first, on governors and governors&#8217; races.&nbsp; Across the country, you&#8217;ve been &#8212; you have a number of governors and candidates for governor who are becoming more and more explicitly anti-government in their rhetoric and rejecting the legitimacy of either the President or the federal government in general, in areas that are undoubtedly the federal government&#8217;s province, such as a Texas gubernatorial candidate saying he would close the borders.&nbsp; You have a guy in Idaho running for governor who has actually taken up arms against federal agents.&nbsp;<br><br>Is the administration concerned that actual violent extremists and people espousing secessionist rhetoric are finding a home in Republican primaries and could actually be elected to office?&nbsp; And then I have a second question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to label people &#8220;domestic violent extremists&#8221; officially from here.&nbsp; I think we have certainly seen problematic revetoric &#8212; rhetorics: followers of QAnon and conspiracy theories who not just &#8212; who don&#8217;t just run but are elected to office.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s already a record of that.<br><br>We&#8217;ll continue to speak out against that.&nbsp; But we will &#8212; our strategy at this point is to continue to advocate for how government can work for the American people; remind people across the country that this President is going to govern for all Americans, not just one &#8212; from one wing of a party or the other; and that, hopefully, the effectiveness of that is something that can help us play a constructive role.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a related follow-up: President Biden&#8217;s predecessor is going to return to his campaign-style rallies in Ohio this coming weekend.&nbsp; Has anyone from the administration reached out to Governor DeWine or anyone in Ohio&#8217;s government about the possibility of violence resulting from his return to the trail?&nbsp; And is there any concern about him going back out there and continuing to insist that the election is fraudulent and that he actually won could result in people being hurt or killed?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Obviously, we take the rhetoric of the &#8212; the other, the &#8212; the &#8220;former guy,&#8221; as we like to say, quite seriously, as everyone should.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any readouts or calls with Governor DeWine.&nbsp; I will see if there&#8217;s anything from our Homeland Security team to read out.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You mentioned that supply &#8212; going back to the vaccine announcement &#8212; was the main &#8212; was not the constraint.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was logistics.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On June 4th, Gayle Smith said that they expected the balance of 80 million &#8212; this 55 million &#8212; to come from the AstraZeneca shots.&nbsp; Those are obviously still under review.&nbsp; Should we infer from your comment that you now expect those 55 million to be from Pfizer and Moderna or Johnson &amp; Johnson?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always had a range of options &#8212; as we are contingency planners here &#8212; and we have plenty of supply to deliver on the 80 million doses.&nbsp; As you noted &#8212; or as you alluded to, my former &#8212; my answer previously, our biggest challenge is logistics &#8212; is the fact that there&#8217;s not a playbook for this.&nbsp; And there are challenges as it relates to getting these doses out to every country.&nbsp;<br><br>Certainly, obviously, once the FDA &#8212; if the FDA &#8212; if the FDA approves sending these AstraZeneca doses overseas, that would be a part of it.&nbsp; But until then, it wouldn&#8217;t be, of course.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have an estimate then on how many doses will be sent this month?&nbsp; Of course, the President Biden&#8217;s pledge initially was that 80 million would be sent this month, and now it will be &#8220;allocated&#8221; instead of &#8220;sent.&#8221;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update on that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I know the COVID team is doing a briefing tomorrow, but I will see if there&#8217;s more we can get back to you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I will be there.&nbsp; And I &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know you will be.&nbsp; A loyal attendee.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Indeed.&nbsp; And going &#8212; for the meeting this afternoon, one of &#8212; one subject I wonder if it&#8217;ll come up is cryptocurrency.&nbsp; Is that something the President is seeking the advice of the &#8212; the (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The agenda is exactly what I outlined earlier.&nbsp; And we will provide a readout once the meeting concludes about the topics.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And this is his first meeting with Jay Powell.&nbsp; Does he have confidence in the job Jay Powell is doing?&nbsp; Does he have any particular message for Powell in particular on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President&#8217;s view is this is a routine meeting with financial regulators to get an update on management of the economy and a range &#8212; and making credit accessible to people across the country.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just wanted to drill down, Jen, on the White House position on a vehicle mileage tax for electric vehicles.&nbsp; Can you explain the White House&#8217;s position and why you&#8217;d be opposed to &#8212; essentially, it would &#8212; wouldn&#8217;t it level set because people who fill up their cars with gasoline pay into the Highway Trust Fund with the 18.3 cent per gallon excise tax.&nbsp; People who drive electric vehicles drive on the same roads; they don&#8217;t pay that tax.&nbsp; Why not?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, the President wants to grow the electric vehicle industry, wants more people to buy electric vehicles, wants to make them accessible to people across the country.&nbsp; That will help our climate, help create jobs in that industry as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And his view is that there are plenty of ways to pay for these proposals, plenty of ways that will not leave the burden on any individuals across the country making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the choice, and he feels we should &#8212; we should have the burden on the wealthiest Americans, as opposed to any other Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the long-term structural impact then on the Highway Trust Fund if, as you hope, more Americans drive electric vehicles, fewer people fill up their cars with gasoline?&nbsp; How do you sustain that if fewer people are paying that excise tax overtime?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I suspect Secretary Pete has thought about this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to talk to him about it over the long term.&nbsp;<br><br>But, again, the purpose of this proposal is to move to electric vehicles, as an industry &#8212; where people are driving electric vehicles, making our climate &#8212; making our climate healthier, but also creating jobs in this industry that he feels is an industry of the future.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The President has been criticized for giving Putin a list of 16 critical infrastructure targets that&#8217;s considered off-limits to cyberattacks.&nbsp; How did that idea come about?&nbsp; And why not tell Putin that everything inside of the United States is off-limits?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I don&#8217;t think it required the President providing a list to &#8212; for President Putin or Russia to determine what is critical infrastructure in the United States.&nbsp; I know that has been part of the conspiracy response to his proposal.&nbsp;<br><br>The President was being clear: These are areas where, you know, we will be watching and we will reserve the option of consequences.&nbsp; That was the message he was sending during that meeting.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he put forward those specific examples.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And why didn&#8217;t he give Putin a list of targets inside of Russia that the United States would target if another cyberattack does take place in the United States?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because we don&#8217;t preview our punches.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And also &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last one question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen?&nbsp; Jen?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last question.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President believes that a 15-week-old, unborn baby is a human being?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Are you asking me if the President supports a woman&#8217;s right to choose?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he believe &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He does.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, another question, actually, on the summit last week with Putin.&nbsp; A State Department official, after the summit, said that the Havana Syndrome &#8212; these anomalous health incidents among U.S. personnel &#8212; had come up.&nbsp; It was referenced.&nbsp; Who referenced it to who?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more specifics from that meeting to read out for you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why would the topic come up if there&#8217;s no confidence in this building or with intelligence agencies as to the perpetrator?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t &#8212; we have not attributed, as you know.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more specifically on this topic from the meeting.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The White House reaction on Fulton versus the City of &#8212; White House reaction on the Supreme Court decision to Fulton versus the City of Philadelphia &#8212; does the White House have a reaction on that &#8212; on the case?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we have issued a reaction to it.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have anything more to it.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, and then the second question &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we got to move on.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead in the &#8212;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Multiple people &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, right there.&nbsp; Yep, go ahead, right &#8211;go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to follow up on the Geneva summit if I may.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What specifics step &#8212; steps is the administration is taking now to implement the understandings reached by President Biden and President Putin in Geneva?&nbsp; I&#8217;m especially interested, as you probably understand, in the potential dialogue on cyber &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and the strategic stability.&nbsp; Should we expect in-person interagency meetings on that, or are we talking about, you know, something online?&nbsp; Any idea about that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, so first let me say, the President did accomplish exactly what he wanted to accomplish in Geneva, which is identifying areas where the United States and Russia could work together in our mutual interest.&nbsp; We launched the strategic stability talks.&nbsp;<br><br>Part of their discussion was the fact that there will need to be a lot of follow-up on a level that is below the two leaders.&nbsp; So that &#8212; some of that could be at the Secretary of State; some of that will be before &#8212; underneath that.&nbsp; And those discussions will be happening or beginning in the weeks ahead.&nbsp; But that was the agreement between them, that there would be follow-up from their teams.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t have any more specific update.&nbsp; I expect you would get them &#8212; those updates from the State Department and others.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, well &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; But, actually, this woman right in front of you.&nbsp; I was trying to point to her, and then I&#8217;ll go to you next?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, no, no.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; right behind you.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Me?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, right there in the &#8212; did you have a question, right there in the polka-dot shirt?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got a question.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was just trying to &#8212; I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t tell.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, sorry.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the debt ceiling &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; there&#8217;s going to be fight coming up next month and they&#8217;ve been known to be &#8220;epic showdowns&#8221; on debt ceiling.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what is the President&#8217;s stance on raising the debt ceiling?&nbsp; And if it cannot &#8212; no agreement can be reached, will the Treasury Department take extraordinary measures?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President believes that Congress will do what they&#8217;ve done three times during the Trump administration, which is to raise the debt ceiling.&nbsp; We know that that will be a central focus and discussion, probably even in here, come the fall.&nbsp; But he expects they will do what they&#8217;ve done three times over the last.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The President said repeatedly on the campaign trail that he opposes defunding the police.&nbsp; He&#8217;s addressing rising crime across the country on Wednesday, and you mentioned this.&nbsp; What is the President&#8217;s message to some mayors who are considering reducing police budgets or already have reduced police budgets?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say person &#8212; the President&#8217;s implementation of the ARP &#8212; part of the funding that goes to late &#8212; local and state authorities is to ensure that there are police that are kept on the beat.&nbsp; Obviously, state and local authorities are going to determine how they spend that money, but, certainly, he included that funding because he feels it&#8217;s important to communities across the country.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, can I ask one more?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I was wondering if you would tell us about the President&#8217;s reaction &#8212; some Senate Republicans are delaying confirmation of his OPM nominee over fears that, if confirmed, she would incorporate what they see as detrimental critical race theory into federal directives.&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s response to that delay?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President believes that this is a qualified nominee, one the Senate should move forward expeditiously, so that we can ensure we have a full team in place across the government to continue to work with Democrats and Republicans in Congress.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Nadia.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just to follow up on Iran.&nbsp; An EU negotiator said, today, that they cleared on certain technical issues, but they still have problems on the political one.&nbsp; And some sources in Geneva &#8212; in Vienna, sorry, indicate that they might reach a deal by the middle of July.&nbsp; Is this optimistic?&nbsp; What&#8217;s your assessment of that?&nbsp; Can a deal be reached considering that re-election &#8212; or the election, rather, of the hardline President?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I don&#8217;t have a new deadline to set here.&nbsp; As you know because you follow this closely, they just finished their sixth round.&nbsp; It&#8217;s natural that they would be returning to capitals &#8212; the negotiators &#8212; to consult with their capitals and leaders in their capitals.&nbsp; That&#8217;s happening now.&nbsp;<br><br>Our view is that there is a decisionmaker here who &#8212; and that has not changed, and it is the Supreme Leader.&nbsp; So, we are going to continue to work to move these diplomatic negotiations forward because it&#8217;s in the interest of the United States and the interests of our national security, but I don&#8217;t have a new timeline to set for you.&nbsp;<br><br>But that &#8212; he’s been the decisionmaker before the election, after the election, and even after an inauguration.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You announced sanctions against Belarus today, which include visa restrictions, property assets designation, but previous reports suggested there would be economical targets, that the sanctions would be tougher.&nbsp; Why have you refrained from putting economic sanctions on Belarus, which would be more significant?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we just announced a huge number of sanctions, in coordination with our European partners to send a clear message that the behavior is unacceptable &#8212; not just the diversion of the Ryanair flight, but oppression &#8212; oppression of democracy within the country.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s something, again, we did in coordination with our partners, because we felt these would be the most effective means of sending that clear message.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why hasn&#8217;t the President nominated anyone to lead the FDA at this point?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s &#8212; this is a popular and understandable question.&nbsp; Certainly, he&#8217;s eager to have somebody who&#8217;s qualified and prepared to pl- &#8212; to take on the role.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s not going to expedite it until he&#8217;s ready to make a decision and make an announcement.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The U.S. Conference of Catholic Bishops is writing a document to clarify who should receive Communion.&nbsp; And this is targeted at politicians, people who have a high public profile.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s reaction to this?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Joe Biden is a strong man of faith.&nbsp; And as he noted just a couple of days ago, it&#8217;s personal.&nbsp; He goes to church, as you know, nearly every weekend.&nbsp; He even went when we were on our overseas trip.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s personal to him.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t see it through a political prism.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not going to comment otherwise on the inner workings of the Catholic Church.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would statements by the bishops make the President reconsider his public support for policies that, you know, increase access to abortion or allow access to abortion in the United States?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, that the President&#8217;s faith is personal.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something that has helped guide him through some challenging moments in his life.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how many Americans see their faith as well, not through a political prism.&nbsp; So I would suspect he will continue to attend church as he has for many, many years.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he realize that &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jonathan.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; his stance on abortion runs contradictory to U.S. CCB teachings?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to move on to the next question because I&#8217;ve just answered that and it&#8217;s personal.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; There’s a gubernatorial election in New Jersey: Governor Murphy is running for reelection.&nbsp; He endorsed the President last time and raised money for him.&nbsp; Is the President going to help Governor Murphy win reelection this fall?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly he&#8217;d be eager to see him win&nbsp; reelection, of course, and be a &#8212; continue to be an important partner in the state of New Jersey as we work to address &#8212; continue to address the pandemic, get people back to work.&nbsp; In terms of what his specific political plans are, I will &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, one more question about Iran &#8212; on Ebrahim Raisi, the new President-elect.&nbsp; He has said that he&#8217;s accusing the U.S. of breaking promises, saying, quote, “Based on the nuclear deal, you are obligated to lift the sanctions and you did not fulfill your commitment.”&nbsp; What does the President have to say about that?&nbsp; And then, secondly, he&#8217;s under U.S. sanctions for the 1988 political prisoner executions.&nbsp; So, how do you deal with him?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that the new President will, of course, be held accountable for violations of human rights on his watch going forward.&nbsp; We strongly urge the Iranian government, regardless of who&#8217;s in power, to release political prisoners, improve respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms for all Iranians.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, again, I would note &#8212; and let me just say, on the sanctions piece, that, as we&#8217;re in these discussions &#8212; in the middle of these discussions, after the sixth round, the precise nature and sequence of the sanc- &#8212; sanctions-related steps the United States would take &#8212; would need to take to achieve a mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA is a subject of the talks and of the discussions.&nbsp;<br><br>And we certainly understand, as we&#8217;ve seen in past rounds of these negotiations, that there will be a range of rhetoric to address political needs at home; we understand that.&nbsp; But our focus remains on these negotiations that we look forward to continuing to participate in.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow-up on that, Jen, if you don’t mind?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; So, even if you manage to reach a nuclear deal or a deal with the Iranians on nuclear deal reentry, Republicans in Congress could force a vote to block sanctions relief, forcing the Democrats who are still in office &#8212; including Majority Leader Schumer, who voted against the original deal when it was negotiated.&nbsp; So are you confident you have the votes in Congress to relieve sanctions and reenter the nuclear deal?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there isn&#8217;t even a deal yet, right?&nbsp; So I understand why you&#8217;re asking that question, but it&#8217;s a little bit ahead of where we are.&nbsp; May we have a deal where we can have that discussion.&nbsp;<br><br>The important case that we are going to continue to make is that Iran is not a good actor in the world on a range of issues, whether it&#8217;s human rights or their engagement in the region.&nbsp; That continues to be the case and would be even after &#8212; if we get to the point where we have a deal.&nbsp;<br><br>But what is in the interest of the United States?&nbsp; What&#8217;s interest &#8212; in the interests of the United States is having that return to visibility, that return to an understanding of what their capabilities are, how close they are to acquiring a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp;<br><br>When we get to a point, if we get to the point when there&#8217;s a deal, we&#8217;re happy to have the discussion about the legislative vote count.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I thought you didn&#8217;t take my question, and so (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; President Biden recently announced that the U.S. will provide corona vaccine to North Korea.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know how many doses?&nbsp; And what kind of a vaccine are you going to provide to North Korea?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, we announced that we would be providing about [half] a billion doses to the global community and the 92 countries, working through COVAX for 75 percent of it, who are the lowest- and middle-income countries in the world. &nbsp;That&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve announced, but I don&#8217;t have any more details than that. &nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead in the back.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think we’re at an hour.<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, we’ll go to this last one since I just called on him, and then we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll wrap it up.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Representing an audience that is quite different from this gentleman&#8217;s, I&#8217;d like to repeat his question: The U.S. Supreme Court decision in City of Philadelphia v. Fulton, you said that the White House issued a reaction to that; I don&#8217;t believe that is the case.&nbsp; Was the President briefed on that decision?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I thought we had.&nbsp; If not, I will get that to you and to this gentleman over here.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks, everyone, so much.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll do this again tomorrow.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>2:00 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum for the Secretary of State on the Delegation of Certain Authorities and Functions Under Section 353 of the United States – Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/21/memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-state-on-the-delegation-of-certain-authorities-and-functions-under-section-353-of-the-united-states-northern-triangle-enhanced-engagement-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 22:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State all authorities and functions vested in the President by section 353 of the United States – Northern Triangle Enhanced&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State all authorities and functions vested in the President by section 353 of the United States – Northern Triangle Enhanced Engagement Act (Subtitle F of Title III of Division FF of Public Law 116-260) (the &#8220;Act&#8221;).<br><br>Any reference herein to the Act related to the subject of this memorandum shall be deemed to include references to any hereafter-enacted provisions of law that are the same or substantially the same as such provisions.<br><br>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
