<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 19:46:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration&#8217;s Work to Lower Healthcare&#160;Costs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-biden-harris-administrations-work-to-lower-healthcare-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 19:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47089</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Germanna Community CollegeCulpeper, Virginia 12:49 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Mr. President.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I could have no more have done that when I was 12 years old than fly.&#160; I used to be a stutterer.&#160; I was scared to death I would stand up and ta-ta &#8212; ta-ta-talk &#8212; talk like that.&#160; And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Germanna Community College<br>Culpeper, Virginia</p>



<p>12:49 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I could have no more have done that when I was 12 years old than fly.&nbsp; I used to be a stutterer.&nbsp; I was scared to death I would stand up and ta-ta &#8212; ta-ta-talk &#8212; talk like that.&nbsp; And I can’t tell you how much &#8212; how proud I am of you.&nbsp; And your brother is equally as impressive as you are.&nbsp; He’s standing there &#8212; he&#8217;s sitting there two seats over.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Shannon and Joshua &#8212; and, by the way, Happy Birthday, man.&nbsp; He’s going to be 13 years old &#8212; a teenager &#8212; in a couple days.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I want you to know that lowering the cost of prescription drugs is one of the reasons why I’m here with Abigail, your congresswoman.&nbsp; And that’s what I want to talk about with you today.&nbsp; Lowering the cost of healthcare overall, as well.&nbsp; Lowering the cost of prescription drugs is important.&nbsp; And giving families like yours just a little bit more breathing room makes a gigantic difference.</p>



<p>Before I get into that, I want to say: It’s good to be here at Germanna school.&nbsp; And, by the way, Abigail, if I wanted to know anything about community colleges in Virginia, I go to my wife.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She teaches full-time and has for the last nine years.&nbsp; She’s in the classroom now at &#8212; at a community college in Northern Virginia &#8212; Northern Virginia Community College.</p>



<p>And she says &#8212; she says, “You know, the single best-kept secret in America is community colleges.”&nbsp; And it really is.&nbsp; They are so flexible.&nbsp; They can do so much &#8212; so much.&nbsp; And if I had more time &#8212; which I don’t &#8212; for all of you, I’d go into what we’re going to try to do to increase the flexibility and the funding of community colleges for people.</p>



<p>But it’s great to be here with Abigail &#8212; with Congresswoman Spanberger.</p>



<p>In every chapter of her career &#8212; in every chapter, she’s always been about one thing: service.&nbsp; Service.</p>



<p>I also want to thank Mark Warner and Tim Kaine, who &#8212; senators here &#8212; are good friends and worked closely with me on so many things when I was a senator and now as President and when I was Vice President.&nbsp; But they needed to be in Washington today because there’s votes in the Senate.</p>



<p>I also want to thank Secretary of Health and Human Services Xavier Becerra for two things.&nbsp; One, for answering my call when I asked him to come and be the Secretary.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I was worried he wouldn’t.&nbsp; And how much he’s helped us make so much progress in getting people vaccinated, getting health insurance, and making more affordable healthcare.</p>



<p>Look, healthcare is part of Abigail &#8212; congresswoman &#8212; your congresswoman’s background.&nbsp; Back in 2017, she saw her representatives in Congress vote to repeal the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; That was one of more than 100 Republican efforts &#8212; there were 100 Republican efforts since we passed it in our last administration to repeal the Affordable Care Act.</p>



<p>But she knew that that was the exact opposite of what central Virginia badly needed.&nbsp; You needed then and you need now more access to quality healthcare that is more affordable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when I became President of the United States, that’s what we did.&nbsp; We passed the American Rescue Plan, which made quality coverage through the Affordable Care Act more affordable than ever before, with families saving, on average, who have signed up &#8212; a family, on average &#8212; $2,400 a year in their annual premiums.</p>



<p>Compared to last year, the average monthly premium for Virginia &#8212; for Virginians has gone down more than 25 percent.</p>



<p>Over 5 million people have gained coverage through the ACA since I became President.&nbsp; As was mentioned by Xavier, over 300,000 Virginians have signed up for health insurance during open enrollment period here in Virginia.</p>



<p>And we want to go further: lowering prescription drug prices; get a cap on the amount people pay on Medicare, pay for prescription drugs; and to bring more clarity and fewer surprises when you get your bills if you&#8217;ve been hospitalized.</p>



<p>So, let me say a few words about each of these things now.</p>



<p>With regard to prescription drugs: In America, we pay the highest prescription drug prices of any nation &#8212; developed nation in the world &#8212; the highest of any.&nbsp; And it’s about two to three times higher than what other countries pay.</p>



<p>Let me give you one example.&nbsp; An anti-cancer drug to treat leukemia and lymphoma costs $14,000 a month in the United States.&nbsp; The same exact drug, made by the same exact pharmaceutical company, is sold in France and it&#8217;s $6,000 a month.&nbsp; $6,000 for the same exact drug, same exact manufacturer, same exact amounts.&nbsp; Not 14, but 6.&nbsp; That’s for a month’s supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, one in four Americans who need prescription drugs struggle to afford them &#8212; one in four.&nbsp; Nearly 30 percent have skipped doses of essential drugs they&#8217;re supposed to take.&nbsp; Others have simply not filled prescriptions that the doctor had given them; tried to use over-the-counter drugs or pills cut in half because they can’t afford the cost of their prescription.</p>



<p>This is the United States of America, for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp; That’s just wrong.&nbsp; It&#8217;s simply wrong, especially since it doesn&#8217;t cost the drug companies nearly, nearly, nearly, nearly as much to make the drug or the research that went into them.</p>



<p>Let me regress for just a moment here.&nbsp; I started when &#8212; in the Obama-Biden administration an effort to deal with the Cancer Moonshot to change the way in which we deal with cancer.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m reinstituting that in my administration now.</p>



<p>And it was interesting.&nbsp; I met &#8212; we had these hearings all over the United States.&nbsp; And one of the major events we did, we &#8212; at Howard University, where there were 35 other events going on simultaneously with this.&nbsp; I had subsequently met with the heads of &#8212; I think it was 13 drug companies.</p>



<p>And I asked them &#8212; I said, &#8220;If you found a cure for a particular cancer, how much you think you should be able to charge?&#8221;&nbsp; And the response universally was, &#8220;What the market will bear.&#8221;</p>



<p>I said, &#8220;Hope I don&#8217;t get elected President, because that&#8217;s just not &#8212; what you&#8217;ll get should be treated more like a utility.&#8221;&nbsp; You should be able to make a significant progress for &#8212; let&#8217;s add up how much &#8212; and like they do in Germany &#8212; how much did it cost you all, the research and development &#8212; all the effort.&nbsp; Add it all up.&nbsp; And then, on top of that, add a significant premium for it &#8212; a profit of 20 to 30 percent above that.&nbsp; Maybe, in some cases, more.</p>



<p>But the idea &#8212; the idea you can charge whatever you want is just not going to happen in the United States of America if I have anything to do with it.</p>



<p>If you think this doesn’t affect you, it does, by the way.&nbsp; Everyone has less money in their pockets today because of high drug pric- &#8212; drug costs and health insurance.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s more expensive for everyone.</p>



<p>And the reason it is, is this is what your insurance companies pay.&nbsp; Every &#8212; all of you who have insurance, you&#8217;re paying a heck of a lot more even if you&#8217;re not using the drugs.</p>



<p>Over the past decade, healthcare costs have gone up 50 percent.&nbsp; Prescription drugs are a big chunk of that.</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s a lot of things that almost every American can agree on.&nbsp; But I think it’s safe to say that all of us &#8212; whatever our background, our age, where we live, whether we agree on prescription drugs &#8212; look, we all acknowledge they&#8217;re outrageously expensive, and in many cases, there is no relationship to cost.</p>



<p>It doesn’t need to be that way.</p>



<p>Josh and Shannon, it costs drug companies less than $10 to make a vial of that insulin.&nbsp; Less than 10 bucks.&nbsp; That’s what it costs.</p>



<p>There’s no reason you should be paying over $300 a vial for medicine you need every day to stay healthy and, in many cases, stay alive.</p>



<p>As your mom said, you got to pay $5,600 for prescriptions before your insurance even kicks in.&nbsp; You got to do the deductible.</p>



<p>Shannon, you should have peace of mind of knowing that if Joshua grows up and leaves your care &#8212; your healthcare plan, he’ll be able to choose a job without ever having to make a choice between which one has the particular healthcare coverage.</p>



<p>You know, we’re now in a position where we can cap co-pays for insulin at $35 a month.&nbsp; And it’s still a staggering profit: three and half times what it costs to produce the drug.</p>



<p>You can do that with a stroke of a &#8212; we can do that with a stroke of a pen.</p>



<p>In my Build Back Better legislation that with Abigail’s leadership passed in the House of Representatives, we can do that.&nbsp; Now we just have to get through the United States Senate, and we’re close.</p>



<p>We can do even more to lower out-of-pocket prescription costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under my proposal, we will hold drug companies accountable for the absurd price increases.&nbsp; Here’s how: Drug companies that increase their prices faster than the rate of inflation, once the price is set, will face a steep tax.</p>



<p>This will help us end the days when drug companies could increase their prices with no oversight, no accountability, and no responsibility.</p>



<p>We’re saying to drug companies: You are finally going to become accountable when you raise prices on the American people.&nbsp; Accountability.</p>



<p>You&#8217;re still going to make a significant profit.</p>



<p>And we can take additional steps to lower drug costs for people with Medicare &#8212; something Abigail has championed.</p>



<p>Right now, the only thing Medicare is not allowed to negotiate the price of are prescription drugs.</p>



<p>For everything else covered by Medicare &#8212; a doctor’s visits &#8212; they negotiate and say, “We’ll pay no more than this much for a doctor’s visit.”&nbsp; So if the doctors don’t want to take any Medicare patients, they don’t have to.&nbsp; But if they have a Medicare patient, which there are millions of them, they cannot charge more than a certain amount.&nbsp; Crutches &#8212; we limit the amount of money they can pay for crutches.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But &#8212; but Medicare can negotiate everything except drug prices.&nbsp; The only outfit that can&#8217;t do &#8212; they &#8212; they can&#8217;t deal with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My plan is going to allow Medicare to negotiate the prices they&#8217;re prepared to pay for each individual drug.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the company says, “I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to sell it to you at that price,” fine, but they&#8217;re going to lose millions of customers.&nbsp; Millions of customers.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re proposing &#8212; what we’re proposing is that we negotiate fair prices &#8212; one that reflects the cost of research and development and the need for significant profit, but still is affordable and has some relationship to the cost the drug company had.</p>



<p>My plan also caps the amount that seniors on Medicare have to spend on prescription drugs each year total, so that if they’re on Medicare, they’ll not have to spend out of pocket more than $2,000 a year, no matter how many drugs they’re taking, with drug companies, insurance companies, and medicine &#8212; and Medicare picking up the rest of the cost.</p>



<p>And just last month, to bring greater transparency to healthcare costs, my administration outlawed surprise billing.</p>



<p>I’ve had significant experience with hospital care.&nbsp; My son Beau, who was Attorney General of Delaware and a &#8212; won the Bronze Star in Iraq &#8212; and, I mean, excuse me, in &#8212; in dealing with being deployed overseas for a long time, for a year.&nbsp; You know, he &#8212; he came back with glioblastoma, and he died.</p>



<p>But you know what?&nbsp; You know, the fact is that &#8212; and I &#8212; I was hospitalized a long time.&nbsp; I had, a couple years ago, a cranial aneurism, was hospitalized for a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you can no longer get that surprise billings we got.&nbsp; If your healthcare plan did not cover a particular doctor but you didn’t even know he was being consulted and you get an extra bill for two to five thousand dollars &#8212; they can’t do that anymore.&nbsp; No more surprise billing.&nbsp; No more.</p>



<p>Millions of hardworking Americans will no longer have to worry about unexpected medical bills.&nbsp; And Abigail has been making sure that we bring the same transparency to drug prices.</p>



<p>A couple of years ago, Abigail worked to pass bipartisan legislation to make drug prices more transparent so you knew what you’re paying for.&nbsp; And my administration is working with Abigail to make sure we enforce that.</p>



<p>She also has been relentless in making sure the law that’s been on the books that says pharmaceutical companies need to provide rural clinics and community health centers with discounts on prescription drugs is actually enforced.&nbsp; And we’re working together on that as well.</p>



<p>I’ve long said healthcare should be a right, not a privilege, in this country.&nbsp; This isn’t a parti- &#8212; diabetes, Alzheimer’s, cancer &#8212; they’re not partisan issues.&nbsp; They’re not Democrat or Republican.</p>



<p>This is about &#8212; this is about whether or not you and your loved ones can afford the healthcare you need and the medi- &#8211; and the medicines you need to stay healthy, because we need to ease the burden on working families by making everything more affordable and accessible.</p>



<p>Look, again, slight digression: Inflation is up.&nbsp; It’s up.&nbsp; And coming from a family when the price of gas went up, you felt it in the household, you knew what it was like, it matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the fact is that, if we’re able to do the things I’m talking about here, it’ll bring down the costs for average families.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll bring down the costs for average families.&nbsp; I don’t know why they keep moving all that, but the fact is: They keep down the costs for average families.</p>



<p>And, look, the fact is that we’re in a situation now where, you know, you should have peace of mind.&nbsp; I know food prices are up, and we’re working to bring them down.</p>



<p>As I said, I grew up in a family where the price at the pump went up, you felt it.&nbsp; And I understand.&nbsp; But these things are necessities.&nbsp; We’re working to bring down prices where there are not totally what families, in fact, have to pay now.</p>



<p>You still have pay to for childcare.&nbsp; Childcare is a cost for millions of families.&nbsp; You still have to pay your prescription drug prices.&nbsp; You still have to pay for healthcare.</p>



<p>You want to lower the cost of living for people?&nbsp; Help them in those areas.</p>



<p>So, there’s more than one way for a family, when it comes to raising their standard of living.</p>



<p>I’m going to work like the devil to bring gas prices down, which I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I&#8217;m working to make sure that we keep strengthening the supply chains to bring the cost of energy and everything else and the goods that come to America down by helping the ports 24/7, by changing a whole range of things that &#8212;</p>



<p>You know, what&#8217;s happened with COVID &#8212; COVID has caused significant increase in prices in the supply chain, because when a factory shuts down in another part of the world and you need that particular product in order to finish and build whatever you’re working on, the price goes up exponentially, like for cars.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in the meantime, there is a lot we can do to give families extra breathing room.&nbsp; We can do this when we cut the cost of childcare, making sure that you don&#8217;t pay more than 7 percent of a family’s income for childcare.&nbsp; That saves thousands of dollars in families &#8212; for families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Shannon, think about what these plans would mean for you and your family.</p>



<p>We’re &#8212; already made a lot of progress on the economy.&nbsp; Last year, more jobs were created in America than in any year in American history.</p>



<p>Unemployment has dropped more than any year in American history.</p>



<p>We reduced the deficit &#8212; the federal deficit, while doing those &#8212; both those things, by $300 billion.</p>



<p>We lowered child poverty by nearly 40 percent in America, more than any year in American history, as a consequence of the Child Tax Credit.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re coming out at these challenges from a position of strength unmatched by any nation in the world.&nbsp; And I might add, and I note here just to all of you, that this does not raise anyone&#8217;s &#8212; if you&#8217;re making less $400,000, you&#8217;re not paying a single penny more in taxes &#8212; not a single penny more in taxes.&nbsp; And it does not increase the deficit because it&#8217;s paid for.&nbsp; It&#8217;s fully paid for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve had a group of major companies, from Intel to General Motors to Ford to &#8212; down across the board &#8212; come to me and say they want to keep these programs going, increase corporate taxes to 24 percent, which they were supposed to be.&nbsp; It gets paid for.&nbsp; They understand the net effect on the economy is to grow it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know that when we invest in ourselves, there&#8217;s no limit to what we can achieve with leaders like Abigail and the brave folks like Shannon and Joshua.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of you know here today that all this progress we&#8217;ve made is going to be just the beginning &#8212; just the beginning.&nbsp; I promise you we&#8217;re going to do so much more, and it will not &#8212; I emphasize, it will not increase the debt.&nbsp; It will not increase taxes on anyone making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; You should be able to make a million or a billion dollars.&nbsp; Just pay a little bit of your fair share.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have over 53 companies in America that made $40 billion last year &#8212; didn&#8217;t pay a single penny in taxes.&nbsp; Not a single penny.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not right.</p>



<p>And so, you find that a lot of these corporations realize: To grow and be competitive, it makes sense just to pay a little more in taxes at the top end in order to afford this economic growth we&#8217;re creating.</p>



<p>But bringing down the cost of healthcare, bringing down the cost of prescription drugs is an easy thing for us to do.&nbsp; It can be done legally with a stroke of a pen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We just got to get Abigail&#8217;s enthusiasm that she gotten it through in the House of Representatives to the United States Senate.&nbsp; So, we may be dragging you over to the Senate to spend some time.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, there&#8217;s so much we can do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank the family for being willing to stand up here and share their story.&nbsp; And, Dad, stand up so everybody knows who you are.&nbsp; I want them to see you.&nbsp; That good-looking guy back there, that&#8217;s Dad.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Every time I&#8217;d walk out of my grandpop&#8217;s house up in Scranton, Pennsylvania &#8212; his name was Ambrose Finnegan; he was an All-American football player out in Santa Clara when he was a kid &#8212; and he used to always yell, &#8220;Joey, keep the faith.&#8221;&nbsp; And my grandmother would yell &#8212; she&#8217;d yell back, &#8220;No, Joey, spread it.&#8221;&nbsp; Let&#8217;s spread the faith and get this done.</p>



<p>Thank you very, very much.  Appreciate it.  (Applause.) </p>



<p>1:09 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to Attend the Bicentennial Celebration of the Arrival of the First Free Black Americans to the Republic of&#160;Liberia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-attend-the-bicentennial-celebration-of-the-arrival-of-the-first-free-black-americans-to-the-republic-of-liberia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Liberia to attend the Bicentennial Celebrations in Monrovia, Liberia on February 14, 2022.&#160; This marks the arrival of the first Free Black Americans to Providence Island in 1822, which led to the establishment of the City of Monrovia,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Liberia to attend the Bicentennial Celebrations in Monrovia, Liberia on February 14, 2022.&nbsp; This marks the arrival of the first Free Black Americans to Providence Island in 1822, which led to the establishment of the City of Monrovia, and in 1847, the Republic ofLiberia.</p>



<p><a></a><a></a>The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong></p>



<p>The Honorable Michael A. McCarthy, United States Ambassador to the</p>



<p>Republic of Liberia</p>



<p>The Honorable Dana Banks, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Africa, National Security Council</p>



<p>Mr. Lonnie G. Bunch III, Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution</p>



<p>Rev. Dr. Teresa Jefferson-Snorton, Bishop of the Fifth Episcopal District of the Christian Methodist Episcopal Church, Chair of the Governing Board, National Council of Churches in the United States</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Houthi Attack Against Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-houthi-attack-against-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 16:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States strongly condemns today’s terrorist attack against Abha in Saudi Arabia, which injured at least a dozen innocent civilians. &#160;The Houthis have claimed responsibility for this attack, and we will work with our Saudi and international partners to hold them accountable. &#160; As the President told His Majesty King Salman yesterday, we are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States strongly condemns today’s terrorist attack against Abha in Saudi Arabia, which injured at least a dozen innocent civilians. &nbsp;The Houthis have claimed responsibility for this attack, and we will work with our Saudi and international partners to hold them accountable. &nbsp; As the President told His Majesty King Salman yesterday, we are committed to supporting Saudi Arabia in the defense of its people and territory from these attacks. &nbsp;America will have the backs of our friends in the region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRICES WEEK FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Plan to Boost the Capacity of the Economy and Lower Costs for Working&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/prices-week-fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-plan-to-boost-the-capacity-of-the-economy-and-lower-costs-for-working-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 16:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Administration this week is highlighting its comprehensive strategy to boost the capacity of the economy and lower costs for working families – from addressing supply chain bottlenecks, to making our economy more competitive, and pushing for legislation to ease everyday costs and make more in America. The President will speak to that this afternoon&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>The Administration this week is highlighting its comprehensive strategy to boost the capacity of the economy and lower costs for working families – from addressing supply chain bottlenecks, to making our economy more competitive, and pushing for legislation to ease everyday costs and make more in America. The President will speak to that this afternoon in Virginia, where he’ll discuss how we can lower the price of prescription drugs for working Americans.</em></p>



<p>Thanks in part to President Biden’s American Rescue Plan, the U.S. is in the midst of a historic economic recovery. In 2021, we saw the strongest monthly job growth ever recorded, the largest decline in unemployment ever recorded, the strongest economic growth in four decades, and an estimated nearly 40 percent decline in child poverty. Despite this progress, the U.S., along with much of the world, is grappling with elevated price increases brought on by the pandemic. These price increases hit families’ budgets, and create anxiety about the future. While experts expect inflation to moderate in the months ahead, President Biden is taking action now.</p>



<p>President Biden’s plan starts with respecting the Federal Reserve’s independence to keep elevated price increases from becoming entrenched. The Federal Reserve provided extraordinary support during the crisis. Given the strength of our recovery, and the pace of recent price increases, it is appropriate for them to recalibrate that support.</p>



<p>Beyond the Fed, the President believes that the most important thing he and Congress can do is build a more productive economy – with greater capacity to deliver goods and services to the American people. He does not agree with those who believe that the only solution is to make working families that are the backbone of our country poorer. Instead, the President is focused on building a growing economy, where folks have more choices, where more small businesses can compete, and where more goods get to market faster and cheaper. That means expanding the supply-side of the economy, over the short-, medium-, and long-term. Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration is:<br></p>



<p><strong><u>Fixing our supply chains and infrastructure, and making more in the United States</u></strong>.</p>



<p>The Administration is restoring American manufacturing and rebuilding American infrastructure, so we can make more here at home and move goods more efficiently and reliably through the economy. In February, the President issued an Executive Order to strengthen our supply chains, and in June established the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-supply-chain-disruptions-task-force-to-address-short-term-supply-chain-discontinuities/">Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force</a> to bring a whole-of-government approach to addressing the immediate disruptions linked to the global pandemic. The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/bipartisan-infrastructure-law/">President Biden’s historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</a> will provide the funding needed to close vulnerabilities and improve efficiency at our ports, roads, waterways, and railroads. &nbsp;The Administration is focused on addressing challenges and boosting capacity in three key sectors: transportation, semiconductors, and agriculture.</p>



<ul><li>In <strong>the transportation sector</strong>, in 2021 the Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach—which process 40 percent of the nation’s containerized imports—broke their 2018 record for annual containerized imports by 13 percent. After working with the Biden-Harris Administration, they also reduced the number of containers sitting on the docks for 9 days or more by 60 percent. Thanks in part to the Administration’s efforts, American retailers’ shelves were well stocked for the record-breaking holiday season and 97 to 99 percent of consumers received their packages on time or with minimal delays. The Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/09/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-action-plan-for-americas-ports-and-waterways/">Ports Action Plan</a> and a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-%E2%81%A0harris-administration-trucking-action-plan-to-strengthen-americas-trucking-workforce/">Trucking Action Plan</a> are helping American port operators move a record amount of goods from ships to shelves as quickly as possible and connect more Americans to good jobs in the trucking industry. And by investing in our longer-term infrastructure needs, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will help make our transportation system more effective and make it easier and cheaper for businesses to move goods to market.<br><br></li><li>In <strong>the</strong> <strong>semiconductor sector</strong>, the Administration is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-bringing-semiconductor-manufacturing-back-to-america-2/">working to expand U.S. chip manufacturing capacity</a>, bring back American manufacturing jobs, address the chip shortage, and ensure we are not exposed to these disruptions again. Auto inflation – caused in part by the global semiconductor shortage – has caused around a third of the core inflation we’ve seen in the last year. But the Administration is making important progress. In just the last few weeks, Intel and GM announced they are building new chip and EV manufacturing plants right here in the United States.&nbsp; To accelerate this progress, the President is urging Congress to pass legislation to strengthen U.S. research and development and manufacturing for critical supply chains, including semiconductors.<br><br></li><li>In <strong>the agriculture and meat processing sector</strong>, the Administration is providing financing to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/03/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-action-plan-for-a-fairer-more-competitive-and-more-resilient-meat-and-poultry-supply-chain/">expand independent food processing capacity and support workers</a>; strengthening rules that protect farmers, ranchers, and consumers; and expanding access to affordable, high-quality food for those in need, including in <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/01/07/usda-announces-increased-funding-support-school-meals-and-help">schools</a>.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Fighting to lower kitchen table costs</u></strong>.</p>



<p>Even before the COVID-19 pandemic, too many working families felt the squeeze of an ever-increasing cost of living. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda is the most significant effort to bring down costs and strengthen the middle class in generations. In addition to major investments in children and care, climate, and health, the framework includes targeted investments that will help lower the costs families pay right away. For example, Build Back Better will lower the cost of health care, child care, and prescription drugs and provide access to free preschool for all three and four year-olds. These investments are paid for, and will increase our economy’s capacity over time by getting more people working and lowering costs families struggle with. President Biden is focused on working with Congress to enact these proposals as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>­­</p>



<p><strong><u>Protecting consumers and promoting competition</u></strong>.</p>



<p>The decades-long trend of corporate consolidation in many sectors of our economy has left consumers, innovators, and our economy worse off. Lack of competition drives up prices for consumers, with families paying higher prices for prescription drugs, hearing aids, internet service, and more.&nbsp; President Biden is focused on promoting competition to make our economy more productive, boost growth and innovation, and generate lower prices and more options for consumers. In July, the President <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">signed a historic Executive Order</a> establishing a whole-of-government effort to boost competition in the American economy. The Order includes 72 initiatives by more than a dozen federal agencies to promptly tackle some of the most pressing competition problems across our economy. For example, in October the Food and Drug Administration released a new proposed rule that would make it possible for hearing aids to be sold over the counter without a prescription, which is expected to save people hundreds of dollars.<br><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on January Consumer Price Index&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/statement-by-president-biden-on-january-consumer-price-index-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 15:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My two top economic priorities have been to create a growing economy with more good-paying jobs, and to lower the prices Americans have faced from the global problem of inflation related to the pandemic. We have seen historic success on the first priority, with the greatest year of job growth in history, Americans finding better&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>My two top economic priorities have been to create a growing economy with more good-paying jobs, and to lower the prices Americans have faced from the global problem of inflation related to the pandemic. We have seen historic success on the first priority, with the greatest year of job growth in history, Americans finding better jobs, better wages, and better benefits, along with the fastest economic growth in decades. On higher prices, we have been using every tool at our disposal, and while today is a reminder that Americans’ budgets are being stretched in ways that create real stress at the kitchen table, there are also signs that we will make it through this challenge.</p>



<p>While today’s report is elevated, forecasters continue to project inflation easing substantially by the end of 2022. And fortunately we saw positive real wage growth last month, and moderation in auto prices, which have made up about a quarter of headline inflation over the last year. We separately saw good news with new unemployment claims continuing to decline. That’s a sign of the real progress we’ve made in getting Americans back to work over the last year.</p>



<p>My administration will continue to be all hands on deck to win this fight. We will continue to rebuild our infrastructure and manufacturing, so we can make more in America and strengthen our supply chains here at home. We will continue to fight to lower costs in areas that have held back families and working people for decades, from prescription drugs to child care and elder care to their energy costs. And we will continue to promote more competition to make our markets more competitive and give consumers more choices.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the United&#160;States Hosting APEC in&#160;2023</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-united-states-hosting-apec-in-2023/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re proud that the United States will be the host of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) in 2023, underscoring our commitment to advance fair and open trade and investment, bolster American competitiveness, and ensure a free and open Indo-Pacific. President Biden and Vice President Harris offered to host APEC next year because of our focus&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We’re proud that the United States will be the host of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) in 2023, underscoring our commitment to advance fair and open trade and investment, bolster American competitiveness, and ensure a free and open Indo-Pacific. President Biden and Vice President Harris offered to host APEC next year because of our focus on expanding and deepening economic ties in the region – and we thank our fellow APEC economies for supporting the U.S. offer to host.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is a top priority for the Biden-Harris Administration to serve as a strong, reliable partner to APEC economies and identify common ways to unleash economic opportunity, prosperity, and growth for us all. Secretary of Commerce Raimondo, United States Trade Representative Ambassador Tai, and our team are working to develop with our partners an Indo-Pacific economic framework that will define our shared objectives around issues vital to our future, including trade facilitation, standards for the digital economy and technology, supply chain resiliency, decarbonization and clean energy, infrastructure, and worker standards.&nbsp;Secretary of State Blinken is also in the region this week to continue strengthening key diplomatic relationships and advancing our shared priorities.</p>



<p>The United States looks forward to working closely with Thailand, the 2022 APEC host, Peru, the 2024 APEC host, and all of the APEC economies on an agenda that benefits all our people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan Meeting with Israeli National Security Advisor Eyal&#160;Hulata</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-meeting-with-israeli-national-security-advisor-eyal-hulata/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan hosted Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata at the White House on Feb. 9 to consult on a range of global and issues of mutual concern. They underscored their shared determination to address security challenges impacting the Middle East, including the threats posed by Iran and its proxies. Mr. Sullivan&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan hosted Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata at the White House on Feb. 9 to consult on a range of global and issues of mutual concern. They underscored their shared determination to address security challenges impacting the Middle East, including the threats posed by Iran and its proxies. Mr. Sullivan reiterated President Biden’s unwavering support to Israel’s security and to ensuring Iran never obtains a nuclear weapon. The National Security Advisors also exchanged views on security challenges outside the Middle East, including the potential for further Russian aggression against Ukraine. They discussed as well ways to deepen U.S.-Israeli cooperation on science and innovation. Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Hulata agreed to maintain the close coordination between their interagency teams on a range of global and regional security challenges.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the President’s Meeting With Utility CEOs Who Support the Climate and Clean Energy Investments in Build Back&#160;Better</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/readout-of-the-presidents-meeting-with-utility-ceos-who-support-the-climate-and-clean-energy-investments-in-build-back-better/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon, the President hosted 10 electric utility executives at the White House for a discussion about his Build Back Better (BBB) agenda to modernize America’s energy system and meet the moment on climate.&#160; These electric utilities &#8211; that collectively employ more than a hundred thousand Americans in communities across the country and provide power&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This afternoon, the President hosted 10 electric utility executives at the White House for a discussion about his Build Back Better (BBB) agenda to modernize America’s energy system and meet the moment on climate.&nbsp; These electric utilities &#8211; that collectively employ more than a hundred thousand Americans in communities across the country and provide power to more than 50 million homes and businesses every day – offered their overwhelming support for the climate and clean energy investments in BBB.</p>



<p>The President thanked these leaders for their support and had a detailed conversation with them about their shared conviction that Build Back Better would support good jobs, lower energy bills for American families, make our electric grid more reliable in the face of extreme weather, enhance U.S. competitiveness, boost economic growth, and reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</p>



<p>The CEOs in attendance spoke about how Build Back Better would make our country more globally competitive by investing in energy innovation, make our electric grid more reliable by investing in transmission, and support the growing number of electric vehicles Americans are buying. They also expressed that, while they may not agree with every aspect of the President’s agenda, they firmly support investments in climate and clean energy.</p>



<p>The climate and clean energy provisions in Build Back Better are a comprehensive set of investments to get America on track to reach the President’s goal of 100% clean electricity by 2035, and he appreciates the partnership of these top electric utility CEOs in that effort.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Roundtable with CEOs of Electric Utilities to Discuss His Build Back Better&#160;Agenda</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-roundtable-with-ceos-of-electric-utilities-to-discuss-his-build-back-better-agenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 23:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 2:40 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, let me begin by thanking all these utility executives for coming in today.&#160; I think this is the beginning of a &#8212; God willing, a new era in the generation of electricity and, fundamentally, clean up the environment.&#160; And I can&#8217;t tell you how much&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>2:40 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, let me begin by thanking all these utility executives for coming in today.&nbsp; I think this is the beginning of a &#8212; God willing, a new era in the generation of electricity and, fundamentally, clean up the environment.&nbsp; And I can&#8217;t tell you how much I appreciate you being here.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to make a few brief comments and then ask a couple questions.&nbsp; And, unfortunately, I have a &#8212; I have to go, not immediately but before we finish.&nbsp; And I want to apologize ahead of time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But thank you, thank you, thank you for being here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m afraid &#8212; as I said, I won&#8217;t be able to stay, but I wanted to come by to thank the utility sector CEOs for being here, you know, and hear from you at the top.</p>



<p>You know, you have some of the most important jobs in America right now: keeping electricity systems running and running reliably.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve spent too much time this last year flying in helicopters over areas of scorched earth that &#8212; because utilities were down, because of what&#8217;s going &#8212; I mean, it really is amazing.&nbsp; More &#8212; more territory is burned to the ground in the West Coast than the entire state of New Jersey in terms of square miles.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just stunning.&nbsp; Absolutely stunning.</p>



<p>And I want to thank you for what you&#8217;re doing to help get the word out about clean energy.&nbsp; And the component &#8212; one of the significant &#8212; the most significant component of my Build Back Better plan &#8212; and thank you for coming to speak on its behalf &#8212; it&#8217;s about building a clean energy future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re seeing incredible enthusiasm and support for the effort not just from you all, but around the country.&nbsp; I mean, there&#8217;s a real &#8212; people are &#8212; I guess when things got really bad, it made people realize, “My Lord, this is real.&nbsp; This is real, this climate change.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s about building that future &#8212; that clean energy future.&nbsp; And &#8212; and how many major announcements have we seen recently?&nbsp; Ford and GM, for example, building out their electric vehicle production, a total &#8212; a total, I think, investment of &#8212; I think it sold almost $18 billion &#8212; 11 and 7.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Union Pacific Railroad: I was recently out in &#8212; in Pennsylvania, in Pittsburgh, but &#8212; to see other parts of what was going on.&nbsp; But they &#8212; Union Electric &#8212; excuse me, the Union Pacific Railroad is buying electric locomotives that are being built in Erie, Pennsylvania.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just yesterday, Tritium announced a new facility in Tennessee that is going to build the electric chargers.&nbsp; They brought in someone to show us what they&#8217;re like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we&#8217;re &#8212; this legislation has already been passed.&nbsp; That’s 500,000 electric chargers on our highways.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to change the dynamic of how &#8212; not only how we travel, but the economy along the way as well, because &#8212;</p>



<p>Any rate, companies are investing in clean energy futures.&nbsp; And the world is betting on American workers to build it and the American people to buy it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, we&#8217;re investing in clean energy &#8212; as a stronger, more resilient grid; 100 percent clean electricity by 2035.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a major piece of the puzzle and one of the commitments that I made &#8212; we would try to do.</p>



<p>Like there rest of my Build Back Better plan, the clean energy companies of this plan are about lowering prices.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is all about.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about reducing family energy bills while protecting the grid from extreme weather and making power more reliable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s also about jobs.&nbsp; No one knows it better than all of you around this table: The investment is going to support the creation of hundreds of thousands of good-paying jobs all across the country and how it flows from this &#8212; what you&#8217;re all about to do, or God willing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s going to make us more economically competitive while reducing pollution and improving public health, and helping us meet the moment on climate change &#8212; the most important piece of it, in my view.</p>



<p>These investments are about today, and they&#8217;re also about the future.&nbsp; And we can do it without increasing the deficit or raising taxes on anyone making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; And 17 Nobel laureates spontaneously &#8212; in economics &#8212; spontaneously wrote to me, telling me that they believed that this would ease long-term inflation.</p>



<p>And so, the CEOs know exactly why a clean energy future matters.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an incredible opportunity for our country.&nbsp; And &#8212; and they know how urgent it is to get this done.&nbsp; And there have been &#8212; you know, they&#8217;ve been key partners throughout this entire process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I&#8217;m grateful for their input, and I look forward to getting a full report from my team on the ideas discussed today.</p>



<p>But with your permission, I&#8217;d like to stick around a little bit and maybe ask a few questions.&nbsp; And again, I can&#8217;t tell you how &#8212;</p>



<p>Back up.&nbsp; Four years ago, when I was sitting talking about this issue, the question was, “No &#8212; no one is &#8212; you guys aren&#8217;t going to do this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not going to happen.”&nbsp; No, I mean, for real.&nbsp; That was the nature of the discussion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you&#8217;re here saying you support this and you&#8217;re going to try to move if we can get this Build Back Better piece done.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;d like to start off with you, Pat, if I may &#8212; excuse me &#8212; mind me calling you Pat.&nbsp; I apolog- &#8212; you can call me Joe.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>You&#8217;re &#8212; PNM operates in New Mexico and Texas and powering 800,000 homes and businesses.</p>



<p>How is this Build Back Better initiative is going to deliver more reliable and affordable power and reduce costs for &#8212; if you &#8212; if we have it available to you to be able to get the tax benefits?</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. President, thank you for the opportunity to speak.&nbsp; And thank you for your support of our clean energy future.</p>



<p>We started our clean energy journey some time ago in New Mexico, working with our governor, the environmental community, the business community, and our Indigenous communities, all who support clean energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’ll &#8212; this legislation is going to allow us to be carbon-free sooner, gives us renewable portfolio standards, allows us to securitize to keep costs down for customers, and very importantly, Mr. President, it provides for a just transition.</p>



<p>There is money in there for worker severance and retraining for the coal miners.&nbsp; We already take care of our coal plant employees at the utility.&nbsp; But it has money for economic development in there to revitalize the communities.&nbsp; So, working with economic development, Indian Affairs, and Workforce Solutions.&nbsp; Because when people move into the clean energy economy, they shouldn&#8217;t have to move away from their Tribal lands.&nbsp; And we are going to work to revitalize those communities so that they can participate in the clean energy future where they currently live.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These clean energy tax policies are going to be so helpful.&nbsp; New Mexico, unfortunately, is the third poorest state.&nbsp; And the areas that we serve in Texas are not the affluent areas of Texas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a regulated utility, we pass all of our tax savings directly back to our customers.&nbsp; And along with reliability in clean, affordable, it is really on the top of our priority list.</p>



<p>We have the number-three solar potential in the United States in New Mexico and the number-three onshore wind potential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, having credits for that and for storage, which is critical to make sure that those resources can be stored &#8212; so we need them when we need them &#8212; and the building of the transmission to export those wind and solar resources to other states is also critical.&nbsp; So that transmission in solar &#8212; and storage &#8212; and wind is really going to help bring down the customer cost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also looking to integrate more electric vehicles into the grid.&nbsp; I tell people: Once you drive an electric vehicle, you don&#8217;t want to drive an internal combustion engine anymore.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re quiet and quick.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:&nbsp; Oh, are they quick.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this will help us make the needed improvements in our grid at a lower cost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on the corporate tax rate, when we keep that low, we also pass those savings back to our customers.&nbsp; And, unfortunately, any increases conversely get pushed back to customers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, President Biden, your support of clean energy and the clean energy tax policies will really allow us to accelerate that &#8212; making energy reliable, affordable, and cleaner sooner.</p>



<p>So, thank you so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.</p>



<p>One of the things that I spent some time in one of the very &#8212; this is how many years ago now?&nbsp; I guess three years ago &#8212; in a very large solar site in Nevada.</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:Yes.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And one of the things we were talking about at the time, and I met &#8212; it created a hell of a lot of jobs, but it will create more jobs if you can actually transmit that solar energy on a line to a destination that is one that can use it well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They &#8212; my team tells me that there is a &#8212; a capacity to, by further investment in machinery on the site, that it is going to be able to, through high voltage &#8212; HVDC tech, move that energy more quickly and lose less of it on the way.&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:Absolutely.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And tell me how that &#8212; I mean, will &#8212; will you be in a better position to be able to &#8212; for your solar sites &#8212; be able to afford that with, in fact, you have the tax credits that are moving?</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:&nbsp; Yeah, the tax credits will make the more sophisticated transmission infrastructure much less expensive.&nbsp; And, again, we pass those savings all along to the consumers.&nbsp; And a lot of the solar &#8212; and where you cite solar fields &#8212; is not near what we call “load centers,” or big cities, so you need that transmission.&nbsp; And it is going to be absolutely critical to building our nation&#8217;s clean energy infrastructure.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, my wife and I, separately, spent a little bit of time with those Indigenous communities in &#8212; in New Mexico and other places.&nbsp; And it really makes a difference &#8212; it will make a difference for them in a big way, I think.</p>



<p>MS. VINCENT-COLLAWN:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And, you know, especially the Navajo Nation is embracing a clean energy future.&nbsp; They&#8217;re very thoughtful about how they move away.&nbsp; But they are very much looking forward to developing the solar potential on their lands.&nbsp; And we will be able to export that to other parts of the West that desperately need some more clean energy.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, as an aside, before I go to you, Nick, I was out in Colorado looking at the experimental efforts going on up there in the mountains.&nbsp; I was stunned.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m familiar with wind energy, because we tried very hard early on in the last administration I was in to promote that.&nbsp; And we had some blowback because people didn&#8217;t want to be able to see it and the like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They showed me a blade of a windmill that&#8217;s 100 yards long.&nbsp; My Lord.&nbsp; I mean, I looked at that and thought, “Holy Lord.”&nbsp; I mean, can&#8217;t fatho- &#8212; I think some of the press was with me on that trip.&nbsp; It was&nbsp;&#8212; it was astounding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you&#8217;re at AEP, Nick.&nbsp; You use a variety of traditional fuels to make power like coal, natural gas, and nuclear.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good to see you now expanding into wind and solar.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tell me a little bit about the expansion and the renewables &#8212; how that&#8217;s going for you.&nbsp; Is it going to reduce costs to customers?&nbsp; How &#8212; and how, if at all, does my initiative on Build Back Better, the over $500 billion we&#8217;re talking about for the energy side of this &#8212; of which, by the way, I think it&#8217;s about $200 billion in tax credits and another $100 billion for resilience.&nbsp; But talk to me about how &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; how you&#8217;re making your decisions.</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; Well, first of all, Mr. President, a pleasure to be with you today to talk about these important issues.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve actually shed the light on a lot of the infrastructure needs of this country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, certainly, the grid is one of those areas that &#8212; that we find &#8212; and I grew up as a system operator.&nbsp; Forty years ago, I started as a system operator running power systems.&nbsp; So, for me, your focus on resiliency and reliability of the grid is extremely important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The addition of renewables in place today is having a substantial impact on the ability to save customers money.&nbsp; Matter of fact, we &#8212; this quarter, we&#8217;ll be putting in &#8212; operational &#8212; the largest wind power project in North America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; About 1,000 megawatts in Oklahoma.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to save customers about $2.2 billion over the life of the agreement.&nbsp; So, certainly, it’s a huge benefit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for us, it&#8217;s really an opportunity to bring these kinds of resources in, lower costs to customers, and be able to move toward that clean energy future.&nbsp; So, as we look &#8212; as we look at that &#8212; we&#8217;ve looked at it across our territories.&nbsp; And now we have a plan by 2030 to put over 16,000 megawatts of generation like that in place.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s really an important opportunity for us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also partner extensively with Lonnie Stephenson, the IBEW, and the unions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re mapping that transition to those skills of the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, partners like that and partners in the federal government can enable this &#8212; this industry to move much more quickly than we would have otherwise, particularly with the tax provisions; ITCs &#8212; investment tax credits; and so forth.&nbsp; Those have really produced benefits for consumers, because those costs &#8212; those benefits actually flow through to our consumers and contribute to the economy.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s a great opportunity for us to make that transition.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s a heck of an opportunity.&nbsp; One of the things &#8212; maybe when the press is still here &#8212; to talk a little bit about &#8212; you know, I was really excited back in, I guess it was probably two thousand and &#8212; don’t hold me to exact year &#8212; probably 2012, &#8217;13, &#8217;14.&nbsp; We were talking about major wind initiative off the eastern coast, the coast of the &#8212; on the East Coast.&nbsp; And they said there was a &#8212; you know, an effort to go off the coast of Delaware and off the coast of New Jersey.&nbsp; And I think it was &#8212; they were going to &#8212; I think it was able to power &#8212; don&#8217;t hold me to the number &#8212; like 800,000 homes in New Jersey.&nbsp; But there was a real blowback when people said, “I don&#8217;t want to see those things.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, remember, up in Nantucket area and Nantucket Sound and &#8212;</p>



<p>Tell me about &#8212; when you say you&#8217;re going to have this largest, essentially, wind farm in Oklahoma, what is the reception of the community with that?</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; Oh, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s been very, very positive, because &#8212; not only do they see the benefits of the clean energy, but also the job creations.&nbsp; But the benefits for customers are considerable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, where we run into some issues is &#8212; when there&#8217;s large-scale transmission, which you mentioned to Pat, we really do need to find ways to scope large transmission to get renewables to the &#8212; to the big cities.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a process that, obviously, your administration has been working on as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for us, it&#8217;s important to scope those projects, because the savings associated with renewables will actually pay for the transmission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. AKINS:&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a key area for us to be able to continue to grow.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Are all of you &#8212; generic question: Are you getting less resistance when you start talking about wind and the windmills?&nbsp; I know they cause cancer.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Bad joke.&nbsp; I shouldn&#8217;t kid about that.&nbsp; I shouldn’t have kidded.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, I mean, people &#8212; I mean, what &#8212; what kind of resistance do you have to &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. ANDERSON:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; if you &#8212; if your using wind?</p>



<p>MR. ANDERSON:&nbsp; I can &#8212; I can speak to the arc in Michigan.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve done a lot of wind in Michigan.&nbsp; We have a pretty good wind regime there.&nbsp; It &#8212; it is what Nick said, that if you get in a community that&#8217;s highly mixed &#8212; where some benefit and some don&#8217;t &#8212; you&#8217;ll get resistance.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re in a community that&#8217;s more rural &#8212; where it becomes a part of their economy, their jobs, their income &#8212; the reception is quite high.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are actually at a transition point in Michigan where solar has now crossed over and is highly competitive with wind.&nbsp; So, I think after a long period of investment in wind, we&#8217;re now going to see our largest-scale investments in solar, and the reception to solar has been very high.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great addition to the tax base.&nbsp; Big construct- &#8212; billions of dollars of construction that plays out, and then the permanent jobs that follow.&nbsp; So we expect that to be a well-received renewable resource in the state.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I spent a fair amount of time, prior to the campaign &#8212; campaigning and since then &#8212; with some of the really entrepreneurial geniuses out in Silicon Valley.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what they&#8217;re now talking about &#8212; and you all know, and I wonder how you view it &#8212; is the ability to store the energy when the wind&#8217;s not blowing and when the sun&#8217;s not shining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I was shown, for example, a &#8212; you could have &#8212; let&#8217;s say you were powered either &#8212; even it could be geothermal, for that matter.&nbsp; But you have a facility &#8212; a &#8212; it looks like &#8212; to me, it looked like a platform about this wide and about that thick that&#8217;s in your basement.&nbsp; And it stores energy when the wind&#8217;s not blowing up when the sun is not shining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Are you &#8212; do you &#8212; and I know you’re not making those, but how &#8212; has that increased the receptiveness of the idea of wind and solar or geothermal?</p>



<p>Yes, Lynn.</p>



<p>MS. GOOD:&nbsp; Yeah, I can respond, Mr. President.&nbsp; Again, thank you for having us join.&nbsp; But we see storage as an incredibly important part of the equation going forward &#8212; not only in people&#8217;s homes, but, frankly, on our system &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. GOOD:&nbsp; &#8212; in order to strengthen it and make it capable of taking on more resiliency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as I look at the number of megawatts of renewables we&#8217;ll add, there&#8217;s a comparable number of storage megawatts we will also add over the next decades.&nbsp; And the tax credits that you have included would be an important part of lowering costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the infrastructure bill, under the Department of Energy, has a lot of investment in the R&amp;D necessary to advance that battery storage.&nbsp; So, we think there&#8217;s great potential for this.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I asked the question for a selfish reason.&nbsp; Because when I said &#8212; this is going to generate jobs well beyond your site.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, there are going to be people manufacturing those battery storage facilities.&nbsp; People man- &#8212; I mean &#8212; so I mean, this has such a ripple effect that &#8212; God willing.</p>



<p>And what&#8217;s going to happen is, I predict &#8212; you know, right now, in some cases, China is ahead of us, but I think we&#8217;re going to end up having a significant export market as well that&#8217;s going to create thousands of good-paying jobs here in the United States.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be in our interests to have this, you know, move around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, I hope that you all are going to look back on this 10 years from now and say, “Boy, that time we didn&#8217;t have any dinner at that dining room table.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; “It still worked.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I want to thank you all very, very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p> 3:01 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Introduction of the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-introduction-of-the-violence-against-women-act-reauthorization-act-of-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 22:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I applaud the bipartisan group of Senators who have joined together to introduce the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022 (VAWA), following passage last year of a bipartisan bill in the House of Representatives to renew and significantly strengthen this essential law.&#160; I am especially grateful to Senators Feinstein, Ernst, Durbin, and Murkowski&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I applaud the bipartisan group of Senators who have joined together to introduce the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022 (VAWA), following passage last year of a bipartisan bill in the House of Representatives to renew and significantly strengthen this essential law.&nbsp; I am especially grateful to Senators Feinstein, Ernst, Durbin, and Murkowski for their ongoing leadership and commitment. I commend the tremendous dedication of advocates and honor the courage and resilience of survivors who have been on the frontlines of advocacy efforts to improve laws and work toward creating a society where everyone has an opportunity to thrive without fear of violence or abuse.&nbsp; I urge the Senate to move quickly to get this passed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I first wrote and championed the original VAWA legislation, it helped break a dam of congressional and cultural resistance that too often saw domestic violence as a ‘family issue,’ with legal and social burdens placed on survivors rather than perpetrators.&nbsp; In the nearly three decades since its passage, the law has been reauthorized three times with broad bipartisan support.&nbsp; Each time, I have helped work to strengthen its protections — expanding access to safety and resources for all survivors, particularly those from marginalized communities. And while studies have shown that domestic violence and sexual assault rates have declined significantly since VAWA took effect, we know that we still have work to do.</p>



<p>The VAWA Reauthorization Act of 2022 will expand prevention efforts and protections for survivors, including those from underserved communities, and will provide increased resources and training for law enforcement and our judicial system.&nbsp; It will strengthen rape prevention and education efforts, support rape crisis centers, improve the training of sexual assault forensic examiners, and broaden access to legal services for all survivors, among other things.</p>



<p>Combatting domestic violence, sexual assault, dating violence, and stalking should not be a Democratic issue or Republican issue. It’s a matter of justice and compassion.&nbsp; I am grateful that this critical bipartisan bill is moving forward, and I look forward to Congress delivering it to my desk without delay.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
