<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 22:34:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Message to the Senate Regarding the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of&#160;Sweden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/message-to-the-senate-regarding-the-protocols-to-the-north-atlantic-treaty-of-1949-on-the-accession-of-the-republic-of-finland-and-the-kingdom-of-sweden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 21:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To the Senate of the United States: I transmit herewith, for the advice and consent of the Senate to its ratification, the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of Sweden (the &#8220;Protocols&#8221;).&#160; The Protocols were signed in Brussels on July 5, 2022,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>To the Senate of the United States:</p>



<p>I transmit herewith, for the advice and consent of the Senate to its ratification, the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of Sweden (the &#8220;Protocols&#8221;).&nbsp; The Protocols were signed in Brussels on July 5, 2022, on behalf of the United States and the other Parties to the North Atlantic Treaty.&nbsp; Also transmitted for the information of the Senate is an overview of the Protocols by the Department of State.&nbsp; Full ratification of the Protocols will allow Finland and Sweden to become Parties to the North Atlantic Treaty and members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</p>



<p>Article 10 of the North Atlantic Treaty, which outlines NATO&#8217;s Open Door policy, is part of the doctrinal foundation of the Alliance.&nbsp; It states that Allies may, by unanimous consent, invite any other European State in a position to further the principles of the Treaty and to contribute to the security of the North Atlantic area to accede.&nbsp; As further explained in the&nbsp;reports on the accession of Finland and Sweden to NATO, transmitted to the Congress on May&nbsp;19 and July 1, 2022, in light of section 3(2)(E) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the Czech Republic of April 30, 1998, Finland and Sweden more than meet these qualifications.&nbsp; They will be net contributors to the Alliance, in both capabilities and resources, and they share critically important values with the United States.&nbsp; Finland&#8217;s and Sweden&#8217;s accession will help further United States priorities within&nbsp;NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I ask the Senate to continue working with my Administration in advancing a strong and free Europe by providing its prompt advice and consent to ratification of the Protocols.&nbsp; We are encouraging all Allies to act expeditiously in their own ratification processes as well, given current global considerations. &nbsp;My Administration stands ready to brief and assist you in your deliberations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 11, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 21:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Ann Marie Yastishock, of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ann Marie Yastishock, of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Solomon Islands and Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Vanuatu.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Manuel P. Micaller, Jr., of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Tajikistan.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kristina A. Kvien, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Armenia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Henry V. Jardine, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Mauritius, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Seychelles.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Diane Susan Kaplan, of Alaska, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting for a term expiring January 31, 2026, vice Patricia D. Cahill, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Patrice H. Kunesh, of Minnesota, to be Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, Department of Health and Human Services, vice Jean Carol Hovland.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Milancy Danielle Harris, of Virginia, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense, vice Kari A. Bingen.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jeffrey R. Gural, of New York, to be Chairperson of the Public Buildings Reform Board for a term of six years.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Phillip A. Washington, of Illinois, to be Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration for the term of five years, vice Stephen M. Dickson, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Frances Kay Behm, of Michigan, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Michigan, vice David M. Lawson, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tamika R. Montgomery-Reeves, of Delaware, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Third Circuit, vice Thomas L. Ambro, retiring.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; James A. Diossa, of Rhode Island, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation for a term expiring October 3, 2024, vice Harvey M. Tettlebaum, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on July 15, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ed Gonzalez, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security, vice Sarah R. Saldana, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Raymond M. Jefferson, of Hawaii, to be Under Secretary for Benefits of the Department of Veterans Affairs, vice Paul R. Lawrence, which was sent to the Senate on March 21, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden Administration Makes Public First Full-Color Image from Webb Space&#160;Telescope</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/biden-administration-produces-first-full-color-image-from-webb-space-telescope/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden Administration made public the first full-color image from the Webb Space Telescope, which captured the highest-resolution images of the infrared universe in history. The Webb Space Telescope launched from French Guiana in December 2021 and is now orbiting the Sun one million miles away from Earth. The image was previewed to President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden Administration made public the first <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/webbfirstimages">full-color image</a> from the Webb Space Telescope, which captured the highest-resolution images of the infrared universe in history. The Webb Space Telescope launched from French Guiana in December 2021 and is now orbiting the Sun one million miles away from Earth. The image was previewed to President Biden and Vice President Harris during a briefing at the White House by officials from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), where they discussed how these revolutionary images will enable breakthroughs in nearly every branch of astronomy.</p>



<p>During the briefing, President Biden publicly showed the first of the images: “Webb’s First Deep Field,” the “deepest” and sharpest infrared image of the distant universe ever produced. This image is filled with galaxies, some more than 13 billion years old, which means they formed just after the Big Bang. Over the coming days, NASA will publish additional images, which reveal details about the atmosphere of an exoplanet outside our solar system, “stellar nurseries” where stars form, galaxies that interact and trigger star formation and black holes, and a glimpse into how stars die.</p>



<p>The Webb Space Telescope is an international program led by NASA with its partners,&nbsp;ESA (European Space Agency)&nbsp;and the&nbsp;Canadian Space Agency. Its revolutionary technology will study every phase of cosmic history over the past 13.5 billion years — from inside our solar system to the most distant observable galaxies in the early universe. The telescope gives us the capacity to explore a wide range of questions that help us understand the origins of the universe and our place within it. The telescope is one of humanity’s great engineering feats, launching from Earth on a rocket, and then unfolding itself in space. Thousands of engineers and hundreds of scientists worked to make the telescope a reality, along with over 300 universities, organizations, and companies from 29 U.S. states and 14 countries.</p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris, who chairs the National Space Council, were briefed by NASA Administrator Bill Nelson, Deputy Assistant to the President Dr. Alondra Nelson, who leads the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, Head of NASA Science Thomas Zurbuchen, James Webb Space Telescope Program Director Greg Robinson, Operations Project Scientist Jane Rigby, and Space Telescope Science Institute Deputy Director Nancy Levenson.</p>



<p>The images from the Webb Space Telescope illustrate the great leaps in science and technology discovery that can be made with U.S. government leadership, in partnership with other countries. The Biden-Harris Administration has worked to restore scientific integrity to Federal policy-making and to more broadly and equitably engage and serve Americans around science and technology solutions, including addressing great challenges like pandemics, cancer, and the climate crisis, and ensuring America remains the world leader in technologies and industries of the future that will be critical to our economic prosperity and national security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:  Richard Mills, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Federal Republic of Nigeria Ann Marie Yastishock, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration: <br></p>



<ul><li>Richard Mills, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Federal Republic of Nigeria</li><li>Ann Marie Yastishock, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, the Solomon Islands, and the Republic of Vanuatu</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Richard Mills, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Federal Republic of Nigeria</u></strong><br><br>Richard Mills, Jr., a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the U.S. Deputy Permanent Representative to the United Nations. Previously, he was Deputy Chief of Mission and then Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at the U.S. Mission to Canada. Prior to that, Mills served as U.S. Ambassador to Armenia. He has also served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Beirut, Lebanon and as Deputy Chief of Mission and Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at U.S. Embassy Valetta, Malta. Other assignments include Senior Democracy Advisor at U.S. Embassy Baghdad, Political Counselor at U.S. Embassy London, and Political Officer at the U.S. Mission to the United Nations. Prior to joining the Foreign Service, Mills was an Associate Attorney with the firm of Duncan, Allen and Mitchell in Washington, D.C. A native of Louisiana, Mills earned a B.A. in Foreign Service from Georgetown University, a J.D. from the University of Texas School of Law and a M.S. in National Security Policy from the National Defense University. He is the recipient of multiple State Department awards and speaks French and Russian.<br><br><strong><u>Ann Marie Yastishock, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, the Solomon Islands, and the Republic of Vanuatu</u></strong><br><br>Ann Marie Yastishock, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator, Bureau for Asia, USAID. Previously, she was the USAID Mission Director in Hanoi, Vietnam. During the transition to the Biden-Harris Administration , she served as the Chief Advisor to the Acting Administrator and Chief Operating Officer for USAID. Prior to that, she was the Acting Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator of the Bureau for Asia responsible for USAID missions and programs in East Asia and the Pacific. Before that, she oversaw USAID activities in South and Central Asia as the Deputy Assistant Administrator in the Bureau for Asia. Earlier in her career, she served as the Deputy Mission Director for the regional office of USAID covering Ukraine, Moldova, Belarus and Cyprus. Other assignments include Interim Deputy Mission Director for USAID Burma; Deputy Director of the USAID Center of Excellence on Democracy, Human Rights and Governance; Senior Legal Advisor to USAID/Afghanistan; and Resident Legal Advisor to Georgia, Armenia and Azerbaijan. Prior to joining USAID, Yastishock worked as a Rule of Law Liaison for the American Bar Association/Central and East European Law Initiative with the parliaments of Kazakhstan and Tajikistan. A native of Pennsylvania, Yastishock earned her B.S. in Economics from Pennsylvania State University and a J.D. from the Widener University School of Law. She is the recipient of numerous USAID performance awards and speaks Russian.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the UnidosUS 2022 Annual&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/11/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-unidosus-2022-annual-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 18:47:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[San Antonio, TX Good afternoon, Unidos. It’s incredibly special to be here with you in San Antonio. Earlier today, the White House celebrated the signing of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act—the most significant gun safety law in 30 years. You know, when Joe and I visited Uvalde, I stood in front of those 21 crosses,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">San Antonio, TX</p>



<p>Good afternoon, Unidos. It’s incredibly special to be here with you in San Antonio.<br><br>Earlier today, the White House celebrated the signing of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act—the most significant gun safety law in 30 years.<br><br>You know, when Joe and I visited Uvalde, I stood in front of those 21 crosses, and touched the pictures of the bright, beautiful faces that would never again laugh, or open birthday presents, or tell their parents that they loved them. And I knew that a piece of Uvalde would always be a part of me. <br><br>Like all of you, Joe and I think about those families—and all who carry that grief—every day.  <br><br>When we were leaving the school, someone shouted “Do something!” And I’m proud that Joe has. He will continue to do everything he can and to call on Congress to act, including on measures that ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines. <br><br>We are committed to building a safer, healthier, more prosperous, and fair America. <br><br>And I know that Unidos is as well—and has been since the very start. <br><br>In fact, I was reminded of the transformational power of this organization when Joe awarded your longtime leader, Raul Yzaguirre, the Presidential Medal of Freedom, our country’s highest civilian honor. <br><br>Raul has dedicated his life to working for so many civil liberties: from fighting poverty to improving education to advancing voting rights. But one of the most powerful things that he did through this organization was to bring the Latino community together. Because he understood that unity is powerful. And he challenges us to be just as brave and bold.<br><br>It’s a reminder that we all need—now more than ever.   <br><br>A little over a month ago, I had the opportunity to give a commencement to Los Angeles City College students. The crowd was a majority Latino, but the students didn’t share one story. <br><br>There were immigrants, and first-generation Americans, and Angelenos whose families have lived on this land since long before it was called the United States. There were engineers and artists, veterans and students who are going on to four-year colleges. <br><br>They didn’t share one path or dream. But as I saw the joy in their faces, I could see that they did have one thing in common: Each of them will bring exceptional gifts and talents to their corner of our country—and will make their community stronger by being a part of it.</p>



<p>Yes, the Latino community is unique. But what I’ve heard from you again and again is that you want what all families want. Good schools. Good jobs. Safe neighborhoods. <br><br>You want justice and equality—the opportunity to build a better life for your families.<br><br>It’s not only what all families want; it’s what all families deserve. But we can’t get those things on our own.<br><br>Raul helped build this organization with the understanding that the diversity of this community—as distinct as the bodegas of the Bronx, as beautiful as the blossoms of Miami, and as unique as the breakfast tacos here in San Antonio—is your strength. <br><br>And yet, it’s when you speak with one voice—unidos—that you find your power.   <br><br>Thanks to the hard work of you and advocates across the country, we have torn down so many of the barriers that kept Latinos out of our seats of power. But your voice hasn’t always been listened to, has it? <br><br>A few years ago, I met with a group of bright, ambitious young Latino leaders. <br><br>And they told me that there were times when they didn’t feel heard. They asked me: How can our leaders work for us if they don’t work with us?<br><br>It’s an idea that’s always been at the heart of Joe’s work. If you want to know what a community needs—ask them. Give them a seat at the table and then listen to what they have to say. <br><br>And he’s done just that. He’s appointed Latinos to the highest offices in his cabinet. He made sure that legislation like the American Rescue Plan focused on equity. His team worked with all of you—Unidos and so many of the affiliates here today—to get Latinos vaccinated, fight hunger, and invest in your small businesses.  <br><br>And let me say how grateful we are to everyone who has been a partner in that work. It’s because you are on the frontlines that our team can meet Latinos and all Americans where they are. <br><br>We’ve made progress together. And I’m so proud of what Joe has done to pass bipartisan legislation, like the infrastructure and gun bills. I’m proud that he recovered all private sector jobs lost during the pandemic, reopened schools, and cut child poverty in half. <br><br>You were right to put your faith in him two years ago. But I also know that we need to do so much more. We will never make the changes we need when so many of our leaders refuse to work together. When politicians block legislation that the majority of Americans want: A ban on guns that only belong on a battle field. The right to make our own decisions about our own bodies. Universal child care, and community college, and ending child poverty. <br><br>Congress is supposed to represent the will of the people. And that’s why we the people need to speak up. All of us—united. <br><br>We need to vote—in races at every single level. And we need to remember that voting is the bare minimum. We have to get involved in the local governments that decide how cities plan their budgets and protect their students. We have to speak up for justice and equity. We have to demand that we the people be heard—to follow the example you have set.  <br><br>For decades, this organization has brought people together. You’ve built coalitions and helped this community raise its voice. You’ve envisioned a better world and done the difficult work to make it real. <br><br>You do your part every day—and Joe and I are committed to doing the same. The road ahead won’t be easy, but we’re with you in this fight—now and always. <br><br>Your longtime leader, Raul, once said: “When things aren’t going your way, you have to have something to sustain you, and having a love for your community is one thing that will sustain you.” <br><br>I see that love here today. A love that gives us the strength to speak up, even when we’re tired. That helps us come together, to cross any divide. That believes in the best of who we are—and knows that justice is within our reach as long as we never give up on each other.<br><br>Your fight is our fight and we will stand with you—in unity, equity, and love. <br><br>Thank you.   <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at an Event Commemorating the Passage of the Safer Communities&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/11/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-an-event-commemorating-the-passage-of-the-safer-communities-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 16:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 11:08 A.M. EDT      THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Thank you, Dr. Guerrero, for the introduction and for your courage and your compassion.  You have been such a source of strength to the families of Uvalde, and I know that is not without personal sacrifice.  Thank you for your leadership.  (Applause.) To our President, Joe Biden;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Lawn</em></p>



<p>11:08 A.M. EDT<br> <br>     THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning. <br> <br>Thank you, Dr. Guerrero, for the introduction and for your courage and your compassion.  You have been such a source of strength to the families of Uvalde, and I know that is not without personal sacrifice.  Thank you for your leadership.  (Applause.)<br> <br>To our President, Joe Biden; members of Congress &#8212; (applause); members of our administration; friends and fellow Americans: Today is indeed an historic day. <br> <br>For 30 years, our nation has failed to pass meaningful gun violence legislation.  Again and again, the American people have called for commonsense action to protect our communities. <br> <br> Last month, their call was finally answered when President Joe Biden signed the bipartisan Safer Communities Act.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Because of our President&#8217;s leadership and because of so many of you, we have passed a law that will make communities around our nation safer.<br> <br>For my whole career, addressing gun violence has been one of my top priorities.  First, as a courtroom prosecutor.  Then as District Attorney of San Francisco, where we created a gun specialist unit to go after violent offenders.  Then, of course, as Attorney General, where our office worked closely with the California Bureau of Firearms to investigate and seize firearms from those who unlawfully possessed them.  As a United States senator, together with my former colleagues in the Senate, we supported various pieces of legislation to address this crisis. <br> <br>So, I knew and I know now, as so many of you do, that we are overdue in getting this work done.  And I know it will save lives. <br> <br>Together, we gather with many of the leaders who made this law a reality.  To the friends and family members of the victims of gun violence: In the face of so much pain, you have shown incredible strength, and it is a profound honor to stand with you today. <br> <br>To the members of Congress who are here with us: In the face of so much pessimism, you passed a bipartisan law.  You worked across the aisle, and the product of that work will make our communities safer.  And that deserves applause.  (Applause.)<br> <br>But as all of us know, gathered here today, we would not be here were it not for the vision, the courage, the unwavering determination of one particular individual: Joe Biden.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Our President, Joe Biden, has fought for decades to end the terror of gun violence.  He has taken on the gun lobby and won.  As a senator, Joe helped pass &#8212; then I would have called him “Joe”; now I call “Mr. President” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; which, as we know, is a background check system that has prevented more than 3 million firearms from falling into dangerous hands.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And he passed a 10-year ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines.  (Applause.)<br> <br>As Vice President, Joe Biden led the Obama-Biden administration&#8217;s efforts to reduce gun violence. <br> <br>President Joe Biden knows the tremendous pain of gun violence.  He has seen it up close.  He has held hands with parents who lost children and with children who lost parents. <br> <br>President Biden knows the urgency of this fight, and he will continue to do all in his power to protect the people of our nation. <br> <br>And now, it is my honor to welcome Garnell Whitfield, Jr., who I spent time with and his family mourning the loss of his beloved mother.<br> <br>     Mr. Whitfield.  (Applause.)<br> <br>                               END                 11:13 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vice President Harris to Address the Pacific Islands&#160;Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/vice-president-harris-to-address-the-pacific-islands-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 15:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday July 12 in Washington, D.C., Vice President Kamala Harris will participate virtually in the annual leaders’ meeting of the Pacific Islands Forum, which is taking place in Suva, Fiji. The Vice President will underscore the commitment of the United States to the Pacific Islands region and discuss opportunities to deepen U.S. engagement in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday July 12 in Washington, D.C., Vice President Kamala Harris will participate virtually in the annual leaders’ meeting of the Pacific Islands Forum, which is taking place in Suva, Fiji. The Vice President will underscore the commitment of the United States to the Pacific Islands region and discuss opportunities to deepen U.S. engagement in the region and areas to deliver concrete results for the people of the Pacific. The Vice President will celebrate the longstanding bonds between the United States and the Pacific Islands and will outline our ongoing work to strengthen them. This engagement builds on President Biden’s remarks to the Pacific Islands Forum meeting last year and Secretary Blinken’s trip to Fiji earlier this year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s 21 Executive Actions to Reduce Gun&#160;Violence</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-21-executive-actions-to-reduce-gun-violence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden has made historic progress on actions to reduce gun violence. To implement his comprehensive strategy to reduce gun crime, the Biden Administration has taken more executive action to reduce gun violence than any other president’s at this point in their Administration. Today, the President is celebrating the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act, the most significant gun violence reduction legislation to pass Congress in 30 years. The&#160;Biden Administration&#160;will continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden has made historic progress on actions to reduce gun violence. To implement his comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">strategy</a> to reduce gun crime, the Biden Administration has taken more executive action to reduce gun violence than any other president’s at this point in their Administration. Today, the President is celebrating the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act, the most significant gun violence reduction legislation to pass Congress in 30 years.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;Biden Administration&nbsp;will continue to use all of the tools at&nbsp;its&nbsp;disposal&nbsp;to address the epidemic of gun violence.&nbsp;The President’s FY 2023 budget proposes $32 billion in additional funding to fight crime, including $20.6 billion in discretionary funding for federal law enforcement and state and local law enforcement and crime prevention programs, an increase of 11% over FY22 enacted ($18.6 billion) and 18% over FY21 enacted ($17.5 billion).&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there&nbsp;is so much more that can and must be done to save lives.&nbsp;The President&nbsp;will continue to urge&nbsp;Congress to&nbsp;take further legislative action to&nbsp;keep dangerous guns out of dangerous hands, including a ban on assault weapons and&nbsp;high-capacity&nbsp;magazines, strengthening background checks, and enacting safe storage laws.</p>



<p>Below are&nbsp;21 ways&nbsp;the Biden Administration&nbsp;has already used executive action to make our communities safer:</p>



<p><strong>Keeping Especially Dangerous Weapons and Repeat Shooters Off Our Streets</strong></p>



<p>1.&nbsp;The Justice Department issued a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-new-rule-modernize-firearm-definitions">final rule</a>&nbsp;to rein in the proliferation of ghost guns, which are unserialized, privately made firearms that are increasingly being recovered at crime scenes.</p>



<p>2.&nbsp;The Attorney General&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/ag/page/file/1468291/download">directed every U.S. Attorney’s Office</a>&nbsp;nationwide to increase resources dedicated to district specific violent crime strategies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>3.&nbsp;The Justice Department issued a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-issues-proposed-rule-and-model-legislation-reduce-gun-violence">proposed rule</a>&nbsp;to better regulate when devices marketed as firearm stabilizing braces effectively turn pistols into short-barreled rifles subject to the National Firearms Act.</p>



<p><strong>Keeping Guns Out of the Wrong Hands</strong></p>



<p>4.&nbsp;The Justice Department&nbsp;published&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/doj/reducing-gun-violence/commentary-extreme-risk-protection-order-model-legislation">model extreme risk protection order legislation</a>&nbsp;to make it easier for states that want to adopt these red flag laws to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>5. The Justice Department issued&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-publication-first-volume-national-firearms-commerce-and">the first volume</a>&nbsp;of its new, comprehensive report on firearms commerce and trafficking.</p>



<p>6.&nbsp;The Justice Department announced a new policy to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/speech/attorney-general-merrick-b-garland-delivers-remarks-biden-administration-s-gun-crime">underscore zero tolerance</a>&nbsp;for willful violations of the law by federally licensed firearms dealers that put public safety at risk.</p>



<p>7.&nbsp;The Justice Department launched five&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-launches-firearms-trafficking-strike-forces-address-violent-crime-crack">new law enforcement strike forces</a>&nbsp;focused on addressing significant firearms trafficking corridors that have diverted guns to New York, Chicago, Los Angeles, the Bay Area, and Washington, D.C.&nbsp;</p>



<p>8.&nbsp;The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) launched a new paid media&nbsp;<a href="https://www.keepitsecure.net/">campaign</a>&nbsp;featuring a series of public service announcements to reinforce the key message that a simple gun lock can save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>9.&nbsp;The Departments of Defense (DOD), Health and Human Services (HHS), Homeland Security (DHS), Justice (DOJ), and Veterans Affairs (VA), as well as the Office of Emergency Medical Services within the Department of Transportation (DOT), announced that they will&nbsp;jointly create a plan&nbsp;for addressing&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Military-and-Veteran-Suicide-Prevention-Strategy.pdf">lethal means safety awareness</a>, education, training, and program evaluation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>10.&nbsp;ATF&nbsp;<a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2022/01/04/2021-28398/secure-gun-storage-and-definition-of-antique-firearm">issued</a>&nbsp;a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-new-rule-help-enhance-safe-and-secure-storage-firearms-publishes">final rule</a>&nbsp;clarifying firearms dealers’ statutory obligations to make available for purchase compatible secure gun storage or safety devices.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Making Additional&nbsp;Progress to Reduce Community Violence</strong></p>



<p>11.&nbsp;The President called for cities and states to use American Rescue Plan funding to reduce gun crime and other violent crime, including by investing in community violence interventions and prevention.&nbsp;Through May 2022,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/fact-sheet-president-biden-issues-call-for-state-and-local-leaders-to-dedicate-more-american-rescue-plan-funding-to-make-our-communities-safer-and-deploy-these-dollars-quickly/">$10 billion</a>&nbsp;in American Rescue Plan funds had been committed to public safety and violence prevention&nbsp;– including at least $6.5 billion in State and Local funds committed by more than half of states and more than 300 communities across the country</p>



<p>12.&nbsp;Five federal agencies made changes to 26 different programs to direct vital support to community violence intervention programs as quickly as possible.&nbsp;For example</p>



<p>•&nbsp;The National Institutes of Health announced funding through its Firearm Injury and Mortality Prevention Research grants for&nbsp;<a href="https://obssr.od.nih.gov/news-and-events/news/director-voice/nih-awards-10-grants-addressing-firearm-violence-prevention">four community violence programs</a>&nbsp;– including a place-based strategy involving repurposing vacant lots in Detroit, an evaluation of READI Chicago, a burnout prevention program for violence interrupters in Chicago, and a hospital-based violence intervention program focused on youth in Virginia.&nbsp;<br></p>



<p>•&nbsp;The Justice Department announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-awards-nearly-187-million-support-community-safety">$187 million</a> for states and $85 million for localities through the Byrne JAG Program to support coordinated violence prevention and intervention; the Department explicitly encouraged the use of these funds for CVI.&nbsp;<br></p>



<p>•&nbsp;The Department of Housing and Urban Development published a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hudexchange.info/resource/6477/cdbg-cv-community-violence-intervention-quick-guide/">guide</a>&nbsp;explaining to localities how Community Development Block Grants&nbsp;–&nbsp;a $3.4 billion annual funding stream&nbsp;–can be used to fund CVI strategies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>• The Department of Education released a&nbsp;<a href="https://oese.ed.gov/files/2021/10/21-007415-OESE-CVI-DCL-os-approved.pdf">letter</a>&nbsp;to state school associations on how 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;Century Learning Centers funds and Student Support and Academic enrichment programs – both billion-dollar formula grant funding streams – can be used to fund CVI strategies in schools.</p>



<p>13.&nbsp;The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services&nbsp;<a href="https://www.medicaid.gov/state-resource-center/downloads/allstatecall-20210427.pdf">hosted a webinar and&nbsp;published information&nbsp;to</a> educate states on how they can use Medicaid to reimburse certain community violence intervention programs, like Hospital-Based Violence Interventions. Last year, Connecticut and Illinois enacted legislation that allows Medicaid to reimburse providers for hospital-based violence prevention services – the first two states in the country to pursue this approach. According to reporting by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2021/09/17/medicaid-funds-tapped-combat-rise-crime-gun-debate-stalls/8326102002/">USA Today</a>, “[t]he idea has been in the works for years, advocates say, but not until the Biden administration signaled that states could – and should – use Medicaid dollars to support these violence prevention programs have state lawmakers stepped up.”</p>



<p>14.&nbsp;&nbsp;Senior White House staff&nbsp;established&nbsp;The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">White House Community Violence Intervention Collaborative</a>, a 16-jurisdiction cohort of mayors, law enforcement, CVI experts, and philanthropic leaders committed to using American Rescue Plan funding or other public funding to increase investment in their community violence intervention infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Providing Law Enforcement with the Tools and Resources They Need to Reduce Gun Violence</strong></p>



<p>15.&nbsp;The Justice Department&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-139-million-law-enforcement-hiring-advance-community-policing">announced</a>&nbsp;$139 million in grants to local law enforcement that will put over 1,000 police officers on the beat through the COPS Office Hiring Program.</p>



<p>16.&nbsp;The Justice&nbsp;Department’s Office on Violence Against Women (OVW)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-announces-expansion-firearms-technical-assistance-project-strengthen">expanded the</a>&nbsp;Domestic Violence Homicide Prevention Firearms Technical Assistance Project (FTAP).&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Addressing the Root Causes of Gun Violence</strong></p>



<p>17.&nbsp;The Department of Labor&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/eta/eta20210610-0">awarded</a>&nbsp;$89 million through its YouthBuild program to provide pre-apprenticeship opportunities for young people ages 16-24.</p>



<p>18.&nbsp;The Department of Labor&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/eta/eta20210610-1">awarded $20 million</a> through its Workforce Pathways for Youth program to expand workforce development activities that serve youth ages 14-21 during “out of school” time (non-school hours).</p>



<p>19.&nbsp;The Department of Labor&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/eta/eta20210621">awarded</a>&nbsp;$85.5 million to help formerly incarcerated adults and young people in 28 communities transition out of the criminal justice system and connect with quality jobs.</p>



<p>20.&nbsp;The Department&nbsp;of Labor&nbsp;awarded $25.5 million in&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/eta/eta20210317-1">Young Adult Reentry Partnership</a>&nbsp;grants to organizations that will help provide education and training services to young adults between 18-24 who were previously involved with the justice system or who left high school before graduation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>21.&nbsp;The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), through the Family Violence Prevention and Services Program, awarded&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/10/25/hhs-announces-nearly-800-million-american-rescue-plan-funds-support-domestic-violence-sexual-assault-survivors-their-children.html">nearly $1 billion</a>&nbsp;in American Rescue Plan (ARP) supplemental funding to support services for survivors of domestic violence and sexual assault and their children.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden In Press&#160;Gaggle</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/10/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-gaggle-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 22:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gordon&#8217;s Pond TrailLewes, Delaware 11:12 A.M. EDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good morning, Mr. President. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good morning! THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I want you to know an important thing: I took off the clamps on my (inaudible).&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Q &#160;&#160; How you feeling? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I’m feeling good.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good.&#160; That’s great. THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I’m looking for the sun&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Gordon&#8217;s Pond Trail<br>Lewes, Delaware</p>



<p>11:12 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning, Mr. President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I want you to know an important thing: I took off the clamps on my (inaudible).&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q &nbsp;&nbsp; How you feeling?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m feeling good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good.&nbsp; That’s great.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m looking for the sun though.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you made a decision on tariffs, sir?&nbsp; I know you had a meeting about that on Friday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, we’re having further discussions on that.&nbsp; And &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you have a &#8212; do you have a message, Mr. President, for women who were protesting outside the White House yesterday?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Keep protesting.&nbsp; Because &#8212; keep making your point.&nbsp; It’s critically important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can do a lot of things to accommodate the rights of women in the meantime.&nbsp; But, fundamentally, the only thing that’s going to change this is if we have a national law that reinstates Roe v. Wade.&nbsp; That’s the bottom line.</p>



<p>Everything else, we can get pieces of it, and I’m trying to do that.&nbsp; Some things that some of the groups want &#8212;</p>



<p>I’m going to look like a fool here in this interview, but &#8212; (points to his bike helmet).&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You look good.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You look great.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;I put a helmet on because this is a tough interview.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, I think that there’s things we can do to accommodate particular abuses beyond like not being able to cross state lines, those kinds of things, and being able to access women’s private information, and so on.&nbsp; That &#8212; we can work on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as President, I don’t have the authority to say that we’re going to, you know, instate Roe v. Wade as the law of the land.&nbsp; The only way we do that is through an election in the United States Congress.&nbsp; In the meantime, states can make those judgments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But &#8212; so my ultimate goal is to reinstate Roe v. Wade as the national law by passing it in the United States Congress.&nbsp; And I’ll sign it the moment that happens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I’m going to go on my ride.&nbsp; Okay?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, yes, Mr. President.&nbsp; One quick follow-up.&nbsp; One of the things they are asking for is a public health emergency.&nbsp; Is that something you’re considering?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s something I’ve asked the folks to &#8212; the medical people in the administration to look at, whether that is &#8212; whether I have the authority to do that and what impact that would have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>11:14 A.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ICYMI: Commerce Secretary Raimondo Exposes Sen. McConnell’s Blockade Against Lower&#160;Prices</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/10/icymi-commerce-secretary-raimondo-exposes-sen-mcconnells-blockade-against-lower-prices/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 19:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[McConnell is “Playing Politics with our National Security” Speaking with George Stephanopoulos on ABC’s&#160;This Week, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo pointed to legislation in Congress to build domestic manufacturing of semiconductor chips as a concrete step that needs to be taken to bring down prices for the American people. This legislation would create thousands of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>McConnell is “Playing Politics with our National Security”</em></p>



<p>Speaking with George Stephanopoulos on ABC’s&nbsp;<em>This Week</em>, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo pointed to legislation in Congress to build domestic manufacturing of semiconductor chips as a concrete step that needs to be taken to bring down prices for the American people. This legislation would create thousands of good-paying jobs and address the chips shortage that has driven prices higher on cars and countless other products. As the Secretary noted, Senator McConnell is now attempting to hold that legislation hostage to block another crucial effort to lower prices on prescription drugs for the American people.<br><br>The Secretary also noted that there are profound national security implications in not addressing the chips shortage, saying “He&#8217;s playing politics with our national security and it&#8217;s time for Congress to do its job on both of those dimensions.”<br><br><strong>Watch the clip:&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://twitter.com/abcpolitics/status/1546127074058031105?s=21&amp;t=S6SP7ACmRsV2YnOLwiulVQ">https://twitter.com/abcpolitics/status/1546127074058031105?s=21&amp;t=S6SP7ACmRsV2YnOLwiulVQ</a><br><br>STEPHANOPOULOS: …Is there anything more the President can do to combat inflation that he’s not doing now?</p>



<p>RAIMONDO: Well, one of the things that Ro Khanna&nbsp;pointed out in that piece is that Congress needs to pass the CHIPS Act. There’s a bill right now before Congress which Ro Khanna supports, President Biden supports, which would increase the domestic supply of semiconductors and also start a supply chain office in the Department of Commerce. That has to pass. Has to pass now. Not in six months from now, now. It&#8217;s bipartisan.</p>



<p>Mitch McConnell just threw a wrench in that about a week ago, saying that he wasn’t going to allow Republicans to move on that unless we move down reconciliation. That’s a perfect example, George, of increasing supply. We have inflation now because of lack of supply. And&nbsp;let&#8217;s increase supply.</p>



<p>STEPHANOPOULOS: But as you point out, Madam Secretary, Mitch McConnell said it&#8217;s not going anywhere as long as the President continues to push a budget reconciliation bill. So doesn&#8217;t that mean the CHIPS bill is dead?</p>



<p>RAIMONDO: It shouldn’t be dead. Why can’t we do both? What’s in that reconciliation bill? Allowing Medicare to negotiate for drug prices. What will that do? Bring down the prices of medicine for the average American consumer.</p>



<p>So the &#8212; again, the President wakes up every day pushing us and his team and Congress, what more can we do to bring down prices? So let&#8217;s bring down prescription drug prices, so that people feel that when they go to the drugstore and also let&#8217;s pass the CHIPS Act to bring down the prices of chips, which will bring down the price of pretty much everything you buy, because everything includes chips.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s a false choice. He&#8217;s playing politics with our national security and it&#8217;s time for Congress to do its job on both of those dimensions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
