<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:50:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Establishing the Fight Against Corruption as a Core U.S. National Security Interest</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-establishing-the-fight-against-corruption-as-a-core-u-s-national-security-interest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:50:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling corruption as an economic and national security priority, and has pledged to lead international efforts to bring transparency to the global financial system and close loopholes that undermine democracy.  As the Interim National Security Strategic Guidance states:  “We will take special aim at confronting corruption, which rots democracy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling corruption as an economic and national security priority, and has pledged to lead international efforts to bring transparency to the global financial system and close loopholes that undermine democracy.  As the Interim National Security Strategic Guidance states:</p>



<p><br> “We will take special aim at confronting corruption, which rots democracy from the inside and is increasingly weaponized by authoritarian states to undermine democratic institutions…We will crack down on tax havens and illicit financing that contribute to income inequality, fund terrorism, and generate pernicious foreign influence.” </p>



<p><br>Today, in line with this commitment, President Biden is releasing a National Security Study Memorandum (NSSM) that establishes the fight against corruption as a core national security interest of the United States. The NSSM directs a 200-day interagency review that will culminate in a report and recommendations on how the U.S. government and its partners can:<br><br><strong>Modernize, Coordinate, and Resource Efforts to Better Fight Corruption. </strong>Corruption threatens U.S. national security by eroding citizens’ faith in government, distorting economies, and enabling authoritarians to weaken democratic institutions. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to identify and where appropriate establish new structures and staffing, improve intelligence collection and analysis, and increase resources aimed at confronting corruption at home and abroad.<br><br><strong>Curb Illicit Finance. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration has pledged to lead efforts internationally to bring transparency to the U.S. and international financial systems, including by reducing offshore financial secrecy, seizing stolen assets, and making it more difficult for those who steal to hide behind anonymity. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to combat all forms of illicit finance, including through accelerating ongoing efforts to establish a “beneficial ownership” registry, so that illicit actors can’t hide the proceeds of corruption behind anonymous shell companies; limiting the ability of illicit actors to hide behind anonymity to buy residential real estate; and closing loopholes in existing regulatory regimes.   <br><br><strong>Hold Corrupt Actors Accountable. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to taking new steps to hold accountable corrupt individuals, transnational criminal organizations, and other actors engaged in illicit activity. This includes strengthening and building upon targeted anticorruption sanctions under the Global Magnitsky Act and similar authorities; and bolstering criminal or civil enforcement actions, such as under the Department of Justice’s Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative. It also means increasing support to grow the capacity of civil society, the media, state and local bodies, international partners, and other oversight and accountability actors.<br><br><strong>Build International Partnerships. </strong>As part of its commitment to strengthening America’s alliances and partnerships, the NSSM directs departments and agencies to work with like-minded international partners through the UN, G7, Financial Action Task Force (FATF), and similar bodies to counteract strategic corruption emanating from autocratic and kleptocratic governments, foreign state-owned or affiliated enterprises, and transnational criminal organizations. This work will include closing loopholes exploited by those actors in order to mask the proceeds of corruption or interfere in democratic processes. <br><br><strong>Improve Foreign Assistance. </strong>The United States partners with foreign governments and civil society to enhance the capacity of their domestic institutions to implement transparency, oversight, and accountability measures. The NSSM therefore directs departments and agencies to focus on anticorruption best practices and improve enforcement measures in the implementation of foreign assistance programs and security cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the National Security Study Memorandum on the Fight Against Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-national-security-study-memorandum-on-the-fight-against-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19563</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Strengthening the resilience of rights-respecting democracies is one of the defining challenges of our era.  Corruption eats away at the foundations of democratic societies. It makes government less effective, wastes public resources, and exacerbates inequalities in access to services, making it harder for families to provide for their loved ones.  Corruption attacks the foundations of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Strengthening the resilience of rights-respecting democracies is one of the defining challenges of our era.  Corruption eats away at the foundations of democratic societies. It makes government less effective, wastes public resources, and exacerbates inequalities in access to services, making it harder for families to provide for their loved ones.  Corruption attacks the foundations of democratic institutions, drives and intensifies extremism, and makes it easier for authoritarian regimes to corrode democratic governance.<br><br>Corruption is a risk to our national security, and we must recognize it as such.  <br><br>Today, I am issuing a National Security Study Memorandum on the Fight Against Corruption to establish combatting corruption as a core U.S. national security interest. With this Memorandum, I am directing departments and agencies to make recommendations that will significantly bolster the ability of the U.S. government to combat corruption.<br><br>The United States will lead by example and in partnership with allies, civil society, and the private sector to fight the scourge of corruption. But this is a mission for the entire the world. And, we must all stand in support of courageous citizens around the globe who are demanding honest, transparent governance.<br><br>Fighting corruption is not just good governance.  It is self-defense.  It is patriotism, and it’s essential to the preservation of our democracy and our future.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on Updates to the President’s Travel to the United Kingdom, Belgium, and Switzerland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-updates-to-the-presidents-travel-to-the-united-kingdom-belgium-and-switzerland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to the United Kingdom, Belgium, and Switzerland in June 2021. This will be the first overseas travel by President Biden, who will be joined by First Lady Jill Biden for the stops in the United Kingdom as previously announced. This trip will highlight America’s commitment to restoring our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to the United Kingdom, Belgium, and Switzerland in June 2021. This will be the first overseas travel by President Biden, who will be joined by First Lady Jill Biden for the stops in the United Kingdom as previously announced. This trip will highlight America’s commitment to restoring our alliances, revitalizing the Transatlantic relationship, and working in close cooperation with our allies and multilateral partners to address global challenges and better secure America’s interests.<br><br>President Biden will meet British Prime Minister Boris Johnson on June 10 to affirm the enduring strength of the special relationship between the United States and the United Kingdom. President Biden will attend the G7 Summit in Cornwall, U.K., which is happening from June 11-13, where he will reinforce our commitment to multilateralism, work to advance key U.S. policy priorities on public health, economic recovery, and climate change, and demonstrate solidarity and shared values among major democracies.  He will also hold bilateral meetings with fellow G7 leaders.<br> <br>On June 13, the President and Dr. Biden will meet Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth at Windsor Castle. Dr. Biden will return to the United States following this meeting.<br><br>From the United Kingdom, President Biden will travel to Brussels, Belgium, where he will participate in the NATO Summit on June 14. President Biden will affirm the United States’ commitment to NATO, Transatlantic security, and collective defense. NATO leaders will discuss how to orient the Alliance to future threats and ensure effective burden sharing. The President will also meet with Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdogan to discuss the full range of bilateral and regional issues.<br><br>While in Brussels President Biden will participate in the U.S.–EU Summit on June 15, which will underscore our commitment to a strong Transatlantic partnership based on shared interests and values. The leaders will discuss a common agenda to ensure global health security, stimulate global economic recovery, tackle climate change, enhance digital and trade cooperation, strengthen democracy, and address mutual foreign policy concerns. President Biden will also meet with His Majesty King Philippe of Belgium and Belgian Prime Minister Alexander De Croo.<br> <br>As previously announced, President Biden will then travel to Geneva, Switzerland where he will hold a bilateral summit with Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin on June 16. While in Geneva President Biden will also meet with Swiss President Guy Parmelin and Foreign Minister Ignazio Cassis.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Establishing the Fight Against Corruption as a Core United States National Security Interest</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/03/memorandum-on-establishing-the-fight-against-corruption-as-a-core-united-states-national-security-interest/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 14:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Section 1.  Policy.  Corruption corrodes public trust; hobbles effective governance; distorts markets and equitable access to services; undercuts development efforts; contributes to national fragility, extremism, and migration; and provides authoritarian leaders a means to undermine democracies worldwide.  When leaders steal from their nations&#8217; citizens or oligarchs flout the rule of law, economic growth slows, inequality widens, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1.  Policy. </span> Corruption corrodes public trust; hobbles effective governance; distorts markets and equitable access to services; undercuts development efforts; contributes to national fragility, extremism, and migration; and provides authoritarian leaders a means to undermine democracies worldwide.  When leaders steal from their nations&#8217; citizens or oligarchs flout the rule of law, economic growth slows, inequality widens, and trust in government plummets.<br><br>In financial terms alone, the costs of corruption are staggering.  It has been estimated that acts of corruption sap between 2 and 5 percent from global gross domestic product.  While such costs are not evenly shared worldwide, the abuse of power for private gain, the misappropriation of public assets, bribery, and other forms of corruption impact every country and community.  The proceeds of these acts cross national borders and can impact economies and political systems far from their origin.  Anonymous shell companies, opaque financial systems, and professional service providers enable the movement and laundering of illicit wealth, including in the United States and other rule-of-law-based democracies.<br><br>Corruption threatens United States national security, economic equity, global anti-poverty and development efforts, and democracy itself.  But by effectively preventing and countering corruption and demonstrating the advantages of transparent and accountable governance, we can secure a critical advantage for the United States and other democracies.<br><br>In issuing this National Security Study Memorandum, I establish countering corruption as a core United States national security interest.  My Administration will lead efforts to promote good governance; bring transparency to the United States and global financial systems; prevent and combat corruption at home and abroad; and make it increasingly difficult for corrupt actors to shield their activities.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 2.  Strategy.</span>  Accordingly, I hereby direct the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor, in coordination with the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy and the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy, to conduct an interagency review process under National Security Memorandum/NSM-2 (Renewing the National Security Council System) and develop a Presidential strategy that will, when implemented, significantly bolster the ability of the United States Government to: <br>     (a)  Modernize, increase, coordinate, resource, and otherwise improve the ability of key executive departments and agencies (agencies), including those represented in the review and listed below, to promote good governance and prevent and combat corruption, including, as needed, by proposing relevant legislation to the Congress;<br>     (b)  Combat all forms of illicit finance in the United States and international financial systems, including by robustly implementing Federal law requiring United States companies to report their beneficial owner or owners to the Department of the Treasury; reducing offshore financial secrecy; improving information sharing; and, as necessary, identifying the need for new reforms;<br>     (c)  Hold accountable corrupt individuals, transnational criminal organizations, and their facilitators, including by, and where appropriate, identifying, freezing, and recovering stolen assets through increased information sharing and intelligence collection and analysis, criminal or civil enforcement actions, advisories, and sanctions or other authorities, and, where possible and appropriate, returning recovered assets for the benefit of the citizens harmed by corruption;<br>     (d)  Bolster the capacity of domestic and international institutions and multilateral bodies focused on establishing global anti-corruption norms, asset recovery, promoting financial transparency, encouraging open government, strengthening financial institutions&#8217; frameworks to prevent corruption in development finance projects, and combating money laundering, illicit finance, and bribery, including, where possible, addressing the demand side of bribery;<br>     (e)  Support and strengthen the capacity of civil society, media, and other oversight and accountability actors to conduct research and analysis on corruption trends, advocate for preventative measures, investigate and uncover corruption, hold leaders accountable, and inform and support government accountability and reform efforts, and work to provide these actors a safe and open operating environment domestically and internationally;<br>     (f)  Work with international partners to counteract strategic corruption by foreign leaders, foreign state-owned or affiliated enterprises, transnational criminal organizations, and other foreign actors and their domestic collaborators, including, by closing loopholes exploited by these actors to interfere in democratic processes in the United States and abroad;<br>     (g)  Enhance efforts to quickly and flexibly increase United States and partner resources of investigative, financial, technical, political, and other assistance to foreign countries that exhibit the desire to reduce corruption;<br>     (h)  Assist and strengthen the capacity of domestic (including State and local) authorities and institutions, as well as partner and other foreign governments at all levels, to implement transparency, oversight, and accountability measures, which will counter corruption and provide their citizens with accessible and usable information regarding government programs, policies, and spending;<br>     (i)  Promote partnerships with the private sector and civil society to advocate for anti-corruption measures and take action to prevent corruption; and<br>     (j)  Establish best practices and enforcement mechanisms such that foreign assistance and security cooperation activities have built-in corruption prevention measures.  </p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 3.  Interagency Review.</span>  In accordance with this memorandum, the interagency review shall consider the recommendations of expert studies and shall include representatives from the following agencies and offices:<br>     (a)  the Office of the Vice President;<br>     (b)  the Department of State;<br>     (c)  the Department of the Treasury;<br>     (d)  the Department of Defense;<br>     (e)  the Department of Justice;<br>     (f)  the Department of Commerce;<br>     (g)  the Department of Energy;<br>     (h)  the Department of Homeland Security;<br>     (i)  the Office of Management and Budget;<br>     (j)  the United States Mission to the United Nations;<br>     (k)  the Office of the Director of National Intelligence;<br>     (l)  the Central Intelligence Agency;<br>     (m)  the Office of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff;<br>     (n)  the United States Agency for International Development; and<br>     (o)  the National Security Agency.<br><br>Executive departments and agencies shall be responsive to all requests from the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor for information, analysis, and assistance related to the interagency review.  The interagency review shall be completed within 200 days of the date of this memorandum, and the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor shall submit a report and recommendations to the President for further direction and action.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><br> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the Election of Isaac Herzog as the 11th President of the State of Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/02/statement-from-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-election-of-isaac-herzog-as-the-11th-president-of-the-state-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On behalf of the people of the United States, I extend my warm congratulations to Isaac Herzog on his election to serve as the 11th President of the State of Israel.&#160; Throughout his career, President-elect Herzog has demonstrated his unwavering commitment to strengthening Israel’s security, advancing dialogue, and building bridges across the global Jewish community.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On behalf of the people of the United States, I extend my warm congratulations to Isaac Herzog on his election to serve as the 11th President of the State of Israel.&nbsp; Throughout his career, President-elect Herzog has demonstrated his unwavering commitment to strengthening Israel’s security, advancing dialogue, and building bridges across the global Jewish community.&nbsp; I am confident that under his presidency, the partnership between Israel and the United States will continue to grow and deepen.</p>



<p>I also want to thank President Reuven Rivlin for his many years of service to the people of Israel.  I look forward to welcoming President Rivlin to Washington in the weeks ahead to honor his dedication to the enduring partnership and the close friendship between our two nations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s and Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh’s Meetings with German Counterparts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/02/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-and-deputy-national-security-advisor-daleep-singhs-meetings-with-german-counterparts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Dr. Jan Hecker, Foreign and Security Advisor to the German Chancellor, to discuss our close cooperation on a range of regional and global issues. They talked about the upcoming G7 leaders meeting and NATO summit, the importance of securing Europe’s energy future, collective efforts to share COVID-19&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Dr. Jan Hecker, Foreign and Security Advisor to the German Chancellor, to discuss our close cooperation on a range of regional and global issues. They talked about the upcoming G7 leaders meeting and NATO summit, the importance of securing Europe’s energy future, collective efforts to share COVID-19 vaccines, coordination on cybersecurity and response to ransomware attacks, and foreign policy priorities including Russia, Ukraine, Iran, the Sahel, and the Western Balkans. Experts from both governments discussed the Nord Stream 2 pipeline, including U.S. concerns about the risks it poses to Ukraine and European energy security.</p>



<p>Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh also met today with Professor Lars-Hendrik Röller, German Chancellery Chief of Division for Economic, Financial, and Labor Policy, to discuss a range of economic issues, including objectives for the upcoming G7 Leaders meetings, vaccine dose sharing, forced labor, post-COVID economic recovery, and 5G security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the COVID-19 Response and Vaccination Program</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/02/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-covid-19-response-and-vaccination-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 22:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 1:41 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT: Good afternoon. Today, the Vice President and I would like to lay out our plan for June, to counter &#8212; continue, I should say, our successful fight against the pandemic as we approach the July 4th date. In just four months, thanks to the American people, we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>1:41 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Good afternoon. Today, the Vice President and I would like to lay out our plan for June, to counter &#8212; continue, I should say, our successful fight against the pandemic as we approach the July 4th date.<br><br>In just four months, thanks to the American people, we have made incredible progress getting people vaccinated quickly, efficiently, and equitably. Nearly 170 million Americans of every party, every background, every walk of life have stepped up, rolled up their sleeves, and gotten the shot.<br><br>Fifty-two percent of adults are now fully vaccinated, including seventy-five percent of all seniors. Twenty-eight states and the District of Columbia have achieved 50 percent of adults being fully vaccinated in their jurisdictions.<br><br>And it’s clearer than ever: The more people we get vaccinated, the more success we’re going to have in our fight against this virus.<br><br>Since January 20 &#8212; and we’re talking, now, about <s>15</s> [5] months &#8212; the average daily cases are down from 184,000 to 19,000, below 20,000 for the first time since March of 2020. Average hospitalizations are down from 117,000 to 21,000. Death rates are down over 85 percent.<br><br>And this didn’t just happen by chance. We got to this moment because we took aggressive action from day one with a whole-of-government response. We used every lever at our disposal to get this done.<br><br>We experienced the production and expanded it in a significant way: in lifesaving vaccines available for every single American. They’re available, and we knew that was the case months ago.<br><br>We worked with cities and states to create over 80,000 vaccination sites. We deployed over 9,000 federal staff, including 5,100 active-duty troops to help get shots in arms. Now, as a result, we have built a world-class vaccination program.<br><br>I promised you we’d marshal a wartime effort to defeat this virus, and that’s just what we’ve been doing.<br><br>And now, tens of millions of Americans have been vaccinated. They’re able to return to closer to a &#8212; closer-to-normal life.<br><br>Fully vaccinated people are safely <s>shredding</s> [shedding] their masks and greeting one another with a smile. Grandparents are hugging their grandkids again. Small-business owners are reopening storefronts and restaurants.<br><br>Because of the vaccination strategy, our economic strategy, we’re &#8212; experienced the strongest economic recovery this country has seen in decades.<br><br>There is a group called the Organization of Economic Co-operation and Development &#8212; OECD &#8212; which includes most of the world’s largest economies in its membership. They’ve been one of those leading bodies analyzing economic growth across &#8212; around the world for 60 years.<br><br>Just this week, they increased their projection for the U.S. economic growth this year to 6.9 percent &#8212; 6.9 percent. That’s the fastest pace in nearly four decades. And that’s because of our vaccination program and our economic response, which, alone, are adding 3 to 4 percentage points to our growth; driving stronger growth not just there &#8212; not just this year, but in years to come.<br><br>In fact, America is the only major country where global forecasters have actually increased their five-year forecasts for economic growth since January of 2020.<br><br>And because of that, America is headed into the summer dramatically different from last year’s summer: a summer of freedom, a summer of joy, a summer of get-togethers and celebrations. An all-American summer that this country deserves after a long, long, dark winter that we’ve all endured.<br><br>But what happens after the summer? The data could not be clearer: For all the progress we’re making as a country, if you are unvaccinated, you are still at risk of getting seriously ill or dying, or spreading disease to others, especially when Americans spend more time indoors again, closely gathered in the fall, as &#8212; and as we face the potential threat of a new, more dangerous variants.&nbsp;<br><br>Even now, if you look at the areas of the country where vaccination rates are the highest, the death &#8212; the death rates are dramatically falling. They &#8212; the vaccines are effective; they’re effective against the variants currently circulating in the United States. On the other hand, COVID deaths are unchanged in many parts of our country that are lagging behind in vaccinations.<br><br>And for young people who may think this doesn’t affect you, listen up, please: This virus, even a mild case, can be with you for months. It will impact on your social life. It could have long-term implications for your health that we don’t even know about yet or fully understand yet.<br><br>It’s true that young people are much less likely to die from COVID. But if you do not get vaccinated, you could get COVID sooner or later. But you could get COVID still.<br><br>A substantial percentage of people with COVID, even young people, will suffer illnesses, and some will have long-term health impacts as a consequence.<br><br>If you’re thinking that the side effects from the shot are worse than the COVID, or that you can’t just take a chance, you are just dead wrong.<br><br>Do it for yourself. Do it to protect those more vulnerable than you: your friends, you family, your community.<br><br>You know, some people have questions about how quickly the vaccines were developed. They say they’ve been developed so quickly, they can’t be that good. Well, here’s what you need to know: Vaccines were developed over a decade of research in similar viruses, and they’ve gone through strict FDA clinical trials.<br><br>The bottom line is this &#8212; I promise you: They are safe. They are safe. And even more importantly, they’re extremely effective.<br><br>And if you’re vaccinated, you are protected. If you are not vaccinated, you are not protected.<br><br>Places with high vaccination rates will also see fewer cases of COVID moving forward. Places with lower vaccination rates are going to see more.<br><br>You know, we were elected to be President and Vice President for all Americans. And I don’t want to see the country that is already too divided become divided in a new way &#8212; between places where people live free from fear of COVID and places where, when the fall arrives, death and severe illnesses return.<br><br>The vaccine is free, it’s safe, and it’s effective. Getting the vaccine is not a partisan act. The science was done under Democratic and Republican administrations. Matter of fact, the first vaccines were authorized under a Republican President and widely developed by a Democratic President &#8212; deployed by a Democratic President.<br><br>All over the world, people are desperate to get a shot that every American can get at their neighborhood drug store at no cost, with no wait.<br><br>Every American over 12 years of age &#8212; no matter where you live, what you believe, who you voted for &#8212; has the right to get vaccinated. It’s your choice.<br><br>So, please, exercise your freedom, live without fear. We need to be one America, united &#8212; free from fear this fall.<br><br>Now, how will we keep beating this virus as we enter &#8212; as we enter the fall after summer? On May 4, I asked Americans to come together to get 70 percent of adults with one shot by July 4th &#8212; 70 percent at least with one shot. To date, 12 states have already reached this important milestone. We expect &#8212; we expect more to make this milestone this week.<br><br>Nationally, we are at 63 percent of adults with one shot. And we are getting closer, but we still have work to do. With 73 percent of Americans over the age of 40 with one shot, and as &#8212; we especially need people under 40 to step up. Over 40 is doing much better.<br><br>That’s why, today, we’re announcing a month-long effort to pull all the stops &#8212; all the stops to free ourselves from this virus and get to 70 percent of adult Americans vaccinated.<br><br>Now, I’m going to take everyone &#8212; you know, it’s going to take everyone &#8212; everyone &#8212; the federal government; the state governments; local, Tribal, and territorial governments; the private sector; and, most importantly, the American people &#8212; to get to the 70 percent mark so we can declare our independence from COVID-19 and free ourselves from the grip it has held over us &#8212; our lives for the better part of a year.<br><br>Each of you has the power to help us gain this freedom as a nation. If you get a shot this week, you can be fully vaccinated by July 4th &#8212; by the week of July the 4th. And you can celebrate Independence Day free from fear or worry.<br><br>This effort has five key parts. First, we’re making it easier than ever to get vaccinated. Ninety percent of you live within five miles of a vaccination site. The vaccinations are free, and most places allow walk-up vaccinations. No appointment needed.<br><br>You can go to Vaccines.gov or text your ZIP Code to 438829 to get a text back with the places you can get a shot that are close by.<br><br>And now, we’re going to make it even easier. In response to our call to action, businesses and organizations across the country have stepped up to help everyone get vaccinated.<br><br>Starting next week, many vaccination sites will be offering extended hours during the month of June, including pharmacies that will be open 24 hours every Friday night &#8212; for 24 hours they’ll be open &#8212; this month.<br><br>And if you’re too busy at work or school, you can get vaccinated around the clock on any Friday. Any Friday.<br><br>For parents who haven’t been able to get the shot because they didn’t have the childcare: Starting today, KinderCare, Learning Care Group, the Bright Horizons, alongside with hundreds of YMC- loc- &#8212; YMCA locations, are going to offer free drop-in childcare while the parents are getting vaccinated.<br><br>In addition, Uber and Lyft are both offering free rides to and from vaccination sites &#8212; vaccination centers. It&#8217;s easier than ever to get vaccinated.<br><br>So, again, text 438829 to vi- &#8212; to find out what the nearest places you can get vaccinated are from where you &#8212; from where your ZIP Code. And visit pharmacies with an extended-hour and walk-up shots that are available. Free childcare, free rides, free shots.<br><br>Second, we&#8217;re going to <s>reduce</s> [redouble] our outreach and public education efforts. We&#8217;re going to relaunch them, in effect. We&#8217;re going to launch a national vaccination tour to encourage people to take the shot. The Vice President is going to lead that tour across the South and the Midwest, where we still had millions of people to vaccinate.<br><br>She&#8217;s going to be joined by Jill &#8212; by the First Lady and the Second Gentleman and Cabinet Secretaries along the way.<br><br>In the spirit of meeting people where they are, we&#8217;ll also be working with the Black Coalition Against COVID and other organizations to launch a new initiative called &#8220;Shots at the Shop.&#8221; Barbershops, beauty shops are hubs of activity and information in Black and brown communities in particular, but in many communities across the nation. Local barbers, stylists, they become key advocates for vaccinations in their communities, offering information to customers, booking appointments for them, even using their own businesses as vaccination sites. We&#8217;re going to work with shops across the country to make an even bigger impact over the next month.<br><br>We&#8217;ll also kick things off this weekend with a National Canvassing Weekend, where thousands of volunteers will be out knocking on doors and encourage their communities to get vaccinated.<br><br>And mayors &#8212; mayors will be stepping up even more over the next month and partnering with us on the City Vaccination Challenge to see which city can grow its vaccination rate the fastest &#8212; the most &#8212; by July 4th.<br><br>We need you to join these efforts. This is the kind of on-the-ground work that’s going to get the job done.<br><br>Third, we&#8217;ll be increasing our work with employers &#8212; employers. A lot of working people are holding back because they&#8217;re concerned about losing pay if they take time off to get a shot, or if they don&#8217;t feel well the next day. I&#8217;ve said before: For small- and medium-sized employers, if you give people paid time off to get a shot, you&#8217;ll get a tax credit to cover that cost.<br><br>Already, millions of workers across the country are eligible for paid time off and incentives from their employers. I&#8217;m asking all employers: Do the right thing.<br><br>And we&#8217;re making it easy for employers to set up on-the-job vaccination clinics to make it even more convenient for their employees to get a shot.<br><br>Fourth, we&#8217;re going to continue encouraging people to get vaccinated with incentives and fun rewards. The state of Ohio had a heck of a fun reward &#8212; a new millionaire last week &#8212; thanks to the creative idea of the governor for holding a vaccination &#8212; a vaccine lottery.<br><br>The grocery store, Kroger, announced that they&#8217;re going to give away $1 million each week to someone who gets vaccinated at one of their pharmacies.<br><br>The NBA, the NHL, NASCAR &#8212; NASCAR tracks &#8212; they&#8217;re offering vaccine- &#8212; vaccines outside playoff games and at races. Major League Baseball will be offering free tickets to people who get vaccinated at the ballpark.<br><br>And to top it off, Anheuser-Busch announced that beer is on them on July the 4th. That&#8217;s right, get a shot and have a beer. Free beer for everyone 21 years or over to celebrate the independence from the virus.<br><br>Fifth, and finally, we&#8217;re asking the American people to help. We need you. We need you to get your friends, family, neighbors, and coworkers vaccinated. Help them find an appointment. Drive them to the site. Talk to them about why you made the choice for yourself. So many Americans have already stepped up to help get their communities vaccinated.<br><br>And over the next month, we&#8217;re going to need you more than ever. We need every American to commit to the five actions I&#8217;ve mentioned this month.<br><br>Go to WeCanDoThis.HHS.gov &#8212; WeCanDoThis.HHS.gov &#8212; to sign up to volunteer and learn more about how you can help.<br><br>Take at least five actions to help in June. And you might even be invited to visit us at the White House in July to celebrate independence together.<br><br>I&#8217;ll close with this: We need everyone across the country to pull together to get us over the finish line. I promise you we can do this. Just look at what we&#8217;ve already done &#8212; we&#8217;ve already accomplished together in only four months.<br><br>We know it for a fact: Americans could do anything when we do it together. So, please, do your part. Give it your all through July the 4th. Let&#8217;s reach our 70 percent goal. Let&#8217;s go into the summer freer and safer. Let&#8217;s celebrate a truly historic Independence Day.<br><br>Thank you for listening. Please get engaged. May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops. Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Mr. President, will you retaliate against Russia for this latest ransomware attack?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT: We&#8217;re looking closely at that issue.<br><br>Q&nbsp; Do you think Putin is testing you?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT: No.<br><br>1:58 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Louisiana Disaster Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/02/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-louisiana-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 21:52:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Louisiana and ordered federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, tornadoes, and flooding from May 17 to May 21, 2021. The President&#8217;s action makes Federal funding available to affected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Louisiana and ordered federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, tornadoes, and flooding from May 17 to May 21, 2021.</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s action makes Federal funding available to affected individuals in the parishes of Ascension, Calcasieu, East Baton Rouge, Iberville, and Lafayette.</p>



<p>Assistance can include grants for temporary housing and home repairs, low-cost loans to cover uninsured property losses, and other programs to help individuals and business owners recover from the effects of the disaster.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named John E. Long as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>Residents and business owners who sustained losses in the designated parishes can begin applying for assistance by registering online at <a href="http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov">http://www.DisasterAssistance.gov</a> or by calling 1-800-621-FEMA(3362) or 1-800-462-7585 (TTY) for the hearing and speech impaired.&nbsp; The toll-free telephone numbers will operate from 7:00 a.m. to 9:00 p.m. (local time) seven days a week until further notice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, June 2, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/02/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-june-2-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 21:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:27 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Happy Wednesday.  Don&#8217;t be distracted by Andrew&#8217;s fabulous seersucker suit over here.  (Laughter.) Okay, a couple of items for all of you at the top.  The President is running a little bit late too, so we&#8217;ll have a hard out at about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:27 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Happy Wednesday.  Don&#8217;t be distracted by Andrew&#8217;s fabulous seersucker suit over here.  (Laughter.)<br><br>Okay, a couple of items for all of you at the top.  The President is running a little bit late too, so we&#8217;ll have a hard out at about five or ten after, but we&#8217;ll keep you honest, for those of you who are joining his event.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris administration launched the Low-Income Household Water Assistance Program, a first-of-its-kind water assistance program that will expand access to more affordable water, and help low-income households affected by the COVID-19 pandemic pay their water and wastewater bills, avoid shutoffs, and support household water system reconnections related to non-payment.  $166.6 million, or 15 percent of allocated program funding, is being made immediately available to grantees, which will then, of course, be distributed in communities.<br><br>In total, $1.1 billion will be available through grants, including $500 million in American Rescue Plan funding.<br><br>The President believes that having access to affordable, clean, and safe drinking water is essential to everybody’s health and wellbeing. <br><br>A little preview of the President’s remarks for later this afternoon: We have now vaccinated 63 percent of<s> the country</s> [adults], and over 72 percent of those 40 and older are vaccinated thanks to aggressive action by this administration.  COVID-19 cases and deaths have plummeted as a result.  Cases are down over 90 percent.  Deaths are down over 85 percent since January 20th.  The fact remains: If you are not vaccinated, you are at risk of getting the virus or spreading it to someone else.<br><br>So, today, the President will announce the launch of a month of action to mobilize an all-of-America sprint to get more people vaccinated by July 4th.  Community leaders, faith partners, businesses, celebrities, athletes, colleges, and thousands of volunteers will participate in this nationwide campaign. <br><br>And as part of the month of action, we’re making it even easier to get vaccinated, which, as we&#8217;ve seen, is the key to increasing numbers and getting more shots in arms. <br><br>So the nation’s largest childcare providers will watching &#8212; will be watching kids for free while parents get the shot.  Vaccines will happen at barber shops, baseball games, and NASCAR races.  Pharmacies will be open 24 hours on Fridays.<br><br>And throughout our time in office, we’ve seen &#8212; we&#8217;ve led a whole-of-government effort to get the vaccine out.  So this next month, we’re continuing to build on that by leading canvassing, phone banking, texting into areas with low vaccination rates; coordinating vaccine events.  More than 100 organizations have committed to hosting over a thousand events the first weekend alone.  And we&#8217;re also launching a National Vaccination Tour.  The Vice President will lead a tour to key communities across the South and Midwest.  That will be coming up. <br><br>And we&#8217;re launching a Mayors Challenge &#8212; and you&#8217;ve seen a little bit of activity about this already &#8212; where cities compete to boost vaccination rates through canvassing, local partnerships, and incentives for people. <br><br>And through the COVID-19 College Challenge, more than 230 colleges and universities are taking pledge &#8212; taking pledge and commit &#8212; taking a pledge and committing to taking action to get their students and communities vaccinated.<br><br>And finally, businesses like Anheuser-Busch, Kroger, and DoorDash are stepping up to offer all adults free beer on July 4th, the chance to win a million dollars, and free meals for people who get vaccinated at community health centers. <br><br>We&#8217;ve seen Krispy Kreme has done this.  I would not recommend a Krispy Kreme with a beer, but I&#8217;ll leave that to other people to decide. <br><br>Finally, the President wants to convey his heartfelt congratulations to Congresswoman-elect Melanie Stansbury on her decisive victory last night, marking the first time in over 100 years that a special election has been won by a larger margin than their party received in the previous general election.  He looks forward to working with her in Congress.  <br><br>Alex, why don&#8217;t you kick us off. <br><br>Q    Sure.  I have a couple of questions.  First, on JBS, can you confirm that a ransom demand came from REvil?  I know it&#8217;s a criminal organization likely based in Russia.  And was the ransom paid? <br><br>And then, can you speak a little bit about &#8212; have you seen any progress on this call from the government for business and private sector to work with the federal government in updating their cybersecurity measures?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  On the last part, I&#8217;m not in a place to confirm the specifics of the ransom request or the origin.  Obviously, our team is continuing to evaluate.  And I would send you to the company for any specific questions about the ransom request. <br><br>I will say that this attack is a reminder about the importance to private sector entities of hardening their cybersecurity and ensuring that they take the necessary steps to prepare for this threat, which we&#8217;ve seen rising even over the last few weeks.<br><br>As it relates to actions we&#8217;re taking in the federal government, the President has launched a rapid strategic review to address the increased threat of ransomware, to include four major lines of effort:<br><br>Disruption of ransomware infrastructure and actors.  Working closely with the private sector &#8212; we will work in partnership with them.  That is something that this administration has done a bit differently than in the past in working to find best practices, ensuring that private sector entities have a seat at the table, and we can work in close coordination.<br><br>Building an international coalition to hold countries who harbor ransom actors accountable.  I mean, this attack is an example of how this is not just a problem in the United States.  These are actors that are working to get into systems around the world.  This was a company obviously based in Brazil, but Australia was a major &#8212; was impacted also by this. <br><br>Expanding cryptocurrency analysis &#8212; obviously, this has been an increasing question out there &#8212; to find and pursue criminal transactions.<br><br>And reviewing our own ransomware policies. <br><br>So this is an internal policy process &#8212; essentially, one that&#8217;s looking at all of these entities within our national security/economic team.<br><br>Q    And then, on the President&#8217;s comments yesterday, he seemed to call out Manchin and Sinema for &#8212; he said, voting &#8220;more with…Republicans&#8221; than Democrats.  But ProPublica actually found that they&#8217;ve so far voted with Biden 100 percent of time on major votes.  And so can you explain where those comments came from and why he felt the need to call out members of his own party?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, first, that if Senator Manchin and Senator Sinema were standing with me here today &#8212; they&#8217;re always welcome &#8212; they would call out their own independent streaks, and that&#8217;s something that I think they&#8217;re both proud of.  They both vote for and represent the people in the states that &#8212; and all the people who elected them to represent them in the Senate. <br><br>If you look at what the Senate &#8212; the President said &#8212; the big tell here is, &#8220;I hear all the folks on TV saying.&#8221;  Now, as a former TV pundit myself, I can tell you that sometimes these conversations can be oversimplified.  TV isn&#8217;t always made for complex conversations about policymaking.  We all know that.  Right? <br><br>And what the President was simply conveying is that he &#8212; his threshold, his litmus test is not to see eye to eye on every single detail of every issue &#8212; and he doesn&#8217;t with Senator Sinema and Senator Manchin, and he doesn&#8217;t with Senator Capito, who&#8217;s coming here later this afternoon.  He believes there&#8217;s an opportunity to work together, to make progress, to find areas of common ground even if you have areas of disagreement. <br><br>And he also believes that sometimes, because there are three entities &#8212; three branches of government &#8212; something he knows well, having served 36 years in the Senate &#8212; that sometimes it&#8217;s not a straight line to victory or success; that sometimes, you know, it takes more time and, you know, he is open to many paths forward.<br><br>So I don&#8217;t think he was intending to convey other &#8212; anything other than a little bit of commentary on TV punditry.<br><br>Q    Well, he did seem to suggest that he is in favor of filibuster reform and wants to see that move.  So why hasn&#8217;t he been more prominent in calling for that?  And is he pressuring Manchin and Sinema to move on that issue privately?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I wouldn&#8217;t say that his comments yesterday were conveying a new position on his view on the filibuster.  His full comment was &#8212;<br><br>Q    But what did he mean by saying that Manchin and Sinema are standing in the way of his agenda, essentially?  What was he referencing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  That&#8217;s not exactly what he said.  I think it&#8217;s important to quote him directly.  What he said was: I hear all the folks on TV saying, “Why doesn&#8217;t Biden get this done?”  Well, because Biden only has a majority of, effectively, four votes in the House and a tie in the Senate, with two members of the Senate who vote more with my Republican friends. <br><br>He&#8217;s not &#8212; he was not giving a specific commentary on a policy.  He was conveying, again, that sometimes that&#8217;s the summary &#8212; shorthand version that he sees on cable news at times.  Again, it&#8217;s not always the forum that&#8217;s easy to provide guidance on how a bill becomes a law.<br><br>His view on the filibuster continues to be that there should be a path forward for Democrats and Republicans to make voting easier, to move forward on progress for the American people.  That position hasn&#8217;t changed.  And he was not intending to convey something different. <br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Back on the ransomware attack, is the U.S. going to retaliate?  And, realistically, what options are on the table?  Is a counterattack an option?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  Well, one, let me say &#8212; not to get ahead of your line of questioning, but I assume this will be a question.  So we do expect this to be one of the issues that the President will discuss with President Putin at the summit.  That will be two weeks from today, if my &#8212; if my calendar is correct in my mind. <br><br>And in terms of considerations of &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re not taking any options off the table, in terms of how we may respond.  But, of course, there&#8217;s an internal policy review process to consider that.  We&#8217;re in direct touch with the Russians, as well, to convey our concerns about these reports. <br><br>Q    You mentioned the meeting.  When it comes to this issue, what does success look like at that discussion?  I mean, what are you looking to accomplish when the President walks away from that table, when it comes to cybersecurity?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, let me say that, you know, this is an issue that we have discussed with the Russian government &#8212; this specific issue &#8212; and we&#8217;ve discussed it in the past, and delivered the message that responsible states do not harbor ransomware criminals.<br><br>As we&#8217;ve also noted from here, and I noted in the beginning: Obviously, ransomware attacks &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen them increase over a period of time.  It&#8217;s an increasing threat to the private sector and to our critical infrastructure.  And there are other countries, many of whom we will see when the President is in Europe, who have similar concerns.  So we expect this to be an issue of discussion throughout the President&#8217;s trip, I will say.<br><br>In terms of what success looks like coming out of the summit, I can&#8217;t predict that at this point in time.  But I can convey to you that this will certainly be a topic of discussion &#8212; that harboring criminal entities that are intending to do harm, that are doing harm to the critical infrastructure in the United States is not acceptable.  We&#8217;re not going to stand by that; we will raise that, and we are not going to take options off the table.<br><br>Q    And in those conversations with the Russian government so far, do you get a sense that they are taking this seriously?  Are they going to be taking steps to try and stop these bad actors?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I am &#8212; as I&#8217;ve said before, I&#8217;m blissfully not a spokesperson for the Kremlin, so I will let them speak for themselves.  But I can assure you that we are raising this through the highest levels of the U.S. government.  It will be a topic of discussion in direct, one-on-one discussions &#8212; or direct discussions with President Putin and President Biden happening in just a couple of weeks. <br><br>And certainly, protecting our own infrastructure in the United States is of the utmost national security importance. <br><br>Q    And just one more on this topic, because the Russians are outlining some of the things they would also like to discuss during the summit.  The foreign minister, Lavrov, indicated that Russia wants to be discussing the human rights violations in the U.S., saying they&#8217;re following with interest the persecution of those persons who are accused of the riots on January 6 this year.  I&#8217;m wondering what you make of that.  Where do you think this is coming from?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we don&#8217;t use the Russian government as our guide to human rights models in the world.  But I will say that the President has not held back in his view that the attacks on January 6th were a mark on democracy, were a dark day in our own democracy.  And certainly, I’m sure he’d be happy to repeat that.<br><br>But the President’s view is that there are a range of topics that we should be discussing in this meeting.  We’ll have more to preview for it, probably in the days in advance of this summit, including on &#8212; his agenda is, of course, these cyberattacks and the use of ransomware, harboring criminal entities in your own country; also is their aggressive actions in Ukraine; and also is &#8212; are areas where there can be an opportunity to work together, including nuclear capabilities and security.  So, lots to discuss.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Just to put a fine point on this very quickly: Is it President Biden&#8217;s view that President Putin can stop these attacks, these hacks, from occurring if he wanted to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say the President &#8212; President Biden certainly thinks that President Putin and the Russian government has a role to play in stopping and preventing these attacks; hence, it&#8217;s a &#8212; it will be a topic of discussion when they meet in two weeks. <br><br>Q    Does the President believe that Vladimir Putin is testing him right now, ahead of the summit?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not going to give any further analysis on that other than to tell you that our view is that when there are criminal entities within a country, they certainly have a responsibility, and it is a role that the government can play.  And, again, that will be a discussion at the summit.<br><br>Q    Of all the threats that the White House has to juggle right now &#8212; and, of course, there are a lot &#8212; how high does ransomware fall on that list right now?  Has it gone dramatically higher in the course of this administration?  Does it need to be higher than it is right now?  Where is it? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  You know how I love rank ordering our focuses and our threats.  (Laughs.)<br><br>Q    How &#8212; but it’s been growing dramatically, obviously.  Right? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  That is true.  And I &#8212;<br><br>Q    This is now a bigger issue.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  And, Peter, I just said that.  I think that this is &#8212; this attack that we&#8217;ve seen over the last couple of days, and certainly following the attack that we saw several weeks ago, is also a reminder to the private sector about the need and the importance of hardening their own cybersecurity protections, of investing in and putting in place protections in their own systems. <br><br>We have given guidance for some time, from the federal government, and it is up to a number of these private sector entities to protect themselves as well.<br><br>Q    The Steamship Authority in Massachusetts reports that they were just the victims of a hack.  Has that been communicated to the White House?  Are you involved?  Do you have any comment or message, or anybody to attribute that to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I have seen those reports.  They &#8212; they just came out. <br><br>Q    They just reported it.  Yeah.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Yes, exactly.  I just don&#8217;t have anything more for you on it, but we can see if there&#8217;s more later this afternoon.<br><br>Q    All good.  Last one, if I can, then.  In March, we heard from the National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan.  He came in here and told us that the U.S., “in the near future” &#8212; to his words &#8212; would name who&#8217;s responsible for the hack on the Microsoft Exchange. <br><br>So can you tell us who that is &#8212; multiple &#8212; several months have passed &#8212; and what the holdup might be? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m happy to check with our national security team and see if they have an update.  As you know, they are quite careful and thorough &#8212; I should say, “thorough” is probably the right word &#8212; in how they review and assess and provide public guidance.  But we can see if there&#8217;s anything more they can report out.<br><br>Q    Is the prevailing theory still that it&#8217;s China?  Or are you &#8212; can you not go any further than he did then?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t think I have an update on it from what we&#8217;ve provided in the past. <br><br>Q    Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Go ahead. <br><br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Why does the White House think there&#8217;s a shortage of workers right now? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we&#8217;ve talked about this a bit in the past, but I’m happy to go through it. <br><br>So, one, our view is that it&#8217;s going to take time for workers to regain confidence in the safety of the workplace; reestablish childcare, school, and commuting arrangements; and finish getting vaccinated.  And even when individuals get their first dose &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen a huge increase in that, as I started the briefing talking about &#8212; it&#8217;s about a five- to six-week cycle.  So we have expected that to have an impact.<br><br>At the same time, as we look at all of the data, we know that our economy is growing faster than at any time &#8212; than any time in the last 40 years.  We&#8217;re creating an average of 500,000 jobs a month, up from 60,000 a month before the President took office.  And we&#8217;re continuing to put in place policies and measures to ensure that we&#8217;re helping people make ends meet and we&#8217;re helping the economy continue to grow. <br><br>Q    And you mentioned thoughts about safety.  You&#8217;re celebrating the number of vaccinations today.  You say the vaccines work.  COVID cases are way down.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  You’re right.<br><br>Q    Is there any thought here that some of the worker shortage could be driven by the extra $300 in weekly unemployment benefits through September? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I will say, Peter, that our economists and our assessment and the assessment of many economists out there is that the impact &#8212; the largest impact are on issues related to the pandemic. <br><br>And, yes, you&#8217;re right that the increased numbers &#8212; that&#8217;s a good sign; it&#8217;s a positive sign.  But it&#8217;s a five- to six-week cycle.  So the data that was taken for the May jobs number &#8212; the jobs numbers that came out for April and early May was from early April.  That&#8217;s almost two months ago, right?  We&#8217;ll see.  We&#8217;ll have jobs numbers come out on Friday.<br><br>People &#8212; the vaccination rates are continuing to go up.  But in terms of people being fully safe, fully vaccinated, it&#8217;s going to take some time.  We always expected that to be a couple of months, and we expect to see continuing improvement in the numbers.<br><br>Q    On the JBS hack, these hackers based in Russia have disrupted American gas supplies and American meat supplies.  Why do you think that these ransomware attacks have been rising since President Biden took office? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would say these are private sector entities who have a responsibility to put in place measures to protect their own cybersecurity.<br><br>As it relates to why criminal actors are taking actions against private sector entities, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m the right one to speak to that.<br><br>Q    So, a total coincidence?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I think you could certainly go track down those cyber criminals in Russia and have a good chat with them. <br><br>Q    Okay.  If you have any leads, we&#8217;ll take that.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.<br><br>Q    And then, on immigration, has the President or the Vice President seen the video from last Friday of a five-year- old boy dropped off along the border, yelling to the adults who abandoned him, “No, no, don&#8217;t go &#8212; no”? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I&#8217;ve seen the video.  It is heartbreaking and the reason we continue to be very clear: Irregularly migrating to the United States puts ourselves and others at risk.  That&#8217;s why we relate &#8212; relaunched certain efforts to build a more fair and orderly immigration system, including programs like the Central American Minors Program that allows kids who are eligible to apply from within country. <br><br>But I don&#8217;t think anyone, whether a parent or not, would have watched that video and not feel heartbroken by a five-year- old, I think, screaming at the border.<br><br>Q    Thanks.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Go ahead. <br><br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  A couple of questions about the COVID numbers.  You talked about the latest vaccination rates.  Does the Biden administration still consider herd immunity to be realistic and achievable? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, first, that Dr. Fauci has spoken to this in the kind of terminology of herd immunity and, kind of, refuted that as the right definition of how we should look to how we&#8217;re going to make progress.  And that&#8217;s why we have set out a goal of getting 70 percent of the American population vaccinated by July 4th.  There&#8217;s still a lot of work to do.  About a dozen states have met that requirement.  That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re launching this big initiative over the past &#8212; over the next month.<br><br>But what Dr. Fauci and other medical experts have conveyed is that it&#8217;s really going to be up to local communities and states to see what their vaccination rate is and make determinations about what&#8217;s going to work locally.  It&#8217;s &#8212; that is how the assessments will need to be made. <br><br>Q    And you talked about the 90 percent drop in cases.  Does the White House worry that as the number of cases drops, that these holdouts will actually be more reluctant to get vaccinated because they won&#8217;t be as worried that they themselves will get sick? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, that&#8217;s one of the reasons why continuing to reiterate that if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, you are not safe.  You&#8217;re not safe against others who are not vaccinated who may carry the virus.  The individuals who can benefit from all of the new guidance the CDC has put out, who can go to concerts and go to baseball games &#8212; I was going to say football; not quite there yet &#8212; go to their kids&#8217; soccer games and not wear a mask, those are vaccinated individuals. <br><br>There&#8217;s huge incentives to getting vaccinated, but it doesn&#8217;t mean that individuals who are not vaccinated are safe from getting the virus.<br><br>And while, yes, we&#8217;ve made a lot of progress, there are still communities where the percentage is higher than it should be, where there are still larger numbers of young adults who are not vaccinated; those are many of the communities that we’re focused on in our month-long effort.<br><br>Q    In the President&#8217;s speech yesterday, when he laid out his new economic equity measures, one of the things he didn&#8217;t talk about was student loan forgiveness, and that&#8217;s something he talked about a lot on the campaign trail. <br><br>We know that student debt is a big driver in racial &#8212; in economic inequality.  So why didn&#8217;t he include that?  And where &#8212; where does the White House want to go on that issue?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would say that one of the ways anyone can know out there about how much the President cares about student debt and student loans is by simply looking at his budget and the budget he proposed and rolled out last Friday.  He makes two years of community college free, along with a major increase in Pell grants that will drastically reduce the cost of an education beyond high school. <br><br>The American Families Plan, which he proposed, we still need to get it, of course, signed into law &#8212; or passed and signed into law, which is included also in the President&#8217;s budget.  It includes a historic $47 billion of investments in HBCUs, Tribal colleges and universities, and minority-serving institutions.  And these institutions are critical to helping underrepresented students move to the top of the income ladder. <br><br>And so President Biden is calling for a historic investment in these areas, and those are things that are laid out specifically in his budget and shows his desire and commitment to level the playing field and provide necessary assistance.<br><br>Q    But why doesn&#8217;t the budget include $10,000 in student loan debt forgiveness, for example?  That&#8217;s something that he called on Congress to do when he was a candidate.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  And he&#8217;d be happy to sign a bill into law if they passed that bill, and he’d look forward to having it on his desk.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  Just a couple of follow-ups on JBS.  Obviously, the White House is engaging directly with Russia on this, and we were wondering if Russia has offered any cooperation or help in tracking down these hackers. <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m just not going to be reading out Russia&#8217;s view or their role here.  You can certainly ask them those questions. <br><br>Q    And considering &#8212; this is obviously the third Russia-linked attack this year, and we understand that the President will bring this up in his meeting with President Putin &#8212; but is the administration really considering any actions in addition to that, just to make sure that this doesn&#8217;t happen?  Sanctions or any other actions that are perhaps on the table? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  I mean, as I said, I think, in response to an earlier question: We&#8217;re not taking options off of the table. <br><br>But it&#8217;s just an opportunity &#8212; there will be an opportunity for the President to discuss this directly with President Putin, to reiterate the fact that we believe that responsible states do not harbor ransomware criminals and that &#8212; and as he said, as we said, around Colonial and the Colonial hack &#8212; or the Colonial ransomware attack &#8212; we will continue to be in direct touch with Moscow.  We will continue to make the case that responsible countries need to take decisive action against ransomware networks.<br><br>At the same time, as I noted a little bit earlier too, we&#8217;re doing our own review of a range of options as well from here. <br><br>Q    And I have one on the surplus vaccines.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure. <br><br>Q    Has there been any decision made on those 80 million vaccines?  And will the President offer any updates on that today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  He won’t offer any updates on that today. Hopefully, we’ll have more for you on that soon.  I know there&#8217;s a lot of interest.  And as I&#8217;ve noted earlier &#8212; or previously &#8212; what we want to do is not just convey, hopefully, some of &#8212; where some of the vaccine may be going, but also what our approach will be to ensure that it is distributed in an equitable manner around the world.  So all of that would be a part of any announcement at the appropriate time.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  During the campaign, Biden promised to host a summit for democracy during the first year of his presidency.  Can you give us an update on if that&#8217;s taking place, when it might take place? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have any date or schedule for you.  We have some time left in the year, fortunately, but I don&#8217;t have any update for you on the timing.<br><br>Q    Is he still planning to do it in his first year?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  That &#8212; that still remains the plan. <br><br>Q    Okay.  And then can you say anything more about the specific mandate that the President gave to the Vice President on voting &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br><br>Q    &#8212; that he mentioned yesterday?  I mean, is there &#8212; how is he going to measure success on that? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, let me say that the President sees the Vice President as an important partner and somebody who can work to take on challenging and hard initiatives.  That&#8217;s the role of the modern-day Vice President.  And she actually asked to run point and lead on voting rights.  It&#8217;s an issue that she is personally committed to and passionate about.<br><br>As she conveyed in her statement yesterday, she expects in the week &#8212; weeks ahead to engage not just with the American people, but with voting rights organizations, community organizations, the private sector to help strengthen and uplift &#8212; uplift efforts on voting rights nationwide.  That includes working with members of Congress, certainly, to move legislation forward &#8212; something the President strongly supports.  It also includes working with local organizations, working with states to see how to make voting more accessible to people across the country. <br><br>So, I think the President is looking to work with the Vice President as a partner and e- &#8212; and looking forward to her taking on this important initiative, something that&#8217;s a priority to him as well.  And I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;ll be regularly updated on her progress.<br><br>Q    Does he expect the Vice President to travel to these states that have imposed voting restrictions in their state laws?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I think the Vice President will have more to say about what &#8212; how she will approach this effort.  As you know, she&#8217;s traveling to the Northern Triangle over the next couple of days on one of the other initiatives she&#8217;s leading, but I expect she’ll have more to say in the coming weeks.<br><br>Q    And just briefly, how does he expect the Vice President to prioritize these multiple things that she has in her &#8212; in her agenda?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, just as the President has to balance a number of different priorities &#8212; whether it&#8217;s the American Jobs Plan or working to protect us from ransomware attacks or preparing for an international summit and all of the other entities that are on the President&#8217;s plate &#8212; a modern-day Vice President does the same thing.<br><br>So he&#8217;s confident in her ability to take on a robust agenda, which she certainly has on her plate.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Yeah, thanks, Jen.  I&#8217;m curious if you can kind of describe &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I’ll come to you next. <br><br>Sorry, go ahead.<br><br>Q    I&#8217;m sorry.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  It’s okay.  Go ahead.<br><br>Q    No, go ahead.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Oh, so chivalrous there.  Go ahead.  Okay.<br><br>Q    Okay.<br><br>Q    I&#8217;m just curious &#8212; (laughter).  See how I did that? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sorry, we’ll come back to you.<br><br>Q    If you can describe for us: How thin is the President&#8217;s patience when it comes to negotiating some of these bipartisan agreements he wants to see &#8212; not just with infrastructure today, but, for example, whether it&#8217;s police reform or the Jobs Plan &#8212; at some point, does he say to his fellow Democrats, “We just have to go at it alone”?  And then does that mean we&#8217;re going to see more executive orders as a result?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would say that the President has a bit of experience legislating, and his approach is to look for means, ways we can find common ground.  That&#8217;s exactly what he&#8217;s going to do when he meets with Senator Capito this afternoon. <br><br>“Negotiations” mean both sides continue to make moves toward each other, both sides continue to look for areas where they agree.  And that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s prepared to do, and he&#8217;s hopeful this meeting is an opportunity to do.<br><br>At the same time, we&#8217;re working on a number of different paths.  There&#8217;s discussions between bipartisan members in the Senate about how they might come to agreement on a path forward on a historic investment in infrastructure, on a version of the American Jobs Plan.  He&#8217;s eager to see what they have to offer.<br><br>We also know, next week, Congressman DeFazio is going to be marking up the American Jobs Plan in the House &#8212; something a lot of members and Democrats in the House are quite excited about. <br><br>So, I would say that we&#8217;re working on many channels.  He&#8217;s going to have discussions with all of these entities and parties.  And he knows that sometimes in this journey and this path, you have to keep a range of options on the table.<br><br>Q    And his level of patience?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say he wouldn&#8217;t have been in the Senate for 36 years if he wasn&#8217;t quite patient.  So &#8212; but, you know, him &#8212; patience is not unending, and he wants to make progress. His only line in the sand is inaction.  He wants to sign a bill into law this summer. <br><br>But I would also remind you that the American Rescue Plan passed in a very quick timeline for how legislation moves forward &#8212; very fast. <br><br>And there&#8217;s historic legislation &#8212; the Affordable Care Act, for example, the Vi- &#8212; the President worked closely on &#8212; that took a year.  We&#8217;re not advising that&#8217;s the timeline, but just to suggest that sometimes these efforts can take a little bit of time. <br><br>He&#8217;s working to move things forward.  And there are certainly items on &#8212; you know, the clock is certainly ticking because there are items like the markup next week that will drive discussion by members of Congress.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    So the President has talked a lot about seeing democracy as under attack.  And his speech Monday, I think &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br><br>Q    &#8212; was pretty blunt about that. <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q    He talked a lot about voting rights in that speech.  Can you just clarify how he sees the stakes of these bills, like in Texas?  Does he truly see them as an existential threat to democracy?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say that, first, he believes that the Texas legislation is a part of a concerted attack on our democracy being advanced, as we see &#8212; have seen, not just in Texas, as you well know, but in states across the country, on the basis of the same repeatedly disproven lies that led to the assault on our nation&#8217;s Capitol on January 6th.<br><br>So, that is, of course, of great concern to the President.  He thinks that must stop.  It must be easier, not harder, for all eligible voters to vote &#8212; to register and cast their ballots.  We need to move forward and not backward. <br><br>And the fact of the matter is that the Texas legislation would make it harder to vote in a state where it is already too hard for many people to vote, but it&#8217;s not the only state where we&#8217;re seeing this troubling trend.<br><br>But this is one of the reasons why he asked his Vice &#8212; or he &#8212; she asked for it, but he certainly was thrilled to have her leading the effort on voting rights moving forward, given this is a huge priority to him and a huge priority to her as well. <br><br>Q    A question on a much different scope.  I have a follow-up on the free beer announcement.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  (Laughs.)<br><br>Q    Can you just clarify, because Anheuser-Busch says this is in partnership with the White House.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q    Can you clarify what that means?  Is like the federal government subsidizing this at all?  And also, are there any concerns that this is kind of &#8212; the way that they&#8217;re going about this &#8212; with like, “Upload a picture of yourself” &#8212; that there&#8217;s any sort of data-harvesting aspect of this promotion?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think all that “in partnership” means is that we&#8217;ve been encouraging private sector entities to take actions to incentivize people to get vaccinated, given we know that will ensure that more Americans have shots in their arms, are safe, are healthy, and communities can return back to normal. <br><br>You know, obviously, as it relates, we take data security and people&#8217;s privacy incredibly seriously.  And, certainly, if there was an area of concern, we would speak out against that.  But we have seen a number of these actions by private sector companies be quite effective, and more shots in arms is a good thing. <br><br>Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br><br>Q    The meeting with Senator Capito today, should we expect President Biden to give her any kind of deadline for a major breakthrough on these talks to happen?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I wouldn&#8217;t expect this meeting to be an exchange of paper.  It would be more of a discussion.  And certainly, we&#8217;ll see what comes out of the meeting and what the appropriate next step is.  But I don&#8217;t know &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to predetermine that before the meeting even begins.<br><br>Q    And should we expect it to be one-on-one, or will White House staff be in the room, just to clarify?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I would expect at least a portion of it to be one-on-one, if not &#8212; if not the whole meeting, but I can check on that for you too. <br><br>Q    Okay.  And just to follow up on your comments on what President Biden said about Senator Manchin and Senator Sinema: Are you saying that that was not a criticism of the two of them?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  It was not.  No.  He considers them both friends.  He considers them both good working partners.  And he also believes that, in democracy, we don&#8217;t have to see eye to eye on every detail of every single issue in order to work together, and he certainly thinks that reflects their relationship. <br><br>Q    But even saying “two Democrats vote with Republicans more than they do with their own party” &#8212; <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  “With my Republican friends.”  I would say that the fact that the President is having Senator Capito here today and has been having ongoing discussions with Republicans in the Senate and that he&#8217;s eager to find a path forward on bipartisan work certainly tells you, I think, what you need to know about what he thinks about working with people even when there&#8217;s disagreement.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Just a few quick ones.  The NAACP criticized Biden&#8217;s plan, as was mentioned earlier, about not including the cancellation of student debt. <br><br>In April, Ron Klain said that the President had asked the Education Department to prepare a memo on wiping out debt for executive action.  And he said, “Hopefully, we&#8217;ll see that in the next few weeks.”  Is there any update on that memo about, kind of, what the President might do on that front?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have an update.  It was Department of Education, but also a legal review as well. <br><br>Q    Okay.  And then one question on Israel: Does Biden have a view on Naftali Bennett’s past statements about annexing the West Bank and negating a two-state solution?  How will Biden approach clear differences there on that issue?  And does he still think he has a partner for peace in an Israeli government led by Bennett? <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we&#8217;re not going to weigh in on an ongoing political process in a foreign country &#8212; in Israel or anywhere in the world.  I think you&#8217;re probably &#8212; know well what the President&#8217;s view is on a two-state solution and how he believes it&#8217;s the only path forward for lasting peace in the region.<br><br>Q    And then just a quick follow-up.  Do you know if Bennett and Biden have met before, they’ve &#8212; or any interaction in person?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  It&#8217;s a good question.  I don&#8217;t know if they have met in the past or have a prior relationship.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    President Biden campaigned on ending the federal death penalty.  When is he going to take steps to do that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  He has &#8212; he did campaign on that and has talked about his views on the death penalty.  I don&#8217;t have any update on any forward action. <br><br>Q    But isn’t his delay there a sign that perhaps he doesn&#8217;t feel as strongly about this as maybe he sounded when he was campaigning?  The &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a sign of that.  There&#8217;s a legal process and a Department of Justice process that would be &#8212; would be standard in any scenario here. <br><br>Q    When did he change his mind on the death penalty?  Because during the &#8217;94 &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I did not convey he changed his mind.<br><br>Q    The &#8217;94 Crime Bill expanded the amount of crimes that receive &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  He spoke to this pretty extensively on the campaign, and that&#8217;s his position.  I think we&#8217;re going to have to move on.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    I wanted to just &#8212; given what you said that his position hasn&#8217;t changed on the filibuster, I just want to go back to the vote last week in the Senate on the January 6th commission &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br><br>Q    &#8212; the fact that there were 54 “yes” votes, 35 “no” votes.  The bill failed.  This is an insurrection that the President has called an “unprecedented assault.” <br><br>I&#8217;m just curious if that math makes sense to this President and if that outcome would be acceptable should it repeat later this month when the Senate takes up voting rights.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  When you say the &#8220;math makes sense,” what do you mean by that exactly?<br><br>Q    I mean the fact that 54 lawmakers in the Senate voted “yes,” 35 voted “no,” and the bill did not pass. <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, first, that the President doesn&#8217;t see a reason for anyone to have voted against that bill, so he doesn&#8217;t understand that version of the math as a starting point. <br><br> He continues to believe that, given that was a dark day in our democracy &#8212; a day that, I think, we will all remember; he will remember, certainly, as President, as a day that does not stand out as a model of what is possible in this country.<br><br>In terms of his view of the filibuster, you know, again, his position has not changed on that.  He does want to see accountability as it relates to &#8212; and he does want to see an assessment of what happened to prevent it from ever happening again.  And he is happy to talk with members of Congress about how to approach that moving forward.<br><br>As you all know, no President can wave a wand and pass a piece of legislation with 50 votes, when it requires 60.  That requires Congress to move forward with that action.<br><br>Q    But it seems like it requires only one more Democratic vote than currently exists for that, and that vote happens to be a person who the President did seem to single out yesterday.<br><br>So you&#8217;re saying that he didn&#8217;t change his position on the filibuster, and yet, you know, he&#8217;s saying things &#8212; I mean, his passion for voting rights was evident yesterday when he spoke.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q    He&#8217;s saying, &#8220;We must find the courage…&#8221; &#8212; I&#8217;m quoting him &#8212; &#8220;…to change the things we know we can change.&#8221;<br><br>So, I just want to be very sure that you&#8217;re saying that: Should that outcome repeat itself later this month &#8212; if the Senate takes up voting rights, more than 50 lawmakers vote for a bill, but if the bill does not advance to his desk &#8212; is that something he&#8217;s going to be okay living with?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Again, I don&#8217;t think the President is okay with a January 6th commission not being in place.  He&#8217;s not okay with voting rights not passing.  And he will continue to advocate for both moving forward. <br><br>Go ahead. <br><br>Q    Yes.  As the President prepares for the summit with leaders of the NATO, some reports surfaced regarding spying on &#8212; on Germany.  How would that affect the summit and the &#8212; like, the reestablishment of the U.S.-NATO relations?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I think you&#8217;re referring to the reports from 2014 &#8212; correct? &#8212; that dated back to, I will say, my last time in government. <br><br>I don&#8217;t &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t say that &#8212; you know, in 2014, let me say, we issued a full &#8212; the United States issued a full review of our approach to overseas surveillance.  President Obama, at that time, issued a presidential directive that changed our approach in significant ways. <br><br>So that is a lot that has happened since &#8212; between the la- &#8212; over the last seven years.  And we will continue to work with our European allies and partners to address any questions through the appropriate national security channels.<br><br>But I can tell you that President Biden will be able to reassure President Merkel and President Macron about current U.S. posture.  And, you know, certainly we look forward to working together on a range of &#8212;<br><br>Q    And Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu said that, you know, he would stand against any agreement between &#8212; you know, with Iran, even if that would, you know, cause trouble with the Israeli-American relations.  Is there any reaction from the White House regarding that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sorry, the first part of your question was what?  It was about &#8212;<br><br>Q    You know, Netanyahu said that, like, he would stand against any agreement on &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Oh, on Iran.<br><br>Q    Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q    And, you know, even if that would, you know, result in, like, tension with, you know, American-Israeli relations.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  That&#8217;s consistently been the Prime Minister&#8217;s position.  And what our responsibility is and the responsibility of President Biden is to act in the interests of the United States.  And our view is that putting in place a diplomatic agreement &#8212; an agreement where we can prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon, where we have returned to the visibility we had before the former President pulled out of that deal &#8212; is in our interest.<br><br>So we will continue to work and brief the leaders in Israel, as we have over the last several years, but our position hasn&#8217;t changed.<br><br>Q    Okay.  Last question, if I may.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br><br>Q    You know, the Israelis requested a billion dollar, you know, in military aid after what had just happened.  You know, is the United States willing to and prepared to provide that aid?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  The President conveyed that &#8212; at his press conference he did with the leader of South Korea just a few weeks ago &#8212; that nothing has changed about our intention to provide assistance to the Israeli government and also our desire and interest in providing humanitarian and security assistance to the Palestinians as well. <br><br>So I expect those will continue.  I don&#8217;t have any assessment of any new request.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  On the vaccination efforts: As of May 7th, only less than 7 percent of the ICE detainee population &#8212; about 22,000 detainees &#8212; have been vaccinated.  Where is that process going?  The ACLU has demanded this White House, via a letter, to speed up that process.  So do you have an update?<br><br>And also, how do you plan to vaccinate eligible unaccompanied minors who are in detention?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, on the first question, Immigration and Customs Enforcement &#8212; ICE &#8212; is firmly committed to the health and wellbeing and welfare of all those in custody.  COVID-19 vaccines for ICE detainees are being allocated by local and state health departments &#8212; that&#8217;s how they are distributed &#8212; based on availability and the state&#8217;s vaccine implementation plans.  So that&#8217;s where they directly come, not from &#8212; not directly from the federal government. <br><br>Additionally, DHS&#8217;s chief medical officer is rapidly working on scaling our own internal capability to vaccinate detainees in our care across the country.  So that would be an additional step in addition to the state and local allocations, but it is a focus and a priority.<br><br>In terms of unaccompanied minors, some eligible unaccompanied children have already received a COVID-19 vaccine.  We&#8217;re working with our state partners to implement broader vaccine distribution.  In keeping with CDC guidance, it hasn&#8217;t been an extensive period of time where children under the age of 18 have been eligible. <br><br>Obviously, these allocations are distributed across states, but, of course, they&#8217;ve been broadly available for some time in the country, so this should provide greater access to the vaccine to unaccompanied children.<br><br>Q    And is the President aware of the current situation in Nicaragua, where the government is harassing journalists, activists, even a presidential candidate, and is claiming &#8212; is investigating them for money laundering in that country with really no legal basis?  Is he aware?  Is the State Department working on this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I know the State Department is, and I&#8217;d certainly send you to them.  On any specific comment from here, obviously, we would speak out against any harassment of journalists, individuals, leaders, the &#8212; you know, crushing of freedom of speech, expression that it sounds like is occurring in this case. <br><br>Q    I think we have an out.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.  All right, thank you, everyone.  I&#8217;ll look forward to seeing you tomorrow. <br><br>1:09 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the United States Naval Academy Graduation and Commissioning Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/02/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-united-states-naval-academy-graduation-and-commissioning-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 17:28:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Navy-Marine Corps Memorial Stadium Annapolis, Maryland 10:21 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  (Applause.)  Acting Secretary Thomas Harker, General David Berger, Admiral Mike Gilday: Looking out at these midshipmen, I know we are all filled with pride. Vice Admiral Sean Buck, Captain T.R. Buchanan, faculty and staff: Thank you for educating such a fine crew.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Navy-Marine Corps Memorial Stadium <br>Annapolis, Maryland</p>



<p>10:21 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  (Applause.)  Acting Secretary Thomas Harker, General David Berger, Admiral Mike Gilday: Looking out at these midshipmen, I know we are all filled with pride.<br><br>Vice Admiral Sean Buck, Captain T.R. Buchanan, faculty and staff: Thank you for educating such a fine crew.<br><br>Alumni, thank you for the support you have shown over these years to this great institution.<br><br>And to my Military Aide, Lieutenant Colonel Frank Machniak, who graduated in 2004, I am very proud to have you with me here today.<br><br>Family and friends of these graduates, thank you for the sacrifices you have already made and will make.<br><br>And I also want to acknowledge Kim and John Johnson.  Your son was taken far too soon.  And I promise you that he will not be forgotten.<br><br>And finally, to the Class of 2021, congratulations.  Congratulations.  (Applause.)  And look how far you&#8217;ve come.  So, you endured 0530 PT and pro-no exams.  You excelled on athletic fields and in academic exercises.  You enjoyed the fare at Dillo’s &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I know &#8212; karaoke at Harvest.  (Applause.)  You guys rolled up your sleeves and you got vaccinated.  And you made it to this day.  You made it to this day.  (Applause.) <br><br>And this day &#8212; this day that is not only a commencement, this day that is a commissioning.  And in a few minutes, you will take an oath.  And it&#8217;s actually the same oath I took as Vice President.  An oath to support our Constitution and defend it against all enemies.  An oath that has its roots in the founding of our nation.  And no matter what changes in our world, the charge in this oath is constant.  <br><br>Remember that as you walk out into the world, because the world you all are walking into is rapidly changing.  In fact, we are at a significant turning point.  Just look at the last several months, and you know what I&#8217;m talking about.  <br><br>And look at several moments in our nation&#8217;s history for perspective.  Think about it: There was the world before the stock market crashed in 1929 and the world after.  The world before the attack on Pearl Harbor in 1941 and the world after.  The world before the Civil Rights Act in 1964 and the world after.  The world before the Berlin Wall fell in 1989 and the world after.  <br><br>At some of these critical moments, our nation was compelled to take a hard look at both our priorities and our preparedness.<br><br>And another turning point was September 11th &#8212; 20 years ago, this year &#8212; when airplanes hit the Twin Towers and our Pentagon, when Flight 93 crashed in Pennsylvania.  That day shaped your entire life, and it shaped our entire nation.  It tested our systems, our structures, our very standing in the world.    <br><br>Well, Midshipmen, we are now entering the next era.  A new age, a new epoch, with its own tests, with its own challenges, and with its own opportunities.<br><br>The global pandemic &#8212; you see, of course &#8212; has accelerated what was happening before, and it has accelerated our world into a new era.  It has forever influenced our perspective.<br><br>And if we weren&#8217;t clear before, we know now our world is interconnected, our world is interdependent, and our world is fragile.  <br><br>Just think, a deadly pandemic can spread throughout the globe in just a matter of months.  A gang of hackers can disrupt the fuel supply of a whole seaboard.  One country&#8217;s carbon emissions can threaten the sustainability of the whole Earth. <br><br>This, Midshipmen, is the era we are in, and it is unlike any era that came before.  So the challenge now &#8212; the challenge before us now is how to mount a modern defense to these modern threats.  <br><br>So, let me share with you, for example, a personal experience.  A few years ago, when I was in the United States Senate, I visited the USS Scranton.  It was outside of San Diego, California.  And at the time, I was also a member of the Senate Intelligence Committee.<br><br>So, when I was aboard the vessel, I asked the officers &#8212; I said, “Hey, tell me, what does it take to protect such a valuable asset against cyberattacks?”  And they told me, “You know, it’s pretty simple: equipment and experts.”  Well, the way I see it, Midshipmen, you &#8212; you &#8212; you are those experts.  <br><br>On the issue of cybersecurity: Foreign advisor- &#8212; adversaries have their sights set on our military technology,<br>our intellectual property, our elections, our critical infrastructure.<br><br>The ransomware attack by criminal hackers earlier this month &#8212; well, that was a warning shot.  In fact, there have been many warning shots. <br><br>So, we must defend our nation against these threats and, at the same time, we must make advances in things that you’ve been learning &#8212; things like quantum computing and artificial intelligence and robotics &#8212; and things that will put our nation at a strategic advantage.  And you will be the ones to do it.  You will be the ones to do it because the United States military is the best, the bravest, and the most brilliant.  (Applause.) <br><br>And just think, from walkie-talkies, to the Internet, to satellite navigation, the United States military has been on the forefront of research, development, and technological advancement.  That is a point of American pride.  And as I look out at all of you, I know you will build on that leadership. <br><br>And then, of course, there is climate change, which is a very real threat to our national security.  And I look at you and I know you are among the experts who will navigate and mitigate this threat.  You are ocean engineers who will help navigate ships through thinning ice.  You are mechanical engineers who will help reinforce sinking bases.  You are electrical engineers who will soon help convert solar and wind energy into power, convert solar and wind energy into combat power. <br><br>And just ask any Marine today, would she rather carry 20 pounds of batteries or a rolled-up solar panel?  And I am positive she will tell you a solar panel, and so would he.  (Laughter and applause.) <br><br>The American people are depending on you: the best, the bravest, the most brilliant.  We saw this during COVID-19, when Americans watched how members of our military helped vaccinate our nation.  Because you know biological threats like pandemics and infectious diseases are yet another threat in this era, and you are confronting this threat.<br><br>Our military helped develop the technology that made the vaccine possible.  Naval researchers also figured out how to use 3D knitting machines to make masks.  Naval labs monitored the spread of the disease.  And the Marine Corps and the Navy are leading on making the connection between the pandemic and medical readiness of our fighting forces for the future.<br><br>Class of 2021, you are prepared for all of this.  You are prepared for any threat.  And you are prepared for this new era. <br><br>And it is not only because of the knowledge and the skills you gained here or those you will continue to learn, but it&#8217;s because of something more.  It&#8217;s because of who each of you is.  It is because of who, collectively, you are. <br><br>So, as I conclude today, that&#8217;s what I want to talk about.  I want to talk about you.  As Vice President, I&#8217;ve come to know the United States Navy quite well.  Every day, in fact, I&#8217;m surrounded by sailors and Marines and your tradition and your history.  And I mean that literally. <br><br>So, I often travel on Marine Two.  In fact, that&#8217;s how I arrived today.  My residence is on the grounds of the United States Naval Observatory.  My West Wing office features a desk built by Seabees from timbers of the USS Constitution.  My ceremonial office &#8212; my ceremonial office was once occupied by the Secretary of the Navy.  And displayed there, I have placed the shoulder boards of your brigade commander, Midshipman Sydney Barber. <br><br>And so here&#8217;s what I know.  Midshipmen, you are tireless.  You are ambitious.  You are a fierce fighting force.  You are idealists in the truest sense.  You are the embodiment of American aspiration. <br><br>So hold on to that.  Because in your career, you may witness some of the worst of humanity.  But promise that you will never forget the best of who we are, that you will never forget the ideals you stand for: duty, honor, loyalty.  Fight for those ideals, and fight for our democracy. <br><br>And remember, our Constitution is not only something to defend; it is a guide.  It is a guide for your service.  It begins with three simple words: &#8220;We, the people.&#8221;  Not &#8220;I.&#8221;  &#8220;We.&#8221;  Our nation was designed to be a team sport.  And we are in this together. <br><br>So, you know, finally, I&#8217;ll just share with you: On my way to the stadium this morning, I stopped by the cemetery to pay my respects to my dear former colleague, a great and courageous American: Senator John McCain.  And, yes.  (Applause.)<br><br>So, most people don&#8217;t know, he wanted to be buried next to his best friend who he met on the Yard: Admiral Chuck Larson.  That is the ultimate example of what I mean &#8212; &#8220;in it together.&#8221; <br><br>So, Midshipmen, throughout our history, officers in the United States Navy, officers in the United States Marine have risked everything to defend our freedoms.  Today, you will swear to do the same.  You are the next links in the chain. <br><br>And so, Midshipmen, when you stand to take the oath, I want you to know that, as we embark on this new era, President Joe Biden and I, our entire nation have great faith in you.  And we are proud of you &#8212; so very, very proud. <br><br>Congratulations again.  May God bless you.  And may God bless the United States of America.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br><br>10:39 A.M. EDT      </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
