<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 18:52:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Richard Lee Buangan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Mongolia Rachna Sachdeva Korhonen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mali Rebecca Haffajee, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Planning and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Richard Lee Buangan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Mongolia</li><li>Rachna Sachdeva Korhonen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mali</li><li>Rebecca Haffajee, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Jaime Areizaga-Soto, Nominee for Chair of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, Department of Veterans Affairs</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Richard Lee Buangan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Mongolia</u></strong></p>



<p>Richard Lee Buangan, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of Global Public Affairs at the State Department. Prior to that, Buangan served as Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs, and as the Executive Assistant to the Secretary of State. Earlier in his career, Buangan was assigned as Managing Director for International Media in the Bureau of Public Affairs, as the Public Affairs Officer of the then-U.S. Consulate General, Jerusalem, and as Deputy Press Attaché and then as Embassy Spokesperson of the U.S. Embassy in Beijing, China. Buangan also served as a staff officer in the Executive Secretariat of the Department of State, and held overseas assignments in Paris, France and Abidjan, Côte d’Ivoire.</p>



<p>Buangan earned a Bachelor of Arts degree from Saint Edward’s University, Austin, Texas. He is the recipient of multiple performance awards from the State Department. He speaks Mandarin Chinese, French, and Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rachna Sachdeva Korhonen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mali</u></strong></p>



<p>Rachna Korhonen is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Counselor. She currently serves as a Deputy Assistant Secretary and the Executive Director of the combined Executive Offices of the State Department’s Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs and the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs. Previously, Korhonen was the Consul General and Principal Officer of the U.S. Consulate in Dharan, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. She also led the Management Section of the U.S. Embassy in Colombo, Sri Lanka and, in Washington, served as a Special Assistant to the Under Secretary for Management. Among her other assignments, Korhonen was the Supervisory General Services Officer and Senior Human Resources Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, and the Political Chief of the Provincial Reconstruction Team in Kirkuk, Iraq.&nbsp; She also had assignments at the U.S. Embassy in Kuwait and at the U.S. Consulate General in Mumbai, India.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Korhonen earned her B.S. from Empire State College. She speaks Hindi, French, Finnish, and Arabic.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rebecca Haffajee, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Rebecca Haffajee was appointed as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation at the Department of Health and Human Services and has been serving as the Acting Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation since March 2021. Before joining the federal government, Haffajee was a policy researcher at the RAND Corporation, and an assistant professor of health management and policy at the University of Michigan School of Public Health. Prior to these roles, Haffajee practiced health care law at Ropes &amp; Gray LLP, where she advised domestic health care providers on regulatory compliance and reimbursement matters, and she was a law fellow at the O’Neill Institute for National and Global Health Law at Georgetown University. Haffajee’s work combines detailed legal analyses with empirical investigations of the relationships between policy and health. Her main research interests are behavioral health, drug policy, health equity, and public health law and policy. Her work has been covered by major news media outlets and published in health journals, including in the New England Journal of Medicine, Journal of the American Medical Association, Annals of Internal Medicine, and Health Affairs.</p>



<p>Haffajee received her Ph.D. in Health Policy (concentrating in evaluative sciences and statistics) from Harvard University, J.D. from Harvard Law School, and M.P.H. from the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health. She attended Duke University for her undergraduate degree. She grew up in Massachusetts, where she now lives with her husband and two children.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Jaime Areizaga-Soto, Nominee for Chair of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Jaime Areizaga-Soto, an attorney, public servant, and Army JAG Brigadier General, is currently mobilized to active duty as the Principal Deputy General Counsel of the National Guard Bureau (NGB), a joint activity of the Department of Defense (DOD). In that role, he works closely with the General Counsel in advising the senior leadership of NGB, in leading an office of over 100 attorneys, and in coordinating among the Air Force, the Army, and the 54 National Guards. From 2014 until earlier this year, Areizaga-Soto served as the Deputy Secretary for Veterans and Defense Affairs of Virginia, where he advised Governors McAuliffe and Northam on matters related to the 730,000 Virginia veterans and military families, and in ensuring an excellent relationship with DOD’s thirty large installations across the Commonwealth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Areizaga-Soto practiced international law for twelve years, focusing on cross-border infrastructure project finance. He served as a White House Fellow assigned to the Treasury Department, and as the Senior Attorney Advisor at USAID’s Office of the General Counsel. Areizaga-Soto grew up in Puerto Rico and graduated from Georgetown University’s School of Foreign Service. He holds a law degree from Stanford Law School, a Masters in Latin American Studies from Stanford University, a Masters in Security and Defense from the Inter-American Defense College in Ft. McNair, and a Mágister from the National Academy of Political and Strategic Studies (ANEPE) of Chile. He is a member of the Virginia, District of Columbia, New York, Maryland, and U.S. Supreme Court Bars; is fluent in Spanish, Portuguese, and French; and has basic knowledge of Italian.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and President Samia Suluhu Hassan of Tanzania Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/15/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-samia-suluhu-hassan-of-tanzania-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 17:12:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President’s Ceremonial Office 10:44 A.M. EDT&#160; VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS: &#160;Okay, good morning, everyone. &#160;It is my great honor and pleasure to welcome President Hassan. &#160;I bring you greetings, of course, from President Biden as well. &#160;And we welcome you for this trip.&#160; As, Madam President, you know, the United States feels very strongly that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President’s Ceremonial Office</em></p>



<p>10:44 A.M. EDT&nbsp;<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS: &nbsp;Okay, good morning, everyone. &nbsp;It is my great honor and pleasure to welcome President Hassan. &nbsp;I bring you greetings, of course, from President Biden as well. &nbsp;And we welcome you for this trip.&nbsp;<br><br>As, Madam President, you know, the United States feels very strongly that Tanzania is a very important partner. &nbsp;And we know, of course, and many Americans have appreciated the incredible natural wonders of Tanzania &#8212; be it the Serengeti or Mount Kilimanjaro, where many Americans have traveled and come back with stories that have lasted a lifetime in terms of the memories.&nbsp;<br><br>You, of course, in Tanzania have a vibrant multicultural society, stretching from the savanna of the mainland to the beaches of Zanzibar.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we do appreciate all that Tanzania represents, both historically and in terms of just the natural beauty of your country.&nbsp;<br><br>And over 60 years ago, we, the United States, sent some of our first Peace Corps volunteers to Tanzania. &nbsp;And the relationship, of course, has grown stronger and warmer ever since. &nbsp;And we&#8217;ve seen great progress during this time, but we also recognize there is more to do.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m looking forward to our discussion today. &nbsp;There are three areas that I know we will focus on in particular. &nbsp;One is with regard to what we will do together to strengthen democracy. &nbsp;And we welcome the progress that you have made during the course of your leadership and, in particular, the work you have done to empower women leaders in Tanzania and the work you have done to support human rights.&nbsp;<br><br>Our conversation will also cover the importance of the economic growth of Tanzania, which I know is one of your highest priorities and a main purpose for your visit to the United States. &nbsp;We welcome, of course, the attention you are giving to that and that the focus of this trip includes, in the United States, focusing on the investment opportunities as it relates to the economy as a general matter, but also in the area of tourism.&nbsp;<br><br>And your trip has also generated nearly $1 billion in new investments from companies in the United States. &nbsp;And that has and will contribute, no doubt, to the economic growth of Tanzania but, in that way, will contribute to the growth &#8212; the economic growth and jobs in the United States as well.&nbsp;<br><br>The third matter that we will discuss that has been a priority for our two nations and for the world is the issue of public health, global health, and, in particular, COVID-19 and other health issues. &nbsp;We will discuss today what we will do together to address those needs and those issues.&nbsp;<br><br>It is our strong belief that as COVID is an issue for any country, it is an issue for all of us. &nbsp;And it is with that spirit that we approach this discussion and our role, as it relates to Tanzania and the work that you are doing to address the issue of COVID, but also the work that you have prioritized around the health of women and children in Tanzania. &nbsp;So, I look forward to our conversation on that.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;ll conclude these comments by saying that our administration is deeply committed to strengthening the ties to Tanzania and to African countries in general. &nbsp;This has been an area of intentional focus and priority for both the President and for me.&nbsp;<br><br>And with that, again, welcome, Madam President. &nbsp;And I look forward to our discussion.&nbsp;<br><br>PRESIDENT HASSAN: &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;Thank you, Madam Vice President. &nbsp;And I must say that I&#8217;m pleased to be here at the White House. &nbsp;And I thank you, Madam Vice President &#8212; I thank you, Madam Vice President, for having me here.&nbsp;<br><br>It makes more exciting to be here for obvious reason: that we&#8217;ll be able to exchange a lot of experiences in what we are doing, as you have also mentioned. &nbsp;And on that note, I bring goodwill message of friendship from &#8212; and solidarity from the government and the people of the United Republic of Tanzania.&nbsp;<br><br>And as this is the first time we are meeting in person since assumption of office, I would like to congratulate President Joe Biden and yourself, of course, Madam Kamala, and the Democratic Party for their resounding victory during the presidential election in 2020.&nbsp;<br><br>We, in Tanzania, have been following very closely that election because there &#8212; for the first time, there was a woman contesting for the vice president position. &nbsp;So, we were very inspired.&nbsp;<br><br>So, let me say that the United States and Tanzania have enjoyed excellent relation for the last 60 years. &nbsp;My government would like to see our relation grow further and strengthened to greater heights.&nbsp;<br><br>I would like to express my government&#8217;s appreciation to the U.S. government for their invaluable development assistance and great work the USAID has been doing in Tanzania over the years, particularly for socioeconomic development and in uplifting the lives of many Tanzanians through various programs and initiatives, including PEPFAR, the Presidential Malaria Initiative, Feed for Future &#8212; or Feed the Future for food security, just to mention a few of them.&nbsp;<br><br>Talking on COVID-19, my country is indeed grateful to the U.S. support in its donation of COVID-19 vaccines through the COVAX facility. &nbsp;To date, the U.S. has so far contributed close to 5 million doses of COVID-19 vaccines to my country.&nbsp;<br><br>It was just last month I had a virtual meeting with the USAID Administrator, Madam Samantha Power. &nbsp;And during our conversation, she revealed that Tanzania was one of the 11 beneficiaries of the Global Vaccine Initiative launched by President Joe Biden. &nbsp;Yeah.<br><br>So, talking on human rights and rule of law and democracy, Tanzania have made commendable strides in these areas, as you have mentioned, and we are committed to taking deliberate measures to ensure inclusion, cooperation, unity, and respect for all Tanzanians.&nbsp;<br><br>And in so doing, the political parties and stakeholders convened meetings to deliberate on collective and productive ways of running political activities in our country while, at the same time, safeguarding country’s interest. &nbsp;So, these meetings have been instrumental in contributing positively to enhancing democracy and strengthening multiparty system in our country, in Tanzania.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, talking on trade and investment, I must say that I&#8217;m excited about the prospects of promoting further trade and investment ties of mutual &#8212; for mutual benefits. &nbsp;And in &#8212; cognizant of that, we need to create an &#8212; an ease of doing business. &nbsp;And my government, in close collaboration with the private sector, has put in place better conditions and favorable environment for the private sector to thrive.&nbsp;<br><br>So, my only request here is to &#8212; for the U.S. government to encourage more the private sector from the U.S. to work with us in Tanzania. &nbsp;There&#8217;s a lot to be offered. &nbsp;We have a lot of potential. &nbsp;So, you are welcome.&nbsp;<br><br>Moreover, the government is collaboration &#8212; with the collaboration with the private sector, is in the process of enacting the Tanzania Investment Act, expected to set the tone for creating the safe lending for investors. &nbsp;So, we are creating &#8212; we are doing all what we can to make the private sector working comfortably in Tanzania.&nbsp;<br><br>Finally, Madam Vice President, I wish to inform you that while I&#8217;m here in the United States, I&#8217;ll also launch “The Royal Tour” program. &nbsp;This program is created to showcase Tanzania&#8217;s touristic and investment potentials.&nbsp;<br><br>The selection of United States, the place for launching, was not by accident. &nbsp;We are aware that &#8212; and we did it intentionally, knowing that this is where the lovers and shakers of entertainment and leisure reside. &nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS: &nbsp;Indeed.<br><br>PRESIDENT HASSAN: &nbsp;And that&#8217;s creating an excellent platform for the visibili- &#8212; visibility of the program across the globe. &nbsp;<br><br>Indeed, it is my hope that the launch of this program will inspire so many people to visit our wonderous country in the not-so-distant future.&nbsp;<br><br>Madam President, I once again thank you for having me here &#8212; for having me here in the statehouse, and looking forward to fruitful discussion.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, Madam Vice President. &nbsp;Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS: &nbsp;Thank you, Madam President. &nbsp;Thank you, Madam President. &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;END &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 10:54 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with President Hassan of&#160;Tanzania</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-president-hassan-of-tanzania/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 17:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with President Samia Suluhu Hassan of Tanzania in Washington. The Vice President underscored that the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to strengthening ties with Tanzania and with countries across Africa, based on the principles of mutual respect and equality. The Vice President welcomed President Hassan’s efforts to strengthen democracy and human&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with President Samia Suluhu Hassan of Tanzania in Washington. The Vice President underscored that the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to strengthening ties with Tanzania and with countries across Africa, based on the principles of mutual respect and equality.<br> <br>The Vice President welcomed President Hassan’s efforts to strengthen democracy and human rights in Tanzania. They reviewed a number of areas of cooperation in our bilateral relationship, including health, agriculture, and infrastructure.<br> <br>The Vice President underscored the importance of our economic and commercial partnership, and discussed recent reforms and others needed to further strengthen our investment relationship. The two leaders noted they are looking forward to the entry into force of an Open Skies Air Transport Agreement, which establishes a modern civil aviation relationship between the United States and Tanzania and agreed it will promote increased travel and trade and help spur economic growth. They also welcomed nearly $1 billion of new investments by U.S. companies in Tanzania in tourism, conservation, and clean energy sectors.<br> <br>The Vice President discussed our efforts to address the COVID-19 pandemic, including through Tanzania’s participation in the U.S.-led Global VAX Initiative, and our donation of nearly 4.9 million vaccine doses provided to Tanzania since the beginning of the pandemic. They discussed broader global health security and global health issues, including supporting women and children’s health.<br> <br>Lastly, they discussed several regional and global issues of concern. The Vice President emphasized the importance of the world standing together in support of international rules and norms, including the sovereignty and territorial integrity of all nations. The Vice President condemned Russia’s invasion of Ukraine and its ongoing brutal attacks against the people of Ukraine and noted there must be severe costs for Russia’s actions.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on&#160;Passover</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-passover/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 15:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tonight, Jewish communities in the United States, Israel, and around the world will celebrate Passover, a holiday whose ancient story has inspired humanity for millennia.&#160; For many, this will mark the first time in three years that families and friends will be able to gather around the Seder table – a testament to the life-saving&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tonight, Jewish communities in the United States, Israel, and around the world will celebrate Passover, a holiday whose ancient story has inspired humanity for millennia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For many, this will mark the first time in three years that families and friends will be able to gather around the Seder table – a testament to the life-saving miracle of modern medicine and the progress we’ve made to address an unforgiving pandemic.</p>



<p>Together again, we will commemorate the Exodus of the enslaved Israelites from Egypt. And we will retell a timeless story about that most human quest for freedom. Redemption. Faith. Hope. And, ultimately, deliverance. A story that has brought solace and a sense of promise to Jewish communities throughout their history as they endured acts of persecution, pogroms, and even genocide. And one that inspired and empowered oppressed peoples everywhere who, even in their deepest despair, sensed that their own liberation was not beyond reach.</p>



<p>This Passover, we hold in our hearts the people of Ukraine and those around the world whose heroic stand against tyranny inspires us all. The enduring spirit of this holiday&nbsp;continues to teach us that with faith, the driest desert can be crossed, the mightiest sea can be split, and hope never stops marching towards the promised land.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To all those celebrating this Festival of Freedom, Jill and I wish you and your loved ones a Happy Passover. <em>Chag Sameach</em>!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on State Unemployment&#160;Rates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/statement-from-president-biden-on-state-unemployment-rates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 15:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Americans are getting back to work in every corner of the country in record numbers. Right now, 17 states are at or tied with the lowest unemployment rate they’ve ever had – and 20 states have jobless rates below 3%. Over the last year, the unemployment rate dropped in every state and many states have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Americans are getting back to work in every corner of the country in record numbers. Right now, 17 states are at or tied with the lowest unemployment rate they’ve ever had – and 20 states have jobless rates below 3%. Over the last year, the unemployment rate dropped in every state and many states have reached historic lows.&nbsp;These aren’t just numbers on a page: these are millions of Americans back at work and able to support themselves and their families with good-paying jobs and enjoy the dignity a job provides.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This wasn’t an accident: this was the direct result of my economic plan to grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out. There’s still more work to do to build on this recovery and bring down costs for working families – and my Administration is working on that every day – but we can’t lose sight of how far, and how quickly, we’ve come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Park Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/15/a-proclamation-on-national-park-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 15:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; From the Great Smoky Mountains in North Carolina and Tennessee, to the wonderous sights of the Grand Canyon in Arizona, to the vast hidden treasures of the Channel Islands in&#160;California, our cherished national parks are home to so many of those most beautiful places on Earth, places that astonish us, inspire us, and fill&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; From the Great Smoky Mountains in North Carolina and Tennessee, to the wonderous sights of the Grand Canyon in Arizona, to the vast hidden treasures of the Channel Islands in&nbsp;California, our cherished national parks are home to so many of those most beautiful places on Earth, places that astonish us, inspire us, and fill us with a sense of pride and belonging. &nbsp;During National Park Week, we celebrate the natural splendor of our national parks and show our appreciation for the Department of the Interior and National Park Service&#8217;s dedicated stewardship of them.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last month, our Nation celebrated the 150th&nbsp;anniversary of Yellowstone National Park &#8212; the world&#8217;s first national park and a place that holds many treasured memories for me. &nbsp;The desire to protect&nbsp;and share the indescribable beauty, bountiful wildlife,&nbsp;and natural resources of Yellowstone laid the foundation for what would become America&#8217;s national parks system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To protect our Nation&#8217;s outdoors and all of its marvels, I was proud to launch the &#8220;America the Beautiful&#8221; initiative &#8212; the first-ever voluntary national conservation effort with a goal to conserve 30 percent of our country&#8217;s lands and waters by&nbsp;2030.&nbsp; I have called for a whole-of-government approach that supports locally-led efforts to conserve and restore lands and waters across the country.&nbsp; In doing so, we will address the interconnected climate and biodiversity crises that our planet faces and also allow more people in more communities to have access to nature and the physical and spiritual nourishment it provides.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Historic investments through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the Great American Outdoors Act are also allowing us to revitalize our national parks and public lands by modernizing facilities and addressing the extensive&nbsp;deferred maintenance and&nbsp;repair backlog. &nbsp;These laws also allow us to make progress on pollution clean-up, environmental sustainability, climate resiliency,&nbsp;and green energy initiatives.&nbsp; Through these important upgrades and restoration efforts, we will make it possible for more people to enjoy our national parks, today and&nbsp;for generations to come.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is working to fully engage with Tribal Nations by acknowledging their history and learning from their ancestral and modern connections to our national parks.&nbsp; By recognizing Native American Tribes&#8217; connection to this land since time immemorial and finding opportunities to collaborate on managing our shared lands and waters, we can preserve Native American Tribes&#8217; rich histories while safeguarding America&#8217;s national parks for future generations.&nbsp; The National Park Service is also working with stakeholders to connect more Americans to our national parks, incorporating the experiences, backgrounds, and history of every community that these sites represent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As part of my Administration&#8217;s efforts to advance equity, diversity,&nbsp;and inclusion,&nbsp;we have made a priority of creating equitable access to our shared natural resources.&nbsp; Through programs funded by the Land&nbsp;and&nbsp;Water Conservation Fund, such as&nbsp;the Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership,&nbsp;we are working with communities to develop and preserve&nbsp;green space, reinvigorating existing national parks, and expanding opportunities to forge connections between people and the outdoors, particularly in economically underserved areas. &nbsp;By&nbsp;tackling the intersecting challenges of environmental and racial justice, we will create a future where all Americans can&nbsp;enjoy everything that our national parks have to offer.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As we have learned throughout the COVID-19 pandemic,&nbsp;providing easy and equitable&nbsp;access to the great outdoors is vital for our physical, mental,&nbsp;and social health. &nbsp;National parks, trails,&nbsp;and other close-to-home public spaces create opportunities for us to get outdoors, enjoy fresh air,&nbsp;and socialize or find sanctuary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our national parks serve as a source of recreation, inspiration, and spirit.&nbsp; They are, indeed, America&#8217;s best idea. &nbsp;I encourage all Americans to take some time during National Park Week to connect with our national parks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 16 through April 24, 2022, as National Park Week. &nbsp; I encourage all Americans to find their park, recreate responsibly, and enjoy the benefits that come from spending time in the natural world.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fifteenth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Volunteer Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/15/a-proclamation-on-national-volunteer-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 14:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the past year, we have seen that the American spirit of service is alive and well. &#160;Every day, Americans are giving their love and labor to care for seniors, help communities rebuild after disasters, support veterans and military families, tackle climate change, guide and mentor our youth, serve and strengthen the democratic process, feed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Over the past year, we have seen that the American spirit of service is alive and well. &nbsp;Every day, Americans are giving their love and labor to care for seniors, help communities rebuild after disasters, support veterans and military families, tackle climate change, guide and mentor our youth, serve and strengthen the democratic process, feed the hungry, and keep communities healthy and safe. &nbsp;Tens of millions of Americans collectively volunteer billions of hours of their time each year. &nbsp;This commitment to service represents the best of who we&nbsp;are as Americans.&nbsp; During National Volunteer Week, we recognize the contributions that our Nation&#8217;s volunteers make every day and encourage all Americans to discover their path to&nbsp;making a&nbsp;difference.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also need to call on that spirit more than ever as we&nbsp;help our Nation recover from the COVID-19 pandemic. &nbsp;For example, we need volunteers in education to help students get back on track, and I encourage Americans to support our youth by&nbsp;serving as tutors and mentors or in other critical roles. As&nbsp;we tackle the pandemic and so many other challenges, government has a&nbsp;role to play, but our Nation is stronger, more connected, and best prepared for the future when government, nonprofits, community organizations, the private sector, and the American people work together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Volunteering also benefits the volunteers. &nbsp;People who volunteer develop new skills, build their personal and professional networks, forge a deeper connection with their communities and service organizations, and experience the joy of&nbsp;serving a larger cause.&nbsp; The opportunities to volunteer are seemingly limitless.&nbsp; Students gain real world experience, workers apply their skills to organizations that benefit from their experience and often develop new skills in the process, and older Americans improve their health and longevity. &nbsp;At&nbsp;every age and stage in life, volunteers experience the profound joy of giving back. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Volunteerism is also a reinforcing cycle. &nbsp;Volunteers are more likely to become further involved in volunteer groups, participate in civic organizations, attend public meetings, and&nbsp;lend a helping hand to their neighbors.&nbsp; Serving together in common purpose has the power to unite us across the lines that sometimes divide. &nbsp;As I pursue a unity agenda in the Congress, volunteering serves as a unity agenda for our national life. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Vice President Harris and I salute all of our fellow Americans who take time to help others in need and the faith-based, nonprofit, national service, military service, and community organizations that make their service possible.&nbsp; My&nbsp;Administration is committed to encouraging and advancing volunteer service throughout our Nation and the world. &nbsp;Through AmeriCorps &#8212; a network of service programs across our country that helps meet community needs &#8212; we are removing barriers to service, expanding volunteer opportunities, and focusing on our Nation&#8217;s toughest challenges. &nbsp;AmeriCorps increased the living allowance for national service members through funding from the American Rescue Plan and is working with partners to recruit volunteers in underserved communities so that service opportunities are more accessible. &nbsp;To serve communities abroad in their response and recovery efforts from the pandemic, the Peace Corps has developed criteria and processes to return volunteers around the world.&nbsp; I encourage all Americans to learn&nbsp;how get involved by visiting AmeriCorps.gov and peacecorps.gov/volunteer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 17 through April 23, 2022, as National Volunteer Week. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to observe this week by volunteering in service projects across the country and pledging to make service a part of their daily lives.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this</p>



<p>fifteenth day of April, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White&#160;House Announces Theme and Activities for the 2022 Easter Egg&#160;Roll</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/white-house-announces-theme-and-activities-for-the-2022-easter-egg-roll/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 13:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President and First Lady to Host the White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll on Monday, April 18, 2022 The White House announced today the full program of activities for the 2022 White House Easter Egg Roll, a tradition&#160;dating back to 1878.&#160; A teacher for more than 30 years, First Lady Jill Biden created this year’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The President and First Lady to Host the White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll on Monday, April 18, 2022</em></p>



<p>The White House announced today the full program of activities for the 2022 White House Easter Egg Roll, a tradition&nbsp;dating back to 1878.&nbsp; A teacher for more than 30 years, First Lady Jill Biden created this year’s event theme, “EGGucation!,” with the South Lawn to be&nbsp;transformed into a school community, full of fun educational activities for children to enjoy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to the time-honored traditions of rolling and hunting eggs, this year’s White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll will also feature a School House Activity Area, Reading Nook, Talent Show, Field Trip to the Farm, Picture Day, a Physical “EGGucation” Zone, a Cafetorium and more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In total, approximately 30,000 people will take part in this year’s Easter “EGGucation” Roll, including thousands of military families, and the crew members and families from the U.S.S. DELAWARE, the U.S. Naval Submarine, for which the First Lady is the sponsor. Tickets for the general public were distributed to guests from all across the country through an online public lottery.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This year’s event will be broken into five sessions, beginning at 7:30 AM ET and end at 6:30 PM ET.&nbsp; Follow along with the White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll festivities with #EasterEggRoll and #EGGucation, and the official @White House, @POTUS, @FLOTUS social media accounts on Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.<br><br><strong>Additional information about this year’s “EGGucational” Activities and Programming:&nbsp;</strong><br>&nbsp;<br><strong>EGG ROLL</strong><br>The tradition that started it all! Children will use wooden spoons to roll colorful eggs in a race across the South Lawn.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>EGG HUNT</strong><br>Children will run to find hidden eggs and collect special prizes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>SCHOOL HOUSE</strong><br>The School House area of the South Lawn will be full of fun educational activities for all to enjoy!<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>TALENT SHOW</strong><br>The Talent Show stage on the South Lawn will feature some of today’s most “egg-citing” kids’ acts and performances.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>CAFETORIUM</strong><br>Children and their families will learn how to make some tasty treats and then sample seasonal snacks!<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>FIELD TRIP</strong><br>It’s time to head to the farm for a school field trip!&nbsp; Children will learn from farmers about how they help feed our families.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>READING NOOK</strong><br>Families will come together for some special story time with children’s books authors, teachers, and some special guests!&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>PICTURE DAY</strong><br>Families will remember this day always with a fun photo! Snap a family picture with the White House in the background or capture a moment with your favorite costumed character.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>PHYSICAL EGGucation (PE)</strong><br>Children of all ages will hop, bounce, kick, run,&nbsp;and throw their way through the South Lawn’s “egg-citing”&nbsp;obstacle course and favorite school yard activities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>This year, the White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll will feature educational activities, school yard fun, and special performances on the South Lawn, which are supported by (in alphabetical order):</strong></p>



<ul><li>2021 National Teacher of the Year, Juliana Urtubey</li><li>4 Imprint&nbsp;</li><li>American Association for the Advancement of Science</li><li>American Egg Board</li><li>Baker, chef, author, Christina Tosi, Milk Bar</li><li>Baltimore Ravens</li><li>Beat Refinery DJ School</li><li>Chef Stephen Durfee, Culinary Institute of America</li><li>Children’s Book Author and host of The Tonight Show, Jimmy Fallon</li><li>Children’s Book Author and singer, Ciara&nbsp;</li><li>Children’s Book Author, Jeff Kinney</li><li>Children’s Book Author, singer, and actress, Kristin Chenoweth</li><li>Children’s Book Author Rocco Smirne (age 6) and his mother, Arioth Smirne</li><li>Cooper Middle School Concert Band from McLean, Virginia&nbsp;</li><li>DC United</li><li>DJ Diamond Kuts</li><li>DJ Mel</li><li>DJs and twin sisters, Amira &amp; Kayla</li><li>Duke Ellington High School for the Performing Arts student and singer, Alyssa Richardson</li><li>Eastern High School Marching Band from Washington, DC</li><li>Indiana Fever&nbsp;</li><li>Lawrence Hall of Science: University of California, Berkeley</li><li>Little Miss Murals chalkboard artist, Stacy Lazzara&nbsp;</li><li>Montgomery County Fire and Rescue</li><li>National Children&#8217;s Museum</li><li>Operation Gratitude</li><li>PBS KIDS</li><li>PBS KIDS Series Creator (Alma’s Way), Children’s Book Author and former Sesame Street character, Sonia Manzano&nbsp;</li><li>PBS KIDS Series Creator (Xavier Riddle and the Secret Museum) and Children’s Book Author, Brad Meltzer&nbsp;</li><li>Philadelphia Eagles</li><li>Professor of Art History and children’s book illustrator for the White House Historical Association, Dr. John Hutton &nbsp;</li><li>Sesame Street Live</li><li>Signature Brands, LLC / PAAS Registered Trademark Easter Egg Color Kits</li><li>Singer, songwriter, and actress Sofia Carson</li><li>Sweetgreen</li><li>The Coca-Cola Company / DASANI Water</li><li>The National Basketball Association</li><li>The National Football League</li><li>“The President’s Own” United States Marine Corps Band</li><li>The United States Navy Band Sea Chanters (singing the National Anthem)</li><li>The United States Air Force Band&nbsp;</li><li>The United&nbsp;States Army Band&nbsp;</li><li>The United States Navy Band&nbsp;</li><li>The Secretary of the Department of Education, Miguel Cardona</li><li>The White House Historical Association</li><li>The Women’s National Basketball Association</li><li>Virginia&nbsp;Egg Council</li><li>Washington Commanders</li><li>Washington DC radio personality Tommy McFly, emcee</li><li>Washington Spirit</li></ul>



<p><br><strong>The following costumed characters (in alphabetical order) will stroll the White House grounds, including:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Disney Characters Miguel: from Coco and Doc McStuffins&nbsp;</li><li>Dr. Seuss Characters: Cat in the Hat, and Thing 1 and Thing 2&nbsp;</li><li>Miffy Bunny</li><li>Milkshake the Cow, from the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA)</li><li>Paramount Pictures Characters: Sonic the Hedgehog and Gabby from Gabby’s Dollhouse&nbsp;</li><li>Patriotic Mouse, DJ Bunny, and DJ Mouse</li><li>PBS KIDS Characters: Alma from Alma’s Way, Donkey from Donkey Hodie, Daniel Tiger from Daniel Tiger’s Neighborhood, Molly from Molly of Denali, Xavier Riddle of Xavier Riddle and the Secret Museum, Dog from WordWorld, and Elinor from Elinor Wonders Why</li><li>Peanuts Characters: Snoopy and Charlie Brown</li><li>Peeps Characters</li><li>Poe, the mascot of the Baltimore Ravens</li><li>Sesame Street Characters: Rosita and Cookie Monster</li><li>Swoop, the mascot of the Philadelphia Eagles</li><li>The Nationals’ Racing Presidents Washington, Jefferson, Lincoln, Roosevelt, Taft, and Coolidge</li><li>Universal Pictures Characters: The Minions</li><li>Warner Brothers Characters: Ace and Kypto from DC League of Super Pets</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on His Intent to Nominate Michael Barr to Serve as Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal&#160;Reserve</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/statement-from-president-biden-on-his-intent-to-nominate-michael-barr-to-serve-as-vice-chair-for-supervision-of-the-federal-reserve/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, I am announcing my intent to nominate Michael Barr as the next Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal Reserve.&#160;Michael brings the expertise and experience necessary for this important position at a critical time for our economy and families across the country.&#160; Since I took office, the economy has created nearly 8 million jobs,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, I am announcing my intent to nominate Michael Barr as the next Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal Reserve.&nbsp;Michael brings the expertise and experience necessary for this important position at a critical time for our economy and families across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since I took office, the economy has created nearly 8 million jobs, and millions of families have the dignity a paycheck can provide and a little bit more breathing room. I know that rising prices and inflation are straining families’ budgets. While I’m doing everything in my power to lower prices for families, the Federal Reserve plays a critical role in fighting inflation and Barr will make a strong Vice&nbsp;Chair for Supervision, joining my other nominees for the Federal Reserve that the Senate is considering.</p>



<p>Barr has spent his career protecting consumers, and during his time at Treasury, played a critical role in creating both the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau and the position for which I am nominating him. He was instrumental in the passage of Dodd-Frank, to ensure a future financial crisis would not create devastating economic hardship for working families. Barr has strong support from across the political spectrum—and has been confirmed by the Senate on a bipartisan basis. And, he understands that this job is not a partisan one, but one that plays a critical role in regulating our nation’s financial institutions to ensure Americans are treated fairly and to protect the stability of our economy.</p>



<p>I will work with Senate Banking Committee Chair Sherrod Brown to move Barr’s nomination forward quickly, and urge the Senate to swiftly confirm the four eminently qualified nominees for the Board of Governors—Jerome Powell, Lael Brainard, Philip Jefferson, and Lisa Cook—currently awaiting a vote.</p>



<p><strong>Michael Barr<br></strong>Michael S. Barr is currently the Joan and Sanford Weill Dean of the Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy, the Frank Murphy Collegiate Professor of Public Policy, the Roy F. and Jean Humphrey Proffitt Professor of Law at the University of Michigan Law School, and the founder and faculty director of the University of Michigan&#8217;s Center on Finance, Law &amp; Policy. At the Law School, Barr taught Financial Regulation and International Finance, and co-founded the International Transactions Clinic and the Detroit Neighborhood Entrepreneurs Project.</p>



<p>Barr served in the Obama Administration as the U.S. Department of the Treasury&#8217;s assistant secretary for financial institutions, and was a key architect of the Dodd-Frank Act. He also served the National Economic Council in the White House. In the Clinton Administration, Barr served as Treasury Secretary Robert E. Rubin&#8217;s special assistant, as deputy assistant secretary of the Treasury, as special adviser to President Clinton, and as a special adviser and counselor on the policy planning staff at the U.S. Department of State.</p>



<p>Barr served as a law clerk to U.S. Supreme Court Justice David H. Souter during October Term 1993, and previously to the Hon. Pierre N. Leval, then of the Southern District of New York. He received his JD from Yale Law School, his MPhil in international relations as a Rhodes Scholar from Magdalen College, Oxford University, and his BA, summa cum laude, with honors in history, from Yale University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary to the Vice President Kirsten&#160;Allen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/14/statement-by-press-secretary-to-the-vice-president-kirsten-allen-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 01:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Vice President spoke with International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers’ (IBEW) locals across the country to discuss the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to workers, and to encourage collaboration as we implement the historic, Bipartisan Infrastructure Law which will create good-paying, union jobs across the country. She also talked about her memorable visits to IBEW halls,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Vice President spoke with International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers’ (IBEW) locals across the country to discuss the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to workers, and to encourage collaboration as we implement the historic, Bipartisan Infrastructure Law which will create good-paying, union jobs across the country. She also talked about her memorable visits to IBEW halls, facilities, and programs through the years, including as Vice President, most recently during a trip to North Carolina.<br> <br>The Vice President thanked IBEW President Lonnie Stephenson for his leadership, and said she looks forward to their continued work together.  <strong>​</strong><br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>###</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
