<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 17:34:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on the Attack Against Congressman&#160;Zeldin</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/22/statement-from-president-biden-on-the-attack-against-congressman-zeldin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 17:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I condemn the attack on Congressman Zeldin in the strongest terms. As I’ve said before, violence has absolutely no place in our society or our politics. I am especially grateful for the courage of those who immediately intervened, and that he is unharmed and was able to continue his speech. I also want to thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I condemn the attack on Congressman Zeldin in the strongest terms. As I’ve said before, violence has absolutely no place in our society or our politics. I am especially grateful for the courage of those who immediately intervened, and that he is unharmed and was able to continue his speech. I also want to thank the law enforcement officers who quickly took action and are investigating this attack that defies our fundamental democratic values.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/22/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $175 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Made in America Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/22/a-proclamation-on-made-in-america-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 17:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; &#160;During Made in America Week, we celebrate American workers, the products they make, the services they provide, and the incredible impact they have on our Nation&#8217;s economy. &#160;Across the world, &#8220;Made in America&#8221; is a badge of quality, and this week we honor the proud legacy and promising future of American goods, services,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;During Made in America Week, we celebrate American workers, the products they make, the services they provide, and the incredible impact they have on our Nation&#8217;s economy. &nbsp;Across the world, &#8220;Made in America&#8221; is a badge of quality, and this week we honor the proud legacy and promising future of American goods, services, jobs, and innovation &#8212; the collective engine of American prosperity.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The COVID-19 pandemic and the economic crisis it caused, as well as Vladimir Putin&#8217;s unjustified and unprovoked war on Ukraine, have underscored the importance of a strong and secure domestic industrial base.&nbsp; We have seen in recent years that when goods made overseas become unavailable or exorbitantly costly, American families feel the pain.&nbsp; For years, &#8220;Buy American&#8221; was&nbsp;a hollow slogan &#8212; too many goods and services paid for by American taxpayers were outsourced abroad at the expense of American jobs. &nbsp;In my Administration, &#8220;Buy American&#8221; is an ironclad promise &#8212; and we have taken bold action to make it real.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During my first year in office, we created more manufacturing jobs on average per month than any other President has in&nbsp;the last 50 years. &nbsp;Businesses are investing in American manufacturing and creating thousands of good-paying union jobs to meet the demands of our modern economy and rebuild that economy around working people.&nbsp; We are creating more opportunity for workers and businesses who have too often been overlooked by investing in racial, gender, and geographic diversity for industries across the country.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Federal Government is the largest buyer of consumer goods in the world.&nbsp; To ensure that we are investing in American products, I recently announced a procurement rule that strengthens Buy American provisions by increasing the Made in America content threshold from 55 percent to 75 percent so that goods have to be truly made in America to be considered &#8220;Made in America.&#8221; &nbsp;This represents the biggest change to the Buy American Act in almost 70 years.&nbsp; I also named our Nation&#8217;s first-ever Made in America Director to serve in a high-level White House role.&nbsp; I continue to call on the Congress to pass the Bipartisan Innovation Act so that we can create more resilient domestic supply chains and unleash the next generation of American innovation for the industries and jobs of the future.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is critical to advancing our Made in America agenda. &nbsp;We are rebuilding our Nation&#8217;s roads, bridges, ports, airports, and so much more.&nbsp; We&nbsp;are constructing a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle chargers installed by union workers on highways and in communities across America.&nbsp; We are ensuring that every American has clean drinking water.&nbsp; We are creating good-paying union jobs, revitalizing American manufacturing, and positioning the United States to continue to lead throughout the 21st century.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In addition, we are leveraging a federally funded national network &#8212; the Manufacturing Extension Partnership &#8212; to help Government agencies connect with new suppliers across the country, including Black, Brown, and Native American-owned small businesses, which have often been excluded from these opportunities.&nbsp; My Administration also launched MadeInAmerica.gov to help American businesses in every community identify available government contracts, and we created a Made in America Council to help ensure that our future is made in all of America by all of America&#8217;s workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A vibrant domestic industrial base is key to building an economy that works for working people and advancing America&#8217;s global leadership with American manufacturers and workers at the&nbsp;forefront. &nbsp;During Made in America Week, let us celebrate everything that is Made in America and the workers, businesses, and innovators who are the driving force behind their success.&nbsp; America is the most innovative country in the world, and together, we will build a competitive economy for the future right here at home.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim July 24 through July 30, 2022, as Made in America Week.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this week by supporting American workers and domestic businesses that are the backbone of building a future here in America and celebrating Made in America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-second day of July, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-second, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-seventh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letters to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Mali</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/22/letters-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-mali/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 16:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register </em>for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the situation in Mali declared in Executive Order 13882 of July 26, 2019, is&nbsp;to&nbsp;continue in effect beyond July 26, 2022.</p>



<p>The situation in Mali, including repeated violations of ceasefire arrangements made pursuant to the 2015 Agreement on Peace and Reconciliation in Mali; the expansion of terrorist activities into southern and central Mali; the intensification of drug trafficking and trafficking in persons, human rights abuses, and hostage-taking; a further coup d&#8217;etat; the presence of foreign mercenaries threatening peace, security, and stability; and the intensification of attacks against civilians, the Malian defense and security forces, the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali (MINUSMA), and international security presences, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; Therefore, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13882 with respect to the situation in Mali<em>.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Mali</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/22/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-mali-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 16:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 26, 2019, by Executive Order 13882, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.)to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in Mali. The situation in Mali,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 26, 2019, by Executive Order 13882, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>)to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in Mali.</p>



<p>The situation in Mali, including repeated violations of ceasefire arrangements made pursuant to the 2015 Agreement on Peace and Reconciliation in Mali; the expansion of terrorist activities into southern and central Mali; the intensification of drug trafficking and trafficking in persons, human rights abuses, and hostage-taking; a further coup d&#8217;etat; the presence of foreign mercenaries threatening peace, security, and stability; and the intensification of attacks against civilians, the Malian defense and security forces, the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali (MINUSMA), and international security presences, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13882 on July&nbsp;26, 2019, must continue in effect beyond July 26, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section&nbsp;202(d) of&nbsp;the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13882 with respect to the situation in Mali<em>.</em></p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 22, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter from Dr. Kevin O&#8217;Connor: President&#160;Biden SARS-CoV-2&#160;Update</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/22/letter-from-dr-kevin-oconnor-president-biden-sars-cov-2-update/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 15:16:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To view the letter from the Physician to the President, visit: https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Letter-7.22.pdf]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>To view the letter from the Physician to the President, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Letter-7.22.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/Letter-7.22.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signing: H.R.&#160;8351</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/07/22/bill-signing-h-r-8351/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 13:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, July 21, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 8351, the “Formula Act,” which amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to suspend temporarily rates of duty on imports of certain infant formula products, and for other purposes. Thank you to Senators Lee, Wyden, and Crapo, and Representatives Blumenauer, DelBene, Larson,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, July 21, 2022, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 8351, the “Formula Act,” which amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to suspend temporarily rates of duty on imports of certain infant formula products, and for other purposes.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Lee, Wyden, and Crapo, and Representatives Blumenauer, DelBene, Larson, Kildee, Neal, and Brady.   </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: National Cyber Workforce and Education&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/fact-sheet-national-cyber-workforce-and-education-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 03:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 19, 2022, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis hosted the National Cyber Workforce and Education Summit at the White House. The event focused on building our Nation’s cyber workforce, improving skills-based pathways to cyber jobs, educating Americans so that they have the skills they need to thrive in our increasingly digital society, and improving&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 19, 2022, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis hosted the National Cyber Workforce and Education Summit at the White House. The event focused on building our Nation’s cyber workforce, improving skills-based pathways to cyber jobs, educating Americans so that they have the skills they need to thrive in our increasingly digital society, and improving Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility (DEIA) in the cyber field. Bringing together entities who employ, train, and educate cyber professionals and Americans at large, the event involved senior U.S. Government officials, senior executives from the private sector, and thought leaders from across the cyber community and the education sector.</p>



<p>Participants included Ambassador Susan E. Rice, White House Domestic Policy Advisor; Secretary of Commerce Gina M. Raimondo; Secretary of Labor Martin J. Walsh; Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas; and Under Secretary of Education James Kvaal. Other U.S. Government participants included Jen Easterly, Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency; Laurie Locascio, Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology; Anne Neuberger, Deputy Assistant to the President and Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology on the National Security Council; George Barnes, Deputy Director of the National Security Agency; and Principal Deputy National Cyber Director Kemba Walden. The Biden-Harris Administration and the various stakeholders in this area are committed to meeting the challenges and opportunities relating to cyber workforce and education, which will help improve the economy, secure Americans and our Nation’s infrastructure, advance our digital way of life, and enable our society to maximize cyber capabilities to achieve our highest aspirations.</p>



<p>The Summit included three roundtable discussions: the “All” roundtable focused on ways to help ensure that all Americans are equipped with the skills and knowledge to effectively and safely engage in our global digital ecosystem; the “Many” roundtable explored ways to improve practices in cyber-adjacent fields that are not focused solely on cyber but are still impacted by it, are related to it, or benefit from it; and the “Few” roundtable discussed the jobs and career pathways that are specifically focused on cyber.</p>



<p>In connection with the Summit, the Biden-Harris Administration announced the following actions:</p>



<ul><li><strong>National Cyber Director Chris Inglis</strong> committed to developing a National Cyber Workforce and Education Strategy in coordination with other elements of the Executive Office of the President (EOP) as well as Federal departments and agencies, with input from key public and private stakeholders. The National Cyber Workforce and Education Strategy will aim to address the challenges and opportunities in these critical areas, improve collaboration across government-wide efforts, help align resources to aspirations, and implement Biden-Harris Administration priorities on education and workforce development.</li><li><strong>Secretary of Commerce Gina M. Raimondo and Secretary of Labor Martin J. Walsh </strong><a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/osec/osec20220719">announced</a> a 120-day Cybersecurity Apprenticeship Sprint that they are leading with support from other Federal agencies, including the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Education, the Office of Personnel Management, and others. This initiative is aimed at providing individuals with the opportunity to receive the training and mentorship they need to begin a career in the cyber workforce by expanding and promoting cyber-related Registered Apprenticeship programs. More information on this program can be found at <a href="https://www.apprenticeship.gov/cybersecurity-apprenticeship-sprint">https://www.apprenticeship.gov/cybersecurity-apprenticeship-sprint</a>.</li><li><strong>Ambassador Susan E. Rice </strong>announced efforts to strengthen the K-12 system to more effectively prepare students for job opportunities in cybersecurity.Specifically, 1) the National Security Agency is supporting an initiative by the U.S. Department of Education’s Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education that will provide technical assistance to state and local educational agencies to accelerate the development, adoption, and implementation of middle grades CTE programs focused on emerging career pathways, such as space and cybersecurity; and 2) the U.S. Department of Commerce’s National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education will make its Cybersecurity Workforce Framework—which provides a range of cyber curricula and resources—easier to use for K-12 teachers and leaders by creating a K12 Educator FAQ resource.</li></ul>



<p>In addition, the following organizations have made substantial announcements, commitments, or pledges in connection with the Summit:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Accenture</strong> is committed to creating access to new roles in cybersecurity, cloud, and other technical areas through its apprenticeship and upskilling programs. This is part of Accenture’s broader goal in the U.S. to fill 20% of entry-level roles from its apprenticeship program. Additionally, Accenture is committed to training all 700,000+ of its own people through its award-winning interactive security awareness courses next year.</li><li><strong>The</strong> <strong>Alperovitch Institute for Cybersecurity Studies</strong>, aimed at developing a unique mix of geopolitical focus and technical rigor with cutting edge research at the intersection of cybersecurity and statecraft, has been established to train postgraduate students to become future policymakers and practitioners for leading firms and government agencies in the field of cybersecurity. The Alperovitch Institute will also offer an executive education program to provide critical understanding of cyber issues to industry executives, boards of directors, Congressional staffers, government officials, and military and intelligence officers, with classes to begin this fall.</li><li><strong>Auburn University’s</strong> Ginn College of Engineering commits to incorporate the U.S. Department of Energy’s National Cyber-Informed Engineering (CIE) Strategy throughout its engineering and computer science programs. As a land grant institution with roots in outreach and extension to its citizenry, Auburn also announced an initiative to partner with cooperative extension offices across the state to better reach underserved communities.</li><li><strong>Cisco </strong>is committing to training an additional 200,000 students in the U.S. over the next three years and will continue to increase the reach and impact of its efforts. For nearly 25 years, Cisco Networking Academy has trained more than two million U.S. students with leading networking and cybersecurity skills, and currently partners with 49% of the nation’s community and technical colleges and 48 of the nation’s 107 Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs).</li><li><strong>CompTIA</strong>, in partnership with ConnectWise,will run a nationwide pilot program to fill critical cybersecurity roles for managed services providers.CompTIA, as a National Program Sponsor for Apprenticeship, will use its training and certifications to provide jobseekers the skills needed for a career in IT and help employers realize the benefits of IT apprenticeship.</li><li><strong>The Council on Competitiveness</strong> National Commission on Innovation and Competitiveness Frontiers is launching two new working groups this fall: “The Future of Work: Developing, Supporting, and Expanding the Modern Innovation Workforce” and “The Future of Technology: Developing and Deploying Disruptive Technologies at Scale.” Both working groups will address how to advance and optimize cyber infrastructures of the future, including the robust cyber security and resiliency on which these digital platforms depend.</li><li><strong>The Cyber Readiness Institute (CRI) </strong>has released a new guide to raise awareness and implementation of multi-factor authentication (MFA) among small and medium-sized businesses (SMB). The new MFA guide provides clear and actionable information SMBs can implement today to enhance their cybersecurity. Developed with input from CRI’s Small Business Advisory Council and subject matter experts at the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), the guide employs an FAQ format to address concerns SMBs have expressed about using MFA.</li><li><strong>Dakota State University </strong>highlighted their $90 million investment for a cyber-research initiative supported by a multi-party, public-private partnership. These funds will be used to double the annual number of graduates of The Beacom College of Computer and Cyber Sciences over the next 5 years, launch a statewide Governor’s Cyber Academy accessible to all high school students, and build and operate an applied research laboratory facility in Sioux Falls, South Dakota.</li><li><strong>Fortinet </strong>is furthering its commitment to close the cyber skills gap by making its information security awareness and training service available for free for all K-12 school districts across the U.S. The expansion of its free training offerings provides the potential to help more than 8 million staff and faculty members in U.S. schools become more cyber aware and improve their skillsets to avoid breaches at educational institutions. This initiative will also advance Fortinet’s pledge to train 1 million people in cybersecurity by 2026.</li><li><strong>Girls Who Code </strong>will develop a coding challenge and activity sets focused on cybersecurity that will be geared toward middle and high school students, and implement workshops for Computer Science Education Week focused on cybersecurity and introductions to cryptography this fall.</li><li><strong>IBM</strong> is creating more pathways to cybersecurity careers through its new Cybersecurity Leadership Centers with Historically Black Colleges &amp; Universities (HBCUs) and Minority Serving Institutions (MSIs) and is partnering with the American Council on Education (ACE) to translate cybersecurity apprenticeships into college credits. This builds on IBM’s commitment last year to train more than 150,000 people in cybersecurity skills over three years through its signature programs – IBM SkillsBuild, IBM Security Academy, and its collaboration with Coursera.</li><li><strong>(ISC)²</strong>—the world’s largest nonprofit association of certified cybersecurity professionals—announced the (ISC)<sup>2</sup>&nbsp;One Million Certified in Cybersecurity<sup>SM</sup>&nbsp;program, pledging to put one million people through its Certified in Cybersecurity entry-level certification exam and education program for free. (ISC)² also has committed that half of this investment – 500,000 course enrollments and exams – will be directed toward students of HBCUs, minority-serving institutions (MSIs), tribal organizations and women’s organizations across the U.S. and the globe.</li><li><strong>The Linux Foundation (LF) </strong>is offering for free the Developing Secure Software training program, which is 15 hours of training across 3 modules (security principles; implementation considerations and software verification; and cloud security). The goal is to teach software developers how to develop more secure software from the beginning because that is much more efficient than finding and remediating vulnerabilities. Since launching it this spring, over 10,000 students have started the course and over 1,000 completed it and received their verifiable certification. Over the next few months, LF will launch new courses and certification exams on topics such as Sigstore, SBOMs and Air Gap Software Delivery.</li><li><strong>NightDragon</strong>, along with several industry partners, is creating the Cyber Talent Hub (CTH) because the Nation must leverage technology to better align the economic incentives of stakeholders involved in addressing the cyber talent shortage. The CTH will take the best attributes and practices from other technology driven marketplaces, helping employers find qualified candidates from diverse backgrounds and subsidize their cybersecurity education and training, which is tailored to the specific positions sought by these students.</li><li><strong>NPower </strong>will offer skill development opportunities and free IT training and credentials to military-connected individuals as well as young adults from underserved and underrepresented communities. NPower will increase the number of students in its Tech Fundamentals certification training by 50% within three years, thereby increasing its pipeline for advanced credentials in cloud computing and cybersecurity. NPower will also double the number of participants in its cybersecurity and cloud training over the next three years. These goals include expanding its SkillBridge cyber training program so that military service members transitioning to civilian employment are well positioned for careers in cybersecurity.</li><li><strong>Trellix </strong>has undertaken numerous initiatives, including hiring 50 interns, 40% of whom are from diverse backgrounds, and committing to hiring 100 more in the next year; partnering with the Hispanic Alliance for Career Enhancement (HACE) to launch a comprehensive mentorship and educational program; and partnering with Gotara, a global career growth platform for women in STEM+.<strong></strong></li></ul>



<p>A video recording of the Summit’s keynote session is available <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I7FvGMpuS8w">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris To Members of Omega Psi Phi&#160;Fraternity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-to-members-of-omega-psi-phi-fraternity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 01:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carole Hoefener CenterCharlotte, North Carolina  THE VICE PRESIDENT: &#160; Thank you.&#160; Good afternoon to the Brothers of the Omega Psi Phi.&#160; It’s good to be with you all. I just &#8212; I stopped by &#8212; I’m so happy that this worked out.&#160; I’m on my way to the airport.&#160; I came here to North Carolina to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Carole Hoefener Center<br>Charlotte, North Carolina </em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT: &nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good afternoon to the Brothers of the Omega Psi Phi.&nbsp; It’s good to be with you all.<br><br>I just &#8212; I stopped by &#8212; I’m so happy that this worked out.&nbsp; I’m on my way to the airport.&nbsp; I came here to North Carolina to talk about a few things, but I’m so happy to see you.&nbsp; The last time, Dr. Marion, we were all together was &#8212; what was it 2019, Atlantic City?<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Atlantic City.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Atlantic City.&nbsp; And we had a huge group there, and I know for the Conclave this is the first time probably in two years &#8212; right? &#8212; that you’ve been in person.<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Four years.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Four years in person.&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;<br><br>I just attended our sorority’s Boulé.&nbsp; We had that in Orlando just a couple &#8212; last week, wasn&#8217;t it?&nbsp; Last week.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>So, it&#8217;s so good to see everybody.<br><br>And listen, I just wanted to come by to say thank you.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been through a lot in our nation over the last couple of years.&nbsp; And the men of Omega Psi Phi, as always, as I have known you my entire life, I feel have been leaders &#8212; national leaders on so many important issues and including what you all did to elect Joe Biden and to elect me as Vice President of the United States.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And I think &#8212; I mean, when I was at the Boulé in Orlando, I was talking about how our sorority, with so many of our sister sororities &#8212; the Divine Nine as a whole &#8212; really organized folks around that important election.<br><br>And, you know, now we&#8217;re 110 days out from a midterm that is so critically important.<br><br>And if you don&#8217;t mind, I&#8217;ll talk just a little bit about that, because I&#8217;m here to also, yet again, come to you to ask for your leadership and to thank you in advance for what I know you&#8217;ve already planned to do.&nbsp;<br><br>A hundred and ten days out.&nbsp; And right now &#8212; I’ll just be very frank with you &#8212; we need to elect two more senators in the United States Senate who are willing to pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act and the Freedom to Vote Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who are willing to take seriously and pass the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Who will stand up for the Women&#8217;s Health <s>Initiative</s> [Protection] Act. &nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause). &nbsp;<br><br>Two votes, right here in North Carolina &#8212; Cheri Beasley &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who can win (inaudible).<br><br>I was just in Pennsylvania &#8212; John Fetterman &#8212; right? &#8212; who can win.&nbsp; And if we pick up some seats, then during the course of our administration, we can really see through what we got started.<br><br>But because of all that you did as leaders, who then inspire other leaders, we did win in 2020 because we convinced people based on our good word and standing in community that it would matter, and it did.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I was just over &#8212; I was with the governor of North Carolina, Roy Cooper, and we were talking about it.&nbsp; Our administration was able to extend the Child Tax Credit, which is why we were able in the first year to lift over 40 percent of Black children in America out of poverty.<br><br>We were able to pass &#8212; (applause) &#8212; a tax cut for working families of up to $8,000 a year, which means more money in their pocket to pay for school supplies and medication and food for their children.&nbsp; We put over $5 billion into our HBCUs because we know they are &#8212; (applause) &#8212; (inaudible).<br><br>We have, through our Delta sister, Marcia Fudge &#8212; Secretary Marcia Fudge at HUD &#8212; taken on one of the longstanding civil rights issues, which has been fair housing, and looking at a very specific issue beyond what we know has been the historic and current issues of things like redlining, but also one of the issues that has received more attention because we are handling it, which is racially biased home appraisals, knowing that our families, our greatest source of wealth and intergenerational wealth &#8212; meaning passing it from the grandparent to the children to grandchildren &#8212; is homeownership.&nbsp;<br><br>However, with home appraisals, we still have an issue &#8212; you all have heard the stories &#8212; those stories of a Black family trying to sell them home, and then the appraiser comes in and appraises the home for what they know is undervaluing the home.<br><br>So they have friends of the family who are a white family, so they invite that family to come in and put up their family pictures and take down the Black family’s pictures.<br><br>The appraiser comes in and, all of a sudden, the appraisal is much higher.&nbsp; Racial bias in home appraisals, which then directly impact the ability of a Black family and, by extension, the community to pass on intergenerational wealth.&nbsp; These are some of the things we&#8217;ve been taking on, but there&#8217;s so much more to do.<br><br>And so, I&#8217;m here to ask you to help us with this because there is so much at stake.<br><br>You look at states like Georgia, like Texas.&nbsp; You look at what some of these folks in North Carolina are doing and South Carolina are doing to do to attack the right of people to vote.&nbsp; And you know why they&#8217;re doing it?&nbsp; You can see a direct link between what Omega Psi Phi and so many others did to increase the voter turnout, which was record highs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and the backlash &#8212; the backlash &#8212; because they saw folks, who weren’t turning up before, turned out.&nbsp; And then all of a sudden, after the election, among those who were denying and lying, frankly &#8212; excuse my word &#8212; but lying about who won the election. &nbsp;By the way, we won.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But then they decided, well, maybe a way to do it is to pass laws that &#8212; for example, now in Georgia &#8212; make it illegal to give folks food and water if they&#8217;re standing in line to vote.&nbsp; Passing laws to make it more difficult to vote around trying to get rid of drop boxes.&nbsp; Why do we need drop boxes?&nbsp; Well, if you are a single father or a single mother and you got them three kids back &#8212; bad kids in the backseat &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and you know you want to go vote, you know you can’t get out and stand in line to vote and wait for four hours.&nbsp; But you can pack them kids in the backseat after &#8212; the night before &#8212; you filled out your ballot, and then drive over to the drop box, drop it off, and keep driving.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>And these are the kinds of things, the details that matter about what we are up against.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I&#8217;m here to thank you and to ask you that we continue to educate &#8212; as is the history of this so important fraternity &#8212; to always educate the people about what is at stake, and to inspire through the model of your success and leadership, to inspire people to see what is possible, and to also remember who we are, who we have been, and who we’re going to be.&nbsp; Because that is who this organization is.&nbsp;<br><br>And one last point that I&#8217;d like to raise is the issue of choice, because I need your help &#8212; and I&#8217;m just having a candid conversation here &#8212; about how we are going to talk with our young men.&nbsp; Because I think it is very important that we not leave our young men out of any conversation that is of national importance.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think it&#8217;s important to also recognize and agree that one does not have to abandon their faith or their beliefs to agree that a woman, and not her government, should make decisions about her own body.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So it may not be your choice, it may not be the choice for your family, but the government shouldn&#8217;t be in the business of making that decision for her.<br><br>And I &#8212; and I &#8212; I&#8217;m here to ask for your help, because it is about our sisters and our daughters and our mothers and our aunties.&nbsp; It is about seeing that, also on the issue of maternal health &#8212; it&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve been working on for years &#8212; the issue of Black maternal mortality is real, which is that Black women are still, in this country, three times more likely than other women to die from pregnancy-related issues.&nbsp; A lot of it which has to do with an ilabi- &#8212; inability to have access to the kind of care she needs.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, when we think about how Black women are experiencing the healthcare system in America, we know it&#8217;s an issue for all of us.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something that we should weigh in to address.<br><br>Not to mention &#8212; you know, my goddaughter is 17 right now, and she&#8217;s applying to college.&nbsp; And she knows she’s pledging AKA wherever she goes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; With all due respect to everybody else.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but she’s &#8212; she was &#8212; I was talking to her the other day, and she was like, “Auntie, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I got to now look at which states I’m looking at in terms of where I’m going to apply for college.”&nbsp; That’s real.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>So I would ask us to think &#8212; because I would like your help, in terms of &#8212; on my &#8212; at my stage and my platform.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s make sure that we&#8217;re not leaving anyone out of this important conversation, because it is front and center as a very real issue in our country.&nbsp;<br><br>And I can&#8217;t emphasize it more than sharing with you my experience as Vice President, which is: I&#8217;ve been traveling around the world.&nbsp; I just was just yesterday, or it was the day before, with the &#8212; President Zelenskyy’s wife, Madam Zelenska.&nbsp; I met him two days before the invasion of his nation when I was in Munich giving an important talk there about the integrity of what should be a global priority around sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp;<br><br>But what I can tell you is this: I&#8217;ve probably talked to &#8212; I&#8217;ve had at least 80 conversations in person or by phone with presidents, prime ministers, and kings, some of whom I’ve hosted at the official residence of the Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>We, as Americans, hold ourselves out to be a leader.&nbsp; We walk into these rooms, chin up, shoulders back, proud &#8212; openly proud of the fact that we hail from a democracy, one of the greatest in the world &#8212; flawed though it may be, imperfect though it may be.&nbsp;<br><br>And people around the world watch us because we are a role model.&nbsp; And each of us knows what that&#8217;s like in our personal lives to be a role model. &nbsp;It means people watch everything you do to see if what you do is consistent with what you say.<br><br>And they’re right now seeing that the United States Supreme Court &#8212; the court of Thurgood &#8212; took a constitutional right, that had been recognized, from the people of America, the women of America.<br><br>So when we&#8217;re looking at an issue like this, when we&#8217;re looking at an issue like voting rights and what is happening in our country, let&#8217;s also understand it’s not only about an attack on the rights that we have been leaders on, but it is an attack on our democracy.&nbsp; And in that way, it also extends to an attack on our standing around the world when we walk into these various rooms talking about the need for protecting human rights and standing up for democratic principles or rule of law.&nbsp;<br><br>So we got a lot of work to do.&nbsp; And this fraternity has always been front and center on all of these issues.&nbsp; And so, again, I&#8217;m here to say thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Enjoy the Conclave.&nbsp;<br><br>And thank you, Dr. Marion, for inviting me to come by and speak with you for a minute.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with North Carolina State Legislators on Reproductive Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-north-carolina-state-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 22:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened more than 20 North Carolina state legislators, local leaders, and advocates who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights.  The Vice President convened state legislators from across the country on July 8, 2022 at the White House; on July 14, 2022 in Orlando, Florida; on July 16,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened more than 20 North Carolina state legislators, local leaders, and advocates who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights.  The Vice President convened state legislators from across the country on July 8, 2022 at the White House; on July 14, 2022 in Orlando, Florida; on July 16, 2022 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; and on July 18, 2022 in Atlantic City, New Jersey.<br> <br>During the meeting, the legislators, advocates, and providers in attendance discussed the importance of building a broad coalition to protect reproductive rights. The state legislators described how Republican leaders in North Carolina are pushing for extreme laws that would take away the right of women to make decisions about their own bodies. The Vice President thanked North Carolina Governor Roy Cooper for using every tool to protect access to reproductive health care, including a recent state executive order issued to protect patients seeking care from harassment and intimidation, and his veto of extreme legislative attacks on reproductive rights.<br> <br>The Vice President shared actions the Administration is taking on a national level in response to the Supreme Court overturning <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, including protecting access to abortion medication, defending the Constitutional right to travel, and addressing patient privacy. The Vice President encouraged the state legislators to keep defending the rights of women in North Carolina and said she looks forward to continuing to fight alongside them to protect the people of our nation.<br> <br><strong>Speakers:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Governor Roy Cooper, North Carolina Governor</li><li>Rep. Julie von Haefen, NC State Representative</li><li>Sen. Natalie Murdock, NC State Senator</li><li>Jenny Black, President and CEO, Planned Parenthood South Atlantic</li><li>Calla Hales, Co-owner and Executive Director, A Preferred Women’s Health Center</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
