<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 15:59:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Applauds House Passage of Bipartisan Government Funding&#160;Bill</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-applauds-house-passage-of-bipartisan-government-funding-bill/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 15:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration applauded House passage&#160;of&#160;the bipartisan funding bill, which delivers for the American people through critical investments in a range of bipartisan priorities—from securing historic support for the Ukrainian people, to launching the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health, to investing in education, to tackling crime. The legislation will reduce costs for American&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration applauded House passage&nbsp;of&nbsp;the bipartisan funding bill, which delivers for the American people through critical investments in a range of bipartisan priorities—from securing historic support for the Ukrainian people, to launching the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health, to investing in education, to tackling crime. The legislation will reduce costs for American families and business, support our historic economic recovery, advance equity, and further restore U.S. leadership abroad. The bipartisan funding bill would also end a damaging series of short-term continuing resolutions that for months have undermined the government’s ability to meet pressing challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are making these historic and necessary investments in a fiscally responsible manner. The deficit dropped last year for the first time since 2015 and is currently on track to drop by more than $1 trillion compared to last year—the largest-ever one-year reduction.</p>



<p>The Senate should send the bipartisan funding bill to the President’s desk for signature without delay. Critical investments in the important legislation include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Delivering Historic Assistance to the Ukrainian People.&nbsp;</strong>As President Biden and bipartisan members of Congress have made clear, the United States is committed to supporting the Ukrainian people as they defend their country and democracy. The bipartisan funding bill includes $13.6 billion in humanitarian, security, and economic assistance for Ukraine and neighboring countries – augmenting the $1.4 billion in assistance the United States has provided to Ukraine since 2021. These resources will mean additional defense equipment for Ukraine, lifesaving humanitarian assistance for the Ukrainian people, and additional support for U.S troop deployments to neighboring countries.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Launching the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health.</strong>&nbsp;The bipartisan funding bill includes $1 billion to help launch the President’s Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health—a bold initiative to help speed transformational research to improve the health of all Americans, with an initial focus on cancer and other diseases such as diabetes and Alzheimer’s.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Tackling Gun Crime and Other Violent Crime. </strong>President Biden has been clear that we need to fund the police with the resources and training they need to protect our communities. The bipartisan funding bill bolsters Federal law enforcement capacity with an increase of $554 million over 2021 for Department of Justice law enforcement. This includes $1.5 billion for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF) to expand its capacity to tackle gun crime. The funding bill also increases the budget for the COPS Office by $126 million for a total of $512 million, and provides $50 million for a new Community Violence Intervention program at DOJ.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Making Education More Affordable.</strong> The bipartisan funding bill includes $17.5 billion for the Title I program – a $1 billion increase over 2021, the largest increase in over a decade &#8212; to ensure that schools with a high percentage of students from low-income families have the resources they need to deliver a high-quality education to all of their students. The bill also makes college more affordable by increasing the maximum Pell Grant by $400 above 2021 – the largest increase in the maximum award in over a decade – for millions of low- and middle-income students. </li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Tackling Climate Change and Advancing Environmental Justice. </strong>The bipartisan funding bill will provide a record $3.2 billion, an increase of $338 million over 2021, for the Department of Energy to build clean energy projects and boost clean energy manufacturing. It also includes $100 million in resources dedicated to advancing environmental justice at the Environmental Protection Agency, and provides an increase of $776 million for the Department of Interior and increases funding at the U.S. Department of Agriculture to prevent wildfires. </li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and President Andrzej Duda of Poland in Joint Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/10/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-in-joint-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 15:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Belweder PalaceWarsaw, Poland 12:57 P.M. CEST PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  Your Excellency and distinguished Madam Vice President of the United States of America, distinguished ladies and gentlemen: This is a very important moment in our relations.  But, first and foremost, under these circumstances which we are facing right now in Europe, behind our Eastern border, in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Belweder Palace<br>Warsaw, Poland</em></p>



<p>12:57 P.M. CEST<br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  Your Excellency and distinguished Madam Vice President of the United States of America, distinguished ladies and gentlemen: This is a very important moment in our relations.  But, first and foremost, under these circumstances which we are facing right now in Europe, behind our Eastern border, in Ukraine &#8212; friendly to us and with us &#8212; where the Russian troops are carrying out a barbarious aggression and murdering innocent people, murdering civilians, bombing maternity hospitals from which, under dramatic circumstances, wounded women right before labor &#8212; are being carried out.<br> <br>None of us has ever expected that we would be able to see such things in the 21st century.<br> <br>Especially it is a great satisfaction to all of us here in Poland that Madam Vice President of the United States of America, Ms. Kamala Harris, is here with us in Warsaw, in our country.<br></p>



<p>And she&#8217;s demonstrating that strength and depth of the atlantic &#8212; transatlantic and Allied bond, demonstrating decisive engagement and commitment of the United States to the security of NATO&#8217;s eastern flank and to Europe as a whole.<br> <br>Let me stress very forcefully: There is no doubt whatsoever that together with the United States and our other Allies within the framework of the North Atlantic Alliance, and along with the entire free and honest world, we stand with Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine, and we will try to do our best to make sure that Ukraine can be defended.<br> <br>Thank you very much, Madam Vice President, for coming.  Thank you for our meetings today, for the conversations that we have had.<br> <br>We had a meeting just a couple of minutes ago.  We had a private meeting, a tête-à-tête meeting.  And we also met with Polish and American delegations.  We discussed all the important topics.  And I highlighted very forcefully how important it is, and I thanked also for the position of the President of the United States, Mr. Joe Biden.  I thanked for the position of Madam Vice President and her team.  But I also thanked for the position of the U.S. Congress. <br> <br>I thanked for this necessity and, actually, the imposition of effective sanctions on the Russian Federation.  The United States is in the vanguard of those sanctions, and, speaking honestly, these sanctions are working.<br> <br>Above all, thank you also for all the support which is being provided to the fight in Ukraine &#8212; to Ukraine, which is defending itself.<br> <br>Thank you for the humanitarian assistance, which is being supplied there.<br> <br>And to you, Madam Vice President, I would like to thank for the involvement of all the organizations and of all the NGOs that are being involved in providing assistance &#8212; humanitarian assistance.  Also, they&#8217;re providing medical aid.  They&#8217;re providing equipment for children, for wounded, for the sick.<br> <br>My wife Agata is involved in this as well.  And I know that, in those respect, she is in cooperation with various institutions from the United States.  She is in contact with the First Lady of the United States, Jill Biden.<br> <br>I’m very happy that this Polish-American cooperation is developing.  But I&#8217;m pleased that it serves to provide common aid to the fight in Ukraine and common aid to all those who are suffering, all those who need this assistance from us.<br> <br>And today, I shared with Madam Vice President &#8212; I described the situation that we are facing.  I said that, today, for a number of days actually, we have been receiving refugees from Ukraine in Poland.  This number is close to 1.5 million persons who have come to us.  And I&#8217;m addressing my compatriots right now.  I was proud to tell Madam Vice President that all those people have not been sent to any camps and refugee camps.  They have been accepted and received by Polish families in Polish homes.  They are accommodated in Polish hotels, in Polish spa resorts, in Polish motels.<br> <br>Most often, however, they&#8217;re accommodated with private people.  They have been received by ordinary Polish people who feel in their hearts that they should extend a helping hand to the people in need.<br> <br>And I thank you so much for this, to my fellow Polish people.  This is a reason to be proud for us, for the Polish authorities.  And I&#8217;m very, very much grateful to you for that.<br> <br>At the same time, I asked Madam Vice President for support, as it is quite obvious that such a huge refugee crisis is a surprise for Poland.  And it is a complicated situation for Poland, for the Polish authorities in the era of the crisis.  The prices are growing &#8212; of fuel prices are growing; generally, the prices are growing.  That is why we do need this support.  And I&#8217;m going to be hugely grateful for any form of support because we have to survive this difficult time.<br> <br>And we have to do that by helping our neighbors, because that is extremely important right now. <br> <br>However, first and foremost, we discussed security issues.<br> <br>The presence of Madam Vice President here in Poland is yet another demonstration of U.S. presidents &#8212; of U.S. presence in Poland, next to the U.S. troops that we have here, next to U.S. defensive systems that are protecting our skies today and our land.<br> <br>We also have with us here today the political representation, the top-level political representation of the United States, led by Madam Vice President. <br> <br>And this is a very clear political message where important &#8212; most important things are happening today on the global stage in Europe: We have to rescue Ukraine.  All of us are acutely aware of that.  All hands should be on board.  Ukraine needs to be helped.  And we have to stay united in that respect.  We need to stand together in this respect within the North Atlantic Alliance, keeping solidarity, speaking absolutely with one voice, just as we have to stand together in the European Union and in all the other international communities.  We have to impose more sanctions on Russia.<br> <br>We cannot accept such military activities, which bear the characteristics of the features of a genocide, because I don&#8217;t think that anybody is in any doubt if hospitals are bombed, if hospitals are bombed where pregnant women are staying, where children are staying, when ordinary people are killed, where bombs are dropped, when missiles are launched into residential houses where there are no military installations, then this is an act of barbarity bearing the features of a genocide.  It aims at eliminating and destroying a nation.  Hence, we have to stand and present a very tough stance here as representatives of the free world. <br> <br>And Poland stands here together with the United States of America, just like &#8212; I have no doubt about that &#8212; our Allies stand with Ukraine and all the honest authorities and states, especially democratic states.<br> <br>And at the end of our conversation, I mentioned the fact that we want to boost our security also on our own here in Poland.  Also, thanks to the purchase of American equipment for our armed forces, there are already ongoing programs such as Patriot programs, such as HIMARS program, the program of the purchase of F-35s, or the recently started program &#8212; the purchase of Abrams tanks for Poland. <br> <br>I asked Madam Vice President that those programs should be accelerated as far as this as possible, because we want to provide this state-of-the-art equipment to our armed forces as soon as possible. <br> <br>If there is such a need &#8212; I think everybody can see that.  We do not need to comment on this situation.  We are able to witness the dramatic scenes unfolding in Ukraine every day in the media.  You can see those horrific &#8212; horrifying scenes. <br> <br>But at the same time, we&#8217;re able to witness the huge heroism and incredible determination of the Ukrainian people.  And we stand at the side of the Ukrainian people.  We’re going to support them with all our strength, but at the same time providing the security of our countries which is of crucial importance to us.<br> <br>Once again, thank you very much, Madam Vice President, for coming to Warsaw.  Thank you for this demonstration that we stand together and that we are a huge Euro-Atlantic community of freedom and security.  Thank you. <br> <br>I’d like to give the floor to Madam Vice President of the United States of America.  Madam Kamala Harris.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Thank you, President Duda, and for the warm welcome under unfortunate circumstances, given what is happening in Ukraine, our friend.  But I thank you for the warm welcome and for the very constructive and productive conversations we had today as part of our ongoing dialogue and friendship that spans generations. <br> <br>I would like to also speak directly to the Polish people.  I have shared with your president that, under his leadership &#8212; and your leadership has been extraordinary &#8212; the world has been watching Poland, Mr. President, your leadership and the leadership of the people of your country.  And we&#8217;ve witnessed extraordinary acts of generosity and kindness.  We have seen through images on the television &#8212; looking at images of ordinary people doing extraordinary things in support of the dignity and the wellbeing of perfect strangers.<br> <br>So I, first and foremost, want to express the thanks for the people of the United States to you, Mr. President, on behalf of our President, Joe Biden, and to the people of Poland for what you are doing every day.  It really represents the best of who we are.<br> <br>We are here and I am here in Poland today as part of an enduring, longstanding friendship and commitment between the United States and Poland based on shared values and priorities. <br> <br>I am here, standing here on the northern flank &#8212; on the eastern flank talking about what we have in terms of the eastern flank and our NATO Allies and what is at stake at this very moment.  What is at stake this very moment are some of the guiding principles around the NATO Alliance and, in particular, the issue and the importance of defending sovereignty and territorial integrity, in this case, of Ukraine.<br> <br>As President Duda has described, we have been witnessing for weeks &#8212; and certainly just in the last 24 hours &#8212; atrocities of unimaginable proportion.  A maternity hospital, a children&#8217;s hospital, where we have witnessed pregnant women who were there for care, for one reason &#8212; being taken out, because they required care because of an act of violence &#8212; unprovoked, unjustified.<br> <br>I am here, in Poland, as an expression of the enduring and important relationship between the United States and Poland that, again, has been longstanding, but, in particular on the issue of Ukraine, is unified and is clear.  We will do everything together, in partnership, in solidarity, to support what is necessary at this very moment in terms of the humanitarian and security needs of Ukraine and the Ukrainian people.<br> <br>Today, we discussed, Mr. President, many issues that relate to our special bond also, because, I will say as a point of personal privilege, we have a substantial Polish American community in my hometown of Los Angeles but throughout the United States, who understands the relationship that we have on many levels, including the diplomatic but also cultural relationships that span generations. <br> <br>And so, through all of that and in the spirit of those relationships and our shared commitments &#8212; our shared commitment to the importance of international norms and rules &#8212; you and I discussed today many important topics, in particular as it relates to the eastern flank.  And we talked specifically about what we cared deeply about in terms of our commitment &#8212; the United States commitment to Article 5. <br> <br>I&#8217;ve said it many times; I will say it again: The United States commitment to Article 5 is ironclad.  The United States is prepared to defend every inch of NATO territory.  The United States takes seriously that an attack against one is an attack against all.  We are here today to restate that commitment, but also do what we must do to reinforce our support of Poland and our Allies through the EU and NATO Alliance.<br> <br>In particular, as it relates to troop deployment, we have recently deployed an additional 4,700 American troops to Poland.  That&#8217;s on top of the years of rotation of about 5,000 American troops in Poland. <br> <br>We are pleased to have announced this week that we have directed two Patriot missile defense systems to Poland.  And today, I can announce that we have delivered those Patriot systems to Poland.  We do this as a reminder and as a demonstration of our commitment to the security of our Allies and our commitment, in particular, to Poland at this moment in time.<br> <br>As it relates to the people of Ukraine: They have suffered immensely.  When we talk about humanitarian aid, it is because, yes, the assistance is necessary, but what compels us also is the moral outrage that all civilized nations feel when we look at what is happening to innocent men, women, children, grandmothers, grandfathers who are fleeing everything they&#8217;ve known.  Our outrage, which compels not only our security assistance but our humanitarian assistance, is rooted in the fact that also we support the people of Ukraine who have shown extraordinary courage and skill and their willingness and, yes, ability to fight against Putin’s war and Russia&#8217;s aggression.<br> <br>So, today we are also announcing, in pursuit of what must happen, which is to provide humanitarian assistance, that we will give another $50 billion &#8212; the United States will &#8212; through the U.N.’s World Food Programme to assist with humanitarian aid. <br> <br>The President and I also talked about the fact that, as he mentioned, Poland has taken, in just a very short period of time, in excess of one and a half million refugees in from Ukraine.  And that has put an extraordinary burden on Poland and the people of Poland.  And so, we will continue with the support that we can give you, Mr. President, in terms of the work that you and the people of Poland have been doing to bear this burden, but in a way that really has been with such grace<br>and such generosity.<br> <br>We also are pleased to have shared with the President what our United States Congress has done, which is there is a commitment now of $13.6 billion in human- &#8212; humanitarian and security assistance that will be then distributed and shared with Ukraine and the people of this region and Europe, all again understanding that this moment in time requires both a humanitarian response as well as security assistance.<br> <br>And today, I&#8217;m also pleased to say that we are in ongoing discussions with Poland and our Allies about the effectiveness of sanctions thus far and going forward.  As we have announced in the United States, we have, through the United States Department of Justice, started a task force to do what is required and necessary and appropriate in terms of investigations as it relates to any criminal activities and behaviors on behalf of institutions and individuals, including oligarchs. <br> <br>We talked &#8212; the President and I &#8212; about the effectiveness of the sanctions we&#8217;ve seen thus far, in terms of the courage and the bold action that has been taken through the NATO Alliance to do what is necessary to send a clear signal that there will be, as we promised, severe cost and consequence for Russia&#8217;s aggression to the point that we have now seen a freefall of the ruble, to the point that we have now seen that Russia&#8217;s credit rating has been rated as junk, and what we know to be real economic consequence to Russia because of Putin&#8217;s war.<br> <br>As you know, the President of the United States also made the decision to do what was necessary in terms of the purchase of Russian oil in the United States. <br> <br>Again, we will continue to focus on this issue, keeping in mind that this is a moment that requires severe and swift consequence for Russia&#8217;s aggression against Ukraine.<br> <br>And I&#8217;ll close by saying what we say every day for these last weeks, which is we stand with the people of Ukraine, that we admire their courage, and that we are aligned in our support of their sovereignty and territorial integrity. <br> <br>Thank you, Mr. President.<br> <br>Q    (As interpreted.)  My name is Żaklina Skowrońska.  I represent Polish Television.  I would like to ask my question to both Madam Vice President and Mr. President.  In what way has this brutal attack of Russia against Ukraine impacted Polish-American relations?  Antony Blinken, State Secretary, during his last visit to Poland was saying that the Polish-American friendship has never been so strong in history as it is now.  Is it going to translate also on the permanent military presence of the United States in Poland?  Thank you very much.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  It cannot be said too frequently or strongly enough: The relationship between the United States and Poland is a deep, enduring, and strong one and, dare I say, has become even stronger when we have been faced as a world with such adversity.  I think we all know, even in our personal lives, adversity really, truly, can present the real measure of an individual or a relationship.  And what we have seen without any doubt is that this friendship and relationship between the United States and Poland is a strong one.<br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  Ladies and gentlemen, answering your question, I want to go a little bit back into history &#8212; or deeper into history.  Let me put it in the following way: When I started my service as President of the Republic of Poland in 2015, I was perfectly aware of the fact that an aggressive Russia, like President Lech Kaczyński was saying in Georgia in 2008, would not stop only attacking Georgia in 2008 and attacking part of Ukraine in 2014.  I knew that this appetite, this imperial appetite will grow. <br> <br>And if the world does not react to that &#8212; if the world does not react, if the North Atlantic Alliance does not stand up, does not present a tough stance, then we will see more attacks from Russia &#8212; to which perhaps, sooner or later, also my country, Poland, would fall victim to.<br> <br>And when I started as President of Poland, I knew that I had to do everything that I could to protect Poland from such a scenario.  One has to use very clear and strong words here in the presence of Madam Vice President of the United States.  Those who understood well what I was saying back then, speaking about the Russian threat, were precisely the representatives of the United States, were the representatives of Barack Obama administration and the President himself back then, the U.S. generals as well.<br> <br>And precisely thanks to their support, we were able to obtain the North Atlantic Alliance presence on the eastern flank, were able to execute the strengthening of the eastern flank for the first time since we joined NATO in 1999.<br> <br>It was precisely in NATO Summit in Warsaw, through, first and foremost, the decisions of the U.S. President and his team, but also through the decisions of other Allies whom we were able to convince, has led to putting this presence on the eastern flank of the Alliance and, symbolically, in Poland.<br> <br>The United States is the framework nation.  At the same time, the U.S. soldiers came here and started the rotational presence in Poland.  It is a rotational but also a persistent presence, enduring presence.  It is a back-to-back presence.  Soldiers change, but the U.S. armed forces are present on our soil all the time.  And that was a breakthrough.<br> <br>If we recall the words of President Lech Kaczyński, which I quoted many times and who said those words to me back in 2008, he said, and I quote: “Andrzej, when U.S. soldiers are on our soil, when U.S. military installations are on our soil, when U.S. military equipment is put in our soil, then the whole world will be able to see that we are no longer a Russian sphere of influence.”  This is a true friendship.<br> <br>As Madam Vice President remarked today, “A friend in need is a friend indeed.”  That is why I&#8217;m really happy that today, when we are in need and when the NATO eastern flank is in need, the United States, by the decision of President Joe Biden, has deployed additional troops.  The U.S. is deploying more troops, and the U.S. is announcing the strengthening of this presence in our part of Europe and also in Poland, because this is precisely the understanding of the geopolitics of strategic goals that have to be achieved by this geopolitics and by the free world.  This is the understanding of the security.<br> <br>Is Polish American presence today, if we look at the last couple of years, stronger than ever?  Yes, Polish-American friendship, for sure, over the last seven years of my presidency is stronger than ever before.<br> <br>And today&#8217;s presence here today in Warsaw of Madam Vice President Kamala Harris is yet another strong evidence of that, just as the presence of all the representatives of Mr. President Joe Biden&#8217;s administration here recently on our soil.<br> <br>And also, this is evidenced by the frequency of contacts that I have with the President of the United States.  We frequently talk and discuss the most important security-related topics and our mutual relations.<br> <br>Yes, of course, whenever we speak about great politics and friendship, this is this friendship and great politics.  And this is the friendship between states for sure.  This is the friendship between Poland and the United States of America.  It is very strong right now &#8212; the strongest perhaps ever in history.<br> <br>WHITE HOUSE AIDE:  The next question will come from Nandita Bose of Reuters.<br> <br>Q    Hi, Madam Vice President.  Thank you for &#8212; and President Duda.  Thank you for taking my question. <br> <br>President Zelenskyy has strongly asked for better air power in recent days.  And my question is: What kind of alternative plans does the United States have to get materials to help Ukraine defend itself, especially now that you have declined Poland&#8217;s offer on jets?  Can you give us some specifics on what you discussed with the Polish leaders on this issue, Madam Vice President?<br> <br>And one for President Duda.  The United States says, Mr. President, it was not consulted before you made the offer to make your jets available to the United States.  Is that accurate?  And did Poland act unilaterally in making an offer?  If yes, why?  Especially now that you have spoken about the strong relationship that U.S. and Poland has shared over the years.  Thank you.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  I want to be very clear: The United States and Poland are united in what we have done and are prepared to do to help Ukraine and the people of Ukraine, full stop.<br> <br>In terms of the work that the United States has done thus far, we have, as you know, given military, humanitarian, and security assistance, and that is an ongoing process.<br> <br>As I mentioned earlier, Congress &#8212; the United States Congress has now made a decision for 13-plus billion dollars of United States &#8212; of U.S. money to go to Ukraine and our European allies to assist in terms of both their security and humanitarian needs.<br> <br>We have also, just this past week, given $240 million in security assistance delivered to Ukraine, and that’s on top of the $1 billion in just the past year that we have sent to Ukraine.<br> <br>I can tell you that the issue facing the Ukrainian people and our Allies in the eastern flank is something that occupies one of our highest priorities in terms of paying attention to the needs, understanding it is a dynamic situation and it requires us to be nimble and to be swift. <br> <br>I mentioned being swift in terms of accountability and consequence.  We also fully appreciate we must be swift in terms of providing assistance where we can be helpful.  And we will continue to do that.<br> <br>Q    Can you (inaudible) plans, especially in light of the issue with Poland on jets?<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Well, we&#8217;re making deliveries every day, in terms of what we can do in terms of assistance and, in particular, when you look at what we&#8217;ve been doing, as it relates to anti-tank and anti &#8212; defense systems.  That is an ongoing process, and that&#8217;s not going to stop to the extent that there is a need. <br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>POLISH AIDE:  (No translation provided.)<br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  One moment.  I need to give an answer as well. <br> <br>Madam, that situation is extremely complicated, because we are all saying that there is a fight going on in Ukraine for independence, for sovereignty, for freedom, and for survival.  And all of us support, with all the strength we have, the people of Ukraine. <br> <br>It is not only the military.  Also, the people of Ukraine have taken to arms to defend their homeland.  It is not only men; it’s also women who fight on the frontline shoulder-to-shoulder with men in order to defend their country.  And we have no doubt whatsoever that they need help and assistance.<br> <br>Let me say something more.  We accept that they have the right to demand this assistance from the international community.  They can demand this support from NATO.  We are providing them humanitarian assistance and material assistance the best we can.  We are trying to do our best. <br> <br>Some expectations were addressed in a very strong and unequivocal way, also towards us &#8212; towards Poland.  However, we are members of the North Atlantic Alliance.  And as far as security-related issues are concerned, we have to look at these not only through our own lens &#8212; through the prism of the security of Poland &#8212; but we also have to adopt the perspective of the security of NATO as a whole. <br> <br>So, in a nutshell, we have to be a responsible member of the North Atlantic Alliance.  That is why there were requests addressed to us.  Those requests were addressed to us by the Ukrainian side and also, to a certain extent, by the media. <br> <br>We behaved in such a way as a reliable member of NATO should behave &#8212; a member of NATO who does not want to expose NATO to any difficult situation.  On the other hand, we, as members of NATO, also wanted and want to look for ways of support for the fight in Ukraine.  And that is why we formulated statements, together with the Polish government &#8212; so myself as president, together with the Polish government. <br> <br>And this statement or this declaration was announced by the Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs.  It talked about the Polish possibilities &#8212; military possibilities of assisting Ukraine.  Simply, we decided to put those jets at the disposal of NATO, not expecting anything in return, because we stressed very clearly that, as a gap filler for the donated equipment, we were able to buy something that we would need as a replacement.  And we, ourselves, we’re ready to provide our equipment free of charge. <br> <br>But we wanted NATO as a whole to make a common decision so that Poland remains a credible member of NATO, not a country who decides on its own on important issues which impact the security of NATO as a whole &#8212; which would impact the security of all members of NATO &#8212; also our neighbors who are part of NATO &#8212; members of NATO. <br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>Another question? <br> <br>POLISH AIDE:  Maja Wójcikowska, TVN24.<br> <br>Q    Madam Vice President, each day we can see death and unimaginable suffering of the Ukraine people caused by decisions made by Vladimir Putin.  My question is: Will the U.S. support an international investigation into war crimes committed by Russia in Ukraine?  And can you see any political future for Putin? <br> <br>(As interpreted.)  This is also the question to the Polish President. <br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Okay, I’ll go. <br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (Points to himself.)<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  You go this time, please.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>Q    (Inaudible) I will start with Madam Vice President.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  (Laughs.)  Okay.<br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (Points to Vice President Harris.) <br> <br>Q    Thank you.  I appreciate that.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Not at all.  I &#8212; we are very clear: The NATO Alliance is stronger and Russia is weaker because of what Putin has done.  That is very clear to us. <br> <br>And when it comes to crimes and violations of international norms and rules, we are also very clear that any intentional attack on innocent civilians is a violation.  The U.N. has set up a process by which there will be a review and investigations, and we will of course participate as appropriate and necessary. <br> <br>But we all watched the television coverage of just yesterday.  That&#8217;s on top of everything else that we know and don&#8217;t know yet, based on what we&#8217;ve just been able to see.  And because we&#8217;ve seen it or not doesn&#8217;t mean it hasn&#8217;t happened.<br> <br>But just limited to what we have seen: Pregnant women going for healthcare being injured by &#8212; I don’t know &#8212; a missile, a bomb in an unprovoked, unjustified war, where a powerful country is trying to take over another country &#8212; violate its sovereignty, its territorial integrity, for the sake of what?  Nothing that is justified or provoked.  Absolutely there should be an investigation, and we should all be watching.  And I have no question the eyes of the world are on this war and what Russia has done in terms of this aggression and these atrocities.  I have no doubt. <br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  It is obvious to us that in Ukraine, Russians are committing war crimes.  I hope that also in the future it will be obvious for a court investigating those issues who bears responsibility for that.<br> <br>Now, please remember that the refugees from Ukraine are coming to us right now.  And right now, as we speak, there are people crossing our border who witnessed their houses destroyed, who saw their neighbors being killed, who saw hospitals being bombed, who saw civilians being shot at, children being shot at.  These are proofs.  These are the reports of witnesses, and they also have those proofs on their smartphones.  If you look at those footages, it just makes your blood curl.  Such scenes are happening today, and they have been happening over the last days in Ukraine, and their perpetrators are Russians. <br> <br>A group of prosecutors has come to us delegated by the court to look at the facts of this case.  They are collecting evidence.  We, as Poland, try as much as we can to give them best &#8212; the best possible conditions for work and then to fulfill this very difficult task. <br> <br>Let us remember, the witnesses are here.  There is a lot of evidence &#8212; the footages as I mentioned.  We have those proofs and the evidence.  All of that is being collected.  The work is ongoing.  And I do believe that it is going to result in very serious indictment acts. <br> <br>And I do believe that the war crimes &#8212; criminals will be sentenced &#8212; those responsible for the war that is happening in Ukraine right now as a result of this (inaudible) Russian assault.<br> <br>WHITE HOUSE AIDE:  And the final question will be from Asma Khalid of NPR.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.  Thank you, Madam Vice President.  I wanted to ask you about some reporting that my colleague here in Poland noticed.  He recently spoke with the mayor of the largest border town, who told him that the refugee system is essentially not set up for this, that it will collapse.  It&#8217;s an improvised system that can work for maybe two weeks, but not indefinitely.  And I&#8217;m wondering what the United States is going to do more specifically to set up a permanent infrastructure.  And relatedly, is the United States willing to make a specific allocation for Ukrainian refugees? <br> <br>And for President Duda, I wanted to know if you think and if you asked the United States to specifically accept more refugees.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Okay.  (Laughs.)  A friend in need is a friend indeed.  (Laughter.) <br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  Okay.  I’ll go first.  Okay, so this time &#8212; (as interpreted) &#8212; Madam, the situation is very complex.  This is what I was saying today and I discussed this at length with Madam Vice President Kamala Harris.  I said, in a very blunt way, that today we are seeing a refugee crisis.  It is unfolding because Poland is still able to receive &#8212; it is all the time able to find the accommodation for those people who are coming to us all the time. <br> <br>But we have got almost 1,500,000 people who have come to us over the last couple of days.  So it&#8217;s been 10 days.  We have received more than 1 million people within 10 days.  Never before have we witnessed such a situation.  So this is something totally new to us, and we are grappling with this huge challenge.  Our entire society is facing up to this challenge.  I have already expressed my gratitude to the Polish people for their wonderful position in this very difficult situation &#8212; that they are so openhearted. <br> <br>But we are aware that the problem is growing and that this problem is increasing.  We have to somehow handle it, and we do not have the experience.  Therefore, yesterday, I had a long conversation with Mr. António Guterres, Secretary General of the United Nations organization.  And I flagged out that problem to him.  I described to him the situation &#8212; how it looks, how it develops.  I described to him the reaction of the Polish society, of the Polish authorities, how we have been handling with this problem.  But I told him that unless we receive international assistance, then, given further influx of refugees to Poland on this scale, this will end up in a refugee disaster.  And I asked for help &#8212; both the material assistance, financial assistance &#8212; so that we are able to solve this in Poland. <br> <br>I also asked for expertise, for the know-how, because the U.N. has got experts who have seen a multitude crisis of this dimension, and I&#8217;m sure that they have worked out methods of how to handle it.  And I&#8217;m sure they know how to solve the problems, which ensue due to such a crisis situation. <br> <br>And this is something that I described in detail also today to Madam Vice President.  I said that the assistance of the United States in this respect is invaluable to us, and we would be very much grateful if we could use this assistance as soon as possible. <br> <br>Furthermore, we discussed the refugees from Ukraine who have got relatives and families in the United States, and who would be willing &#8212; at least for the time when the war is still waging, they would like to visit those families, to stay with their families in the United States, and to wait there until the war is over and then come back to their homes.<br> <br>I asked to speed up and simplify the procedures for such people &#8212; the consular procedures to be simplified for those people who would like to leave for the United States, to give the opportunity to these people to see their families as soon as possible, to be reunited with their families, to help them to survive this time. <br> <br>So we are acting, and we are looking for international support because, indeed, the vast majority of Ukrainian refugees are coming to our country.  Frankly speaking, that is because, first of all, we are a big country.  And also, the material status of an ordinary citizen of Poland is for sure much better than the material status, the living conditions of an ordinary Ukrainian citizen, although we are not among those wealthy countries of Western Europe, but our living standards have increased over the last couple of years in Poland. <br> <br>But they are coming because I believe that also the &#8212; it is their belief that thanks to the presence of NATO armed forces, thanks to the presence of our Allies from NATO &#8212; from Canada, from the UK, from Romania, and from other countries whose soldiers are deployed in Poland &#8212; they believe that Poland, due to that presence, is a safe country, a country which is not going to be attacked, a country where you can safely wait out this difficult situation.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  As the President said, we did discuss this issue.  And I started by thanking the President in Poland and the people of Poland for what they have done.  And I will restate what I said earlier this afternoon: They&#8217;ve shown extraordinary generosity and kindness and courage.  And they have &#8212; there have been some here who have relatives who have arrived from Ukraine, but I think there are many more who are taking in perfect strangers with barely a lot to give but giving a lot nonetheless. <br> <br>So, we recognize that, and we recognize the burden that it places on the government of Poland, on the president, and the infrastructure of this country; when you look at &#8212; as the President said, over one and a half million people coming within two weeks, virtually.  Unprecedented if you track and look at refugee flows over the history of time from regions of conflict.<br> <br>So the United States is absolutely prepared to do what we can and what we must to support Poland in terms of the burden that they have taken on that I think all of us who understand the moral obligation we should feel to help people who are fleeing harm and seeking refuge; the burden we should all be prepared to take on to support those people who are fleeing their home when they don&#8217;t want to leave.<br> <br>In terms of what we are doing in the United States, we will then take this in terms of what we can do to support and look at those Ukrainians who want to come to the United States.  What we&#8217;re seeing thus far is large parts of that population who are fleeing Ukraine, who desire to stay in Europe. <br> <br>You probably know that we have made a decision as it relates to TPS &#8212; the Temporary Protected Status.  So for Ukrainians that are in the United States whose visa may expire or has expired: If they were in the United States before &#8212; I believe it&#8217;s March; I don&#8217;t have the exact date &#8212; they will be able to stay; they won&#8217;t be required to leave, even though their visa has expired because, of course, we would not send them back to what is a warzone. <br> <br>And the bottom line is that I have stated the position to the President this afternoon.  As we have said many times through our work collectively in the U.N., through NATO, we will support Poland in terms of the burden it is facing and our collective responsibility to ensure the safety and wellbeing of these refugees.<br> <br>POLISH AIDE:  (As interpreted.)  This concludes our press conference.  Thank you very much for your participation, ladies and gentlemen. <br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Thank you.<br> <br>END                 1:43 P.M. CET<br> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Consumer Price Index in&#160;February</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/statement-by-president-biden-on-consumer-price-index-in-february/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 15:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s economic data tells the tale of two recoveries. Our jobs recovery remains strong.&#160; New unemployment claims remain low, as jobs are created at a record level.&#160;The rate of people on unemployment insurance is the lowest since 1970 – more than 50 years.&#160; &#160;And, private sector job growth is strong, boosted by the steps we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s economic data tells the tale of two recoveries.</p>



<p>Our jobs recovery remains strong.&nbsp; New unemployment claims remain low, as jobs are created at a record level.&nbsp;The rate of people on unemployment insurance is the lowest since 1970 – more than 50 years.&nbsp; &nbsp;And, private sector job growth is strong, boosted by the steps we took in the American Rescue Plan a year ago this week.</p>



<p>At the same time, today’s inflation report is a reminder that Americans‘ budgets are being stretched by price increases and families are starting to feel the impacts of Putin’s price hike.&nbsp;A large contributor to inflation this month was an increase in gas and energy prices as markets reacted to Putin’s aggressive actions.&nbsp; As I have said from the start, there will be costs at home as we impose crippling sanctions in response to Putin’s unprovoked war, but Americans can know this:&nbsp; the costs we are imposing on Putin and his cronies are far more devastating than the costs we are facing.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that higher prices impact a family’s budget, which is why I am fighting to bring down the everyday prices that are squeezing Americans. Last week, in coordination with our allies, the U.S. secured a release of 60 million barrels of oil from our strategic reserves. My Administration is pushing for investments so we can manufacture more in America, strengthen our supply chains, and move goods to market at lower cost. I’m promoting competition to make sure big corporations are offering consumers fair prices, and I’m pressing Congress to pass my plan to lower the cost of essentials like prescription drugs and energy.</p>



<p>Finally, I want to be clear:  we can do all this, and reduce the huge federal budget deficit that I inherited from my predecessor.  Earlier this week, we learned that after reducing the deficit last year &#8212; for the first time since 2015 – CBO reported that we are on track to cut the deficit this year by over $1 trillion – the largest one year reduction in the deficit in US history. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>During Week of Anniversary of American Rescue Plan, Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Highlights Health Insurance Subsidies That Promoted Critical Increases in Enrollment and Cost&#160;Savings</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/during-week-of-anniversary-of-american-rescue-plan-biden-harris-administration-highlights-health-insurance-subsidies-that-promoted-critical-increases-in-enrollment-and-cost-savings/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The American Rescue Plan (ARP) made essential investments to expand health care coverage and reduce costs for millions of Americans.&#160; The COVID-19 pandemic laid bare critical shortcomings in our health care and health insurance systems, and the ARP shored up vital gaps by providing more affordable coverage to millions of American, including many who lost&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><strong><u>The American Rescue Plan (ARP) made essential investments to expand health care coverage and reduce costs for millions of Americans.</u></strong>&nbsp; The COVID-19 pandemic laid bare critical shortcomings in our health care and health insurance systems, and the ARP shored up vital gaps by providing more affordable coverage to millions of American, including many who lost their jobs over the last two years. &nbsp;Today, the Biden Administration is announcing a state-by-state breakdown of health insurance enrollment changes during this year’s Open Enrollment Period (OEP).&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Total Enrollment in this year’s OEP was 14.5 million:</u></strong> During the 2022 OEP,14.5 million Americans enrolled in a Marketplace plan through HealthCare.Gov or a State-Based Marketplace. <strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Coverage increased by 21% due to the American Rescue Plan:</u></strong> The increase to 14.5 million people represented a 21% increase over 2021 due to the expansions of cost-saving subsidies in the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p><strong><u>Americans saved $800 per person last year, and thousands per family because of American Rescue Plan affordability measures.</u></strong> As a result of the American Rescue Plan (ARP), families were able to keep more money in their pockets, with actual savings of $67 per month per person in premiums – that’s more than $800 each year per person for groceries, child care, or other essentials. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>5.8 million <em>new</em> consumers enrolled during the 2021 Special Enrollment and Open Enrollment periods</u></strong>, according to data from HHS. Between 2016 and 2019, 3.6 million Americans lost coverage.</p>



<p><strong>The ARP reduced the cost of health care coverage by:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring that consumers eligible for financial assistance through premium tax credits had at least a couple plans to choose from </strong>that won’t cost more than 8.5% of their household income on their Marketplace plan premium per year.</li><li><strong>Expanding the number of people eligible to save money on health care coverage</strong> by temporarily expanding eligibility for premium tax credits for those previously excluded from financial assistance.</li><li><strong>Increasing affordability for low- and middle-income Americans</strong> by increasing the size of tax credits.</li><li><strong>Addressing racial health inequities by expanding coverage and reducing costs.&nbsp; </strong>Increased affordability and health insurance coverage expansion allowed historically uninsured communities – especially those who have faced significant health disparities – to access coverage, thereby improving opportunities for health care during and beyond the COVID-19 pandemic.</li></ul>



<p>Factsheet by State/Territory:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-AL.pdf">Alabama</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-AK.pdf">Alaska</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-AZ.pdf">Arizona</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-AR.pdf">Arkansas</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-CA.pdf">California</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-CO.pdf">Colorado</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-CT.pdf">Connecticut</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-DE.pdf">Delaware</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-FL.pdf">Florida</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-GA.pdf">Georgia</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-HI.pdf">Hawaii</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-ID.pdf">Idaho</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-IL.pdf">Illinois</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-IN.pdf">Indiana</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-IA.pdf">Iowa</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-KS.pdf">Kansas</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-KY.pdf">Kentucky</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-LA.pdf">Louisiana</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-ME.pdf">Maine</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-MD.pdf">Maryland</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-MA.pdf">Massachusetts</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-MI.pdf">Michigan</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-MN.pdf">Minnesota</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-MS.pdf">Mississippi</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-MO.pdf">Missouri</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-MT.pdf">Montana</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-NE.pdf">Nebraska</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-NV.pdf">Nevada</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-NH.pdf">New Hampshire</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-NJ.pdf">New Jersey</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-NM.pdf">New Mexico</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-NY.pdf">New York</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-NC.pdf">North Carolina</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-ND.pdf">North Dakota</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-OH.pdf">Ohio</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-OK.pdf">Oklahoma</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-OR.pdf">Oregon</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-PA.pdf">Pennsylvania</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-RI.pdf">Rhode Island</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-SC.pdf">South Carolina</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-SD.pdf">South Dakota</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-TN.pdf">Tennessee</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-TX.pdf">Texas</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-UT.pdf">Utah</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-VT.pdf">Vermont</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-VA.pdf">Virginia</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-WA.pdf">Washington</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-WV.pdf">West Virginia</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-WI.pdf">Wisconsin</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-WY.pdf">Wyoming</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/American-Rescue-Plan-State-by-State-ACA-DC.pdf">District of Columbia</a><br>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris Announces Additional U.S. Funding to Respond to Humanitarian Needs in Ukraine and Eastern&#160;Europe</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-additional-u-s-funding-to-respond-to-humanitarian-needs-in-ukraine-and-eastern-europe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 13:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48762</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During her trip to Warsaw, Poland, today, U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris announced nearly $53 million in&#160;new&#160;humanitarian assistance from the United States government, through the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), to support&#160;innocent civilians&#160;affected by Russia’s unjustified invasion of Ukraine. This additional assistance includes support to the UN World Food Program (WFP) to provide lifesaving&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>During her trip to Warsaw, Poland, today, U.S. Vice President Kamala Harris announced nearly $53 million in&nbsp;new&nbsp;humanitarian assistance from the United States government, through the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), to support&nbsp;innocent civilians&nbsp;affected by Russia’s unjustified invasion of Ukraine. This additional assistance includes support to the UN World Food Program (WFP) to provide lifesaving emergency food assistance to meet immediate needs&nbsp;of&nbsp;hundreds of thousands affected by the invasion, including people who are displaced from their homes and who are crossing the border out of Ukraine. In addition, it will support WFP’s logistics operations to move assistance into Ukraine, including to people in Kyiv.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This assistance builds on the United States’ announcement less than two weeks ago of nearly $54 million in humanitarian assistance to provide critically needed health supplies, food assistance, high thermal blankets, and other relief.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States is the&nbsp;largest&nbsp;provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and has provided $159 million in overall humanitarian assistance to Ukraine&nbsp;since October 2020, including&nbsp;nearly $107 million in&nbsp;the past two weeks in&nbsp;response to Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. This includes food, safe drinking water, shelter, emergency health care, and winterization services to communities affected by ongoing fighting. To date, two million people have been forced to flee Ukraine due to the conflict, and an estimated one million are displaced inside Ukraine. &nbsp;At least 12 million people are in need of humanitarian aid across Ukraine.&nbsp;The United States continues to stand with the people of Ukraine and will continue to work to meet immediate needs and save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and Prime Minister Morawiecki of Poland Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/10/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-prime-minister-morawiecki-of-poland-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 12:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48760</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PRIME MINISTER MORAWIECKI:&#160; Madam Vice President, it’s so good to welcome you in Poland.&#160; Well, lacking those specific circumstances, I’m so happy that we have such a strong alliance with the United States.&#160; It’s very important to strengthen the eastern flank, in particular right now, with what is happening in the Ukraine.&#160; And we have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>PRIME MINISTER MORAWIECKI:&nbsp; Madam Vice President, it’s so good to welcome you in Poland.&nbsp; Well, lacking those specific circumstances, I’m so happy that we have such a strong alliance with the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s very important to strengthen the eastern flank, in particular right now, with what is happening in the Ukraine.&nbsp; And we have to dedicate quality time to discuss what &#8212; how to help Ukrainians to maintain their sovereignty and territorial integrity and their freedom, because they&#8217;re fighting for our freedom &#8212; for the freedom of the whole of Europe.<br><br>Thank you also for your brave decision about, you know, being independent of the Russian oil and gas, because this is the &#8212; this is their money for the war machine, so to say, in the first place.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you so much for being with us in Poland.&nbsp;<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Prime Minister, for this warm welcome.&nbsp; I wish it were under other circumstances.&nbsp; And I am here &#8212; standing here on the eastern flank of NATO to reaffirm our commitment, the United States commitment to Poland and our NATO Allies.&nbsp; And there is no question that we stand united as it relates to many issues and the particular issue of Ukraine &#8212;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER MORAWIECKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; &#8212; and what we are prepared to do to defend all of the principles that are integral to us as NATO countries, in terms of fighting for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of, in this case, Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>I appreciate the conversation that you and I had by telephone &#8212;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER MORAWIECKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; &#8212; just last week, where we discussed a number of issues that includes the extraordinary work that your leadership, the people of Poland have been doing &#8212;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER MORAWIECKI:&nbsp; The people of Poland, yes.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER MORAWIECKI:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; &#8212; to invite, with such courage and such generosity, the refugees who have fled Ukraine.&nbsp; I have been watching and reading about the work of ordinary people doing extraordinary things in this time of great difficulty.&nbsp; And so, I bring you thanks from the American people to the Polish people for what you all have been doing.<br><br>We will discuss many issues today, and it will include the ongoing commitment that the United States has to support of this region, including the people of Ukraine.&nbsp; That ranges from security assistance, to humanitarian assistance, to all the other work that must be done to ensure that Russia also pays a serious and severe consequence.<br><br>As we have said from the beginning, if Russia were to take aggressive action, there would be consequence.&nbsp; And those consequences, I believe, have been evident but are a result of the work that we have been doing together as a unified force.&nbsp;<br><br>So I thank you, and I look forward to our discussion.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER MORAWIECKI:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; And also, in particular, thank you for the unity of the Western world, because this is what surprised Mr. Putin, I’m sure.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Yes, it did.&nbsp; Yes, it did.&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER MORAWIECKI:&nbsp; That’s important.&nbsp;<br><br>END<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Joseph R. Biden, Jr.’s Call with President-Elect Yoon Suk-yeol of the Republic of&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/readout-of-joseph-r-biden-jr-s-call-with-president-elect-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 02:34:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol of the Republic of Korea (ROK) to congratulate him on his election. Together, they affirmed the strength of the U.S.-ROK alliance, which is the linchpin for peace, security and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific. President Biden emphasized the United States’ commitment to the defense of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President-elect Yoon Suk-yeol of the Republic of Korea (ROK) to congratulate him on his election. Together, they affirmed the strength of the U.S.-ROK alliance, which is the linchpin for peace, security and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific. President Biden emphasized the United States’ commitment to the defense of the ROK and that he looks forward to working together to deepen cooperation on key global challenges, including climate change, the COVID-19 pandemic, and supply chains. The two also committed to maintain close coordination on addressing the threats posed by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s nuclear and missile programs.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in Roundtable With CEOs and Governors in Support of the Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/09/remarks-by-president-biden-in-roundtable-with-ceos-and-governors-in-support-of-the-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 22:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 2:05 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:  All right.  Well, thanks, everybody, for being here.  And for my colleagues that are on the screen, thank you for being here. I’m pleased to be joined by &#8212; by a group of very distinguished people, and particularly by the governor from Indiana, Eric Holcomb; and my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>2:05 P.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  All right.  Well, thanks, everybody, for being here.  And for my colleagues that are on the screen, thank you for being here.<br><br>I’m pleased to be joined by &#8212; by a group of very distinguished people, and particularly by the governor from Indiana, Eric Holcomb; and my good friend, Gretchen Whitmer, from the state of Michigan; and some of America’s world leaders and most important manufacturers in the world and &#8212; Cummins, Hewlett-Packard, Meda- &#8212; Medtronic, Micron, Samsung, Whirlpool.</p>



<p>And just last week, in my State of the Union message, I said that we’re seeing the revitalization of American manufacturing, especially in the Industrial Midwest.</p>



<p>Our economy created <s>432,000</s> [423,000] new manufacturing jobs in America since we took office.  And today, companies are choosing to build new factories here &#8212; here in the United States, when just a few years ago, they would have built them overseas.</p>



<p>What I also said is that companies are ready to do more &#8212; a lot more if Congress passes the Bipartisan Innovation Act.&nbsp; And that’s why we’re here to today to talk about the bipartisan act.</p>



<p>And we have the President and CEO of Micron with us.&nbsp; Sanjay, thanks for being here.&nbsp; Micron is looking to making a multibillion-dollar semiconductor investment here in America if &#8212; if this bill gets passed.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Dr. Choi, the CEO of Samsung, is also on the screen.&nbsp; Thank you for being here.&nbsp; Samsung has committed $17 billion &#8212; its largest-ever U.S. investment &#8212; to build a semiconductor facility in Texas, which I understand is going to create 2,000 good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>Other CEOs that are here are making their own investments in America.&nbsp; But they need Congress to pass the bipartisan innovation bill.</p>



<p>And one of the reasons &#8212; one of the reasons we need to do that is because there is perhaps no production more important than reclaiming America’s leadership and owning our future than semiconductors.</p>



<p>You know, these semiconductors that are the size of a fingertip, power about every day &#8212; almost everything in our everyday life &#8212; smartphones, the Internet, appliances, technologies we haven’t invented yet.</p>



<p>And our nation &#8212; and the semiconductor was invented here in the United States of America.&nbsp; And over 30 years ago, America had 40 percent of the global production of semiconductors.</p>



<p>But since then, something happened.&nbsp; American manufacturing &#8212; the backbone of our economy &#8212; got hollowed out.&nbsp; Companies moved jobs and production overseas, especially from the industrial Midwest.</p>



<p>As a result, today, we barely produce 10 percent of these computer chips, despite being a leader on chip design and research.</p>



<p>This puts us at the mercy of shortages and supply chain bottlenecks.&nbsp; But we have an opportunity &#8212; we have an opportunity to reclaim the position of leadership.</p>



<p>I think it’s a bipartisan consensus.&nbsp; There’s an inno- &#8212; there’s an innovation bill that &#8212; this innovation bill has bipartisan support in both House and Senate now.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It includes billions of dollars for new incentives to produce semiconductors here in America.</p>



<p>And the bill is not just about funding semiconductors; it includes an office at the Department of Commerce that will be tasked with monitoring and strengthening critical supply chains.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And it &#8212; and it expands programs that help manufacturers across the country benefit from our investments, particularly small manufacturers.</p>



<p>It invests in R&amp;D the way we need to so we can invent and make the technologies of the future and in industries like biotechnology, artificial intelligence, telecommunications, and others we can barely imagine today and which we’re going to build a foundation for future jobs and prosperity not just here but around the world.</p>



<p>So today, I’m urging the House and Senate to work out the differences between their ver- &#8212; two versions of this bill and get it to my desk as quickly as you can.</p>



<p>Passing this bill will do four important things:</p>



<p>First, it will send a message to the world that America is back in the game, open for investment, commitment to creating clean energy economy and competing to win in the 21st century.</p>



<p>Second, we’re going to create jobs: good paying, cutting-edge jobs; manufacturing jobs &#8212; many that don’t require a four-year college degree.</p>



<p>Third, making it in America is one of the ways we can address our cost and supply chain challenges.&nbsp; When we build a pr- &#8212; when we build products we need, we don’t have to wait.&nbsp; And we reduce ship- &#8212; shipping costs.&nbsp; And we can get goods moving faster.</p>



<p>And fourthly, we have &#8212; it will be a &#8212; it will mean that we aren’t overly reliant on other countries from risks like wars and pandemics.&nbsp; And I saw it during the pandemic that when we needed it the most, we were in short supply of masks, gowns, gloves, ventilators, and other essential equipment.</p>



<p>We should never be in that position again.&nbsp; And the bottom line is this Bipartisan innovation bill will allow us to stamp more products “Made in America”.&nbsp; And it’s going to bolster our national security and our economic security.</p>



<p>It matters, so let’s get it done.</p>



<p>And now, it’s my honor to turn this over to the governors, and then we’re going to hear from the CEOs.&nbsp; And so, Governors, I’m sure they agree with the Ohio Senator Sherrod Brown, who said, “It’s time to bury the label ‘Rust Belt.’”&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Like, the Industrial Midwest today, you see something special is happening.</p>



<p>Let me start with you, Governor –- Governor Holcomb from Indiana.<br><br>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; And, Madam Secretary, great to be back with you again.&nbsp; I would just echo or underscore the point that &#8212; points that you’ve made.&nbsp; And certainly, the Midwest is no longer the Rust Belt; it is a shining buckle on that belt.&nbsp; And we are just open for business but able to do more.<br><br>This innovation bill &#8212; ultimate bill that comes together is a key part of our futures.&nbsp; It’s a key part of a Midwestern microelectronics corridor, if you will, that has everything to do with economic development and national security.<br><br>For a state like Indiana &#8212; and you could probably say this about a lot of Midwestern states &#8212; but we’re heavy intensive in manufacturing &#8212; number one per capita for a state like Indiana.&nbsp; Five auto OEMs, medical devices, the list just goes on and on and on.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I would &#8212; I would just say that it’s two things.&nbsp; One, it’s been said that speed kills, and in this sense, slow speed kills.&nbsp;&nbsp;We need to get this done.&nbsp; We need to get it on your desk.&nbsp; We need to get it signed so that we cannot just catch up with the competition but lead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know a little something about this in Indiana.&nbsp; We got the Indy 500, and we like to go fast.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible) going fast.&nbsp; A gallon of gas is down 14 percent today.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So I want to make sure they go fast.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And I didn’t mean to interrupt you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; No, so, you know, it&#8217;s speed.&nbsp; We got to get there, and we got to get there yesterday.&nbsp; And then also partnerships.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for us in the Midwest, we have those talent pipelines, Madam Secretary, that we&#8217;ve spent a lot of time talking about: Purdue University, one of the largest engineering schools in the country &#8212; top ranked; Rose-Hulman, number-one undergraduate engineering school.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve got a community college system that is built &#8212; the structure in place &#8212; as well as Naval Surface Warfare Center Crane, with the DOD &#8212; and all the research that goes into it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those &#8212; the federal, the private sector, and the state governments that come together &#8212; those partnerships are in place right now so that we can get it to your desk and get on with business.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll do anything to help if you get me to be able to drive a lead car in the Indy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; Write that down.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not kidding.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; Oh, we know you&#8217;re not kidding.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen you drive a lot of cars in Michigan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; Oh, God, I tell you what &#8212;</p>



<p>GOVERNOR HOLCOMB:&nbsp; I think the Secretary is driving the pace car, by the way.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:  Yeah, I know.  I &#8212; I don&#8217;t know, man.  I&#8217;m ready.  Anyway. Gov.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; Yeah, well I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m really glad to be sitting here next to Eric because, in the Midwest, you know, we are proud of what we do.&nbsp; We work hard.&nbsp; We solve problems.&nbsp; We’re not afraid of digging in.&nbsp; And this &#8212; I think this act that we&#8217;re talking about is a huge opportunity for our nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, in places like Michigan, this is about creating good-paying jobs.&nbsp; This is about lowering costs for families.&nbsp; This is about our national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know my fellow governors on both sides of the aisle support getting this to your desk so that you can sign it and make a reality.&nbsp; You know, right now, thousands of jobs up and down the auto supply chain are at risk because we&#8217;re not making chips; we don&#8217;t have access.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I also know &#8212; my friend from Whirlpool here, also from Michigan, is going to remind me it&#8217;s not just the auto industry &#8212; right? &#8212; it&#8217;s appliances as well.&nbsp; It is the smartphones, as you said, Mr. President.</p>



<p>You know, chip shortages have impacted more than 575,000 American jobs.&nbsp; And in 2021 alone, automakers in North America lost production of an estimated 2.2 million vehicles, equaling 3,000 days of work.&nbsp; So, these shortages are driving up costs, they&#8217;re jeopardizing families.&nbsp;&nbsp; And increasing this manufacturing here at home will reduce supply chain delays in transportation, as well as lowering the cost of consumer electronics, et cetera, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we also saw during the pandemic that American manufacturing is crucial to our national security.&nbsp; And when the whole world comes to a halt because swabs are manufactured in Italy or N95 masks are manufactured in China, it is a national security issue.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, doing this important advanced manufacturing where we can stamp it “Made in America” and preferably “Made in Michigan” is a good thing for our whole nation.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s why I think it&#8217;s so important that both sides of the aisle &#8212; we are here, we are eager to throw our support behind getting this bill to your desk, and recognize that critical importance to the people of our states and our nation.</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m excited to be here and eager to jump in wherever we can be helpful.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;re old friends.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard me say many times &#8212; you know, that was something my dear mother, God bless her soul, used to say: “Out of everything bad, something good will happen if you look hard enough for it.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think we&#8217;re in a position now &#8212; we&#8217;re in a real inflection point in history &#8212; not just America, but across the world.&nbsp; There are going to be changes that are going to &#8212; whether &#8212; no matter who&#8217;s in charge, they&#8217;re going to create fundamental &#8212; fundamental change is taking place geographically, politically, economically, technologically.</p>



<p>And, you know, one third of the inflation last year was because of the cost of automobiles, and it was one reason: didn&#8217;t have the computer chips.&nbsp; Rising prices were &#8212; you know, that&#8217;s one third of the inflation.&nbsp; And so, we can solve a lot of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to, with her permission &#8212; Liz, I&#8217;d like to go to you a little bit, speaking of Whirlpool.</p>



<p>And you announced an $80 million investment in a manufacturing plant in Ohio and Oklahoma last year, which are going to create about 250 jobs, if I&#8217;m not mistaken.</p>



<p>My question is that &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; why is domestic production of semiconductors important to Whirlpool?&nbsp; And how will this bipartisan initiative, if it passes it and gets to my desk &#8212; how that&#8217;s going to affect you?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think I know the answer, but I think it&#8217;s important for it to be heard from you.&nbsp; No, I really mean it.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s important.</p>



<p>Look, the one thing we&#8217;ve had as we brought in CEOs and VPs and others the last, I don&#8217;t know, a couple months, right here in this fora, is people go, &#8220;Whoa, this is real,&#8221; when they hear from the companies what they want to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I&#8217;d love to &#8212; you to tell me a little bit about how you see it moving, if you would.</p>



<p>MS. DOOR:&nbsp; Well, first of all, thank you, Mr. President, for inviting Whirlpool Corporation to sit here today at this table with all these leaders.&nbsp; We&#8217;re very, very grateful to be able to be here today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would say is that the $80 million investment in Ohio and Oklahoma, as you said &#8212; you know, that is us supporting the United States.&nbsp; Additionally, we have made an investment, $60 million commitment, in Michigan in our R&amp;D Center.&nbsp; So this is demonstrative of our commitment to the United States.</p>



<p>We have nine factories in the U.S.&nbsp; We sell &#8212; 80 percent of the products that we sell in the U.S. are produced in the U.S.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s definitely a commitment here to the United States.</p>



<p>We have been challenged with the supply chain &#8212; you know, not being able to deliver appliances to each of the consumers in the U.S. every day due to the semiconductor issues.</p>



<p>We see the semiconductors as an essential component to our appliances.&nbsp; They&#8217;re found in almost every one of our appliances, and they&#8217;re absolutely critical because they deliver the technology that delights our consumers, whether it&#8217;s cleaning your laundry or your dishes, or cooking in the home, or using it to store your food and medicine during these very challenging times.</p>



<p>So, semiconductors are absolutely essential for us.&nbsp; And certainly, if we had all the semiconductors, as Governor Whitmer said, we&#8217;d be able to deliver the appliances to all of our customers, which we have been challenged to do so.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are absolutely committed to deliver to our consumers every day.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Do you think your customers and/or even maybe some of your employees who have been around a long time really appreciated how critical a semiconductor was for them to make the products and move?</p>



<p>MS. DOOR:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; I think everyone inside our company &#8212; and I even think if you ask consumers &#8212; and world leaders are very, very familiar now with semiconductors and how critical they are to technology, research and development, upskilling the workforce, and STEM education.&nbsp; So, absolutely.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s interesting.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s been a &#8212; unfortunately, a &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s been a reality that the American public realizing that a semiconductor mattered a great deal whether or not your washing machine functioned, or whether your cellphone functioned, or whether your automobile functioned.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s not that &#8212; I think we &#8212; they just took an awful lot for granted; we all did &#8212; that this was, &#8220;We can do this.&nbsp; It’s not a problem.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the irony of &#8212; I keep reminding everybody of the irony is: We actually invented the semiconductor; we headed to the Moon.&nbsp; So, we also &#8212; I have no parenthetic.&nbsp; We got to be &#8212; start investing a hell of a lot more money in research and development &#8212; pure research and development.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We used to do about 2 percent of our GDP; now we&#8217;re down by 1 percent.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; anyway, but I don&#8217;t want to get off on that and get you going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also like Madam President, Jennifer, I &#8212; you &#8212; at Cummins, you make some pretty big engines.&nbsp; You manufacture &#8212; and &#8212; now &#8212; but now you&#8217;re making battery electric alternative fuel engines, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. RUMSEY:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And so, how has the ship [sic] shortage affected &#8212; chip shortage affected your company and your customers?&nbsp; And as we move toward this energy future, how can this Innovation Act &#8212; and it&#8217;s a shame &#8212; you have to know all about this legislation; I mean, you&#8217;re running the company &#8212; but how can this act help companies like yours remain globally competitive, not just here at home?</p>



<p>MS. RUMSEY:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, first, Mr. President, thank you so much for the opportunity to speak today and talk about Cummins&#8217;s support of both the domestic innovation focus of this legislation as well as funding semiconductor manufacturing.</p>



<p>Cummins is a 100-year-old company headquartered in Columbus, Indiana.&nbsp; We employ 25,000 employees in the United States.&nbsp; And our employees are really focused on driving innovation and producing power solutions, engines, and also, as you said, fuel cell and battery-electric power solutions for commercial and industrial equipment.&nbsp; And those applications serve some of the world&#8217;s most demanding and economically vital applications.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I spent time, prior to my current role, as chief technical officer, so I saw firsthand the need for innovation &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.) (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. RUMSEY:&nbsp; &#8212; yeah, really &#8212; the need for innovation, and the power of government and private sectors coming together to focus on innovation.</p>



<p>Cummins worked closely for a number of years with the Department of Energy &#8212; a 21st Century Truck Program.&nbsp; And in that program, we were able to advance technology and improve fuel efficiency in trucks by 50 percent &#8212; a 50 percent reduction in&nbsp;<a>CO2</a>.&nbsp; And much of that work has now made its way into trucks that are on the road today and are benefiting society.</p>



<p>And I think there&#8217;s never been a more important time than now to continue to focus on domestic innovation when you consider the environmental and the technical challenges that we face as a society.</p>



<p>So, I think it&#8217;s critically important that we can come together.&nbsp; Our industry and other industries are transforming how we will compete as we tackle these challenges &#8212; like, climate change is changing.</p>



<p>And so, I think coming together in a bipartisan way to talk about how we drive and fuel innovation in America is critical to keep us at the leading edge with these advanced technologies and new solutions and bring high-tech and manufacturing jobs to the United States and the future.&nbsp; So, I think it&#8217;s critically important.</p>



<p>In my operational role, I&#8217;ve been spending a lot of time on this semiconductor issue, and it has been a real issue for us for the last 18 months.&nbsp; Our products do not run, in most cases, without semiconductors.&nbsp; They&#8217;re critical for emissions and safety-control systems.&nbsp; And increasingly, we&#8217;re utilizing them as our technology advances.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have not been able to get enough.&nbsp; It has impacted our ability to build and deliver product to our customers.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an issue we continue to deal with today.</p>



<p>So we strongly support the CHIPS Act, really focusing on bringing domestic production of semiconductors here, including some for our industry &#8212; which, by the way, are different than what we use in our cellphone.&nbsp; You know, because of the durability and harsh environment our products operate in, we have specific chips that are critical to continue to invest and fund here in the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we look forward to being a part of the conversation as we move this important work forward.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, you know, the point you&#8217;ve all made is that as everything changes, there&#8217;s a fundamental shift to the reality that we can&#8217;t &#8212; we can&#8217;t keep the combustion engine the way it has been.&nbsp; It&#8217;s even &#8212; you see what&#8217;s happening in locomotives now.&nbsp; You know?&nbsp; And you see what&#8217;s happening just across the board.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; and I think it presents an enormous opportunity &#8212; enormous opportunity to improve the health of the public overall, number one, because we&#8217;re moving in the direction, and we don&#8217;t need to propel most of what we have in the future by &#8212; with regard to oil products or &#8212;</p>



<p>And, you know, I was really pleased to &#8212; and Gina &#8212; or Gretchen and I talked about this a lot.&nbsp; When we met with the CEOs of the automobile companies, particularly Mary Barra &#8212; and she had sued the state of California for having a higher mileage standard than the national standard.&nbsp; And we had a long talk.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not taking credit for her changing her mind, but she ended up calling me and saying that, “We&#8217;re going to go &#8212; we dropped the suit, and we&#8217;re going to go all electric.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll get to halfway there within the next…” &#8212; and then she said a date.&nbsp; And then Ford jumped on and everybody else.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a &#8212; because it is the future.</p>



<p>And it also creates, really, a hell of a lot of jobs too &#8212; good-paying jobs &#8212; and increasing the technological breakthroughs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, at any rate, I think what you&#8217;re doing really matters.&nbsp; And I know we got a lot to talk about.&nbsp; You saw the team over here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure about, you know, anybody but Gina over here on this side, including me.&nbsp; But all kidding aside, we got a lot to do and I think we can get a lot done.&nbsp; I really do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s a little thing going on in Europe right now, and I&#8217;m not going to be able to stay with you the whole time we&#8217;re here.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s not going to in any way diminish the content of what we&#8217;re discussing here.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Brian, I&#8217;m told that you&#8217;re going to run this show here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Yeah, we&#8217;ll give you a chance to depart, and the press as well, and then we’ll continue on here.</p>



<p>2:28 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, March 9,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/09/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-march-9-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 22:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48746</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:13 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, so I have a couple of short items at the top.&#160; A lot of paper.&#160; A lot of things to talk about today. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Today, the President will host an event with business leaders and bipartisan governors, including Governor Whitmer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:13 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, so I have a couple of short items at the top.&nbsp; A lot of paper.&nbsp; A lot of things to talk about today.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, the President will host an event with business leaders and bipartisan governors, including Governor Whitmer and Governor Holcomb, to call on Congress to quickly pass competitiveness legislation like the Bipartisan Innovation Act.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During the event, the President, Secretary Raimondo, and the participants will focus in particular on why passing competitiveness legislation is critical for lowering prices for working families on essentials like cars and household appliances by addressing bottlenecks like semiconductor chips, manufacturing more in America, and strengthening our supply chains to make our economy more productive.</p>



<p>As we’ve seen over the past year, global events like the pandemic or Russia’s unprovoked aggression in Ukraine can result in disruptions to global supply chains that lead to higher prices for American consumers, which further underscores the importance of strengthening our economy and making it more resilient to shocks like that in the future.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note that today the President signed an executive order outlining the first-ever whole-of-government approach to addressing the risks and harnessing the potential benefits of digital assets.</p>



<p>Previously, there has been &#8212; never been an organized effort to bring together the expertise and authorities of the entire U.S. government to inform a holistic approach to digital assets.</p>



<p>With this executive order, the President is calling on experts across the federal government to assess and develop policy recommendations that address the implications of growing digital asset sec- &#8212; of the growing digital asset sector across consumer protection, financial stability, national security, and climate risk.</p>



<p>Let me finally say: I heard there was a little kerfuffle in here after the briefing the other day.&nbsp; I just want to say that what we&#8217;re going to do today is we&#8217;re going to try to start with the third and fourth row, and fifth and sixth row; get more people&#8217;s questions answered.&nbsp; We are always happy to answer questions from here.&nbsp; I could go on for hours.&nbsp; Just sit in your seats.</p>



<p>But we also know you all have a lot on your plates.&nbsp; So what we try to do, for everybody&#8217;s knowledge, is balance between all the things reporters and all of you have focused on and trying to be informative in this briefing room.&nbsp; But we also are here as people have follow-up questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, Josh, let me have you start.&nbsp; Kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I know the pool is supposed to gather around 1:45 &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; if that’s still on.</p>



<p>So, one easy question: The U.S. declined to help facilitate the transfer of jets to Ukraine yesterday.&nbsp; Does the U.S. want the Ukraine to get jets?&nbsp; And how urgent a priority is that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, let me give you an update on the status.&nbsp; As of now, the &#8212; Secretary Austin, Chairman Milley, and members of our Defense Department are in touch with Ukrainian counterparts, NATO counterparts, discusting [sic] &#8212; discussing what are clearly logistical challenges here.</p>



<p>And I would note, Josh, that in the statement put out by my colleague at the Pentagon yesterday, he made clear that obviously the proposal from yesterday that fighter jets manned by Americans departing a NATO base to fly into airspace contes- &#8212; contested with Russia raises serious concerns for the United States and NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the logistical questions here, just to put a little fine point on it, are things like how do you get planes into Ukraine in a way that is not escalatory, and what are the logistics and operational details of that.</p>



<p>Those are conversations that are happening between counterparts at the military level, and I would expect any update might come from them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, let&#8217;s go around.&nbsp; Michael, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Two questions on Venezuela.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, obviously, yesterday two Americans were freed and they are now home.&nbsp; Nicolás Maduro has agreed to re-engage in the Mexico City talks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, is the ball in the President&#8217;s court at this point to continue the engagement?&nbsp; And what is the plan (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the &#8212; let me note that the return of two American citizens is certainly welcome news, exciting news.&nbsp; And it would not have happened without the tireless work over the series &#8212; a series of months by a number of our diplomats, including, of course, our Special Envoy for Hostage Affairs, Roger Carstens, who worked on this for months over the course of time.</p>



<p>You know, we are &#8212; we&#8217;ll continue to discuss a range of issues, including, first and foremost, Americans unjustly held.&nbsp; Unfortunately, they&#8217;re not the only individuals held there &#8212; the individuals who returned.&nbsp; So that will be something that we will look to have ongoing discussions about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that Maduro said he will resume talks with Venezuela&#8217;s interim president in Mexico.&nbsp; So that is an encouraging sign.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there were a range of issues discussed on this trip.&nbsp; There are a range of issues to discuss moving forward.&nbsp; But right now, we&#8217;re just celebrating the return of two Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just to follow up: Are there concrete plans for continued engagement for another round of talks?&nbsp; And is there &#8212; you know, you mentioned, I think on Monday, that energy security was part of the conversation.&nbsp; What can Venezuela contribute to energy security?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of additional talks or rounds of talks.&nbsp; But again, we are &#8212; we are very pleased to have these two Americans returned home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; if there are opportunities to continue to discuss that, that&#8217;s something we are open to.&nbsp; There are obviously ongoing concerns about the health and wellbeing of anyone detained, whether it&#8217;s there or in Venezuela or Russia or Afghanistan, Syria, China, Iran, and elsewhere.&nbsp; Those are conversations we are always going to want to engage in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, it is facts- &#8212; factual &#8212; you all know &#8212; that Venezuela is a large producer of oil.&nbsp; But in terms of any decisions or discussions or where that may go from here, I have no &#8212; nothing to preview or predict for you on that front.</p>



<p>Nadia, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Many American companies declared yesterday that they&#8217;re shutting down in Russia, including Visa card, Masters, and McDonald&#8217;s, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Russians say that they&#8217;re going to confiscate their assets there.&nbsp; How would the White House react to that?&nbsp; I know they’re all private companies, but basically declaring that they&#8217;re going to nationalize these assets, according to the Russians.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And second &#8212; not exactly related: Do you &#8212; there are some reports indicating that Russia is delaying the signing of the Iran agreement and delaying the negotiation in Vienna from taking place for their own interests because they don&#8217;t want, obviously, oil to be released to make up for the shortage.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me take the second one first.&nbsp; I would say that our team &#8212; we&#8217;re continuing to engage with Iran deal partners, including Russia, on Iran nuclear negotiations.&nbsp; We believe Russia shares a common interest in ensuring Iran never acquires a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In our view, there&#8217;s nothing that should be required of or will be offered from the United States as it relates to Russia sanctions &#8212; that is related to their invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, we believe we share an objective here.&nbsp; Always in the final stages, there are details to be worked through, and we will continue to work through those.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of your first question on the seizing &#8212; I think it was on the potential seizing of private sector assets in Russia for companies that have decided to pull back and pull out of the country &#8212; obviously, we have not &#8212; while we have applauded the actions of a number of companies, that is not something we have been pushing from behind the scenes, if that makes sense.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If they were to take those actions, I&#8217;m certain there would be steps we would take, but nothing has happened at this point in time.&nbsp; So let me talk to our economic team and see if there&#8217;s anything more we can predict for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; First, about the Florida bill that just passed restricting the speaking about homosexuality and gender identity after third grade.&nbsp; And then I have a question about surveillance matters that have been in the news.</p>



<p>Regarding the Florida bill: In 1994, when many of us in this room were in school, President Biden actually voted for a much broader restriction that banned federal funds from being used for, quote, &#8220;the promotion of homosexuality as a positive lifestyle alternative.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why did he do that?&nbsp; And can you describe how his thinking has evolved over the years?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that you have seen the President speak passionately about his view that a bill like this &#8212; a bill that would discriminate against families, against kids, put these kids in a position of not getting the support they need at a time where that&#8217;s exactly what they need &#8212; is discriminatory.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a form of bullying.&nbsp; It is horrific.&nbsp; I mean, the President has spoken to that.</p>



<p>In terms of his views and comments from 25 years ago, I think the most important question now is: Why are Florida leaders deciding they need to discriminate against kids who are members of the LGBTQI community?&nbsp; What prompts them to do that?&nbsp; Is it meanness?&nbsp; Is it wanting to make kids have more difficult times in school, in their communities?&nbsp; I would pose that question to them, and we can talk about it more tomorrow if you get an answer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there a reason he supported the same policy, though, in the &#8217;90s when we were all in school?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what&#8217;s important to note here is how outspoken the President has been against discrimination against kids, against members of the LGBTQI+ community.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re looking at here is a bill that would propagate misinformed, hateful policies and impact children…</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s the question I hope &#8212; maybe you can pose that to some of the leaders in Florida.&nbsp; Maybe they&#8217;ll return your phone calls.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll look forward to having a conversation with you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow up on that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, perhaps Chris could follow up afterwards.&nbsp; But I&#8217;d like to ask about the surveillance matters as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senators Wyden and Heinrich, who are Democrats, recently alleged that the CIA is conducting a mass surveillance program that implicates American data and that it&#8217;s outside of the statutory bounds that people think it&#8217;s within.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, could you say anything about that to reassure Americans regarding their data?</p>



<p>And secondly, according to a recent court filing by Special Counsel Durham, there was a technology executive who was, quote, “mining” the Executive Office of the President&#8217;s DNS traffic and other data.&nbsp; CISA, the federal agency for cybersecurity, said in a 2020 document that DNS data can be sensitive and that&#8217;s important to secure.</p>



<p>There are competing narratives, of course, about what data was actually implicated.&nbsp; So could you share with us what data was implicated in this and whether the White House has any security or privacy concerns regarding this alleged review?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have nothing further to comment on your questions.&nbsp; Obviously, this is an investigation.&nbsp; I point you to the Department of Justice, members of Congress.&nbsp; Obviously, we have serious respect for people&#8217;s privacy in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; A quick follow-up.&nbsp; You mentioned the logistical challenges about flying planes &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to Ukraine, through contested airspace.&nbsp; Why can&#8217;t the United States put those planes on trains or automobiles?&nbsp; I guess, are we really to believe that when we&#8217;re sending &#8212; or preparing to send billions in aid, that, you know, this is the logistical bottleneck that is stopping us from getting them those planes?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it is a serious logistical bottleneck, right?&nbsp; Obviously &#8212; there&#8217;s obvious concerns that the Department of Defense has spoken to about flying planes from U.S. airbases &#8212; right? &#8212; that they spoke to yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These planes &#8212; carting them down the street, I think, is not as easy as you may think it is.&nbsp; Planes &#8212; if they have to be taken apart and put back together, you have to have people who are able to put those planes back together.&nbsp; You have to ensure that there&#8217;s &#8212; they can be safely moved through the course of a contested country, or not &#8212; you know, a country where there is a war going on with the Russians, you know, who implemented that war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there are a range of logistical and operational challenges.&nbsp; Those are important conversations to happen between military experts and our Defense Department leaders and officials &#8212; Secretary Austin, Chairman Milley, and their counterparts.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, should we expect that the U.S. Export-Import Bank is going to continue to underwrite loans that would support commerce with Russian companies and corporations, given the tranche of sanctions that we&#8217;ve seen against (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to check and see how these sanctions are implemented.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re going to abide by all of our &#8212; our own sanctions.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve tried to implement them as quickly as possible, but I can see if there&#8217;s any specific impact on them.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, John Kirby&#8217;s line is that transferring the planes &#8212; or the latest iteration &#8212; was not &#8220;tenable.&#8221;&nbsp; Can you say: Is what&#8217;s not tenable the arming of the Ukrainians with jet fighters?&nbsp; Or is it merely the logistical things you&#8217;re speaking to?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the Defense Department spoke primarily to this, and they were very specific, Geoff.&nbsp; They said fighter jets manned by Americans departing a NATO base to fly into airspace contested with Russia raises serious concerns for the United States and for the NATO Alliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have provided a billion dollars in military assistance.&nbsp; I would say the $350 billion that was announced just &#8212; less than two weeks ago, I believe the Defense Department has conveyed almost all of that has been delivered.&nbsp; We have not held back on providing weapons, anti-missile systems, tank systems at all at any point in this process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there are important operational, logistics concerns here and steps &#8212; conversations that should happen between military experts.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what&#8217;s happening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, in principle, it&#8217;s a policy that the White House would support or like to find a way to solve?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;re having discussions about it, but there are operational and logistical questions that are important ones that we will leave to our Defense Department colleagues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick one.&nbsp; You know, there was another round of arrests in Russia &#8212; it was, like, estimated at 5,000 &#8212; over the weekend.&nbsp; Is the &#8212; protesting the war.&nbsp; What is the assessment of the White House as far as how this has all affected regime stability over there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t think we assess that President Putin thought that there would be such an outpouring of objection in his own country.&nbsp; He would probably not have cut off access to media, access to social media, access to basic information for the people of his country if that were the case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we have seen people across Russia bravely, courageously protest, speak out against a war that they believe is unjust, is unwarranted.&nbsp; And, you know, that is incredibly powerful.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, unfortunately, as you know and many of you know from working for these networks and news organizations, there have been tough decisions that news organizations have had to make, whether &#8212; about whether they&#8217;re going to keep a presence in Russia because of the restrictions.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not just &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s not just the speaking out of President Putin.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about fines.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about the threat of arrest.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about safety and security that organizations have to consider.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in terms of stability, I don’t have any assessment for that other than to tell you that it&#8217;s pretty clear he didn&#8217;t bet on the opposition from within his own country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Shrish, why don’t you go in the back?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; One, if I could follow up on the earlier</p>



<p>questions about the jet fighters.&nbsp; Is this a difference of kind or a difference of degree?&nbsp; I mean, is the objection that it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s an airplane, or because, as you point out, we&#8217;re sending them things that destroy tanks, things that shoot down airplanes?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I mean, if it can be done without &#8212; I mean, they would know where they came from and &#8212; I don&#8217;t even see if there&#8217;s plausible deniability or anything like that.&nbsp; What is the hang-up exactly?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s pretty clear.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t require a military expert to understand why having planes fly from a U.S. airbase into a contested part of a country where there is a war is not in our interest and not in NATO interests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there are logistical and operational challenges to consider and discuss.&nbsp; It isn&#8217;t that easy to move military planes around &#8212; maybe not as easy as some of you may suspect it is.&nbsp; And those are conversations, again, that are happening between military experts.&nbsp; And I would point you to the Department of Defense for the status of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And more broadly, is there any concern that making the lives of average Russians miserable &#8212; you know, with all these companies pulling out and things that are designed to hurt the economy, as opposed to Putin personally, as opposed to his oligarchs personally &#8212; is there a worry that that&#8217;s going to consolidate his support within the country rather than make him &#8212; rather than diminishing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that our view and the view of our global partners is that when a president like President Putin, you know, launches a war of choice where he is brutally killing, injuring people in a sovereign country, there have to be consequences.&nbsp; Those consequences are economic and significant, no question about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our target is not to hurt the Russian people; it is to squeeze President Putin and the leadership around him.&nbsp; But what the impact is, is certainly having a devastating impact on the Russian economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our view is that over the over the medium and long term, that that is not going to be sustainable for President Putin and the team around him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Ed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I’m starting to hear the administration talk about gas prices &#8212; as a way to speed up the lowering of gas prices, to speed up the transition to those clean energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gas prices have risen month over month, every month since the President has been in office.&nbsp; So, is the feeling then from the President that the American people just have to wait until 2030 when the President set his goal for zero emissions &#8212; or to have cars being sold with zero emissions &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible) higher gas prices.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s never been our theory or our belief.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say that since President Putin began his military buildup on Ukrainian borders, the price of gas at the pump in America has gone up 75 cents, which is significant, of course.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There is widespread consensus that the sharp runup of energy prices since January was called by &#8212; caused by the building of Putin&#8217;s troops at Ukraine&#8217;s border.&nbsp; The reality, as we know, is that Russia is the world&#8217;s third-largest oil producer.&nbsp; And energy supply disruptions and market volatility are a result of his aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Don&#8217;t &#8212; you don’t have to take my word for that.&nbsp; There have been a number of assessments.&nbsp; Back in January, Federal Chair &#8212; Fed Chair Powell warned that there was a risk to our economy based on, quote, “what&#8217;s going on in Eastern Europe.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In early February, JP Morgan analysts projected that disruptions of oil flows from Russia could push oil prices to $120 per barrel, which is what has happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our approach has always been twofold.&nbsp; One, we need to ensure the supply meets the demand out there in the marketplace.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a couple of ways to do that.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re engaging with big global oil producers around the world to meet that demand.&nbsp; But there are also, as we&#8217;ve talked about a few times in here, 9,000 unused oil leases that oil companies could certainly tap into, and we&#8217;ve encouraged them to do that.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s certainly a way to address.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the price of gas on February 14th was at a high &#8212; highest level since 2014.&nbsp; So it was already at an elevated level.</p>



<p>I want to ask you &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And the build-up of troops was even before that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to ask you about tomorrow.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to get a CPI inflation number that&#8217;s expected to be pretty big.&nbsp; It&#8217;s supposed to rise from the 7.5 percent that it was month over month.&nbsp; So gas prices are part of that.&nbsp; I want to know what specifically the administration has done, they&#8217;ve been working on that has worked to bring down inflation.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first because while we don&#8217;t have the data at this point yet, but as we&#8217;re looking ahead, we certainly assess that &#8212; that we expect to see a high headline in &#8212; headline inflation in tomorrow&#8217;s February inflation data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A key reason, as you touched on, are energy prices.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen the price of gas increase, as I noted, 75 cents since the beginning of the year as Putin built up his military near Ukraine and took increasingly aggressive measures that were felt in the markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also expect some increases in pandemic-affected sectors given our strong recovery from Omicron in February.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a positive sign for our economy and for Americans who are going out again, traveling, going to restaurants, and getting back to normal.&nbsp; And we also expect to see continued moderation in used car prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what our prediction, our assessment is at this point in time.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of steps we have taken to address inflation &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what has worked?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What has &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What has worked?&nbsp; So October 13th is when you announced the port initiative.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What specifically can you point to that has worked to bring down inflation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there are a number of steps we&#8217;ve taken.&nbsp; If you&#8217;ve seen &#8212; if you compare a month-to-month, we&#8217;ve seen inflationary pressure &#8212; or inflationary numbers go down month to month &#8212; even as we looked at the year-to-year numbers go up, which we entirely predicted.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One, we&#8217;ve taken steps to address bottlenecks in the supply chain, to reduce those bottlenecks.&nbsp; Those are steps we&#8217;ve taken not just since October but since earlier this year.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question that we&#8217;ve seen impacts as it relates to getting goods and supplies out to the American public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also taken steps to address what we see as shortages and issues in the semiconductor space.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We &#8212; I just opened this briefing by pressing for the passing of the competitiveness legislation that the President would love to sign into law, because we know that one of the big pressures is, of course, from the car and manufacturing sector or the car sector.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, third, we know that because of the pressures on the energy sector that that has been an area where we&#8217;ve continued to see have an impact on inflationary pressure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We believe in the last few months that has been because of President Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; But as I&#8217;ve noted, there are a number of steps working to address that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t you go ahead in the yellow?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, there’s &#8212; is there an assessment by the White House for the losses on the Russian side, like financial, economy losses?&nbsp; Because every time a new or fresh wave of sanctions is imposed, the response from Moscow would be, “It was expected.”&nbsp; So, is there, like, an assessment of the losses as a result of all the sanctions that have been imposed?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, another question on EU.&nbsp; As you know, President Zelenskyy asked for an accelerated push to join the EU.&nbsp; And EU leaders or, I think, representatives are meeting today in Brussels.&nbsp; Does the White House support Ukraine in EU?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the last question, that&#8217;s really up to the EU and Ukraine to determine together.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the &#8212; on the first question, I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s what they&#8217;re saying anymore.&nbsp; They have had &#8212; their stock market has been closed for days.&nbsp; The ruble is worth a penny.&nbsp; They&#8217;re headed toward what many outside economists have described as a recession.&nbsp; They have had a huge strain on their financial markets and systems.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think the facts bear out if that is the claim anyone is making, and I have not seen that claim be made, much less.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, go ahead in the middle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Does the White House believe there&#8217;s an opportunity to convince China to play an effective role in resolving the crisis in Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve seen China do to date:&nbsp; We have seen them speak out at the Munich Security Conference or have a public comment, I should say, about the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen them abstain from U.N. Security Council votes.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen them largely abide by the sanctions that have been put in place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would note, though, that if any country tries to evade or work around our economic measures, they will experience the consequences of those actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So our assessment right now is that they&#8217;re abiding by the requirements that have been put in place, but we would continue to encourage any country to think a lot about what place they want to &#8212; what role they want to play in history as we all look back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let me go to the front.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; A couple questions on the future leadership of NATO.&nbsp; What is the White House thinking on Jens Stoltenberg stepping down in just a few months as the leader of the Alliance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that NATO has not been more united, in the last several months, in decades.&nbsp; And while no one wanted that to be prompted by the invasion of a dictator, like President Putin, into a foreign country, that unity among NATO partners and the strength of that unity is certainly something that has been a direct impact of his aggression.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of future leadership, obviously, that would be for NATO partners to determine.&nbsp; But we certainly recognize and value the leadership that has been displayed by NATO &#8212; NATO leaders and the Alliance over the course of the last few months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Follow-up on that: Have you, as a NATO member, ruled out asking Stoltenberg to continue in this time of the biggest crisis since World War Two?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you in terms of the future of NATO leadership from here.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you started the search for a new leader of NATO?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, it&#8217;s up to NATO leaders and partners to determine that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not a spokesperson for the NATO Alliance, so I would certainly point you to them to speak to that in any further detail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to go back to Venezuela, if we can.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s a few here you&#8217;re probably going to not be able or just not answer &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but we’re going to ask them anyway.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gustavo Cárdenas and Jorge Alberto Fernández &#8212; do we know why they were released?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more details on that I can provide.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; U.S. officials who were part of that delegation &#8212; are they all back from Venezuela?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I believe, yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will confirm that for you, though.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we anticipate the imminent release of any other Americans who are being held there right now?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, as we are working on bringing any unjustly detained Americans home from any country in the world &#8212; whether it&#8217;s Venezuela, Russia, Afghanistan, Syria, China, Iran, and elsewhere &#8212; we typically don&#8217;t discuss that because it puts at risk the potential for bringing individuals home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But yes, we would still &#8212; we are still going to work on bringing others home who have &#8212; who did not return on the plane last night.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A high-ranking member of Juan Guaidó’s team told the Miami Herald this week, quote, “It is foolish to think that Maduro will quit Russia when a great deal of the corruption funds have been deposited in Russia and when Russia, furthermore is its greatest ally…This is a mistake.&nbsp; To buy oil from Maduro is the same as buying oil from Putin.”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two things.&nbsp; I think I know where you&#8217;ll go on the first one, but I want to give you the opportunity to respond.&nbsp; If the United States &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We spend so much time together, Ed.&nbsp; I appreciate it.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If the United States recognizes Guaidó as the leader of Venezuela, why did the U.S. feel it necessary to negotiate with the Maduro regime?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And was the Guaidó team made aware of the plans for U.S. officials to go to Venezuela to meet with the Maduro government before they went?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the last, I just don&#8217;t have anything more to convey to you about private diplomatic conversations.&nbsp; I would note that one of the steps that was announced yesterday was Maduro saying he was willing to resume talks with Venezuela’s interim president.&nbsp; Certainly, we would note that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, obviously, we &#8212; part of our effort here, as you now know, was related to the health and wellbeing of American citizens detained in Venezuela, hence we had discussions with those who are detaining them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one, because there were so many questions &#8212; good ones &#8212; about the planes &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; going from Poland to Ukraine and whether we&#8217;d be the interlocutor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Sunday, when the Secretary of State was asked about this possibility of a plane swap, he said, quote, “That gets a green light,” and we&#8217;re working with Poland on possibly backfilling their military equipment.&nbsp; What changed between him saying that on Sunday and Tori Nuland and others yesterday at the Pentagon saying, “Actually, that&#8217;s not tenable”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s exactly how I would see how the events transpired.&nbsp; I believe that Tony &#8212; Secretary Blinken was asked about Poland’s giving planes to the Ukrainians.&nbsp; That&#8217;s certainly a choice they make as a sovereign country.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never opposed that, never stood in the way of that; we still do not today.</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re talking about here though is &#8212; the proposal yesterday, as you know, was for these planes to fly from a U.S. air base in Germany.&nbsp; And we have understandable concerns about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what we&#8217;re talking about now, through military channels, is the operational concerns: how this could work, the logistics of it.&nbsp; And those conversations are ongoing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Why did you guys decide to rebrand the rise in gas prices as the “#PutinPriceHike”?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I mean, if you want to use that on Fox, I welcome that.&nbsp; But &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I think it&#8217;ll get a lot of airtime because we have heard the President warn for months that gas prices were rising because of the supply chain and because of post-pandemic demand.&nbsp; If you guys knew for months that this was going to be the #PutinPriceHike, why are we just hearing that now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, if we go back to six months ago, I don&#8217;t think anybody was predicting we would be exactly where we are as it relates to Russia and Ukraine, as you know that events in the world, including the invasion by Russia of a foreign country, does prompt instability and volatility in the global oil markets.&nbsp; And there are all sorts of different issues that can impact that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing now.</p>



<p>Outside economists and analysts have conveyed and said publicly that Russia&#8217;s invasion, Russia&#8217;s buildup of troops, President Putin&#8217;s decision to do that very early this year led to a lot of the instability and volatility in the oil markets.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t have to take my word for it.</p>



<p>So, therefore, if President Putin&#8217;s buildup of military troops is leading to volatility and an increase in oil &#8212; in prices, hence you have “Putin pump &#8212; gas price pump &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; You and the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; rise.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You and the President are both talk &#8212; thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You and the President are both talking about &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Spit that out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You and the President are both talking about producing energy here, saying that oil and gas companies “have 9,000 permits to drill now.&nbsp; They could be drilling right now.”&nbsp; Would President Biden cut red tape to make that possible?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What red tape needs to be cut when they have the permits, they have the capacity to do it?&nbsp; What&#8217;s holding them up?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does President Biden think that each of these 9,000 leases that are available have oil or gas in them?&nbsp; Because industry experts are saying that “that accusation is a complete red herring”; “some permits are viable and some are not”; and that when you say that, “This represents a fundamental misunderstanding as to how this process works.”</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, the &#8212; nearly 60 percent of leased acres remain non-producing &#8212; that&#8217;s a lot &#8212; in the range of 20 million acres.&nbsp; So there are 9,000 unused approved permits to drill in.&nbsp; They should not require &#8212; that should not require us inviting them to do that.&nbsp; They should do that themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you said they can&#8217;t get the additional permits.&nbsp; So would the President &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What additional permits do they need?&nbsp; There&#8217;s no &#8212; they have &#8212; the leases are there.&nbsp; The permits are there. I don&#8217;t think they need an embroidered invitation to drill.&nbsp; That is their oil companies.&nbsp; What is &#8212; what is happening &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s not an embroidered invitation, it’s a federal permit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What is happening &#8212; what is ha- &#8212; but what was is &#8212; the permits have been granted, Peter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s not just one permit though.&nbsp; Would you &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What is happening here is that we are seeing &#8212; these are private sector companies.&nbsp; We recognize that.&nbsp; Many of them are making record profits.&nbsp; We see that that.&nbsp; That is all publicly available data.&nbsp; They have pressure to return cash to investors and their shareholders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re saying right now is: There is a war.&nbsp; We&#8217;re asking them to go use the approved permits, use the unused space, and go get more supply out of the ground in our own country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just a quick yes-or-no, because there&#8217;s a lot of gray area here.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is a restart of the Keystone XL construction completely off the table as long as Joe Biden is President?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, why don&#8217;t you tell me what that would help address.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking you if it is an option.&nbsp; You guys say, “All options are on the table.”&nbsp; Is restarting Keystone construction one of them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; If we&#8217;re trying to bring about more supply, that does not address any problem.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s supply from Canada, a friendly ally, instead of Saudi Arabia or Iran or Venezuela.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That &#8212; that’s already &#8212; we’re already getting that oil, Peter.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; the pipeline is just the delivery mechanism.&nbsp; It is not an oil field.&nbsp; So it does not provide more supply into the system.&nbsp; It does not address &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it off the table?&nbsp; Is it possible that Joe Biden will ever say, “You guys can go ahead with construction of Keystone XL”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no plans for that, and it would not address any of the problems we&#8217;re having currently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you help us &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And we’re going to have to wrap up soon, but we’ll try to get to MJ.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you help us understand what exactly would have transpired for the Polish government to publicly propose this idea of getting the fighter jets to Ukraine that the U.S. would then publicly reject?&nbsp; Was there, at any point, a breakdown in communication between the two countries?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I think as our Undersecretary of State, Tori Nuland, testified yesterday, we were not made aware of their plans to make that announcement yesterday.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t call that a breakdown in &#8212; I guess it&#8217;s a temporary breakdown in communication, but we have a strong and abiding relationship with Poland.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President spoke with President Duda just last Friday.&nbsp; Obviously, the Vice President is on her way there, not &#8212; not related to this particular issue, which will be worked through military channels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it was more about the mechanism for how it would be delivered.&nbsp; And that is the issue that is operational, and we&#8217;re still discussing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it safe to say that the U.S. was caught off guard by the initial announcement from the Polish government?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we said that yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On gas prices &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; quickly.&nbsp; The President said yesterday, “I&#8217;m going to do everything I can to minimize Putin’s price hike here at home.”&nbsp; And then hours later as he was getting off the Air Force One, he said, I “can&#8217;t do much about that right now.”&nbsp; “Can&#8217;t do much right now.”&nbsp; That was the exact words from the President.</p>



<p>For anyone that might have been confused seeing the two statements from the President within a couple of hours, what would be your explanation?&nbsp; Does the President believe there is action that he can take to address gas prices, or does he believe there&#8217;s not much that can be done?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the short gaggles when the President is getting off the plane and getting into a car are not always super comprehensive, as I think many of you have experienced.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not always extensive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what the President said yesterday in his lengthy remarks before his trip and what we have said many times is that there are a range of steps that we will continue to take, including coordinating with the global community about ensuring the supply in the marketplace meets the demand.&nbsp; That includes the release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve that he announced a second one just a few weeks ago.&nbsp; That includes continuing to work and coordinate with global oil suppliers around the world, something that his national security team and he is engaged in, in a nearly daily basis.&nbsp; And that includes considering a range of domestic options.</p>



<p>But the oil markets &#8212; oil markets are global.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And it is all about meeting the supply demands that are out there.&nbsp; And clearly, given the invasion and given the impact of that, we need to look at a range of options, but we&#8217;ve already taken a number of steps and we will continue to.&nbsp; And he said that all yesterday morning in the same day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, to clarify &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, I got to &#8212; this may have to be the last one.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to clarify on the military planes &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and the Vice President’s trip.&nbsp; You said that what&#8217;s going on now are discussions with military officials.&nbsp; So this issue is not a priority, is not going to be part of the Vice President&#8217;s discussions with the Polish leader tomorrow?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would expect it&#8217;s going to happen through military channels.&nbsp; Those conversations have on- &#8212; been ongoing, and I would expect they would continue to happen through those channels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, not &#8212; not a priority?&nbsp; Not a central part of the Vice President&#8217;s discussions tomorrow (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m never going to say it&#8217;s not a priority, but I would just say that the appropriate channels for it &#8212; because they&#8217;re about the operational movement of military equipment &#8212; are through military channels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A quick follow-up?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a clarification.&nbsp; Just a clarification on the &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know we’re going to have to wrap up in a minute here because you guys have to go to the event.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick reaction to the Russian airstrikes reportedly striking a children’s hospital in the Ukrainian city of Mariupol?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have &#8212; we have certainly seen those reports.&nbsp; And as a mother &#8212; I know a number of you are mothers yourself &#8212; it is horrifying to see the type of &#8212; the barbaric use of military force to go after innocent civilians in a sovereign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, I know we&#8217;ve seen the reports on all &#8212; that you have all been broadcasting over the last couple of hours.&nbsp; Unfortunately, I don&#8217;t have more details than that at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just for clarification &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You all have to go to an event with the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just for clarification on the question &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the U.S. recognize Juan Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela?&nbsp; Because I think that was a direct question from Ed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That we had &#8212; that’s how we’ve &#8212; we have referred to him, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, no, but you didn’t say.&nbsp; Does the U.S. recognize Juan Guaidó &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s how we refer to him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone, so much.&nbsp; Have a good rest of your day.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:50 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe&#160;Biden’s Roundtable with CEOs and Bipartisan Governors in Support of the Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-roundtable-with-ceos-and-bipartisan-governors-in-support-of-the-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 21:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. joined by Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo and Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese, met with business leaders and a bipartisan pair of governors to call on Congress to take swift action and deliver competitiveness legislation like the Bipartisan Innovation Act to the President’s desk. The governors and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. joined by Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo and Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese, met with business leaders and a bipartisan pair of governors to call on Congress to take swift action and deliver competitiveness legislation like the Bipartisan Innovation Act to the President’s desk.<br> <br>The governors and business leaders—which included some of the world’s leading manufacturing and semiconductor firms—discussed how the bill will foster domestic semiconductor manufacturing, create more resilient supply chains, invest in basic research and set a course for America’s innovation agenda while lowering costs for the middle class. Business leaders discussed their plans to reshore manufacturing and make more in America, building on the momentum of 423,000 manufacturing jobs created since President Biden took office. They discussed how their companies are trying to build more resilient supply chains, leading them to re-locate production in America, and how the bill would result in quicker innovation in American manufacturing and more investments in worker training. They also discussed how domestic production can help Americans by addressing bottlenecks that are raising the costs of household goods like appliances, air conditioners, and washing machines.  And the group discussed how, as we’ve seen over the past years, global events like the pandemic or Russia’s unprovoked aggression in Ukraine can result in higher prices for American consumers, which further underscores the importance of strengthening our economy and making it more resilient to these types of shocks.<br> <br>Indiana Governor Eric Holcomb and Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer, spoke to the economic imperative of passing this bipartisan legislation for the economies of their states. Governor Holcomb said “Slow speed kills—we need to get this done and get it to your desk” and Governor Whitmer explained “Chip shortages have impacted more than 575,000 American jobs…These shortages are driving up costs, are jeopardizing families, and increasing the manufacturing here at home will reduce supply chain delays in transportation as well as lowering the costs of consumer electronics.”<br> <br><strong>Participants include:</strong><br>Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer<br>Indiana Governor Eric Holcomb<br>Dr. Siyoung Choi*, President and GM, Device Solutions Division, Samsung<br>Elizabeth Door, Senior Vice President, Global Strategic Sourcing, Whirlpool<br>Enrique Lores*, President and CEO, Hewlett-Packard<br>Geoff Martha, CEO, Medtronic<br>Sanjay Mehrota, President and CEO, Micron<br>Jennifer Rumsey, President and COO, Cummins<br> <br>*Denotes virtual participant</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
