<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:21:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Signing of H.R. 3076, the “Postal Service Reform Act of&#160;2022”</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/06/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-h-r-3076-the-postal-service-reform-act-of-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 4:28 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; You know, Annette, as you were speaking, I looked down at &#8212; Senator Carper used to be chairman of this committee.&#160; How many years, Tommy, you’ve been working on this? SENATOR CARPER:&#160; Four hundred.&#160; (Laughter.) THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; I tell you what &#8212; your service both in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>4:28 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, Annette, as you were speaking, I looked down at &#8212; Senator Carper used to be chairman of this committee.&nbsp; How many years, Tommy, you’ve been working on this?</p>



<p>SENATOR CARPER:&nbsp; Four hundred.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I tell you what &#8212; your service both in the Air Force as a letter carrier is real, and it&#8217;s all about serving your community, and I appreciate it very much.</p>



<p>Matter of fact, when I said, “It&#8217;s good to meet you,” she said, “I know you.&nbsp; We’ve met before.”&nbsp; And I said, “I apologize.”&nbsp; She said, “You used to show up every &#8212; in Wilmington” &#8212; how often?</p>



<p>MS. TAYLOR:&nbsp; In D.C.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, in D.C.</p>



<p>MS. TAYLOR:&nbsp; Every year.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Every year, I&#8217;d show up to the letter carriers’ breakfast or lunch or dinner &#8212; I can’t remember which.&nbsp; But it reminded me why I &#8212; I think foreign policy is easier.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; “War and Peace” goes down easier, Gerry, I think.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senator Peters, Senator Portman, Senator Carper, Senator Tillis; Representatives Maloney, Comer, Connolly, and Virginia Foxx and Stephen Lynch &#8212; Stephen, good to see you, pal.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t do &#8212; I didn&#8217;t know you did post offices.</p>



<p>REPRESENTATIVE LYNCH:&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And &#8212; and Brenda Lawrence, who served the U.S. Postal Service for 30 years before being elected to Congress.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Which was harder?&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Well, look, some of you know, before I became President &#8212; I&#8217;m sure you all know this &#8212; I was the Ben Franklin Professor of Practice at the University of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; Professor, Jim.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And everybody walks in and they wonder why Ben Franklin&#8217;s picture is hanging in my &#8212; portrait is hanging in my office.&nbsp; Because if I didn&#8217;t put that up, there&#8217;d be no &#8212; nobody I knew would get into University of Pennsylvania again. (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m only kidding.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Ben Franklin, one of our Founding Fathers, was our first postmaster general.&nbsp; And he saw the Postal Service in a way to connect the colonies and to build together as one nation.&nbsp; I mean, literally, that&#8217;s what it was seen as: It was to connect the colonies and build one nation &#8212; connect everything.</p>



<p>He saw the power of the Postal Service to deliver more than the mail, but some of our most basic freedoms and basic rights were delivered by the Post Office.&nbsp; Freedom of speech by allowing citizens the voice and to &#8212; their voices to be amplified all across the country.&nbsp; Freedom of the press by offering discounted rates for newspapers.&nbsp; The right to privacy by expressly prohibiting &#8212; this sounds silly &#8212; but expressly prohibiting the opening of mail that belonged to somebody else.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And beyond those rights and freedoms, our oldest postal roads helped give rise to some of our nation’s most essential infrastructure.&nbsp; There were postal highways.&nbsp; That’s why a lot of these roads were built: to provide post.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, we used to serve with a guy who was from West Virginia, Jennings Randolph.&nbsp; And he &#8212; the thing he &#8212; he started an airline.&nbsp; But the way the airlines used to work was there’d be a great &#8212; Tommy, they’d put up two big poles like goal posts, and they would put a wire between it and they’d hang whatever the Postal Service &#8212; the post mail used to be collected.&nbsp; And the airplane would come down with a hook on it and pick it up and take it off.&nbsp; So, you know &#8212; I’m not going to say &#8212; if Jennings were here, he’d say there’d be no Post Office out there.&nbsp; But anyway, I’m only kidding.&nbsp; But &#8212;</p>



<p>But today, more than 670,000 &#8212; -75,000 dedicated men and women of the U.S. Postal Service continue to deliver for the American people.</p>



<p>They help keep us healthy by shipping 4 million prescriptions per day.&nbsp; Four million per day.&nbsp; And when we’re dedicated &#8212; and when we dedicated to send and committed we would send to &#8212; free &#8212; to &#8212; COVID-19 tests directly to people’s homes, the Postal Service stepped up to make that happen as well.</p>



<p>And now they delivered over two hundred and &#8212; three hundred &#8212; excuse me &#8212; 320 million COVID test 19 kits so far, in every state, territory, and U.S. military base in the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>An impressive turnaround for an unprecedented task.&nbsp; And it’s continuing the truly heroic service that they provided throughout this pandemic.</p>



<p>When everyone was worried about &#8212; that supply chain delays would ruin the holidays, the Post Office delivered the packages that were &#8212; that &#8212; more than any other shipper in the world, and they got the gifts to our homes and our loved ones on time.</p>



<p>And the Postal Service is central to our economy and is central to rural America, delivering mail and packages between small businesses and customers every single, solitary day.</p>



<p>And the deliveries &#8212; you know, and delivering seeds and even live animals, often, to parts of the country that private carriers can&#8217;t or won&#8217;t or aren&#8217;t required to reach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is another essential thing the Postal Service delivers: your vote.&nbsp; In 2020, 43 percent of the votes cast by ballot were cast by mail.&nbsp; And on average, it took those ballots &#8212; (applause) &#8212; on average, it took those ballots less than two days to get from the voter to the election office, faster than the average delivery time for first-class mail.</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s no exaggeration to say that the Postal Service delivers democracy.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s no exaggeration to say the Postal Service is as essential as it ever was, as it’s ever been &#8212; today.</p>



<p>In 2006, the law required the Postal Service to prepay &#8212; prepay retirement benefits 50 years into the future.&nbsp; No other &#8212; no other company or federal agency has to do anything like that.&nbsp; And the requirement of that law stretched the Postal Service&#8217;s finances almost to the breaking point, with real consequences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are stories of people across the country getting hit with late fees because their credit card bill arrived a week late, if it arrived at all.&nbsp; Small businesses on the verge of collapse because payments they were counting on were &#8212; were severely delayed.&nbsp; Elderly Americans suffering because they had to go weeks without their medication.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I, like many of you, made a campaign promise to fix this. And today we are.&nbsp; You all &#8212; the members in front of me did all the work.&nbsp; I made the promise; you did all the work.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I&#8217;m glad that strong, bipartisan majorities in the House and Senate have come together to deliver on this needed reform.</p>



<p>With this bill, we&#8217;re repealing the pre-funding mandate and setting the Postal Service on a more sustainable and stable financial footing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re guaranteeing that the mail will continue to be delivered six days a week.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the bill increases transparency by requiring the Postal Service to develop online &#8212; an online public dashboard updated weekly with local and national service performance data.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ll be able to see in real-time how well the Postal Service is delivering for you and for your community.&nbsp; And this bill streamlines healthcare for Postal workers as well.&nbsp; They deliver for us, so &#8212; through rain and snow and sleet, and we&#8217;re making sure the healthcare they need will be there for them as well.</p>



<p>And finally, this bill will allow the Postal Service to partner with state, local, and Tribal governments to offer valuable and helpful non-postal services to the public.&nbsp; Imagine a trip to the Post Office where you can pick up your bus pass or your hunting license or your fishing license.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, there are more areas where we want to see the Postal Service leading.&nbsp; For example, it needs to do more to modernize and electrify its fleet of vehicles to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and to save money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we’re going to do that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll continue to fight for these commonsense improvements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But today, we enshrine in law our recognition that the Postal Service is fundamental to our economy, to our democracy, to our health, and the very sense of who we are as a nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this bill &#8212; this bill recognizes the Postal Service is a public service, and we&#8217;re ensuring that it can continue to serve all Americans for generations to come.</p>



<p>Now, I’ll now go over and sign that postal bill.&nbsp; And those of you who are going to come up while I sign it, I&#8217;m not going to read out your names; they told me who you are.&nbsp; Everybody but Steny can come.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’m only kidding, Steny.</p>



<p>And we’ll get this reform bill finally signed.&nbsp; And, Thom, it only took what?&nbsp; Eleven years?</p>



<p>SENATOR TILLIS:&nbsp; (Inaudible).</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Twelve.&nbsp; Twelve.&nbsp; Twelve years.</p>



<p>SENATOR TILLIS:&nbsp; It seems like more.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Rob, now that’s pretty fast, right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyway, all kidding aside, thank you for the hard work you’ve done.&nbsp; You’ve done a good job.&nbsp; Let me walk over here.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>(The bill is signed.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, it’s official.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Congressional Briefing on National Security Impact of Semiconductor Supply Chain and Importance of Passing Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/readout-of-congressional-briefing-on-national-security-impact-of-semiconductor-supply-chain-and-importance-of-passing-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon, senior Administration officials including Commerce Secretary Raimondo, Deputy Defense Secretary Hicks, National Security Advisor Sullivan, and National Science Foundation Director Panchanathan held a briefing with a bipartisan and bicameral group of Members of Congress to discuss the urgent need to invest in made-in-America semiconductors as well as research and development that will protect&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This afternoon, senior Administration officials including Commerce Secretary Raimondo, Deputy Defense Secretary Hicks, National Security Advisor Sullivan, and National Science Foundation Director Panchanathan held a briefing with a bipartisan and bicameral group of Members of Congress to discuss the urgent need to invest in made-in-America semiconductors as well as research and development that will protect our economic and national security.</p>



<p>During the briefing, the Administration officials underscored how decades of disinvestment in domestic semiconductor manufacturing capacity have left America producing only 12% of global semiconductor output and vulnerable to the sort of supply chain disruptions we’ve seen in recent years, like the pandemic and Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine. A significant interruption to our supply of semiconductors could cause historic damage to the U.S. economy – damage far greater than the impact of chips shortages on the American auto industry right now – and would undercut our technological competitiveness and military advantages over adversaries globally.</p>



<p>The House and Senate have each passed bills to make historic investments in research, domestic manufacturing and America’s capacity to make semiconductors – including with $52 billion in new funding authorized in the CHIPS Act. This support would help spur further private sector investments in America’s semiconductor industry after nearly $80 billion in new investments in President Biden’s first year in office, including Intel’s $20 billion fabrication facility in Ohio.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These investments in semiconductors are crucial and must be complemented by investment in other advanced technologies as well, including the research and development leading to the next generation of these technologies, and related workforce development. These investments are critical to making our economy stronger and more resilient, and to protect our national security. That’s why the Administration officials urged Congress to move quickly to get legislation to the President’s desk for his signature, including through action to formally go to conference and name conferees this week.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at North America’s Building Trades Unions Legislative&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/06/remarks-by-president-biden-at-north-americas-building-trades-unions-legislative-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington HiltonWashington, D.C. 12:58 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It’s good to be home!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Whoa.&#160;&#160; AUDIENCE:&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe! THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you. AUDIENCE:&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe! THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; You better stop; I’ll start believing it.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Washington Hilton<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>12:58 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s good to be home!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; You better stop; I’ll start believing it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Please, have a seat if you have one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s good to be home!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You know, I look out there and I see an awful lot of you who &#8212; as they say in Claymont, Delaware &#8212; “who brung me to the dance.”&nbsp; And I &#8212; no, I really mean it.&nbsp; There is no exaggeration: I’d not be standing here without labor, without union &#8212; union labor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, as we used to say when I was a senator, “If you’d excuse the point of personal privilege” &#8212; before I turn to my main remarks, I’d like to &#8212; I have to briefly address the horrifying reports of the atrocities taking place in Ukraine and the steps the United States is taking to respond in close coordination with our Allies and our partners.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’m sure you’ve seen the pictures from Bucha and out &#8212; just outside of Kyiv: bodies left in streets as Russian troops withdrew, some shot in the back of the head with their hands tied behind their backs; civilians executed in cold blood; bodies dumped into mass graves.&nbsp; The sense of brutality and inhumanity left for all the world to see unapologetically.&nbsp; There’s nothing less happening than major war crimes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Responsible nations have to come together to hold these perpetrators accountable.&nbsp;&nbsp;And together with our Allies and our partners, we’re going to keep raising the economic cost and ratchet up the pain for Putin and further increase Russia’s economic isolation.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, the steps we’ve already taken are predicted to shrink Russia’s gross domestic product by double digits this year alone.&nbsp; Just in one year, our sanctions are likely to wipe out the last 15 years of Russia’s economic gains.&nbsp; And because we’ve cut Russia off from importing technologies like semiconductors and encryption security and critical components of quantum technology that they need to compete in the 21st century, we’re going to stifle Russia’s ability and its economy to grow for years to come.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, this is the United States, and we’re taking additional steps in lockstep with our Allies and partners to raise the economic pressure on Putin.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, the United States will impose full blocking sanctions on Sberbank, by far the largest financial institution in Russia, and Alfa Bank, its largest private bank.&nbsp; We’re locking down any accounts, any funds that those banks hold in the United States.&nbsp; They’ll not be able to touch any of their money.&nbsp; They’ll not be able to do any business here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, second, I’m going to sign an executive order that’s going to ban any new U.S. investment in Russia &#8212; more than 600 private sector companies.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, corporate America is stepping up, a change.&nbsp; From McDonalds to Exxon, they’ve left the Russian market on their own accord &#8212; 600 of them.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; The private businesses choosing to leave Russia rather than risk being associated with Putin’s brutal war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this ban on investment is going to make sure that new money cannot come in to Russia to replace what’s left so that the Russian economy doesn’t feel the loss &#8212; and the loss of these businesses for the long term.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, we’re adding more critical state-owned enterprises&nbsp;to the list of fully blocked Russian companies.&nbsp; These companies are major revenue generators owned by Russia and the government, which Putin uses to fund himself and enable his war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’ll also be cut off from doing any business with the United States.&nbsp; They will not be able to access or use any assets they have in the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, fourth, we, along with our European allies, are adding the names to the list of Russian elites and their families that we are sanctioning.&nbsp; Did you see these yachts we’re &#8212; that are being picked up?&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yeah!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No &#8212; no, think about it.&nbsp; Think about the &#8212; the incredible amounts of money these oligarchs have stolen.&nbsp; These yachts are a hundred &#8212; millions and millions of dollars.</p>



<p>Look, these oligarchs and their family members are not allowed to hold on to their wealth in Europe and the United States and keep these yachts worth hundreds of millions of dollars, their luxury vacation homes, while children in Ukraine are being killed, displaced from their homes every single day.</p>



<p>And, finally, we’re continuing to supply Ukraine with the weapons and resources to defend their country.&nbsp; Last Friday &#8212; (applause) &#8212; last Friday, we announced millions in funding to procure new equipment for Ukraine &#8212; advanced drones, laser-guided rocket systems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, I signed another package to send more Javelins missiles &#8212; those shoulder-mounted missiles&nbsp;that can take out tanks and armored vehicles &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to keep getting an uninterrupted supply&nbsp;to the Ukrainian military.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we won’t be able to advertise every piece of security we give because our Allies and partners are supplying to Ukraine through us, but advanced weapons and ammunition are flowing in every single day.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you may have seen yesterday on television, when the Secretary of Defense was being cross-examined by one of our &#8212; how can I say it? &#8212; our congresspersons &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; saying, “What have you done?”&nbsp; And he basically looked at him and said, “What the hell do you think we’ve done?&nbsp; Why do you think they’re able to fight?&nbsp; We’ve trained them and we’ve given them the weapons.”&nbsp; That’s what’s happening.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, thanks to the bravery, the grit, and the fight- &#8212; the fighting spirit of the Ukrainian people, Russia has already failed in its initial war aims.&nbsp; Russia wanted to take Ukraine’s capital city of Kyiv and topple its democracy and elected government.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, Kyiv still stands, and that government still presides.&nbsp; This fight is far from over.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And here’s the point: This war could continue for a long time, but the United States will continue to stand with Ukraine and the Ukrainian people in the fight for freedom.&nbsp; And I just want you to know that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, if I got to go to war, I’m going with you guys.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I’ll tell you.&nbsp; (Inaudible.) I mean it.</p>



<p>I want to talk about &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I want to talk about what I’m here today to talk about: You women or men in the American union movement remember, you know, when the Fair Labor Standards Act was first passed, everybody said you “can” have unions.&nbsp; It didn’t say that.&nbsp; It says we “should” have more unions.&nbsp; We should.&nbsp; American labor of the Building Trades Unions.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>President McGarvey.&nbsp; And, by the way, Dad, Jack &#8212; where are you, Jack?</p>



<p>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; Right in front there.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll tell you what, Dad, as they say in southern Delaware, “You done good with this boy.”&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)</p>



<p>And, you know, I just know Jack is a Philadelphia guy.&nbsp; You know why?&nbsp; He &#8212; I just asked Sean.&nbsp; I said, “Where is…”&nbsp; He said, “Well, he’s down the shore.”&nbsp; Now, if you’re from Philadelphia or Jersey, you go to “the shore.”&nbsp; If you’re from northern Delaware, you go to “the shore.”&nbsp; A little bit further south, you go to “the beach.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You go to the beach.&nbsp;&nbsp; You can always tell where someone is from.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Dad, I asked whether or not &#8212; whether or not you &#8212; like my wife Jill, who is from Philly &#8212; still talks about “Broad Street.”&nbsp; The Broad Street Run, you know?&nbsp; And &#8212; and, you know, “Jeet, yet?”&nbsp; You know?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; I had to learn to speak Philadelphian when I got married.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But, Dad, it’s an honor to meet you from a distance here.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. JACK MCGARVEY:&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look &#8212; it’s good to be with you all, and I mean that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there’s an old expression, as I said earlier: “You go home with them that brung you to the dance.”&nbsp; And you all &#8212; you folks brought me to the dance.&nbsp; And the people that brought me to the dance were union workers &#8212; not just workers, union workers: IBEW, Ironworkers, Boilermakers, Teamsters, Laborers, Bricklayers, Masons, Plumbers and Pipefitters, Painters, Plasterers, Roofers, Operating Engineers, Steel Metal Workers.&nbsp; You’re all represented in this room &#8212; and so many more who are not in the building trades that are union members across the country.</p>



<p>I want to thank you for what you did to support my election this last time out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I remember going to a guy sitting down here a little further to the right when I refused to &#8212; I wasn’t going to introduce my &#8212; my climate plan until I decided I was going to speak a guy from the IBEW because I wanted to make sure you all knew what I was doing and why it not only was good for the environment, but good for labor.&nbsp; And I sat down with that guy right there.&nbsp; And he thought about it, and he went out and he talked to other people, and you all stepped up.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I mean it sincerely: You’re probably the biggest reason why I’m standing here today.&nbsp; I’ve never forgotten not only what you’ve done for me but, more importantly, what you’ve done for this country.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’re the ones who literally built this country, and that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; And you heard it a thousand times when I was running for office, that we’re going to build this economy not from the top down anymore, but from the middle up and out.&nbsp; That’s how you build America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because we know that when the middle class does well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy are just fine.&nbsp; And that’s exactly what we’re doing.</p>



<p>And, by the way, the reason there is a middle class is because of unions.&nbsp; Unions.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Fact.&nbsp; Unions.&nbsp; That’s a fact.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s true.&nbsp; And look, it’s not only to provide a good living but what you do more than anything else &#8212; what my dad used to say &#8212; you allow people to have dignity &#8212; the dignity of their work, to be treated with respect.</p>



<p>When it comes time to rebuild the economy &#8212; before I did anything, as I said, I talked to you.&nbsp; I laid out my plan for economic growth.&nbsp; I talked with a lot of the folks sitting behind me here and others in the union movement.&nbsp; And with your help, it was a darn good plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And look at the results: Our economy created 431,000 jobs in March &#8212; (applause) &#8212; 7.9 million since I became President.&nbsp; More jobs in 14 months than any President in the history of America has ever created because of you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unemployment is down to 3, 6 &#8212; 3.6 percent from 6.4 when I took office &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment from the start of a term of a President ever recorded because of you.&nbsp; And the economy grew 5.7 percent last year &#8212; the fastest growth in 40 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know people are still hurting.&nbsp; I’m not &#8212; I’m not unaware of it.&nbsp; As my dad would say, every time that price of gas went up at the pump, guess what?&nbsp; It was a conversation at our kitchen table that mattered.&nbsp; It’d affect outcomes.&nbsp; It affected what we did.</p>



<p>But in the process, we were able to cut the deficit by $360 billion last year.&nbsp; And it’s been a long, tough stretch, but Americans are back to work.&nbsp; Our economy has gone from being on the mend to being on the move.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It started with the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; When I took office in the midst of the worst economic crisis since the Great Depression, you all remember the lines of cars stretching for miles, waiting for a box of food to be put in their trunk &#8212; not just poor folks, folks across the board waiting for that box of food.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because of the American Rescue Plan &#8212; helped 41 million Americans put food on their table.&nbsp; Because of the American Rescue Plan, we helped keep a roof over the heads of 4 million people.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>When you helped get that plan passed, 4 million people were on the verge of being evicted from their homes and apartments.&nbsp; That’s a fact, not a joke.&nbsp; Four million.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Rescue Plan put money in the pockets of hardworking Americans who, through no fault of their own, were in trouble, giving families what my dad used to call “just a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; “Just a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because of the Rescue Plan, we had the best year of state and local job growth in 20 years, adding back 467,000 jobs; and the educators, firefighters, police officers who were laid off got back on the job.&nbsp; We made a &#8212; you made a gigantic difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, because of the Rescue Plan, 320,000 construction jobs last year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; 320,000.&nbsp; You’re building America again!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I meant what I said.&nbsp; We’re the only nation in the world that’s come out of every serious problem we’ve had stronger than when we went in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there are now more construction jobs today than we had before the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A leading financial firm, Moody’s, from Wall Street, estimates that because of the Rescue Plan, 4 million more jobs were created and unemployment is 2 percent lower than it would have been had we failed to act.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, look, that wasn’t all we did to the Rescue Plan.&nbsp; We also included the law called the Butch Lewis Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; you know what it is; most people don’t &#8212; to ensure that as we rebuilt America, we upheld a promise &#8212; a promise to secure a dignified retirement for millions of workers and retirees all across America, protecting pensions you all worked so damn hard for, you sacrificed to secure.</p>



<p>And it didn’t stop there.&nbsp; Because we can’t compete for the jobs of the 21st century if we don’t fix our infrastructure.&nbsp; That’s why it was so important to pass the&nbsp;Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; You know, and now not only is it &#8220;Infrastructure Week&#8221; finally arrived, it’s infrastructure decade.&nbsp; Infrastructure decade.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, for real.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>Already &#8212; already, as all of you know, we’ve announced nearly $5 billion to improve 3,000 airports across 50 states this year.&nbsp; We’ve announced $5 billion, including $615 million this year alone so Lonnie Stephenson and the IBEW can get to work building a national network of electric vehicle charging stations &#8212; 500,000 across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve announced $4.7 billion to cap and plug hundreds of thousands of orphaned wells and gas wells spewing methane into the air, creating jobs as good as the jobs the folks who dug those wells got paid in the first place.&nbsp; Same folks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, nearly $17 billion for ports, waterways, and dams; 700 projects already announced across 50 states; $52.5 billion for highways and road repairs this year; $5.4 billion for bridges this year.&nbsp; The I-5 Bridge over the Columbia River in Washington State.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; The I-95 Bridge in West Haven, Connecticut.&nbsp; The Jefferson Highway, U.S. 61&nbsp;in East Baton Rouge Parish in Louisiana.&nbsp; The list goes on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And not only that.&nbsp; We’re getting rid of poisonous lead pipes in 10 million homes and 400,000 schools and childcare centers &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so kids and families can have drinking water that doesn’t poison them.</p>



<p>Look, folks, this is America &#8212; the United States of America.&nbsp; We’re investing $65 billion to deliver affordable high-speed Internet everywhere in America &#8212;&nbsp;urban, rural, suburban, and Tribal communities.&nbsp; You can’t be a country where a mother has to pull, with her child, up in her car to a McDonald’s parking lot to connect to an Internet so the kid can do their homework.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, think about that.&nbsp; It’s the United States of America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, this law puts an end to that and creates thousands of jobs doing it &#8212; good-paying jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, look, what this means for all of you is jobs &#8212; good-paying union jobs; jobs you can raise a family on; jobs you &#8212; can’t be outsourced.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is about more than rebuilding our infrastructure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about rebuilding our middle class.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so sick and tired.&nbsp; I was raised by a dad &#8212; not a joke &#8212; who, when things would go bad &#8212; I remember we lived in a &#8212; we weren&#8217;t poor, but we lived in a three-bedroom, split-level house with four kids and a grandpop living with us.&nbsp; And I &#8212; looking back on it, we thought it was great, but I wonder how my mom and dad thought about it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Because &#8212; and I remember one night &#8212; true story &#8212; I remember on my &#8212; my headboard with a bunk bed I was in.&nbsp; We had two sets of bunks in my &#8212; in our room.&nbsp; And one was up against the wall that divided between my mom&#8217;s bedroom and ours.&nbsp; And I could tell my dad was restless; I could hear him.&nbsp; And I asked my mom the next morning what was the matter.&nbsp; She said, “He just found out he lost insu- &#8212; we lost our insurance, honey.&nbsp; We lost our insurance.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; You &#8212; you are the ones who keep millions of people from losing their insurance.&nbsp; Unions built the middle class.&nbsp; We have to rebuild the middle class.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we made sure that the Infrastructure Law included significant labor protections.&nbsp; For example, overwhelming &#8212; the overwhelming majority of the funds included in this law are subject to Davis-Bacon requirements.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, as you may remember, when I &#8212; the &#8212; President Obama asked me to do the Recovery Act back in our administration, the previous one, we didn&#8217;t do anything you guys didn&#8217;t do.&nbsp; If they wanted the money, they had to show me that they were doing it and prevaying [sic] &#8212; paying a prevailing wage.</p>



<p>As you know, that means folks who are rebuilding the country are going to earn a prevailing wage now.&nbsp; And, by the way, the Labor Department, led by a proud former president of the Laborers’ Union 223, Marty Walsh &#8212; (applause) &#8212; good man.&nbsp; If I&#8217;m in a foxhole &#8212; if I&#8217;m in a foxhole, I want Marty next to me.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Look, he recently proposed a new regulation to strengthen prevailing wage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Another thing the law does is help expand registered apprenticeships.  Wasn&#8217;t it wonderful when businesses said, “Don’t worry, we’ll do the apprenticeships”?  Wasn’t that a great, generous thing for them to do early on?  Well, come on, man &#8212; union partnerships that allow workers to earn while they learn, that matters. </p>



<p>Because laying a strong foundation for the future of this country is about more than having strong roads and bridges, ports and airports that can compete with any in the world.&nbsp; It’s also about making sure that here, in America, folks who work hard and live their lives, they have an opportunity to live it with dignity and respect.&nbsp; That’s what unions are about, in my view &#8212; about providing dignity and respect for people who bust their neck.</p>



<p>That’s why I created the White House Task Force on Worker Organization and Empowerment to make sure the choice to join a union belongs to workers alone.&nbsp; And, by the way &#8212; (applause) &#8212; by the way: Amazon, here we come.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Watch.&nbsp; Watch.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, it’s why I’ve called on Congress to finally pass the PRO Act and send it to my desk.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And that’s why we’re strongly encouraging grantees who get infrastructure funding to use &#8212; use what we know as the project labor agreements &#8212; you know what they are; the vast majority listening to this won&#8217;t know &#8212; which helps ensure that people building major projects are well-trained, highly-skilled workers who have a voice on the work site.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, you all know why this matters.&nbsp; Union members get higher wages and benefits like healthcare and insurance and paid leave; protections against discrimination and harassment; safer, healthier workplaces.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there’s another reason &#8212; the basic American reason: Workers who join a union gain power &#8212; the power over the decisions that affect their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you’ve got a union, workers’ voices are heard and heeded.&nbsp; Unions provide, in one word, democracy in the workplace.&nbsp; Organizing, joining a union &#8212; that’s a democratic and democracy action &#8212; in action.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unions aren’t just good for the workers who join them.&nbsp;&nbsp; Rebuilding America with union labor is smart for business and the American public and for our entire country.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Union workers &#8212; and I&#8217;m not just saying because you&#8217;re sitting there, but giving you my word &#8212; you&#8217;re the best in the world at what you do &#8212; highly skilled, highly trained.&nbsp; You’ve got a voice in the workplace, a sense of ownership in the project.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When union workers are on the job, projects are completed efficiently and they&#8217;re completed professionally.&nbsp; That’s good for the American taxpayer.&nbsp; It’s good for families in every neighborhood where infrastructure projects are underway, and &#8212;</p>



<p>So we’re going to keep investing in you and your families.&nbsp; We can and we must do more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, there are nearly 1.2 million extremely qualified women who haven’t returned to the workforce.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a simple reason: There’s no affordable childcare for them.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Many families pay up to &#8212; in this city and other major cities, they pay up to $14,000 a year for one child.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I got to the Senate, as some of you know, right after I got elected in November 17 &#8212; in December 18th, after that election, I got a phone call saying my wife and daughter had just been killed.&nbsp; A tractor trailer broadsided them, and my two boys weren’t al- &#8212; weren&#8217;t supposed to make it.&nbsp; My boys did make, thank God.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the point was, everybody thinks I commuted every day because I was this good</p>



<p>father wanting to go home.&nbsp; That&#8217;s true.&nbsp; But &#8212; but I couldn&#8217;t afford daycare.&nbsp; So I had my mom and my sister and my brother &#8212; I had to do it from home.&nbsp; I had no choice.&nbsp; And I was making a good salary.&nbsp; I think, at the time, we were making $42,000 a year, which was a fair amount of money.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford childcare.&nbsp; And these women can&#8217;t afford it either.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you capped childcare, as I have proposed, at 7 percent of a family’s income making less than 125 grand a year, it could cut co- &#8212; in half the costs of childcare, saving thousands of dollars and freeing so many people to be able to go back to work, particularly these women who are totally qualified but have no alternative but to stay home.</p>



<p>Or take prescription drugs, like insulin.&nbsp; Many of you know people who have Type 1 diabetes &#8212; another reason for insulin.&nbsp; Do you know how much it costs to make that vial of insulin?&nbsp; Ten dollars &#8212; T-E-N.&nbsp; Ten dollars.</p>



<p>But you see families paying, on average, over $641 a month for that insu- &#8212; up to $1,000 a month.&nbsp; Think about those 200,000 kids out there &#8212; maybe some of your children &#8212; who have Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; Two hundred thousand.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And think about what it does to a parent who looks at their child, doesn&#8217;t have insurance, doesn&#8217;t have the cash, and wonders, &#8220;My God, what am I going to do?&nbsp; I have no idea how we&#8217;re going to pay for what we need so desperately.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It not only puts the child&#8217;s life in jeopardy, it strips you of your dignity.&nbsp; How can you look at your child, knowing they need this but there&#8217;s no way?&nbsp; You don&#8217;t qualify for it because you&#8217;re making some money, but you don&#8217;t have enough money to pay for that monthly bill.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s easy.&nbsp; We can cap insulin at $35 a month.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll still make 350 percent profit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, there’s so much more we can do if we let Medicaid be able to do what they do.&nbsp; Those of you who are veterans, they negotiate &#8212; Veterans Administration negotiates with Medicare for the pri- &#8212; for the price they charge.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a big deal.&nbsp; They still make a lot of money.</p>



<p>But what&#8217;s going on now &#8212; we can do it all without adding to inflation.&nbsp; You don’t have to believe me that &#8212; about that.&nbsp; Seventeen Nobel laureates in economics within the last six months wrote to me independently and said, &#8220;Guess what?&nbsp; If you do what you&#8217;re talking about, it will not only not increase inflation, it will reduce the impact on inflation.&#8221;</p>



<p>We can do this without raising a penny in taxes on anyone making under $400,000.&nbsp; We have to do it.&nbsp; All we have to do is ask the wealthiest Americans among us and major corporations to pay their fair share &#8212; just a little bit more.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Really.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a joke.</p>



<p>I made a commitment: No one making less than $400,000 in my administra- &#8212; while I&#8217;m President will pay a many &#8212; a penny more in taxes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I held up the passage of the &#8212; of the Infrastructure Bill.&nbsp; They wanted to add a fee for highways.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;No.&nbsp; People &#8212; ordinary people are going to be paying for that.&nbsp; I’m not for that.&#8221;&nbsp; We got to have everybody chip in and pay their fair share.</p>



<p>Look, folks, there&#8217;s no reason why someone making $10 million a year should pay a lower tax rate than a married couple who are a firefighter and a schoolteacher.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s how it works.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I mean, for real, there&#8217;s no reason why, in 2020, the 55 of the companies &#8212; Fortune 500 companies paid zero in federal income tax and they made $40 billion.&nbsp; Zero.&nbsp; Zero.</p>



<p>Look, I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; If you can go out and make a million or a billion dollars, go at it.&nbsp; But for God&#8217;s sake, chip in and pay your fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I think &#8212; you know, a lot of my friends are registered Republicans living out there.&nbsp; They think that too.&nbsp; I mean, it&#8217;s just so outrageous.&nbsp; That $2 trillion tax cut, the last guy &#8212; what was his name?&nbsp; Anyway, the last guy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I forgot it.&nbsp; He never showed up for the inauguration, but anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside &#8212; I shouldn’t kid.&nbsp; But that tax cut basically went to the top one tenth of 1 percent of the American public.&nbsp; And it didn&#8217;t grow the economy.</p>



<p>Look, the bottom line is this: The United States is in a position to outcompete the world once again.&nbsp; If we can keep coming together to invest in the backbone of America, there&#8217;s no limit to what we can achieve.</p>



<p>When I &#8212; I wasn&#8217;t going to run again, as some of you know. Some of you are my friends.&nbsp; But when I finally decided to run &#8212; and my kids encouraged it because &#8212; anyway, I won&#8217;t go into that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I finally decided to run.&nbsp; And the fact of the matter is I made a judgment that we just had to &#8212; there&#8217;s no reason why we have to keep it the way it&#8217;s been.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When&#8217;s the last time trickle-down economy has trickled anybody you know?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.</p>



<p>So, look, I said I was running for three reasons back then.&nbsp;&nbsp; One, to restore the soul of this country.&nbsp; And by that, I meant decency and honor and honesty and what we&#8217;re going to do to.&nbsp; And two, to rebuild the backbone of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; To rebuild the backbone of America, which is the middle class and working people.&nbsp; And two &#8212; and three, to try to unify the country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been the hardest thing so far.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to get there, because you can&#8217;t have a democracy function unless you can generate consensus.&nbsp; You ultimately have to unify it, as angry as I sometimes get.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, America &#8212; this is a fact: America has always counted on union workers.&nbsp; And given just half a chance, you have never, ever, ever &#8212; not a &#8212; you&#8217;ve never let the country down.&nbsp; We&#8217;re counting on you again.&nbsp; And you can count on me to keep fighting for you, I promise you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, folks, let&#8217;s continue giving working families a fighting chance.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s face the challenge ahead.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s keep building a better America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And one last thing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re announcing today an investment through the Infrastructure Law &#8212; the largest investment in public transit in American history: $20.5 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s going to accomplish two big things: create more good union jobs using products made in America and reduce pollution at the same time, while making it safer and easier for folks to get to work.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s keep going.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s keep building.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s keep it on the way.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you. And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>1:30 P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;3076</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/04/06/bill-signed-h-r-3076/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:05:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Wednesday, April 6, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3076, the &#8220;Postal Service Reform Act of 2022,&#8221; which establishes the Postal Service Health Benefits Program, repeals the prefunding requirement related to Postal retirement benefits, makes reforms to nonpostal and postal services, among other things. Thank you to Representatives Carolyn Maloney, James Comer, Virginia&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Wednesday, April 6, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3076, the &#8220;Postal Service Reform Act of 2022,&#8221; which establishes the Postal Service Health Benefits Program, repeals the prefunding requirement related to Postal retirement benefits, makes reforms to nonpostal and postal services, among other things.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Carolyn Maloney, James Comer, Virginia Foxx, Gerry Connolly, and Brenda Lawrence and Senators Gary Peters, Rob Portman, Tom Carper, Thom Tillis, and many others, for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary to the Vice President Kirsten&#160;Allen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/statement-by-press-secretary-to-the-vice-president-kirsten-allen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50683</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jamal Simmons, the Vice President’s Communications Director, tested positive for COVID-19 today. Jamal was in close contact to the Vice President as defined by CDC guidance. &#160;Jamal is&#160;isolating and working from home. The Vice President will follow CDC guidance for those that have been in close contact with a positive individual and will continue to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jamal Simmons, the Vice President’s Communications Director, tested positive for COVID-19 today. Jamal was in close contact to the Vice President as defined by CDC guidance. &nbsp;Jamal is&nbsp;isolating and working from home.</p>



<p>The Vice President will follow CDC guidance for those that have been in close contact with a positive individual and will continue to consult with her physician. The Vice President plans to continue with her public schedule.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Carol Spahn, Nominee for Director of the Peace Corps Robin Hutcheson, Nominee for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administrator, Department of Transportation Jaime Lizárraga, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission Mark Uyeda,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Carol Spahn, Nominee for Director of the Peace Corps</li><li>Robin Hutcheson, Nominee for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administrator, Department of Transportation</li><li>Jaime Lizárraga, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission</li><li>Mark Uyeda, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission</li><li>Vincent Logan, Nominee for Member of the Farm Credit Administration</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Carol Spahn, Nominee for Director of the Peace Corps</u></strong></p>



<p>Carol Spahn is serving as Chief Executive Officer of the Peace Corps, and was officially Acting Director from January 20, 2021 until November 16, 2021. Under her leadership, the agency is returning Volunteers to overseas service after being evacuated for two years due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Additionally, the agency created a domestic service initiative for only the second time in Peace Corps’ history, working with the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to support vaccination campaigns across the United States, and launched a new strategic plan which focuses on re-imagining service, advancing equity, and delivering quality. Prior to serving as Acting Director, Spahn served as Chief of Operations in the Africa Region covering Eastern and Southern Africa, and before that, served a five-year term as Country Director of Peace Corps Malawi. Her Peace Corps roots extend back to her service, with her husband, as a Volunteer from 1994 to 1996 in Romania where she served as a Small Business Advisor shortly after the fall of communism.</p>



<p>Before returning to the Peace Corps as Country Director, Spahn was Senior Vice President of Operations at Women for Women International. Prior to that, she served as Executive Director of Accordia Global Health Foundation. She also served as Vice President, Chief Financial Officer, and Treasurer of Small Enterprise Assistance Funds. Spahn has held positions at leading private sector institutions, including GE Capital and KPMG Peat Marwick. She holds a bachelor’s degree from the Catholic University of America and a master’s degree in international development from the George Washington University Elliott School of International Affairs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Robin Hutcheson, Nominee for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administrator, Department of Transportation</u></strong></p>



<p>Robin Hutcheson currently serves in the Biden-Harris Administration as the Deputy Administrator and Acting Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA). She was previously appointed as the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Safety Policy for the U.S. Department of Transportation where she led the development of the National Roadway Safety Strategy and was instrumental in the development of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, especially the new Safe Streets and Roads for All program.</p>



<p>Prior to being appointed to the Biden-Harris Administration, Hutcheson was the Director of Public Works for the City of Minneapolis, overseeing a team of 1,100 people across nine divisions including drinking water, surface waters and sewers, solid waste and recycling, fleet management, and all transportation functions. Prior to her appointment in Minneapolis, she served as the Transportation Director for Salt Lake City, UT, working to improve all modes of transportation. Hutcheson also has served as a transportation consultant, and has worked throughout the western United States, and in Europe. Hutcheson served for seven years on the Board of Directors for the National Association of City Transportation Officials (NACTO), most recently serving as its President. She received a bachelor’s degree from the University of Colorado Boulder and a master’s degree from the University of Utah.</p>



<p><a><strong><u>Jaime Lizárraga, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission</u></strong></a></p>



<p>Jaime Lizárraga currently serves as Senior Advisor to Speaker of the House Nancy Pelosi. In this role, he oversees issues relating to financial markets, housing, international financial institutions, immigration, and small business policy. He also serves as the Speaker’s liaison to the Congressional Hispanic Caucus. Throughout his 31-year public service career, Lizárraga has advised Congressional leaders and heads of executive agencies on policy and legislative strategy. He previously served on the Democratic staff of the House Financial Services Committee, and as a presidential appointee at the U.S. Department of the Treasury and the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>



<p>Lizárraga has played key roles in numerous successful legislative initiatives, including the Build Back Better Act, the American Rescue Plan, COVID relief legislation, omnibus appropriations bills, the Dream and Promise Act, the PROMESA Act, the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010, the Economic Emergency and Stabilization Act of 2008, and many others. Lizárraga graduated from the University of California, San Diego with high honors, and earned a master’s degree from the Lyndon B. Johnson School of Public Affairs at the University of Texas. The son of immigrant farm workers, Lizárraga was raised in San Diego. He lives in Virginia with his wife and five children.</p>



<p><strong><u>Mark T. Uyeda, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Mark T. Uyeda is a career attorney with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). He is currently on detail from the SEC to the U.S. Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, where he serves as Securities Counsel on the Committee’s Minority Staff. He has over 25 years of experience in corporate and securities law, including 18 years of public service working in federal and state government. Uyeda joined the SEC in 2006 and has worked in various capacities, including as Senior Advisor to Chairman Jay Clayton and Acting Chairman Michael S. Piwowar, and as Counsel to Commissioner Paul S. Atkins. He has also served as Assistant Director and Senior Special Counsel in the SEC’s Division of Investment Management. Uyeda has been recognized with multiple SEC awards, including the SEC Chairman’s Award for Excellence and the SEC Capital Markets Award. He is a past Chair of the SEC Asian Pacific American Employees Committee.</p>



<p>From 2004 to 2006, Uyeda served as Chief Advisor to the California Corporations Commissioner, the state’s securities regulator. Before entering public service, Uyeda was an attorney in private practice with O’Melveny &amp; Myers LLP in Los Angeles, and Kirkpatrick &amp; Lockhart LLP in Washington, D.C. He is a past President of the Asian Pacific American Bar Association of the Greater Washington, D.C. Area. Uyeda received his law degree with honors from Duke University and his undergraduate degree in business administration from Georgetown University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Vincent Logan, Nominee for Member of the Farm Credit Administration</u></strong></p>



<p>Vincent Logan, a member of the Osage Nation, currently serves as the Chief Financial Officer and Chief Investment Officer for the Native American Agriculture Fund (NAAF). NAAF is the largest U.S. philanthropic organization focused exclusively on the needs of Native American farmers and ranchers. Nominated by President Obama and confirmed by the U.S. Senate in 2014, Logan served as the Special Trustee for American Indians at the U.S. Department of the Interior. During his tenure, he was appointed to the Department of the Treasury’s Financial Literacy Education Commission.</p>



<p>Logan has worked in New York in both asset-based financing as a lawyer and in asset management as an investment advisor. As a lawyer, he practiced in aircraft, shipping, and equipment finance. As an investment advisor, he worked with institutional clients in developing investment policies, diversification strategies, and sovereign wealth funds. He is an Oklahoma State University Foundation Governor, Director for The Christensen Fund, and serves on the Board of Directors for the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis, Little Rock Branch. He has mentored numerous professionals, guiding them through careers in law and the securities industry. Logan was educated at Oklahoma State University, the University of Oklahoma College of Law, and the School of International and Public Affairs at Columbia University. His partner is Dr. Steven Lieberman of New Jersey.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris On Extending the Pause on Student Loan Repayment Through August 31st,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-extending-the-pause-on-student-loan-repayment-through-august-31st-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President announced that our Administration is pausing federal student loan repayments through August 31, 2022. This pause will help 41 million people keep up with their monthly bills and meet their basic needs. It will give borrowers some urgently needed time to prepare for a return to repayment.   This is personal for me.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President announced that our Administration is pausing federal student loan repayments through August 31, 2022. This pause will help 41 million people keep up with their monthly bills and meet their basic needs. It will give borrowers some urgently needed time to prepare for a return to repayment.  <br><br>This is personal for me. I had student loans. Each month, I would sit at the kitchen table, fill out paperwork, and send a check to pay down my balance. Later, as California Attorney General, I took on predatory for-profit colleges and won $1 billion for defrauded veterans and students. President Biden and I understand that student loan debt adds stress for borrowers and their families.<br><br>We have made strong progress as a country in the face of a global pandemic and an economic downturn, but there is still work to do. Today’s announcement will make a meaningful difference as we continue moving forward. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress, on Prohibiting New Investment in and Certain Services to the Russian Federation in Response to Continued Russian Federation&#160;Aggression</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/a-message-to-the-congress-on-prohibiting-new-investment-in-and-certain-services-to-the-russian-federation-in-response-to-continued-russian-federation-aggression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701&#160;et seq.), the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1601&#160;et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&#160;States Code, I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701&nbsp;<em>et seq</em>.), the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1601&nbsp;<em>et seq</em>.), and section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code, I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024 of April 15, 2021, with respect to the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States posed by specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The order prohibits the following:&nbsp;&nbsp;(i)&nbsp;new investment in the Russian Federation by a United States person, wherever located; (ii) the exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United&nbsp;States person, wherever located, of any category of services as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to any person located in the Russian Federation; and (iii)&nbsp;any approval, financing, facilitation, or guarantee by a United States person, wherever located, of a transaction by a foreign person where the transaction by that foreign person would be prohibited by this section if performed by a United States person or within the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>&nbsp;        April 6, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prohibiting New Investment in and Certain Services to the Russian Federation in Response to Continued Russian Federation&#160;Aggression</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/06/prohibiting-new-investment-in-and-certain-services-to-the-russian-federation-in-response-to-continued-russian-federation-aggression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701&#160;et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601&#160;et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&#160;States Code, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701&nbsp;<em>et seq</em>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601&nbsp;<em>et seq</em>.), and section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code,<br><br>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024 of April&nbsp;15, 2021,&nbsp;expanded by Executive Order 14066 of March 8, 2022, and relied on for additional steps taken in Executive Order 14039 of August&nbsp;20, 2021, and Executive Order 14068 of March 11, 2022, hereby order:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;Section&nbsp;1.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;The following are prohibited:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;new investment in the Russian Federation by a United States person, wherever located;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;the exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United States person, wherever located, of any category of services as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to any person located in the Russian Federation; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii)&nbsp;any approval, financing, facilitation, or guarantee by a United States person, wherever located, of a transaction by a foreign person where the transaction by that foreign person would be prohibited by this section if performed by a United States person or within the United States.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; (b)&nbsp;&nbsp;The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or license or permit granted prior to the date of this order.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;2.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;3.&nbsp;&nbsp;Nothing in this order shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the Federal Government or the United Nations (including its specialized agencies, programs, funds, and related organizations) by employees, grantees, or contractors thereof.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;4.&nbsp;&nbsp;For the purposes of this order:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;the term&nbsp;&#8220;person&#8221;&nbsp;means an individual or entity;&nbsp;and<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;the term&nbsp;&#8220;United States person&#8221;&nbsp;means any United&nbsp;States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;5.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.&nbsp;&nbsp;The&nbsp;Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.&nbsp;&nbsp;All executive departments and agencies of the United&nbsp;States shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to implement this order.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;6.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (b)&nbsp;&nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (c)&nbsp;&nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p> THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>    April 6, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on New Economic Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/06/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-new-economic-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 18:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:05 A.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining us today. So, as a quick reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call. For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:05 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining us today.</p>



<p>So, as a quick reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on the call today is [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you for some opening remarks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [moderator].&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;ll say a few things at the top, and then happy to jump into your questions.</p>



<p>The sickening brutality in Bucha has made tragically clear the despicable nature of the Putin regime.&nbsp; And today, in alignment with G7 allies and partners, we’re intensifying the most severe sanctions ever levied on a major economy.</p>



<p>All of you have seen the factsheet, so I&#8217;m going to step back and just explain the rationale for choosing these actions in the context of the five pillars that underpin our sanctions strategy.</p>



<p>So, number one, as all of you know, we’ve sought to generate a financial shock by cutting off Russia’s largest banks and its central bank from doing any business with the U.S. and freezing any of its assets that touch the U.S. financial system or those of our allies.</p>



<p>And today, we’re dramatically escalating the financial shock by imposing full blocking sanctions on Russia’s largest financial institution, Sberbank, and its largest private bank, Alfa Bank.</p>



<p>Sberbank is the main artery in the Russian financial system.&nbsp; By itself, it holds nearly one third of Russia’s total banking sector assets; that&#8217;s over $500 billion.&nbsp; That’s roughly twice the size of the second-largest Russian bank, which we previously fully blocked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in total, we’ve now fully blocked more than two thirds of the Russian banking sector, which, before the invasion, held $1.4 trillion in assets.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, we said we would cut off cutting-edge exports to Russia to disable Putin’s military and deny him the ability to diversify and modernize his economy.</p>



<p>So, today, in alignment with the G7 and the EU, we&#8217;re announcing a ban on new investment in Russia, which President Biden will implement with an executive order.&nbsp; And this will make sure that the mass exodus from Russia that we’re seeing from the private sector, which is now over 600 multinational companies and growing &#8212; that it will endure.</p>



<p>And without investment from our private sector, Putin will lose private sector know-how and skills that travel with investment, and the knock-on effects to the ongoing brain drain from Russia will be profound.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, we&#8217;ve said we&#8217;re methodically ejecting Russia from the international economic order to deny the privileges and benefits it once enjoyed, such as its most-favored-nation trading status, its borrowing privileges from the IMF and the World Bank.</p>



<p>And in that spirit, on Monday we cut off Russia’s ability to use its frozen central bank funds to make debt payments.&nbsp; And so, Russia will now have to find new sources of dollars from outside the U.S. and to find a new payment route, other than U.S. banks, to avoid falling into default. &nbsp;And that&#8217;s Russia&#8217;s choice as to how it proceeds.</p>



<p>And of course, even if Russia taps into other sources of hard currency to remain current on its debt obligations, that will translate into fewer resources available to Putin to fund his war machine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fourth, we’ve said we’d degrade Russia’s status as a leading energy supplier and thereby cut off its largest source of export and budget revenue.&nbsp; We’ve done that previously by banning U.S. imports of Russian oil, gas, and coal; by working with the Germans and the EU to shut down Nord Stream 2; and by cutting off energy technologies that Russia needs to sustain its oil and gas production.</p>



<p>And today, just as a preview, you’ll hear more from the EU on their efforts to take this a step further.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lastly, we said we’d expose Russia’s kleptocracy and show that Putin and his cronies have been ripping off the Russian people for decades.&nbsp; Already, before today, we had sanctioned more than 140 oligarchs and their family members, and over 400 Russian government officials.&nbsp; These are the key architects of the war.</p>



<p>And today, we’re sanctioning Putin’s adult children, Minister Lavrov’s wife and his daughter, and members of Russia’s Security Council.</p>



<p>In terms of impact &#8212; and we can get into this in the questions if you&#8217;d like &#8212; I mean, as all of you have seen, these sanctions are generating the impact we warned Putin about for months prior to the invasion.&nbsp; Russia&#8217;s GDP is projected to shrink by double digits this year.&nbsp; And to put that in perspective, that’s more than twice the contraction it suffered after it defaulted in 1998.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But unlike then, when Russia was in the process of getting integrated into the global economy, it’s now in the process of being isolated as a pariah state.</p>



<p>The economic shock this year alone is projected by the IEF to wipe out the past 15 years of economic gains.  Russia used to be the 11th-largest economy in the world.  It&#8217;s now very likely to drop out of the top 20. </p>



<p>Inflation: The latest print this week was that inflation in Russia is already above 15 percent and projected to hit 20 percent or more.&nbsp; Interest rates in Russia are already 20 percent.</p>



<p>And so, this combination of sky-high inflation and interest rates will cripple Russia&#8217;s long-term growth potential and so will the exit of the more than 600 companies that I referenced earlier. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And the sad reality is Putin&#8217;s war will make it harder for Russians to travel abroad. &nbsp;It means their debit cards may not work. &nbsp;They may only have the option to buy knockoff phones and knockoff clothes.&nbsp; The shelves at stores may be empty. &nbsp;The reality is the country is descending into economic and financial and technological isolation. &nbsp;And at this rate, it will go back to Soviet-style living standards from the 1980s.</p>



<p>But look, don&#8217;t take my word for it: Putin himself has said the sanctions will require deep structural changes to the Russian economy to deal with the new realities, including inflation and unemployment.&nbsp; Minister Lavrov has said “no one could have predicted” the central bank actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They simply weren&#8217;t prepared for their economic fortress to crumble. &nbsp;And that&#8217;s what&#8217;s happened.</p>



<p>Let me stop there and take your questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Could we cue up the directions to ask a question please?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q    Thanks for doing this.  My question is about India.  You were [redacted], and that&#8217;s been reported on extensively.  Where does India stand on the second set of sanctions?  And how far have they come towards convergence on the U.S. view regarding the sanctions (inaudible) applied?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; You know, India is our friend; India is our partner.&nbsp; And we share &#8212; we share interests, and we share core principles that are at stake in this conflict.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve had extensive discussions about ways to further our cooperation on global food security, on global energy supplies, and certainly in terms of recognizing that Putin&#8217;s brutality affects all of us.&nbsp; And the geopolitical implications of Russia&#8217;s actions do have ripple effects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we &#8212; India is not part of the G7.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a guest country this year.&nbsp; So, we will certainly collaborate with India and share the details of our measures.&nbsp; And, of course, we remain hopeful that we can have alignment to the maximum extent possible.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering if you could clarify on Putin&#8217;s adult children.&nbsp; Are you sanctioning his two daughters, Mariya Putina and Katerina Tikhonova?&nbsp; Or are there any additional children that you have identified that you are applying sanctions to?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, you’ve got it right.&nbsp; Those are the two.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thank you for taking our questions.&nbsp; Can you speak a little bit more about these full blocking sanctions come on the major SOEs that are coming tomorrow?&nbsp; Is that, sort of like, all major SOEs or a certain major?&nbsp; Are there particular sectors?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So these are not all Russian SOEs.&nbsp; And they will not be energy &#8212; they will not be SOEs in the energy sector.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll hear more from Treasury tomorrow on the specific institutions, and that will likely come later today or tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I wanted to just ask if you could say whether you saw, currently, that China is complying with sanctions that you&#8217;ve implemented so far, and what the thinking is on applying secondary sanctions to Chinese or other foreign companies or entities.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So as I think everyone is aware, we&#8217;ve had a series of private consultations, going up to the highest level of our government and China&#8217;s government, about the importance of respecting the sanctions regime that we’ve put in place as well as the export controls.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have anything new to tell you, other than we&#8217;ve been really clear about the consequences of any efforts to circumvent or backfill those sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;ve seen, I think, in the public rhetoric from China that they&#8217;re not, openly at least, indicating any intention to do so.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re watching that very closely.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing this call.&nbsp; Can you tell us whether you think these sanctions and all the impact on Russia will actually stop Russia&#8217;s military advances given the projection to Congress yesterday from General Milley that this war could last years?&nbsp; And Vladimir Putin &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t seem signs of slowing down.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think &#8212; yeah, thanks, Andrea.&nbsp; I mean, I&#8217;ll say it this way: I mean, sanctions are never a standalone solution.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t impose these costs as an end to themselves.&nbsp; And, you know, in our judgment, sanctions work when they&#8217;re embedded in a broader strategy, and you referenced this.&nbsp; It has to &#8212; these sanctions have to work alongside doing all we can to support Ukraine&#8217;s fight for freedom.&nbsp; They work alongside doing all we can to help the rest of the world deal with the spillovers of Putin&#8217;s war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve surged supplies of energy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why we&#8217;re coming together to welcome the millions of refugees that are fleeing Ukraine, and trying to come together with the rest of the world to deal with the disruptions to global food supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if we execute on all those fronts &#8212; and that&#8217;s our that&#8217;s our plan; that&#8217;s our strategy &#8212; that&#8217;s how we create staying power in these sanctions.&nbsp; And staying the course is how we think we’ll create leverage for the outcome that we&#8217;re seeking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’ll &#8212; let me add one more point on the sanctions impact: I mean, even an autocrat like Putin has a social contract with the Russian people.&nbsp; He took away their freedom in exchange for promising stability.&nbsp; And so he&#8217;s not giving them stability at the moment; he&#8217;s giving them instability and insecurity, and he&#8217;s imposing that upon them.&nbsp; And at some point, that ought to matter to any leader if only because they care about staying in power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the question really is not so much, “What can we do and when will that have an effect?”&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s, “What&#8217;s the endgame here for Putin?&nbsp; What&#8217;s he playing for?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is very clearly becoming a failure for him.&nbsp; And at some point, he will have to recognize that reality.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Earlier, you mentioned that you have worked with senior Chinese officials regarding those sanctions.&nbsp; Do you also find that China is also learning how United States and allies are using the financial sanctions right now and possibly find ways to counter those measures in the future if, one day, China has to face similar sanctions?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, I think, you know, China has become &#8212; has gained an economic prominence by engaging with the world, by integrating itself with the global economy and with the global financial system.</p>



<p>And the United States &#8212; because of the quality of our financial markets, the transparency of our regulations, the effectiveness of our corporate governance, and really the soft power that we’ve enjoyed for decades and decades &#8212; is the central player in the global financial system.&nbsp; And so we will remain integrated with China as long as it continues to engage with the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, that’s the way in which we have leverage with financial sanctions.&nbsp; And we don’t use that leverage in an arbitrary way.&nbsp; We use that leverage when we’re defending a core international principle.&nbsp; And that’s certainly what’s going on in the crisis in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re using these sanctions because we want to demonstrate resolve and say, “You can’t redraw your neighbors’ borders at the barrel of a gun.&nbsp; You can’t subjugate their free will.&nbsp; Countries have the right to set their own course and choose their own destiny.”&nbsp; That’s &#8212; those are the conditions in which we use these sanctions.&nbsp; We know how severe they are.&nbsp; And our message to China is: We hope you respect those principles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you guys for doing the call.&nbsp; I just had a more, sort of, technical question.&nbsp; Could you clarify specifically the sanctions that are being placed on Sberbank: how those differ or what is being done, compared to what had already been put on them earlier this month?&nbsp; I&#8217;m just unclear on that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And thanks for asking that, because previously we had imposed what are called “dollar-clearing prohibition” with Sberbank, which meant that any transactions that Sberbank tried to undertake with a U.S. financial institution using dollars would not be allowed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So now, this is a full blocking sanction, which means that any transaction in any currency with a U.S. person or a U.S. institution is prohibited, and also any of Sberbank’s assets that touch the U.S. financial system are now frozen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a much more severe action.&nbsp; This is the most severe action we can take in terms of financial measures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in practice, the history of sanctions show us that when we impose a full blocking sanction on a financial institution, that the rest of the world, even in other jurisdictions that have not yet imposed a full blocking sanction, they respect the regime and so there tends to be a multiplier effect.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we expect to happen here as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, thank you.&nbsp; And to be clear, there&#8217;s no carve-outs there?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I should have said there is a carve-out for energy, yes.&nbsp; Just like the other full block &#8212; full blocking sanctions.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the same carve-out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks very much.&nbsp; I was wondering if there has been discussion of the downside effects of so detaching the Russians from the global economy that their investment in it over the long term basically becomes so diminished that they become more interested in disruptive action than any hope that they would get back in?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, I mean, I would say this, David &#8212; is the sanctions are designed to be quite flexible.&nbsp; We can escalate and we can de-escalate depending on the circumstances.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but really, the way to think of it, if you want a metaphor, it&#8217;s a negative feedback loop.&nbsp; So, we deny capital, we deny technology, we deny talent that can flow into Russia.&nbsp; And the combination of the steps that we&#8217;re taking create this downward spiral that accelerates the more that Putin escalates.</p>



<p>And if he were to change course, someday, that negative feedback loop would slow and could possibly reverse.&nbsp; None of this is permanent. &nbsp;The only aspect that&#8217;s permanent are the lives that he&#8217;s taken away, and he can never bring those back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the sanctions &#8212; the sanctions are designed to be able to respond to the conditions on the ground and to create leverage for the outcome we seek.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks again for doing the call.&nbsp; About the sanctions against Putin&#8217;s daughters: Are these symbolic sanctions or do you have reason to believe that they do have assets either in the U.S. or in Europe?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, we have reason to believe that Putin and many of his cronies and the oligarchs hide their wealth, hide their assets with family members, that place their assets and their wealth in the U.S. financial system but also many other parts of the world.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the coordination &#8212; the coordinated effort to freeze their assets and seize their physical luxury goods &#8212; their cars, their yachts, their homes, et cetera &#8212; that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that we act together.</p>



<p>But to answer your question directly: Yes, we believe that many of Putin&#8217;s assets are hidden with family members, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re targeting them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; So, thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Given the call is ending a little bit earlier than 10:30, we&#8217;re going to go ahead and lift the embargo on the factsheet as well.&nbsp; So, now that the call has ended, you know, both the content of the call and the factsheet embargo will lift.</p>



<p>And as a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; So, thanks, everyone, for joining.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>10:25 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
