<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 17:09:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Maximizing Assistance to Respond to&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/01/memorandum-on-maximizing-assistance-to-respond-to-covid-19-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY               THE ADMINISTRATOR OF THE FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, 42 U.S.C. 5121–5207 (the &#8220;Stafford Act&#8221;), I hereby&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY</p>



<p>              THE ADMINISTRATOR OF THE FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, 42 U.S.C. 5121–5207 (the &#8220;Stafford Act&#8221;), I hereby order as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to combat and respond to the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic with the full capacity and capability of the Federal Government to protect and support our families, schools, and businesses, and to assist State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments to do the same, including through emergency and disaster assistance available from the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and through Federal support of the Governors&#8217; use of the National Guard.</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Assistance for Category B COVID-19 Emergency Protective Measures.&nbsp; FEMA shall provide a 100 percent Federal cost share for all work eligible for assistance under Public Assistance Category B, pursuant to sections 403 (42 U.S.C. 5170b), 502 (42 U.S.C. 5192), and 503 (42 U.S.C. 5193) of the Stafford Act, including work described in section 3(a) of the Presidential Memorandum of January 21, 2021 (Memorandum to Extend Federal Support to Governors&#8217; Use of the National Guard to Respond to COVID-19 and to Increase Reimbursement and Other Assistance Provided to States), and in section 2 of that memorandum on the Governors&#8217; use of the National Guard, performed from January 20, 2020, through July 1, 2022.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (c)&nbsp; This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (d)&nbsp; The Administrator of FEMA is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Supporting Veterans Experiencing Financial Hardship and Addressing the Harmful Effects of Military Environmental&#160;Exposures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-supporting-veterans-experiencing-financial-hardship-and-addressing-the-harmful-effects-of-military-environmental-exposures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President believes that our Nation has a sacred obligation– to properly prepare and equip the troops we send into harm’s way, and to care for them and their families when they return home. Far too often military service comes with a cost, and we owe it to our veterans and their families to address&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President believes that our Nation has a sacred obligation– to properly prepare and equip the troops we send into harm’s way, and to care for them and their families when they return home. Far too often military service comes with a cost, and we owe it to our veterans and their families to address the consequences comprehensively. This means helping veterans build lives of opportunity when they leave military service by helping them to find employment, providing pathways to home ownership, and providing financial support and relief for those who are struggling.</p>



<p>Our veterans are the best of America and supporting the women and men who wear the uniform is a commitment that unites all of us. Throughout history, Democrats and Republicans have been working together to ensure access to world-class health care and benefits for our veterans. And, while our nation’s longest war is over, our commitment to support our veteran continues.</p>



<p>To honor those who have worn the uniform of the United States, and to ensure we address the needs of veterans in financial hardship or those who have encountered environmental hazards, the Biden-Harris Administration is:</p>



<p><strong><u>Reducing Financial Hardship</u></strong></p>



<p>The President’s American Rescue Plan provided $17 billion to help veterans, ensuring the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) had funding to provide health care services for veterans, including funding for homelessness programs, and to implement a rapid retraining assistance program to help veterans impacted by the pandemic. The American Rescue Plan also eliminated all out-of-pocket medical cost for veterans and provided much needed financial relief to veterans experiencing economic hardship during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Veterans in financial hardship who get treatment through VA are entitled to get their medical debt forgiven. But currently, they can only apply for that medical debt relief through a complex, paper form with complicated eligibility requirements. Veterans may be deterred from applying for much-needed relief because the application process is too confusing and time-consuming. To address this barrier, today the President is announcing that VA is:</p>



<p><strong>Simplifying the process for claiming medical debt forgiveness. </strong>VA will streamline the request process and set a simple income threshold for receiving medical debt relief. The request process will include an online option for veterans and reduce the effort required by veterans to access relief. These changes will go into effect in the next 90 to 120 days. This change comes on top of the approximately $1 billion in medical debt the VA has already forgiven for veterans under the American Rescue Plan, which eliminated all out-of-pocket medical cost for veterans and provided much needed financial relief to veterans experiencing economic hardship during the COVID-19 pandemic. It also comes on top of a <a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5758">final rule</a> VA issued in February 2022, under which it will virtually cease reporting unfavorable debt, including medical debt, to consumer reporting agencies.</p>



<p><strong><u>Addressing Harmful Effects of Environmental Exposures</u></strong></p>



<p>Too often, military service results in increased health risks and other consequences for our veterans. Some of these injuries and illnesses may take years to manifest. Some are visible and some are invisible. This can make it difficult for veterans to prove in-service exposure and establish a direct connection for disabilities resulting from military environmental exposures such as burn pits.</p>



<p>To mitigate the difficulty in establishing entitlement to benefits, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) has established the presumption of exposure and service connection for various chronic conditions when the evidence of a military environmental exposure and the associated health risks are strong in the aggregate but hard to prove on an individual basis.</p>



<p>To further advance efforts to address the harmful effects of exposures during military service, the Biden-Harris Administration is:</p>



<p><strong>Proposing to establish presumption for rare respiratory cancers.</strong> Based on a focused review of scientific and medical evidence related to exposure to fine particulate matter and the subsequent development of rare respiratory cancers, the Secretary of VA plans to propose a rule that will add presumptive service connection for several rare respiratory cancers for certain veterans. These cancers under consideration include squamous cell carcinoma (SCC) of the larynx, SCC of the trachea, adenocarcinoma of the trachea, salivary gland-type tumors of the trachea, adenosquamous carcinoma of the lung, large cell carcinoma of the lung, salivary gland-type tumors of the lung, sarcomatoid carcinoma of the lung and typical and atypical carcinoid of the lung.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting legislation to better care for veterans with environmental exposures</strong>. TheAdministration strongly supports ongoing legislative efforts to expand access to health care services and benefits for veterans impacted by environmental exposures. We are committed to ensuring we are able to quickly and fairly recognize additional presumptions of service-connected disabilities by modernizing the processes for evaluating the relationship between exposure and health outcomes. The President looks forward to signing legislation that addresses the toxic legacy of environmental exposures sustained by veterans during their military service.</p>



<p>These actions build on ongoing efforts the Administration is taking to ensure timely access to services and benefits for veterans who experience service connected disabilities from military environmental exposures, including:</p>



<p><strong>Processing claims for new presumptive conditions.</strong>&nbsp;In August, VA began processing disability claims for asthma, rhinitis, and sinusitis based on presumed exposure to particulate matter. Veterans who served in the Southwest Asia theater of operations and other areas and who developed these conditions within 10 years of military service are now eligible to apply for disability benefits and access to VA health care. This rulemaking was based upon application of the new presumptive model and involved careful review of a study conducted by the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine, as well as other evidence assessed by VA subject matter experts.<strong> </strong>Since August, VA has completed 16,537 claims, granting over 12,000 veterans and their survivors benefits for one or more conditions, leading to over $36 million in retroactive benefit payments. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Applying a new model to review evidence of service connection for constrictive bronchiolitis</strong>. VA continues to test and refine a new decision-making framework to determine whether to establish presumptions of service connection based on exposure to military environmental hazards during active military service and other purposes. The new model is evidence-based, transparent, and allows VA to make faster policy decisions on crucial exposure issues. This new model will fundamentally change how VA makes decisions on environmental exposures. VA continues to test the model, solicit feedback from internal and external stakeholders, and evaluate its effectiveness. <strong></strong></p>



<p><strong>Raising awareness of VA benefits related to military exposures.&nbsp;</strong>Many veterans were unaware of their eligibility for benefits and services related to potential military exposures. In addition, some claims adjudicators may not have up-to-date awareness of recent policies related to conditions newly presumed to be service-connected.&nbsp;Beginning in November 2021, VA launched a proactive campaign to inform and encourage veterans to file claims related to military environmental exposures. In December 2021, military environmental exposures were featured in the VA Benefits Newsletter, reaching nearly 5 million subscribers. VA continues to share information via its social media platforms weekly.</p>



<p><strong>Requiring training for VA and non-VA providers. </strong>Veterans often find that their providers and compensation and pension examiners are not well-trained to understand or treat veterans’ exposure concerns. To address this, VA directed compensation and pension providers and Veterans Health Administration clinicians to complete a training module on assessing deployment related to environmental exposures. This is the first module in a series of five essential trainings. VA is also encouraging all providers who care for veterans outside of VA through the Community Care Network contract to complete training on the TRAIN Learning Network, VA’s publicly available training site. Furthermore, VA employees and community care providers have been directed to utilize the Exposure Ed App to help providers provide information to Veterans on health effects associated with certain exposures during military service. More information on the app is available <a href="https://mobile.va.gov/app/exposure-ed">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Implementing a network of specialized providers and call center.</strong> Veterans with concerns about the health outcomes of military exposures experience inconsistent care to address these specific issues, especially outside of VA. Earlier this year, VA launched VET-HOME, The Veterans Exposure Team-Health Outcomes of Military Exposures. VA plans to hire a total of 73 health professionals, including physicians, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants who will specialize in conducting patient assessments regarding the health effects of military exposures. By January 2023, VA expects to have a fully operational call center and network of experts to help veterans concerned about environmental exposure and provide consultative services to veterans in primary care clinics.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Read Across America Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/01/a-proclamation-on-read-across-america-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reading ignites imagination, insight, and inspiration.  It nourishes a child&#8217;s creativity and curiosity, and inspires a passion for lifelong learning.  Books can challenge and inspire.  They can teach important lessons, reveal new worlds, and enrich our understanding of our own &#8212; of different people, perspectives, and cultures.  On Read Across America Day, we celebrate the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Reading ignites imagination, insight, and inspiration.  It nourishes a child&#8217;s creativity and curiosity, and inspires a passion for lifelong learning.  Books can challenge and inspire.  They can teach important lessons, reveal new worlds, and enrich our understanding of our own &#8212; of different people, perspectives, and cultures.  On Read Across America Day, we celebrate the joy of learning and give thanks to the parents, caregivers, educators, librarians, authors, and community members who invest in our Nation&#8217;s children. </p>



<p>For many young Americans, the path to literacy begins with treasured and timeless traditions:&nbsp; being read to at bedtime, gathering in classrooms for story time, and attending events at local libraries with family and friends.&nbsp; Children&#8217;s classics such as Dr. Seuss&#8217; &#8220;Green Eggs and Ham&#8221; and &#8220;Oh, the Places You&#8217;ll Go!&#8221; have inspired a passion for reading and endless creativity that spans generations. &nbsp;Today&#8217;s stories and adventures are as diverse as the world in which we live, and by reading them, we come to more fully understand the vibrant diversity of our Nation &#8212; and the world.&nbsp; This is especially important as young people learn and grow and engage with their own sense of identity.&nbsp; Books build each child&#8217;s sense of belonging and can help inculcate respect and empathy for others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The First Lady, a lifelong educator, has said, &#8220;reading is the foundation of all education.  It affects every aspect of our society.&#8221;  This has never been truer than today.  It is one of the many reasons why my Administration is committed to advancing educational excellence for every child and literacy for every American.  It is why I have proposed making 2 years of high-quality preschool available to every child in America.  It is one of the reasons why safely reopening schools for in-person instruction was a priority for my Administration from day one &#8212; so that children could get back to learning in the classroom with their peers &#8212; and why the American Rescue Plan included $122 billion to keep schools open safely and help address the learning loss and mental health impacts of missing school.  School districts across the country are already using these funds to support literacy efforts by updating curricula and hiring specialists.</p>



<p>My Administration is also committed to supporting volunteer and literacy programs that help young people and adults master reading.&nbsp; This work is crucial, as half of adults in the United&nbsp;States are unable to read a book written for the eighth-grade level, and nearly a quarter of American adults have not read a book over the last year.</p>



<p>I often say that children are the kite strings that keep our National ambitions aloft.&nbsp; On Read Across America Day, we dedicate ourselves to helping each new generation of readers and thinkers become the leaders who will write a more hopeful chapter in the American narrative and in the story of our shared world.&nbsp; As the great American writer Toni Morrison reminds us:&nbsp; &#8220;If you find a book you really want to read but it hasn&#8217;t been written yet, then you must write it.&#8221;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2, 2022, as Read Across America Day.&nbsp; I call upon children, families, educators, librarians, public officials, and all the people of the United States to observe this day with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Coordinated IEA Release to Support Global Energy&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-coordinated-iea-release-to-support-global-energy-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 16:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s announcement is another example of partners around the world condemning Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and working together to address the impact of President Putin’s war of choice. President Biden was clear from the beginning that all tools are on the table to protect American businesses and consumers, including from rising prices&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s announcement is another example of partners around the world condemning Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and working together to address the impact of President Putin’s war of choice. President Biden was clear from the beginning that all tools are on the table to protect American businesses and consumers, including from rising prices at the pump.<br> <br>After intensive around-the-clock coordination and consultation by President Biden, the Administration and our Allies and partners, the International Energy Agency (IEA) Member countries, supported by the European Commission, agreed to a collective release of an initial 60 million barrels of crude oil from our strategic petroleum reserves. As part of this agreement, President Biden will authorize the Department of Energy to release 30 million barrels from the U.S. Strategic Petroleum Reserve.<br> <br>IEA Member countries also agreed to continue monitoring markets and consider further releases as necessary. We are prepared to use every tool available to us to limit disruption to global energy supply as a result of President Putin’s actions. We will also continue our efforts to accelerate diversification of energy supplies away from Russia and to secure the world from Moscow’s weaponization of oil and gas.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Announce Strategy to Address Our National Mental Health Crisis, As Part of Unity Agenda in his First State of the&#160;Union</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-announce-strategy-to-address-our-national-mental-health-crisis-as-part-of-unity-agenda-in-his-first-state-of-the-union/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In his first State of the Union, the President will outline a unity agenda consisting of policy where there has historically been support from both Republicans and Democrats, and call on Congress to send bills to his desk to deliver progress for the American people.&#160; As part of this unity agenda, he will announce a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In his first State of the Union, the President will outline a unity agenda consisting of policy where there has historically been support from both Republicans and Democrats, and call on Congress to send bills to his desk to deliver progress for the American people.&nbsp; As part of this unity agenda, he will announce a strategy to address our national mental health crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our country faces an unprecedented mental health crisis among people of all ages. Two out of five adults <a href="https://www.kff.org/report-section/the-implications-of-covid-19-for-mental-health-and-substance-use-issue-brief/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">report </a>symptoms of anxiety or depression. And, Black and Brown communities are <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2767308">disproportionately</a><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2767308" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> </a>undertreated – even as their burden of mental illness has continued to rise. Even before the pandemic, rates of depression and anxiety were inching <a href="https://www.apa.org/pubs/journals/releases/abn-abn0000410.pdf">higher</a>. But the grief, trauma, and physical isolation of the last two years have driven Americans to a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/12/24/collective-trauma-public-outbursts/">breaking point</a>.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our youth have been particularly impacted as losses from COVID and disruptions in routines and relationships have led to increased social isolation, anxiety, and learning loss.&nbsp; More than half of parents <a href="https://www.psychiatry.org/newsroom/news-releases/new-apa-poll-shows-sustained-anxiety-among-americans-more-than-half-of-parents-are-concerned-about-the-mental-well-being-of-their-children">express</a> concern over their children’s mental well-being. An <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/education/our-insights/covid-19-and-education-the-lingering-effects-of-unfinished-learning">early study</a> has found that students are about five months behind in math and four months behind in reading, compared with students prior to the pandemic. In 2019, one in three high school students and half of female students <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchhstp/dear_colleague/2020/dcl-102320-YRBS-2009-2019-report.html">reported</a> persistent feelings of sadness or hopelessness, an overall increase of 40 percent from 2009. Emergency department <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/07/science/pandemic-adolescents-depression-anxiety.html">visits</a> for attempted suicide have risen 51 percent among adolescent girls.<br>&nbsp;<br>This youth mental health crisis has been accentuated by large social media platforms, which for years have been conducting a national experiment on our children and using their data to keep them clicking—with enormous consequences. While technology platforms have improved our lives in some ways, there is <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-youth-mental-health-advisory.pdf">mounting evidence</a> that social media is harmful to many kids’ and teens’ mental health, well-being, and development. As the Surgeon-General has <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-youth-mental-health-advisory.pdf">said</a>, “when not deployed responsibly and safely, these tools can pit us against each other, reinforce negative behaviors like bullying and exclusion, and undermine the safe and supportive environments young people need and deserve.” In the State of the Union, the President will call on Congress to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children, and demand technology companies stop collecting personal data on our children.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden is laying out a vision to transform how mental health is understood, perceived, accessed, treated, and integrated – in and out of health care settings. The American Rescue Plan laid the groundwork, providing critical investments to expand access to mental health services. Now, far more is needed to ensure that everyone who needs help can access care when and where they seek it.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is announcing a national mental health strategy to strengthen system capacity, connect more Americans to care, and create a continuum of support –transforming our health and social services infrastructure to address mental health holistically and equitably.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Strengthen System Capacity</u></strong><br>At the center of our national mental health crisis is a severe <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/best-states/articles/2021-06-10/northeastern-states-have-fewest-mental-health-provider-shortages">shortage</a> of behavioral health providers. More than one-third of Americans live in designated <a href="https://data.hrsa.gov/topics/health-workforce/shortage-areas">Mental Health Professional Shortage Areas</a>, communities that have fewer mental health providers than the minimum their level of population would need. Even outside of these shortage areas, the fragmentation of the current system makes it hard for mental health providers to meet people where they are. We must dramatically expand the supply, diversity, and cultural competency of our mental health and substance use disorder workforce – from psychiatrists to psychologists, peers to paraprofessionals – and increase both opportunity and incentive for them to practice in areas of highest need.&nbsp; Our crisis response infrastructure must also be strengthened to ensure that those facing acute behavioral health challenges can be seamlessly connected to necessary services.&nbsp; We will:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in proven programs that bring providers into behavioral health.</strong>&nbsp; The President’s FY23 budget will invest $700 million in programs – like the National Health Service Corps, Behavioral Health Workforce Education and Training Program, and the Minority Fellowship Program – that provide training, access to scholarships and loan repayment to mental health and substance use disorder clinicians committed to practicing in rural and other underserved communities. These major new investments will both expand the pipeline of behavioral health providers and improve their geographic distribution to target areas with the greatest unmet need.</li><li><strong>Pilot new approaches to train a diverse group of paraprofessionals</strong>.&nbsp; Doctors, nurses, and other clinicians cannot do this work alone.&nbsp; In the fall of 2022, HHS expects to award over $225 million in training programs to increase the number of community health workers and other health support workers providing services, including behavioral health support, in underserved communities. The President’s FY23 budget will also propose major new multi-year funding to develop provider capacity and support mental health transformation.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Build a national certification program for peer specialists.&nbsp; </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration will convene stakeholders, launch development, and support implementation of a national certified peer specialist certification program, which will accelerate universal adoption, recognition, and integration of the peer mental health workforce across all elements of the health care system.<br></li><li><strong>Promote the mental well-being of our frontline health workforce. </strong>Three-quarters of frontline health care workers <a href="http://https:/mhanational.org/pandemic-taking-dangerous-toll-mental-health-frontline-healthcare-workers">report</a> burnout, while more than half say they lack adequate supports to cope. The Administration has already <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/07/16/hhs-announces-103-million-arp-funding-to-address-health-workforce-burnout.html">dedicated</a> $103 million in American Rescue Plan funding to address burnout and strengthen resiliency among health care workers. The President will strengthen this commitment by signing the bipartisan Dr. Lorna Breen Health Care Provider Protection Act into law, which will invest $135 million over three years into training health care providers on suicide prevention and behavioral health while launching an awareness campaign to address stigmatization, promote help-seeking and self-care among this workforce. In addition, HHS will continue grant programs to support health systems and provider groups to prevent burnout, relieve workplace stressors, administer stress first aid, and increase access to high-quality mental health care for the frontline health care workforce.<br></li><li><strong>Launch the “988” crisis response line and strengthen community-based crisis response.</strong>&nbsp; This summer, HHS will launch the <a href="https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/current-events/the-lifeline-and-988/">988</a> mental health crisis service hotline, which will create a national network of local crisis centers fortified by national back up centers to answer calls and texts. Through the American Rescue Plan, the Administration has provided $180 million to support local capacity to answer crisis calls, and establish more community-based mobile crisis response and crisis stabilizing facilities to minimize unnecessary emergency department visits. The President’s FY23 budget will build on this investment with an additional nearly $700 million to staff up and shore up local crisis centers while also building out the broader crisis care continuum: someone to call, someone to respond, and somewhere for every American in crisis to go.<br></li><li><strong>Expand the availability of evidence-based community mental health services.</strong> The American Rescue Plan invested millions of dollars to expand Certified Community Behavioral Health Clinics (CCBHCs), a proven model of care that has been <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/reports/preliminary-cost-quality-findings-national-evaluation-certified-community-behavioral-health-clinic-0">shown</a> to improve health outcomes while lowering costs, by delivering 24/7 mental health and substance use care to millions of Americans, no matter who they are or whether they’re able to pay. The President’s FY23 budget will build on this down payment, by proposing to make this program permanent while granting states funding to expand CCBHCs for the communities that need them most. The President’s budget will also permanently extend funding for Community Mental Health Centers, which provide essential mental health services to vulnerable communities that would otherwise lack access.<br></li><li><strong>Invest in research on new practice models</strong>.&nbsp;&nbsp; New scientific and technological innovation has the opportunity to expand our capacity to meet American’s mental health needs, but there is a pressing need for research to validate what works and build a robust evidence base. The President’s FY23 budget will call for investing $5 million in research into promising models for treating mental health conditions.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Connect Americans to Care</strong><br>Less than half of Americans with mental health conditions <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/10/cost-and-accessibility-of-mental-health-care-in-america.htm">receive</a> treatment. The average delay from the onset of mental health symptoms to treatment is <a href="https://www.nami.org/mhstats">11 years</a>.&nbsp; Too often, <a href="https://www.apa.org/monitor/2020/07/datapoint-care">costs</a> prevent people from accessing care far. At the same time, those with mental illness are <a href="https://www.psychiatry.org/patients-families/stigma-and-discrimination">often</a> misunderstood, mistreated, mislabeled, and misdirected to services. It is imperative that we promote better pathways to care and make it as easy as possible for all Americans with behavioral health needs – including common and pervasive conditions like anxiety and depression – to access the resources that will improve their well-being. We must fight to ensure that every American can access mental health and substance use disorder care through their insurance coverage, while integrating mental health services and supports into a variety of other settings, online and in the community. The Biden-Harris Administration will: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Expand and strengthen parity</strong>. The <a href="https://www.cms.gov/CCIIO/Programs-and-Initiatives/Other-Insurance-Protections/mhpaea_factsheet">2008 Mental Health Parity and Addiction Equity Act</a> called for mental health care benefits to be covered at the same level as physical health care benefits. The President’s fiscal year 2023 (FY23) budget will propose that all health plans cover robust behavioral health services with an adequate network of providers, including three behavioral health visits each year without cost-sharing.</li><li><strong>Integrate mental health and substance use treatment into primary care settings</strong>. Equipping primary care providers with the tools to identify, treat, and manage behavioral health conditions is a <a href="https://bipartisanpolicy.org/download/?file=/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/BPC_Behavioral-Health-Integration-report_R03.pdf">proven</a> approach for delivering quality mental health and substance use care, particularly for individuals with depression. To facilitate adoption of these models, the President’s FY23 budget will double funding for primary and behavioral health integration programs. In addition, using existing authority, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will test payment models that support the delivery of whole-person care through behavioral health integration and authorize Medicaid reimbursement of inter-professional consultations so that primary care providers can consult with a specialist and provide needed care for patients.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Improve veterans&#8217; access to same-day mental health care. </strong>Veterans are at <a href="https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_briefs/RB10087.html">higher</a> risk for mental health and substance use challenges than the general population. Increasing their access to quality mental health care is the first step to closing this disparity. The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) will reduce barriers to mental health access by fully implementing their Primary Care Mental Health Integration and Behavioral Health Interdisciplinary Program, which connect veterans to same-day mental health care and improve the integration of these services into primary care settings.<br></li><li><strong>Expand access to tele- and virtual mental health care options. </strong>&nbsp;The use of telehealth to address mental health and substance use needs <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/12/03/new-hhs-study-shows-63-fold-increase-in-medicare-telehealth-utilization-during-pandemic.html">rose</a> dramatically during the height of the pandemic and has remained above pre-pandemic levels even where COVID has waned. These tele-mental health services have proven both <a href="https://www.commonwealthfund.org/blog/2020/using-telehealth-meet-mental-health-needs-during-covid-19-crisis">safe and effective</a>, while reducing barriers to care. To maintain continuity of access, the Administration will work with Congress to ensure coverage of tele-behavioral health across health plans, and support appropriate delivery of telemedicine across state lines. At the same time, the HHS will create a learning collaborative with state insurance departments to identify and address state-based barriers, like telehealth limitations, to behavioral health access. And the United States Office of Personnel Management will facilitate widespread, confidential, and easy access to telehealth services, in part by strongly encouraging Federal Employees Health Benefits Program carriers to sufficiently reimburse providers for telehealth services, and to eliminate or reduce co-payments for consumers seeking tele-mental service.<br></li><li><strong>Expand access to mental health support in schools and colleges and universities. </strong>&nbsp;The President has committed to doubling the number of school-based mental health professionals. The Department of Education (ED) will continue to support states, school districts, colleges and universities, in using relief funds – including the more than $160 billion invested by the American Rescue Plan in the Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief (ESSER) and Higher Education Emergency Relief Fund (HEERF) – to address the mental health needs of students, including by training, recruiting, and retaining more school- and college and university-based mental health professionals. With the help of ESSER funds, schools have already seen a 65% increase in social workers, and a 17% increase in counselors. To help schools sustain these roles, the Department of Health and Human Services will make it easier for school-based mental health professionals to seek reimbursement from Medicaid, and the President’s FY23 budget will propose $1 billion to help schools hire additional counselors and school psychologists and other health professionals.<br></li><li><strong>Embed and co-locate mental health and substance use providers into community-based settings</strong>. Expanding pathways to care also means creating new, low-barrier access points, in settings where Americans already live, work, and play. To that end, the President’s FY23 budget will include $50 million to pilot models that embed and co-locate mental health services into non-traditional settings like libraries, community centers, schools, and homeless shelters.<br></li><li><strong>Increase behavioral health navigation resources. </strong>Finding the right care or an available provider can be a frustrating experience. We need to make it easier for Americans both to find help, and to receive it. To meet this need, the Administration will build new easy-to-access, user-friendly online treatment locator tools – starting with a redesigned and refurbished mentalhealth.gov – so Americans can find care when they need it, where they need it, with the click of a button. The Department of Defense will also create a one-stop online resources for service members and their families to access mental health information and locate mental health providers.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Support Americans by Creating Healthy Environments</strong></p>



<p>We cannot transform mental health solely through the health care system. We must also address the determinants of behavioral health, invest in community services, and foster a culture and environment that broadly promotes mental wellness and recovery. This crisis is not a medical one, but a societal one. In December 2021, the Surgeon-General released an <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-youth-mental-health-advisory.pdf">Advisory on Protecting Youth Mental Health</a> that outlined a wide range of causes for the national youth mental health crisis and underscored growing concern about the harms of digital technologies, particularly social media, to the mental health and well-being of young people, as well as calling for practical action from technology companies to address these concerns.</p>



<p>We need a whole-of-society effort to address these concerns: to expand prevention programs and actions that improve mental health at every age and across settings; and to enhance programs that support recovery, especially for populations at increased risk during vulnerable transition periods. The Biden-Harris Administration will:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Strengthen children’s privacy and ban targeted advertising for children online.</strong><br>The online platforms have <a href="https://wearesocial-cn.s3.cn-north-1.amazonaws.com.cn/common/digital2021/digital-2021-global.pdf">billions</a> of users worldwide, many of whom use the platforms for <a href="https://datareportal.com/reports/digital-2022-united-states-of-america">hours a day</a>. These companies know everything from <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/states-file-new-suits-against-google-over-location-tracking-11643037890">where users are physically located</a> at any moment, to how many seconds they spend reading a particular post, to intimate personal data like what medical symptoms they have been researching. Children are also subject to the platforms’ intensive and excessive data collection vacuum, which they use to deliver sensational and harmful content and troves of paid advertising to our kids. <a href="https://neweconomics.org/uploads/files/i-Spy__NEF.pdf">By one estimate</a>, online advertising firms hold 72 million data points on the average child by the time they reach the age of 13. The President is calling on Congress to ban excessive data collection on and targeted advertising online for children and young people.<br></li><li><strong>Institute stronger online protections for young people, including prioritizing safety by design standards and practices for online platforms, products, and services. </strong>Social media platforms are designed to be addictive, too often deliver age-inappropriate content, promote unhealthy social comparisons, and enable harassment, child sexual exploitation, stalking, and cyber-bullying. Children, adolescents and teens are uniquely vulnerable to harmful and dangerous content online. Other democratic countries have been acting to prevent and reduce the online harms to their children. The President believes not only that we should have far stronger protections for children’s data and privacy, but that the platforms and other interactive digital service providers should be required to prioritize and ensure the health, safety and well-being of children and young people above profit and revenue in the design of their products and services.<br></li><li><strong>Stop discriminatory algorithmic decision-making that limits opportunities for young Americans. </strong>When a girl searches for jobs online, platforms will too often push her away from fields like engineering that historically have excluded women. Searches for “Black girls,” “Asian girls,” or “Latina girls” too often return harmful content, including pornography rather than role models, toys, or activities. Platforms shape how our kids understand what is possible and access opportunities. When young people are treated unfairly, it can have mental health impacts including anxiety and depression. We must ensure that platforms and other algorithmically-enhanced systems do not discriminatorily target our kids.<br></li><li><strong>Invest in research on social media’s mental harms.</strong> Ample research has now emerged that social media is <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/health-news/articles/2021-07-20/social-media-is-a-public-health-crisis">associated</a> with negative mental health outcomes, particularly among <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/health/mental-health/social-media-linked-rise-mental-health-disorders-teens-survey-finds-n982526">young people</a>, and that children under 18 are disproportionately <a href="https://www.apa.org/news/apa/2022/social-media-children-teens">vulnerable</a> to the dangerous and harmful content that they might encounter online. More research, however, is needed to understand why and how these harms occur – and how they can be prevented and treated. To meet this need, the President&#8217;s FY23 budget will dedicate at least $5 million toward advancing research on social media&#8217;s harms, as well as the clinical and societal interventions we might deploy to address them. Over the next year, the Department of Health and Human Services will also launch a national Center of Excellence on Social Media and Mental Wellness, which will develop and disseminate information, guidance, and training on the full impact of adolescent social media use, especially the risks these services pose to their mental health.      <br></li><li><strong>Expand early childhood and school-based intervention services and supports</strong>. Half of all mental disorders begin <a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/data/sites/default/files/report_1973/ShortReport-1973.html">before</a> the age of 14. And when systems act to promote well-being at early developmental stages, youth reap the mental and emotional benefits for <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapediatrics/fullarticle/2766307">years</a> to come. The American Rescue Plan dedicated millions of dollars to youth mental health. The President’s FY23 budget builds on this investment and proposes to make historic investments in youth mental health services, including more than $70 million in infant and early childhood mental health programs. For example, Project LAUNCH works to ensure that the systems that serve young children have the resources and knowledge to foster their social, emotional, cognitive, and behavioral development. The FY23 budget will also continue funding for the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program of the Department of Health and Human Services, which supports new families by teaching positive parenting skills, conducting developmental and mental health screenings, promoting school readiness, and linking to community resources and supports. Additionally, the President&#8217;s FY23 budget will propose to dramatically expand funding for community schools by increasing funding for the Full-Service Community School program by over $400 million dollars relative to current levels – a more than ten-fold increase. Community schools provide a range of wraparound supports to students and their families, including mental health services and other integrated student supports.<br></li><li><strong>Set students up for success. </strong>When students struggle in school, it impacts their well-being. A comprehensive strategy to support student wellness must also include efforts to address the impact of the pandemic on student learning, particularly on students most impacted by the pandemic, and create supportive learning environments. ED will continue to help states and school districts use the $122 billion in ARP ESSER funds for this purpose. Specifically, the Department will help states and districts use the funds to provide more individual and small group instruction, hire instructional and other critical staff, launch high-impact tutoring programs, provide high-quality afterschool and summer learning and enrichment programs, and invest in other evidence-based strategies that will help our students recover from the pandemic. Districts nationwide are already using ARP ESSER funds to invest in these strategies. To support this work, we need more caring adults taking on roles supporting students. The President is calling on Americans nationwide to take on roles as tutors and mentors to help our students recover. Those looking to return to the workforce, who are just out of school, or changing careers, should consider the rich, rewarding job opportunities in our schools and with our young people. The investments the President will propose in his FY23 budget will support and sustain efforts that set up students for success. This includes more than doubling funding for Title I, a ten-fold increase for the Full-Service Community School program, and an historic $3.3 billion increase for Individuals with Disabilities Education Act grants that support PK-12 children with disabilities and $450 million for IDEA PART C, which supports early intervention services for infants and toddlers.<br></li><li><strong>Increase mental health resources for justice-involved populations</strong>. In too many communities, jails and other correctional facilities have become the <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/04/25/605666107/insane-americas-3-largest-psychiatric-facilities-are-jails">largest</a> provider of mental health care. Approximately <a href="https://www.prisonpolicy.org/research/mental_health/">40 percent</a> of incarcerated individuals have a mental illness, yet merely <a href="https://bjs.ojp.gov/content/pub/pdf/imhprpji1112.pdf">one-third</a> receive treatment. The President believes that we have both a moral and a public health obligation to increase access to comprehensive mental health care for the justice-involved. To this end, the Department of Justice will expand funding and technical assistance to local communities and corrections systems to provide behavioral health care, case management services, family services, and other transitional programming for adults returning from incarceration into the community. <br></li><li><strong>Train social and human services professionals in basic mental health skills. </strong>It’s not enough to train health care providers to deliver mental health care; social and human services providers must also be equipped to identify, understand, and respond to signs of mental illness and addiction among those they serve. To this end, the Department of Housing and Urban Development will launch a national effort to train housing counselors, housing-based services coordinators, and Fair Housing grantee staff to recognize the signs of emotional distress and to connect residents with mental health resources. The U.S. Department of Agriculture will provide training on mental health resources and communication strategies to Farm Production and Conservation Mission Area field employees, who serve farmers and ranchers, as well as incorporate updated mental health information into its online resource center for State, local and clinic staff administering the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC). ED will continue to highlight the effectiveness of Mental Health First Aid training for educators, so that they can better support their students and one another. And the Department of Health &amp; Human Services will provide additional training support to Head Start, Early Head Start, and home visiting grantees to spot and address mental health challenges among children.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Women’s Health Protection&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-womens-health-protection-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At a time when women’s access to reproductive health care is under increased assault in states across the country,&#160;it is extremely disappointing that&#160;Senate Republicans&#160;blocked passage of&#160;the Women’s Health Protection Act,&#160;which&#160;would strengthen health care access and codify constitutional rights affirmed half a century ago by&#160;Roe v. Wade&#160;and in subsequent Supreme Court precedent. Today, we mark six&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>At a time when women’s access to reproductive health care is under increased assault in states across the country,&nbsp;it is extremely disappointing that&nbsp;Senate Republicans&nbsp;blocked passage of&nbsp;the Women’s Health Protection Act,&nbsp;which&nbsp;would strengthen health care access and codify constitutional rights affirmed half a century ago by&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>&nbsp;and in subsequent Supreme Court precedent.</p>



<p>Today, we mark six months since Texas law SB8 went into effect,&nbsp;brazenly&nbsp;violating Texans’ constitutional rights and empowering private citizens to act as&nbsp;bounty hunters against&nbsp;their neighbors.&nbsp;Now, a number of other states&nbsp;are also&nbsp;considering&nbsp;passing laws&nbsp;in open defiance of the U.S. Constitution,&nbsp;threatening&nbsp;the&nbsp;reproductive freedom&nbsp;of all&nbsp;Americans.&nbsp;These restrictions&nbsp;are particularly devastating for&nbsp;communities of color,&nbsp;rural Americans, and all those faced with&nbsp;fewer options and fewer resources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As dangerous new laws proliferate in states across the country, the Biden-Harris Administration will continue to explore the measures and tools at our disposal to stand up for women’s equality. This is a moment for us to recommit to strengthening access to women’s health care, defend the constitutional right affirmed by <em>Roe</em>, and protect the freedom of all people to build their own future. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter from President&#160;Biden to the Dedicated Members of the Federal&#160;Workforce</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/letter-from-president-biden-to-the-dedicated-members-of-the-federal-workforce/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To the Dedicated Members of the Federal Workforce: Tonight, I will deliver my State of the Union address to the Congress and the American people. Before I do, I want to thank each of you for your dedication in service to our Nation. Thanks to your tireless work this past year, America is on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>To the Dedicated Members of the Federal Workforce:</p>



<p>Tonight, I will deliver my State of the Union address to the Congress and the American people. Before I do, I want to thank each of you for your dedication in service to our Nation.</p>



<p>Thanks to your tireless work this past year, America is on the move again. Together, we have made significant progress confronting the pandemic, fueling our economy’s historic recovery, tackling the climate crisis, advancing racial equity, and protecting our national security. While our work is not finished, and deep challenges remain, this progress would not have been possible without you.</p>



<p>The strength of any organization rests in its people. Your capabilities and dedication are what make the Federal Government strong and ensure we deliver the basic needs for everyday Americans. As we look to the year ahead, we must build on the innovations and technologies that we put to work serving the American people throughout the pandemic, making our government more efficient, resilient, and effective. And because of our progress combatting the pandemic, we can safely increase in-person work, while continuing to protect your health and safety. Together, we can lead by example and show our country a way forward—not only by what we do, but by how we do it.</p>



<p>Thank you for your service and sacrifices, and that of your family. Your talents could have taken you many places, but you chose to serve our country. I am forever grateful, and with your continued dedication and leadership, I have never been more optimistic for the future of America.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Joe Biden</p>



<p>To view a signed copy of President Biden&#8217;s letter, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Letter-from-President-Biden-to-the-Dedicated-Members-of-the-Federal-Workforce_20220301.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Letter-from-President-Biden-to-the-Dedicated-Members-of-the-Federal-Workforce_20220301.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 28,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/28/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-28-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:31 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; Happy Monday.&#160; State of the Union eve, shall we say?&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Okay.&#160; I just wanted to get &#8212; start off and give you &#8212; highlight some of the ongoing assistance &#8212; obviously, we made a number of announcements over the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:31 P.M. EST</p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Happy Monday.&nbsp; State of the Union eve, shall we say?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I just wanted to get &#8212; start off and give you &#8212; highlight some of the ongoing assistance &#8212; obviously, we made a number of announcements over the weekend &#8212; to get everybody up to speed.&nbsp; We have some charts to give you all the specifics, in case that is helpful.</p>



<p>The United States is the largest provider of assistance to Ukraine, and President Biden has committed more security assistance to Ukraine over the past year than the United States has provided at any other time in history.</p>



<p>On Friday night, the President authorized an additional $350 million of military assistance in support of Ukraine’s frontline defenders as they face armored, airborne, and other threats.&nbsp; He did so hours after speaking with President Zelenskyy to ask him what support he needed.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are working to expedite deliveries from the latest package the President approved &#8212; I would note that the prior package that we had already announced has been ongoing and &#8212; and has been delivered, even in the last few days &#8212; parts of that &#8212; of that package.&nbsp; We expect equipment to start arriving within the next couple of days from this package.</p>



<p>That brought the total security assistance we’ve approved for Ukraine to $1 billion over the past year.&nbsp; It is the third time the President has expedited emergency security assistance for Ukraine’s defense in recent months using the Presidential Drawdown Authority.&nbsp; We’re also working with NATO Allies to facilitate the transfer of U.S.-made equipment from their inventories to Ukraine.</p>



<p>The United States is also the largest &#8212; the single-largest provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and recently deployed a Disaster Assistance Response Team to the region to lead the U.S. humanitarian response and support the Ukrainian people as they bear the brunt of Russian aggression.</p>



<p>You may have seen that our USAID &#8212; head of USAID, Samantha Power, is on the ground in Poland and has been there as well, providing guidance and assistance there.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have provided over $106 million in humanitarian assistance to Ukraine in the past year, including an additional $54 million we announced this weekend to cover critical needs such as safe drinking water, sanitation, hygiene supplies, and critical emergency health supplies to meet the needs of hundreds of thousands of people, as well as emergency food assistance to meet the immediate needs of 125,000 people.</p>



<p>I will stop there.&nbsp; I know there’s lots to talk about, so, Aamer, why don’t you kick us off?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; In light of President Putin putting Russia&#8217;s nuclear forces into &#8220;special combat readiness,&#8221; has the United States changed its nuclear posture?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first start by saying that throughout the crisis, Russia and President Putin have falsely alleged that it is under threat, including from Ukraine, including from NATO.&nbsp; Neither the United States nor NATO has any desire or intention for conflict with Russia.&nbsp; And we think provocative rhetoric like this regarding nuclear weapons is dangerous, adds to the risk of miscalculation, should be avoided, and we’ll not indulge in it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are assessing President Putin&#8217;s directive and, at this time, we see no reason to change our own alert levels.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s also important to remember that, even over the course of the last several months and years, when we have had significant disagreements with Russia over a range of issues, Russia and the United States have long agreed that nuclear use would have devastating consequences and have stated many times, including earlier this year, that a nuclear war cannot be won and must never be fought.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we have not &#8212; had seen reason to change our alert levels, and we are &#8212; see obvious, significant danger in escalatory rhetoric.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask &#8212; there’s been a great deal of movement of unity, and it comes after no shortage of angst about the Western Alliance, I think, in recent years, particularly going back to the last administration.&nbsp; Is the President going to use this moment, though, to push NATO members to get on track with that 2 percent of GDP on defense spending?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, President Putin has been one of the greatest unifiers of NATO in modern history, so I guess that is one thing we can thank him for.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I would just look at, Aamer, some of the announcements that have been made even over the last couple of days.&nbsp; One, the President has always been an advocate and a supporter of countries abiding by the 2 percent component.&nbsp; He was a supporter of that back when he was Vice President, where, for history’s sake, there was a great deal of progress made before the last president even took office and talked about it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But as we look even over the past &#8212; course of the past weekend, not only did you see a NATO Alliance that was incredibly unified and agreement among Europeans that there needed to be additional assistance provided in the form of security assistance to Ukraine, but you saw a number of countries take steps that they had not taken in recent history.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Germany has historically not sent weapons to conflict zones; this weekend, they changed course.&nbsp; Sweden also has not changed &#8212; sent arms to countries in active conflict; that changed this weekend.&nbsp; Finland also changed course.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not all NATO members, of course, but the point is: What you&#8217;re looking at here is a unified Europe, a unified West, a unified NATO who are standing up to the aggression and the invasion led by President Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if I could just quickly follow up on that, we&#8217;ve also seen some signs and responses beyond sanctions to isolate Russia.&nbsp; I think FIFA &#8212; and I’m sorry, I’m not a soccer fan &#8212; I think it’s &#8220;FIFA,&#8221; how you pronounce it &#8212; and the IOC have taken action to put pressure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Can that type of pressure &#8212; is it sustainable in the long term, given the economic pressures?&nbsp; The longer this crisis goes on, can you maintain that sort of unity and those sort of collective actions?&nbsp; Can they continue beyond this early moment?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well &#8212; and you&#8217;re referring to the IOC, as in the International Olympic Committee?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s &#8220;Fie-fa&#8221; or &#8220;FIFA.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; FIFA.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; FIFA.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I kind of &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I apologize to the international community.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; I tried to be soft there.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; FIFA.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I think, Aamer, obviously the preference of everybody is for President Putin to take de-escalatory steps.&nbsp; That is everybody&#8217;s preference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as it relates to unity among international organizations, among the West, among countries, among many leaders in the United States even, I think what we&#8217;ve seen over the last few days is a commitment to remain united and to send a strong message to President Putin that this act &#8212; these actions, this rhetoric is unacceptable and the world is building a wall against it.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think the Crown Prince of Saudi Arabia had a call with Emmanuel Macron yesterday where he reiterated the commitment for OPEC Plus’s production agreement.&nbsp; Has there been an explicit U.S. request to Saudi or to members of OPEC Plus to increase production, given what&#8217;s happening right now?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without getting into specific details from here, just because it wouldn&#8217;t be constructive to our overarching objectives, we have been in touch.&nbsp; I think you may remember that Brett McGurk and Amos Hochstein made a trip to the region just a few weeks ago to have conversations with the Saudis and others about a range of topics, including the conflict in Yemen, but also to have a conversation about the need to address any impact on the global markets &#8212; global oil markets that we expect could happen &#8212; expected at the time could happen and could continue to happen as a result of President Putin&#8217;s invasion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But was any request made for a specific production increase?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, there is a &#8212; there has been an ongoing discussion about steps that we can all take as a global community to address any volatility in the market.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then given, I think, the speed and scale of the ramp-up on the sanction side of things over the course of the last 72 hours, does the U.S., European Allies have a &#8212; like, a threshold for which they view if you cross this, it would be viewed as an act of war by President Putin?&nbsp; As in, how do you calibrate your actions in terms of response and what may be coming back?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he was &#8212; he&#8217;s already in a war &#8212; committed an act of war, invaded a sovereign country.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean for NATO countries or EU countries.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, you mean for NATO countries to act further, in terms of further military steps or further sanctions?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As in, if you game out &#8212; as you game out what a response would be, given the scale of the sanctions package &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that was unveiled, is there a line that if we do this sanction or if we go this far, then that would for sure draw a response directly towards the U.S. or towards the EU from Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if you look at the significance of the steps we&#8217;ve taken to date, including the announcements over the weekend about cutting off major financial &#8212; major fin- &#8212; banks in Russia from the SWIFT banking system, we have continued to escalate and build in close coordination and alignment with the Europeans.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Unity is a top principle for President Biden as we take steps forward.&nbsp; That doesn&#8217;t happen on its own.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t happen by accident.&nbsp; It happens as a result of a lot of conversations, diplomacy, and hours by the President and others on his national security team behind the scenes.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the other piece, just to get to the core of your question, that we very much weigh is maximizing the impact on President Putin, the Russian elite, the economy while minimizing it on the global markets and the American people.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, as we look at steps to take &#8212; I mean, even if you look at the impact on the energy sector, you know, we have &#8212; we have taken steps &#8212; we have not taken some steps on energy sanctions, in part because we weigh that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That doesn&#8217;t mean that they&#8217;re off the table.&nbsp; That remain &#8212; they remain on the table.&nbsp; But Europeans, for example, are very concerned about further price spikes on gas, in particular.&nbsp; Their prices have gone up 335 percent over the last three &#8212; yes, over the last year and 26 percent over the last five days.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So sanctioning energy would affect Russia&#8217;s income stream &#8212; certainly that would be a reason to do it &#8212; but it would also have extreme consequences on the world energy markets, particularly for our Allies in Europe.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I use that as an example because we have to weigh all of the factors as we weigh whether to take additional steps.&nbsp; We have additional steps we could take, but we consider all of those factors as we make determinations.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, last one, just real quick: Is the Biden administration considering following what the EU and Canada did in barring Russian flights from the U.S. at any point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to update you on, on that front at this point in time.&nbsp; There are obviously a range of &#8212; of options that remain on the table.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s not off the table, but I don&#8217;t have anything to announce and no decision made.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; You spoke about &#8212; a little bit about the sanctions that were announced over the weekend &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on Russia’s Central Bank.&nbsp; How long does the U.S. anticipate keeping them in place?&nbsp; I mean, is there sort of a timeframe there?&nbsp; Perhaps &#8212; you spoke about, you know, Russia considering de-escalatory tactics or, you know, maybe announcing a ceasefire.&nbsp; Or, you know, is there &#8212; is there, sort of, a broad timeframe that the U.S. is thinking about?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s hope that&#8217;s the discussion we&#8217;re having.&nbsp; Obviously, right now, President Putin is continuing to take escalatory steps, so we&#8217;re not at that point of having that discussion.&nbsp; We hope that&#8217;s one that we will be a part of.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, for the time being, there is, sort of, no discussion on perhaps, you know, putting an end to the sanctions that have been put in place?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean, President Putin and the Russian military is moving toward the capital of Ukraine, and there are hundreds of thousands of refugees leaving the country because he has invaded a sovereign country.&nbsp; So, no, I would not say we&#8217;re talking about reducing sanctions at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, sorry, one quick question on President Zelenskyy saying he wants to be a member of the European Union.&nbsp; We did see some comments come in from the EU over the weekend saying they are a part of us.&nbsp; However, this morning, there were some conflicting comments again from the EU saying, you know, there are, sort of, discussions among EU members about, you know, whether such a decision can be made.&nbsp; What is the U.S. position on Ukraine joining the EU?&nbsp; Do you support it?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s up to the European Union.&nbsp; We’re not a member of the European Union.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If they did consider taking Ukraine in, would you support that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s up to the European Union to make that decision.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a process.</p>



<p>And, of course, we support the aspirations of any country to join any organization and the decision of that organization to make a decision.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Zelenskyy is urging President Biden and NATO to impose this no-fly zone.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve said that this would significantly escalate the situation.&nbsp; So, just to be clear: Is this a no go for right now, or is this completely off the table &#8212; something that you would not consider?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President has been very clear that he is not intending to send U.S. troops to fight a war with Russia.&nbsp; And I think what&#8217;s important to note here is that is essentially what this would be a step toward, because a no-fly zone would require implementation.&nbsp; It would require deploying U.S. military to enforce, which would be a direct conflict &#8212; potentially a direct conflict and potentially war with Russia, which is something we are not planning to be a part of.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Vladimir Putin, you’ve said, you know, you&#8217;re not going to assess his mental state, but the President has said, you know, he knows Putin well.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve talked a few times over the last several weeks and months.&nbsp; Has the President himself noticed or commented on any change that he&#8217;s picked up on in Putin&#8217;s demeanor or tone?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; any more assessment about the President&#8217;s view of President Putin&#8217;s mental acuity to state from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s no question &#8212; outside of that, we&#8217;ll leave that to others &#8212; that what we&#8217;ve seen from President Putin, whether it is escalatory rhetoric as it relates to nuclear capabilities and nuclear intentions &#8212; something that is in direct conflict with something President Putin, himself, and the Russians committed to &#8212; had an alternate &#8212; you know, committed to something else just a year ago, or whether it is the speech he gave last week where he questioned the sovereignty of the country of Ukraine at all, or the actions he&#8217;s taking right now.&nbsp; Those are not actions of a &#8212; of a global leader that &#8212; that that should be treated with respect on the global stage.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But given the behavior that you have seen, some of the things that you just noted, and the very severe consequences that he is now facing &#8212; these severe sanctions &#8212; is there any concern that instead of retreating that Putin will feel so squeezed and so pressured that he will lash out even more, intensifying his attacks &#8212; that any of this could backfire, essentially?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that it is our responsibility &#8212; the United States, President Biden as a leader in the world &#8212; to rally the world in making clear how unacceptable his behavior is and to put in place severe consequences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now what he is feeling on the ground &#8212; there are protests, there have been oligarchs in his own cozy circle who have been outspoken.&nbsp; And obviously, the pinch is being felt significantly in the Russian economy, even if you just look at the fact that the market was closed today.&nbsp; The ruble has been plummeting.&nbsp; So those are the ways that he is feeling this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He has a decision he can make to de-escalate.&nbsp; And certainly, we would welcome that decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Does the White House believe it is possible to say whether Ukraine or Russia are winning this war right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re going to make an assessment of that from here.&nbsp; But what I will reiterate is something we have said in the past, is that: President Putin and Russian military have made clear that they have every intention of taking over the capital city.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While it &#8212; while there has been a greater pushback in the country than they may have assessed to begin with, and I know my colleagues at the Department of Defense have spoken to this &#8212; the Ukrainian military, President Zelenskyy, and others, have fought courageously, have fought boldly in this moment &#8212; they are continuing to proceed, continuing to move towards the capital.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think their ambitions have changed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What would Putin have to do to get these sanctions lifted?&nbsp; Would he have to agree to a ceasefire?&nbsp; Would he have to pull all of his troops out of Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to make a prediction or assessment of that from here.&nbsp; If he starts to take the de-escalatory steps, I&#8217;m sure we can have that conversation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How great is the concern &#8212; this is sort of building on Mary&#8217;s question: How great is the concern that these sanctions are so punishing that, essentially, Putin will have nothing left to lose and no offramp?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the sanctions are punishing so that they will inflict significant consequences and change the outcome at the end of the day &#8212; and de-escalate at the end of the day.&nbsp; That is what they are intended to do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, you were talking about a no-fly zone over Ukraine, but I know officials have been discussing the possibility of imposing a no-fly zone for Russia over the U.S.&nbsp; Where do those talks stand right now and what are the pros and cons to doing something like that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, while &#8212; while no option is off the table, there &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of a decision or anything along those lines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that there are a lot of flights that go over &#8212; that &#8212; that U.S. &#8212; U.S. airlines fly over Russia to go to Asia and other parts of the world, and we factor in a range of factors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally, what&#8217;s the U.S. doing to reduce the possibility of nuclear war?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, one, we are not escalating our own rhetoric.&nbsp; Two, we are certainly assessing what President Putin&#8217;s comments mean.&nbsp; But, as I noted a little bit earlier, we have not changed our own posture.&nbsp; What we are trying to do is reduce the tension; take the &#8212; the tenor of the rhetoric down; and make clear that we have seen this pattern in the past, which is posing threats or suggesting, through misinformation of sorts, that there are threats posed to President Putin in Russia that don&#8217;t exist.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; There are reports of illegal cluster bombs and vacuum bombs being used by the Russians.&nbsp; If that&#8217;s true, what is the next step of this administration?&nbsp; And is there a red line for how much violence will be tolerated against civilians in this manner that&#8217;s illegal and potentially a war crime?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is &#8212; it would be.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any confirmation of that.&nbsp; We have seen the reports. &nbsp;If that were true, it would potentially be a war crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, there are a range of international fora that would assess that.&nbsp; So, certainly, we would look to that to be a part of that conversation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, the new aid that you just laid out at the beginning here.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Post reported over the weekend that this aid will not include Stingers, that it would likely come in a future batch of aid.&nbsp; What is the reason for that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics of what is in the military package.&nbsp; It is &#8212; it is a combination of ground and airborne defense capabilities.&nbsp; And, obviously, we have provided those in the past, but I&#8217;m not going to have more details &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; to outline for you from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you mentioned that this next batch is going to be coming in the next few days.&nbsp; Why so long?&nbsp; I mean, &#8220;days&#8221; doesn&#8217;t sound like a long time to us, but &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The package that we had and already announced continues to be delivered. &nbsp;So, we have expedited the plans for delivery of this new package.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the nuclear rhetoric we&#8217;ve been hearing from Putin: Does this influence at all the upcoming Nuclear Policy Review?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In terms of how we &#8212; our relationship with &#8212; look, I would say &#8212; it&#8217;s a good question, Jacqui.&nbsp; But I would say what&#8217;s important for people to note &#8212; and this is why I noted it a little bit earlier &#8212; is that even at moments where we had huge tension with President Putin and Russia around the 2016 election, around the invasion of Georgia, around their prior invasion of Ukraine, it was agreed that escalatory rhetoric around nuclear ambitions was dangerous.&nbsp; And that was something we committed to with Russia not to pursue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, we &#8212; I think, for right now, we&#8217;re going to remind the global community of those commitments.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on that same note, does this administration trust Russia to be an honest broker in the talks with Iran right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s not about trust in any of these negotiations or discussions; it&#8217;s about verifying and then trusting later, including with the Iranians.&nbsp; But the Russians have been, in the past, a part of the P5+1 negotiations.&nbsp; They’re a part of it now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would &#8212; I would &#8212; I would just convey that, you know, it is in everyone&#8217;s interest to have an understanding and visibility into Iran&#8217;s capacity to acquire a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, at this point, we&#8217;re just &#8212; we&#8217;re just continuing to work &#8212; hope to make progress on that agreement.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then after all of this, what is the stance of the U.S. and buying Russian gas at this point?&nbsp; At this point, are we ready to pledge not to buy any more Russian gas?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, it&#8217;s really &#8212; let me give you actually kind of an update on this because it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s &#8212; I think there&#8217;s been a little confusion.&nbsp; One moment.</p>



<p>So, as it relates to Russian gas, the U.S. government doesn&#8217;t dictate where the U.S. market sells our own oil and gas products nor where it acquires crude or refined products from for domestic consumption.&nbsp; This is all up to the private sector, other than exceptions like countries under sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the U.S. refiners currently importing Russian products are largely legacy refinery operations tooled in Hawaii and Alaska for certain supplies because of geography; and imports to the Gulf, both of certain refined products and of crude, as refiners in the Gulf mix crude supplies to meet the needs of their particular refinery designs.</p>



<p>There have been companies &#8212; obviously, private sector companies &#8212; who have made decisions and announcements, and we certainly applaud that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, can you just explain, though, what you laid out at the beginning because I&#8217;m a little bit unclear.&nbsp; You just &#8212; just in layman&#8217;s terms: We are not going to be making any policy from the U.S. government that would prohibit the sale or the purchase of Russian gas then because it&#8217;s not something that we already do?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t ruled out that, but I think what I wanted to convey is what is accurate about what happens now and how it currently works.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thank you.&nbsp; Staying on that topic for a moment &#8212; of oil and gas.&nbsp; You have said “nothing is off the table” when it comes to releasing more reserves, more barrels from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; Where are those negotiations right now?&nbsp; Is the administration closer to moving forward with that, given the sanctions and what we&#8217;re seeing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you on that front.&nbsp; It remains an option on the table and, obviously, it would help meet any supply issues in the marketplace.&nbsp; There are conversations that we&#8217;ve been having with global partners.&nbsp; And obviously, we have our own Strategic Petroleum Reserve stockpile to tap into.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you characterize if you’re closer to making a decision on that front though, given what we are seeing and obviously the global impact that these very harsh sanctions (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It has remained on the table.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Just a short time ago, the President was asked by our colleagues here if Americans should be concerned about a nuclear threat.&nbsp; He said very firmly, “No.”&nbsp; Can you explain what gives him that confidence?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because, as I said a little bit earlier, while we think provocative rhetoric regarding nuclear weapons is dangerous and adds to the risk of miscalculation and should be avoided &#8212; which we&#8217;re not going to indulge in &#8212; we are continuing to assess President Putin&#8217;s directive and, at this time, we see no reason to change our own alert levels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also seen, throughout this crisis, President Putin falsely allege that they are under threat and use that as a predicate for taking more aggressive action.&nbsp; So, we assess &#8212; we have our own capacities and capabilities here, but nuclear war cannot be won.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what everybody should be doing around the world is taking steps to reduce the rhetoric, reduce the tension, and that&#8217;s certainly what our objective is.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One breaking news development that I wanted to ask you about.&nbsp; The U.S. has expelled 12 diplomats &#8212; 12 Russian diplomats.&nbsp; The Russian ambassador just said a short time ago that move was a “hostile step” toward Russia.&nbsp; Can you give us the thinking behind the decision?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, again, following up on some of the lines of questioning that you&#8217;ve already gotten, could there be a backlash to this step?&nbsp; Is this escalatory?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first state that today’s action has been in the works for several months.&nbsp; We informed &#8212; the United States informed the United Nations and the Russian Mission to the United Nations that we were beginning the process of expelling 12 intelligence operatives from the Russian Mission who had abused their privileges of residency in the United States by engaging in espionage activities that are adverse to our national security.&nbsp; So, it takes some time to make those evaluations and that &#8212; again, those actions were &#8212; were in the works for months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And your response to the Russian ambassador who called this a “hostile act”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the hostile act is committing espionage activities on our own soil.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Jen, just finally, on the issue of refugees &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you have also said &#8212; you were asked by my colleague earlier today whether the administration would move to give refugees from Ukraine protective status.&nbsp; Can you give us a timeline for that?&nbsp; These are people who are suffering, and they want to know what the answer is.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, to be clear: Temporary Protected Status applies to people currently living in the United States.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So that, I think, is one of the questions &#8212; a good question &#8212; that has been asked.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s a process that&#8217;s run by the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; They evaluate, through an interagency process, both what everybody&#8217;s recommendations are and, obviously, the conditions on the ground in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second piece is whether we would accept refugees.&nbsp; Yes, we would.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think it&#8217;s important to note that the vast majority of refugees are going to want &#8212; in our assessment and through the discussion with refugee agencies, with other countries in the region &#8212; will want to be in Europe and neighboring countries, many of whom have already conveyed very clearly that they will welcome refugees in.&nbsp; Many of them have family members there.&nbsp; Many have work there.&nbsp; So, we are also coordinating and supporting those efforts as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The U.S. has authorized the departure of non-emergency employees and diplomats’ relatives from the embassy in Moscow.&nbsp; How confident is the administration that the U.S. Embassy in Moscow can remain open in the long term?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t make an assessment of that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the State Department looks at and assesses.&nbsp; Obviously, our &#8212; our embassies and consulates around the world play an incredibly important role in communicating with American citizens who are in a country, but also with the Russian people.&nbsp; And so that is something &#8212; that&#8217;s why we have a diplomatic pres- &#8212; you know, consulates in and around the world, including in Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are also decisions that are made for a range of reasons &#8212; the State Department could outline it more specifically for you &#8212; including temporary departure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something that has happened around the world for many, many decades for a variety of reasons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would, you know, give you an example of: Just a couple of years ago in Turkey, there was ordered departure, right?&nbsp; Then diplomats return.&nbsp; That&#8217;s obviously the objective, but it really depends on the conditions on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what level of concern is there for the safety of American citizens who are living in Russia?&nbsp; Is there concern that they could face retaliation in light of this conflict?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I would point you to the State Department.&nbsp; They do assessments, and they give clear guidance to people who are on the ground and what their recommendations are for their security.&nbsp; I would note that one difficulty, right now in Russia because of these sanctions, is of gaining access to U.S. currency and using banking cards.&nbsp; And that is a hindrance for many people who are living there right now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just, lastly, you know, you&#8217;ve been very clear that the President does not have any intention to deploy U.S. troops to engage militarily in this conflict.&nbsp; But would you say that there is any particular red line that this administration has that would necessitate military action?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As in sending our U.S. military into Ukraine?&nbsp; The President has no plans to send U.S. military to fight a war in Ukraine against Russia.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you share any details about what came out of the President&#8217;s secure call with other Allied nations this afternoon?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I know we were working on a readout, which we will get to you shortly after the briefing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a bit of a busy day, so let me venture to get that to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The purpose of this call was for the President to have an opportunity to continue to engage with other leaders about what we&#8217;re seeing on the ground, the range of assistance we&#8217;re providing, the financial sanctions and economic consequences steps we&#8217;re taking, and ensure we remain closely coordinated.&nbsp; But I will see if there&#8217;s more details we can get you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And then administration officials earlier this &#8212; earlier today had a background briefing with reporters about the State of the Union coming up.&nbsp; Can you tell us a little bit more?&nbsp; We understand &#8212; or we understood from the call that the President will be addressing elements of the Build Back Better plan when it comes to things like childcare and paid family leave.&nbsp; And officials talked about how those things, if implemented, will lower costs for families, but they were hesitant to use the word “inflation” or say whether that would be addressed directly in the President&#8217;s speech.&nbsp; So can you say whether the President will be addressing any new policies &#8212; not necessarily new domestic programs but policies that would address inflation directly?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say, the President will absolutely use the word “inflation” tomorrow, and he will talk about inflation in his speech.&nbsp; Of course, that is a huge issue on the minds of Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, one thing to note is one of the best, most important steps that the Senate could take is to confirm his slate of eminently qualified nominees to fill out the Federal Reserve Board, given they &#8212; given they have a very important role as it relates to inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I think what you will hear the President talk about &#8212; and I think this is what they were talking about on this call &#8212; is how we&#8217;re going to address costs for the American people and lower costs.&nbsp; And we talked a lot about inflation in here, our economists talk about inflation, the Federal Reserve talks about inflation &#8212; hugely important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How people experience it is what it means for their pocketbooks, for their budgets, for their bank accounts, and how they&#8217;re paying for things.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why a lot of what you&#8217;re going to hear about tomorrow, as he talks about it, is how he&#8217;s going to reduce costs.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, the Build Back &#8212; you know, parts of his agenda that have &#8212; that he has talked about significantly &#8212; a lot over the course of the last several months &#8212; lowering costs for childcare, lowering costs for eldercare, lowering costs for prescription drugs &#8212; those are not done yet.&nbsp; So he will reiterate his call for Congress to move forward on those.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I would also note that, in the speech, he&#8217;s going to make clear that one of the best ways to lower costs over the long run is to &#8212; is to increase the productive capacity of our economy, to make more things in America with more American workers contributing and earning a good living.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to describe the emerging manufacturing comeback with American companies betting on America again because of the administration&#8217;s commitment to domestic industrial revitalization and technological development.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He will also call on &#8212; he will also explain that we can also lower costs by promoting fair competition in the U.S. economy.&nbsp; And there are new steps to lower &#8212; and he will talk about steps to lower consumer prices and level the playing field for American businesses in ocean shipping and new steps to protect seniors and other nursing home residents by cracking down on unsafe nursing homes.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also going to talk about &#8212; reflect on one of the strongest labor market recoveries in American history and make clear that it&#8217;s important to continue to take steps to eliminate barriers to good-paying jobs for workers across America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I would expect that you will hear a lot, the American people will hear a lot about how he&#8217;s going to lower their costs, how he&#8217;s going to buil- &#8212; continue to build a strong economy over the long term.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I could just follow up on what you were saying about addressing lowering costs for families &#8212; the President has been encouraging Congress to pass at least elements or his entire Build Back Better agenda for months; Congress has been negotiating for months.&nbsp; What gives the President any confidence that this time around things would be more likely to pass, given we are just months out from midterm elections?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because there is strong support across the country for lowering costs for prescription drugs.&nbsp; It&#8217;s incredibly popular.&nbsp; Who wants to pay more for prescription drugs?&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know why that gets to be a Democratic idea, but we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;re happy to own that one.&nbsp; Or for lowering the cost of childcare, for lowering the cost of eldercare and healthcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also strong support for those &#8212; those items and those priorities and those good ideas in &#8212; in the Senate among Senate Democrats.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s going to keep pressing to get it done, and he thinks the American people want us to get it done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, just on Ukraine.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Over the past 72 hours or so, there have been a series of announcements that have come on aiding Ukraine or punishing Russia.&nbsp; But it has appeared that Europe has taken the lead on many of these announcements, and I can go through a few of them if you want.&nbsp; But the brunt of my question is I know &#8212; whether you can explain whether there&#8217;s a deliberate strategy right now in this moment to have Europeans and European nations and European leaders being the ones out front on punishing Russia or supporting Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first that the SWIFT banking system is a European system.&nbsp; So, in terms of the steps that would be taken, it would be only natural for those steps to be taken or announced by them.&nbsp; It is something we have clearly been long open to, but I just wanted to state that from the beginning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would also say that, you know, the &#8212; the President and the United States has been leading this effort around the world in building this coalition, which includes many countries in Europe but also many from other parts of the world, in standing up to President Putin and standing up to the aggression and the invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, all of this coordinated action did not happen by accident.&nbsp; It wouldn&#8217;t have happened without the President&#8217;s efforts, the President&#8217;s time he spent on diplomacy, the time of our national security team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The order of announcements and how that has gone, I would not overread into that because we would not be here had the President not been leading this effort around the world for months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I think you just saw, you know, over the weekend in particular, this sort of onslaught of news and, sort of, changing posture in Europe, and the President was not &#8212; not present at all in the, sort of, like, you know, living rooms of the American people.&nbsp; You know, we were seeing newscasts of these vacuum bombs and whatnot, but no sort of visual image of the President taking &#8212; you know, doing the kind of behind-the-scenes leadership that you just described.&nbsp; And I do wonder if that is on purpose or if that just happens to be the way the schedule worked.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President was at a memorial service for a family member yesterday, and he was with the family on Saturday.&nbsp; And so that was his priority this weekend &#8212; or one of his priorities this weekend.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He also, though, engaged in a meeting with his national security team, and I think you saw him quite visible last week and again today &#8212; well, I guess you know about his call he had today &#8212; and he will continue to, in the days ahead, lead the world in not only building the coalition but pushing for agreement and a coordinated effort to hold Russia accountable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I would say this weekend, he had some personal family reasons &#8212; an important one: a memorial service for a family member &#8212; as to why he was not giving a speech yesterday.&nbsp; But he is somebody who has been leading this effort behind the scenes for months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on that front, if you could just preview, for a minute &#8212; the call earlier today was very focused on the President&#8217;s economic agenda, and if you could talk a little bit about what the President may say and how he will, you know, frame this &#8212; this moment and, sort of, this international crises, and the extent to which he sees this a, you know, global audience, you know, more so than it normally would be in a State of the Union.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first I would say that there&#8217;s no question that this speech is a little different than it would have been just a few months ago.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s always national security in every State of the Union speech, but every State of the Union speech also reflects a moment of time.&nbsp; And so, the President will lay out the efforts we are taking, he has taken, he has led on to rally the world to stand up for democracy and against Russian aggression.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He will talk about the steps we&#8217;ve taken to not only support the Ukrainian people with military and economic assistance but also the steps he&#8217;s taken to build a glo- &#8212; global alition [coalition]&nbsp; imposing crippling financial sanctions on President Putin, his inner circle, and the Russian economy.&nbsp; And he will talk about the steps he&#8217;s taking to mitigate the impact of President Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine on the global economy and the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And certainly, you know, I think people can expect to hear him, you know, position that as the importance of the United States as a leader in the world &#8212; standing up for values, standing up for &#8212; for global norms, but also, you know, the efforts that he has undertaken to mitigate how it will impact people here.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just have one other quick one.&nbsp; But, again, based on the background briefing earlier today about the State of the Union &#8212; it focused on the economy and various programs that the President wants Congress to push.&nbsp; Could you characterize what percentage of the programs that the President will talk about are just a repackaged parts of Build Back Better &#8212; like chunks that he wants to see the Congress pass versus like brand new ideas that he&#8217;s introducing for the first time tomorrow night?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s what I will tell you, having been through a few State of the Unions in the past, and I know you have as well: They don&#8217;t get longer, they get shorter.&nbsp; Nobody wants a two- or three-hour State of the Union.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think anyone in here does.&nbsp; So I just don&#8217;t want to preview more at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can certainly expect to hear him talk about some &#8212; call on Congress to send bills to his desk that deliver progress on ideas that have historically been supported by Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; Some of those are economic and some of those are in other areas that could just impact and help communities across the country.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you will certainly hear him call, as you &#8212; as you touched on, for a continued effort &#8212; a redoubling of the effort to move forward on steps that will reduce costs for the American people in these key areas of childcare, healthcare, prescription drugs.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you know, stay tuned for tomorrow night.&nbsp; But we have a lot of hours between the speech, and I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have more previews between now and then.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just staying on the State of the Union topic.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about what &#8212; what it would look like, in terms of masking or what you expect it could look like in terms of masking?&nbsp; Specifically, this &#8212; is the President &#8212; will he walk in, shake hands?&nbsp; Will he be wearing a mask when he walks in?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he will certainly not be wearing a mask when he&#8217;s speaking.&nbsp; I have not talked to him yet about whether he&#8217;s going to wear a mask when he&#8217;s walking down the aisle.&nbsp; But it has been announced, I think, that it&#8217;s not required, and certainly he will abide by that.&nbsp; But I will see if there&#8217;s more we can report out to you on that later today.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Was it important to the President that masks come off dur- &#8212; before the State of the Union?&nbsp; Is there a message that he hopes to send with &#8212; you know, with that news?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say the President is very powerful, but he couldn&#8217;t make us be in the green zone that we&#8217;re in right now in D.C.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we are not required &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to be required to wear a mask starting tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I would say that for him, it had nothing to do with the timing around the State of the Union.&nbsp; He wanted to give the CDC the time to assess and make recommendations that would be clear to the American public about what their recommendations would be for mask wearing moving forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask one question about the Ukraine-Bel- &#8212; on Belarus &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about the Belarus situation and aiding Russia?&nbsp; What &#8212; is there &#8212; are there additional actions that the United States is considering?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just speaking of SWIFT, there&#8217;s been some reports that Europe is considering or looking at kicking Belarus out of SWIFT.&nbsp; Is that something &#8212; is the United States part of those discussions?&nbsp; Does it support that type of action against Belarus?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict on that front at this point in time, but what I will say is we&#8217;ve already taken steps to put in place sanctions on some leaders in Belarus, some of the military components; certainly, we could build on that.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict at this point in time.&nbsp; But we certainly are a part of those discussions.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; One of the topics &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t want to get into, you know, stuff that might be cut.&nbsp; But you guys have said many times that the Chinese have, at least tacitly, supported Putin’s moves into Ukraine.&nbsp; Is the President going to call out the Chinese for that behavior or President Xi Jinping or what you guys have been trying to get the Chinese to do on helping with Ukraine or helping with Russia on this crisis?&nbsp; Is he going to mention that at all?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say this speech is more about the unity of the vast majority of the global community in standing up against President Putin, it&#8217;s more about American leadership in this moment, and it&#8217;s more about even unity here in standing up against the aggression of President Putin into Ukraine.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would say, on the Chinese, what we&#8217;ve said generally is that it&#8217;s important at this moment for any country to be vocal in speaking out against the actions of President Putin and &#8212; and Russian leaders in this moment.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What we have seen from the Chinese last weekend &#8212; or, I guess, a weekend before that at the Munich Security Conference &#8212; they reiterated their support for the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine.&nbsp; We saw them abstain from the U.N. Security Council vote.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, you know, this is not a moment to be on the sidelines.&nbsp; This is a moment to be vocal, and this is a moment to think about where you are in history.</p>



<p>But I think the speech, for everyone&#8217;s expectation for tomorrow, is more about laying out efforts to the American people that the United States has undertaken to rally the world for democracy and against Russian aggression.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you are, in general, pushing the Chinese to be less on the sidelines and not trying to have it both ways, basically, by being vocal?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, they have implemented the sanctions.&nbsp; If they don&#8217;t do that, then we obviously have steps we can take.&nbsp; We are encouraging every country to continue to be vocal and more vocal as it relates to Russia&#8217;s aggression and invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more &#8212; just breaking news.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Prime Minister of Canada, Justin Trudeau, just announced that he &#8212; the Canadians would unilaterally ban Russian crude oil imports.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve just talked a lot about how you&#8217;re taking into account how this will impact the Europeans.&nbsp; But is there something you had &#8212; is this something you would just do unilaterally, not as a coordinated effort?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; From the beginning &#8212; again, all options remain on the table &#8212; you have seen us take a number of actions over the last several days that play that out.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict at this point, other than to reiterate that we have really worked to take steps in lockstep with the Europeans and a number of our NATO partners.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On Friday, you said this isn&#8217;t &#8212; this is not a “moment where diplomacy feels appropriate.”&nbsp; The French President talked with Putin hours ago.&nbsp; So, have the discussions between the Russian and Ukrainian delegations changed &#8212; or how are they influencing President Biden’s stance on having leader-to-leader discussions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re a few days out from that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nothing has changed in terms of the President &#8212; this President&#8217;s assessment of having a conversation or engagement with President Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we said before, we&#8217;re not ruling it out ever; it just is not the appropriate moment or the moment for the United States President to have a conversation with the President of a country invading a sovereign country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s our view; other countries make their own decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of the engagements or discussion between the Ukrainians and the Russians, I&#8217;d really point you to the Ukrainians to get more of a readout from that.&nbsp; There have been reports that those will continue.&nbsp; I would point you to them to confirm whether that is the case.&nbsp; And I expect we will be in touch with the Ukrainians, as we are nearly every day.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At the beginning, you kind of outlined all of the support being given not just by the United States but other countries who typically have not done so.&nbsp; But I wonder if you &#8212; if the administration has any concerns about how President Putin would use that as an excuse to escalate and possibly attack NATO Allies, considering his warnings about the West getting involved in this crisis?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to step back and remember who the aggressor is here.&nbsp; The aggressor is President Putin.&nbsp; The aggressor is the Russian military at the direction of President Putin into a sovereign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The world is standing up against this aggression, and he is feeling the impact already of the financial sanctions and consequences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you just look purely at the impact on the Russian economy, even today: The ruble fell 20 to 25 percent and is trading at its weakest level ever.&nbsp; The Russian stock market was kept closed today, likely due to a fear of capital flight once it opens.&nbsp; The Russian Central Bank more than doubled their key interest rate to 20 percent, the highest in almost 20 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is the world saying, “This is not acceptable.”&nbsp; It is now up to President Putin, if he wants those circumstances to change, to change his own behavior.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, last one: The U.N. Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change released kind of a major, unprecedented report with lots of warnings today and said some places in the world have basically maxed out their capacity to adapt to climate change, while others soon will.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious &#8212; I mean, Joe Manchin offered kind of a slimmed down BBB version with $555 billion for climate &#8212; will the administration be pressing Democrats to at least move on that portion of climate change in light of the recent developments of this recent report?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, the President agrees absolutely that we need to do more.&nbsp; That is why they &#8212; that he has been such an advocate for historic levels of investment in addressing our climate crisis.&nbsp; And if we had had 50 votes to move that forward, we would have done that.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there are ongoing discussions, of course; they are happening a lot on the Hill between members on the Hill.&nbsp; The President remains committed to moving that forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would also note that part of what was in that report was the need to bolster adaptation efforts that increase our resilience to the impacts of climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And one of the &#8212; and a couple of pieces that the President has already done: He launched an Emergency Plan for Adaptation and Resilience, a whole-of-government response, to help more than half a billion people in developing countries adapt to and manage the impacts of climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he also &#8212; the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we often forget &#8212; not you, maybe, but some of us &#8212; that it will strengthen our nation’s resilience &#8212; that’s a big part of it &#8212; to extreme weather and climate change while reducing greenhouse gas emissions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we absolutely need to do more.&nbsp; We want to do more.&nbsp; But we have &#8212; he has already taken some steps to help address because we recognize that resilience is something that there needs to be more work and effort on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The administration has been studying for months the impact of the sanctions that were rolled out over the weekend and their potential impact on financial markets in the West.&nbsp; You just detailed what happened in the Russian markets, but I&#8217;m wondering if there&#8217;s been any fallout that&#8217;s been seen that would warrant government intervention by central banks in Western countries.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In Europe or in the United States?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In either.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can only speak to the United States.&nbsp; I mean, I think that our effort &#8212; and, as you noted, we have been preparing and studying and analyzing for months now.&nbsp; As you know, Russia is, I think, our 26th-largest trading partner; it&#8217;s not an enormous trading partner of ours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve obviously been taking steps to mitigate any impacts on our markets.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not trying to tank our markets, to state, kind of, the obvious here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to maximize the impact on the Russian economy and squeeze around President Putin.</p>



<p>In terms of analysis, otherwise, I would point to the Treasury Department and European officials.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Pentagon has also said that President Putin and Russian forces continue to advance on Kyiv, that that is still the ultimate goal of President Putin.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m wondering, with all of the sanctions that have already been rolled out, what else can the U.S do besides wait?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, we have provided an additional enormous package of security assistance &#8212; the President announced over the weekend.&nbsp; We have provided an enormous package of humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re continuing to plus up support for our neighbors in the region.&nbsp; That is &#8212; we continue to be the largest provider of all of those, and we continue to have the backs of the Ukrainian leadership and the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Zelenskyy says the next 24 hours are critical, though. &nbsp;So is there a risk that all of that equipment ends up in Russian hands?&nbsp; How do you prevent that?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s always steps the Department of Defense takes to mitigate that, and we take them in &#8212; in coordination with our partners.&nbsp; I would have you speak with them about more specifics.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Oh &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wanted to ask for more specifics on refugees.&nbsp; I know that you told Kristen just now that the U.S. will accept refugees from Ukraine.&nbsp; Do you have a specific number of refugees?&nbsp; And what &#8212; how would you determine that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s &#8212; I would first note that we &#8212; we continue to believe that the vast, vast majority will go to Europe.&nbsp; And so, this is different from other conflicts where that has not been the &#8212; the likely outcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; in terms of specific numbers, we do not have that.&nbsp; There are refugee programs that they would have to, of course, apply for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a question about Temporary Protected Status, whether that applies to refugee &#8212; people who are in &#8212; not refugees, but people who are in the United States right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, again, what our focus is on &#8212; because we think it will impact the vast majority of refugees &#8212; is working in close coordination with our European partners and plussing up our humanitarian assistance and assistance in these countries where they&#8217;re &#8212; where they are receiving refugees.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also wanted to ask about voting.&nbsp; Texas has an election coming up, and they&#8217;re beginning to have people who vote by mail &#8212; their ballots being rejected.&nbsp; I know this administration has been very vocal about new voting laws that it disagrees with.&nbsp; Can you talk about what you, as an administration, are doing to leverage the resources of the White House and of the executive branch to help people get access to voting in the coming weeks, not just in Texas but around the country, as elections get going?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, we absolutely can get you a readout of that.&nbsp; I would say, though, that the vast majority of this is going to come from the Democratic National Committee and the political arm.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So, I would really point you to them for more specifics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I just have two quickies on Ukraine.&nbsp; First of all, with the upcoming ASEAN Summit, does President Biden hope to use this summit to shore up support &#8212; I guess you could say, in opposition to Ukraine &#8212; in opposition to Russia, or however you want to put it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And how does the administration feel about Myanmar&#8217;s support of Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, for any country, what our message is, is that it&#8217;s important to deter- &#8212; to think about what place &#8212; where you want to stand on the side of history, and that is how you will be judged moving forward.&nbsp; And obviously, we are encouraging every country who has &#8212; who has not been condemning the actions of Russia to change course.</p>



<p>As it relates to the ASEAN Summit, which is in a couple of weeks, I don&#8217;t have anything about the agenda at this point in time.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re certainly not waiting to communicate &#8212; the President is not waiting to communicate with &#8212; or our national security team is not waiting to communicate with ASEAN countries about steps they can take to help be a part of the solution here, whether it is providing &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen a lot of progress on this front &#8212; LNG gas access to European countries that they don&#8217;t need, or condemning the actions, or putting in place sanctions and steps themselves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, quickly, just on sanctions: Every round of sanctions the administration describes is &#8220;the harshest yet,&#8221; &#8220;the strictest yet.&#8221;&nbsp; But President Putin is not responding to these so far.&nbsp; And so, what &#8212; what happens next?&nbsp; Do you have anything else in your tool belt?&nbsp; Because, I mean, these all seem very severe, and it boggles the mind as to what more you can do.&nbsp; So, what else do &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We always have more we can do.&nbsp; But I would say that what we&#8217;re seeing, in terms of the impact on the financial markets in Russia, is significant.&nbsp; And I outlined some of the impacts, of course, on the ruble, on inflation, on central bank lending there in Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of these steps squeeze not just President Putin, but squeeze the people around him and have a huge, devastating impact on the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they are more significant.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve built them more significant over time.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what they&#8217;re intended to do &#8212; is to have those consequences that build over the course of time.</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  I will see you all tomorrow.  Thank you, everyone, very much. </p>



<p>4:24 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Celebration to Mark Black History&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/28/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-celebration-to-mark-black-history-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:43 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT: &#160; Well, Cateo, I tell you what, you didn&#8217;t there &#8212; we have a little ongoing thing in &#8212; in the administration.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; As you&#8217;ve mentioned, there are a fair number of African Americans in high places in my administration, but &#8212; and I&#8217;m always hearing about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>East Room</em></p>



<p>2:43 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp; Well, Cateo, I tell you what, you didn&#8217;t there &#8212; we have a little ongoing thing in &#8212; in the administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you&#8217;ve mentioned, there are a fair number of African Americans in high places in my administration, but &#8212; and I&#8217;m always hearing about Howard &#8212; great school; I&#8217;m hearing about Morgan men; I&#8217;m hearing about &#8212; you know, all these other things.&nbsp; But I keep talking about it: Delaware State.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And although I went to the University of Delaware, I tell you &#8212; there&#8217;s an old expression: &#8220;I tell you who brung me to the dance.&#8221;&nbsp; Delaware State University is in the southern &#8212; the middle of my state &#8212; in Dover, Delaware.&nbsp; And the lower &#8212; we have the eighth-largest Black population in America, as a percent of the population.&nbsp; And the lower two counties are fairly conservative compared to the northern county.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I &#8212; I operated out of Delaware State for a significant portion of my career and campaign, as the gentlewoman from the state of Delaware can tell you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there was a guy named Tony Allen who used to work for me &#8212; worked for me for years.&nbsp; He went out and he got his PhD.&nbsp; Then he left and became a president.&nbsp; You know, he&#8217;s now &#8212; Tony, stand up &#8212; president of Delaware State University.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I learned a long time, from good friends of mine in Delaware in the Civil Rights community, that if you want to know where the real power in America lies, it&#8217;s in the Divine Nine.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We&#8217;re in the only administration in history that actually has an office.&nbsp; Right, Jim?&nbsp; We have a Divine Nine office.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I &#8212; I understand &#8212; I understand, as they say, who &#8220;brung me to the dance.&#8221;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And all kidding aside, you&#8217;re going to be incredible, old buddy.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to do well.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to do very well.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, you know, there is a &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if they&#8217;ve been introduced, but my Secretary of Defense &#8212; Secretary Austin &#8212; stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Secretary of Housing, Secretary Fudge.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administrator &#8212; the guy who&#8217;s running and taking care of the EPA and all the rest &#8212; from Carolina &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; Administrator Regan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Acting Director of OMB &#8212; the woman who has all &#8212; controls all the money &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; Shalanda &#8212; Shalanda Young.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a woman who &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; has let the whole world know who we are.&nbsp; No, really.&nbsp; A woman who has been so incredibly effective in her job.&nbsp; But it wasn&#8217;t until recently &#8212; until the outrage of Putin and Soviet Union &#8212; and the Soviet Union &#8212; trying to re-establish the Soviet Union, basically, but &#8212; and Russia.&nbsp; To hear her, to listen to her run the debates on &#8212; at the Security Council, as well as the General Assembly at the United Nations &#8212; Linda Greenhouse [sic] &#8212; Thomas-Greenfield.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a woman who knows a little bit about the economy &#8212; Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers, Ceci- &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I kid her all the time, being from Princeton, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; (inaudible).&nbsp; Cecilia, congratulations.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Mr. Secretary &#8212; I&#8217;m talking about Cateo right now &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I think they&#8217;re ready to elect you anything you want to be, pal.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I want to welcome everyone to the White House.&nbsp; This has been &#8212; it&#8217;s been a long drought, the last year and a half, not being able to have not just Black History Month, we weren&#8217;t &#8212; not able to have any gathering here at the White House of any crowd at all.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s good to have you back.&nbsp; It&#8217;s wonderful to be able to host this event in person.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it’s great to see so many friends.&nbsp; If I begin calling out &#8212; calling the roll, we&#8217;ll be all night here, and I don&#8217;t want to do that.&nbsp; But so many significant leaders who&#8217;ve changed the face of America sitting in the audience, not on this stage.&nbsp; So, thank you all so very, very, very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; I&#8217;m Jill Biden&#8217;s husband.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; As you&#8217;ve already figured out, I can&#8217;t dance.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I do it, but I ain&#8217;t good at it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; oh man, you have great opportunities now, don&#8217;t you, Jilly.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tomorrow, I&#8217;m going to be delivering the State of the Union Address.&nbsp; And today, I simply want to thank you for all you’ve done for me, for all of the country.&nbsp;&nbsp; So much has been accomplished in the people in this room.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Black History Month is more than a celebration.&nbsp; It’s a powerful, powerful reminder that Black history is American history.&nbsp; Black culture is American culture.&nbsp; Black stories are essentially an ongoing story of America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I see it every day with the Vice President and the incredible job she&#8217;s doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We see it in the Black members of the Cab- &#8212; my Cabinet and the White House staff who are here today, who serve to defend the nation; protect the planet; build the economy; deliver housing, jobs, and justice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we see it the tireless, heroic efforts of the Congressional Black Caucus.&nbsp; And I want to &#8212; I&#8217;m going to embarrass him, but I want &#8212; the former Chairman of the Black Caucus has come over to help me run things.&nbsp; Cedric, stand up.&nbsp; Let everybody see you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I used to &#8212; I never played golf until I was 46 years old.&nbsp; I got to be pretty good.&nbsp; Then I &#8212; and I asked Cedric to help me in my campaign.&nbsp; Then I played golf, and he beat the hell out of me.&nbsp; I wish I had never done it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I don’t know.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so many state and local leaders and faith leaders here &#8212; lawyers, educators &#8212; that are here today.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, of course, we see another first in the nomination of Ketanji &#8212; well, you saw her.&nbsp; I guess you saw Justice Brown &#8212; Justice Brown Jackson, who is on the &#8212; on the Circuit Court of Appeals right now.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She is an incredible woman.&nbsp; This is a woman who graduated magna cum laude from Harvard.&nbsp; She graduated &#8212; she was editor of the Law Review.&nbsp; She has done so many other things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I want to make it clear: Not only is she is eminently qualified, there were so many others I had to choose from.&nbsp; I can tell you, Jim &#8212; Jim is &#8212; supported all the nominees, but the one he most supported (inaudible) &#8212; I&#8217;ve already nominated her to be on the Circuit Court of Appeals, the second-highest court in the nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But Judge &#8212; Judge Jackson is going to be an outstanding justice.&nbsp; She&#8217;s part of an incredible group of Black women who I’ve nominated to the federal bench.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve nominated more Black women to the federal bench than any administration in the history of the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I made that commitment when I was running for President, and I&#8217;ve tried to keep that commitment my whole career.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, and the first executive order I signed when I came into office &#8212; and it was with Cedric&#8217;s help.&nbsp; I sat down, put pencil to paper &#8212; or pen to paper, and signed a &#8212; I instructed every single element of my administration, every department, from the Defense Department to the &#8212; to the Justice Department and on, that equity should be the center of our &#8212; all of what we do.&nbsp; And we did that in the COVID-19 response.&nbsp; Remember at the beginning, everyone was concerned whether or not, as usual, African Americans would be left behind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, we helped Black &#8212; they &#8212; we helped raise the vaccination rate among Black Americans and bring it on par with white adults.&nbsp; All &#8212; the same across the board.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank the members of the Black Coalition Against COVID represented here today as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I also want to thank Derrick Jones, also as D-Nice &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; for being &#8212; stand up, man.&nbsp; Let them see who you are.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; He provided the soundtrack of hope to keep our spirits up during the worst days of that pandemic.&nbsp; And thank you, thank you, thank you, man.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know, when I took office, I said, “the American story depends not on&#8221; how many of us &#8212; &#8220;any one of us, not on some of us, but on all of us.”&nbsp; “On all of us.”&nbsp; So, we’re investing in all of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So many of you here helped enact the American Rescue Plan to deliver immediate economic relief with Rescue checks, to tax cuts, to eliminate &#8212; and the estimate is that we’ve cut Black poverty by over 30 percent.&nbsp; We’ve reduced child poverty by more than 50 percent in the Black community.</p>



<p>The American Rescue Plan also included historic funding that allowed cities and states to invest in community violence intervention programs and keep neighborhoods safe.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, you were critical in getting the Infrastructure Law passed &#8212; a bipartisan bill that’s going to get &#8212; that’s going to do so much.&nbsp; It’s going to replace decades of disinvestment in the United States of America.&nbsp; A commitment to reconnecting communities and people and job opportunities.&nbsp; Lots &#8212; so much of what they &#8212; the early investments in highways and in interstates &#8212; they cut neighborhoods in half.&nbsp; They divided things.&nbsp; We can put it back together again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Clean water.&nbsp; High-speed Internet.&nbsp; It’s going to &#8212; we’re going to eliminate every lead pipe in America so our children don’t have to worry about whether they&#8217;re drinking poison water, in effect.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as part of that law, we made Minority Business Development Agency permanent and seeded it with $110 million so Black businesses can get the capital they need to grow.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I’m also proud to be joined by Opal Lee, when &#8212; we made the Juneteenth the first federal holiday in the last 40 years.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s good to see Ms. Lee here.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we’ve made landmark investments of $5.8 billion in Historic Black Colleges and Universities not just because we’ve got some serious advocates for Howard and Morehouse &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and other HBCUs you’ve heard of, like Delaware and others.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But all &#8212; but all kidding aside, because they offer so much promise to the nation &#8212; so much promise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s good to see the many HBCU leaders here tonight, including Dr. Devona Williams of Delaware State; Tony Allen &#8212; I mean, Tony of Delaware State, chair of the Board of Advisors of HBCUs.</p>



<p>And, look &#8212; and I want all of you to know, we’re ready to closely investigate the cowardly, un-American bomb threats against HBCUs.&nbsp; That’s underway.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have so much more to do as a nation on making everyday things more accessible and affordable.&nbsp; As my friend Jim Clyburn says, “That’s the test of whether government delivers.”&nbsp; Are they accessible and affordable?&nbsp; Prescription drugs.&nbsp; Child care.&nbsp; Housing.&nbsp; Make healthcare more affordable and make progress on Black maternal health, something that Kamala has been leading the effort on.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; To end cancer as we know it by putting science and technology to work to address the inequities in testing and diagnosis and access to care.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we’ve got work to do to deliver police and criminal justice reform as well.&nbsp; Even though Congress isn’t acting, we are making changes in federal law enforcement policies: banning chokeholds, restrictions on no-knock warrants, requirements on federal &#8212; for federal agents to wear and activate their body cameras, ending the Department of Justice’s use of private prisons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of this is being &#8212; is happening.&nbsp; And the Justice Department has opened pattern-and-practice investigations for systemic police misconduct in several key police departments in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve just got to stay on it.&nbsp; With your help, we’re going to keep pushing on this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we &#8212; we’re protecting our country’s threshold liberty, the sacred right to vote, which I’ve never seen as under such attack.&nbsp; You know, it’s always made it harder for Blacks to vote, but this is trying to be able to figure out how to keep the Black vote, when it occurs, from even counting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the past year, we’ve directed federal agencies to promote access to voting.&nbsp; We’ve &#8212; we’ve appointed top civil rights advocates to help the U.S. Department of Justice, which is &#8212; has doubled the number of voting rights enforcement on &#8212; enforcement folks on their staff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, again, we call on Congress: Pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Pass the Freedom to Vote Act.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We can do this.&nbsp; The American people agree with us &#8212; Black and white, Hispanic and all.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me conclude with this.&nbsp; Look &#8212; I don’t want to take much more of your time, but let me conclude with this: I know progress can be slow and frustrating.&nbsp; But I also know it’s possible if we work together, if we keep the faith, if we remember the changes and the charges that have passed down to us from all those who came before us &#8212; many sitting in this room right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’ve heard &#8212; you know, as you‘ve heard, we had a wonderful exhibit downstairs celebrating Black History Month.&nbsp; And I want to thank Lonnie Bunch and the Smithsonian, as well as the Library of Congress for their &#8212; giving us access to their collection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I introduced Judge Jackson on Friday out in the hallway here, I thought about the display that holds the signature of the Judicial Oath of Office sworn and signed by Thurgood Marshall himself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It was Justice Marshall who reminded us, in a speech shortly before he died, and I quote, “America can do better because America has no choice but to do better.”&nbsp; “America has no choice but to do better.”&nbsp; It’s a powerful reminder of the history of the journey of America and the power each of us hold to write a more just and hopeful chapter.&nbsp; And I really mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am more optimistic about our chances to bring equity to this country than we ever have before now.</p>



<p>And if you wonder about it, just take a look &#8212; take a look at the dif- &#8212; the reason I have so much hope is the younger generation.&nbsp; Those folks be &#8212; they learn from grade school through 30 years of age.&nbsp; Look at what&#8217;s going on.&nbsp; Look at how they act with one another.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not this isolation.&nbsp; There is everything you see &#8212; everything you see from television commercials, down to how we act with one another.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have so much going for us.&nbsp; We got to just let them have their shot.</p>



<p>Folks, I want to thank you all for being here.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I want to thank you for all you&#8217;ve done, all that we can do, and being committed that we&#8217;re going to do so much more.</p>



<p>So thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you all.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>(The President and First Lady move to exit.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, should Americans be worried about nuclear war?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p> 3:00 P.M. EST                 </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of&#160;Turkey</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-ibrahim-kalin-spokesperson-and-chief-advisor-to-the-president-of-turkey-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Dr. Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey.  They discussed their shared commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression and the importance of a coordinated international response to the crisis. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Dr. Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey.  They discussed their shared commitment to supporting Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression and the importance of a coordinated international response to the crisis.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
