<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:07:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on Senior Administration Official Travel to&#160;Colombia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-senior-administration-official-travel-to-colombia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer will travel to Colombia July 21-22 for official meetings with President Ivan Duque, President-Elect Gustavo Petro, and Vice President-Elect Francia Marquez. He will be accompanied by National Security Advisor to the Vice President Phil Gordon, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian Nichols, and National Security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Principal Deputy National Security Advisor Jon Finer will travel to Colombia July 21-22 for official meetings with President Ivan Duque, President-Elect Gustavo Petro, and Vice President-Elect Francia Marquez. He will be accompanied by National Security Advisor to the Vice President Phil Gordon, Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs Brian Nichols, and National Security Council Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere Juan Gonzalez. The delegation will engage in discussions on a range of issues including combatting climate change, support for peace implementation and rural development, working together to reduce violence and combat criminal groups, advancing equitable and sustainable economic growth for both our countries, and other regional and global issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Safer America&#160;Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/fact-sheet-president-bidens-safer-america-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden knows what works to make our communities safer: investing in community policing and crime prevention. We need to fund police who walk the beat, know the neighborhood, are accountable to those they are sworn to serve, and build community trust and safety. We need to invest in mental health and substance use treatment&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden knows what works to make our communities safer: investing in community policing and crime prevention. We need to fund police who walk the beat, know the neighborhood, are accountable to those they are sworn to serve, and build community trust and safety. We need to invest in mental health and substance use treatment services, crisis responders, and social workers to reduce the burden on police officers and prevent violent crime. We need to expand community violence interventions – led by trusted messengers breaking the cycle of violence and trauma. We need to enforce our commonsense gun laws, require background checks for all gun sales in order to keep firearms out of the hands of felons and domestic abusers, and ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines – weapons of war that have no place in our communities.<br><br>President Biden has taken action to make our communities safer during his first 18 months in office:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Funded the police and improved police accountability</strong>. Other politicians talk about funding the police, but President Biden and Congressional Democrats actually got it done by enacting the American Rescue Plan (ARP). <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/fact-sheet-president-biden-issues-call-for-state-and-local-leaders-to-dedicate-more-american-rescue-plan-funding-to-make-our-communities-safer-and-deploy-these-dollars-quickly/">Over $10 billion in ARP funds</a> have already been committed to policing and other public safety efforts – including at least $6.5 billion in State and Local funds committed in more than 300 communities across the country. Along with ongoing support from the Justice Department, ARP investments made 2021 among the largest single-year commitments of federal resources for state and local law enforcement and public safety on record. President Biden also signed a historic <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/25/executive-order-on-advancing-effective-accountable-policing-and-criminal-justice-practices-to-enhance-public-trust-and-public-safety/">executive order</a> to advance effective, accountable policing that will build public trust and strengthen public safety. Leading civil rights organizations and law enforcement organizations such as the International Association of Chiefs of Police and the Fraternal Order of Police support this order.<br></li><li><strong>Tackled gun violence</strong>. President Biden is implementing his comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">strategy</a> to reduce gun crime. The Biden Administration has taken <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-21-executive-actions-to-reduce-gun-violence/">more executive action</a> to reduce gun violence than any other president at this point in their Administration, including by reining in the proliferation of ghost guns and cracking down on gun traffickers and rogue gun dealers. The President was the first president in nearly 30 years to bring together Members of Congress from both parties to take action on gun violence, signing the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act. The President also secured Senate confirmation of career prosecutor Steve Dettelbach to serve as Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, empowering this law enforcement agency with its first confirmed leader since 2015.<br></li><li><strong>Investing in community-led crime prevention and intervention.</strong> States and cities across the country have used ARP funding to invest in public safety strategies such as summer jobs for young adults and substance use and mental health services. Through the bipartisan budget deal and the Bipartisan Safer communities Act, the President has secured $300 million to expand community violence interventions. The Biden Administration has also made changes to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/07/fact-sheet-more-details-on-the-biden-harris-administrations-investments-in-community-violence-interventions/">26 different federal programs</a> to direct additional funding to evidence-based violence interventions. And, the Department of Labor is <a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/eta/eta20220307">investing in job programs</a> to help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities.</li></ul>



<p>The President believes we can and must do more to reduce crime and save lives. Today, President Biden is building on this progress with his Safer America Plan<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/budget_fy2023.pdf">. President Biden’s fiscal year 2023 budget</a> requests a fully paid-for new investment of approximately $35 billion to support law enforcement and crime prevention – in addition to the President’s $2 billion discretionary request for these same programs. The plan he is releasing today outlines, for the first time, how this $37 billion will be used to save lives and make communities safer.<br><br>Specifically, the Safer America Plan:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Funds the police and promotes effective prosecution of crimes affecting families today.</strong> The Safer America Plan will provide communities the resources they need to keep our streets safe, including by helping them hire and train 100,000 additional police officers for accountable community policing (nearly $13 billion over the next five years through the COPS Hiring Program) and setting aside dedicated funds for small law enforcement agencies. At the same time, this plan will invest nearly $3 billion to help communities clear court backlogs and solve murders so we can take shooters and other violent criminals off the streets, including by helping communities set up task forces to share intelligence to bring down the gun violence rate. The plan also aims to crack down on other serious crimes affecting families today. The plan will impose tougher penalties for fentanyl trafficking. To tackle organized retail theft, the plan calls on Congress to pass legislation to require online marketplaces, like Amazon, to verify third-party sellers’ information, and to impose liability on online marketplaces for the sale of stolen goods on their platforms.<br></li><li><strong>Invests in crime prevention and a fairer criminal justice system. </strong>The Safer America Plan will invest in services that address the causes of crime and reduce the burdens on police so they can focus on violent crime, including mental health and substance use disorder services; crisis responders, violence interrupters, and social workers; and expanding access to job training, education, housing, and other supportive services that prevent crime and advance equity. The Plan establishes a new $15 billion grant program called Accelerating Justice System Reform that cities and states can use over the next 10 years to advance strategies that will: (1) prevent violent crime and/or (2) ease the burden on police officers by identifying non-violent situations that may merit a public health response or other response. It also invests an additional $5 billion in evidence-based community violence intervention programs. The plan proposes to end the crack-powder disparity, making the fix retroactive. The plan will help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter society, including by lifting nearly all restrictions on eligibility and access to vital federal benefits and programs that people need to get back on their feet after leaving incarceration.<br></li><li><strong>Takes additional commonsense steps on guns</strong> <strong>to keep dangerous firearms out of dangerous hands. </strong>The President has already proposed to increase funding for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) by 13% so ATF can hire new agents and investigators to help cities trace firearms and analyze ballistics from crime scenes. The President will also continue to call on Congress to take additional actions on guns, including requiring background checks for all gun sales, banning assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, closing the dating violence restraining order loophole, and banning the manufacture, sale, or possession of unserialized “ghost guns.”</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Harris Marks Important New Milestone in Administration’s Efforts to Cut Costs for American&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-highlights-milestone-of-1-million-new-participants-on-reducing-high-speed-internet-cost-for-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President announces that since GetInternet.gov launch in May, Administration has signed up 1 million new households to save hundreds of dollars a year on internet service Access to high-speed internet is no longer a luxury. Still, too many families go without high-speed internet because of the cost or have to cut back on other&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President announces that since GetInternet.gov launch in May, Administration has signed up 1 million new households to save hundreds of dollars a year on internet service</em></p>



<p>Access to high-speed internet is no longer a luxury. Still, too many families go without high-speed internet because of the cost or have to cut back on other essentials to make their monthly internet service payments.  That’s why President Biden and Vice President Harris worked with Democrats, Republicans, and Independents to include the Affordable Connectivity Program (ACP) in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which <a href="https://www.internetforall.gov/">provides $65 billion</a> to expand internet for all — to ensure that every American has access to reliable and affordable high-speed internet.  <br><br>The ACP, administered by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), provides eligible households up to $30/month (or $75/month on Tribal lands) off internet bills, as well as a one-time $100 discount off a connected device. To further lower costs, in May, President Biden and Vice President Harris announced commitments from internet service providers across the country to offer high-speed plans that are fully covered by the ACP—meaning millions of working families can now get high-speed internet without paying a dime. They simultaneously launched <a href="https://getinternet.gov/">GetInternet.gov</a>—a one-stop shop to check eligibility and sign up.<br><br>Today in North Carolina, Vice President Harris is announcing that, <strong>thanks to the Administration’s “all of government” enrollment drive,1 million new households have signed up to save on home broadband through the ACP.</strong><br>The Administration’s efforts increased the rate of ACP enrollments by about 35%.<br><br>To build on this success, today the Vice President called on the nation’s governors to join the Administration’s enrollment drive, sending them letters describing key steps they can take to boost enrollment in their states. For example, today, the State of North Carolina committed to email 5 million households to let them know they can lower their internet bill by visiting GetInternet.gov to check eligibility and sign up.<br><br><br><strong><u>THE BIDEN-HARRIS ADMINISTRATION’S “ALL OF GOVERNMENT” ENROLLMENT DRIVE</u></strong><br><br><strong><em>Partnering with state and local governments</em></strong>: The Vice President’s call to action today builds on the Administration’s existing successful partnerships with state and local governments to spread the word. For example:</p>



<ul><li>Michigan texted about 1.3 million likely eligible Michiganders and gained 25,000 new ACP enrollees as a result.</li><li>Albemarle County, Virginia now includes a “P.S.” about GetInternet.gov in every client communication by county social service workers.</li><li>Massachusetts recently texted more than 1 million Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) and Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) beneficiaries about GetInternet.gov and saw their rate of enrollments double in the five days following the text.</li><li>The City of Mesa, Arizona reports that constituents who hear about ACP are extremely interested. Mesa’s texts to residents about GetInternet.gov have a 10% clickthrough rate, as compared to a usual 1-5% rate for other Mesa governmental outreach.</li><li>New York City sent backpack flyers about ACP home via 1,700 principals to reach about 1 million children who attend Free and Reduced-Price School Lunch Community-Eligible Schools, and it will advertise GetInternet.gov at bus stops in zip codes with a high number of households likely eligible for ACP.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Leveraging all of the federal government</em></strong>: In addition to working with state and local partners, the Administration is using every tool in its toolbox to get the word out—including communicating directly with households that are automatically eligible for ACP due to their participation in other federal government programs. For example:</p>



<ul><li>The Social Security Administration (SSA) emailed all 1.7 million Supplemental Security Income recipients who have a “my social security” account letting them know that they are eligible for ACP. SSA plans to send a second email to recipients this summer. The agency is also running PSAs on Social Security Television, broadcast in more than 1,200 local social security offices nationwide.</li><li>This summer, the Department of Education will email over 6 million Pell grant recipients who are eligible for ACP. It will also conduct a Back-To-School campaign with information about ACP.</li><li>The Department of Veterans Affairs sent information to its 12 million VetResources email subscribers and 120 Community Veteran Engagement Boards, as Veterans Pension and Survivors Benefit recipients are eligible for ACP. This summer the Veterans Benefits Administration will also directly mail all 380,000 Veterans and Survivors currently receiving pension benefits a notification letter and flyer.</li><li>The Department of Housing and Urban Development emailed over 3,000 Public Housing Authorities with information about the ACP to share with their over 3 million families who receive Federal Public Housing Assistance and are eligible, and is currently doing follow-up engagement.</li><li>The Department of the Interior’s Bureau of Trust Funds Administration reached out to over 400,000 beneficiaries with a direct mailing to let them know about ACP. The Department also trained over 200 call center and field staff who work at the Bureau of Trust Funds Administration to disseminate information and answer questions about eligibility and how to enroll in ACP.</li><li>Broadband infrastructure grant programs operated by the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Commerce are all requiring grant funding recipients to participate in the ACP, helping ensuring federal funds are used to deploy networks that are actually affordable.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Working with advocates and digital navigators</em></strong>: The Administration is also working with trusted community leaders to get the word out and enroll eligible households. For example:</p>



<ul><li>The FCC has registered over 40,000 individuals and organizations to be ACP outreach partners. To build on these efforts, the FCC is in the process of standing up a new grant program to empower partners to engage their communities and has reserved up to $100 million of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding to conduct ACP outreach efforts, including consumer research, focus groups, paid media campaigns, and grants to outreach partners over the next five years.</li><li>The Administration partnered with civil rights groups to kick off a Week of Action in June, in which the Leadership Conference and partner civil rights organizations reached out to communities to encourage households to sign up for ACP.</li><li>Thanks to Administration outreach, United Way will share information about ACP in communications reaching at least 15,000 people per month.</li><li>The Administration also worked with Propel, a financial technology platform used by SNAP beneficiaries that reaches over 5 million low-income households. Propel is running an ACP promotion campaign through July.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>THE AFFORDABLE CONNECTIVITY PROGRAM (ACP)</u></strong></p>



<p>The ACP is a key part of the Administration’s <a href="https://www.internetforall.gov/">Internet for All</a> initiative and the largest internet affordability program in our nation’s history. Experts estimate that&nbsp;<a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/610831a16c95260dbd68934a/t/62785ccb671629771cd1a60d/1652055243247/Broadband-Connectivity-Fact-Sheet-CPSP-2022.pdf">48 million households</a>—or nearly 40% of households in the country—qualify for the ACP either because their income is at or below 200% of the Federal Poverty Level, or because a member of the household meets one of the other criteria below:</p>



<ul><li>Participates in one of the following programs:<ul><li>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as Food Stamps</li><li>Medicaid</li><li>Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC)</li><li>Supplemental Security Income (SSI)</li><li>Federal Public Housing Assistance (FPHA)</li><li>Veterans Pension and Survivors Benefit</li><li>Free and Reduced-Price School Lunch Program or School Breakfast Program, including at U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) Community Eligibility Provision schools</li><li>Federal Pell Grant (received in the current award year)</li><li>Lifeline</li><li>Certain Tribal assistance programs, including Bureau of Indian Affairs General Assistance, Head Start (only households meeting the income qualifying standard), Tribal Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (Tribal TANF), and Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations</li></ul></li><li>Meets the eligibility criteria for a participating broadband provider’s existing low-income internet program.</li></ul>



<p>As of now, more than 1,300 internet service providers participate in the program, and about 13 million households have signed up to receive the ACP benefit.<br><br>Households can check their eligibility for ACP, sign up, and find fully covered plans by visiting <a href="https://getinternet.gov/">GetInternet.gov</a>. They can also learn more by calling (877) 384-2575.<br><br>The ACP enrollment drive is just one part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s <a href="https://www.internetforall.gov/">Internet for All Initiative</a> to ensure that every American has access to reliable and affordable high-speed internet. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides a $65 billion investment in high-speed internet access—on top of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-over-25-billion-in-american-rescue-plan-funding-to-help-ensure-every-american-has-access-to-high-speed-affordable-internet/">billions</a> in funding for high-speed, affordable internet provided by the American Rescue Plan that is currently being deployed across the nation.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Air Force One&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/20/remarks-by-president-biden-after-air-force-one-arrival-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 22:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George’s County, Maryland 5:19 P.M. EDT      THE PRESIDENT:  Thanks for coming up.  That’s going to be a cool plant.  &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, you talked a lot about climate being an emergency today.&#160; Why not just declare it an emergency? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Because I’m running into traps on the totality of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George’s County, Maryland</p>



<p>5:19 P.M. EDT<br><br>     THE PRESIDENT:  Thanks for coming up.  That’s going to be a cool plant. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, you talked a lot about climate being an emergency today.&nbsp; Why not just declare it an emergency?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because I’m running into traps on the totality of the authority I have.&nbsp; I will make that decision soon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what would be the ramifications of doing it?&nbsp; Do you think you&#8217;d be able to do more?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I think I can do more, unless the Congress acts.&nbsp; In the meantime, I can do more, because not enough is being done now.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s still discussions going on about whether or not there will be some action on my climate plan.&nbsp; And that’s &#8212; I&#8217;m told that&#8217;s in play.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll see.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see what happens.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you still have hopes for a legislative agreement with Senator Manchin on climate?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve not spoken to Senator Manchin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, no?&nbsp; No hopes for one?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I do not have an agreement with Senator Manchin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you think it&#8217;s a good idea for Speaker Pelosi to travel to Taiwan this summer?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I think that &#8212; the military thinks it’s not a good idea right now, but I don&#8217;t know what the status of it is.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what about declaring a public health emergency for abortion, sir?&nbsp; Where does that stand?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s in consideration as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Still?&nbsp; That’s still under consideration?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Okay &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, are you pleased with your administration&#8217;s response to monkeypox?&nbsp; Senator Patty Murray today expressed concern to the HHS.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I’ve &#8212; I think we should be doing all that we possibly can.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m getting a report on that on Friday.</p>



<p>Okay?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect to talk to President Xi soon, sir?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;ll be talking to President Xi within the next 10 days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s your take on the next steps for COVID, Mr. President?&nbsp; Cases are going up.&nbsp; What should the country be doing right now?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Getting vaccinated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And for those who aren&#8217;t?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They’ve got a problem.&nbsp; It’s not &#8212; it’s not in their interest or the public’s interest not to get vaccinated.&nbsp; We have the capacity to control it.&nbsp; They should get vaccinated now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you said you’re going to speak to President Xi in the next 10 days.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I didn’t say that.&nbsp; I said I expect to.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Expect to.&nbsp; What will you tell him about tariffs?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll tell him to have a good day.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; What about the student loan decision, sir?&nbsp; People have said that you&#8217;re going to make that decision by the end of August.&nbsp; Where does that stand at this point?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; By the end of August.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you so much.</p>



<p>5:21 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Actions to Tackle the Climate&#160;Crisis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/20/remarks-by-president-biden-on-actions-to-tackle-the-climate-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 22:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brayton Point Power StationSomerset, Massachusetts 2:43 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; And thank you for your patience.&#160; You’ve been sitting out here.&#160; Appreciate &#8212; please, have a seat, if you have one. Well, hello, Massachusetts.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; It’s an honor to be with your outstanding members of Congress today:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Brayton Point Power Station<br>Somerset, Massachusetts</p>



<p>2:43 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; And thank you for your patience.&nbsp; You’ve been sitting out here.&nbsp; Appreciate &#8212; please, have a seat, if you have one.</p>



<p>Well, hello, Massachusetts.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s an honor to be with your outstanding members of Congress today: Senator Ed Markey.&nbsp; Ed?&nbsp; Where’s &#8212; there you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Senator Elizabeth Warren.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Congressman Auchincloss &#8212; -oss.&nbsp; Where is she?&nbsp; There you go, Jake.&nbsp; Bill Keating &#8212; Congressman.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And your great former members and one of my dearest friends, John Kerry, who’s doing a great job leading our international &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Special Presidential Envoy on Climate, traveling the world and talking with an awful lot of people he’s talking into moving more than they’ve been doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And another great Massachusetts nata- &#8212; native, Gina McCarthy.&nbsp; Gina?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There she is.&nbsp; My National Climate Advisor is leading our climate efforts here at home.</p>



<p>It’s an honor to be joined by your neighbor by &#8212; your neighbor from Rhode Island.&nbsp; He’s not a bad guy at all.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I live in his house.&nbsp; Sheldon Whitehouse &#8212; a great champion &#8212; (applause) &#8212; a great champion of the environment.&nbsp; And he’d been banging away at it.</p>



<p>I come here today with a message: As President, I have a responsibility to act with urgency and resolve when our nation faces clear and present danger.&nbsp; And that’s what climate change is about.&nbsp; It is literally, not figuratively, a clear and present danger.</p>



<p>The health of our citizens and our communities is literally at stake.</p>



<p>The U.N.’s leading international climate scientists called the latest climate report nothing less than, quote, “code red for humanity.”&nbsp; Let me say it again: “Code red for humanity.”&nbsp; It’s not a group of political official &#8212; elected officials.&nbsp; These are the scientists.</p>



<p>We see here in America, in red states and blue states, extreme weather events costing $145 billion &#8212; $145 billion in damages just last year &#8212; more powerful and destructive hurricanes and tornadoes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve flown over the vast majority of them out west and down in Louisiana, all across America.&nbsp; It’s a &#8212; it’s amazing to see.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ravaging hundred-year-old droughts occurring every few years instead of every hundred years.&nbsp; Wildfires out west that have burned and destroyed more than 5 million acres &#8212; everything in its path.&nbsp; That is more land than the entire state of New Jersey, from New York down to the tip of Delaware.&nbsp; It’s amazing.&nbsp; Five million acres.</p>



<p>Our national security is at stake as well.&nbsp; Extreme weather is already damaging our military installations here in the States.&nbsp; And our economy is at risk.&nbsp; So we have to act.</p>



<p>Extreme weather disrupts supply chains, causing delays and shortages for consumers and businesses.</p>



<p>Climate change is literally an existential threat to our nation and to the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So my message today is this: Since Congress is not acting as it should &#8212; and these guys here are, but we’re not getting many Republican votes &#8212; this is an emergency. &nbsp;An emergency.&nbsp; And I will &#8212; I will look at it that way.</p>



<p>I said last week and I’ll say it again loud and clear: As President, I’ll use my executive powers to combat climate &#8212; the climate crisis in the absence of congressional actions, notwithstanding their incredible action.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the coming days, my administration will announce the executive actions we have developed to combat this emergency. &nbsp;We need to act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But just take a look around: Right now, 100 million Americans are under heat alert &#8212; 100 million Americans.&nbsp; Ninety communities across America set records for high temperatures just this year, including here in New England as we speak.</p>



<p>And, by the way, records have been set in the Arctic and the Antarctic, with temperatures that are just unbelievable, melting the permafrost. &nbsp;And it’s astounding the damage that’s being done.</p>



<p>And this crisis impacts every aspect of our everyday life.&nbsp; That’s why today I’m making the largest investment ever &#8212; $2.3 billion &#8212; to help communities across the country build infrastructure that is designed to withstand the full range of disasters we’ve been seeing up to today -– extreme heat, drought, flooding, hurricanes, tornadoes.</p>



<p>Right now, there are millions of people suffering from extreme heat at home.&nbsp; So my team is also working with the states to deploy $385 million right now.</p>



<p>For the first time, states will be able to use federal funds to pay for air conditioners in homes, set up community cooling centers in schools where people can get through these extreme heat crises.&nbsp; And I mean people &#8212; and crises that are 100 to 117 degrees.</p>



<p>An Infrastructure Law that your members of Congress have delivered includes $3.1 billion to weatherize homes and make them more energy efficient, which will lower energy cost while keeping America cool in the summer and warm in the winter, and not using too much energy.</p>



<p>And my Department of Labor, led by a guy named <em>Marty Walsh &#8212;</em> (said in Boston accent) &#8212; he talks funny, but he’s a hell of a guy.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But all kidding aside, Marty was a great mayor, and I know &#8212; I know he knows how to get a job done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he’s doing two things for me:</p>



<p>First of all, as Secretary of Labor, he’s developing the first-ever workplace standards for extreme heat, saying, under these cond- &#8212; under these conditions, if it hits this pr- &#8212; you cannot do the following &#8212; you cannot ask people to do a certain thing.</p>



<p>Second, he’s sending folks out from the Labor Department to make sure we hold workplaces and &#8212; to those standards that are being set.&nbsp; They’ve already completed over 500 heat-related inspections of workplaces across 43 states.&nbsp; At the end of the day, it’s going to save lives.</p>



<p>Now, let me tell you why we’re here at Brayton Point.&nbsp; Five years ago, this towering power plant that once stood with cooling towers 500 feet high closed down.&nbsp; The coal plant at Brayton Point was the largest of its kind in New England &#8212; 1,500 megawatts of power, enough to power one in five Massachusetts homes and businesses.</p>



<p>For over 50 years, this plant supported this region’s economy through their electrici- &#8212; the electricity they supplied, the good jobs they provided, and the local taxes they paid.</p>



<p>But the plant, like many others around the country, had another legacy: one of toxins, smog, greenhouse gas emissions, the kind of pollution that contributed to the climate emergency we now face today.</p>



<p>Gina McCarthy, a former regulator in Massachusetts, was telling me on the way up how folks used to get a rag out and wipe the gunk off of their car’s windshields in the morning just to be able to drive &#8212; not very much unlike where I grew up in a place called Claymont, Delaware &#8212; which has more oil refineries than Houston, Texas, had in its region &#8212; just across the line in Pennsylvania.  And all the prevailing winds were our way.<br><br>I just lived up the road.  I just &#8212; in an apartment complex when we moved to Delaware.  And just up the road was a little school I went to, Holy Rosary grade school.  And because it was a four-lane highway that was accessible, my mother drove us and &#8212; rather than us be able to walk.<br><br>And guess what?  The first frost, you knew what was happening.  You had to put on your windshield wipers to get, literally, the oil slick off the window.  That’s why I and so damn many other people I grew up [with] have cancer and why can- &#8212; for the longest time, Delaware had the highest cancer rate in the nation.</p>



<p>But that’s the past, and we’re going to get &#8212; we’re going to build a different future with one &#8212; one with clean energy, good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>Just 15 years ago, America generated more than half its electricity from coal &#8212; coal-fired plants.&nbsp; Today, that’s down to 20 percent because there’s a big transition happening.</p>



<p>Many of these fossil fuel plants are becoming sites for new clean energy construction.&nbsp; Others are switching to new, clean technologies.</p>



<p>Look at Brayton Point.&nbsp; Today, Brayton is one of the frontiers &#8212; on the frontier of clean energy in America.&nbsp; On this site, they’ll manufacture four hun- &#8212; 248 miles of high-tech, heavy-duty cables.&nbsp; Those specialized, subsea cables are necessary to tie offshore wind farms to the existing grid.</p>



<p>Manufacturing these cables will mean good-paying jobs for 250 workers &#8212; as many workers as the old plant &#8212; power plant had at its peak.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the port &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the port here, 34 feet deep, was used to carry coal into the power plant.&nbsp; Now we’re going to use that same port to carry components of &#8212; for wind power into the sea.</p>



<p>The converter station here and the substation nearby are the assets that move energy across the power lines.</p>



<p>They’ll now move clean electricity generated offshore by the wind &#8212; (applause) &#8212; enough power to power hundreds of thousands of homes onto the grid &#8212; putting old assets to work delivering clean energy. &nbsp;This didn’t happen by accident.&nbsp; It happened because we believed and invested in America’s innovation and ingenuity.</p>



<p>One of the companies investing in the factory here joined me at the White House this month.&nbsp; Vineyard Winds, whose CEO told me about the ground-breaking project labor agreements they’ve negotiated, would create good-paying union jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I want to compliment Congressman Bill Keating for his work in this area.</p>



<p>I’m also proud to point out that my administration approved the first commercial project for offshore wind in America, which is being constructed by Vineyard Winds.</p>



<p>Folks, elsewhere in the country, we are pr- &#8212; we are propelling retrofits and ensuring that even where fossil fuel plant retires, they still have a role in powering the future.</p>



<p>In Illinois, for example, the state has launched a broad effort to invest in converting old power plants to solar farms, led by Governor Pritzker.</p>



<p>In California, the IBEW members have helped turn a former oil plant into the world’s largest battery storage facility &#8212; the world’s largest facility.</p>



<p>In Wyoming, innovators are chosen to &#8212; a retiring plant as the next site for the next-generation nuclear plant.</p>



<p>And my administr- &#8212; my administration is a partner in that progress, driving federal resources and funding to the communities that have powered this country for generations.&nbsp; And that’s why they need to be taken care of as well.</p>



<p>I want to thank Cecil Roberts, a friend and President of United Mine Workers of America, and so many other labor leaders who worked with &#8212; worked with on these initiatives.</p>



<p>Since I took office, we’ve invested more than $4 billion in federal funding to the 25 hardest-hit coal communities in the country, from West Virginia, to Kentucky, to Wyoming, to New Mexico.</p>



<p>Through the Infrastructure Law, we’re investing in clean hydrogen, nuclear, and carbon capture with the largest grid investment in American history.</p>



<p>We’ve secured $16 billion to clean up abandoned mines and wells, protecting thousands of communities from toxins and waste, particularly methane.  And we still &#8212; and we’re going to seal leaking methane pollution &#8212; an incredibly power[ful] greenhouse gas that’s 40 times more dangerous to the environment than carbon dioxide.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, folks, with American leadership back on climate, I was able to bring more world leaders together than &#8212; we got 100 nations together to agree that &#8212; at the major conference in Glasgow, England &#8212; I mean, Scotland &#8212; to change the emissions policies we had.</p>



<p>We’ve made real progress, but there is an enormous task ahead.&nbsp; We have to keep retaining and recruiting building trades and union electricians for jobs in wind, solar, hydrogen, nuclear, creating even more and better jobs.</p>



<p>We have to revitalize communities, especially those fence-line communities that are smothered by the legacy of pollution.</p>



<p>We have to outcompete China and in the world, and make these technologies here in the United States &#8212; not have to import them.</p>



<p>Folks, when I think about climate change &#8212; and I’ve been saying this for three years &#8212; I think jobs.&nbsp; Climate change, I think jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Almost 100 wind turbines going up off the coasts of Massachusetts and Rhode Island with ground broken and work underway.</p>



<p>Jobs manufacturing 2,500-ton steel foundations that anchor these offshore wind farms to the sea’s floor. &nbsp;Jobs manufacturing a Jones Act vessel in Texas to service these offshore wind farms.</p>



<p>We’re going to make sure that the ocean is open for the clean energy of our future, and everything we can do &#8212; give a green light to wind power on the Atlantic coast, where my predecessor’s actions only created confusion.</p>



<p>And today we begin the process to develop wind power in the Gulf of Mexico as well for the first time.&nbsp; A real opportunity to power millions of additional homes from wind.</p>



<p>Let’s clear the way &#8212; let’s clear the way for clean energy and connect these projects to the grid.</p>



<p>I’ve directed my administration to clear every federal hurdle and streamline federal permitting that brings these clean energy projects online right now and right away.&nbsp; And some of you have already come up and talked to me about that.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And while so many governors and mayors have been strong partners in this fight to tackle climate change, we need all governors and mayors.&nbsp; We need public utility commissioners and state agency heads.&nbsp; We need electric utilities and developers to stand up and be part of the solution.&nbsp; Don’t be a road block.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You all have a duty right now to our economy, to our competitiveness in the world, to the young people in this nation, and to future generations &#8212; and that sounds like hyperbole but it’s not; it’s real &#8212; to act boldly on climate.</p>



<p>And so does Congress, which &#8212; notwithstanding the leadership of the men and women that are here today &#8212; has failed in this duty.&nbsp; Not a single Republican in Congress stepped up to support my climate plan.&nbsp; Not one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let me be clear: Climate change is an emergency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in the coming weeks, I’m going to use the power I have as President to turn these words into formal, official government actions through the appropriate proclamations, executive orders, and regulatory power that a President possesses.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when it comes to fighting the climate change &#8212; climate change, I will not take no for an answer.&nbsp; I will do everything in my power to clean our air and water, protect our people’s health, to win the clean energy future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This, again, sounds like hyperbole, but our children and grandchildren are counting on us.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If we don&#8217;t keep it below 1.5 degrees Centigrade, we lose it all.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t get to turn it around.&nbsp; And the world is counting on us.&nbsp; And this is the United States of America.&nbsp; When we put our hearts and minds to it, there&#8217;s not a single thing beyond our capacity &#8212; I mean it &#8212; when we act together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And of all things we should be acting together on, it’s climate. &nbsp;It’s climate.</p>



<p>And, by the way, my dear mother &#8212; God rest her soul &#8212; used to say, “Joey, out of everything bad, something good will come if you look hard enough.”&nbsp; Look what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be able to create as many or more good-paying jobs.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make environments where people live safer.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make the clean &#8212; the air safer.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; We have an opportunity here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ll bet you when you see what&#8217;s happened here in this cable construction here &#8212; manufacturing &#8212; and you go back and ask all the people who grew up in this beautiful place what they’d rather have: Do they want the plant back with everything it had, or what you&#8217;re going to have?&nbsp; I will be dumbfounded if you find anybody, other than for pure sentimental reasons, saying, “I&#8217;d rather have the coal plant.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll end by telling you another quick story.&nbsp; When we moved from Scranton &#8212; when coal died in Scranton, everything died in Scranton.&nbsp; And my dad wasn&#8217;t a coal miner.&nbsp; My &#8212; my great &#8212; my great-grandfather was a mining engineer.&nbsp; But my dad was in sales, and there was no work.&nbsp; So we left to go down to Delaware, where I told you where those oil plants were.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I remember driving home &#8212; when you take the trolley in Scranton, going out North Washington and Adams Avenues. &nbsp;Within 15 blocks &#8212; we didn&#8217;t live in the neighborhood &#8212; among the most prestigious neighborhood in the region, in the &#8212; in the town where the Scrantons and other good, decent people lived, there was a pla- &#8212; you&#8217;d go by a wall that &#8212; my recollection is it was somewhere between 15 and 18 feet tall.&nbsp; And it went for the &#8212; essentially, a city block.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you could see the coal piled up to the very top of the wall from inside.&nbsp; It was a coal-fired plant.&nbsp; A coal-fired plant.&nbsp; And all of that &#8212; all of the negative impacts of breathing that coal, the dust were effecting everybody.&nbsp; But at the time, people didn&#8217;t know it and there wasn&#8217;t any alternative.</p>



<p>Folks, we have no excuse now.&nbsp; We know it.&nbsp; There are answers for it.&nbsp; We can make things better in terms of jobs.&nbsp; We can make things better in terms of the environment.&nbsp; We can make things better for families overall.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m looking forward to this movement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy En Route Somerset,&#160;MA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/20/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-climate-advisor-gina-mccarthy-en-route-somerset-ma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Somerset, Massachusetts 12:46 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; It’s is a short flight, so I’m going to be really quick at the top here. Today, the President is headed to Somerset, Massachusetts, to reiterate that climate change is an emergency.&#160; He will make clear that since Congress is not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Somerset, Massachusetts</p>



<p>12:46 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; It’s is a short flight, so I’m going to be really quick at the top here.<br><br>Today, the President is headed to Somerset, Massachusetts, to reiterate that climate change is an emergency.&nbsp; He will make clear that since Congress is not acting on that emergency, he will.<br><br>While there, the President will visit an old, coal-fired power plant in Brayton Point that is becoming a manufacturing hub for undersea cables that will support Massachusetts’s booming offshore wind industry.</p>



<p>The President will be joined by his National Climate Advisor, Gina McCarthy, who is standing right next to me, and Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry &#8212; both Massachusetts natives.<br><br>He will also be joined by Senator Ed Markey, Senator Elizabeth <s>Warner</s> [Warren], Senator Sheldon Whitehouse, Congressman Jake Auchincloss, and Congressman Bill Keating.</p>



<p>With that, I am incredibly excited to welcome National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy, who leads our climate efforts here at home, to talk more about the climate actions the President will be taking today.</p>



<p><br>Gina, it’s all yours.&nbsp; I don’t know if you want to &#8212; you good?<br><br>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; Oh, thank you.&nbsp; Well, first of all, as we now know, the President is going to Brayton Point, which is in Somerset.&nbsp; I would point out that that&#8217;s one of the oldest and largest coal-fired power plants that was in New England, and it closed back in 2017.<br><br>And the reason why we&#8217;re going today is because it really shows that you can turn an old power plant into something new.<br><br>This is about transforming it into a clean manufacturing hub.&nbsp; It is a company that is going to be actually manufacturing cable that connects those offshore wind turbines and keeps them solid and connects them to the grid.<br><br>So it is going to end up with the same kind of workforce as you would have had in the coal facility.&nbsp; And this is one of a number of coal units that are actually transforming themselves.&nbsp; When coal goes out, they&#8217;re beginning to invest in a clean energy future.<br><br>You’ve seen one in California that&#8217;s now focused on battery manufacturing.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to see one in Wyoming that&#8217;s actually moving forward with &#8212; with a new-generation nuclear.&nbsp; And so there&#8217;s a lot going on.&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s an indication that the President is really embracing and working with the private sector to actually have people understand that we are living in the beginning of the clean energy future.&nbsp; And we need to keep moving that forward.<br><br>And one of the actions that the President is going to talk about is a simple recognition that climate change is an emergency.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to indicate that, over the next few weeks, the White House and he are going to come out with executive actions that actually put some definition and some plans around that, because we&#8217;re not ready to give up on our strong goals; we&#8217;re ready to double down to make sure we get those.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And while it&#8217;s disappointing that Congress couldn&#8217;t get it over the finish line, that in no way precludes the President from using the full range of his executive authorities to get us where we need to go.<br><br>And I think the last thing that I would mention is: At the event today at Brayton Point, for good reason, we&#8217;re going to be talking about investments in heat to ensure that people can stay safe.<br><br>There&#8217;s about 100 million-plus people in the world right now that are experiencing tremendous amounts of heat, which is life threatening to so many, particularly our senior citizens.  And heat is actually talked about as the “silent killer” in climate change.  It actually impacts more human beings than all other climate impacts combined.<br><br>And so, right &#8212; the President is going to announce some new investments to allow states to be more prepared and resilient in the face of the heat and to, frankly, save lives, because that&#8217;s what it&#8217;s going to take.<br><br>So you&#8217;re going to be looking at an investment from FEMA that&#8217;s going to be over $2 billion.  And that $2 billion is going to <s>go to</s> [include] support[ing] states who want to build cooling centers so that folks have a place to go when the heat gets hot if they don&#8217;t have the air conditioning.  And, of course, many people don&#8217;t have the wherewithal to afford that or the energy costs that goes with it.<br><br>On &#8212; we&#8217;re also going to &#8212; the Housing and Urban Development Agency is also going to be putting out guidance so that people can easily access LIHEAP dollars, which we all know &#8212; if you lived in Massachusetts, you needed LIHEAP money for the heat.  Well, now we need LIHEAP money in the summer to keep us cool enough to actually st- &#8212; withstand these &#8212; this type of heat.<br><br>And so there&#8217;s resources in the area of 300-plus million [dollars] that &#8212; I think it&#8217;s 380 &#8212; that are going to be allocated to states who want to actually provide opportunities for air conditioning to be purchased through LIHEAP, as well as some reductions in energy costs so that consumers can afford it.<br><br>So those are the kind of efforts that we&#8217;re going to move forward with today and advance them.  And for obvious reasons, it&#8217;s a great backdrop.  It does sort of show off the work that we&#8217;re doing on offshore wind, which is really remarkable and way beyond our expectations.  And we see the same in electric vehicles.<br><br>And one of the best, I think, exciting parts for me in this job is that the President&#8217;s framing of moving forward with &#8212; with clean energy, using innovation and technology improvements, is &#8212; I think it gives us great hope, because the private sector is all in.<br><br>You know, when the President talked to the car industry about electric vehicles, they were the ones that said 100 percent by 2035.  We said 50 percent by 2030.  And then they put in well over $100 billion to start charging stations and electric battery manufacturing units, more &#8212; more manufacturing of electric vehicles.  And we found that the unions jumped on board, because these are the kind of increases in jobs, not decreases, that they were worried about.<br><br>So the framing of the President is really engaging the private sector significantly, because they know that a clean energy future is one that we actually need to provide stability and how we are going to grow our economy, but it&#8217;s also one in which they can actually find the cost-effective way for them to make money.  So once the private sector sees that sweetener in the pot, it&#8217;s great.  And I think that&#8217;s what they see.<br><br>When the President went forward on solar and issued an order under the Defense Production Act, just maybe a month or maybe six weeks ago, the first thing we heard the following week was $6 billion in money that the solar industry was going to put towards domestic manufacturing.  This is what happens when you lead.</p>



<p>And so I&#8217;m pretty excited about today.&nbsp; I know we&#8217;ll have a lot of work to do.&nbsp; And the President will be announcing executive authority efforts and actions moving forward.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll work hard and we&#8217;ll make sure that we cannot just achieve the goals that the President laid out but actually exceed them.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; So let’s &#8212; yep, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gina, can you address how the administration will meet your emissions targets if you don&#8217;t get legislation?&nbsp; I know you say there&#8217;s more executive action coming, but is that enough to meet the very ambitious goals that you set?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; I&#8217;d hope that you&#8217;d wait and see about the plans that we&#8217;re going to outline.&nbsp; But I also find that when &#8212; just in my experience, you know, when you set strong goals, when the private sector is engaged in spending their own money, there&#8217;s a lot &#8212; a lot of ability to accelerate beyond what the economists would anticipate at the moment.</p>



<p>And so while I would have loved to have seen lots more investment, we&#8217;re going to do everything we can to get a strategy in place that&#8217;s going to meet that goal.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the U.S. will meet that commitment, though?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; That’s certainly what our intention is, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about &#8212; can you just walk us through what the thinking is for the administration about why you decided &#8212; why people decided not to declare a climate emergency this week?&nbsp; What was the thinking behind that, from your perspective?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; I think that it was just a decision that we need to be thoughtful about this, and we want to outline actions, not just declare things.</p>



<p>So I think it was just important for the President to get his arms around the various threads of work that we can put together and lay them out in a way that he&#8217;s comfortable with.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what do you see as the pros and cons of that decision, of declaring a climate emergency?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; I think the President is making it very clear today that climate change is an emergency.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s making very clear today that while Congress didn&#8217;t move forward, that just is driving him to move forward with much clearer plans and much larger and more accelerated commitments.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President or the White House have any concerns about potential executive overreach in declaring a climate emergency?&nbsp; Is that one of the considerations?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; I think the considerations are just that the President wants to make sure that we&#8217;re doing this right, that we&#8217;re laying it out, and that we have the time we need to get this work done.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to be sure, the &#8212; just to clarify, the White House does believe that an emergency declaration can be applied to climate as opposed to a singular natural event?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; I would lea- &#8212; I really don&#8217;t want to answer that.&nbsp; All I know is that the President has broad authority in these areas, and he&#8217;s going to utilize the authorities he feels most appropriate.&nbsp; Okay?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May I ask a follow-up to Seung Min’s question?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; I’m not a lawyer, so it’s best if I don’t do that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I could follow up on Seung Min’s question about overreach: Are you thinking at all about the calculus for Senator Manchin and not wanting to potentially alienate him in case he does come back and support climate in a reconciliation package this fall?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Or dur- &#8212; while the healthcare package also moves through the (inaudible).</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; You know, I do not know what Congress is anticipating now or any one senator.&nbsp; But the idea that the President is initiating here is to acknowledge the challenge.&nbsp; He talks a little bit about the science in his remarks to remind people that this is here and now, and he&#8217;s going to take action here and now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give any detail or a sense of how big the toolbox is when it comes to executive actions?&nbsp; You talked about how the President would be taking many in the coming weeks, but just what kind of &#8212; what&#8217;s the breadth of actions that we&#8217;re talking about here?</p>



<p>ADVISOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more de- &#8212; more detailed to announce to you right now.</p>



<p>Anything?&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I really</p>



<p>appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, I think we have to be in our seats by like, what &#8212; like &#8212; in, like, five, six minutes.</p>



<p>All right, I have another topper, and then I&#8217;ll take some questions from you guys.&nbsp; Give me one second.</p>



<p>So, last night, the Senate cleared a procedural hurdle on the CHIPS Act with a strong bipartisan vote: 16 Republicans voted in support of moving the bill forward.&nbsp; This brings up &#8212; this brings us one step closer to passing a package that will lower prices for Americans, strengthen our domestic supply chains and manufacturing power, and bolster our national security.</p>



<p>Importantly, as Speaker Pelosi noted this morning, this package includes strong guardrails.&nbsp; These guardrails would prevent companies from using CHIPS Act money for stock buybacks and from expanding certain types of semiconductor manufacturing in China.</p>



<p>These guardrails will ensure that these important investments stay in the United States.&nbsp; They will sharpen our competitive edge against China and protect our national security.</p>



<p>We look forward to getting a final bill to the President&#8217;s desk and signed as soon as possible.&nbsp; The stakes are high, and there&#8217;s no time to waste.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Since we have a couple minutes, you guys have anything?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I &#8212; there seems to be a lot of momentum, even among Republicans, building behind the same-sex marriage bill that passed the House yesterday.&nbsp; So I wanted to know the White House&#8217;s reaction to that momentum and if the President is going to get personally involved in pushing that bill across the finish line.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, this is something that&#8217;s personal to the President.&nbsp; He has led on this issue for many years.&nbsp; I was just talking to him about this earlier.&nbsp; So he is a &#8212; as I said, a proud champion of the right for people to marry whom they love, and is grateful to see bipartisan support for that right.&nbsp; He believes it is nonnegotiable and that the Senate should act swiftly to get this to the President&#8217;s desk.&nbsp; He wants to get &#8212; he wants to sign this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we need this legislation, and we urge Congress to move as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; and it&#8217;s something the vast majority of the country support, just like they support restoring Roe, stopping a national abortion ban, and protecting the right to use contraception.</p>



<p>To your &#8212; to your specific question: Look, as I &#8212; as I&#8217;ve said many times before, and you hear me say this all the time, our office of Leg Affairs and other offices across the White House are constantly in touch with Congress.&nbsp; This is, again, a very important issue.&nbsp; He led on this issue as a senator.&nbsp; He led as an &#8212; on the issue as a Vice President, and he&#8217;s going to continue to do so as President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just &#8212; Politico reported last night that the White House &#8212; top aides in the White House were growing more comfortable with declaring a public health emergency &#8212; sort of a much more narrow version of it &#8212; when it came to abortion access.&nbsp; And I wonder if you could shed some light on what the thinking is there and what would be the thinking behind sort of doing that &#8212; I think it&#8217;s called PREP &#8212; versus sort of a broader one.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, as you know, we &#8212; we’re not going to go &#8212; get into our private discussions that we have in the White House.&nbsp; The President has said, when it comes to abortion and Roe and fighting for the rights and freedoms and privacy of the American public, everything is on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce at this time.&nbsp; But the President is going to continue to do everything that he can to protect the rights of women and their reproductive health.&nbsp; He has done that by signing an executive order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen announcement from the &#8212; HHS.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen announcements, strong statements from the Department of Justice on what they will do to protect, in particular, women who are &#8212; who travel to get that healthcare that they need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so we&#8217;re &#8212; we have &#8212; we&#8217;re looking at other things that we can do, other meaningful steps that we can take.&nbsp; We just &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have anything to share specific on that thinking and how we&#8217;re going to get to &#8212; get to any announcement that we might be making the next couple of days or sooner.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, do you have any updated thinking or reaction to a trip by Speaker Pelosi to Taiwan?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have much more to say.&nbsp; I spoke to that yesterday.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just not going to speak to any travel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From what I understand, it has not been locked in.&nbsp; But we refer you to her office for any &#8212; anything further.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We continue &#8212; as I said yesterday, you know, the United States remains committed to our One China Policy, which is set forth in Taiwan Relations Act, the Three Joint Communiqués, and Six Assurances.&nbsp; This has been a consistent U.S. position for decades across multiple administration.&nbsp; U.S. support for Taino- &#8212; Taiwan remains rock solid, principled, bipartisan, and it is in line with our, again, One China Policy and longstanding U.S. commitments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; can you provide any preview of the President&#8217;s message on the gun event tomorrow in Wilkes-Barre?&nbsp; Is he going to announce new actions or have a new message when it comes to the issue?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, he&#8217;s going to be traveling to Pennsylvania tomorrow to do his crime &#8212; crime event.&nbsp; And the President will give remarks on building on the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act, which he signed into law last month, and how we can further reduce gun crimes and save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we should have more information to come.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll likely have a backgrounder later tonight so that you guys could get some insight on what the &#8212; what tomorrow is going to look like and our travels.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one last thing.&nbsp; And I know you were asked about this yesterday, but I&#8217;m just &#8212; you know, since it&#8217;s such a fast-moving story on both fronts, I just wanted to ask you again.&nbsp; Is there any concern that if you, sort of &#8212; that there is a desire internally to declare public health emergencies &#8212; like, to declare a climate emergency and a public health emergency a little bit concurrently rather than sort of &#8212;</p>



<p>I think that when I talk to people, it seems like you guys will catch a lot of flak from abortion rights activists if there is, you know, a climate emergency that&#8217;s rolled out fairly quickly after what happened last week with Manchin and, whereas, you know, there has been a lot of wait and see on the public health emergency.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, on &#8212; when it comes to climate change, the per- &#8212; the President &#8212; you&#8217;re going to hear from him today, as Gina just stated, how urgent it is.&nbsp; The urgency is now to do something, and he has been doing &#8212; taking action since very early in his administration, and he&#8217;ll continue to do that.</p>



<p>When it comes to Roe, when it comes to abortion more specifically, the President has taken action on that and made that a priority since Texas S.B. 8 happened a few months ago.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve heard from our administration there on ways that we were going to &#8212; to help to make sure that women are able to make their own decision and get that safe care that they need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, look, everything is on the table.&nbsp; We have not made any decisions yet.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the policy process.&nbsp; I&#8217;m certainly not going to get ahead of the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But these are two issues that are priorities for him, that are important for him.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard from the President directly on Roe and the decision &#8212; that extreme decision that SCOTUS made just a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today you&#8217;re going to hear where he is and how he&#8217;s going to continue to fight for climate change.&nbsp; Because we got to remember climate change is about our economy, it&#8217;s about our national security &#8212; all the things that are so important &#8212; and our families and how do we make sure that we do everything that we can to protect those things.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see you on the ground.</p>



<p>1:06 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on the President&#8217;s Actions to Tackle the Climate&#160;Crisis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/20/background-press-call-on-the-presidents-actions-to-tackle-the-climate-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 19:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:01 A.M. EDT &#160;MR. HASAN:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Thanks for joining us today.&#160; This is Abdullah from the White House. Today, we&#8217;ll be holding a background briefing on the actions the President will announce while in Somerset, Massachusetts, to tackle the climate crisis and seize the opportunity of a clean energy future. As a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:01 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;MR. HASAN:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us today.&nbsp; This is Abdullah from the White House.<br><br>Today, we&#8217;ll be holding a background briefing on the actions the President will announce while in Somerset, Massachusetts, to tackle the climate crisis and seize the opportunity of a clean energy future.<br><br>As a reminder, the call will be on background, attributable to a senior administration official.&nbsp; It will be embargoed until the start of the President&#8217;s remarks in Somerset today.<br><br>Not for reporting purposes but for your awareness, joining us for the call today is [senior administration official].&nbsp; He will deliver some remarks up top, and then we will take your questions.<br><br>Over to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; And really, really excited for an opportunity to talk to you about what the President will be laying out this afternoon in Massachusetts.<br><br>As the President, I think, has said from day one, we really face an urgent crisis in the changing climate.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something that is becoming increasingly manifest across our country, whether it&#8217;s in the wildfires or hurricanes, the extreme flooding events, or &#8212; as is front of mind for the 100 million Americans who face different forms of heat advisories and warnings around the country right now &#8212; extreme heat, which it has shattered 90 records around the country, which is driving folks to face increasingly severe health ailments, putting people in the ER, and which drives home the point that this is a clear and present danger for our country, for our health, for our economy, for our national security.&nbsp; And it demands that we take action boldly.</p>



<p><br>In addition to that recognition that what we face is a challenge, what we face is urgent, what has already been unleashed in terms of climate is devastating &#8212; in addition to making that point, making it vividly and clearly, the President will also talk about the incredible opportunity that we have if we get our act together, square our shoulders, and take on the climate crisis.<br><br>And going to Massachusetts is a great opportunity for him to lay that out in a place that really represents the playbook for what it means to tackle the climate crisis in a way that can unlock tons of opportunity for our workers, for our communities, and for our economy.<br><br>Brayton Point, where the President will speak, used to be the site of the largest coal plant in New England &#8212; 1500 megawatts, burning coal since 1963.<br><br>The President will speak to how we&#8217;ve had these sources of energy that had been critical to our economy over time and that we&#8217;re seeing a transition to clean energy.&nbsp; And if we embrace that transition, then we&#8217;ll see what&#8217;s happening at Brayton Point happening all around the country.<br><br>Today, Brayton Point is poised to be on the frontier of the clean energy transformation.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be manufacturing subsea cables that will help tie offshore wind plants into the grid.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be the place where several wind projects actually tie in to the grid, bringing clean electrons into Massachusetts and into New England from where it&#8217;s being generated off the Atlantic coast.<br><br>So, you know, I think part of what the President wants to do this afternoon is lay out that sense of urgency and the clarity around the impacts that we&#8217;re already seeing, and also to lay out the urgency and the &#8212; and his enthusiasm for tapping into the opportunity that we also have in front of us.<br><br>The other thing that you can anticipate is specific actions underneath both of those things.<br><br>First, on heat, the President will be announcing $2.3 billion in funding through the FEMA Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities Program for fiscal year 2022.<br><br>This is a program that existed prior to this administration.&nbsp; But this is the largest amount of funding under BRIC ever in the history of the country.&nbsp; And not only is it large, it is focused on helping communities build resilience to a broad set of climate impacts, including heat waves, which is particularly salient; doing it in a way that is going to support the administration&#8217;s Justice40 Initiative and make sure that we&#8217;re lifting up communities that have been disadvantaged.<br><br>And then in addition to the announcement on BRIC, the President will be talking about new guidance from the Department of Health and Human Services, which will actually allow communities, acting through the states, of course, to leverage the historic funding that the President has delivered to the LIHEAP program.&nbsp; That is the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program.&nbsp; Used to be something that helped folks deal with heating issues in the wintertime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This administration is broadening that program out, calibrating it to this new climate reality.&nbsp; And with it, states will be able to establish cooling centers, they will be able to help folks buy or lend efficient air conditioning units, help defray the costs that are incurred to keep cool during the summer for these vulnerable populations.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s immediate. &nbsp;That&#8217;s an incredibly important thing to get out there.<br><br>And then on the opportunity side, I think many of you covered when the President brought together state and local leaders, industry leaders, and union leaders together at the White House this past month to launch the Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership.&nbsp; Building on that, the President is going to the Interior Department &#8212; direct the Interior Department to propose the first wind energy areas in the Gulf of Mexico.<br><br>For those keeping score at home &#8212; you know, when we came into office, offshore wind was facing a uncertain future.&nbsp; Not only did this administration approve the first commercial wind project, Vineyard Wind &#8212; which actually is a partner in building this facility at Brayton Point &#8212; but it also opened up these wind energy areas all across the Atlantic, as far south as North Carolina; started opening up wind energy areas on the Pacific; and today we open up yet another coast and frontier in expanding offshore wind.<br><br>And at the same time, the President is also directing the Secretary of Interior to advance wind energy development in the waters off the mid- and southern Atlantic coast and off Florida&#8217;s Gulf Coast, alleviating uncertainty cast by the prior administration.<br><br>So those are some of the actions the President will announce.&nbsp; And bottom line: You know, I think this is a &#8212; this is an opportunity for the President, in part also, to just come out and provide his take on where we are on climate &#8212; on the urgency, on the opportunity.&nbsp; And, of course, he had issued a written statement last week with regard to action in Congress.&nbsp; And this is an opportunity for him to also speak to that.<br><br>So with that, maybe, Abdullah, back to you.</p>



<p><br>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to go into questions now, but just before we do, I forgot to mention at the top, we will have embargoed materials coming around shortly.&nbsp; Sorry you didn’t get them ahead of the call, but they will be coming to you soon.<br><br>With that, we&#8217;ll go ahead and take some questions.&nbsp; If you would like to ask a question, please use the “raise hand” feature at the bottom of your screen.<br><br>Again, if you&#8217;d like to ask a question, please use the “raise hand” feature at the bottom of your screen.<br><br>And for the first question, we&#8217;ll go Coral Davenport.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing the call.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], in addition to making these announcements, is he going to talk about the regulations that are currently under development at EPA, give any kind of update, any kind of timeline on those?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, are we going to see anything else later in the week?&nbsp; Karine suggested yesterday that there could be more to come.&nbsp; She said no climate emergency this week, but it potentially is still on the table.&nbsp; Will we see that?&nbsp; And will we see &#8212; I mean, will we see any other &#8212; you know, any other executive authority or orders or anything else in this space later during this week?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I think the President is going to be very clear that since Congress is not going to act on this emergency, he will.&nbsp; He is going to state it loudly, he&#8217;s going to state it clearly &#8212; what he put in his written statement last week, and that is that as President, he will use his executive powers to combat the climate crisis in the absence of additional congressional action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think he will also lay out that, in the coming days, he expects his administration to begin to announce the executive actions that his administration has developed and is developing to combat this emergency.&nbsp; So I think you will hear that from him in his &#8212; in his own words.&nbsp; And hopefully, that&#8217;s responsive to part of your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the second bit: This administration, really, almost on a daily basis, from January 21st, has been advancing climate action.&nbsp; So if you&#8217;re asking me to forecast the rest of the week, yeah, we&#8217;re going to keep taking climate action every single day because that&#8217;s been part and parcel of this administration&#8217;s focus.&nbsp; This is one of the four crises the President defined when he was inaugurated.&nbsp; And that direction has been very clear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think what he &#8212; what he has expressed and what he will express this afternoon is about accelerating that action, heightening that ambition, and using the executive powers to combat the climate crisis in the absence of additional congressional action.</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And we’ll go to Ben (inaudible) next.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, good morning.&nbsp; Can you hear me okay?&nbsp; (Cat meows.)</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; We can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; One of our cats is joining, sorry.&nbsp; Anyway, I just &#8212; not to overly parse words, but, [senior administration official], you said a moment ago that the President is going to be very clear that “since Congress is not going to act on this emergency.”&nbsp; Does that mean that the President has concluded that there is no longer any option for a reconciliation package with these large clean energy incentives and investments?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, Ben, thanks.&nbsp; Thanks for &#8212; thanks for the question.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think we can hear the cats.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But &#8212; but, I’ll &#8212; you know, I&#8217;ll restate it: The President is going to lay out what he can do, what he intends to do.&nbsp; He has very specific executive powers.&nbsp; He has leveraged executive action to date.&nbsp; He has directed his administration to look at a broad set of options for how to accelerate those actions, to how to implement that &#8212; those executive powers with the highest ambition, and that&#8217;s his focus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the rest of your question &#8212; probably there are other folks who can who can answer that better.&nbsp; And, you know, our focus is on what we can do in light of where we find ourselves between the urgency of action and the clarity of opportunity that&#8217;s in front of us.</p>



<p>MR. HASAN:&nbsp; All right, thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; I actually do think we are at time now &#8212; 11:15.&nbsp; So, apologies if we weren&#8217;t able to get to your question.&nbsp; Please feel free to follow up with me via email.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, again, we&#8217;ll try to get you the materials as soon as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder, the call is embargoed until the President’s &#8212; the top of the President&#8217;s remarks.&nbsp; And it is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; Thanks for joining.</p>



<p>11:15 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Executive Actions on Climate to Address Extreme Heat and Boost Offshore&#160;Wind</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/20/fact-sheetpresident-bidens-executive-actions-on-climate-to-address-extreme-heat-and-boost-offshore-wind/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Actions to Accelerate Clean Energy, Create Jobs, and Lower Costs Today, President Biden will reiterate that climate change is a clear and present danger to the United States. Since Congress is not acting on this emergency, President Biden will. In the coming weeks, President Biden will announce additional executive actions to combat this emergency.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>New Actions to Accelerate Clean Energy, Create Jobs, and Lower Costs</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden will reiterate that climate change is a clear and present danger to the United States. Since Congress is not acting on this emergency, President Biden will. In the coming weeks, President Biden will announce additional executive actions to combat this emergency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing his latest set of executive actions to turn the climate crisis into an opportunity, by creating good-paying jobs in clean energy and lowering costs for families. His actions will protect communities from climate impacts already here, including extreme heat conditions impacting more than 100 million Americans this week, and expand offshore wind opportunities and jobs in the United States.</p>



<p>The President will make the announcements at a former coal-fired power plant in Brayton Point, Massachusetts that will host a cable manufacturing facility to support the flourishing offshore wind industry – representing how the President’s leadership is accelerating the nation’s transition away from the pollution, environmental injustice, and volatile price swings of the past toward the good-paying jobs and energy security of the future.</p>



<p>President Biden’s new executive actions will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect Communities from Extreme Heat and Dangerous Climate Impacts: </strong>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) is announcing $2.3 billion in funding for its Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) program for Fiscal Year 2022— the largest BRIC investment in history, boosted by the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. This funding will help communities increase resilience to heat waves, drought, wildfires, flood, hurricanes, and other hazards by preparing before disaster strikes. BRIC is among hundreds of federal programs that the Biden-Harris Administration is transforming to support the Justice40 Initiative and prioritize delivering benefits to disadvantaged communities.<br><br></li><li><strong>Lower Cooling Costs for Communities Suffering from Extreme Heat:</strong> Today, the Department of Health and Human Services is issuing <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/policy-guidance/liheap-im-2022-06-heat-stress-flexibilities-and-resources-fy2022">guidance</a> that for the first time expands how the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP) can promote the delivery of efficient air conditioning equipment, community cooling centers, and more. In April, the Biden-Harris Administration released $385 million through LIHEAP to help families with their household energy costs, including summer cooling—part of a record $8 billion that the Administration has provided, boosted by the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expand Offshore Wind Opportunities and Jobs:</strong> The Department of the Interior is proposing the first Wind Energy Areas in the Gulf of Mexico, a historic step toward expanding offshore wind opportunities to another region of the United States. These areas cover 700,000 acres and have the potential to power over three million homes. President Biden is also directing the Secretary of the Interior to advance wind energy development in the waters off the mid- and southern Atlantic Coast and Florida’s Gulf Coast —alleviating uncertainty cast by the prior Administration. These actions follow the President’s launch of a new <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-launches-new-federal-state-offshore-wind-partnership-to-grow-american-made-clean-energy/">Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership</a> that brought together Governors to deliver more clean, affordable energy and new jobs.<br><br></li></ul>



<p>Millions of Americans feel the effects of climate change each year when their roads wash out, power goes down, homes are destroyed by wildfires, or schools get flooded. Last year alone, the United States faced 20 extreme weather and climate related disaster events with losses exceeding $1 billion each – a cumulative price tag of more than $145 billion. People of color and underserved communities are disproportionately vulnerable to the climate crisis and are more likely to experience the negative health and environmental effects of climate-related and extreme weather events. Further, the country’s critical infrastructure is at risk from climate and extreme weather.</p>



<p>President Biden will not back down from addressing this emergency. Since taking office, he has <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/climate/">mobilized his entire Administration to tackle the climate crisis</a> and secured historic clean energy and climate resilience investments in his Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. He will continue taking bold action to secure a safe, healthy, clean energy future—all while saving families money, delivering clean air and water, advancing environmental justice, and boosting American manufacturing and competitiveness.</p>



<p><strong><u>PROTECTING COMMUNITIES FROM EXTREME HEAT</u></strong></p>



<p>This summer, millions of Americans are navigating the challenges and dangers that come with extreme heat advisories and record-breaking temperatures exceeding 100 degrees Fahrenheit. The climate crisis is making heat waves more intense and frequent, taking a toll on health across the country—sending tens of thousands of Americans to the emergency room, increasing risks of heart and respiratory problems, and especially endangering our workers, children, seniors, historically underserved and overburdened communities, and people with underlying health conditions.</p>



<p>To respond, last year the Biden-Harris Administration launched a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/20/fact-sheet-biden-administration-mobilizes-to-protect-workers-and-communities-from-extreme-heat/">broad set of new initiatives</a> to  advance workplace safety, build local resilience, and address the disproportionate impacts of extreme heat. Today, the Administration is announcing additional steps and progress on:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing Record Funding to Increase Community Resilience:</strong> Last year, President Biden doubled the funding available through FEMA’s Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) program. This year, he is doubling it again, to a historic level of $2.3 billion available for states, local communities, Tribes, and territories to proactively reduce their vulnerability to heat waves, drought, wildfires, flood, hurricanes, and other hazards boosted by the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. As part of the President’s Justice40 Initiative, which set a goal of delivering 40% of the overall benefits of Federal investments in climate and clean energy to disadvantaged communities, FEMA is prioritizing communities that have long been marginalized, overburdened, and underserved.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Access to Home Air Conditioners and Community Cooling Centers: </strong>In April, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) released $385 million through LIHEAP to <a>help families with their household energy costs, including summer cooling</a>—part of a record $8 billion that the Administration has provided, boosted by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, to reduce cooling and heating costs for low-income Americans. Today, HHS is issuing <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/policy-guidance/liheap-im-2022-06-heat-stress-flexibilities-and-resources-fy2022">guidance</a> that will help states, Tribes, and territories expand how they respond to extreme heat and support vulnerable communities through LIHEAP. The guidance provides for a range of flexible options including increasing funding for cooling assistance through the American Rescue Plan; establishing community cooling centers; and purchasing, distributing, or loaning efficient air conditioning equipment, evaporative coolers and electric heat pumps—a more energy-efficient alternative for providing cooling services—to vulnerable households and individuals. HHS has also developed a <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/liheap-and-extreme-heat">LIHEAP and Extreme Heat</a> website to provide online resources including the Heat Stress Geographic Information (GIS) Dashboard to help grant recipients and stakeholders track, visualize, and respond to heat stress trends and needs across the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Enforcing Workplace Safety: </strong>Heat is a growing threat to workplace safety, especially in high-risk sectors like agriculture and construction. In April, Vice President Harris and Secretary of Labor Walsh launched the first-ever National Emphasis Program to protect millions of workers from heat illness and injuries. Since then, the Department of Labor’s Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) has <strong>already conducted</strong> <strong>564 heat-related inspections, which are focused on over 70 high-risk industries across 43 states. </strong>On days when the heat index is 80°F or higher, OSHA inspectors and compliance assistance specialists are engaging in proactive outreach and technical assistance to help stakeholders keep workers safe on the job.<br><br></li></ul>



<p>Through the Extreme Heat Interagency Working Group under the National Climate Task Force, the Administration is advancing a wide range of additional efforts, including a <a href="https://www.osha.gov/heat-exposure/rulemaking">historic OSHA rulemaking process</a> toward the first federal heat standard to protect workers, EPA support for community <a href="https://www.epa.gov/innovation/lets-talk-about-heat-challenge">communication strategies</a> to help people keep safe on the hottest days, a DHS <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/science-and-technology/news/2022/07/05/dhs-prize-winners-announced-challenge-counter-extreme-temperatures">Cooling Solutions Challenge</a> to fund innovative extreme heat responses,&nbsp; NOAA’s community-led <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news-release/noaa-and-communities-to-map-heat-inequities-in-14-us-cities-and-counties">urban heat island mapping campaign</a>, a USDA <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/managing-land/urban-forests/ucf">urban and community forestry program</a> to equitably improve heat resilience, and a new <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/climate-change-health-equity-environmental-justice/climate-change-health-equity/climate-health-outlook/index.html">HHS Climate and Health Outlook</a> to inform health professionals about extreme heat and other climate-related health hazards.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>BOOSTING THE OFFSHORE WIND INDUSTRY AND CREATING JOBS</u></strong></p>



<p>Since President Biden set a bold goal of deploying 30 gigawatts of offshore wind by 2030, the Administration has approved the first large-scale projects and new wind energy areas, held record-breaking wind auctions, and issued an action plan to accelerate permitting. The private sector is following suit with investments to expand an American-made wind energy supply chain. In 2021 alone, investors announced $2.2 billion in new supply chain funding, including commitments to develop nine major manufacturing facilities to produce the foundations, towers, cables, and blades of offshore wind turbines. Historic project labor agreements are helping to grow a diverse union workforce, create good-paying jobs, and support training programs.</p>



<p>To further expand these opportunities, today President Biden is:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Kickstarting Potential for Offshore Wind in Gulf of Mexico:</strong> Today, the Department of the Interior is announcing draft Wind Energy Areas and an accompanying draft Environmental Assessment to consider potential offshore wind power in the Gulf of Mexico. The Administration will seek public input on two potential Wind Energy Areas—one off the coast of Galveston, Texas and another off the coast of Lake Charles, Louisiana. The area for review covers over 700,000 acres, with the potential to power over three million homes with clean energy. As with prior proposals, the Administration is committed to working in partnership with stakeholders to advance offshore wind development while protecting biodiversity and promoting ocean co-use.<br><br></li><li><strong>Promoting Offshore Wind Opportunities in the Southeast:</strong> The prior Administration cast uncertainty over the future of offshore wind and other clean energy development off the coasts of Florida, Georgia, South Carolina, and North Carolina. Today, President Biden is directing the Secretary of the Interior to advance clean energy development in these federal waters—ensuring that these southeast states will be able to benefit from good-paying jobs in the burgeoning offshore wind industry.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>These actions follow the President’s announcement last month of a new <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-launches-new-federal-state-offshore-wind-partnership-to-grow-american-made-clean-energy/">Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership</a>, joining with Governors to ensure that federal and state officials are working together to build a U.S.-based supply chain, including manufacturing and shipbuilding, for the rapidly-growing offshore wind industry. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Invests in Summer Learning and Enrichment Programs to Help Students Catch&#160;Up</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-invests-in-summer-learning-and-enrichment-programs-to-help-students-catch-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57905</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[First Lady Jill Biden and U.S. Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona Embark on a Multi-State Summer Learning Tour  Summer learning and enrichment programs can play a critical role in student success. From providing students opportunities to catch up academically from what they may have missed during the pandemic to providing channels for students to engage with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>First Lady Jill Biden and U.S. Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona Embark on a Multi-State Summer Learning Tour </em></p>



<p>Summer learning and enrichment programs can play a critical role in student success. From providing students opportunities to catch up academically from what they may have missed during the pandemic to providing channels for students to engage with their peers, friends, and caring adults, summer programs across the country are helping students recover and thrive. President Biden has invested significantly in expanding summer programs for students and families across the nation, because he knows it is an essential ingredient in student recovery and success. Through President Biden’s American Rescue Plan (ARP), states and districts received $122 billion to help schools reopen and help students catch up academically and access mental health supports, including by increasing summer programming. As a result, all 50 states, Washington D.C. and Puerto Rico, are investing in summer learning and enrichment offerings, providing more opportunities for students – especially those disproportionately impacted by the pandemic – to benefit academically and socially from these programs.</p>



<p>Further elevating the importance of high-quality summer learning programs, President Biden has called on schools to use American Rescue plan funds to provide high-quality summer learning programs – as well as tutoring and afterschool programs – at the scale needed to support, on average, an additional four months of learning gains in reading and math.</p>



<p>Starting today, First Lady Jill Biden and Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona embark on a tour across the country to amplify that call and highlight how the Biden-Harris Administration is helping students catch up academically through summer learning programs supported by the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p><strong>Summer learning and enrichment programming is among the top strategies school districts are using to address missed instruction – and the American Rescue Plan is funding it.</strong></p>



<p>President Biden’s American Rescue Plan provided states and districts with $122 billion to help schools reopen and help students recover academically and access the mental health supports they need. States were also required to set aside over a billion dollars in funding to invest in summer programs, because summer is an important time for students to reengage with their peers and teachers, catch up academically from missed instruction, and get the social, emotional, and mental health supports they need.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Local school districts plan to spend $27 billion of American Rescue Plan funds on academic recovery. </strong>According to a June <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/financial-trends-in-local-schools-covid-aid-spending/">analysis</a> by Future Ed, school districts across the country plan to spend $27 billion on academic recovery, second only to investments in staffing to help students recover from the pandemic and thrive. The American Rescue Plan requires districts to spend 20% of their ARP Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief (ESSER) funds on academic recovery, but according to the analysis, districts are planning to spend more than the required percentage – at least 25% &#8211; to help more students catch up academically. Districts are also planning to spend an additional 23% of their ARP funds on staffing – which will play a critical role in helping students recover academically and access the supports they need.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Summer learning is among the top strategies school districts are using to provide additional academic instruction &nbsp;</strong>The Future Ed analysis also found that summer learning and afterschool programs make up nearly a quarter of the academic recovery investments. Its analysis projects that schools plan to spend over $6 billion of their ARP ESSER funds on these types of programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>First Lady Jill Biden and Secretary Cardona will highlight summer learning and enrichment programs in Connecticut, Michigan, and Georgia.</strong></p>



<p>Today, First Lady Jill Biden and Secretary Cardona kicked off a multi-state tour highlighting ARP-funded summer learning programs that are helping students catch up academically and providing them with mental health, social, and emotional supports they need to succeed. Together Connecticut, Michigan, and Georgia received $9 billion in ARP ESSER funds to support safe school reopening and recovery and are anticipated to spend at least $2 billion dollars on academic recovery, including through summer learning and afterschool programs.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Connecticut has received $1.1 billion in ARP ESSER funds, and the state and school districts are anticipated to spend at least $275 million dollars on state and local academic recovery efforts through September 2024. </strong>The Connecticut State Department of Education launched a Summer Enrichment Grant Program to provide up to $250,000 in funds each to dozens of grant recipients that are providing and expanding summer programs this year, particularly those serving students most impacted by the pandemic. Last summer, Connecticut awarded nearly $9 &nbsp;million to grant recipients for summer programming.</li></ul>



<p>Dr. Biden and Secretary Cardona will visit a&nbsp;Horizons National summer learning program,&nbsp;held at&nbsp;Albertus Magnus College in New Haven,&nbsp;CT,&nbsp;serving&nbsp;elementary&nbsp;students from local public schools. Horizons received a $157,500 ARP grant, which is allowing the organization to expand its programming across the New Haven region to serve 1,000 students.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Because of ARP ESSER funds, public schools in Detroit, MI have been able to double the number of students in summer school this year. </strong>Detroit, MI received over $800 million in ARP ESSER funds, and the state overall received over $3.7 billion in ARP ESSER funds. The state and school districts are anticipated to spend at least $925 million dollars on academic recovery, including through summer programming. Because of ARP ESSER, Detroit was able to expand its summer enrichment offerings and doubled the number of students in summer programs this year. As a result, 8,000 students are attending summer school this year.</li></ul>



<p>Dr. Biden and Secretary Cardona will visit a Detroit Public Schools Community District summer learning program, held at Schulze Academy for Technology and Arts in Detroit, MI, serving kindergarten through 8th grade students from the school district. ARP funding has enabled thousands more students in the district to access summer programming, with a focus on enrichment opportunities including STEM and STEAM programming, arts, coding and cooking.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Georgia is granting $40 million to over 100 organizations across the state operating summer and afterschool programs. </strong>Georgia received $4.2 billion in ARP ESSER funds, roughly $1 billion of which the state and school districts are anticipated to spend on academic recovery. As part of this effort, Georgia created the Building Opportunities in Out-of-School Time (BOOST) Grant program, where the state funds grants to community-based organizations that operate summer and afterschool programs. The goal of the program is to provide evidence-based programming focused on supporting students most impacted by the pandemic and helping them recover. Georgia is granting $40 million to approximately 100-120 organizations doing this critical work across the state, funded by ARP.</li></ul>



<p>Dr. Biden and Secretary Cardona will visit a Horizons National summer learning program,&nbsp;held at the&nbsp;University of Georgia&nbsp;in Athens, GA,&nbsp;serving students from Barnett Shoals Elementary School. Horizons received a BOOST Grant of $192,500 per year for three years starting this year to provide and expand programming to more Athens youth during the summer and year-round.</p>



<p>Dr. Biden and Secretary Cardona’s tour is part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s broader commitment to addressing lost instructional time and ensuring students have the mental health supports they need to recover and thrive. Earlier this month, the Administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/05/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-national-effort-to-support-student-success/">launched</a> a national strategy to help students recover academically, with the goal of mobilizing 250,000 tutors and mentors to support students’ academic needs across the country. Tutors, mentors, and other adults in high-impact roles will play a critical role this summer and during the school year in helping students recover academically and succeed in and out of the classroom. To sign up to volunteer, or get help expanding, launching or improving high-quality programs, visit <a href="https://www.partnershipstudentsuccess.org">www.partnershipstudentsuccess.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris to the 2022 U.S.-Africa Business&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/20/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-to-the-2022-u-s-africa-business-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:52:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Recorded Video As Prepared for Delivery Greetings from Washington, D.C. I want to thank the Corporate Council on Africa, the Kingdom of Morocco, and His Majesty King Mohammed for hosting the 2022 U.S.-Africa Business Summit. I am honored to participate in this opening ceremony. President Joe Biden and I recognize the critical importance of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Recorded Video</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">As Prepared for Delivery</p>



<p>Greetings from Washington, D.C. I want to thank the Corporate Council on Africa, the Kingdom of Morocco, and His Majesty King Mohammed for hosting the 2022 U.S.-Africa Business Summit. I am honored to participate in this opening ceremony.</p>



<p>President Joe Biden and I recognize the critical importance of strengthening our relationship with countries across Africa. To that end, I will start with some very important news. President Biden and I are looking forward to welcoming leaders from across the African continent to Washington, D.C. from December 13<sup>th</sup> through the 15th, for the United States-Africa Leaders Summit.</p>



<p>This Summit will demonstrate America’s enduring commitment to our African partners, and it will be based on principles of mutual respect and shared interests and values. And a critical part of this Summit will be to bolster our economic relationship, which brings me to the importance of this gathering of public and private sector leaders in Marrakech.</p>



<p>I believe in the power of public-private —partnerships that bring together the experience and the expertise of the private sector with the mission of government to act for the public good and with the public trust, and the reach and capacity that governments can give, uniquely, to any endeavor.</p>



<p>By working together, we can unleash growth and opportunity that far exceeds what either the public or private sector can achieve on its own. And, as everyone here knows, there is so much opportunity for economic growth &#8211;in Africa and, of course, the United States—when we all collaborate and coordinate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Africa is the world’s fastest-growing continent. By 2030, the continent will have 1.7 billion people, home to one-fifth of the world’s population. The continent is also increasingly young, urban and connected. There is a growing demand for food, healthcare, education, technology, and infrastructure.</p>



<p>Yet, barriers remain: limited access to capital, the high cost of financing, and legal and regulatory bottlenecks. This is on top of the global challenges that I know are felt acutely in Africa, including recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic, the climate crisis, and food insecurity.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to working with all of you to address these issues, in furtherance of  the African Union’s Agenda 2063.</p>



<p>With regard to food insecurity, we are focused on the urgent need to increase food production and exports with and within Africa, a challenge made worse by Putin’s war in Ukraine. To this end, since last October, the United States has pledged more than $7 billion in humanitarian and food security assistance across Africa.</p>



<p>More broadly, our Administration’s goal is to promote inclusive and sustainable economic growth and development across the continent, to expand capital flows, and to promote the vibrant spirit of entrepreneurship and innovation that is so prevalent across Africa.</p>



<p>I am pleased to see the advances made in implementing the African Continental Free Trade Area and we will work with you to ensure its success.</p>



<p>The United States is committed to bring to bear all the tools at our disposal, including, development financing, grants and technical assistance, and support for legal and regulatory reforms—all to help our African partners thrive.</p>



<p>As part of this, our signature investment initiative in Africa—Prosper Africa—has convened a delegation to be with you in Marrakech. Led by Millennium Challenge Corporation CEO Alice Albright, it includes officials from 10 U.S. government departments and agencies. It also includes a group of investors who collectively manage more than a trillion dollars in assets.</p>



<p>Over the coming days, our delegation will discuss with you a range of issues. This includes work to advance our new global infrastructure initiative, and our work to mobilize hundreds of billions of dollars for high-quality, sustainable infrastructure investment.</p>



<p>It also includes our effort to expand Power Africa, one of our largest public-private partnerships in the world—this work will increase access to electricity, support a just energy transition, and more.</p>



<p>This week’s convening is very important. When everyone is at the table, we are better able to collaborate, coordinate, and identify new opportunities. So, I wish you a productive Summit in Marrakech.</p>



<p>This work will benefit United States-African business ties and diplomatic ties. And most importantly, it will benefit both the people of Africa and the people of the United States.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
