<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:18:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Amends Puerto Rico Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-amends-puerto-rico-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for Public Assistance projects undertaken in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico as a result of earthquakes during the period of December 28, 2019, to July 3, 2020. Under&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for Public Assistance projects undertaken in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico as a result of earthquakes during the period of December 28, 2019, to July 3, 2020.<br><br>Under the President’s major disaster declaration issued for the Commonwealth of Puerto on January 16, 2020, Federal funding was made available for Public Assistance, Hazard Mitigation, and Other Needs Assistance at 75 percent of the total eligible costs.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Under the President&#8217;s order today, the Federal share for Public Assistance has been increased to 90 percent of the total eligible costs.<br><br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on American Red Cross Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/28/a-proclamation-on-american-red-cross-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout our history, Americans have always stepped up for each other in moments of crisis.&#160; This spirit is woven into the fabric of our Nation, and for more than 140 years it has been exemplified by devoted employees, volunteers, and supporters of the American Red Cross.&#160; This month, we honor the American Red Cross and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Throughout our history, Americans have always stepped up for each other in moments of crisis.&nbsp; This spirit is woven into the fabric of our Nation, and for more than 140 years it has been exemplified by devoted employees, volunteers, and supporters of the American Red Cross.&nbsp; This month, we honor the American Red Cross and the selfless Americans who serve our communities in need across our country and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since its founding in 1881 by Clara Barton, a nurse and educator, the American Red Cross has carried out its noble mission of preventing and easing human suffering.&nbsp; Today, in big cities and small towns across the country, hundreds of thousands of Red Cross workers &#8212; more than 90 percent of whom are volunteers &#8212; continue to carry out that mission by selflessly giving blood, making donations, and teaching first aid in local communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Support from the American Red Cross has provided hope to people in their darkest hours &#8212; in the face of armed conflict, climate-related disasters, and the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; Red Cross volunteers are on the front lines of recovery, providing emergency shelter to families impacted by devastating floods, tornadoes, fires, and other disasters; donating lifesaving blood to meet the rising demand of hospital patients; supporting our Nation&#8217;s service members, veterans, and their families; and providing medical care and essential resources to combat diseases worldwide.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During American Red Cross Month, Americans who can are encouraged to answer the call to donate blood and serve communities in need.&nbsp; You are encouraged to learn more about eligibility and the steps involved to donating blood.&nbsp; Let us renew our commitment to Clara Barton&#8217;s timeless ideal of caring for one another in times of hardship and uncertainty.&nbsp; Let us take part in this proud tradition of lending a helping hand to those in need.&nbsp; Let us live up to the duty of care we owe each other through acts of compassion every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America and Honorary Chair of the American Red Cross, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2022 as American Red Cross Month.&nbsp; I encourage all Americans to observe this month with appropriate programs, ceremonies and activities, and by supporting the work of service and relief organizations.</p>



<p>                IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-eighth day of February, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                             JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Women&#8217;s History Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/28/a-proclamation-on-womens-history-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every March, Women&#8217;s History Month provides an opportunity to honor the generations of trailblazing women and girls who have built our Nation, shaped our progress, and strengthened our character as a people.&#160; Throughout our history, despite hardship, exclusion, and discrimination, women have strived and sacrificed for equity and equality in communities across the country. &#160;Generations&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every March, Women&#8217;s History Month provides an opportunity to honor the generations of trailblazing women and girls who have built our Nation, shaped our progress, and strengthened our character as a people.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout our history, despite hardship, exclusion, and discrimination, women have strived and sacrificed for equity and equality in communities across the country. &nbsp;Generations of Native American women were stewards of the land and continue to lead the fight for climate justice. &nbsp;Black women fought to end slavery, advocate for civil rights, and pass the Voting Rights Act. &nbsp;Suffragists helped pass the 19th Amendment to the Constitution so that no American could be denied a vote on the basis of sex.<br><br>Standing on the shoulders of the heroines who came before them, today&#8217;s women and girls continue to carry forward the mission of ensuring our daughters have the same opportunities as our sons. &nbsp;Women of the labor movement are achieving monumental reforms to help all workers secure the better pay, benefits, and safety they deserve. &nbsp;LGBTQI+ women and girls are leading the fight for justice, opportunity, and equality &#8212; especially for the transgender community. &nbsp;Women and girls continue to lead groundbreaking civil rights movements for social justice and freedom, so that everyone can realize the full promise of America.<br><br>But despite the progress being made, women and girls &#8212; especially women and girls of color &#8212; still face systemic barriers to full participation and wider gaps in opportunity and equality. &nbsp;The COVID-19 pandemic has exposed and exacerbated those disparities which have disproportionately impacted women&#8217;s labor force participation, multiplied the burden on paid and unpaid caregivers, and increased rates of gender-based violence. &nbsp;The constitutional right to abortion established in Roe v. Wade is facing an unprecedented assault as States pass increasingly onerous restrictions to critical reproductive health care and bodily autonomy. &nbsp;Workers contend with gender and racial wage gaps that can amount to hundreds of thousands of dollars denied over the course of their lifetimes. &nbsp;The Congress sent the Equal Rights Amendment to the States for ratification 50 years ago and it is long past time that the principle of women&#8217;s equality should be enshrined in our Constitution.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration has made this issue a top priority from day one. &nbsp;Through historic Executive actions, my Administration launched Government-wide efforts to advance gender equity and equality, racial equity, and LGBTQI+ equality.&nbsp; Through the American Rescue Plan, my Administration delivered immediate relief to women and families, funded domestic violence and sexual assault services, supported child care providers, and invested in care workers &#8212; who are disproportionately women of color.&nbsp; Through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we are working to ensure equitable access to good-paying jobs, particularly in sectors where women have historically been underrepresented. &nbsp;We have taken critical steps to end the scourge of gender-based violence and advocate for the long overdue reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act &#8212; legislation that I was proud to author and champion as a United States Senator.&nbsp; We are confronting the epidemic levels of violence that transgender women and girls continue to face.&nbsp; We are working to expand access to health care, including reproductive health care for all people regardless of their gender, race, ethnicity, income, or zip code. &nbsp;We are fighting to lower the costs of child care and provide access to free preschool for all three- and four-year olds.&nbsp; We issued a call to action to eliminate racial disparities in maternal health care, which disproportionately impact Black and Indigenous women.&nbsp; And my Administration established a Gender Equity and Equality Action Fund to advance the rights and economic security of women and girls around the world.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;This work is being led by the most diverse and gender-balanced Cabinet in American history, including the first woman &#8212; and woman of color &#8212; to serve as Vice President, Kamala Harris; the first women ever to serve as Treasury Secretary and Director of National Intelligence; the first Native American woman to serve as a Cabinet Secretary; women leading the Departments of Commerce, Energy, Housing and Urban Development, along with the Small Business Administration and the Office of Management and Budget; and women of color representing America on the world stage as United States Ambassador to the United Nations and the United States Trade Representative as well as leading my Council of Economic Advisers in the White House.&nbsp; In addition, I&nbsp;established the first White House Gender Policy Council to advance gender equity across the Federal Government and released the first-ever national gender strategy to support the full participation of all people &#8212; including women and girls &#8212; in the United States and around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This Women&#8217;s History Month, as we reflect on the achievements of women and girls across the centuries and pay tribute to the pioneers who paved the way, let us recommit to the fight and help realize the deeply American vision of a more equal society where every person has a shot at pursuing the American dream. &nbsp;In doing so, we will advance economic growth, our health and safety, and the security of our Nation and the world.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2022 as Women&#8217;s History Month. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to observe this month and to celebrate International Women&#8217;s Day on March 8, 2022, with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.&nbsp; I also invite all Americans to visit www.WomensHistoryMonth.gov to learn more about the vital contribution of women to our Nation&#8217;s history.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this<br>twenty-eighth day of February, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/28/a-proclamation-on-national-colorectal-cancer-awareness-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Cancer is personal to nearly every family, including my own.  Each year, more than 50,000 families across the country lose a loved one to colorectal cancer &#8212; the fourth most common cancer and the second leading cause of cancer deaths in America.  The toll it exacts is immeasurable, but when we detect colorectal cancer early,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p> Cancer is personal to nearly every family, including my own.  Each year, more than 50,000 families across the country lose a loved one to colorectal cancer &#8212; the fourth most common cancer and the second leading cause of cancer deaths in America.  The toll it exacts is immeasurable, but when we detect colorectal cancer early, we can save lives and deliver hope.  During National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month, we raise awareness of this dreaded disease and renew our commitment to ending cancer as we know it.  <br><br>     While anyone can be afflicted by colorectal cancer, we know that this illness strikes at a disproportionate rate among Black Americans as well as Americans over the age of 50.  Getting regular screenings and identifying symptoms and risk factors are both pivotal to saving lives.  According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, symptoms such as blood in the stool, a change in bowel habits, stomach pain, bloating, cramps that do not go away, or weight loss without a known cause should be discussed with a health care provider.  However, early stages of colorectal cancer often emerge without symptoms, and it is important to begin regular screenings starting at the age of 45.<br><br>     In addition, people who smoke, consume alcohol, or are obese are more likely to be diagnosed with colorectal cancer.  Adopting healthy behaviors &#8212; including quitting the use of tobacco products, reducing alcohol consumption, and eating meals that include fruits, vegetables, and whole grains &#8212; can also reduce your risk.  For more information on risk factors, please visit <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=bf58d1fb1b&amp;e=dbfe791882">www.Cancer.gov</a>. <br><br>     I believe that it is within our power to end cancer as we know it.  That is why I have re-ignited the Cancer Moonshot and set new ambitious goals, to reduce the death rate from cancer by 50 percent over the next 25 years and to improve the lives of people and their families living with and surviving cancer.  I have called on the Congress to create the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA-H), which will invest billions of dollars to advance breakthroughs in the prevention, detection, and treatment of cancer and other deadly diseases.  As we continue to pursue game-changing scientific breakthroughs, my Administration also remains steadfast in our commitment to increasing colorectal cancer screenings, follow-ups, and referrals, with a particular focus on underserved populations.  On February 2, 2022, the First Lady and I launched a call to action on cancer screening and early detection.  Our goal is to jumpstart progress on potentially life-saving screenings that far too many Americans have missed as a result of the pandemic and help ensure that everyone in the United States benefits equitably from the tools we have to detect and diagnose cancer.  We are calling on every American to get back on track with their recommended screenings, including colorectal cancer screenings, and for the public and private sectors to increase access to early detection for individuals and communities.<br><br>     Ensuring that every American has access to quality, affordable health coverage is another critical way that we can win the fight against cancer.  Thanks to the Affordable Care Act, most health insurance plans must cover certain preventive services with no out-of-pocket costs.  This coverage now includes colorectal cancer screenings for adults over the age of 45, making it easier to get colorectal cancer screenings and helping improve access to earlier treatment.  Health coverage under the Affordable Care Act has never been more accessible and affordable than it is today, and I encourage all Americans to learn more by visiting <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=4cdbbe63ea&amp;e=dbfe791882">www.HealthCare.gov</a>.  <br><br>     During National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month, I urge every American to exercise vigilance around their own health and the health of their loved ones.  Early diagnosis and treatment save lives &#8212; and getting screened for colorectal cancer is vitally important as we continue our shared mission to end cancer as we know it.<br><br>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2022 as National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month.  I encourage all citizens, government agencies, private businesses, non-profit organizations, and other groups to join in activities that will increase awareness and prevention of colorectal cancer.<br><br>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this<br>twenty-eighth day of February, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br>                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Irish-American Heritage Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/28/a-proclamation-on-irish-american-heritage-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For centuries, Irish Americans have played a crucial role in helping define the soul of our Nation, and today, nearly 1 in 10 Americans proudly trace their roots back to the Emerald Isle.  With hope and faith in their hearts, the first immigrants from Ireland crossed the Atlantic in search of liberty and opportunity.  It&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For centuries, Irish Americans have played a crucial role in helping define the soul of our Nation, and today, nearly 1 in 10 Americans proudly trace their roots back to the Emerald Isle.  With hope and faith in their hearts, the first immigrants from Ireland crossed the Atlantic in search of liberty and opportunity.  It was the dream of a better life that brought my ancestors &#8212; the Blewitts of County Mayo and the Finnegans of County Louth &#8212; and countless other Irish immigrants. <br><br>Like so many Irish American families, my grandparents carried the spirit and memory of Ireland in their hearts &#8212; a pride and passion they instilled in their home in Scranton, Pennsylvania.  Through the journeys of their own mothers and fathers and in the lessons they passed on to my mother, Catherine Eugenia Finnegan Biden, they joined Irish Americans in every corner of America in helping to write the next chapter of the American story.<br><br>The story of Irish Americans has always been one of strength and perseverance through adversity.  Many Irish immigrants arrived on America&#8217;s shores to escape the Great Famine, only to face discrimination, prejudice, and poverty.  Despite these hard times, they embraced their new homes in every corner of America &#8212; from the Atlantic to the Pacific, across the Midwest and through the Rocky Mountains &#8212; and helped build and fortify our Nation into what it is today.  <br><br>Irish Americans expanded the American middle class, building ladders of opportunity that future generations could climb.  They became teachers, firefighters, police officers, labor leaders, farmers, business owners, and more.  Along the way, Irish Americans contributed enormously to the American labor movement &#8212; championing safe working conditions, advocating for children&#8217;s rights, and fighting racism, prejudice, and income inequality.  They bravely answered the call to serve, defending our Union and its values in every battle.  They continue to work on behalf of the American people as public servants &#8212; serving in the Congress, the Supreme Court, Federal agencies, the White House, and in State and local offices across the country.  Irish Americans have enriched our culture and nourished our hearts and souls through the arts and humanities, earning recognition as Nobel and Pulitzer prize-winning poets and authors, award-winning musicians, storytellers, and dancers, and critically acclaimed actors.  They have blessed our Nation with their indomitable spirit, faith, and love for family that has been passed down through the generations.  This sense of community, hospitality, resilience, and passion are integral pieces of America&#8217;s cultural tapestry. <br><br>The United States and Ireland are deeply and forever intertwined:  linked in memory and imagination &#8212; in joy, sorrow, and resilience &#8212; by our common love and common dreams.  We share, in every heart, an unrelenting optimism &#8212; a flicker of hope that guides us through even the darkest of nights.<br><br>As we celebrate Irish-American Heritage Month, let us honor the journey and contributions of Irish Americans who helped shape this land of opportunity and define what it means to be American.  Let us reaffirm the legacy of friendship and strong family ties between the United States of America and Ireland &#8212; united by our common purpose, by our histories, and by our futures.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2022 as Irish-American Heritage Month.  I call upon all Americans to celebrate the achievements and contributions of Irish Americans to our Nation with appropriate ceremonies, activities, and programs.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-eighth day of February, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Kentucky Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/27/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-kentucky-disaster-declaration-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 04:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47937</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Kentucky and ordered Federal assistance to supplement Commonwealth and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, flooding, landslides, and mudslides from December 31, 2021 to January 2, 2022. Federal funding is available to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Kentucky and ordered Federal assistance to supplement Commonwealth and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, flooding, landslides, and mudslides from December 31, 2021 to January 2, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to Commonwealth and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, flooding, landslides, and mudslides in the counties of Boyd, Breathitt, Carter, Christian, Clay, Floyd, Green, Johnson, Knott, Lawrence, Owsley, Pike, and Taylor.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures for the entire Commonwealth.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named John Brogan as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the Commonwealth and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on Imposing Additional Severe Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/27/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-imposing-additional-severe-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 17:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (February 26, 2022) MODERATOR:&#160; Thanks, everyone, for joining.&#160; As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&#160; We’re going to be discussing further restrictive economic measures we’re imposing on Russia today in coordination with Allies and partners. For your awareness and not for reporting, the speaker on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(February 26, 2022)</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&nbsp; We’re going to be discussing further restrictive economic measures we’re imposing on Russia today in coordination with Allies and partners.</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, the speaker on the call today is [senior administration official].</p>



<p>The contents of the call are embargoed until the end of this call.</p>



<p>So with that, [senior administration official], I’ll turn it over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; So as a result of Putin’s war of choice and ongoing assault on Ukraine and the core principles of peace and stability that have prevailed since the Second World War, President Biden and the leaders of the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, and the United Kingdom decided to take further measures to isolate Russia from the global financial system and the global economy.</p>



<p>In an unprecedented act of global sanctions coordination, our leaders decided to take three actions today: one, to apply the Iran model and disconnect sanctioned Russian banks from SWIFT; two, to undermine the Russian Central Bank’s ability to defend the ruble; and three, to launch a joint task force to collectively hunt down the physical assets of sanctioned Russian companies and oligarchs &#8212; their yachts, jets, fancy cars, and luxury homes.</p>



<p>Let me go into some detail on each of these three measures.</p>



<p>First, our leaders decided to follow the Iran model and disconnect key sanctioned Russian banks from SWIFT.&nbsp; The EU will implement a regulation that removes sanctioned Russian banks from the SWIFT international payments network, effectively shutting them out of the world’s most important financial system.</p>



<p>The reason de-SWIFTing is severe is that this is a network that almost all banks in the world use to transmit financial information to each other as they make payments or receive payments.&nbsp; The SWIFT code is on the bottom of every check you sign.&nbsp; About 11,000 banks across the world are members of the SWIFT network.&nbsp; If one of these de-SWIFTed Russian banks wants to make or receive a payment with a bank outside of Russia, such as a bank in Asia, it will now need to use the telephone or a fax machine.&nbsp; In all likelihood, most banks around the world will simply stop transacting altogether with Russian banks that are removed from SWIFT.</p>



<p>Two, leaders have committed to target the Russian Central Bank &#8212; the single-most important financial institution in Russia.&nbsp; We are collectively planning to impose measures to ensure Russia cannot use its Central Bank reserves to support its currency and thereby undermine the impact of our sanctions.</p>



<p>This will show that Russia’s supposed sanctions-proofing of its economy is a myth. The 600-billion-plus war chest of Russia’s foreign reserves is only powerful if Putin can use it and without being able to buy the Ruble from Western financial institutions, for example, Putin’s Central Bank will lose the ability to offset the impact of our sanctions.&nbsp; The Ruble will fall even further, inflation will spike, and the Central Bank will be left defenseless.</p>



<p>Third, this coming week, we will launch a multilateral transatlantic task force to identify, hunt down, and freeze the assets of sanctioned Russian companies and oligarchs &#8212; their yachts, their mansions, and any ill-gotten gains that we can find and freeze under the law.</p>



<p>We’ve already seen the impacts of transatlantic cooperation yesterday, when the French government seized a cargo ship owned by the sanctioned Russian bank Promsvyazbank.</p>



<p>As part of our new task force, we’re committed to fully implementing sanctions and other anti-money-laundering financial and enforcement measures to maximal effect on sanctioned Russian officials and elites close to the Russian government, as well as their families and their enablers, to identify and freeze the assets they hold in our jurisdictions.&nbsp; As I say, we’ll go after their yachts, their luxury apartments, their money, and their ability to send their kids to fancy colleges in the West.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ll also engage other governments so as to detect and disrupt the movement of ill-gotten gains and deny these individuals their ability to hide their assets in jurisdictions across the world.</p>



<p>We’re also announcing our commitment to take measures to limit the sale of citizenship &#8212; so-called golden passports that allow wealthy Russians connected to the Russian government to become citizens in certain countries and gain access to our financial systems.</p>



<p>Any current or future sanctioned individual trying to flee the impact of our sanctions by buying their way into Western citizenship will be forced to endure the consequences of supporting Putin’s war of choice.</p>



<p>These unprecedented actions we’re announcing today build on the swift and severe steps we’ve taken jointly with Allies and partners throughout the past week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In alignment with the decision by our European Allies yesterday, the United States sanctioned President Putin, Foreign Minister Lavrov, and members of the Russian national security team.</p>



<p>Yesterday, the President also directed the Secretary of the Treasury to impose full blocking sanctions on the Russian Direct Investment Fund in the coming days.&nbsp; This is a state-owned financial entity that functions as a sovereign wealth fund and attracts capital &#8212; is meant to attract capital into the Russian economy in high-growth and high-tech sectors.&nbsp; Sanctioning this entity will further curtail Putin’s strategic ambitions to expand the instruments of war and repression.</p>



<p>And, in total this week, as you reflect upon the financial sanctions we’ve implemented, we’ve now targeted all 10 of Russia’s largest financial institutions, holding nearly 80 percent of the Russian banking sector’s total assets.&nbsp; We’ve cut off Russia’s largest bank from the U.S. financial system, a very significant blow to its ability to function and process global trade.</p>



<p>The export control measures we took in lockstep with Allies and partners across the world, both in Europe and in Asia, will cut off more than half of Russia’s high-tech imports, restricting Russia’s access to vital technological inputs, atrophying its industrial base, and undercutting Russia’s strategic ambitions to exert influence on the world stage.</p>



<p>We’ve also sanctioned Russian oligarchs and Putin’s inner circle and their family members, including Putin’s cronies who sit atop Russia’s largest financial institutions and are responsible for providing the resources necessary to support Putin’s further invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>This has been the worst week for the Russian stock market on record.&nbsp; This has been the worst week for the Russian Ruble since March 2020, and the currency hit an all-time low against the Dollar earlier this week.&nbsp; Russia’s government borrowing costs have more than doubled to almost 17 percent.&nbsp; The S&amp;P credit rating agency has downgraded Russia to junk status.&nbsp; Within 24 hours of our actions, the demand for cash in Russia spiked 58-fold, according to reports, and the Russian government scrambled to deplete its own resources to try and shore up its banks and its currency.</p>



<p>In short, Russia has become a global, economic, and financial pariah.&nbsp; Over 30 countries representing well over half the world’s economy have announced sanctions and export controls on Russia.&nbsp; Putin’s government is getting kicked off the international financial system.</p>



<p>To be clear, this is a sad outcome for the people of Ukraine, the people of Russia, and many others.&nbsp; This is not where we wanted to be, but this is Putin’s war of choice, and only Putin can decide how much more cost he is willing to bear.&nbsp; The United States and our allies and partners are unified and will continue to impose costs.</p>



<p>Let me stop there.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great. Could we queue up the directions to ask a question please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you explain the move on the Central Bank?&nbsp; Are you putting it on the SDN lists?&nbsp; And if not, what mechanism are you using?</p>



<p>And then just more broadly, can you give us some sense about why everyone has moved quickly on Saturday to do this?&nbsp; Was there something that prompted you to go so quickly beyond what was happening in Ukraine in terms of Russia moving assets to avoid sanctions preemptively?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, thanks, Demetri.&nbsp; Well, we said all along: If Putin continues to escalate, we’ll escalate, and that all options remained on the table.&nbsp; We’re delivering on what we said.</p>



<p>And specifically, with respect to the Central Bank, today’s statement was a commitment by the leaders that I mentioned across the world to restrict the actions that the Russian Central Bank can take to undermine the impact of our sanctions.</p>



<p>So, as I mentioned at the outset, you heard about Fortress Russia &#8212; the war chest of 630 billion of foreign reserves.&nbsp; It’s impressive, but it’s only impressive if Russia can use those reserves.&nbsp; And that means Russia has to be able to sell those reserves and buy Ruble to support its currency.</p>



<p>And so, what we’re committing to do here is to disarm the Central Bank.&nbsp; And the way we can do that, for example, is by preventing U.S., EU, UK persons from selling Rubles to the Central Bank of Russia.&nbsp; That means very simply, the Russian Central Bank can’t support the Ruble, full stop, and that means our sanctions will have much greater force.</p>



<p>There are other measures, too, we could take against the Central Bank, and you’ll be hearing more about that later.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official]. And just to follow up on Demetri’s question: Are you, in fact, placing the Central Bank of Russia on the SDN list &#8212; or, in other words, are you freezing their assets?&nbsp; Or is it something less?</p>



<p>And does the SWIFT cutoff affect only banks that are already sanctioned, and which Russian banks are selected and how did you select them? Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, thanks, Ellen. We’re still finalizing the specific execution modality for the Central Bank sanctions, and it could involve both the flows that the Russian Central Bank is allowed to undertake, as well as the assets they have.</p>



<p>With respect to SWIFT and which banks will be de-SWIFTed, there’s a process underway, Ellen, to finalize the list of banks that will be cut off from the SWIFT system.&nbsp; There are several banks that Europe and the U.S. have sanctioned, and those will be the first ones considered.</p>



<p>And ultimately, as a matter of regulation, the list of banks that will be de-SWIFTed will be finalized by the EU, since SWIFT is under Belgian jurisdiction.</p>



<p>But we’re going to work very closely, as we have throughout this process, with our European partners to finalize that list.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing the call.&nbsp; Can you tell us if you have any indications from China or other countries that they’re going to help Russia soften the blow of these sanctions?&nbsp; Have you seen any sign of any transactions, for instance, that indicate &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Andrea.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what China is going to do?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I’m sorry to interrupt. Yeah, so, if anything, I would say, Andrea, the latest signs suggest that China is not coming to the rescue.&nbsp; I think it was reported yesterday or the day before that China was actually restricting some of its banks to provide credit to facilitate energy purchases from Russia, which suggests that, much like has been the pattern for years and years, China has tended to respect the force of U.S. sanctions.</p>



<p>And, you know, as we’ve said &#8212; just lifting up a little bit, as we said from the start, it really would be an unfortunate signal for China’s vision of the world if it gave tacit or explicit accommodation to Russia’s invasion of a sovereign country in the heart of Europe.&nbsp; It would do profound damage to its reputation in Europe, but really across the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; We have a question about energy carveouts in the de-SWIFTing process. Is there going to be carveouts for energy companies in Russia to still do business outside of Russia, similar to how Venezuela was de-SWIFTed a few years ago?</p>



<p>And also, how much of the 630 billion or -40 billion or so in reserves in the Central Bank do you think you’ll be able to really freeze?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so when an institution is de-SWIFTed, there tends not to be a carveout for the product type.&nbsp; And so, we are going to go institution by institution, in terms of those that are removed from the network, and we&#8217;ll pick those very carefully to maximize the impact on Russia and minimize the spillovers to Europe and the global economy.</p>



<p>I’m sorry, the second question?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Can we open up the line again, please, for Jordan Fabian?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, you know what?&nbsp; I just remembered.&nbsp; It was a question about how many of the 630 billion are subjected to the sanction, and &#8212; all of it.&nbsp; All of it.</p>



<p>So, right now, all 630 billion of Russia’s foreign reserves could be used theoretically to &#8212; they could sell those reserves and buy ruble.&nbsp; And that would offset some of the impact of our sanctions.&nbsp; I mean, as you know, the Russian ruble has already fallen 15 percent in this episode, and the Central Bank intervened already this week for the first time since 2014.</p>



<p>What this measure does, among other things, is it prevents Russia from transacting with Western banks, U.S. banks, European banks, UK banks, which it needs to do to actually intervene in foreign exchange markets.&nbsp; It must buy the ruble and sell its hard currency reserves to support its currency.&nbsp; That’s why I say we’re disarming &#8212; we’re disarming Fortress Russia by taking this action.</p>



<p>And there may be other actions, too, that are unveiled with respect to the Russian Central Bank, and we’ll be finalizing those over the weekend.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Can you say how quickly you believe that we will see the impact from these actions?&nbsp; I realize you’re still finalizing which banks will be impacted, but does this mean, on Monday, Moscow wakes up and feels the difference?&nbsp; And when you say you’re trying to minimize the impact to the global economy, what’s the risk you’re trying to minimize here, specifically?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I have great confidence the effects of these measures will be felt immediately in Russian financial markets.&nbsp; I think market participants understand that without Russia having the ability to defend its currency, it will go into free fall.</p>



<p>The actions with respect to SWIFT do require the Europeans to issue a directive that will then go to Belgium for a vote of the SWIFT Board of Directors.&nbsp; Those are the specific requirements under Belgian law.&nbsp; But with this decision made, I think you will immediately see a chilling effect fall over the Russian banking sector, even beyond what’s already occurred.</p>



<p>With respect to spillovers and costs and so forth, look, I mean, our judgment here, our calculus is that we have two choices: either we continue to ratchet costs higher to make this a strategic failure for President Putin, or, you know, the alternative, which is unacceptable &#8212; and that would be allowing unchecked aggression in the heart of Europe, in defiance of the core principles that have kept the peace and security across the continent for 70 years.</p>



<p>And those costs of doing nothing and allowing those uncertainties to fester, and the chilling effect to take hold, and the questions that will be asked about which country is next to be bullied and which autocrat is next to exert a sphere of influence &#8212; those costs are unacceptable to us.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this, [senior administration official].&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on Jordan’s question about the carveouts.&nbsp; The U.S. and Allies have been very careful to have carveouts on the previous sanctions to limit the impact on energy.&nbsp; Are you saying that it’s not going to be &#8212; that energy is not going to be &#8212; there’s not going to be a carveout with SWIFT for energy?&nbsp; Or is that the plan to go back and do one by one, and energy will be carved out?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, Franco.&nbsp; So, I mean, I’ll give you as much detail as I can.&nbsp; There are really two paths from here.&nbsp; One is we are trying, over this weekend and around the clock, to work with SWIFT to figure out if they have the capability of identifying the product type.</p>



<p>I mean, so let’s remember: SWIFT is like a &#8212; it’s like Gmail for banks.&nbsp; And what we’re trying to understand is: In those messages that are sent from one bank to another to make or receive payments, is there a marking which denotes that an energy payment is being made?&nbsp; If so, we could exempt those payments.&nbsp; So that’s one path.</p>



<p>But the second path is to choose our institution &#8212; choose the institutions that we de-SWIFT wisely.&nbsp; So, we know where most of the energy flows occur, through which banks they occur.&nbsp; And if we take that approach, we can simply choose the institutions where most of the energy flows do not occur.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well, thanks everyone for joining the call.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&nbsp; The contents of the call are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>



<p>If you have any more questions, please feel free to reach out to me and we’ll make sure to get back to you.</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone. Have a good night.</p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Japan’s Announcement to Hold Russia&#160;Accountable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/27/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-japans-announcement-to-hold-russia-accountable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 15:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We welcome Japan’s announcement today that it will stand with the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States to isolate Russia from the international financial system and our economies. Following Japan’s announcement, the entire G7 now supports disconnecting selected Russian banks from SWIFT, restrictions on the Russian Central Bank,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">We welcome Japan’s announcement today that it will stand with the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States to isolate Russia from the international financial system and our economies. Following Japan’s announcement, the entire G7 now supports disconnecting selected Russian banks from SWIFT, restrictions on the Russian Central Bank, and sanctioning key Russian leaders, including President Putin. Prime Minister Kishida and the Government of Japan have been leaders in condemning President Putin’s attack on Ukraine and we will continue working closely together to impose further severe costs and make Putin’s war of choice a strategic failure.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on Further Restrictive Economic&#160;Measures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/26/joint-statement-on-further-restrictive-economic-measures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 22:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the leaders of the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States condemn Putin’s war of choice and attacks on the sovereign nation and people of Ukraine. We stand with the Ukrainian government and the Ukrainian people in their heroic efforts to resist Russia’s invasion. Russia’s war represents an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We, the leaders of the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States condemn Putin’s war of choice and attacks on the sovereign nation and people of Ukraine. We stand with the Ukrainian government and the Ukrainian people in their heroic efforts to resist Russia’s invasion. Russia’s war represents an assault on fundamental international rules and norms that have prevailed since the Second World War, which we are committed to defending. We will hold Russia to account and collectively ensure that this war is a strategic failure for Putin.</p>



<p>This past week, alongside our diplomatic efforts and collective work to defend our own borders and to assist the Ukrainian government and people in their fight, we, as well as our other allies and partners around the world, imposed severe measures on key Russian institutions and banks, and on the architects of this war, including Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>



<p>As Russian forces unleash their assault on Kyiv and other Ukrainian cities, we are resolved to continue imposing costs on Russia that will further isolate Russia from the international financial system and our economies. We will implement these measures within the coming days.</p>



<p>Specifically, we commit to undertake the following measures:</p>



<p>First, we commit to ensuring that selected Russian banks are removed from the SWIFT messaging system. This will ensure that these banks are disconnected from the international financial system and harm their ability to operate globally.</p>



<p>Second, we commit to imposing restrictive measures that will prevent the Russian Central Bank from deploying its international reserves in ways that undermine the impact of our sanctions.</p>



<p>Third, we commit to acting against the people and entities who facilitate the war in Ukraine and the harmful activities of the Russian government. Specifically, we commit to taking measures to limit the sale of citizenship—so called golden passports—that let wealthy Russians connected to the Russian government become citizens of our countries and gain access to our financial systems.</p>



<p>Fourth, we commit to launching this coming week a transatlantic task force that will ensure the effective implementation of our financial sanctions by identifying and freezing the assets of sanctioned individuals and companies that exist within our jurisdictions. As a part of this effort we are committed to employing sanctions and other financial and enforcement measures on additional Russian officials and elites close to the Russian government, as well as their families, and their enablers to identify and freeze the assets they hold in our jurisdictions. We will also engage other governments and work to detect and disrupt the movement of ill-gotten gains, and to deny these individuals the ability to hide their assets in jurisdictions across the world.</p>



<p>Finally, we will step up or coordination against disinformation and other forms of hybrid warfare.</p>



<p>We stand with the Ukrainian people in this dark hour. Even beyond the measures we are announcing today, we are prepared to take further measures to hold Russia to account for its attack on Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino&#160;Heritage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/26/readout-of-white-house-virtual-celebration-of-afro-latino-heritage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 21:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, as part of Black History Month programming, the White House hosted a virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino Heritage, where Administration officials highlighted how President Biden has prioritized equity and diversity in his Administration. The program consisted of two panels and remarks from Ambassador to Spain Julissa Reynoso, Senior Advisor to the President and Director of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, as part of Black History Month programming, the White House hosted a virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino Heritage, where Administration officials highlighted how President Biden has prioritized equity and diversity in his Administration. The program consisted of two panels and remarks from Ambassador to Spain Julissa Reynoso, Senior Advisor to the President and Director of the White House Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond, Dean of the USC Rossier School of Education Dr. Pedro Noguera, as well as a spoken word by writer Melania Luisa Marte.</p>



<p>Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute CEO Marco Davis moderated a discussion focused on Afro-Latino representation with Chair of the National Endowment for the Arts Dr. Maria Rosario Jackson; Director of the Office of Intergovernmental and External Affairs at the Department of Health and Human Services Marvin Figueroa; and Hispanic Association on Corporate Responsibility CEO Cid Wilson. White House Senior Advisor for Public Engagement Carissa Smith later moderated a second discussion focused on achieving Black wellness, the theme for this year’s Black History Month, with Deputy Director for Energy Justice, Shalanda Baker, at the Department of Energy, and Acting National Director of the Minority Business Development Agency, Miguel Estién, from the Department of Commerce. Administration officials shared accomplishments from the first year of the Biden-Harris Administration and participants shared their own experiences as leaders in the Afro-Latino community.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
