<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 14:25:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Korean War Veterans Armistice Day, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/26/a-proclamation-on-national-korean-war-veterans-armistice-day-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 14:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and the Republic of Korea are allies with a long history of shared sacrifice.&#160; In a call to defend freedom and democracy abroad, 1.8 million Americans joined the fight to protect our Korean Peninsula allies from the communist regimes in North Korea and The People&#8217;s Republic of&#160;China. &#160;In 1953, after 3 years&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and the Republic of Korea are allies with a long history of shared sacrifice.&nbsp; In a call to defend freedom and democracy abroad, 1.8 million Americans joined the fight to protect our Korean Peninsula allies from the communist regimes in North Korea and The People&#8217;s Republic of&nbsp;China. &nbsp;In 1953, after 3 years of violent combat and&nbsp;millions of casualties, an armistice was signed by representatives of the United States, The People&#8217;s Republic of China, and North Korea.&nbsp; The armistice made possible the exchange of prisoners of war as well as an opportunity to negotiate a peaceful settlement. &nbsp;Almost 70 years later, that&nbsp;settlement still has not been reached, and the Korean Peninsula remains divided along the 38th parallel.&nbsp; Yet,&nbsp;the Republic of Korea has grown into a thriving, vibrant country, and the enduring relationship between our two nations has flourished through decades of peace.&nbsp; Today, we take this opportunity to honor, remember, and pay tribute to the Korean War veterans who fought to defend those universal values and freedoms that the people of South Korea enjoy today.</p>



<p>American service members, along with our United Nations counterparts, fought through some of the most unforgiving terrain and weather conditions on the Korean Peninsula. &nbsp;Through searing summer heat, bitter winter cold, and torrential rains, our forces fought with relentless courage, resilience, and perseverance.&nbsp; In the mountains, valleys, and&nbsp;rice paddies, the battles fought and lives lost in Inchon, the Chosin Reservoir, Heartbreak Ridge, and the Pusan Perimeter, we remember their valor. &nbsp;Earlier this year, I&nbsp;had&nbsp;the great privilege of awarding the Medal of Honor to&nbsp;Colonel Ralph Puckett, Jr., USA (Ret.), a&nbsp;legend in the Army Ranger community, for his extraordinary selflessness and heroism during the Korean War in the Battle of&nbsp;Hill 205. &nbsp;His&nbsp;story, and those of all our veterans of the Korean War, remind every American the high price of freedom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We shall never forget the service members who made the ultimate sacrifice. &nbsp;On the National Mall at the Korean War Memorial, a Wall of Remembrance will be established to further honor and venerate the more than 36,000 American lives lost during the war, along with more than 7,000 Korean Augmentation to the United States Army soldiers who were killed in action. &nbsp;As a grateful Nation, we owe it to the families of the fallen to memorialize, commemorate, and pay tribute to the heroes who have given their lives for our Nation &#8212; and to uphold and honor the democratic values for which they fought. We must also always recognize the patriotism and service of our veterans and their families and caregivers, and uphold our sacred obligation to provide the support they need when they come home.</p>



<p>Our commitment to protecting peace on the Korean Peninsula has endured and grown in the ensuing decades.&nbsp; We&nbsp;are immensely proud of our historic friendship and the trust we share with the&nbsp;Republic of Korea.&nbsp; The service and&nbsp;sacrifices of both our nations have left an indelible determination to sustain peace and promote regional stability.&nbsp; Training side-by-side with the Korean military, our Armed Forces abroad help keep the watch while proudly upholding the legacy of those serving before them.&nbsp;Our partnership remains crucial to maintaining peace and stability today, and to expanding economic growth in a&nbsp;critical region of the world.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the&nbsp;United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States, do hereby proclaim July 27, 2021, as National Korean War Veterans Armistice Day.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this day with appropriate ceremonies and activities that honor and give thanks to our distinguished Korean War Veterans.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-sixth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.                </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Eight Nominees to Serve as U.S. Attorneys</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/president-biden-announces-eight-nominees-to-serve-as-u-s-attorneys/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is announcing eight nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as the top federal law enforcement officials for their districts. These individuals—many of whom are historic firsts—were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is announcing eight nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as the top federal law enforcement officials for their districts.</p>



<p>These individuals—many of whom are historic firsts—were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials in this field, their dedication to pursuing equal justice for all, and their commitment to the independence of the Department of Justice.</p>



<p>The President has launched a comprehensive effort to take on the uptick in gun crime that has been taking place for the last 18 months—putting more cops on the beat, supporting community prevention programs, and cracking down on illegal gun trafficking. Confirming U.S. Attorneys as the chief federal law enforcement officers in their district is important for these efforts.</p>



<p><strong>Erek L. Barron, U.S. Attorney nominee for the District of Maryland</strong></p>



<p>Erek L. Barron is a partner at the law firm of Whiteford Taylor &amp; Preston LLP. He has also been a member of the Maryland legislature since 2015. From 2007 to 2009, Mr. Barron served as Counsel and Policy Advisor to then-Senator Joseph R. Biden on the United States Senate Judiciary Committee’s Subcommittee on Crime and Drugs. From 2006 to 2007, Mr. Barron served as a federal prosecutor in the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice. Prior to that, Mr. Barron served as a Maryland prosecutor in the Prince George’s County State’s Attorney’s Office and subsequently in the Baltimore City State’s Attorney’s Office. Mr. Barron received his LL.M. from Georgetown University Law Center in 2007, his J.D. from the George Washington University Law School in 1999, and his B.A. from the University of Maryland at College Park in 1996.</p>



<p><strong>Nicholas W. Brown, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Western District of Washington</strong></p>



<p>Nicholas W. Brown is a partner at Pacifica Law Group. Mr. Brown previously served as General Counsel to the Governor of Washington from 2013 to 2017, and as an Assistant United States Attorney for the Western District of Washington from 2007 to 2013. Mr. Brown began his legal career as a Judge Advocate General in the United States Army, serving as both a prosecutor and defense counsel. Mr. Brown received his J.D. from Harvard University in 2002 and his B.A. from Morehouse College in 1999.</p>



<p><strong>Matthew M. Graves, U.S. Attorney nominee for the District of Columbia</strong></p>



<p>Matthew M. Graves has been a partner at DLA Piper LLP in Washington, D.C. since 2016. Previously, from 2007 to 2016, Mr. Graves worked as an Assistant United States Attorney in the District of Columbia, where he served in the Office’s Fraud and Public Corruption Section, ultimately serving as the acting chief of the Section. From 2002 to 2007, Mr. Graves was an associate at WilmerHale. From 2001 to 2002, he served as a law clerk for Judge Richard W. Roberts on the United States District Court for the District of Columbia. Mr. Graves received his J.D. from Yale Law School in 2001 and his B.A. from Washington and Lee University in 1998.</p>



<p><strong>Clifford D. Johnson, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Northern District of Indiana</strong></p>



<p>Clifford D. Johnson served as an Assistant United States Attorney for the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of Indiana from 1986 until 2020. Mr. Johnson held numerous positions during his tenure, including as the First Assistant United States Attorney from 2010 to 2020, and as the Acting United States Attorney for several months in 2017. Before joining the United States Attorney’s Office in the Northern District of Indiana in 1986, Mr. Johnson was a Trial Attorney in the Employment Litigation Section of the Department of Justice’s Civil Rights Division in Washington, D.C. from 1980 to 1985. Mr. Johnson received his J.D. from Valparaiso University Law School in 1980 and his B.A. from Valparaiso University in 1976.</p>



<p><strong>Zachary A. Myers, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Southern District of Indiana</strong></p>



<p>Zachary A. Myers is an Assistant United States Attorney for the District of Maryland, where he has served since 2014. Since 2018, Mr. Myers has worked in the District of Maryland’s National Security and Cybercrime Section, serving as Cybercrime Counsel for the District. From 2011 through 2014, Mr. Myers served as an Assistant United States Attorney for the Southern District of Indiana. From 2008 through 2011, Mr. Myers was as an attorney at the Indianapolis law firm then known as Baker &amp; Daniels. Mr. Myers received his J.D. from the Georgetown University Law Center in 2008, his M.A. from the George Washington University in 2005, and his B.A. from Stanford University in 2003.</p>



<p><strong>Rachael S. Rollins, U.S. Attorney nominee for the District of Massachusetts</strong></p>



<p>Rachael S. Rollins was elected District Attorney for Suffolk County, Massachusetts in 2018. Ms. Rollins served as the Chief Legal Counsel to the Massachusetts Port Authority from 2013 to 2015, and as the General Counsel to the Massachusetts Department of Transportation from 2011 to 2013 and contemporaneously to the Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority from 2012 to 2013. Ms. Rollins was an Assistant United States Attorney for the District of Massachusetts from 2007 to 2011. From 2002 to 2006, Ms. Rollins was an attorney at Bingham McCutchen LLP, and from 1999 to 2002, she was a Field Attorney for the National Labor Relations Board. Ms. Rollins began her legal career as a clerk to Judge Frederick Brown of the Massachusetts Appeals Court from 1997 to 1998. Ms. Rollins received her LL.M. in labor and employment law from Georgetown University Law Center in 1999, her J.D. from Northeastern University School of Law in 1997, and her B.A. from the University of Massachusetts, Amherst in 1994.</p>



<p><strong>Trini E. Ross, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Western District of New York</strong></p>



<p>Trini E. Ross has served as the Director of Investigations, Legal Division, with the National Science Foundation’s Office of Inspector General since 2018. Ms. Ross has also been an adjunct professor at The State University of New York, at Buffalo, School of Law, since 2006. From 1995 to 2018, Ms. Ross was an Assistant United States Attorney for the Western District of New York, where she served as the Senior Litigation Counsel and the Chief of the Anti-Fraud and Corruption Section from 2012 to 2017. Ms. Ross also served as an Assistant Counsel with the Department of Justice’s Office of Professional Responsibility from 2007 to 2009. She was previously a civil litigation associate at Hiscock &amp; Barclay, LLC from 1994 to 1995. Ms. Ross served as an Appellate Court Attorney for the New York State Supreme Court from 1992 to 1994. Ms. Ross received her J.D., cum laude, from The State University of New York, at Buffalo, School of Law, in 1992, her M.A. from Rutgers University in 1990, and her B.A. from The State University of New York, at Fredonia, in 1988.</p>



<p><strong>Vanessa Waldref, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Eastern District of Washington</strong></p>



<p>Vanessa Waldref has been a Trial Attorney with the Environment and Natural Resources Division of the United States Department of Justice since 2020. Previously, Ms. Waldref served as an Assistant United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Washington from 2013 to 2020. She was a litigation associate at two Spokane-based law firms: Lee &amp; Hayes from 2012 to 2013, and Lukins &amp; Annis from 2011 to 2012. Ms. Waldref served as a law clerk for Judge John D. Bates on the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia from 2010 to 2011. She began her legal career as a litigation associate at Morrison &amp; Foerster from 2008 to 2010. Waldref received her J.D., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from Georgetown University in 2008 and her B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from Georgetown University in 2002.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Marks Anniversary of Americans with Disabilities Act and Announces Resources to Support Individuals with Long COVID</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-marks-anniversary-of-americans-with-disabilities-act-and-announces-resources-to-support-individuals-with-long-covid/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24965</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, on the 31st Anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), we celebrate the inclusion and access promoted by the landmark civil rights law for disabled Americans. Grounded in four core outcomes of full participation, equal opportunity, independent living, and economic self-sufficiency, the ADA prohibits discrimination on the basis of disability in contexts such&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, on the 31st Anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), we celebrate the inclusion and access promoted by the landmark civil rights law for disabled Americans. Grounded in four core outcomes of full participation, equal opportunity, independent living, and economic self-sufficiency, the ADA prohibits discrimination on the basis of disability in contexts such as of public accommodation, employment, transportation, and community living and provides recourse for people with disabilities who faced discrimination. The nation has made significant progress since the law was signed.  To commemorate this day, President Biden will sign a proclamation marking the 31st anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration has taken significant steps to achieve a more inclusive, accessible, and equitable country for people with disabilities, including people with disabilities that experience multiple forms of discrimination and bias on the basis of race, gender, sexual orientation and other factors. Through quick policy action, the Administration has ensured disabled Americans are receiving resources and are included in key administrative proposals. Specifically, the Administration has:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Centered Equity as a Priority on Day One. </strong>President Biden’s Inauguration Day Executive Order 13985 on <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/">Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities</a> Through the Federal Government directs the whole of federal government to pursue a comprehensive approach to advancing equity for all, including with respect to persons with disabilities. Additionally, the EO establishes an Equitable Data Working Group to assess federal data, including on disability, to advance equity.<br></li><li><strong>Increased Access to Democracy for Voters with Disabilities. </strong>Executive Order 14019 on <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/07/executive-order-on-promoting-access-to-voting/">Voting Access</a> ensures people with disabilities can access key voting resources, requires an assessment of barriers to the right to vote independently and privately, and will help ensure that all Americans, including voters with disabilities, can exercise their right to vote.<br></li><li><strong>Raised Wages for Federal Contractors to $15. </strong>In April, President Biden signed Executive Order 14026 raising the minimum wage for workers employed by <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/04/27/executive-order-on-increasing-the-minimum-wage-for-federal-contractors/">federal contractors</a>, including with respect to workers with disabilities.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Advanced Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility Across the Federal Government.</strong> In June, President Biden signed Executive Order 14035 advancing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility (<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/25/executive-order-on-diversity-equity-inclusion-and-accessibility-in-the-federal-workforce/">DEIA</a>) across the Federal government.&nbsp; The EO charges agencies with assessing their state of DEIA to eliminate barriers employees face.&nbsp; For federal workers with disabilities, the EO sets a path for the Federal government to become a model employer to improve accessibility, ensure accommodations can be requested, increase opportunities for advancement and hiring, and reducing physical accessibility barriers.<br></li><li><strong>Provided Billions of Dollars to Children and Adults with Disabilities. </strong>President Biden’s American Rescue Plan is the first COVID relief bill to include explicit provisions for people with disabilities.&nbsp;<br><ul><li>The American Rescue Plan provides states with billions in additional Medicaid funding for home- and community-based services (HCBS) for one year.&nbsp; The additional Medicaid funding will help expand access to home and community-based services for people with disabilities as well as older adults and ensure that caregivers are fairly compensated for their work.&nbsp; The Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services recently <a href="https://www.medicaid.gov/federal-policy-guidance/downloads/smd21003.pdf">released guidance</a> on the use of funds for HCBS and the Administration for Community Living released an accompanying <a href="https://acl.gov/news-and-events/acl-blog/acl-policy-update-american-rescue-plans-additional-funding-medicaid-hcbs">blog post</a>.<br></li><li>The American Rescue Plan also provides direct support to students with disabilities and infants and toddlers with disabilities through the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act. On July 1, the Department of Education <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-releases-more-3-billion-american-rescue-plan-funds-support-children-disabilities">released</a> $2.58 billion to elementary and secondary education students with disabilities, $200 million for preschool students with disabilities, and $250 million for infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Produced Critical Resources for Americans with Disabilities:</strong><br><ul><li><strong>Expanded Access to Competitive Integrated Employment. </strong>&nbsp;The Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education and the Social Security Administration released a <a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/ODEP/pdf/508_odep_cie_07152021.pdf?utm_source=govdelivery&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=ODEP_Newsletter_7-16-21">fact sheet</a> on funding opportunities to expand access to competitive integrated employment for youth and adults with disabilities.<br></li><li><strong>Supported Economic Self-Sufficiency. </strong>Office of Disability Employment Policy, Employee Benefits Security Administration, and Employment and Training Administration within Department of Labor announced a webinar and toolkit to support a successful financial future for disabled individuals.&nbsp; The <a href="https://www.addevent.com/event/iy7331133?utm_source=govdelivery&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=ODEP_Newsletter_7-16-21">webinar</a> and <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ebsa/secure-your-financial-future?utm_source=govdelivery&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=ODEP_Newsletter_7-16-21">toolkit</a> are designed for people with disabilities who are experiencing new levels of financial stress and unemployment. Organized around the five phases of the work-life cycle &#8212; (1) preparing for a job, (2) starting a job, (3) maintaining a job, (4) changing or losing a job, and (5) retiring from a job &#8212; it offers users tools and resources to help them address financial questions.<br></li><li><strong>Reflected on 30 years of Independent Living. </strong>The Administration for Community Living (ACL) at the Department of Health and Human Services released <em>30 Years of Community Living for Individuals with Intellectual and/or Developmental Disabilities</em> <em>(1987-2017)</em>, a <a href="https://acl.gov/sites/default/files/Aging%20and%20Disability%20in%20America/PNS_Book_FINAL_07-12-21.pdf">report</a> about community living for people with intellectual and developmental disabilities over the last 30 years.&nbsp; The report was developed through of a collaboration among three ACL grantees conducting the longitudinal studies about services for people with developmental disabilities.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Leveraged Technology to Support Reengagement with Communities. </strong>CMS hosted the second of two webinars for states, associations, and other stakeholders to explore lessons learned during the COVID-19 public health emergency to discuss the use of technology in supporting reintegration into the community for people with disabilities leveraging in-person services and home and community-based services (HCBS).&nbsp; This second webinar addressed critical considerations for states as they explore incorporating technology into state HCBS waivers.<br></li><li><strong>Expanded Opportunities for Accessible, Affordable Housing. </strong>The Departments of Health and Human Services and Housing and Urban Development <a href="https://acl.gov/sites/default/files/ada/HHS-HUD_HousingFactSheetpdf.pdf">announced a partnership</a> to increase access to accessible, integrated, affordable housing and the services that support community living for people with disabilities.&nbsp; One focus of the collaboration is working with states participating in the Money Follows the Person program and public housing authorities with available housing choice vouchers targeted to people leaving or at risk of entering nursing homes and other institutions, which can include people experiencing homelessness. The Departments also are working to strengthen partnerships between housing and service networks at the state and local levels to streamline access to both housing and community services for people with disabilities .<br></li><li><strong>Provided Guidance on School Reopening for Students with Disabilities. </strong>The Department of Education’s Office for Civil Rights released a <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/qa-reopening-202105.pdf">questions and answers document</a> on civil rights and the reopening of schools during the pandemic.&nbsp; The document helps students, families, schools and the public understand their&nbsp;rights and&nbsp;responsibilities in remote, hybrid, and in-person&nbsp;educational environments, including rights under Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act and Title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act.<br></li><li><strong>Increased Access to COVID-19 Vaccinations and Affirmed the Civil Rights of Americans with Disabilities in Vaccine Distribution</strong>. Agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services released funding and resources during the first 100 days to increase access for people with disabilities to the COVID-19 vaccine, provide <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/federal-legal-standards-prohibiting-disability-discrimination-covid-19-vaccination.pdf">guidance on discrimination</a> when distributing the vaccine, and <a href="https://acl.gov/covid19/VaccineAccessStrategies">support best practices</a> in vaccine access.&nbsp; The Administration for Community Living in partnership with the Centers for Disease Control provided <a href="https://acl.gov/news-and-events/announcements/partnership-cdc-increase-access-covid-19-vaccines">nearly $100 million</a> in grants to help expand access.&nbsp; Additional resources include an overview of <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/disability-access-vaccine-distribution.pdf">disability rights laws</a> in vaccine distribution from the Office for Civil Rights, and information from the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation on barriers faced by older adults who cannot leave their homes when trying to <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/system/files/aspe-files/265346/homeboundvaccovid.pdf">access the vaccine</a>.&nbsp;</li></ul></li></ul>



<p>In addition, President Biden’s Build Back Better agenda outlines a path towards a more competitive, inclusive, and resilient America.&nbsp; If enacted, these plans will provide significant investments to children and adults with disabilities to achieve independent living, economic self-sufficiency, equitable educational opportunities, and full participation in the workforce and communities.&nbsp;<br><br>They include the following key elements:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in the Caregiving Economy. </strong>The Build Back Better agenda would expand access to long-term services and supports for people with disabilities. This investment will also support well-paying caregiving jobs that include benefits and the ability to collectively bargain as well as building state infrastructure to improve the quality of services and to support workers. The funding will take significant steps to help people with disabilities access high-quality care in their homes and communities.<br></li><li><strong>Phase Out of Subminimum Wages. </strong>The Build Back Better agenda proposes a phase out of the subminimum wage provision in section 14(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act.&nbsp; In addition, President Biden proposes investments to expand access to competitive, integrated employment opportunities for workers with disabilities.<br></li><li><strong>Expansion of Inclusive, Accessible Preschool. </strong>&nbsp;The Build Back Better Agenda calls for a national partnership with states to offer free, high-quality, accessible, and inclusive preschool to all 3-and 4-year-olds—benefitting five million children.&nbsp; Children with disabilities benefit from&nbsp;inclusive,&nbsp;accessible pre-school programs with their peers,&nbsp;and all children benefit&nbsp;when we create socio-economically diverse preschool classrooms where all students can thrive.<br></li><li><strong>Address Teacher Shortages</strong><strong> through the Development of Special Education Teachers</strong>.&nbsp; The Build Back Better agenda invests in personnel preparation funds under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA), funding pathways to additional certifications, and strengthening existing teacher preparation programs for special educators.<br></li><li><strong>Paid Leave that Supports <em>All</em> Families</strong>. President Biden’s Build Back Better agenda proposes a guarantee of 12 weeks of paid parental, family, and personal illness/safe leave by year 10 of the program, and also ensures workers get three days of bereavement leave per year starting in year one. The program will provide workers up to $4,000 a month, with a minimum of two-thirds of average weekly wages replaced, rising to 80 percent for the lowest wage workers. The plan has an inclusive definition of family, ensuring workers can care and be cared for by a loved one who is not related by blood, which will greatly benefit many communities, including&nbsp;LGBTQ+ individuals&nbsp;and&nbsp;people with disabilities.</li></ul>



<p>Today the Administration is also releasing a package of guidance and resources to support individuals experiencing the long-term symptoms of COVID-19 or “Post-​Acute Sequelae of SARS-CoV-2 infection (PASC),” known commonly as “long COVID.” The announcements from the Departments of Health and Human Services (HHS), Justice, Education, and Labor provide information about where individuals can access resources and accommodations and clarifies the rights for health and educational services and supports. This includes:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Guidance explaining that long COVID can be a disability under various Federal civil rights laws. </strong>The Office for Civil Rights at HHS and Department of Justice released guidance (available <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/civil-rights/for-providers/civil-rights-covid19/index.html">here</a> and <a href="https://www.ada.gov/long-covid-joint-guidance.html">here</a>) explaining that some individuals with long COVID may have a disability under various civil rights laws that entitles them to protection from discrimination.<br></li><li><strong>Guidance that addresses the needs of children with long COVID who may be children with disabilities.</strong> The Department of Education Office for Civil Rights and Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services issued a resource document providing information&nbsp;about schools’&nbsp;and public agencies’ responsibilities&nbsp;for the provision of services&nbsp;and reasonable modifications&nbsp;to&nbsp;children and students&nbsp;for&nbsp;whom&nbsp;long COVID&nbsp;is a disability.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Access to resources on disability support services. </strong>The Administration for Community Living at HHS released a <a href="https://acl.gov/sites/default/files/COVID19/ACL_LongCOVID.pdf">guide</a> to community-based resources that can help people if they now need assistance to live in their own home, go to work or school, or participate in the community. These resources can provide information about what is available locally; help people connect to services, such as transportation and personal care attendants; help arrange reasonable accommodations and access vaccinations; and more. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Information about accommodations in the workplace.</strong>&nbsp; The Office of Disability Employment Policy (ODEP) at the Department of Labor launched a new <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/odep/topics/coronavirus-covid-19-long-covid">webpage</a> that includes resources on long COVID organized by stakeholder groups, such as workers, youth and young adults, and employers.&nbsp; The resources include information on requesting and providing workplace accommodations for individuals with long COVID. In addition, ODEP released a <a href="https://blog.dol.gov/2021/07/06/workers-with-long-covid-19-may-be-entitled-to-accommodations">blog</a> discussing the impact of long COVID on workers with disabilities.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing the Visit of Prime Minister Mustafa Al-Kadhimi of the Republic of Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/26/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-the-visit-of-prime-minister-mustafa-al-kadhimi-of-the-republic-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Hey, everyone.&#160; Again, thank you for participating in today&#8217;s call, which is on background and attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&#160; The contents of the call are embargoed until Monday, July 26th, at 5:00 a.m.&#160; For awareness only, you&#8217;ll be speaking with [senior administration official].&#160; With that, I turn it over to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, everyone.&nbsp; Again, thank you for participating in today&#8217;s call, which is on background and attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&nbsp; The contents of the call are embargoed until Monday, July 26th, at 5:00 a.m.&nbsp; For awareness only, you&#8217;ll be speaking with [senior administration official].&nbsp;<br><br>With that, I turn it over to SAO-1.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks for joining me here on a Friday, late in the day.&nbsp; So, I think, as Jen &#8212; as Jen [Psaki] previewed from the podium earlier this week and today, President Biden looks forward to welcoming Prime Minister Mustafa Kadhimi of Iraq on Monday afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>And this visit will come in the middle of what&#8217;s really a week-long &#8212; starting middle of this week and heading into the middle of next week &#8212; events with the government of Iraq, which just demonstrates our commitment to strategic partnership under the strategic framework agreement we have with this important country.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I thought what I&#8217;d [do] for this background call is just give you some of the sense of the breadth of what&#8217;s happening and some of the initiatives that have already been announced and some that will be announced here over the coming days.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of the sequence of events, we had very senior-level meetings yesterday at the Pentagon with senior Iraqi commanders, and Secretary Austin joined that meeting.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, at the State Department, I was with Secretary Blinken for the Strategic Dialogue, in which Secretary Blinken and Iraqi Foreign Minister Fuad Hussein co-chaired a meeting of our higher coordinating committee, discussing a whole host of issues on the bilateral agenda.&nbsp; And then Secretary Blinken and Foreign Minister Hussein had a bilateral meeting.<br><br>And at the State Department &#8212; almost through the day, I think &#8212; still going on &#8212; are a number of breakout sessions with experts talking about various aspects of commerce, trade, education, culture, and energy, which I&#8217;ll talk about a little bit as we really move forward on these critical components of our agenda.&nbsp;<br><br>On Monday will be the meeting in the Oval Office with the Prime Minister.&nbsp; And the Prime Minister Kadhimi, of course, will have a number of events throughout the week, but there&#8217;ll be a number of counterpart meetings as well.&nbsp; Iraq&#8217;s Finance Minister Ali Allawi will be seeing Secretary Yellen, and so on and so forth.<br><br>In terms of just the &#8212; some of the &#8212; &#8220;deliverables&#8221; is a word we use for these trips &#8212; but the deliverables that we&#8217;ve been working on with the Iraqi government over the last four to five months that have &#8212; some of which have been announced and some of which will be.&nbsp; So let me just kind of roll them up so you get a sense of the breadth of what we&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp;<br><br>First, given that we&#8217;re all dealing with the COVID crisis, and particularly Iraq has been hard-hit by COVID, we are delivering 500,000 Pfizer vaccines through COVAX to Iraq.&nbsp; In addition, $155 million in humanitarian assistance to support over 1 million IDPs in Iraq, announced by the State Department.<br><br>Iraq has an election coming up in October, and there was a call by a number of very senior Iraqi leaders and also Grand Ayatollah Sistani, interestingly, also called for a significant U.N. role to help observe the election that&#8217;s coming up in October.&nbsp; And the United States led an effort in the U.N. Security Council and secured a unanimous U.N. Security Council resolution a few months ago to establish that mission.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re announcing today a $5.2 million contribution for that electoral monitoring mission.&nbsp; And again, that election is taking place in October.<br><br>We&#8217;re also contributing about $9.7 million for technical electoral assistance to Iraq&#8217;s independent High Electoral Commission through the U.N. mission in Iraq; about $1.2 million also from the State Department to restore Iraqi universities up in Ninewa Province, which are devastated by the campaign &#8212; in the occupation by ISIS and in the campaign to liberate Mosul from ISIS.&nbsp; This is part of an ongoing initiative.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been going on for a couple of years.&nbsp;<br><br>Similar to the &#8212; in the COVID bucket, about $800,000 towards facilitating high-consequence pathogen track-and-trace methodology.&nbsp;<br><br>In the climate agenda, we have a huge climate agenda with the Iraqis which I want to highlight.&nbsp; USAID funded technical assistance for renewable energy and climate adaptation with a figure &#8212; monetary figure I just can&#8217;t announce yet.&nbsp; But that is also something very much on the agenda.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll get to a couple other energy-related initiatives fairly soon.<br><br>Centers for Disease Control signing a new arrangement to work with Iraq&#8217;s public health sector to help improve their public health capacity is particularly important because Iraq has suffered from just a couple horrific hospital fires over the past few months that have just been devastating.&nbsp; And we want to help them as best we can through our expertise and technical advice to get a handle on that problem.&nbsp;<br><br>The Development Finance Corporation plans to invest about a billion dollars in Iraq to boost private-sector activity, create jobs, provide opportunities for Iraqis.<br><br>Some on the energy &#8212; on the energy front.&nbsp; King Abdullah, of course, was here this week.&nbsp; And we are in the process of finalizing arrangements for connecting the Jordanian electricity grid with the Iraqi electricity grid.&nbsp; This is a project that USAID is helping to fund on the Jordanian side and General Electric is helping to fund on the Iraqi side.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll help bring power to about a million Iraqis in southern Iraq and also some revenues to Jordan.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s a really major win-win initiative.&nbsp;<br><br>Also on the energy and climate side, if you follow these issues, Iraq flares gas from its oil exploration in southern Iraq.&nbsp; And they will be breaking ground later this fall on a &#8212; a really historic project that has been many years under discussion, and we were finally able to get it over the line.&nbsp; And it&#8217;ll be a gas capture project.&nbsp; Baker Hughes is a part of this project.&nbsp; But it&#8217;ll capture about 5.2 million cubic meters of flared gas every day.&nbsp;<br><br>And just why that&#8217;s so important not only for Iraq&#8217;s own energy needs, which are critical, but also these &#8212; this flared gas in southern Iraq contributes about 10 percent of flared emissions of greenhouse gases worldwide.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s a critical not only energy initiative, but also on the on the climate side, which is obviously central to our agenda here in the Biden administration.<br><br>So, that&#8217;s just, like, a peek of what is under discussion.&nbsp; It is truly an enormous agenda.<br><br>Of course, there have been talks, yesterday, at the Pentagon on the security side and military side.&nbsp; We are in Iraq at their invitation to help Iraq&#8217;s capacity Security Forces and Peshmerga in the campaign against ISIS.<br><br>We&#8217;ve &#8212; are completing the fourth Strategic Dialogue.&nbsp; There were two last year in 2020.&nbsp; And two &#8212; there was one in April.&nbsp; This will be the final one.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll talk about &#8212; still under discussion, but we&#8217;re talking about shifting to a new phase in the campaign in which we very much complete the combat mission against ISIS and shift to an advisory and training mission by the end of the year.<br><br>So, I know that has been in the news.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that is a part of the visit, but just one piece of this &#8212; of this, overall, just massive agenda between our two countries.<br><br>Of course, all of this will be discussed between the two leaders on Monday, and we&#8217;re very much looking forward to the meeting.&nbsp; And I am happy to answer any of your questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official], thanks for doing this.&nbsp; And thanks, [senior administration official], for making it happen.&nbsp; First, a housekeeping matter: Can you tell us what time the Oval meeting is and what you know of the &#8212; you know, sort of, like, will there be a pool spray?&nbsp; Are they doing a press conference?&nbsp; That kind of stuff, like the logistics.&nbsp; And then, I have a policy question after that.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I believe it&#8217;s at two o&#8217;clock and likely a pool spray at the top.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That is correct to both.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not a side by side, like two-and-two press conference?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That is correct.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think they&#8217;ll both &#8212; they&#8217;ll both make remarks in the Oval, similar to King Abdullah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, yeah.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, you just mentioned, a moment ago, the discussion at the Pentagon and the larger discussions that have been taking place before that toward ending the combat mission.&nbsp; Do you anticipate that the President will be able to announce &#8212; you know, put a period on the end of that sentence, basically, on Monday, and say, &#8220;We are ending combat operations this year…&#8221; on a certain day?&nbsp; You know, something like that.&nbsp; What would that look like?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, I&#8217;m confident of that.&nbsp; There will be a communiqué issued, probably at the end of the day on Monday.&nbsp; It will be a broad communiqué, kind of wrapping up many of these initiatives that I discussed, and similar to prior Strategic Dialogue communiqués.&nbsp; There have been <s>four</s> [three] of them, so you can go see those.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think something similar to that, and I think it will make very clear that this has been an evolution.&nbsp; So when the Strategic Dialogues began, I think there were about 9,000 U.S. forces in the country.&nbsp; Each Strategic Dialogue has resulted in an a &#8212; in a communiqué and an arrangement agreement about consolidation, redeployment of forces, and there has been a consolidation.<br><br>So, I defer to DOD, but I think we&#8217;re down (inaudible) 2,500 troops or so in the country doing a variety of things, really helping the Iraqis continue to build their capacity.<br><br>Iraq has also reached out to NATO &#8212; NATO training mission and other coalition partners to train and support Iraqi forces.&nbsp; And again, I think those are very important initiatives.<br><br>So, to put a period on your question about whether we&#8217;ll have a period on it: Yes, a statement, a communiqué will come out on Monday.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re excited about that.&nbsp; And that will wrap up, I think, the entire breadth of what I, kind of, conveyed up top.&nbsp; And there will be a security component in the communiqué as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you guys hear me?&nbsp; Hello?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, sorry about that.&nbsp; So &#8212; and to put a period at the end of that.&nbsp; Is that period that the combat mission will end at the end of 2021?&nbsp;<br><br>And secondly, just, I guess, more broadly, it seems like Iraqis want to be able to say there&#8217;ll be no combat troops, but the combat mission seems to have been done, for all intents and purposes, for some time now.&nbsp; So is this really more of something about semantics than actually a really great shift in what&#8217;s happening on the ground?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, no, I wouldn&#8217;t say that.&nbsp; I think if you, you know, look at the <s>four</s> [three] Strategic Dialogues and a significant evolution from our Presidents at the height of that until now, and then between now and the end of the year, I think you can anticipate additional adjustments.&nbsp;<br><br>But what the communiqué will also make clear and what the Iraqis have made clear and Prime Minister Kadhimi himself, I think, in an interview with The Washington Post has made clear is that, as this evolution continues, and as we formally end the combat mission and make clear that there are no American forces with a combat role in the country, Iraq has requested, and we very much agree, that they need continued training; support with logistics, intelligence, advisory capacity building &#8212; all of which will continue.<br><br>So, it’s far more than semantics.&nbsp; And if you look at what’s happened over the last <s>four</s> [three] Strategic Dialogues from where we were at that point to where we are now, and then between now and the end of the year &#8212; I don’t want to get into numbers or anything like that, and I think in none of the Strategic Dialogues were those types of details put out.&nbsp;<br><br>But no, it’s &#8212; you know, it’s a significant evolution and I think it’s something that we feel good about, just given the fact that we’ve trained about 250,000 Iraqi Security Forces and Peshmerga.&nbsp; They are, you know, battle-tested.&nbsp; They have proven very capable in protecting their country.<br><br>At the same time, ISIS remains a threat.&nbsp; And we saw a bombing in Baghdad just this week &#8212; the first one in some time, which, I think, just, kind of &#8212; just reinforces the need that we both understand and recognize that Iraq continues to need support in this kind of advisory training/capacity-building sense.&nbsp; And that’s something that will continue.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you.&nbsp; So, how many American forces will still be there after the 2,500 are gone &#8212; and they’ll be in this training role?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I’m not going to &#8212; I’m just not going to talk about numbers at all.&nbsp; So, I think right now we have about 2,500 in the country.&nbsp; Of course, we have a mission in Syria as well.&nbsp; But I think you’ll see a shift in roles and responsibilities, but I’m just not going to get into numbers or make predictions on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about &#8212; first, can you say: Will any U.S. troops be leaving?&nbsp; And can you define what you mean by “combat troops” and “combat forces”?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, again, I am not going to get into details of what capabilities are there, what capabilities we intend to have in the training/advisory role, for reasons I think you can understand.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, between now and the end of the year, I think a number of things will be happening &#8212; changes of command &#8212; you know, I think a number of things over the next five months.&nbsp; And I think it’s fair to anticipate adjustments as we shift to this new role.&nbsp; But I’m just not, from here, going to get into details on numbers or capabilities or anything.<br><br>But it is a significant evolution in the mission.&nbsp; I think, if you look to where we were when we had Apache helicopters in combat, when we had U.S. Special Forces doing regular operations.&nbsp; I mean, I remember those days.&nbsp; It’s a significant evolution.&nbsp; And just &#8212; so, by the end of the year, we think we’ll be in a good place to really formally move into an advisory and capacity-building role.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, yeah, sorry.&nbsp; I missed asking one last thing at the beginning, which is &#8212; I mean, you were just touching about this.&nbsp; You, maybe more than anybody in this &#8212; in government right now have been telling about what &#8212; the issue from the beginning.&nbsp; What does it look and feel like to you to be part of this, as you put it, &#8220;significant evolution&#8221; in the mission?&nbsp; I mean, it must be pretty different than thinking about those combat helicopters and the days that you were at the embassy.&nbsp; I mean, this is a long way from that, right?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, I think if you do reflect on the situation in 2014, when ISIS swept through Mosul and we had 40,000 foreign fighters pouring into Iraq and Syria, you had 50 suicide bombers a month going off in Iraq, and the Iraqi Security Forces, you know, almost collapsed, and you had a psychological collapse in the country.&nbsp;<br><br>And the Iraqis, at the time, asked for help.&nbsp; We built one of the largest international coalitions in history.&nbsp; And we began to help them claw back territory.&nbsp; And it was extremely, extremely difficult.&nbsp; I just don’t think we can under- &#8212; that can’t be understated.&nbsp;<br><br>Some of these battles in Mosul were extremely costly on the Iraqi side.&nbsp; And so, nobody ever wants to see something like that again.&nbsp; And we’re committed to making sure, as we always said from the beginning, nobody is going to declare “mission accomplished.”&nbsp;<br><br>The goal is the enduring defeat of ISIS.&nbsp; We recognize you have to keep pressure on these networks as they seek to reconstitute, but the role for U.S. forces and coalition forces can very much recede, you know, deep into the background where we are training, advising, sharing intelligence, helping with logistics.&nbsp; And that’s about where we are now.<br><br>I&#8217;d say, off the record, [redacted].<br><br>But back on background.&nbsp; So, yeah, it’s a good question.&nbsp; And I think it is a &#8212; it is an important moment to reflect on how far we’ve come &#8212; the sacrifices, particularly from Iraqis, from Syrians, the couple dozen American causalities in the campaign against ISIS.&nbsp;<br><br>And so it’s important.&nbsp; I think it’s poignant.&nbsp; And I think the fact that two leaders like President Biden and Prime Minister Kadhimi &#8212; two leaders who really believe in solving problems, in leading with diplomacy, and in working together.&nbsp; And that’s why this visit is so important.<br><br>And I just highlight there &#8212; I&#8217;m sure one of the topics in the Oval Office will be the orientation of this Iraqi government under Prime Minister Kadhimi’s leadership. &nbsp;He has worked extremely hard to kind of reintegrate Iraq into its neighborhood.<br><br>You saw &#8212; we just had King Abdullah here this week.&nbsp; And this was a topic when King Abdullah saw the President.&nbsp; King Abdullah was in Baghdad with President Sisi &#8212; a pretty historic summit.&nbsp; First visit of an Egyptian President to Baghdad since before the first Gulf War in 1991.&nbsp;<br><br>Iraq has restored its relations with Saudi Arabia and the entire GCC.&nbsp; The GCC, in fact &#8212; I mentioned the electricity connection from Jordan into Iraq.&nbsp; The GCC is also supporting and helping to finance electoral [sic] &#8212; electricity grid connection from the GCC through Kuwait into southern Iraq.&nbsp; That is a project that will take some time to get on line, but it is moving.&nbsp;<br><br>And Prime Minister Kadhimi has really kind of led these diplomatic initiatives.&nbsp; Again, just two more examples of that: Under his leadership and at his invitation, prote- &#8212; including with his &#8212; the President of Iraq, Barham Salih &#8212; the Pope visited Iraq for this historic, incredible visit to the land of Abraham in visiting Najaf; Baghdad, of course; but also Mosul and Ninewa, where all these atrocities from ISIS were committed.&nbsp;<br><br>And Iraq is also &#8212; Prime Minister Kadhimi has helped facilitate direct talks between Saudi Arabia and Iran in Baghdad.&nbsp; So a pretty extraordinary leader &#8212; diplomatically minded, pragmatic, focused on solving problems, and very similar, of course, to President Biden and our orientation here.<br><br>So, I think it&#8217;ll be a great meeting, an extraordinary meeting.&nbsp; And given the agenda that I laid up on top with everything we&#8217;re talking about, there&#8217;s a lot to talk about.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re excited about it.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I think you, a little bit, answered that &#8212; my question just there.&nbsp; But what &#8212; you&#8217;ve been &#8212; you&#8217;ve been there and you&#8217;ve seen so many of these Prime Ministers.&nbsp; What &#8212; what&#8217;s your measure and what&#8217;s the President&#8217;s measure of Kadhimi?&nbsp; And what &#8212; why is &#8212; why, I guess &#8212; and I&#8217;m making an assumption here &#8212; do you think that he has some staying power?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s different this time with this Prime Minister?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, I think I just laid out, kind of, his outlook and what he&#8217;s working to do.&nbsp; He inherited, of course, an awful situation when he came into power earlier last year, following protests and Iraqi militias killing protesters and incredible heightened regional tensions.&nbsp; And he has worked very much to try to get a handle on that and deescalate things.<br><br>We hear now &#8212; what&#8217;s interesting &#8212; we hear now, from almost every country in the Middle East, one of their first agenda items is the importance of Iraq and the importance of supporting Iraq and the Iraqi government.&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s a sea change from even four or five years ago.&nbsp;<br><br>And, I think, again, that’s a testament to Prime Minister Kadhimi &#8212; just his &#8212; his orientation and pragmatism and trying to be a problem solver rather than someone who, you know, tries to use problems for his own political interests, which is something we&#8217;ve seen in the past.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, I don&#8217;t know if that answers your question.&nbsp; But he is, I think, a testament to his leadership is what we hear from so many other leaders in the region.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, just &#8212; you look at the visit of the Pope &#8212; that&#8217;s quite extraordinary; Iran and Saudi Arabia holding talks in Baghdad &#8212; that&#8217;s no small thing; a trilateral summit from the President of Egypt and the King of Jordan; and many other things.&nbsp; The initiatives with Saudi Arabia and the GCC and the electricity connections &#8212; the electricity connection to Jordan.&nbsp; And these are real things, and they&#8217;re things to build on.<br><br>Of course, Iraq will have an election in October, and that&#8217;s their process to sort through.&nbsp; But we have answered the call through the U.N. and with our leadership in the U.N. Security Council, which took a lot of diplomacy, for a unanimous U.N. Security Council resolution to provide the U.N. support for the election that Iraq requested.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s quite important.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s also something, I think, that we&#8217;ll highlight over the course of the week.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, two things.&nbsp; Has President Biden ever met with Prime Minister Kadhimi before, and when was that?&nbsp; And what &#8212; I know you&#8217;ve been trying to arrange a visit by the Israeli Prime Minister.&nbsp; Is that coming?&nbsp; What &#8212; give us an update on that.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, so, President Biden has met so many Iraqis, and I think this will be the first face-to-face between the President and Prime Minister Kadhimi.&nbsp; But I &#8212; they have spoken on the phone and developed a relationship. And so I think the face-to-face will be &#8212; they’ll be very familiar with each other, and I think we&#8217;re &#8212; it should be a great meeting.&nbsp;<br><br>On &#8212; I have nothing to announce on Prime Minister Bennett’s visit, but we will be looking forward to having him in Washington fairly soon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I wanted to just ask, related on Syria, that it&#8217;s a similar mission, as you know, to ISIS (inaudible) in Iraq.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you anticipate a similar kind of shift in mission.&nbsp; Or has that shift already been completed?&nbsp; Do you anticipate any change in the U.S. mission there?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t anticipate any changes right now to the mission or the footprint in Syria.&nbsp;<br><br>I would just add, as you know, just in Syria, we&#8217;re supporting Syrian Democratic Forces in their fight against ISIS.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been quite successful, and that&#8217;s something that we’ll continue.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And on that note, we will go ahead and wrap up.&nbsp; Thank you, again, for everyone for participating on a Friday evening.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, this call is on background and attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; The contents of this call will be embargoed until Monday, July 26th, at 5:00 a.m.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Bye.<br><br>END&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at Campaign Event for Virginia Gubernatorial Candidate Terry McAuliffe</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/24/remarks-by-president-biden-at-campaign-event-for-virginia-gubernatorial-candidate-terry-mcauliffe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lubber Run ParkArlington, Virginia (July 23, 2021) 8:01 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, Virginia!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; It’s so great to be back.&#160; First off, it goes without saying how much I appreciate your current governor, Ralph Northam, by the way.&#160; (Applause.) &#160;Because of the hard work of the American people, we’ve put ourselves in a position&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Lubber Run Park<br>Arlington, Virginia</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 23, 2021)</p>



<p>8:01 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, Virginia!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s so great to be back.&nbsp; First off, it goes without saying how much I appreciate your current governor, Ralph Northam, by the way.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;Because of the hard work of the American people, we’ve put ourselves in a position for us to control the virus instead of it controlling us.</p>



<p>Here in Virginia, COVID-19 deaths and hospitalizations are down 90 percent since January.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Fifty-four percent of your population has been fully vaccinated, eighty-two percent of your seniors &#8212; both of which are above the national average.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this pra- &#8212; this didn’t happen by itself.&nbsp; It’s due to the heroic vaccination program &#8212; one of the greatest and most complex operational challenges in American history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It happens when we all work together &#8212; the federal government, states, cities, the private sector, and all of Americans.</p>



<p>Look, it happens when you have governors like Ralph who’ve been a key partner, coordinating FEMA and the National Guard to move personnel and resources around the state to get shots in arms.&nbsp; It happens when you’re honest with people.</p>



<p>You know, I know folks are watching the number of cases rising again and are wondering what it means for them.&nbsp; Well, here’s the truth: If you&#8217;re fully vaccinated, you’re safer with a higher degree of protection.&nbsp; But if you’re not vaccinated, you are not protected.</p>



<p>And now &#8212; (applause) &#8212; what we have now is a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; And, by the way &#8212; you know the old expression &#8212; you notice a lot of our very conservative friends have finally had an “altar call.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; They’ve seen the Lord, whether it’s on Fox News or whether it’s the most conservative commentators or governors.</p>



<p>Thank God the governor of Arkansas &#8212; excuse me, of &#8212; of Alabama &#8212; had one of the lowest vaccination rates in the country &#8212; is now &#8212; and I give &#8212; I&#8217;m genuinely complimenting her &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBERS:&nbsp; Stop line three!&nbsp; Stop line three! Stop line three!</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We love you, Joe!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all right.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all right.&nbsp; No, no, no, no.&nbsp; Let &#8212; let him talk.&nbsp; No, let &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; Look, this is not a Trump rally.&nbsp; Let them holler.&nbsp; No one is paying attention to them.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, here’s the point: Virtually all the COVID-19 deaths and hospitalizations are today among the unvaccinated people.&nbsp; And I know &#8212; I know this has gotten a bit politicized, but I hope it’s starting to change.&nbsp; It’s not about red states or blue states or guys like that hollering; it’s about life and it’s about death.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know Governor Northam is going to work like the devil to finish the job.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, Gov.</p>



<p>Look &#8212; and, of course, it’s great to be with another great friend that&#8217;s been around &#8212; I&#8217;ve been around a long time, and I&#8217;ve &#8212; seldom do I get to campaign for someone who I&#8217;ve agreed with more on basically everything. We go back all the way to roots in Syracuse, New York. (Applause.)</p>



<p>I&#8217;m talking about &#8212; and before that, I&#8217;m actually talking about Dorothy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Her roots don&#8217;t go there, but &#8212; look, she&#8217;s always been there for me and Jill when we&#8217;ve needed her most. &nbsp;She was an incredible First Lady of Virginia and she will be again.&nbsp; She is the very best.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, Dorothy, speaking of First Ladies, I&#8217;m Jill&#8217;s husband.&nbsp; Jill wanted to be here tonight.&nbsp; But if you turn on your &#8212; if you turn on the Olympics and watch Team USA, you&#8217;ll see Jill Biden standing there, cheering with them.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The Japanese Prime Minister, who was &#8212; I invited him to be the first person to come to the White House &#8212; head of state &#8212; he made it real clear: He didn&#8217;t want me, he wanted her to go.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; He is a man of incredible judgment.</p>



<p>Look, folks, now, of course, it&#8217;s great to be with my friend and your once and future governor, Terry McAuliffe.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I mean this &#8212; think about this &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Terry! &nbsp;Terry!&nbsp; Terry!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You got it.&nbsp; You’re not going to find anyone &#8212; I mean anyone &#8212; who knows how to get more done for Virginia than Terry.&nbsp; That’s a fact.&nbsp; You don’t have to wonder what kind of governor Terry will be; you know what kind of governor he was and what kind of governor he’ll be again.</p>



<p>He was a great governor of Virginia, and he’ll be even greater this time because he even has more going for him.&nbsp; And, Virginia, you got to elect him again.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You got to elect him again.</p>



<p>And I mean this: not just for Virginia, but for the country.&nbsp; The country is looking.&nbsp; These off-year elections, the country is looking.&nbsp; This is a big deal.</p>



<p>Terry and I share a lot in common.&nbsp; I ran against Donald Trump, and so is Terry.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; And I whipped Donald Trump in Virginia and so will Terry.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I tell you what, the guy Terry is running against is an acolyte of Donald Trump, for real.&nbsp; I mean, it’s just like &#8212; I don’t know where these guys come from.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I really mean it.</p>



<p>But above all, Terry and I &#8212; Terry, we share the same vision about delivering results and, maybe most importantly, why we got involved in politics in the first place.&nbsp; The very wealthy &#8212; and I respect anybody who makes a lot of money; you should be able to be a millionaire or billionaire, whatever you want, as long as you pay your fair share.&nbsp; But here’s the deal &#8212; (applause) &#8212; they don’t need me to protect them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I got involved in politics because the neighborhood I came from, the towns I came from &#8212; Scranton and Claymont, Delaware &#8212; little steel town &#8212; delivering results for hardworking people, who, if you just give them a chance &#8212; (applause) &#8212; just a chance, they never, never let the country down.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know &#8212; I really mean that.&nbsp; That’s not &#8212; that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; Just, look &#8212; I’ve been in office now for six months, as of a couple days ago.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And I think &#8212; I think the administration has a lot to be proud of.</p>



<p>We’ve vaccinated over 160 million Americans.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’ve created over three million new jobs &#8212; more than any administration has in the first six months in entire presidential history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Never has it happened before.</p>



<p>We eliminated &#8212; what we’re on &#8212; we’re now estimated to be on track &#8212; the economy, not growing before the recession, before COVID, said the economy would grow &#8212; it would be three, three and a half percent.&nbsp; Now everything from the OECD to all Wall Street suggests that we’re going to grow this economy 7 percent just this year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That is the highest growth in more than four decades in America.&nbsp; In fact, it’s the best job growth in the world right now.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And in just the past few weeks, one of the biggest tax cuts in the history for families in American with kids went into effect this last week.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve been saying &#8212; I really mean this &#8212; it&#8217;s about time ordinary, hardworking people get a tax break.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because that&#8217;s what it is.&nbsp; Parents should see that money going into their bank accounts right now.&nbsp; And let me tell you what it&#8217;s going to mean for Americans: We&#8217;re going to cut child poverty in half this year because of that.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, Terry and I share the same basic truth: Trickle-down economies never work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s time to build the economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where we are.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, the wealthy have never done poorly when the middle-class and the working-class people do well &#8212; they do well.</p>



<p>Look, Terry understands that it started with the American Rescue Plan that&#8217;s delivering immediate relief to the folks who needed it most &#8212; folks who were on the back of their &#8212; on heels, a lot of them knocked down.</p>



<p>Those rescue checks that went out to more than 80 percent of the adults and children in Virginia that provide a little extra breathing room for people.</p>



<p>My dad used to say &#8212; I really mean this &#8212; my dad used to say, &#8220;Joey, a job is about a lot more than a paycheck; it&#8217;s about your dignity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about respect.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about your place in the community.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about just having, Joey…&#8221; &#8212; and I mean this sincerely.&nbsp; When he left &#8212; lost everything in Scranton and we moved to Delaware, he said, &#8220;Joey, it&#8217;s about a little breathing room.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all people are asking for &#8212; just a little bit of breathing room, a little extra room.&#8221;</p>



<p>Look, aid for small businesses that helps them hire and reopen there doors.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking &#8212; here it is.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Aid to cities and counties to keep their police officers and firefighters and first responders on the job, educators on the job.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The American Rescue Plan lowered health insurance premiums for those buying into the Affordable Care Act by 40 percent on average, saving people $600 a year.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And Terry knows the work continues &#8212; that healthcare should be right, just not a privilege, folks.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And as I said when I was running, with Terry and Dorothy&#8217;s help, it&#8217;s not enough to build back.&nbsp; I mean this sincerely.&nbsp; America is the only nation in the world, when it&#8217;s faced a crisis, has come back stronger than before the crisis &#8212; the only one.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.</p>



<p>We have to build back and build back better.&nbsp; It&#8217;s amazing how that phrase has caught on around the world, isn&#8217;t it?&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>But Terry and I know, along with Mark Warner and Tim Kaine and Don Beyer and Abby Spanberger &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who are working on this in Congress.&nbsp; It means modernizing our physical infrastructure.</p>



<p>Folks, we used to invest more than any country in the world in research and development.&nbsp; We had the number-one infrastructure in the world &#8212; the best roads, highways, airports, ports.</p>



<p><br>Infrastructure is about rebuilding roads and bridges, replacing lead pipes that are poisoning our kids and the water system; delivering high-speed Internet to every single Virginian, rural and urban &#8212; (applause); making sure &#8220;Buy American&#8221; &#8212; so when we invest in the jobs, when we purchase all this, that American workers are doing the work.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not that complicated.&nbsp; It really isn&#8217;t if you fight for it.</p>



<p>Terry and I share the belief that building back better means investing also in our human infrastructure.&nbsp; You know, that&#8217;s my plan.&nbsp; It includes all the things Terry is fighting for.&nbsp; Terry and I believe that when we educate our children earlier, they do better.&nbsp; They do better.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No matter what &#8212; no matter what background they come from, all the studies at the great universities in this state and others have &#8212; in the last eight years &#8212; have pointed out that if a kid goes to &#8212; not daycare, but preschool, beginning at age three, they increase, by 58 percent, the possibility of going all the way through school and on to community college.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we support universal pre-K for three- and four-year-olds. (Applause.)&nbsp; And, Terry, if I get it done, you all aren&#8217;t going to have to pay for it here in Virginia.</p>



<p>And, look, we believe 12 years of education is not enough to compete in the 21st century economy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I want to make two-year community college available to every single American.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We can afford to do this.</p>



<p>I do have one concern.&nbsp; My wife Jill is teaching fulltime still as a community college professor and First Lady.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But Terry is going to be her boss again.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Because she teaches at Vir- &#8212; anyway &#8212; Northern Virginia Community College.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, Terry, since the time she started working there, she&#8217;s never stopped teaching.&nbsp; When we got elected, she thought that she was going to continue to teach.&nbsp; She thought I might object.&nbsp; I strongly supported it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Teaching is not what my wife does; it&#8217;s who she is.</p>



<p>And, folks, look &#8212; look, the fact is that the idea that we are able to bring together people to give them great opportunities is totally within &#8212; you know, look &#8212; and we can afford to do this. We can afford to do this. If the very wealthy just start paying their fair share just a little bit. (Applause.)</p>



<p>Terry and I know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; how hard the pandemic has been on working families, especially women.&nbsp; About 2 million women are still unable to go back into the workforce during this pandemic due to things like not being able to afford childcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, when I got elected to the United States Senate, I was 29 years old.&nbsp; Between the time I got elected and before I was sworn in, there was an automobile accident.&nbsp; My wife and daughter were killed and my two boys almost died.&nbsp; And, by the way, I thank all firefighters.&nbsp; It took the Jaws of Life three hours to get them out on top of their dead mom and dead sister.&nbsp; You saved their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I needed help.&nbsp; I was a senator making $42,000 a year.&nbsp; I could no longer afford daycare and someone to take care of my kids (inaudible).&nbsp; And thank God I had a sister who is my friend, who &#8212; she and her husband, without my asking, moved in and helped me raise my kids.&nbsp; My mom and my brother as well.&nbsp; I got lucky.</p>



<p>But, look, the idea, as a single mom or a single dad, working and having young children &#8212; it&#8217;s awful hard.&nbsp; That’s why Terry and I want to expand paid leave and childcare in this country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, Terry, you and I have been talking about this for a long time.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been talking about high drug prices &#8212; how incredibly high they are and how we keep getting ripped off.&nbsp; You know, we pay more for our drugs than any major country in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the deal.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a way to do it: Let Medicare negotiate drug prices.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; All of the prices are going to come down.&nbsp; And it will pay for itself.&nbsp; I promise you, I&#8217;m going to get that done.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look &#8212; and here&#8217;s the deal, Terry and I know this can be paid for.&nbsp; Look, we support asking the wealthiest 1 percent who got that $2 trillion tax cut that, in fact &#8212; in fact, not a single penny was paid for &#8212; the so-called &#8220;Trump tax cut.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And guess what?&nbsp; Just pay.&nbsp; Begin to pay their fair share.&nbsp; Corporate America &#8212; I come from the corporate capital of the world.&nbsp; More corporations are, in fact, registered in Delaware than every other state in the union combined.&nbsp; I got elected 36 years there because I was honest with them.</p>



<p>Look, fift- &#8212; right today, 50 of the biggest corporations in America of the Fortune 500 &#8212; 50 of them don’t pay &#8212; and this is not an exaggeration; check it out &#8212; not a single solitary penny in federal taxes.&nbsp; Not one.&nbsp; And they made over 40 &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, but &#8212; no, but I’m not doing this to get &#8212; I just want to make it clear to you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the deal: They made over $40 billion.&nbsp; If they just paid a minimum tax of 15 percent, they&#8217;d raise the dollars &#8212; all we need to do all this education we&#8217;re talking about here.</p>



<p>Look, you know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; when I was Vice President, the President asked me to check out what the major corporations needed the most.&nbsp; Along with the Secretary of Commerce, we interviewed three hundred and, I think it was, fifty-six &#8212; it could have been forty-six &#8212; but over three hundred and fifty CEOs and major corporations.</p>



<p>You know what they all said?&nbsp; &#8220;I need a better-educated workforce.&#8221;&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; They&#8217;re not spending any money to educate the workforce.</p>



<p>But if we want to make sure America succeeds and runs the world again &#8212; economically runs and &#8212; be the most powerful economy in the world, we should make sure that they have a chance.</p>



<p>These millionaires and billionaires &#8212; I&#8217;m not one of these guys that say you shouldn&#8217;t be able to be a millionaire or billionaire.&nbsp; But just pay your fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, all told, experts in the World Bank &#8212; outfits like Wall Street like Moody&#8217;s estimate that my plan will grow the economy and create $2 million more jobs over the $16 million they said in 10 years we&#8217;d create &#8212; good-paying jobs.&nbsp; Good-paying jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>A significant amount of these jobs will pay the prevailing wage of 30, 40, 50 bucks an hour.&nbsp; Ninety percent of the jobs in our infrastructure plan go to people without a college degree.</p>



<p>Folks, we&#8217;re proposing a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America &#8212; a once-in-a-generation investment in American jobs and families that&#8217;s going to position us to win the competition for the 21st century.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;ve got to get it done.&nbsp; And I need a partner like Terry who not only is respected in this state, but is respected by governors all across America, who knows how to get it done in the states.</p>



<p>Folks, on his watch as governor the last time, the Virginia economy boomed.&nbsp; Two hundred million &#8212; 200,000 jobs created.&nbsp; Unemployment went down in every single county, including rural Virginia, by nearly 50 percent.</p>



<p>He attracted major companies to this state.&nbsp; Look how your state grew.&nbsp; And by the way, any of you who are in the business know the first thing you try to attract a company to come to your city, your state, your town &#8212; the first thing they ask is, “What&#8217;s the highway system?&nbsp; Will I have access to interstate?&nbsp; Is the port available?&nbsp; Tell me whether or not I have broadband.&nbsp; Tell me whether or not…”&nbsp; All the things.&nbsp; All the things we’re going to build.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, look, Terry worked with Republicans to invest in education, transportation, and workforce development.&nbsp; And, by the way, Virginia has a whole bunch of veterans and active-duty military members &#8212; more than almost any state.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And guess what?&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan marked one of the biggest investments in veterans’ health in a long, long time.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It will upgrade VA hospitals that are 50 years old, reduce the shortages of doctors and nurses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No veteran &#8212; from my son who passed away on &#8212; should pick up a phone and say, or have a wife or husband call and say, “I need help,” and say, “We can&#8217;t see you for a while.”&nbsp; We owe them immediate action.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Immediate.&nbsp; It’s a sacred obligation.</p>



<p>And I know no governor who stood up for our veterans and military families more than this guy, helping them apply their skills to good-paying civilian jobs &#8212; fields like cybersecurity and healthcare.</p>



<p>He also worked with the General Assembly to fund two new veteran care centers, including the first one in Hampton Roads region, which is hard to believe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Terry understands.&nbsp; He knows &#8212; he knows also about crime prevention as a top priority.</p>



<p>He understands how important it is funding &#8212; to find funding &#8212; from the American Rescue Plan to provide law enforcement personnel with more resources, not fewer resources.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, we need to help in a lot of ways.&nbsp; We need to do away with chokeholds and all those things.&nbsp; I agree, but (inaudible) side of this is we need them to have more social workers, more veterans, more psychological help, more psychologists.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And where it happens, it works.&nbsp; Personnel and resources, they keep communities safe.</p>



<p>And he has taken on the gun lobby to enact sensible gun safety measures without infringing on anybody’s Second Amendment right, including keeping guns out of the hands of domestic abusers.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Here’s what else: Terry is going to guarantee he&#8217;s going to move to get a $15 minimum wage.&nbsp; Think about it, folks.&nbsp; Just think about it.&nbsp; And you &#8212; maybe some of you, maybe you know people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anybody working 40 hours a week making less than $15 an hour is, in fact, living in poverty as defined by poverty in America.&nbsp; It should not happen, period.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>An amazing number of American people who are struggling have rental costs and housing costs that are at least 30 to 35 percent of their total income.&nbsp; How do you do that?&nbsp; How do you make it, especially if you have a child?&nbsp; Look, folks, housing that&#8217;s affordable &#8212; everybody is going to be in the plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, like me, when Terry thinks about the climate crisis, he thinks three things: jobs, jobs, jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It is the reason why we’re going to lead the world.</p>



<p>Let me close with this &#8212; and I’m sorry, I’m getting kind of wrapped up in this.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I need him.&nbsp; I need him.&nbsp; Look, in this election and in 2022, the question the American people are going to be asking is whether or not we’re helping them and their families &#8212; not giving them anything.&nbsp; Are we giving them a shot &#8212; just giving them an even shot?&nbsp; Do we understand what they’re going through?&nbsp; Can we deliver for them?</p>



<p>As Democrats, we have to show we do understand, and we’re delivering for them, and we’re keeping our promises.&nbsp; We just have to keep making the case &#8212; just as the Republican Party today offers nothing but fear, lies, and broken promises.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>No, listen &#8212; I mean, think about it &#8212; turning on the television every day and seeing a replay of what happened on January 6th and saying, “I was told there were a lot of peaceful, wonderful people.”</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; God &#8212; no, I really mean it.&nbsp; Think about it. &nbsp;It is bizarre.</p>



<p>We have to keep cutting through the Republican fog that government is the problem and show that &#8220;We the People&#8221; are the solution.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re the most unique country &#8212; think about this &#8212; we’re the most unique country in the history of the world.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Every other country is put together based on race, religion, ethnicity, background, except the United States.</p>



<p>The United States is based on &#8212; the only country in the world based on the proposition that “We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all women and men are created equal.&nbsp; Endowed by their creator with certain unalienable rights.”&nbsp; Life, liberty, the pursuit of happiness.&nbsp; We’ve never met the test, but we’ve never walked away from it like the Republicans have.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have never walked away.&nbsp; And we keep &#8212; every administration, we keep moving that needle further and further.</p>



<p>Look, folks, we’re going to have to go out and win &#8212; win this thing, win races up and down the ticket.&nbsp; We got to protect your majority in the House of Delegates.&nbsp; (Applause)&nbsp; We got to re-elect Mark as Attorney General.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We got to re-elect Hala as your Lieutenant Governor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We got to elect Terry back as Governor. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp; He’s been here before.&nbsp; He knows what to do to.&nbsp; He knows how to get things done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Virginia, we did it in 2020.&nbsp; In the battle for the soul of America, the people voted.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Democracy prevailed.&nbsp; The Constitution held.&nbsp; We have to do this again.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I’ve said, time and again, no matter what, you can never stop the American people from voting.&nbsp; And they’re trying like hell.&nbsp; We have to decide.&nbsp; The power must always be with the people.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Fifty &#8212; I promise you this &#8212; fifty years from now &#8212; fifty years from now, our children and grandchildren will look back and know that it was at this moment America won the 21st century again.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And it starts now.&nbsp; Virginia, it starts with Terry.&nbsp; It starts with you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>8:28 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with President Ashraf Ghani of Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-president-ashraf-ghani-of-afghanistan-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 23:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Ashraf Ghani of Afghanistan.&#160; President Biden and President Ghani discussed the situation in Afghanistan and reaffirmed their commitment to an enduring bilateral partnership.&#160; President Biden emphasized continued U.S. support, including development and humanitarian aid, for the Afghan people, including women, girls, and minorities.&#160; President Biden and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Ashraf Ghani of Afghanistan.&nbsp; President Biden and President Ghani discussed the situation in Afghanistan and reaffirmed their commitment to an enduring bilateral partnership.&nbsp; President Biden emphasized continued U.S. support, including development and humanitarian aid, for the Afghan people, including women, girls, and minorities.&nbsp; President Biden and President Ghani agreed that the Taliban’s current offensive is in direct contradiction to the movement’s claim to support a negotiated settlement of the conflict. &nbsp;President Biden also reaffirmed the United States’ commitment to continue supporting the Afghan security forces to defend themselves. The FY2022 request to Congress for $3.3 billion for the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund prioritizes:</p>



<ol><li>$1 billion to ensure the Afghan Air Force and Special Mission Wing have the capabilities and maintenance to support ongoing combat operations, including by delivering additional aircraft, such as the three newly-refurbished UH-60 Blackhawk helicopters delivered to Kabul on July 16;</li><li>$1 billion to purchase and deliver key supplies for Afghan forces such as fuel, ammunition, and spare parts; and</li><li>$700 million to fund continued payment of salaries for Afghan soldiers.</li></ol>



<p>They deplored the loss of innocent Afghan lives, including through continued targeted killings, as well as displacement of the civilian population, looting and burning of buildings, destruction of vital infrastructure, and damage to communication networks.&nbsp;The United States recently announced more than $266 million in additional&nbsp;humanitarian assistance and released $300 million in development and other non-humanitarian assistance to help the Afghan people.&nbsp;The President has also requested an additional $364 million in development and other non-humanitarian assistance for the State Department and USAID for FY2022.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden urged continued work for unity among Afghan leaders on behalf of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan and the values on which it is based.&nbsp; The two leaders discussed the importance of Afghans coming together to support their common interest in security and peace, and President Biden underscored continued U.S. diplomatic engagement in support of a durable and just political settlement.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Roundtable with Transgender Women of Color Advocates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-transgender-women-of-color-advocates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council Julissa Reynoso hosted a roundtable at the White House with transgender women of color advocates from around the country. This event was the first in a series of listening sessions that will be convened by the White House-led Interagency Working Group&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council Julissa Reynoso hosted a roundtable at the White House with transgender women of color advocates from around the country. This event was the first in a series of listening sessions that will be convened by the White House-led Interagency Working Group on Safety, Inclusion, and Opportunity for Transgender Individuals, which was <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-advances-equality-for-transgender-americans/">announced</a> by the White House in June.</p>



<p>Participants discussed the epidemic levels of violence and harassment faced by transgender women and girls of color. They noted that discrimination, homelessness, intimate partner violence, poverty, unemployment, immigration and other systemic barriers take a disproportionate toll on transgender women and girls of color and are drivers of the violence visited upon transgender women of color. Participants shared their policy recommendations for advancing economic justice, opportunity, health equity, and safety for transgender individuals. They also highlighted the strength, resilience, and hope that drive their advocacy and the importance of creating more opportunities to lift up diverse voices from the transgender community and support their leadership.</p>



<p>Ambassador Rice and Co-Chair Reynoso shared their appreciation for the advocacy and policy recommendations provided by the participants. They reiterated that the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to advancing justice, opportunity, and safety for transgender women of color and all LGBTQ+ people and families in America. They emphasized that the Domestic Policy Council and Gender Policy Council will take an intersectional approach to advancing gender equity and racial justice as they lead the Interagency Working Group on Safety, Inclusion, and Opportunity for Transgender Individuals.</p>



<p>Participants in today’s roundtable included:</p>



<ul><li>Tori Cooper, Director of Community Engagement for the Transgender Justice Initiative, Human Rights Campaign</li><li>Ruby Corado, Founder, Casa Ruby</li><li>Sage Dolan-Sandrino, youth advocate, National Black Justice Institute</li><li>Andrea “Andy” Marra, Executive Director, Transgender Legal Defense &amp; Education Fund</li><li>Bamby Salcedo, President and CEO, TransLatin@</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Iranian-American Journalist and Activist Masih Alinejad</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-iranian-american-journalist-and-activist-masih-alinejad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Iranian-American journalist and activist Masih Alinejad and her husband Kambiz Foroohar. During the meeting, Mr. Sullivan expressed concern for Ms. Alinejad’s family and colleagues who are detained in Iran. He affirmed the U.S. Government’s strong continued support for Ms. Alinejad’s work to advance universal human rights, particularly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Iranian-American journalist and activist Masih Alinejad and her husband Kambiz Foroohar. During the meeting, Mr. Sullivan expressed concern for Ms. Alinejad’s family and colleagues who are detained in Iran. He affirmed the U.S. Government’s strong continued support for Ms. Alinejad’s work to advance universal human rights, particularly her tireless efforts on behalf of women, the Iranian people, and all those unjustly detained by the Iranian government. Mr. Sullivan noted with concern the growing practice of authoritarian regimes such as Iran targeting dissidents, activists, and journalists across international borders, including within the United States. The U.S. Government will continue to strenuously oppose these illegal actions, which violate human rights and threaten the rules-based international order.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/memorandum-on-unexpected-urgent-refugee-and-migration-needs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 2(c)(1) of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (22 U.S.C. 2601(c)(1)) (MRAA), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 2(c)(1) of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs<br><br><br>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 2(c)(1) of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (22 U.S.C. 2601(c)(1)) (MRAA), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 2(c)(1) of the MRAA, that it is important to furnish assistance under the MRAA in an amount of up to $100 million from the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund for the purpose of meeting unexpected urgent refugee and migration needs, victims of conflict, and other persons at risk as a result of the situation in Afghanistan, including applicants for Special Immigrant Visas.  Such assistance may be provided on a bilateral or multilateral basis as appropriate, including through contributions to international organizations and through funding to other nongovernmental organizations, governments, and United States departments and agencies.<br><br>This determination supersedes Presidential Determination 2021-08 of June 11, 2021. <br><br>You are authorized and directed to submit this determination to the Congress, along with the accompanying Justification, and to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum for the Secretary of State on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/23/memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-state-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a2-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 652 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), and in order to provide assistance for refugees, victims of conflict,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 652 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), and in order to provide assistance for refugees, victims of conflict, and other persons at risk as a result of the situation in Afghanistan, including applicants for Special Immigrant Visas, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(1) &nbsp;the authority under section 506(a)(2) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $200,000,000 in articles and services from the inventory and resources of any agency of the United States Government and military education and training from the Department of Defense for the purposes and under the authorities of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(2) &nbsp;the authority to make the determination under section&nbsp;506(a)(2) of the FAA to direct such drawdown; and<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(3) &nbsp;the authority under section 652 of the FAA to make, before any such drawdown, the required notifications to the&nbsp;Congress.<br><br>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
