<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 17:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Responds to Early Wildfires in New&#160;Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/07/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-responds-to-early-wildfires-in-new-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 14:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early season wildfires in New Mexico and across the Southwest are devastating communities and ravaging landscapes.&#160; So far this year, the number of acres burned across the United States is approximately 78% above the 10-year average.&#160; Much of the West, Plains, and Texas remain in a historic drought with above average temperatures and below normal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Early season wildfires in New Mexico and across the Southwest are devastating communities and ravaging landscapes.&nbsp; So far this year, the number of acres burned across the United States is approximately 78% above the 10-year average.&nbsp; Much of the West, Plains, and Texas remain in a historic drought with above average temperatures and below normal precipitation, creating the conditions for more large and dangerous wildfires this year.&nbsp; While the National Wildland Fire Preparedness Level remains at Level 2 (of 5), the Southwest Region was elevated to Preparedness Level 4 on April 19<sup>th</sup>, the earliest date this has ever occurred.&nbsp; New Mexico has been particularly hard hit, with six of the Nation’s ten large wildfires currently burning in the State, consuming more than 250,000 acres.&nbsp; This has created an unprecedented situation in the State, with far reaching impacts on communities, families, and livelihoods.</p>



<p><strong>The Biden Administration is taking prompt action to ensure that all applicable Federal resources are mobilized to help New Mexico communities respond to and recover from these devastating wildfires.</strong>&nbsp; The President receives regular briefings on the spread of fires in New Mexico from his Homeland Security Advisor.&nbsp; On Wednesday May 4, he approved a Major Disaster Declaration for Colfax, Lincoln, Mora, San Miguel, and Valencia Counties in New Mexico to support the State in responding to and recovering from several intense wildfires.</p>



<p><strong>Robust Wildfire Response</strong></p>



<p>The National Interagency Fire Center continues to surge resources to the area to address this early start to the region’s wildfire season, including firefighting crews, aircraft, engines, and incident management teams from the U.S. Forest Service (USFS) and the Department of the Interior (DOI).&nbsp; These Federal firefighters joined state, local, and Tribal firefighters in New Mexico for a unified and coordinated response growing to nearly 2,700 personnel as of May 6</p>



<p>FEMA has approved six Fire Management Assistance Grants to support New Mexico this year.&nbsp; These funds will support the state in providing mitigation, management, and control of the fires, as well as provide funding for emergency work, including procuring equipment and supplies for responders, supporting evacuation requirements such as traffic control and sheltering residents, pre-positioning resources to support the response, and establishing field camps and meals for responders.</p>



<p>Throughout the response, the Department of Energy’s Los Alamos National Laboratory (LANL) in Los Alamos, New Mexico has been working to ensure the safety and security of facilities and staff and is actively engaged with the surrounding community and response officials.&nbsp; LANL has pre-positioned assets to assist the Los Alamos Fire Department and Federal responders with the protection of key facilities.&nbsp; LANL is also continuing ongoing efforts to mitigate the risk of wildfire through fuels reduction activities. In addition, the Laboratory’s Wildland Fire team has reduced undergrowth and other fuels in the forests around the Lab property for many years and the Lab has prepared to prevent the spread of fire on Lab property.</p>



<p><strong>Support to Communities</strong></p>



<p>The President’s approval of a Major Disaster Declaration on May 4 provides <a href="https://www.fema.gov/disaster/4652">additional Federal funding</a> to help communities recover from the impacts of these fires.&nbsp; This support includes financial assistance for temporary and long-term housing, repairs, and other critical needs for people who have had to evacuate and makes available low-interest loans from the Small Business Administration for businesses and homeowners impacted by the fires.&nbsp;</p>



<p>FEMA has pre-positioned meals, water, and shelter items for 30,000 people.&nbsp; In addition, the American Red Cross and New Mexico have established shelters for residents who are displaced from their homes.</p>



<p>A Federal Coordinating Officer is on the ground and working with the State to identify and address emerging or unmet needs.&nbsp; FEMA’s Incident Management Assistance Team is embedded with the State Emergency Operations Center to assist with coordination of all Federal resources available to the State, and they are continuing to work with the State to conduct joint preliminary damage assessments that will inform recovery planning.&nbsp; FEMA has placed multi-lingual disaster survivor assistance teams on the ground to work directly with New Mexico residents impacted by the fires to ensure they have access to and are able to register quickly for Federal assistance.</p>



<p><strong>Resilient Recovery</strong></p>



<p>Looking ahead, the summer Southwestern monsoon season and associated heavy rains can cause substantial watershed impacts from burned areas. These events can result in significant soil erosion, flooding, and debris flows and impact both natural resources and communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;Federal agencies are working with the State and local communities to anticipate and prepare for potential flooding and to support post-fire mitigation activities.&nbsp;&nbsp;The USFS has established a statewide post-fire response and recovery team with New Mexico, the Natural Resource Conservation Service, the Farm Bureau, and other Federal interagency partners to coordinate efforts and access to funding for environmental response, stabilization, and recovery.</p>



<p>DOI and USFS interagency Burned Area Emergency Response teams have already been assigned to the New Mexico Fires. Teams are composed of resource specialists who determine the need for, prescribe, and can implement emergency treatments to minimize threats to life or property or prevent further damage to natural and cultural resources on Federal land. Assessments completed by these teams will support development of post fire recovery plans and actions in coordination with the state.</p>



<p>The USDA has made resources available to support farmers and ranchers whose land, crops, or livestock have been damaged or lost as a result of wildfires.&nbsp; These programs include the Livestock Indemnity Program; Emergency Assistance for Livestock, Honey Bees, and Farm-raised Fish; Forage Disaster Program; and the Noninsured Crop Disaster Assistance Program.&nbsp; USDA also provides low-interest loans to help farmers and ranchers recover from production and physical losses and reestablish their operations.&nbsp; Local USDA staff at county service centers near the declared counties are available to assist farmers and ranchers with accessing this assistance.</p>



<p>USDA also has programs to support mitigation and recovery, including an Environmental Quality Incentives Program to assist with immediate needs and long-term support to help recover from natural disasters and conserve water resources, an Emergency Conservation Program to rehabilitate farmlands damaged by disaster, and an Emergency Forest Restoration Program to restore private forestlands.&nbsp; USDA’s Emergency Watershed Protection Program can also help relieve imminent threats to life and property caused by fire that impairs a watershed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden Administration will continue to work hard to ensure that the Federal government does everything it can to provide support to New Mexicans who need help as a result of these early and extremely damaging wildfires. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Trudeau of&#160;Canada</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-trudeau-of-canada/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 01:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada. Both leaders underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine and economic and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada. Both leaders underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine and economic and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected by the violence. The President lauded Canada’s close partnership throughout this crisis, and leadership in enacting comprehensive sanctions and restrictions on Russia. The leaders also discussed their upcoming participation in the Summit of the Americas in June, and their shared vision for green and equitable growth for the hemisphere, among other Summit goals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden on the Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act￼</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/06/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-bipartisan-innovation-act%ef%bf%bc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 21:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United Performance MetalsHamilton, Ohio 3:18 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Sherrod, for that introduction.&#160; Folks, he’s a &#8212; he’s a real champion of a really important aspect of work.&#160; My dad used to say, “A job is about a lot more than a paycheck &#8212; it’s about your dignity.&#160; It’s about your place in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">United Performance Metals<br>Hamilton, Ohio</p>



<p>3:18 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Sherrod, for that introduction.&nbsp; Folks, he’s a &#8212; he’s a real champion of a really important aspect of work.&nbsp; My dad used to say, “A job is about a lot more than a paycheck &#8212; it’s about your dignity.&nbsp; It’s about your place in the community.”&nbsp; These guys do, because they care about the dignity of the worker.&nbsp; And I see things are really beginning to change.&nbsp; I really believe it.</p>



<p>And Senator Portman &#8212; since he’s not running again, I can say all the nice things about him that I want &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and it won’t get him in any trouble, because he’s &#8212; he’s leaving.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Rob spoke at the White House when I signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that he helped &#8212; they both helped put together.&nbsp; And the truth of the matter is we may not agree on everything, although we agree on more than he’d want to admit.&nbsp; I think his &#8212; I want thank to him for his leadership for bringing folks together to find common ground.</p>



<p>You know, things have kind of changed since the days when I first got there.&nbsp; He’s been there a couple terms.&nbsp; I was there &#8212; I got elected when I was 29 years old, in the United States Senate, from a very modest background.&nbsp; And I was there for 36 years before becoming Vice President.</p>



<p>We always used to fight like hell &#8212; and even back in the old days when we had real segregationists, like Eastland and Thurmond and all those guys &#8212; but at least we’d end up eating lunch together.</p>



<p>Things have changed.&nbsp; We got to bring it back.</p>



<p>And, Rob, I’m sorry you’re leaving because you’re one of the good guys.&nbsp; I don’t mean &#8212; I mean because the way you treat other senators, the way you treat everybody.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Sherrod &#8212; Sherrod and Rob and I were together at the White House in January.&nbsp; And we were with the CEO of Intel, who asked whether he could come to the White House; he wanted to talk to me.&nbsp; And he announced in the White House &#8212; at the White House a $20 billion commitment to build state-of-the-art semiconductors and a “mega-site” on nearly 1,000 empty acres just near Cleveland &#8212; or Columbus, I should say.</p>



<p>It’s one of the largest investments of its kind, period, that we’ve ever had in Amer- &#8212; all of American history: 7,000 jobs building the facility; 3,000 permanent jobs to run that facility.&nbsp; You know what the average salary is going to be for that person run- &#8212; the folks working in that factory?&nbsp; $135,000 a year.&nbsp; They’re going to get paid a decent wage, and they’re not all experts and college-educated folks.&nbsp; A lot of blue-collar folks, too.&nbsp; Making the timely &#8212; this thin, thin, little computer chip that literally powers everything in our life these days &#8212; almost everything in life, including the cellphone you’re holding up.&nbsp; It makes a difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In my State of the Union address, I called it a “field of dreams” where America &#8212; America’s future is going to be built.&nbsp; And I quoted Sherrod at the time because he said he’s going to bury the label “Rust Belt.”&nbsp; He’s going to bury the label “Rust Belt.”</p>



<p>I come from Scranton, Pennsylvania.&nbsp; And we used to, from Scranton all the way through Ohio and all the way across the Midwest, be the manufacturing citadel of the world.</p>



<p>Today, we’re joined by leaders of some of the biggest manufacturers in the comp- &#8212; in the country &#8212; GE, Siemens Energy, Honeywell, Raytheon, Lockheed Martin &#8212; to announce a new initiative that &#8212; that buries &#8212; going to bury that label for good, the “Rust Belt.”</p>



<p>You know, we’re at this plant because it’s smaller manufacturers &#8212; smaller manufacturers that are going to make this happen.&nbsp; And we’re here to show why, along with the innovation bill in front of Congress, all of this is going to help address what is on everyone’s mind: fighting inflation, getting prices down.</p>



<p>We just toured the productivity bay looking at cutting-edge 3D printing.&nbsp; And we met with a group of suppliers that use 3D printing to make parts for big, complex machines like aircraft, power generators, consumer products like hip implants.&nbsp; It goes across the board.</p>



<p>And now, for the folks at home, you might ask why does it matter to you at home?&nbsp; Well, I know you’re worried about the price of gas, food, and other necessities.&nbsp; And why &#8212; why it matters if we make more things here in America.<br><br>Well, it matters a great deal because the pandemic and the economic crisis that we inherited, and Putin’s war in Ukraine, have all shown the vulnerability when we become too reliant on things made overseas.</p>



<p>We learned the hard way that we can’t fight inflation if supply chains buckle and send prices through the roof every time there’s a disruption &#8212; which there have been constant disruptions, particularly in South Asia.</p>



<p>We know that one of the best ways to fight inflation is &#8212; to bring prices down &#8212; and bring prices down is to strengthen the resilience of our supply chains, and that includes making more things here in America, at home, from top to bottom.&nbsp; And that’s been my priority since day one.</p>



<p>If I can slow here for just a second and point out that, you know, I didn’t realize &#8212; I’d been a senator for a long time and a Vice President for eight years &#8212; I didn’t realize there was an act passed back in 1939; it was called “Buy American.”&nbsp; I didn’t know it existed.&nbsp; It’s totally within the bounds of negotiated eve- &#8212; negotiated deals on trade.&nbsp; It says that when the President spends your money appropriated by the Congress, the President should only buy products or elect contracts for things that are made in America, whether it’s the deck of an aircraft carrier or it’s a computer chip.</p>



<p>Today’s jobs report shows our plans and priorities have produced the strongest job creation the econ- &#8212; in the modern times of the American economy.</p>



<p>Today’s report shows we created 428,000 jobs last month.&nbsp; And that means we have now created a total of 8.3 million jobs&nbsp;in my first 15 months in office, with the help of the gentlemen behind me.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the unemployment rate now stands at 3.6 percent &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment in the start of a President’s &#8212; in a President’s term ever recorded.&nbsp; Again, because of the guys behind me.</p>



<p>Black unemployment has been cut nearly in half since I took office.</p>



<p>And unlike previous administrations where the deficit went up, every single year, we’ve reduced the deficit.&nbsp; Last year, with all we’ve done, we’ve reduced the deficit &#8212; (the President is handed a microphone) &#8212; does this work? &#8212; we reduced the deficit by a total of $350 billion.&nbsp; That’s reduced the deficit.&nbsp; Last year.&nbsp; And this year, by the end of the fiscal year &#8212; by October 1st &#8212; we will reduce this year’s deficit by one trillion five hundred billion dollars.&nbsp; Never in the history of America has that happened before.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the backbone of our recovery is manufacturing.&nbsp; Manufacturing employment is up, in America, 545,000 jobs since I took office &#8212; the largest 15-month gain since 1985.</p>



<p>And these manufacturing jobs matter because they fuel our economic growth.&nbsp; They fuel exports.&nbsp; And, as we’ve seen, they can fuel innovation, and that is a critically &#8212; critically strong economic growth that we need.</p>



<p>And, folks, look &#8212; and in small and large towns across America, they bring quality jobs and middle-class jobs to the &#8212; to the &#8212; to people.<br><br>I &#8212; if you, again, excuse me to digress a second, I &#8212; when I ran, I made it clear &#8212; and I’m no bones about it; I was a senator for 36 years, so I’m not new to this: I’m tired of trickle-down economics.&nbsp; I’ve never seen it really work.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But I tell you what: I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; I want to build this economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; Because when that happens, everybody does well.&nbsp; The poor have a way up, the middle class do fine, and the wealthy do very, very well.&nbsp; Never get hurt when that happens.<br><br>Just ask small manufacturers here today in Ohio, Illinois, Florida, Connecticut, Virginia.&nbsp; They know what’s going on.</p>



<p>Folks, here &#8212; you know, all of you know &#8212; every one of you know that competitiveness and resilience of American supply chain rests on tens of thousands of small-sized manufacturers like the ones I met here today.&nbsp; That’s &#8212; that’s where the supply chain in America is.&nbsp; And they account for nearly 99 percent of all manufacturing enterprises and more than 5 million American jobs.</p>



<p>And every General Electric, Honeywell, Siemens Energy, Raytheon, Lockheed Martin &#8212; there are hundreds &#8212; for every one of them, there’s hundreds if not thousands of smaller suppliers that help these iconic American businesses compete globally.&nbsp; And when they do well, the big businesses do even better.</p>



<p>These small firms are the foundation of America’s industrial base.&nbsp; And increasing their capacity &#8212; which these big businesses are doing as well &#8212; is critical to making more things in America, getting products faster and cheaper and reliably, and outcompeting the rest of the world.&nbsp; That’s what it’s about.</p>



<p>But here’s the deal: 3D printing technology &#8212; 3D printing technology is incredible.&nbsp; It can reduce the parts lead times by as much as 90 percent &#8212; not always, but as much as 90 percent &#8212; slash material cost by 90 percent, and cut energy use in half.</p>



<p>That all helps to lower the cost of making goods here in America.</p>



<p>But not all small- and medium-sized firms have access to the resources and financing and support they need to adapt these &#8212; to this technology, until today.</p>



<p>The executives here today have agreed to launch a new compact between large iconic manufacturers and smaller American suppliers.</p>



<p>A commitment by these large companies to help those smaller ones adapt new technologies so we can continue to be the leading exporter of aircrafts and engines and in areas like medical devices, clean energy technologies, and so much more.</p>



<p>Look, our hope is that the compact will grow with more companies and expand into different industries.&nbsp; And as part of this initiative, agencies across the federal government &#8212; all across the federal government &#8212; are going to step up with access to loans, technical assistance, and so much more, including education.<br><br>We’re supporting this new partnership because this private sector has told us they can’t do it alone.</p>



<p>I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; I’m here, and I believe in the free market.&nbsp; But I believe in a federal government’s obligation to invest in America itself, invest in American workers.&nbsp; And we’re at risk of falling behind.</p>



<p>Decades ago, the federal government used to invest 2 percent of our entire GDP &#8212; 2 percent of our GDP &#8212; in research and development.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; We’re down to investing less than 1 percent.</p>



<p>We were ranked number one in the world in R&amp;D three decades ago.&nbsp; Number one.&nbsp; Now we’re ranked number nine in the world.&nbsp; China was number eight in the world 30 years ago.&nbsp; Now they’re number two in the world.</p>



<p>We’ve got to up our game.&nbsp; It’s a simple proposition.&nbsp; If we do, everybody is going to win.&nbsp; That’s the other reason why I came here today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Right now, Congress is considering a Bipartisan Innovation Act &#8212; that’s what it’s called &#8212; that’s going to make generational investments in American innovation and manufacturing.</p>



<p>Now, look, if we’re going to compete for the jobs of the future, we need to level the playing the field with our competitors.&nbsp; The bill does that.</p>



<p>The CEO of Intel told us that if this bill passes &#8212; what we’re talking about &#8212; and the guys behind me support it, and they’re actually moving it &#8212; this would increase the investment that Intel will make in Ohio, outside of Columbus, from $20 billion to $100 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we Irish say: That’s no malarkey, that’s a fact.&nbsp; One hundred billion dollars.&nbsp; Imagine what that’s going to do to &#8211;for Ohio, let alone Columbus.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; It’d be staggering.&nbsp; And it will nail down, for generations, the leadership of this state once again, like it used to be 30, 40, 50, 60 years ago.</p>



<p>And it’s not just Intel.&nbsp; Foreign companies, like Samsung and TSMC, are ready to make state-of-the-art chips &#8212; those computer chips &#8212; ready to make them in Arizona and Texas.&nbsp; They already have the fa- &#8212; if this passes.</p>



<p>And this is a bipartisan bill.&nbsp; Senators Brown and Portman have been working hard to get it done.</p>



<p>So, every Republican and Democratic member of Congress &#8212; most of us agree on this.&nbsp; Pass the damn bill and send it to me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If we do, it’s going to help bring down prices, bring home jobs, and power America’s manufacturing comeback.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, and we’ll &#8212; and we’re going &#8212; also going to help reduce costs and strengthen our economic and national security.&nbsp; It’s no wonder the Chinese Communist Party is literally lobbying &#8212; paying lobbyists &#8212; against this bill passing.</p>



<p>If I’d note parenthetically again: I have spent, according to international folks &#8212; I spent more time with Xi Jinping, leader of China, than any other world leader has &#8212; over 76 hours, nine of them on a telephone, the rest in person &#8212; since I was Vice President and he was Vice President of China.</p>



<p>And you know what?&nbsp; He makes it real clear &#8212; he makes it real clear: He believes, like other autocrats around the world, that democracies can’t compete in the 21st century.&nbsp; Because things are changing so rapidly; technology is changing things so &#8212; in such a startling way.&nbsp; Countries are changing literally &#8212; literally changing their physical characteristics because of climate change.</p>



<p>And he believes &#8212; and he says it straight up with me &#8212; that there is no way for democracies to compete with autocracies.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Because we have to rai- &#8212; we have to reach a consensus when we’re in a democracy, and it takes time.&nbsp; But autocrats can move immediately; they don’t have to wait.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; So far, in the last decade, he’s been right.&nbsp; So much has changed.&nbsp; Just look around the world, what’s happening.</p>



<p>Those of you who are international business people, look what you have to do when you go to China to do business.&nbsp; You have to give them access to everything &#8212; everything you have, including your trade secrets.<br><br>Not just China though.&nbsp; China is not alone, but it is a single-greatest competitor we have.&nbsp; And if we don’t step up, we’re going to be out.&nbsp; We’re going to be out.<br><br>And, by the way, I showed up at a meeting called the G7, where the largest economies in the world meet.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; Two of them said to me that they thought that America’s days were over as leader.<br><br>I sat down at the meeting &#8212; the first meeting I attended &#8212; I had one on Saturday &#8212; but the first meeting I attended in England.&nbsp; And I had all the major G7 nations there, including two members who were not &#8212; two nations that were not members, including India.<br><br>And I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And the President of one of the major [countries]<s>companies</s>&nbsp;looked at me and said, “For how long?&nbsp; For how long?”&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; You guys know it.&nbsp; I mean, these guys are sophisticated as hell.&nbsp; “For how long?”<br><br>Well, guess what?&nbsp; They know we’re back now &#8212; not because of me, because of them and all the attitude is changing in America.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve never seen a time when Europe and NATO was more closely aligned.&nbsp; No &#8212; no breathing room between us.&nbsp; Closer than we have ever been.&nbsp; Because a lot of us &#8212; I spent well over 120 hours either in person or on the phone with my colleagues and my counterparts every single solitary week and most days of the week, making it clear that for democracies to sustain what used to be the case, we have to step up our game across the board.<br><br>You know, there’s a thing for the &#8212; the Democratic Institute where you have &#8212; I was supposed to hold a meeting of all the heads of state of democratic countries.&nbsp; And we had to do it virtually from the White House.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; In the last 10 years, there’s 15 fewer democracies in the world.&nbsp; Fewer.&nbsp; Not more, fewer.<br><br>There’s a lot at stake, but we’re better prepared than anybody else.&nbsp; I know that Senator Brown and Portman are going to work with our colleagues to finish this bill.&nbsp; But it didn’t &#8212; you know, they did it in infrastructure; they’re doing it again in this.&nbsp; Let’s get this Bipartisan Innovation Act to my desk.<br><br>And look, folks, just&nbsp;look at what’s within our reach.&nbsp; I’ve never been more optimistic &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; I’ve never been more optimistic about America than I am today.&nbsp; Not because I’m President, but because people &#8212; everybody is waking up.&nbsp; It’s a new time.</p>



<p>Because of my economic strategy, companies and &#8212; are &#8212; and jobs are coming home again.&nbsp; We’re making “Buy America” a reality, not just a slogan.</p>



<p>Because of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that Sherrod and Rob worked really hard to pass, we’re going to rebuild America.&nbsp; We’re going to rebuild a better America&nbsp;&#8212; $1.2 billion &#8212; trillion.</p>



<p>That bridge, if you really want to go to Kentucky, is going to get better.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, but really.&nbsp; We’re talking about billions of dollars modernizing roads, bridges, airports, delivering clean water, high-speed Internet in every &#8212; to every American.</p>



<p>And it’s going &#8212; it’s going to move goods faster and more efficiently, lowering transportation costs and helping us compete &#8212; outcompete anyone in the world.</p>



<p>Where are those two beautiful, young girls?&nbsp; Do you see these young girls here?&nbsp; They wrote me a letter about wanting me to help do more on trains.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; Because of the guys behind me, we have allocated more money for rail systems in America than the entirety of Amtrak appropriation began the first.&nbsp; And I know about Amtrak.&nbsp; I’ve traveled 1.2 million miles on Amtrak, because I commuted every single solitary day, 270 miles a day, as my colleagues can tell you, when the Senate was in session.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; you’ll get a kick out of this, Sherrod.&nbsp; I was &#8212; the Secret Service doesn’t like me taking the train because it stops too many places. &nbsp;And &#8212; and so I was riding home to see my mom, who was living with me because she was in hospice, and &#8212; on a Friday.&nbsp; And a guy named Angelo Negri, a conductor &#8212; senior conductor &#8212; walked up and said, “Joey, baby!”&nbsp; Grabbed my cheek.&nbsp; I thought they were going to shoot him. &nbsp;You know, he goes,&nbsp;“Joey!”&nbsp; I said, “Ange.”&nbsp; I said, “He’s okay.&nbsp; He’s a friend.”&nbsp; True story.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He said, “What’s all this I read in the paper?&nbsp; You travel over a million miles on Air Force planes.”&nbsp; Every single mile a Vice President or President travels, they keep a public record of, on a &#8212; on the aircr- &#8212; on American aircraft.</p>



<p>And he said, “The boys and I, we were at the retirement dinner up in Jersey, so we figured it out: An average 222 days a year, 36 years, a total of 269 miles every day.&nbsp; Joey…”&nbsp; Whether it’s true or not, he said, “One million two hundred thousand miles, not counting as Vice President.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I know a lot about trains.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And we’re going to &#8212; and, by the way, the reason we’re doing it and the reason these guys supported it &#8212; and it’s not just Amtrak, it’s also vehicles and buses in towns and cities, and light rail &#8212; is because it’s going to clean the environment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Everybody knows if you can get on a train and travel from here to Columbus and do it quicker than you can in your car, you’re going to do it.&nbsp; It’s going to take thousands of vehicles off the road.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my point is &#8212; folks, look, there’s so much &#8212; so much we can do.&nbsp; This is the United States of America, for God’s sake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When did we lose our &#8212; our absolute confidence in our ability to do anything?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I was in the Tibetan Plateau with Xi Jinping, with a translator.&nbsp; We each had a translator.&nbsp; And, by the way, for the record, I turned all my notes over.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; And &#8212; seriously.</p>



<p>And so, he looked at me and he said, “Can you define America for me?”&nbsp; I said, “Yes, I can.&nbsp; One word.”&nbsp; And I mean it from the bottom of my heart &#8212; think about this. &nbsp;The one word that defines America better than any other country in the world: “possibilities.”&nbsp; Possibilities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve never believed there is anything out of our reach if we set our mind to it.&nbsp; And we’ve never failed when we’ve set our mind to it, whether it’s going to space or to the bottom of the ocean.&nbsp; This is the United States of America, for God’s sake.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I just told you about those computer chips and Intel that’s going to make them here in Ohio.&nbsp; Well, America invented those chips.&nbsp; We invented them.&nbsp; Nobody else.</p>



<p>They helped power the NASA mission to the Moon.&nbsp; They gave us a military edge in the Cold War.</p>



<p>And the federal investment from NASA and the military that kept fledging the chip industry alive brought down the cost of making them, built a market, ushered in a new digital age.</p>



<p>But then we stopped investing in ourselves.&nbsp; These chips are now predominately made overseas.&nbsp; We learned a hard lesson during the pandemic.</p>



<p>One third of the core inflation we fe- &#8212; we faced last year is because of automobiles.&nbsp; The cost.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; We couldn’t make.&nbsp; We had a lot of buyers because peo- &#8212; wages went up 5.5 percent and people wanted to buy things.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But why couldn’t they buy them?&nbsp; Because they couldn’t make them.&nbsp; Why couldn’t they make them?&nbsp; They didn’t have the chips.&nbsp; A shortage of semiconductors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that’s &#8212; let’s not let the same thing happen here, today, with 3D printing and other advanced manufacturing that was invented and pioneered in America.</p>



<p>These technologies revolutionize the way of life; they keep prices low for businesses and families.<br><br>So, let’s make them in America again.&nbsp; Let’s build the future here in America. &nbsp;Let’s remember who in God’s name we are.</p>



<p>We’re the only country in the world &#8212; and the reason why we sometimes are called “ugly Americans” &#8212; who can’t be defined by the notion of possibilities.&nbsp; There is nothing beyond our capacity &#8212; nothing beyond our capacity, not a single thing &#8212; if we act as the “United” States of America.&nbsp; The United States of America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, folks, I really am optimistic, because of the guys behind me and other men and women like them, we’re about to enter a new period.&nbsp; We just got to stay the course, have confidence in ourself.&nbsp; And, by the way, there’s overwhelming strength in our diversity &#8212; in our diversity.&nbsp; And it’s about time.</p>



<p>I’ll end by saying: When I got elected, I made a promise.&nbsp; I said my administration is going to look like America. &nbsp;Whether it’s a Vice President or a Secretary of State or a Cabinet member or a senior person, it’s going to look like America.&nbsp; And it does.</p>



<p>And one more thing: I know how to say the word “union.”&nbsp; Not labor, union.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; The single-best workers in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, folks, let’s go do this, okay?&nbsp; I want to thank the folks here.&nbsp; I want to thank all the major corporations here.&nbsp; And I want to thank what you’re doing with all the small businesses we’re going to bring together here &#8212; you’re bringing together &#8212; because we’re going to provide good, decent jobs.&nbsp; And we’re going to educate people to be able to handle all of these jobs.</p>



<p>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:43 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/06/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-and-section-614a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 21:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the following authorities, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section&nbsp;614(a)(3) and section 652 of the FAA, in order to&nbsp;provide assistance to Ukraine:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp;&nbsp;the authority under section 614(a)(1) of the FAA to determine whether it is important to the security interests of the United States to furnish up to $150&nbsp;million in assistance without regard to any provision of law within the purview of section 614(a)(1) of the FAA; and</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp;&nbsp;the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to&nbsp;direct the drawdown of up to $150 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Women&#8217;s Health Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/06/a-proclamation-on-national-womens-health-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 21:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During&#160;National Women&#8217;s Health Week, we recommit to ensuring the health and well-being of women and girls across our Nation.&#160;&#160;Central to this mission is protecting women&#8217;s fundamental rights to make their own choices&#160;and build their own future.&#160;&#160;I am committed to defending women&#8217;s rights, including their access to reproductive health care.&#160;&#160;Roe&#160;has been the law of the land&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>During&nbsp;National Women&#8217;s Health Week, we recommit to ensuring the health and well-being of women and girls across our Nation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Central to this mission is protecting women&#8217;s fundamental rights to make their own choices&nbsp;and build their own future.&nbsp;&nbsp;I am committed to defending women&#8217;s rights, including their access to reproductive health care.&nbsp;&nbsp;Roe<em>&nbsp;</em>has been the law of the land for almost 50 years; basic fairness and the stability of our law demand that it not be overturned.&nbsp;&nbsp;In response to the continued attack on abortion and reproductive rights across the country, my Administration is exploring all the tools at our disposal to strengthen and protect women&#8217;s access to critical reproductive health care.&nbsp;&nbsp;We&nbsp;will continue to work with the Congress to pass the Women&#8217;s Health Protection Act, which will ensure that all women have access to critical reproductive health care, no matter where they live.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>For every American, health care is a right, not a privilege, and gender equity in health care is a top priority for my Administration.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is why we are building upon the Affordable Care Act (ACA) to improve the health of all Americans &#8212; especially women.&nbsp;&nbsp;Through the ACA, millions of people are able to access health care.&nbsp;&nbsp;In addition, women with preexisting conditions cannot be denied coverage, and women can no longer be charged more for health insurance simply because they are women.&nbsp;&nbsp;Last month, my Administration proposed the most significant administrative action to improve the ACA by eliminating the &#8220;family glitch,&#8221; which will save families hundreds of dollars a month and help them afford family coverage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am committed&nbsp;to ensuring that women also have access to the life-saving preventive care screenings that so many Americans have skipped or delayed because of the pandemic &#8212; including cholesterol, blood pressure, and cancer screenings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Advancing health equity also requires&nbsp;improving maternal health care.&nbsp;&nbsp;America&#8217;s maternal mortality rates are among the highest in the developed world, especially among Black and Native American women.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is why, through the American Rescue Plan, we have given States the opportunity to provide 12 months of extended postpartum coverage to pregnant women who are enrolled in Medicaid and the Children&#8217;s Health Insurance Program.&nbsp;&nbsp;By expanding access to maternal care and lowering health care costs, we can drive down mortality rates and ensure women can live full and healthy lives.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I mentioned in my State of the Union Address, it is also time for America to make bolder investments to address our national mental health crisis &#8212; a crisis that disproportionately impacts young women and girls, who&nbsp;are twice as likely to be diagnosed with mental health conditions like depression and anxiety.&nbsp;&nbsp;My vision will&nbsp;broaden the pipeline of behavioral health providers, integrate mental health and substance use treatment into primary care, and expand access through more virtual care options.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As President, Vice President, and Senator, I have long been committed to endinggender-based violence and trauma, which&nbsp;have lasting effects on health outcomes for women, girls, and their families.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is why I first wrote the Violence Against Women Act in 1990 and worked with the Congress to reauthorize it through 2027 to&nbsp;increase support, funding, and resources for survivors and improve the health care system&#8217;s response to domestic violence and sexual assault.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have achieved great progress, but there is still more work to do –- including to defend reproductive rights, which are under unprecedented attack, and to ensure we do not go backwards on women&#8217;s equality.&nbsp;&nbsp;As we celebrate National Women&#8217;s Health Week, let us recommit to ensuring equal access to high-quality, affordable care for all women and girls and to improving the health of our Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 8 through May 14, 2022, as National Women&#8217;s Health Week.&nbsp; During this week, I encourage all Americans to join us in a collective effort to improve the health of women and girls and promote health equity for all.&nbsp;&nbsp;I encourage all women and girls &#8212; especially those with underlying health conditions &#8212; to prioritize their health and catch up on any missed screenings, routine care, and vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this sixth day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Mother’s Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/06/a-proclamation-on-mothers-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 20:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every Mother&#8217;s Day, we give special thanks to honor and celebrate the mothers in our lives.&#160; Mothers across America provide unconditional love and extraordinary strength. &#160;They are our rocks in moments of crisis and our guiding lights when we need it most. &#160;Our Nation would not be where we are today without their enduring foundation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every Mother&#8217;s Day, we give special thanks to honor and celebrate the mothers in our lives.&nbsp; Mothers across America provide unconditional love and extraordinary strength. &nbsp;They are our rocks in moments of crisis and our guiding lights when we need it most. &nbsp;Our Nation would not be where we are today without their enduring foundation of love and support.</p>



<p>This Mother&#8217;s Day and every day, I celebrate the mothers who have anchored my life.&nbsp; I honor my wife, Jill &#8212; the love of my life and my north star.&nbsp; After profound loss, Jill gave me back my life, and she made me believe that our family could be whole again.&nbsp; She brings us joy and laughter every day.&nbsp; And I&nbsp;remember my own mother &#8212; Catherine Eugenia &#8220;Jean&#8221; Finnegan Biden &#8212; who has been gone since 2010 and whom I miss every day. &nbsp;She taught me that character and integrity matter. &nbsp;When I&nbsp;succeeded, she was also quick to remind me it was because of&nbsp;the support and prayer of others.&nbsp; And if I did not succeed the first time, she made sure I picked myself up and kept at it.&nbsp; To&nbsp;this day, I live by her words.</p>



<p>In a year of extraordinary challenges, mothers have done what they always have &#8212; carried their families, communities, and our Nation with selflessness and courage, despite the barriers that they so often face. &nbsp;Americans must always care for our mothers in turn: &nbsp;mothers who have worked to make ends meet for their families, even in workplaces where they face discrimination and disparities; mothers who serve simultaneously as frontline workers and caregivers; mothers who are grieving the loss of a child; and all mothers across the Nation, who sacrifice every day.</p>



<p>My Administration is working to build our economy from the bottom up and the middle out to give America&#8217;s hardworking mothers some much needed breathing room. &nbsp;Through the American Rescue Plan, we delivered a historic expansion of the Child Tax Credit, which helped us reduce child poverty last year by an estimated 40 percent.&nbsp; We also delivered increased Federal subsidies for child care providers, along with critical utility assistance for low-income families. &nbsp;My Administration is also committed to ensuring that pregnancy and childbirth are safe and&nbsp;dignified experiences for all families.&nbsp; That is why we are working hard to address our maternal health crisis.&nbsp; America&#8217;s maternal mortality rates are among the highest in the developed world, and they are especially high among Black women and Native American women, regardless of their income or education levels.&nbsp; We must continue working to improve health outcomes for pregnant women and mothers across the board.</p>



<p>The progress we are making for mothers is undeniable, but we are not done yet. &nbsp;We are still fighting hard to pass paid family and medical leave for American workers, to address the barriers and discrimination women continue to face in the workplace, and to strengthen and invest in our country&#8217;s care infrastructure. &nbsp;As we work to build a better America, I will continue to use every tool at my disposal to ensure that all mothers and families have the opportunities they need to thrive.</p>



<p>My mom used to always say, &#8220;The greatest virtue of all is courage, because without courage, you couldn&#8217;t love with abandon.&#8221; &nbsp;Every day, mothers summon the courage to love us with abandon.&nbsp; On Mother&#8217;s Day, we honor all of the mothers who continue to build, shape, and sustain our Nation.</p>



<p>The Congress, by joint resolution approved May 8, 1914 (38&nbsp;Stat. 770), has designated the second Sunday in May each year as &#8220;Mother&#8217;s Day&#8221; and requested the President to call for&nbsp;its appropriate observance.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 8, 2022, as Mother&#8217;s Day.&nbsp; I urge all Americans to express their love, respect, and gratitude to mothers everywhere.&nbsp; I call upon all citizens to observe this day with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this sixth day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Additional Security Assistance to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-additional-security-assistance-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 20:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the United States is continuing our strong support for the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their country against Russia’s ongoing aggression. I am announcing another package of security assistance that will provide additional artillery munitions, radars, and other equipment to Ukraine. The United States has provided a historic amount of security assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the United States is continuing our strong support for the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their country against Russia’s ongoing aggression. I am announcing another package of security assistance that will provide additional artillery munitions, radars, and other equipment to Ukraine.</p>



<p>The United States has provided a historic amount of security assistance to Ukraine at rapid speed. We are sending the weapons and equipment that Congress has authorized directly to the front lines of freedom in Ukraine. U.S. support, together with the contributions of our Allies and partners, has been critical in helping Ukraine win the battle of Kyiv and hinder Putin’s war aims in Ukraine.</p>



<p>With today’s announcement, my Administration has nearly exhausted funding that can be used to&nbsp;send security assistance through drawdown authorities for&nbsp;Ukraine.&nbsp;For Ukraine to succeed in this next phase of war its international partners, including the U.S., must continue to demonstrate our unity and our resolve to keep the weapons and ammunition flowing to Ukraine, without interruption. Congress should quickly provide the requested funding to strengthen Ukraine on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/06/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 19:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Cincinnati, Ohio 12:31 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; So, welcome to our trip to Cincinnati.&#160; This is my last gaggle on Air Force One, so I have a lot of things to get off my chest.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I’m just kidding. Okay, I wanted to give you guys a sense of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Cincinnati, Ohio</p>



<p>12:31 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, welcome to our trip to Cincinnati.&nbsp; This is my last gaggle on Air Force One, so I have a lot of things to get off my chest.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’m just kidding.</p>



<p>Okay, I wanted to give you guys a sense of the week ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Sunday morning, the President will participate in a G7 virtual leaders meeting chaired by German Chancellor Scholz.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaders will be joined by President Zelenskyy of Ukraine.&nbsp; They will discuss the latest developments in Russia&#8217;s war against Ukraine, the global impact of Putin’s war, showing support for Ukraine and Ukraine&#8217;s future, and demonstrating continued G7 unity and our collective response, including building on our unprecedented sanctions to impose severe costs for Putin&#8217;s war.</p>



<p>On Monday, President Biden and Vice President Harris will deliver remarks from the Rose Garden on how the Biden-Harris administration is lowering the cost of high-speed Internet for millions of American families and expanding access through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</p>



<p>Also Monday, the President will sign the Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease &#8212; Lend-Lease Act of 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sorry.&nbsp; Next page.</p>



<p>On Tuesday, the President will welcome Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy to the White House.&nbsp; They will reaffirm the strong bilateral relationship between Italy and the United States.&nbsp; They will discuss their ongoing coordination with allies and partners on measures to support the people of Ukraine and impose economic costs on Russia for its unprovoked aggression.&nbsp; They will also discuss our close cooperation on promoting global economic prosperity, increasing Europe’s energy security, and combating climate change.</p>



<p>On Wednesday, the President will travel to Chicago, Illinois, to attend the 40th IBEW International Convention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Thursday, he will welcome the leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, or ASEAN, to the White House for dinner.</p>



<p>On Friday, the President will participate in a summit with the ASEAN leaders at the State Department to recognize ASEAN’s central role in delivering sustainable solutions to the region&#8217;s most pressing challenges and commemorate 45 years of U.S.-ASEAN relations.</p>



<p>With that, let&#8217;s get to your questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just want to ask you: Congress has limited the President now on some of his &#8212; the administration’s biggest ideas.&nbsp; Build Back Better and the Voting Rights Act has been a frustration.&nbsp; And now, many in the base with &#8212; since the Alito leak &#8212; are eager for him to push for codifying Roe.&nbsp; But as you pointed out this week, easier said than done.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just wondering: How is the President and the administration looking forward?&nbsp; Is there any sort of angst or frustration about the ability to deliver the big idea?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that the President is incredibly proud of what he has already accomplished to date in 15 months of his presidency.&nbsp; And not only did he get the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law passed, but 80 bills &#8212; bipartisan bills that he has helped lead the effort to move forward and sign into law.</p>



<p>And today he&#8217;s going to talk about the Bipartisan Infrastructure &#8212; or Innovation Act, and the need to move that forward in order to build more things in the United States, manufacture, make us more competitive here at home, and help address costs for the American people.</p>



<p>He was in the Senate for 36 years.&nbsp; He knows and understands it sometimes takes more time than he would like to get &#8212; to get his agenda forward, to get your agenda forward.&nbsp; He also understands that with such a slim majority in the Senate, it requires having either every single Democrat prepared to move forward on, say, the reconciliation package, which we&#8217;re still working to move forward, or it requires working in a bipartisan way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So while I&#8217;m not &#8212; while I’m not getting into politics here, I would just refer you and also point you to what the President said in his statement about the leaked document the other night, and how &#8212; and how having more senators and House members in Congress who support his agenda will help him move it forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the President want protesters to influence Supreme Court justices so that they uphold Roe?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President believes in peaceful protest.&nbsp; He believes that&#8217;s part of our democracy and part of the history of the United States and this country.&nbsp; But he also respects and understands the independence of the third branch of government, and &#8212; I mean, obviously, the Justice Department &#8212; but also the role of the Supreme Court and what they play.</p>



<p>So I wouldn&#8217;t say he has a view on that.&nbsp; He believes in peaceful protests, but they&#8217;re going to make decisions they make, and we&#8217;re not going to prejudge a final opinion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a little bit about the Sunday meeting with the G7?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is &#8212; sanctions are on &#8212; new sanctions are on the table.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us any sense of what kind of sanctions?&nbsp; Are these aimed at individuals, you know, big companies?&nbsp; Is it more about sort of clamping down on people evading the sanctions that are existing?&nbsp; What is the meeting about?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview specifically on what&#8217;s next other than to say that all of those are steps that we&#8217;ve taken to date and we will continue to take to date.&nbsp; So, sanctioning additional individuals, additional companies, and also making sure we&#8217;re taking steps to prevent companies or others from evading the sanctions we&#8217;ve put in place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point about what’s next.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President have a particular message to the rest of the G7 that he plans to deliver that was different from the previous meetings?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it should not be lost &#8212; the significance &#8212; or on anyone &#8212; the significance of when the timeline &#8212; when his &#8212; when this G7 meeting is happening, which is the day before Russia&#8217;s Victory Day, which President Putin has certainly projected his desire to mark that day as a day where he is victorious over Ukraine.&nbsp; Of course, he&#8217;s not.&nbsp; While he expected to be marching through the streets of Kyiv, that’s obviously not what is going to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But certainly having this meeting and conversation on Sunday is an opportunity to not only show how unified the West is in confronting the aggression and the invasion by President Putin, but also to show that unity requires work; requires effort; requires blood, sweat, and tears sometimes.&nbsp; And the President is committed to continuing to engage to make sure people are unified &#8212; that these leaders are unified moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, finally, we understand many people are attending his speech to &#8212; or his event today.&nbsp; Representative Tim Ryan, who just won the nomination, is not planning on being here.&nbsp; Do you have any comment on that &#8212; his absence as the new Democratic nominee?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just note they have been in touch.&nbsp; My understanding is Congressman Ryan has to attend a funeral and had other events he needed to attend.&nbsp; But the President remains in close touch with him; he’s obviously very supportive of him.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s looking forward to having both senators from Ohio there today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the President have a position on the &#8212; Senator Manchin’s efforts to do a bipartisan climate change bill?&nbsp; Is he aware of that specific bill and those efforts?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s certainly aware of them.&nbsp; And the President has long believed that there should be a bipartisan path forward for a range of his ideas, including the importance of addressing the climate crisis and doing more on that front.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re not going to prejudge those efforts.&nbsp; But at the same time, we&#8217;re not stalling or we&#8217;re not delaying our conversations with a range of members about attempting or working to move the reconciliation package forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know&nbsp;<a></a><a></a>that you’re not negotiating in public or with us but &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; can you give us any sense of where those talks stand with regard to climate in the reconciliation bill?&nbsp; It is the beginning of May.&nbsp; The window is closing.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I would say that we made a decision, per the President’s direction, not to talk publicly about conversations he’s having or others are having on the Hill because we feel it’s more constructive that way.<br><br>What I can tell you is there is still a great deal of passion and engagement happening behind the scenes.&nbsp; The President is very focused on moving his climate agenda forward. And so he’s going to continue those conversations and continue working until we get it done.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one on abortion. &nbsp;Sorry, Franco.&nbsp; &nbsp;Can you give us a sense of whether or not the White House is in touch with women’s groups about this?&nbsp; What is your engagement?&nbsp; What is the level of, probably, both frustration and anger out there at the Supreme Court and perhaps at the White House about this?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not aware of anger at the White House.&nbsp; Others could speak to that.&nbsp; Obviously, this is a leaked &#8212; not final &#8212; opinion from the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So what our effort and our focus is on is on broadly engaging about the specifics on possible actions and preparing for the release of a final opinion when the &#8212; when that is released early this summer.<br><br>We are in conversations with a wide range of people, including women’s groups; including pro-choice activists; including folks inside of D.C., outside of D.C.; including business leaders; philanth- &#8212; philanthropy; members of Congress; state legislatures; governors; advocacy groups, across the board.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’re using the convening power of the White House to talk to a broad range of groups.&nbsp; That effort is being led by the Gender Policy Council, which is coordinating work from the Department of Health and Human Services, from the White House Counsel’s Office, from a range of &#8212; from the &#8212; from the Domestic Policy Council, from a range of officials in the government, working to see what our options are and what levers we have in government.<br><br>I would note that we already took steps in reaction to S.B. 8 in Texas, and we will continue to build on them and prepare for a range of options.<br><br>I’d also note that today we saw &#8212; or yesterday, I should say &#8212; we saw that, in Connecticut, Governor Lamont signed a bill that will protect medical providers and patients seeking abortion care in Connecticut who may be traveling from other states that have outlawed abortion.&nbsp; And additionally, the law expands abortion access in Connecticut by expanding the type of practitioners eligible to perform certain abortion-related care.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we’re also here and available to states who are looking to take steps to protect women’s rights.&nbsp; Obviously, our pri- &#8212; our preference would be for Congress to codify Roe and, of course, for the final opinion not to look like the leaked opinion.<br><br>But we are also supportive of states.&nbsp; We’re going to work with a broad range of stakeholders as we prepare for a final opinion to be released.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you talk a little bit more about the ASEAN Summit &#8212; what you hope to get out of that?&nbsp; Will that be &#8212; will one of the objectives be building the coalition against Moscow?&nbsp; How much of an objective will that be?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would note that there has been a broad response to the invasion of Ukraine by President Putin and the Russian military, including by a number of countries who are participating.&nbsp; So, certainly, the war in Ukraine will be a topic of discussion, but it’s also an opportunity to discuss security in the region; to discuss our fight against the pandemic, which is ongoing and important on the global front as well; and to discuss a broad range of issues &#8212; North Korea as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So it has a broad-ranging agenda.&nbsp; The President, as I noted earlier, will be participating in not just hosting a dinner on Thursday evening, but in a two-hour session on Friday afternoon to cover a range of topics.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On &#8212; more on Ukraine. &nbsp;There has been some discussion or some calls to cut, cancel, or reduce Ukraine’s foreign debt, kind of reduce their burden so they can put that money elsewhere.&nbsp; What’s the administration’s position on that?&nbsp; Does it have a position on whether or not there should be efforts to reduce Ukraine&#8217;s foreign debt?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s a good question.&nbsp; I’m happy to dig into it further.&nbsp; We’re very open to anything that would help the Ukrainians rebuild their country; obviously fight against the invasion of Russia.&nbsp; And we know that humanitarian and economic assistance that will take many forms &#8212; right?&nbsp;&#8212; is vital to them and to their success moving forward.&nbsp; And I can check if we have a specific view on the canceling of foreign debt.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, from me, just &#8212; there’s language in the Ukraine supplementable [sic] &#8212; supplemental &#8212; excuse me &#8212; about Afghan adjustment for status.&nbsp; Can you talk &#8212; what’s the status of that?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This has been &#8212; this has been tried before and it didn’t make it in.&nbsp; Do you have the support?&nbsp; How important is that to the administration?&nbsp; What’s &#8212; what’s the status?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have an update on the status in Congress on it.&nbsp; I can also see if there’s an update we have from here.&nbsp; I’d really ask members &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How important is it for the White House to get it in now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you noted, it’s something that we have supported in the past.&nbsp; But I &#8212; I can’t &#8212; there’s &#8212; there’s a lot of factors at play here, so I can’t &#8212; I can’t speak to that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One the news that the House is voting on a resolution next week to &#8212; for congressional workers’ right to organize, does the White House have a position on that?&nbsp; Does the President take a position on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can &#8212; I can check more into the specifics of it.&nbsp; I don’t think we&#8217;ve taken a specific position on it.&nbsp; Obviously, I haven&#8217;t looked at the details of it.&nbsp; The President has been a supporter of the right to organize, of collective bargaining for some time.&nbsp; But I&#8217;d have to look into more details of what the other components of it are.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine, maybe, we&#8217;ve seen reports about how U.S.&nbsp;intelligence is helping the Ukrainians take out generals and ships.&nbsp; Is there a risk that those revelations could help the Russians in the sense that they go with the rhetoric of a proxy war and that this could lead to further escalation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say, to speak to the reports: They’re inaccurate.&nbsp; We did not provide Ukraine with specific targeting information for the Moskva.&nbsp; We were not involved in the Ukrainians’ decision to strike the ship or in the operation they carried out.&nbsp; We had no prior knowledge of Ukraine&#8217;s intent to target the ship.&nbsp; The Ukrainians have their own intelligence capabilities to track and target Russian naval vessels, as they did in this case.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;ve discussed this with both our National Security Advisor and the President, and the view is that, one, this is an inaccurate over-claiming of our role and an under-claiming of the role of the Ukrainians who, frankly, have a greater level of intelligence and access to intelligence than we do.<br><br>They take &#8212; we do provide a range of intelligence to help them understand the threat posed by Russian ships in the Black Sea and to help them prepare to defend themselves against potential sea-based assaults, but they take our intelligence and they combine that with what they have access to.&nbsp; And so, on this specific report, it’s just not an accurate depiction of how this happened.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President tested in the last few days?&nbsp; There’s, sort of, such a surge post-White House Correspondents’ Association Dinner.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He is regularly tested, as you know.&nbsp; The last test I&#8217;m aware of was Tuesday.&nbsp; I can check if there has been an additional test.&nbsp; And he was obviously negative then.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did we not ask you that you’re prepared to answer today, Jen?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I don’t know, Jeff.&nbsp; What’s &#8212; what else is on your mind?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we ask you just on the job numbers &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; today? &nbsp;You know, good job numbers, but with the Fed hike, are we seeing the end of the bump of, you know, just what the economy can do as a result of the Fed rate &#8212; pushing up the interest rates?&nbsp; And what’s the way forward from there?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’m not going to speak &#8212; I mean, the Fed and,&nbsp;obviously, Chairman Powell spoke to a lot of that earlier this week, so I&#8217;m going to let those comments stand.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would note, though, is that, you know, the jobs numbers today &#8212; 428,000 jobs in April &#8212; bring the total number of jobs created by &#8212; under the President&#8217;s watch to 8.3 million.&nbsp; What he will talk about &#8212; which we are very encouraged by.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is also true that inflation is too high, that costs are too high.&nbsp; And what he will also talk about today is what we can do to address that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And his view is that we need to do &#8212; take a couple of steps.&nbsp; One is, of course, lowering costs for families and taking steps like addressing the supply chain manufacturing goods in the United States, which the Bipartisan Innovation Act would help do.&nbsp; And launching the initiative he&#8217;s launching today &#8212; the administration is launching today &#8212; will help do &#8212; will help make sure that by manufacturing goods here, we&#8217;re lowering those costs.</p>



<p>Obviously, he&#8217;s taken a lot of steps to address energy costs, which we know is a major driver of inflation.&nbsp; And the other piece that he&#8217;s very focused on, that you&#8217;ve heard him talk about, is lowering the deficit.&nbsp; And he talked about, earlier this week, the revised Treasury &#8212; the data, which showed that we lowered the deficit &#8212; he lowered the deficit by $300 billion and on track to lower it by $1.5 trillion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you&#8217;ll hear him talk about all of that today.&nbsp; We know that&#8217;s on the minds of Americans.&nbsp; And we certainly understand that with an unemployment rate of 3.6 percent, that &#8212; you know, with that historically low number, that, you know, things will level.&nbsp; And we understand that and recognize that as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a follow-up on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, Aamer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a sort of deadline/goal line for when the President wants to see the Bipartisan Innovation Act passed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we know it&#8217;s in conference now, which is certainly a good sign.&nbsp; And he has been out there making the case in the country because he does believe that this is a piece of legislation that there is bipartisan support for it, there should be &#8212; because certainly manufacturing goods in the United States, making sure we&#8217;re not relying on the whims of a dictator, is to the advantage of all of the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow-up on that topic broadly, is the White House concerned about the risk of recession?&nbsp; You hear more and more people using that word recently.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; to what extent is that on your radar, and is it a concern?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re always looking at economic data, of course.&nbsp; But what we also look at is signs of strength in the economy, which is not just the jobs numbers and continued economic growth.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also &#8212; even in the GDP numbers earlier &#8212; was it earlier this week, or last week?&nbsp; It&#8217;s all running together. &nbsp;We saw business investment.&nbsp; We saw &#8212; we saw &#8212; the fact that the export numbers were down was actually because we are doing better than the rest of the world.</p>



<p>So, there is still a range of data that we look at and a lot of outside economists, frankly, look at to show where we are in the economy at this point in time.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s not something we are predicting at this point.&nbsp; We know some people can make their own predictions on the outside, but we&#8217;re not assessing that or making that prediction at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you on the SPR? &nbsp;There was notice this week of the buybacks, but that&#8217;ll take some time.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of the timeline on that?&nbsp; How quickly will the U.S. begin replenishing the barrels that it is drawing down over the next months?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, that&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I mean, it was &#8212; as you noted, it was yesterday we announced the start of that process to replenish.&nbsp; So, we would have that ability to have the supply at a higher level so we could have it for the future.</p>



<p>I can check and see how &#8212; the length of time of that &#8212; what that will take.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The markets kind of jumped.&nbsp; They were thinking the U.S. was immediately buying it back, but it didn&#8217;t seem like that was the case.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s an overnight thing, but I will see if we have a timeline of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Going back to COVID quickly: As someone referenced earlier, there&#8217;s been a spike of cases following the Correspondents’ Dinner.&nbsp; With the upcoming foreign trip, is the President taking any additional mitigation strategies to ensure that he can go on the trip, and, you know, make sure he doesn&#8217;t test positive before his next foreign trip?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that we have a range of strict protocols in the White House that go far beyond what the CDC requirements are, including the fact that everybody who is meeting with the President is tested, everybody who is traveling with him is tested.&nbsp; We take steps to make sure we&#8217;re socially distanced in meetings, and we wear masks in meetings with the President.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he, of course, is tested regularly.&nbsp; He went to the Correspondents’ Dinner to honor the work of all of you and your colleagues and made a decision &#8212; a risk assessment, like we all do every day, that that was important for him to do.</p>



<p>But beyond that, we&#8217;ll just continue the strict protocols we already have in place.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of international travel, is the U.S. considering lifting its testing requirements for people flying in?&nbsp; Other countries have started to pull back those sorts of measures.&nbsp; Is that on the table at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of a timeline for that.&nbsp; Obviously, we are &#8212; we are basing any decisions on the CDC and what their recommendations are.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The CDC said on May 3rd that they still recommend masking on airplanes.&nbsp; They did not say whether they would have extended that rule had the court not knocked it down.&nbsp; Because it would have &#8212; that would have been the sort of pivot point, regardless of the court ruling.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know whether they would have extended it regardless of that? &nbsp;And is there any update on the appeal that DOJ has stuck its foot in the door on?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point at the Department of Justice.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve indicated their plans to appeal, and that has been the case for several weeks now.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to what the CDC would or wouldn&#8217;t have done.&nbsp; Obviously, they made a decision, and we still have a masking require- &#8212; or recommendation in place.&nbsp; And &#8212; but, you know, it&#8217;s hard to get into a reverse hypothetical.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, finally, can you give a sense: Does the President view the Roe v. Wade potential repeal, the issue more broadly, as a core message for Democrats heading into the midterms?&nbsp; And if so, or regardless, who does he think should be giving that message?&nbsp; Is it him?&nbsp; Is it the Vice President?&nbsp; Should, frankly, men be out in front on it?&nbsp; Should women be out in front on it?&nbsp; Does it matter?&nbsp; Who does he think &#8212; does he think Democrats should be leaning into this issue?&nbsp; And if so, who does he think should be leaning into it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you saw in his initial written statement that he spoke to, you know, the need to have more Democrats &#8212; pro-choice Democrats in Congress in order to codify Roe.&nbsp; And that spoke to his view of politics, without me getting into it too much.</p>



<p>I think his view is that it should be all of the above: him, the Vice President, any others.&nbsp; And, you know, as it relates &#8212; what was the last part of your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he think Democrats should make this a key issue, or is it sort of one of a range of issues?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, you heard the President, two days ago, talk about the Ultra-MAGA Agenda.&nbsp; And what he&#8217;s referring to there &#8212; yes, he spoke about Chairman Scott&#8217;s plan to raise taxes on people making less than $100,000 a year; he&#8217;s also talking about the advocacy by some in &#8212; elected officials, Republicans &#8212; to take away a woman&#8217;s right to make choices about her own body and make choices with their doctor.&nbsp; And his view is that is another example of the Ultra-MAGA Agenda as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the timing of this trip just &#8212; you know, Tuesday, they had their primary.&nbsp; Is he going in part to also contrast the Democratic agenda versus what some of the people that may be coming in and what they&#8217;re offering?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think you will see him do a whole lot of that moving forward, but today is &#8212; his remarks are largely focused on making the case for the Bipartisan Innovation Act, how it would help us manufacture jobs in the United States, lower costs, make us more competitive.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One quick follow-up on Ukraine.&nbsp; Ukraine&#8217;s Ambassador to the U.S. told reporters yesterday that a definition of &#8220;victory&#8221; would include restoring sovereignty to Crimea and the Donbas region.&nbsp; Is that a definition the White House supports in terms of victory for Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have long said that we would support the Ukrainians and their efforts through negotiations in a diplomatic process to determine what victory looks like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I would say that, in our view, the victory or the definition of victory that President Putin outlined from the beginning &#8212; which was taking over Ukraine, taking over their territorial integrity, their sovereignty, dividing NATO, dividing the West &#8212; has been ineffective &#8212; has been ineffective. &nbsp;And, therefore, because President Putin will not be marching through the streets of Kyiv, we&#8217;ve already won in many ways.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has also said he&#8217;s going to host his vaccine summit &#8212; his second vaccine summit on &#8212; next Thursday, the 12th.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is he hoping to get out of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to lift up the need to continue to fight around the world to combat COVID, and the fact that our job is not done, there is great deal of work ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States remains far and away the largest provider of vaccines and know-how to the global community.&nbsp; The world needs to continue to do more.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to discuss that. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we should all sit down.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.</p>



<p>12:55 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve in key roles in his administration: Donald R. Cravins Jr., Nominee for Under Secretary for Minority Business Development, Department of Commerce David P. Pekoske, Nominee for Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, Department of Homeland Security Hugo F. Rodriguez Jr.,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve in key roles in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Donald R. Cravins Jr., Nominee for Under Secretary for Minority Business Development, Department of Commerce</li><li>David P. Pekoske, Nominee for Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, Department of Homeland Security</li><li>Hugo F. Rodriguez Jr., Nominee for Ambassador to Nicaragua</li><li>Rosie Hidalgo, Nominee for Office on Violence Against Women Director, U.S. Department of Justice</li><li>Jonathan W. Burks, Nominee for Member, United States Institute of Peace</li><li>Michael K. Singh, Nominee for Member, United States Institute of Peace</li><li>Kathryn Wheelbarger, Nominee for Member, United States Institute of Peace</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Donald R. Cravins Jr., Nominee for Undersecretary of Commerce for Minority Business Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Donald R. Cravins, Jr. serves as the Executive Vice President and Chief Operating Officer at the National Urban League.&nbsp;Cravins graduated from LSU in 1994. Upon graduation, he attended&nbsp;the Southern University Law Center and obtained a juris doctorate in 1998. In 2004, he was elected to the Louisiana House of Representatives and inn 2006, he was elected to the Louisiana Senate. During his tenure in the Louisiana Senate, Cravins was heavily involved in post-Hurricanes Katrina and Rita business recovery issues as the Chair of the Insurance Committee.</p>



<p>In January 2009, Cravins left the Louisiana Legislature to serve as Staff Director and Chief Counsel for the United States Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. In that role, he was instrumental in the passage of the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010. In January 2013, he began serving as Chief of Staff for U.S. Senator Mary L. Landrieu of Louisiana.&nbsp;In addition to his duties at the National Urban League, Cravins is an adjunct professor at The George Washington University. He also serves as an officer in the District of Columbia Army National Guard. He is a Life Member of Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, Inc. and a member of the 100 Black Men of Prince George&#8217;s County. Cravins’ honors include being inducted into the Southern University Law School Hall of Fame in 2018 and being named a&nbsp;Distinguished Alumnus of LSU in 2015. He and his family reside in Maryland.</p>



<p><strong><u>David P. Pekoske, Nominee for Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, U.S. Department of Homeland Security</u></strong></p>



<p>David Pekoske was confirmed by the U.S. Senate as the Transportation Security Administration’s seventh administrator in August 2017.&nbsp; He leads a workforce of over 60,000 employees and is responsible for security operations at nearly 440 airports throughout the United States.&nbsp; While serving as TSA Administrator, Pekoske also served at the Department of Homeland Security as Acting Secretary from January 20 to February 2, 2021, and as the Senior Official Performing the Duties of Deputy Secretary from April to November 2019 and again from February to June 2021.&nbsp; He was also a Commissioner on the Cyberspace Solarium Commission that developed a consensus on a strategic approach to defending the United States in cyberspace against attacks of significant consequence.</p>



<p>Before joining TSA, Pekoske was an executive in the government services industry, where he led teams that provided counterterrorism, security and intelligence support services to government agencies. Pekoske served as the 26th Vice Commandant of the U.S. Coast Guard, culminating a Coast Guard career that included extensive operational and command experience. As the Vice Commandant, Pekoske was second in command, also serving as Chief Operating Officer and Component Acquisition Executive of the Coast Guard. He is a recognized expert in crisis management, strategic planning, innovation and aviation, surface transportation and maritime security. In addition, he has been twice awarded the Homeland Security Distinguished Service Medal. Pekoske holds a Master of Business Administration degree from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, a Master of Public Administration degree from Columbia University and a Bachelor of Science degree from the U.S. Coast Guard Academy.</p>



<p><strong><u>Hugo F. Rodriguez, Jr., Nominee to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Nicaragua</u></strong></p>



<p>Hugo F. Rodriguez, Jr., a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as a Senior Advisor in the U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs.&nbsp; He was previously Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs, and in 2021 assumed the role of Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the bureau.&nbsp; Before that, Rodriguez served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Asunción, Paraguay and as the Embassy’s Charge d’ Affaires a.i. from 2017 to 2018.&nbsp; Earlier, Rodriguez served as Consul General at the U.S. Embassy in Mexico City and as the Mission’s Acting Minister Counselor for Consular Affairs.&nbsp; He previously served as Deputy Director of the Office of Mexican Affairs, as Division Chief for the Western Hemisphere in the Bureau of Consular Affairs’ Overseas Citizen Services office, and as a Watch Officer and Senior Watch Officer in the Executive Secretariat’s Operations Center.&nbsp; Other overseas assignments include U.S. Embassies in Lima, Peru and Rome, Italy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A native of Pennsylvania, Rodriguez holds a Master’s degree in Business Administration from the Darden School of Business at the University of Virginia and a Bachelor of Arts degree in Economics from Hampden-Sydney College. The recipient of numerous State Department performance awards, Rodriguez speaks Italian and Spanish.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Rosie Hidalgo, Nominee for the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women, U.S. Department of Justice</u></strong></p>



<p>Rosie Hidalgo currently serves as Special Assistant to the President and Senior Advisor on Gender-Based Violence at the White House Gender Policy Council. She has worked in the movement to end gender-based violence for over 25 years as a public interest attorney and as a national policy advocate. Most recently, she was the Senior Director of Public Policy for Esperanza United, a national resource center with a focus on providing training, research, and policy advocacy to prevent and end domestic violence and sexual assault.&nbsp; Hidalgo previously served as the Deputy Director for Policy at the Office on Violence Against Women at the U.S. Department of Justice during the Obama-Biden Administration, and served on a detail to the Office of the Vice President, working with the White House Advisor on Violence Against Women.&nbsp; After law school, she worked as a Skadden Fellow providing direct legal services through non-profit organizations in New York and Virginia.&nbsp; Hidalgo also served on the Biden Foundation’s Advisory Council for Ending Violence Against Women, and on the American Bar Association’s Commission on Domestic and Sexual Violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hidalgo received her Bachelor’s degree in Government and International Relations from Georgetown University and holds a J.D. from New York University School of Law, where she was a Root-Tilden Scholar.&nbsp; She is married and has three children.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Jonathan W. Burks, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace</span></strong></p>



<p>Jonathan W. Burks is Vice President for Global Public Policy at Walmart, where he leads the global retailer’s efforts to analyze and develop positions on pressing public policy issues.&nbsp;Prior to joining Walmart, he was a partner at the global consultancy the Brunswick Group where he was the co-lead for the U.S. public affairs office. Before moving to the private sector, Burks served as the Chief of Staff to Speaker of the House Paul Ryan, a Policy Advisor on budget and appropriations issues to Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell, Policy Director of the House Budget Committee, Director of Legislative Affairs at the Securities and Exchange Commission, Senior Advisor to the Under Secretary of the Treasury for International Affairs, and Policy Advisor in the transition office of the newly created Director of National Intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Burks was the Deputy Policy Director on the 2012 Romney for President campaign. Earlier in his career, he served for four years at the White House, working first for Vice President Cheney and then for President Bush in a variety of positions, including as the Vice President’s Staff Secretary, Associate Staff Secretary to the President, and Special Assistant to the President for Policy in the Chief of Staff’s office.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Michael K. Singh, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace</span></strong></p>



<p>Michael K. Singh currently serves as Managing Director and Senior Fellow at the Washington Institute for Near East Policy, and Interim Director of the Institute’s Glazer Program on Great Power Competition and the Middle East.&nbsp; Singh was Senior Director for Middle East Affairs at the National Security Council from 2007-2008, and a Director on the NSC staff from 2005-2007.&nbsp; Earlier, he served as Special Assistant to Secretaries of State Colin Powell and Condoleezza Rice, and at the US Embassy in Tel Aviv.&nbsp; He co-chaired the Congressionally-mandated Syria Study Group, and served on the Congressional Task Force on Extremism in Fragile States. In addition, Singh co-chaired Mitt Romney’s State Department transition team in 2012, and served as Middle East advisor to the Romney campaign.&nbsp; Singh also serves on the “Welcome Council” of Welcome.US, a bipartisan initiative to empower Americans to welcome refugees.&nbsp; Singh has been an adjunct fellow at the Belfer Center at Harvard’s Kennedy School of Government and an economics instructor at Harvard College.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Singh earned his bachelor’s degree in economics and Near Eastern studies from Princeton University and an MBA from Harvard Business School.&nbsp; He lives in Virginia with his wife, Kellie, and their two sons.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Kathryn Wheelbarger, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace</span></strong></p>



<p>Kathryn Wheelbarger is currently Vice President for Future Concepts at Lockheed Martin Government Affairs, where she leads a team focused on encouraging advanced technological solutions to global security challenges.&nbsp; She previously served as Acting Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs at the U.S. Department of Defense.&nbsp; In that role, she was responsible for developing and advising the Secretary of Defense on defense policies related to the Middle East, Europe/NATO, Africa, the Western Hemisphere, and Russia and Eurasia.&nbsp; For her service, she was awarded the Defense Distinguished Public Service Medal, the Defense Department’s highest civilian award.&nbsp; Immediately prior to joining Lockheed Martin, she was a fellow with The Washington Institute.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From 2009 to 2017, Wheelbarger held several senior roles on Capitol Hill to include Policy Director on the Senate Armed Services Committee for Chairman McCain (R-AZ), Deputy Staff Director on the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence for Chairman Mike Rogers (R-MI), and Deputy Staff Director on the Energy and Commerce Committee for Ranking Member Joe Barton (R-TX).&nbsp; Earlier in her career, she served as Counsel to Vice President Dick Cheney and Associate General Counsel and Counselor to the Secretary at the Department of Homeland Security. Kathryn began her career clerking on the 9th Circuit Court of Appeals and litigating with two nationally recognized law firms.&nbsp; Raised in California, Wheelbarger &nbsp;graduated Summa Cum Laude from UCLA with a BA in Political Science and Cum Laude with a J.D. from Harvard Law School.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on the William T. Coleman, Jr. and Norman Y. Mineta Federal Building Act and Passing of Norman&#160;Mineta</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-the-william-t-coleman-jr-and-norman-y-mineta-federal-building-act-and-passing-of-norman-mineta/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, our nation lost an American hero and I lost a dear friend in Norman Mineta. Earlier today, I signed a bill to name the United States Department of Transportation headquarters in his honor, along with the late William T. Coleman, Jr. As a boy during World War II, Norm and his family were&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, our nation lost an American hero and I lost a dear friend in Norman Mineta. Earlier today, I signed a bill to name the United States Department of Transportation headquarters in his honor, along with the late William T. Coleman, Jr.</p>



<p>As a boy during World War II, Norm and his family were cruelly confined in the Heart Mountain Relocation Center in Wyoming during America’s shameful period of Japanese Incarceration.&nbsp; Undaunted — and eternally hopeful — Norm was motivated by this early injustice to pursue a life of service.&nbsp; He was determined to ensure that the nation he loved lived up to its defining promise of liberty, equality, and justice for all — and he worked with grace and dignity to bring us closer to those ideals.</p>



<p>Norm will always be remembered for the many barriers he broke.&nbsp; He was the first Asian American to serve as Mayor of a major city — his beloved hometown of San Jose — as well as the first Asian American to serve in the Cabinet.&nbsp; Over two decades in the House of Representatives, Norm was a force of purpose and progress.&nbsp; He was the first chair of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, and led passage of the landmark Civil Liberties Act of 1988 — legislation that, at long last, acknowledged and remunerated families like his own who had been incarcerated in camps during World War II.</p>



<p>But beyond his remarkable lifetime of accomplishments, I will remember Norm for his steadfast commitment to a belief he held dear: that America can accomplish anything when we come together.&nbsp; It is no accident that Norm was entrusted to lead Cabinet departments under both Democratic and Republican presidents — nor that some of his closest friendships in Congress were with members across the political spectrum.&nbsp; Norm treated everybody he met with equal dignity, and earned the respect of all who knew him.</p>



<p>Our thoughts are with Norm’s wife, Deni, his four children, his 11 grandchildren, and generations of constituents and staff who were inspired by the power of his example and who followed his lead in serving this nation.</p>



<p>May God bless Norman Mineta.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
