<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:04:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden Providing an Update on Russia and&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-president-biden-providing-an-update-on-russia-and-ukraine-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 10:01 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160;&#160;Good morning, everyone.&#160; Sorry to keep you waiting a little bit.&#160; I had the honor of spending some time with the Ukrainian Prime Minister, who’s in town today.&#160; And he is meeting with some of my Cabinet members, including the Secretary of Treasury and others.&#160; And we had a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>10:01 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp;Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Sorry to keep you waiting a little bit.&nbsp; I had the honor of spending some time with the Ukrainian Prime Minister, who’s in town today.&nbsp; And he is meeting with some of my Cabinet members, including the Secretary of Treasury and others.&nbsp;<br><br>And we had a &#8212; a good discussion.&nbsp; I talked about what I’m about to tell you about today, as well as &#8212; he was thanking the American people for their support, understands it’s significant, and was &#8212; we talked about keeping everyone together, in terms of Europe, the European Union, and others, in the effort to stop Putin’s brutality.&nbsp;<br><br>But before I head out to the West Coast, I want to quickly update the American people on the latest steps we’re taking to support the people of Ukraine and to hold Putin accountable for his brutal and bloody war.&nbsp;<br><br>Russian forces have retreated from Kyiv, leaving behind them a horrifying evidence.&nbsp; And you’ve seen it and you reported it &#8212; your folks.&nbsp; And, by the way, I &#8212; I don&#8217;t say this often, but I think we should give enormous credit to the folks in your agencies that are on the ground in Ukraine, in these spots.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re really &#8212; I&#8217;ve spoken to several of them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a &#8212; we owe them.&nbsp; But uncovering these evidences of their atrocities and war crimes against the Ukrainian people &#8212; it’s so clear to the whole world now.<br><br>Now they’ve launched and refocused their campaign to seize new territory in eastern Ukraine.<br><br>And we’re in a critical window now of time where that &#8212; they’re going to set the stage for the next phase of this war.<br><br>And the United States and our Allies and partners are moving as fast as possible to continue to provide Ukraine the forces that they need &#8212; the weapons they need &#8212; excuse me &#8212; and the equipment they need &#8212; their forces need to defend their nation.<br><br>Last week, I signed an $800 million package of security assistance to Ukraine that included new capabilities like artillery systems and armored personnel carriers &#8212; equipment that is responsive to Ukraine’s needs and tailored to support the intensified fighting in the Donbas region, which is a different war than in other places because both &#8212; topographically it’s different.&nbsp; It’s flat, it’s not in the mountains, and it requires different kinds of weapons to be more effective.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I’m announcing another $800 million to further augment Ukraine’s ability to fight in the east &#8212; in the Donbas region.<br><br>This package includes heavy artillery weapons &#8212; dozens of Howitzers &#8212; and 144,000 rounds of ammunition to go with those Howitzers.&nbsp; It also includes more tactical drones.<br><br>In the past two months, we’ve moved weapons and equipment to Ukraine at record speed.<br><br>We’ve sent thousands of anti-armor and anti-[air] missile[s], helicopters, drones, grenade launchers, machine guns, rifles, radar systems.&nbsp;More than 50 million rounds of ammunition had already been sent.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States alone has provided 10 anti-armor systems for every one Russian tank that’s in Ukraine &#8212; a 10 to 1 ratio.<br><br>We’re sharing and will continue to share significant, timely intelligence with Ukraine to help defend them against Russian aggression.<br><br>And on top of this, these direct contributions from the United States, we’re facilitating; we’re the outfit facilitating the significant flow of weapons and systems to Ukraine from other Allies and partners around the world, like the S-300 long-range, anti-aircraft systems that Slovakia recently transferred to Ukraine.&nbsp; We are getting them in there.&nbsp;<br><br>We won’t always be able to advertise everything we &#8212; that our partners are doing to support Ukraine in its fight for freedom.&nbsp;<br><br>But to modernize Teddy Roosevelt’s famous advice: Sometimes we will speak softly and carry a large Javelin.&nbsp; Because we’re sending a lot of those in as well.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, but we’re not &#8212; we’re not sitting on the funding that Congress has provided for Ukraine.&nbsp; We’re sending it directly to the frontlines of freedom, to the fearless and skilled Ukrainian fighters who are standing in the breach.<br><br>You got to admit, you have &#8212; must be amazed at the courage of this country, the resolve that they’re showing, not just the milit- &#8212; their military, but the average citizen: men and women, young &#8212; young men, young women as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>It’s &#8212; you know, the sustained and coordinated support of the international community, led and facilitated by the United States, has a &#8212; is a significant reason why Ukraine is able to stop Russia from taking over their country thus far.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Every American taxpayer, every member of our Armed Forces can be proud of the fact that our country’s generosity and the skill and service of our military helped arm and repel Russia’s aggression in Ukraine, to beat back Putin’s savagery that tried to seize Ukraine’s capital and wipe out Ukraine’s government.<br><br>The Battle of Kyiv was a historic victory for the Ukrainians.&nbsp; It was a victory for freedom, won by the Ukrainian people with unprecedented assistance by the United States and our Allies and our partners.&nbsp;<br><br>Now &#8212; now we have to accelerate that assistance package to help prepare Ukraine for Russia’s offensive that’s going to be more limited in terms of geography, but not in terms of brutality &#8212; not in terms of brutality.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Combined with our recent drawdowns, it will ensure a steady flow of weapons and equipment into Ukraine over the next few weeks.<br><br>However, with this latest disbursement, I’ve almost exhausted the drawdown authority I have that Congress authorized for Ukraine in a bipartisan spending bill last month.<br><br>In order to sustain Ukraine for the duration of this fight, next week I’m going to &#8212; have to be sending to Congress a supplemental budget request to keep weapons and ammunition flowing without interruption to the brave Ukrainian fighters and to continue to deliver economic assistance to the Ukrainian people.<br><br>Hope &#8212; and my hope is and my expectation is Congress would move and act quickly.&nbsp; And I want to thank the Congress &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; for their support for the people of Ukraine.<br><br>Our unity at home, our unity with our Allies and partners, and our unity with the Ukrainian people is sending an unmistakable message to Putin: He will never succeed in dominating and occupying all of Ukraine.&nbsp; He will not &#8212; that will not happen.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to bolstering Ukraine’s resistance on the battlefield, we’re also demonstrating our support for the people of Ukraine.<br><br>Today, the United States is announcing that we intend to provide an additional $500 million in direct economic assistance to the Ukrainian government.<br><br>This brings our total economic support for Ukraine to $1 billion in the past two months.<br><br>This is money the government can help use to help stabilize their economy, to support communities that have been devastated by the Russian onslaught, and pay the brave workers that continue to provide essential services to the people of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, these past weeks have seen a terrible human cost of Putin’s ambition for conquest and control.&nbsp; Approximately two thirds &#8212; two thirds &#8212; of all Ukrainian children have been displaced from their homes.&nbsp; More than 5 million Ukrainians have fled their country.&nbsp; It’s an absolute outrage.&nbsp;&nbsp;The idea this is happening approaching the second quarter of the 21st century is just &#8212; (sighs).<br><br>Last month, when I was in Europe, I announced that the United States would welcome 100,000 Ukrainians so that we share in the responsibility of supporting Ukrainians fleeing Putin’s war machine.<br><br>We’ve already welcomed tens of thousands of Ukrainians to the United States.<br><br>And today, I’m announcing a program, “Unite for Ukraine” &#8212; a new program to enable Ukrainians seeking refuge to come directly from Europe to the United States.<br><br>This new humanitarian parole program will complement the existing legal pathways available to Ukrainians, including immigrant visas and refugee processing.<br><br>It will provide an expedient channel for secure, legal migration from Europe to the United States for Ukrainians who have a U.S. sponsor, such as a family or an NGO.<br><br>This program will be fast.&nbsp; It will be streamlined.&nbsp; And it will ensure the United States honors its commitment to go to the Ukrainian people and need not go through our southern border.<br><br>We’re also continuing to ratchet up the pressure on Putin and further isolate Russia on the world stage.<br><br>Yesterday, the Treasury Department rolled out additional measures to crack down on the entities and individuals attempting to evade our unprecedented sanctions &#8212; not just ours, but throughout the West.<br><br>Today, I’m announcing that the United States will ban Russian-affiliated ships from our ports, as they did in Europe.<br><br>That means no ship &#8212; no ship that sails under the Russian flag or that is owned or operated by Russian interests will be allowed to dock in a United States port or access our shores.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; None.<br><br>This is yet another critical step we’re taking in concert with our partners in the European Union, the United Kingdom, and Canada and &#8212; further to deny Russia the benefits of the international economic system that they so enjoyed in the past.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We don’t know how long this war will last.&nbsp; But as we approach the two-month mark, here’s what we do know:<br><br>Putin has failed to achieve his grand ambitions on the battlefield.&nbsp; After weeks of shelling Kyiv, Kyiv still stands.<br><br>President Zelenskyy and his democratically elected government still remain in power.<br><br>And the Ukrainian armed forces, joined by many brave Ukrainian civilians, have thwarted Russia’s conquest of their country.<br><br>They have been bolstered from day one by an unstinting supply of weapons, ammunition, armor, intelligence from the nations of the free world led by us, the United States.<br><br>As Russia continues to grind out the military advances and &#8212; their military advances and the brutalities against Ukraine, Putin is banking on us losing interest.&nbsp; That’s been my view; you’ve heard me say this from the beginning.&nbsp; He was counting on NATO, the European Union, our allies in Asia cracking, moving away.&nbsp; He’s betting on Western unity will crack.&nbsp; He’s still betting on that.<br><br>And, once again, we’re going to prove him wrong.&nbsp; We will not lessen our resolve.&nbsp; We’re going to continue to stand with the brave and proud people of Ukraine.&nbsp; We will never fail in our determination to defend freedom and oppose tyranny.&nbsp; It’s as simple as that.<br><br>So, again, I want to thank the American people &#8212; thank the American people for their support of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; This is our &#8212; this is our responsibility, it seems to me, and we’ve been able to hold the whole world together in this effort.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you very much.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m going to take just one or two questions.&nbsp; I’ve got a plane to catch.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does &#8212; what does Putin claiming control over Mariupol mean?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; how significant is that?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first of all, it’s questionable whether he does control Mariupol.&nbsp; One thing for sure we know about Mariupol: He should allow humanitarian corridors to let people on that steel mill and other places that are buried under rubble to get out &#8212; to get out.&nbsp; That’s what any, any, any head of state would do in such a circumstance.<br><br>And so, there is no evidence yet that Mariupol has completely fallen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on Title 42, sir, are you considering delaying lifting Title 42?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; What I’m considering is continuing to hear from my &#8212; my &#8212;<br><br>Well, first of all, there’s going to be an appeal by the Justice Department because, as a matter of principle, we want to be able to be in a position where if, in fact, it is strongly concluded by the scientists that we need Title 42, that we be able to do that.<br><br>But there has been no decision on extending Title 42.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how long can the U.S. maintain the level and pace of this military support for Ukraine?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I &#8212; well, we have the capacity to do this for a long time.&nbsp; The question is: Are we going to continue to maintain the support of the international community and keep the pressure on Putin to prevent him from overrunning the country?&nbsp; Number one.&nbsp; And, number two, make sure we continue to maintain the economic sanctions, which, over time &#8212; and we’re beginning to see it &#8212; are devastating their economy and their ability to move forward.<br><br>So, the most important thing right now is maintain the unity.&nbsp; So far, so good.<br><br>Thank you very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How much money are you going to ask for in the supplemental?&nbsp; How much money in the supplemental, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The answer &#8212; that’s being decided now.&nbsp; And I’m asking the Defense Department to put together what they think we need.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>10:14 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: White&#160;House Announces Additional $385 Million to Lower Home Energy Bills for American&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-additional-385-million-to-lower-home-energy-bills-for-american-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Total Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program Funding Reaches Record $8.3 Billion for Hard-Pressed American Families in Fiscal Year 2022 Today, the White House is announcing that the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will release more than $385 million to states to help families and individuals with their home energy costs –&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Total Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program Funding Reaches Record $8.3 Billion for Hard-Pressed American Families in Fiscal Year 2022</em></p>



<p>Today, the White House is announcing that the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will release more than $385 million to states to help families and individuals with their home energy costs – including summer cooling – through the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP). These funds are in addition to the $4.5 billion that the American Rescue Plan provided to LIHEAP and the<a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/media/press/2022/president-bidens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-directs-100-million-lower-heating"> first $100 million installment</a>&nbsp;of a five-year, $500 million investment in LIHEAP from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. Altogether, this year the Biden-Harris Administration is providing more than $8.3 billion in LIHEAP assistance to reduce heating and cooling costs for low-income Americans – the largest investment in a single year since the program was established in 1981.</p>



<p>The President is traveling today to the Pacific Northwest, which saw record heat last year, where he will highlight actions he has taken to help lower costs for families, including home energy costs. These actions include:</p>



<p><strong>Record LIHEAP Funding for States:</strong> Today, HHS announced the expected final state-by-state allocation of over $8.3 billion in LIHEAP funding outlined below. For example, Oregon, where the President is traveling today, will receive an additional $3.8 million, bringing the total for Oregon – including American Rescue Plan funds – to $92.6 million in LIHEAP funding. Washington, where the President will travel tomorrow, will receive an additional $6.5 million, bringing its total to $151.2 million.</p>



<p><strong>The American Rescue Plan’s Historic Resources and Relief for Homeowners:</strong>&nbsp;The American Rescue Plan provided other critical resources that states and localities can use to address home energy costs. This includes Emergency Rental Assistance (ERA) programs, which received an additional $21.5 billion in funding from the American Rescue Plan, can provide help with past-due utility bills or ongoing assistance with energy costs to help distressed renters avoid shut-offs and keep current on expenses. Over $30 billion of ERA funds have been obligated to assist households with rent and utility costs. The Treasury Department is also working with states and tribes to distribute $9.8&nbsp;billion in funding for the Homeowners Assistance Fund, with a majority of approved plans&nbsp;including&nbsp;utility assistance to homeowners in need. State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds can also be deployed to help deliver energy relief to families. Jurisdictions – such as California; Maryland; Louisville, Kentucky; Mesa, Arizona; Burlington, Vermont; and the Menominee Tribe of Wisconsin – are already helping households eliminate unpaid bills, avoid shut-offs, and reduce their energy bills.</p>



<p><strong>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s Historic Investments to Reduce Home Energy Costs:</strong>&nbsp;The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invested a historic <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-administration-announces-investments-make-homes-more-energy-efficient-and-lower">$3.5 billion in the Department of Energy’s Weatherization Assistance Program</a>, reducing energy costs for hundreds of thousands of low-income households by increasing their homes’ energy efficiency.</p>



<p><strong>Saving Families Money with Energy Efficiency Standards:</strong> The Biden-Harris Administration is continuing a series of 100 actions, to be completed this year, that together will save families $100 every year with more efficient home appliances and equipment. The Department of Energy recently <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-releases-energy-saving-rules-federal-buildings-and-proposes-new-standards-consumer">proposed new standards</a> for appliances like air conditioners to help consumers save on their utility bills, which is critical as communities cope with increasingly common and extreme heat events. The Administration will continue taking action to make homes, offices, schools, appliances, and more energy efficient to cut costs for consumers.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement also builds on the Administration’s previous actions to ensure these historic resources are distributed swiftly and equitably:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Encouraged States to Plan Early:</u></strong>&nbsp;In November 2021, the White House&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/18/fact-sheet-biden-administration-deploys-american-rescue-plan-funds-to-protect-americans-from-rising-home-heating-costs-calls-on-utility-companies-to-prevent-shut-offs-this-winter/">called on states, localities, and tribes to plan early</a>&nbsp;to distribute American Rescue Plan funds to address home energy costs.</li><li><strong><u>Secured Commitments from Utilities to Avoid Shut-offs and Expedite Aid:</u></strong>&nbsp;The White House has&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/18/fact-sheet-biden-administration-deploys-american-rescue-plan-funds-to-protect-americans-from-rising-home-heating-costs-calls-on-utility-companies-to-prevent-shut-offs-this-winter/">called on utility companies</a>&nbsp;to prevent devastating utility shut-offs and help expedite the delivery of unprecedented federal aid.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/07/biden-administration-announces-state-by-state-funding-to-address-home-energy-costs/">In January, the White House announced</a> commitments from fourteen major utility companies across the country as well as a delivered fuel trade association.</li><li><strong><u>Called for Coordination of Home Energy Relief to Families:</u></strong>&nbsp;In November 2021, the White House called for coordination across programs to maximize the impact of home energy assistance. HHS and Treasury <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/policy-guidance/liheap-im-2022-01-liheap-coordination-era-during-winter-fy22">issued guidance</a> and co-hosted webinars on LIHEAP and ERA best practices that attracted 500 administrators from across the country. By December 2021, more than half of these administrators reported that they are coordinating across these programs.</li><li><strong><u>Provided Best Practices on Coordination with Utility Providers:</u></strong>&nbsp;In January, HHS and Treasury hosted a webinar <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/policy-guidance/liheap-dcl-2022-04-additional-training-opportunities-guidance-emergency-rental">with over 700 utility assistance program administrators and utility providers</a> from across the country to discuss how programs including LIHEAP and ERA can coordinate with utility providers to increase the efficiency and reach of their programs.</li><li><strong><u>Conducted Outreach and Celebrated National Energy Assistance Day:</u></strong>&nbsp;To celebrate the inaugural National Energy Assistance Day on February 1, HHS released a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/podcast/liheap-celebrates-national-energy-assistance-day-2022-audio-news-release">radio announcement in English</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/podcast/liheap-celebrates-national-energy-assistance-day-2022-spanish">Spanish</a>&nbsp;and a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7XebYS0OEm0">video</a>&nbsp;to encourage families to apply for LIHEAP. The radio announcement aired over 5,000 times and reached more than 80 million listeners. HHS also <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/policy-guidance/liheap-dcl-2022-06-national-energy-assistance-day-fy2022">encouraged LIHEAP Administrators to participate</a> in National Energy Assistance Day. Agencies across the Administration and the White House disseminated information about assistance programs and coordinated outreach.</li><li><strong><u>Released Brief on Using Pandemic Emergency Assistance Fund for Utility Assistance:</u></strong>&nbsp;The American Rescue Plan provided $1 billion for states, territories and tribes to distribute cash or targeted assistance to needy families. In February, HHS&nbsp;<a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/documents/ofa/peaf_energy_security_brief_1_27_2022_508.pdf">released a brief</a>&nbsp;on how to use these funds for utility needs.</li></ul>



<p>Households in need of help with their energy bills can identify resources in their area at&nbsp;<a href="http://energyhelp.us/">EnergyHelp.us</a>&nbsp;or by calling the National Energy Assistance Referral hotline at 1-866-674-6327.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">HHS LIHEAP Funding Awards Available in FY 2022</span></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><a><strong>State/Territory</strong></a></td><td><strong>Share of $4.5 Billion American Rescue Plan Award</strong></td><td><strong>Share of FY 2022 CR Award (November 1, 2021)</strong></td><td><strong>Share of FY 2022 Infrastructure Act Award (January 25, 2022)</strong></td><td><strong>Share of Over $385 Million Announced Today</strong></td><td><strong>Total Share of Record Over $8.3 Billion Available in FY 2022</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Alabama</strong></td><td>$41,305,882</td><td>$56,406,127</td><td>$2,682,444</td><td>$6,652,710</td><td>$107,047,163</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Alaska</strong></td><td>$14,390,003</td><td>$10,212,175</td><td>$313,945</td><td>$1,168,240</td><td>$26,084,363</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Arizona</strong></td><td>$23,569,301</td><td>$26,214,931</td><td>$1,688,238</td><td>$3,539,429</td><td>$55,011,899</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Arkansas</strong></td><td>$30,164,262</td><td>$29,809,774</td><td>$809,945</td><td>$3,461,419</td><td>$64,245,400</td></tr><tr><td><strong>California</strong></td><td>$203,610,805</td><td>$179,228,041</td><td>$4,177,848</td><td>$20,649,415</td><td>$407,666,109</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Colorado</strong></td><td>$71,759,071</td><td>$53,827,678</td><td>$1,545,991</td><td>$6,154,339</td><td>$133,287,079</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Connecticut</strong></td><td>$94,096,941</td><td>$65,781,175</td><td>$2,003,413</td><td>$7,491,598</td><td>$169,373,127</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Delaware</strong></td><td>$12,883,578</td><td>$12,188,013</td><td>$355,385</td><td>$1,413,086</td><td>$26,840,062</td></tr><tr><td><strong>District of Columbia</strong></td><td>$14,560,741</td><td>$10,333,343</td><td>$317,672</td><td>$1,182,101</td><td>$26,393,857</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Florida</strong></td><td>$80,777,150</td><td>$89,844,309</td><td>$5,785,953</td><td>$12,130,404</td><td>$188,537,816</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Georgia</strong></td><td>$63,876,744</td><td>$71,046,847</td><td>$4,575,402</td><td>$9,592,448</td><td>$149,091,441</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Hawaii</strong></td><td>$4,995,879</td><td>$4,719,446</td><td>$166,951</td><td>$547,391</td><td>$10,429,667</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Idaho</strong></td><td>$26,673,978</td><td>$18,929,763</td><td>$581,945</td><td>$2,165,504</td><td>$48,351,190</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Illinois</strong></td><td>$252,788,881</td><td>$155,362,999</td><td>$3,175,315</td><td>$17,479,037</td><td>$428,806,232</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Indiana</strong></td><td>$114,066,354</td><td>$70,324,816</td><td>$1,322,623</td><td>$7,445,267</td><td>$193,159,060</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Iowa</strong></td><td>$78,507,818</td><td>$49,844,389</td><td>$937,361</td><td>$5,277,033</td><td>$134,566,601</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Kansas</strong></td><td>$38,821,123</td><td>$33,327,874</td><td>$235,620</td><td>$3,835,029</td><td>$76,219,646</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Kentucky</strong></td><td>$61,571,174</td><td>$51,647,357</td><td>$1,572,878</td><td>$5,944,024</td><td>$120,735,433</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Louisiana</strong></td><td>$41,415,195</td><td>$50,324,275</td><td>$1,307,770</td><td>$5,897,192</td><td>$98,944,432</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Maine</strong></td><td>$55,172,305</td><td>$35,028,740</td><td>$658,740</td><td>$3,708,498</td><td>$94,568,283</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Maryland</strong></td><td>$73,506,086</td><td>$69,851,450</td><td>$1,505,787</td><td>$8,090,410</td><td>$152,953,733</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Massachusetts</strong></td><td>$187,074,431</td><td>$120,461,255</td><td>$3,972,082</td><td>$13,640,497</td><td>$325,148,265</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Michigan</strong></td><td>$238,219,248</td><td>$146,524,948</td><td>$2,749,484</td><td>$15,510,284</td><td>$403,003,964</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Minnesota</strong></td><td>$167,346,852</td><td>$106,248,039</td><td>$1,998,074</td><td>$11,248,495</td><td>$286,841,460</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Mississippi</strong></td><td>$33,752,229</td><td>$33,175,153</td><td>$932,139</td><td>$3,851,250</td><td>$71,710,771</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Missouri</strong></td><td>$103,843,419</td><td>$75,090,936</td><td>$2,284,410</td><td>$8,569,578</td><td>$189,788,343</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Montana</strong></td><td>$27,134,445</td><td>$19,256,542</td><td>$591,992</td><td>$2,202,887</td><td>$49,185,866</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Nebraska</strong></td><td>$41,180,965</td><td>$29,208,760</td><td>$898,443</td><td>$3,341,442</td><td>$74,629,610</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Nevada</strong></td><td>$11,597,336</td><td>$12,899,126</td><td>$830,700</td><td>$1,741,587</td><td>$27,068,749</td></tr><tr><td><strong>New Hampshire</strong></td><td>$35,498,757</td><td>$25,192,456</td><td>$774,475</td><td>$2,881,938</td><td>$64,347,626</td></tr><tr><td><strong>New Jersey</strong></td><td>$172,973,948</td><td>$112,665,663</td><td>$3,945,446</td><td>$12,766,391</td><td>$302,351,448</td></tr><tr><td><strong>New Mexico</strong></td><td>$22,314,041</td><td>$18,984,981</td><td>$0</td><td>$2,145,210</td><td>$43,444,232</td></tr><tr><td><strong>New York</strong></td><td>$535,676,404</td><td>$340,099,422</td><td>$6,395,824</td><td>$36,006,375</td><td>$918,178,025</td></tr><tr><td><strong>North Carolina</strong></td><td>$86,970,460</td><td>$96,322,663</td><td>$3,031,982</td><td>$11,251,451</td><td>$197,576,556</td></tr><tr><td><strong>North Dakota</strong></td><td>$27,147,464</td><td>$19,265,782</td><td>$592,275</td><td>$2,203,944</td><td>$49,209,465</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Ohio</strong></td><td>$226,879,639</td><td>$140,491,616</td><td>$4,470,005</td><td>$15,847,745</td><td>$387,689,005</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Oklahoma</strong></td><td>$31,955,095</td><td>$38,316,431</td><td>$872,191</td><td>$4,497,380</td><td>$75,641,097</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Oregon</strong></td><td>$54,008,001</td><td>$33,704,628</td><td>$1,081,558</td><td>$3,804,103</td><td>$92,598,290</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Pennsylvania</strong></td><td>$297,671,482</td><td>$182,800,295</td><td>$3,417,885</td><td>$19,353,129</td><td>$503,242,791</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Rhode Island</strong></td><td>$30,818,515</td><td>$21,871,020</td><td>$672,368</td><td>$2,501,975</td><td>$55,863,878</td></tr><tr><td><strong>South Carolina</strong></td><td>$35,117,531</td><td>$45,075,688</td><td>$2,923,507</td><td>$6,086,407</td><td>$89,203,133</td></tr><tr><td><strong>South Dakota</strong></td><td>$24,482,535</td><td>$17,374,556</td><td>$534,136</td><td>$1,987,594</td><td>$44,378,821</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Tennessee</strong></td><td>$64,310,966</td><td>$66,094,629</td><td>$1,897,763</td><td>$7,692,249</td><td>$139,995,607</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Texas</strong></td><td>$134,407,308</td><td>$149,494,402</td><td>$9,627,413</td><td>$20,184,105</td><td>$313,713,228</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Utah</strong></td><td>$32,932,053</td><td>$23,370,940</td><td>$718,478</td><td>$2,673,560</td><td>$59,695,031</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Vermont</strong></td><td>$26,607,583</td><td>$18,882,643</td><td>$580,497</td><td>$2,160,115</td><td>$48,230,838</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Virginia</strong></td><td>$90,218,680</td><td>$88,899,724</td><td>$2,833,722</td><td>$10,327,646</td><td>$192,279,772</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Washington</strong></td><td>$86,208,581</td><td>$57,425,673</td><td>$1,053,477</td><td>$6,499,393</td><td>$151,187,124</td></tr><tr><td><strong>West Virginia</strong></td><td>$40,464,237</td><td>$28,716,314</td><td>$882,807</td><td>$3,285,056</td><td>$73,348,414</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Wisconsin</strong></td><td>$150,636,196</td><td>$95,638,491</td><td>$1,798,553</td><td>$10,125,261</td><td>$258,198,501</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Wyoming</strong></td><td>$12,721,025</td><td>$9,029,982</td><td>$276,494</td><td>$1,032,995</td><td>$23,060,496</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Subtotal to States</strong></td><td><strong>$4,428,682,697</strong></td><td><strong>$3,316,836,280</strong></td><td><strong>$98,359,406</strong></td><td><strong>$379,244,616</strong></td><td><strong>$8,223,122,999</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Subtotal to Tribes/ Tribal Organizations</strong></td><td><strong>$48,803,948</strong></td><td><strong>$38,434,012</strong></td><td><strong>$1,132,653</strong></td><td><strong>$4,405,488</strong></td><td><strong>$92,776,101</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>American Samoa</strong></td><td>$372,429</td><td>$278,797</td><td>$8,402</td><td>$31,882</td><td>$691,510</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Guam</strong></td><td>$816,537</td><td>$611,253</td><td>$18,422</td><td>$69,900</td><td>$1,516,112</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Northern Mariana Islands</strong></td><td>$283,604</td><td>$212,305</td><td>$6,398</td><td>$24,280</td><td>$526,587</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Puerto Rico</strong></td><td>$20,268,659</td><td>$15,172,946</td><td>$457,298</td><td>$1,735,097</td><td>$37,634,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Virgin Islands</strong></td><td>$772,126</td><td>$578,007</td><td>$17,421</td><td>$66,097</td><td>$1,433,651</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Subtotal to Territories</strong></td><td><strong>$22,513,355</strong></td><td><strong>$16,853,308</strong></td><td><strong>$507,941</strong></td><td><strong>$1,927,256</strong></td><td><strong>$41,801,860</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Total to All Recipients</strong></td><td><strong>$4,500,000,000</strong></td><td><strong>$3,372,123,600</strong></td><td><strong>$100,000,000</strong></td><td><strong>$385,577,360</strong></td><td><strong>$8,357,700,960</strong></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Denys Shmyhal of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-of-ukraine-denys-shmyhal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met with Prime Minister Shmyhal of Ukraine this morning. The leaders discussed recent developments in Russia’s brutal war of aggression against Ukraine. President Biden conveyed the continued commitment of the United States to support the people of Ukraine and to impose costs on Russia. He also previewed his announcement today of an additional&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met with Prime Minister Shmyhal of Ukraine this morning. The leaders discussed recent developments in Russia’s brutal war of aggression against Ukraine. President Biden conveyed the continued commitment of the United States to support the people of Ukraine and to impose costs on Russia. He also previewed his announcement today of an additional $800 million in security assistance and $500 million in economic support.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the Declaration of National Emergency and Invocation of Emergency Authority Relating to the Regulation of the Anchorage and Movement of Russian-Affiliated Vessels to United&#160;States&#160;Ports</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/21/a-proclamation-on-the-declaration-of-national-emergency-and-invocation-of-emergency-authority-relating-to-the-regulation-of-the-anchorage-and-movement-of-russian-affiliated-vessels-to-united-states-po/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.) and section 1 of title II of Public Law 65-24, ch. 30, June 15, 1917, as amended (Magnuson Act) (46 U.S.C. 70051), I,&#160;JOSEPH R. BIDEN&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.) and section 1 of title II of Public Law 65-24, ch. 30, June 15, 1917, as amended (Magnuson Act) (<em>46 U.S.C. 70051),</em> I,&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, hereby find and proclaim that:</p>



<p>The policies and actions of the Government of the Russian Federation to continue the premeditated, unjustified, unprovoked, and brutal war against Ukraine constitute a national emergency by reason of a disturbance or threatened disturbance of international relations of the United States. &nbsp;In order to address this national emergency and secure the observance of the rights and obligations of the United States, I hereby authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to make and issue such rules and regulations as the Secretary may find appropriate to regulate the anchorage and movement of Russian-affiliated vessels, and delegate to the Secretary my authority to approve such rules and regulations, as authorized by the Magnuson Act.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1</span>.  I hereby prohibit Russian-affiliated vessels from entering into United States ports.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 2</span>.  The prohibition of section 1 of this proclamation applies except:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; to Russian-affiliated vessels used in the transport of source material, special nuclear material, and nuclear byproduct material for which, and for such time as, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce, determines that no viable source of supply is available that would not require transport by Russian-affiliated vessels; and</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; to Russian-affiliated vessels requesting only to enter United States ports due to force majeure, solely to allow seafarers of any nationality to disembark or embark for purposes of conducting crew changes, emergency medical care, or for other humanitarian need.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 3</span>.  For the purposes of this proclamation:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; the term &#8220;Russian-affiliated vessels&#8221; means:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; vessels of Russian registry (i.e., the vessel is Russian flagged);</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; vessels that are Russian owned (i.e., the legal title of ownership of the vessel that appears on the ship&#8217;s registration documents is the Government of the Russian Federation or a Russian company, citizen, or permanent resident); or</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (iii)&nbsp; vessels that are Russian operated (i.e., a Russian company, citizen, or permanent resident is responsible for the commercial decisions concerning the employment of a ship and decides how and where that asset is employed).</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; the term &#8220;byproduct material&#8221; has the same meaning given to that term in section 11(e) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended (AEA) (42 U.S.C. 2014(e)).</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (c)&nbsp; the term &#8220;source material&#8221; has the same meaning given to that term in section 11(z) of the AEA (42 U.S.C. 2014(z)).</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (d)&nbsp; the term &#8220;special nuclear material&#8221; has the same meaning given to that term in section 11(aa) of the AEA (42 U.S.C. 2014(aa)).</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 4</span>.  The prohibition set forth in this proclamation shall be effective as of 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 28, 2022, and shall be immediately transmitted to the Congress and published in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-first day of April, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and President of the Senate on the Declaration of National Emergency and Invocation of Emergency Authority Relating to the Regulation of the Anchorage and Movement of Russian-Affiliated Vessels to United&#160;States&#160;Ports</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-president-of-the-senate-on-the-declaration-of-national-emergency-and-invocation-of-emergency-authority-relating-to-the-regulation-of-the-ancho/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Pursuant to the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et&#160;seq.) and section 1 of title II of Public Law 65-24, ch. 30, June 15, 1917, as amended (Magnuson Act) (46 U.S.C. 70051), I&#160;hereby report that I have issued a proclamation with respect to the policies and actions of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Pursuant to the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et&nbsp;seq</em>.) and section 1 of title II of Public Law 65-24, ch. 30, June 15, 1917, as amended (Magnuson Act) (<em>46 U.S.C. 70051),</em> I&nbsp;hereby report that I have issued a proclamation with respect to the policies and actions of the Government of the Russian Federation to continue the premeditated, unjustified, unprovoked, and brutal war against Ukraine, which constitute a national emergency by reason of a disturbance or threatened disturbance of international relations of the United&nbsp;States.</p>



<p>The proclamation prohibits Russian-affiliated vessels from entering into United States ports with limited exceptions for Russian-affiliated vessels used in the transport of source material, special nuclear material, and nuclear byproduct material for which, and for such time as, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce, determines that no viable source of supply is available that would not require transport by Russian‑affiliated vessels; and for Russian-affiliated vessels requesting only to enter United States ports due to force majeure, solely to allow seafarers of any nationality to disembark or embark for purposes of conducting crew changes, emergency medical care, or for other humanitarian need.&nbsp; The proclamation also authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to make and issue such rules and regulations as the Secretary may find appropriate to regulate the anchorage and movement of Russian-affiliated vessels, and delegates to the Secretary my authority to approve such rules and regulations, as authorized by the Magnuson Act.</p>



<p>I am enclosing a copy of the proclamation I have issued.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/21/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 14:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $800 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: White&#160;House Releases 2022 National Drug Control Strategy that Outlines Comprehensive Path Forward to Address Addiction and the Overdose&#160;Epidemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/fact-sheet-white-house-releases-2022-national-drug-control-strategy-that-outlines-comprehensive-path-forward-to-address-addiction-and-the-overdose-epidemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden sent his Administration’s inaugural National Drug Control Strategy to Congress at a time when drug overdoses have taken a heartbreaking toll, claiming 106,854 lives in the most recent 12-month period. The Strategy delivers on the call to action in President Biden’s Unity Agenda through a whole-of-government approach to beat the overdose epidemic.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden sent his Administration’s inaugural <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/National-Drug-Control-2022Strategy.pdf"><em>National Drug Control Strategy</em></a> to Congress at a time when drug overdoses have taken a heartbreaking toll, claiming 106,854 lives in the most recent 12-month period. The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/National-Drug-Control-2022Strategy.pdf"><em>Strategy</em></a> delivers on the call to action in President Biden’s Unity Agenda through a whole-of-government approach to beat the overdose epidemic.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/National-Drug-Control-2022Strategy.pdf"><em>Strategy</em></a> focuses on two critical drivers of the epidemic: untreated addiction and drug trafficking. It instructs federal agencies to prioritize actions that will save lives, get people the care they need, go after drug traffickers’ profits, and make better use of data to guide all these efforts.</p>



<p><strong>Addressing Untreated Addiction for Those At-Risk of an Overdose</strong><br>According to the 2020 National Survey on Drug Use and Health, among the 41.1 million people who needed treatment for substance use disorders (SUD), only 2.7 million (6.5-percent) of them received treatment at a specialty treatment facility over the previous year. One reason for this gap is that people with addiction and those who care for them face too many barriers to treatment. Similarly, key tools like naloxone and syringe services programs are often restricted or underfunded at the community level, which limits access for people who use drugs. For example, some states still have legal barriers that limit access to naloxone, and even in states where those barriers don’t exist, naloxone does not always make it to those most at-risk of an overdose. The President’s National Drug Control Strategy is the first-ever to champion harm reduction to meet people where they are and engage them in care and services. It also calls for actions that will expand access to evidence-based treatments that have been shown to reduce overdose risk and mortality. Finally, it emphasizes the need to develop stronger data collection and analysis systems to better deploy public health interventions.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Expand high-impact harm reduction interventions like naloxone<br><br></strong>The Biden-Harris Administration’s efforts focus on meeting people where they are, and building trust and engagement with them to provide care and services. Specifically, the Strategy calls for greater access to harm reduction interventions including naloxone, drug test strips, and syringe services programs. It directs federal agencies to integrate harm reduction into the U.S system of care to save lives and increase access to treatment. It also calls for collaboration on harm reduction between public health and public safety officials, and changes in state laws and policies to support the expansion of harm reduction efforts across the country.<br></li><li><strong>Ensure those at highest-risk of an overdose can access evidence-based treatment<br><br></strong>The Biden-Harris Administration’s efforts to expand access to treatment are focused around delivering treatment to those at the highest-risk of overdosing, which includes people experiencing homelessness, those who are incarcerated or re-entering society, and people who inject drugs. The Strategy directs federal agencies to take actions that meet people who need treatment where they are, improves the quality of treatment to include payment reform, supports those at-risk of an overdose, and builds up the Nation’s treatment workforce and infrastructure. It also includes a chapter on Criminal Justice that focuses on direct actions that will improve the delivery of evidence-based treatment when appropriate for people in carceral settings or in the reentry process in addition to other justice-impacted persons.<br></li><li><strong>Improve data systems and research that guide drug policy development.</strong><br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to deploying an evidence-based approach to policy-making as directed in the Presidential Memorandum on scientific integrity and evidence-based policymaking. Development of effective drug policy requires timely and rigorous data covering the full range of trends and activities, including consumption patterns, drug use consequences, prevention, harm reduction, treatment, recovery, drug production, transportation and distribution by drug trafficking organizations, and many more. The Strategy directs relevant agencies to strengthen existing data systems, establish new data systems, including for non-fatal overdoses, and enhance the usefulness of drug data for practitioners, researchers and policy-makers.</li></ul>



<p><strong><br>Going After Drug Trafficking and Illicit Drug Profits</strong><br>Law enforcement agencies at all levels—federal, state, local, Tribal, and territorial—work to reduce domestic and international cultivated and synthetic drug production and trafficking with the goal of protecting Americans. However, drug producers continue to produce entirely new synthetic drugs, and drug traffickers continue to refine their methods and techniques for distributing them throughout our communities.</p>



<p>The Strategy builds on the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/FY-2023-ONDCP-CONGRESSIONAL-BUDGET-SUBMISSION.pdf">President’s FY 23 budget request</a> for a $300 million increase to support the work of Customs and Border Protection (CBP)–one of the largest ever increases for CBP–and for a $300 million increase for the Drug Enforcement Administration. The Strategy prioritizes a targeted response to drug traffickers and transnational criminal organizations (TCOs) by hitting them where it hurts the most: their wallets. It also includes efforts to strengthen domestic law enforcement cooperation to disrupt the trafficking of illicit drugs within the United States, and increase collaboration with international partners to disrupt the supply chain of illicit substances and the precursor chemicals used to produce them. Lastly, the National Drug Control Strategy includes three companion documents that direct Federal agencies to take actions that stop the trafficking of drugs across our Caribbean, Northern, and Southwest Borders.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Obstruct and disrupt financial activities of transnational criminal organizations (TCOs) that manufacture illicit drugs and traffic them into the United States<br><br></strong>The illicit drugs smuggled throughout the world generate enormous revenue, which must be moved and laundered so that traffickers can profit from their illicit enterprise.TCOs also require funds to operate their illicit supply chains and exert their transnational corruptive influence. While bulk cash smuggling remains one of the predominant methods for moving illicit proceeds, smugglers also use trade-based money laundering (TBML) such as Black-Market Peso Exchanges and mirror transfers via informal networks. Additionally, TCOs are adept at using darknet markets and virtual assets to launder funds. The National Drug Control Strategy directs agencies to strengthen and employ every available tool, and seek new ones, to uncover financial networks to obstruct and disrupt the illicit financial activities that fund the TCOs who produce and traffic illicit drugs into the United States.<br></li><li><strong>Reduce the supply of illicit drugs through domestic collaboration and international coordination.</strong><br><br>The Strategy directs federal agencies to improve cooperation across all levels of government to strengthen our domestic response to drug trafficking; commercially disrupt the production, trafficking, and distribution of illicit substances; improve assessment of supply reduction initiatives; and protect individuals and the environment at home from criminal exploitation. The Strategy also aims to strengthen foreign partnerships to address drug production and trafficking, leverage the influence of multilateral organizations to tackle shared challenge of synthetic drugs, and protect individuals and the environment abroad from criminal exploitation by those involved in drug trafficking.<br></li><li><strong>Reduce the supply of illicit drugs smuggled across our borders.</strong><br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration is focused on stopping drugs from entering our communities. The President’s National Drug Control Strategy includes specific border strategies that direct federal agencies to strengthen interdiction and law enforcement capabilities on our Nation’s borders, counter criminal networks, disrupt illicit finance efforts, target drug transportation routes and modalities, and otherwise aggressively reduce the trafficking of illicit drugs. The Strategy also directs agencies to work with partner governments in drug producing and transit countries to prevent illicit drugs from ever reaching our borders.</li></ul>



<p>In addition, the Strategy directs federal agencies to expand efforts to prevent substance use among school-aged children and young adults, and support community-led coalitions implementing evidence-based prevention strategies across the country. It directs federal agencies to expand scientific understanding of the recovery process by establishing a federal recovery research agenda; adopt flexible, responsive approaches that help people with SUD find and follow a pathway to recovery or remission that works for them; and eliminate barriers and increase economic opportunities for people in recovery. And the Strategy includes specific actions to improve access to medication for opioid use disorder (MOUD) programs for jails and prisons; identify ways to advance racial equity in the investigation, arrest, and sentencing for drug related offenses without negatively impacting public safety; divert non-violent individuals from the criminal justice system and juvenile justice systems to treatment when appropriate; and remove barriers and expand supportive&nbsp; services to help reintegrate people into society after incarceration.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has already taken <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ondcp/briefing-room/2021/11/17/fact-sheet-actions-the-biden-harris-administration-has-taken-to-address-addiction-and-the-overdose-epidemic/">significant actions</a> to address addiction and the overdose epidemic based on the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/BidenHarris-Statement-of-Drug-Policy-Priorities-April-1.pdf?fbclid=IwAR2TBk34U_XRqlqK_pAYnUd_9f7zY3IbCQI9KxI6S5eYeRJdFzl9B09hZ84">Drug Policy Priorities for Year One</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with President David Panuelo of the Federated States of&#160;Micronesia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/20/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-president-david-panuelo-of-the-federated-states-of-micronesia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with President David Panuelo of the Federated States of Micronesia to affirm the abiding U.S. commitment to the security and prosperity of the Freely Associated States, as well as to discuss issues of common concern in the Pacific Islands region. Noting the appointment of Special Presidential Envoy Ambassador&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with President David Panuelo of the Federated States of Micronesia to affirm the abiding U.S. commitment to the security and prosperity of the Freely Associated States, as well as to discuss issues of common concern in the Pacific Islands region. Noting the appointment of Special Presidential Envoy Ambassador Joseph Yun to lead negotiations for the United States on renewing the Compact of Free Association, Sullivan affirmed the U.S. goal of concluding the process by the end of the year. The two discussed the existential threat posed by climate change to Pacific Island nations, and voiced common concern about the People’s Republic of China and the Solomon Islands signing a bilateral security agreement. President Panuelo and Mr. Sullivan agreed to identify additional opportunities to continue deepening U.S. engagement in this vital region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Creates Cost-Saving Clean Energy Opportunities to Combat Climate&#160;Crisis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-creates-cost-saving-clean-energy-opportunities-to-combat-climate-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 22:53:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Initiatives Remove Barriers to Local Clean Energy, Reduce Greenhouse Gas Emissions Since taking office, President Biden has prioritized expanding clean energy technologies as part of his historic efforts to tackle the climate crisis – all while helping American families lower their energy costs and creating good-paying, union jobs. Distributed Energy Resources (DERs) – like&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New Initiatives Remove Barriers to Local Clean Energy, Reduce Greenhouse Gas Emissions</em></p>



<p>Since taking office, President Biden has prioritized expanding clean energy technologies as part of his historic efforts to tackle the climate crisis – all while helping American families lower their energy costs and creating good-paying, union jobs. Distributed Energy Resources (DERs) – like rooftop solar, battery storage, heat pumps, and electric vehicles – will cut consumer costs, improve public health, strengthen U.S. energy security, and help meet the President’s goal to reduce emission 50-52% below 2005 levels in 2030. Recent analysis shows that the average American family can save an additional $500 a year from using clean electricity like solar and heat pumps to power their homes. The President’s National Climate Task Force formed a Distributed Energy Resources Working Group to advance these clean energy technologies and ensure these cost-saving opportunities are available to all Americans.<br><br>Today, as part of the President’s commitment to tackling the climate crisis, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new partnerships and initiatives designed to increase access to these cost-saving local clean energy resources. These announcements leverage existing programs, funding, and guidance, including the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, to unlock resources and pave the way for good-paying jobs in the growing clean energy economy in communities across the country. Additionally, they build on those investments proposed in the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/omb/briefing-room/2022/03/28/president-bidens-fy-2023-budget-reduces-energy-costs-combats-the-climate-crisis-and-advances-environmental-justice/?msclkid=fd01b572c0b411ec90840de7b0f43bef">President’s FY 2023 Budget</a>. These announcements will also further the President’s Justice40 Initiative which commits to delivering at least 40 percent of the benefits from federal climate and clean energy investments to disadvantaged communities that are marginalized, underserved, or overburdened by pollution.<br><br><strong>STREAMLING CLEAN ENERGY RESOURCES FOR AMERICANS</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Leveraging Community Financial Institutions to Lower Costs and Expand Clean Energy: </strong>Existing programs at the Department of Energy (DOE), Treasury and U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) are collectively poised to support the investment of billions of dollars in state and local DER projects. These investments can be leveraged by institutions like community development financial institutions, credit unions, green banks, regional and community banks and state revolving funds to drive climate resilience and clean energy projects in underserved communities across the country. To accelerate these cost saving projects DOE, Treasury, and USDA will convene a community of practice to help community financial institutions understand how existing federal funding and technical assistance for clean energy investments can be leveraged for DER projects. To complement the work of the community of practice, the Distributed Energy Resources Working Group formed under the President’s National Climate Taskforce will compile a toolkit of DER financing resources, convene a community financial institutions summit focused on leveraging private and philanthropic capital for DER projects, and expand the work of the National Community Solar Partnership’s <a href="https://www.energy.gov/communitysolar/credit-ready-solar-initiative">Credit Ready Solar initiative</a> to include all DERs.<br></li><li><strong>Charting Strategic Deployment of DERs: </strong>DOE and <a href="https://appliedenergyscience.lbl.gov/">Lawrence Berkeley National Lab</a> (LBNL), as part of the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/communitysolar">National Community Solar Partnership</a> , are enhancing their REPAIR modeling tool to better understand how to maximize the benefits and cost savings of community solar and other DER projects to the local grid. DOE will use this tool and stakeholder engagement efforts to develop case studies and model technical, policy, and economic scenarios to inform stakeholders, like utilities, public service commissions, and DER developers on how to maximize the benefits of DER for communities.<br></li><li><strong>Enabling More Efficient Systems and Grid Infrastructure: </strong>DOE is announcing the establishment of new Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funded programs that will provide rebates for replacing old transformers and electric motor systems with newer ones that will be resilient to the impacts of extreme weather and increase energy efficiency. Replacing aging electric motor systems helps companies make pumps, fans, and compressors more efficient, providing significant energy and cost savings opportunities. Likewise, switching-out distribution transformers, which are some of the most vulnerable parts of America’s power grid, increases resilience and energy efficiency.</li></ul>



<p><strong>DELIVERING CLEAN ENERGY TO UNDERSERVED COMMUNITIES</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Developing a Community Solar Customer Platform: </strong>The Department of Energy (DOE) and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) <a href="https://energy.gov/communitysolar/liheap-community-solar-subscription-platform">will partner to develop and pilot a digital platform</a> that will manage the enrollment, use, and monitoring of community solar subscriptions for customers in the <a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ocs/low-income-home-energy-assistance-program-liheap">Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program</a> (LIHEAP). The platform will connect customers who are LIHEAP-eligible with community solar subscriptions, to further reduce customer energy costs and remove barriers for application, while increasing the deployment of community solar projects and reducing the cost of customer acquisition. DOE’s <a href="https://www.energy.gov/communitysolar">National Community Solar Partnership</a> will lead coordination with HHS, utilities, state and local governments, and industry to develop the platform, with the goal of piloting the subscription program in 3-5 states.<br></li><li><strong>Ensuring Residents of HUD-Assisted Multifamily Housing Benefit from Solar Energy: </strong>Washington, D.C.’s “Solar for All” initiative aims to bring the benefits of solar energy to 100,000 families with low to moderate incomes in the District of Columbia. The U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) has determined that D.C. Solar for All’s community-net-metering (CNM) credits will be excluded from household income and utility allowance calculations and therefore will not increase housing costs for residents in properties participating in HUD Multifamily rental assistance programs. HUD is also updating guidance to allow residents of affordable housing to better access cost-saving community solar subscriptions and reviewing guidance to allow Public Housing Authorities to more easily enter into power purchase agreements for low-cost clean energy.</li></ul>



<p><strong>BUILDING THE CLEAN ENERGY WORKFORCE OF THE FUTURE</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Creating Youth Climate Jobs: </strong>The Department of Labor’s (DOL) <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/eta/youth/youthbuild">Youthbuild</a> program will award 68 organizations more than $90 million to support the development of Registered Apprenticeship and other career pathway models that prepare underserved young adults (16-24 years) who are not currently in school for jobs in construction and other in-demand industries, including green building. This model will provide valuable training enabling the acquisition of occupational skills while promoting educational opportunities with youth &#8211; splitting time between workplace training and the classroom to obtain their high school diploma or equivalency degree.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Meeting with the Secretary of Defense, Deputy Secretary of Defense, Joint Chiefs of Staff, and Combatant&#160;Commanders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/20/remarks-by-president-biden-before-meeting-with-the-secretary-of-defense-deputy-secretary-of-defense-joint-chiefs-of-staff-and-combatant-commanders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 22:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cabinet Room 4:28 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Okay.&#160; Secretary Austin, Deputy Secretary Hicks, and General Milley, my &#8212; and all our other outstanding military leaders around this Cabinet table: I&#8217;m honored to welcome you to the White House.&#160; And I really mean it &#8212; I’m honored to welcome you to the White House.&#160; Above all,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cabinet Room</p>



<p>4:28 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Secretary Austin, Deputy Secretary Hicks, and General Milley, my &#8212; and all our other outstanding military leaders around this Cabinet table: I&#8217;m honored to welcome you to the White House.&nbsp; And I really mean it &#8212; I’m honored to welcome you to the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Above all, I want to thank each of you for your dedication to the service of this country and your members, families, and the longstanding service that you’ve all put in.</p>



<p>I also want to recognize the groundbreaking nature of this gathering.&nbsp; For the first time in the proud history of the Armed Forces, we not only have highly &#8212; highly quai- &#8212; hali- &#8212; a highly qualified woman as Vice President, but as Deputy Secretary of Defense and two women combatant commanders.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an important milestone, I think, that speaks to how we&#8217;re harnessing the strength and diversity of our country in making sure women succeed in the military and throughout their careers.</p>



<p>As I said when I got elected &#8212; and I didn&#8217;t think people thought I meant it &#8212; but my administration is going to look like America.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; Not just in the military, but across the board.&nbsp; That’s where our strength comes from, in my view.</p>



<p>And today, I want to hear from all of you on your assessments on what you&#8217;re seeing in the field and across our forces.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the strategic environment is evolving rapidly in the world, but that means our plans and force posture have to be equally dynamic.&nbsp; Things are changing.&nbsp; And, you know, ensuring that &#8212; the security of the American people, our interests, and the interests of our Allies means having to constantly adapt to anything and everything that’s happening around the world.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re seeing this very day the need for adapt &#8212; adaptation as a consequence of our standing with Ukraine against Putin’s brutal and unjustified war.</p>



<p>And I want to applaud the exceptional work you&#8217;re doing to arm and equip brave Ukrainians that defend their nation.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know about you, but I&#8217;ve been to Ukraine a number of times before the war.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken to the Rada.&nbsp; I was deeply involved in what was going on in Ukraine.&nbsp; And I knew they were tough and proud, but I tell you what: They&#8217;re tougher and more proud than I thought.&nbsp; I&#8217;m amazed what they&#8217;re doing with your help, in terms of providing advice and &#8212; and weaponry we&#8217;re providing, along with the rest of NATO.<br><br>Weapons and ammunition are flowing in daily.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re seeing just how vital our alliances and partnerships are around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Our Allies are stepping up, amplifying the impact of our response.&nbsp; And NATO is united, focused, and energized as it’s ever been.&nbsp;<br><br>When I was a kid in the United States Senate in my 30s and in my 40s, I was chairman of the NATO subcommittee &#8212; the Foreign Relations Committee.&nbsp; I &#8212; not because of me or any particular thing, but I&#8217;ve never seen NATO as united.&nbsp; I know all the &#8212; I &#8212; I&#8217;m confident, in my view, just &#8212; this was Biden speaking &#8212; that I don&#8217;t think that Putin counted on being able to hold us together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ve spoken well over 150 times to our NATO Allies, either &#8212; like, yesterday, there were four- &#8212; how many on &#8212;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Twelve of them.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; How many?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Twelve.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Twelve, yesterday for a couple hours.&nbsp; They &#8212; they are &#8212; they’re &#8212; they&#8217;re stepping up.&nbsp;<br><br>And the same is true of the Indo-Pacific, where our allies are the foundation for the future we want to see in that vital region of the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Your central, indispensable mission to deter aggression from all our enemies, if required, is &#8212; is on display, and to fight, to win wars remain critical to American power.<br><br>And as Commander-in-Chief, I &#8212; I rely on your advice and maintain our &#8212; to maintain our military edge and remain the ultimate guarantor of America&#8217;s security.<br><br>Quite frankly, even though I&#8217;ve been Vice President for 8 years and a senator for 36, I didn&#8217;t fully appreciate that &#8212; how the rest of the world literally looks to us as the leader of the free world.&nbsp; I mean, looks to us in very precise, specific ways.&nbsp; And something you all fully, fully understand.<br><br>And I rely, as I said, on your device &#8212; your advice and your ability to maintain our military edge.<br><br>And, you know, in return, I promise you &#8212; and I hope it&#8217;s been demonstrated since I&#8217;ve been President &#8212; that we as a nation will uphold the sacred duty we have and we owe you, our military men and women, to prepare, properly equip you before we send you into harm&#8217;s way.&nbsp; And when we do, to care for those and your family when you come home.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doing so much at the &#8212; at the Veterans Affairs as well.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a sacred obligation.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I want to thank you all again.&nbsp; I’m looking forward to our discussion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I thank the press for coming in.  Thank you.<br><br>4:34 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
