<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:15:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Education and Sharing Day, USA,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/11/a-proclamation-on-education-and-sharing-day-usa-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50865</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we work together to build a better America, we must remember that education is the key to achieving greater opportunity, prosperity, stability, and equality both here and around the world.&#160;&#160;A high-quality education develops the mind, opens the heart, nurtures our talents, and fortifies our character.&#160;&#160;Through education, we learn to recognize ourselves in our neighbors&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As we work together to build a better America, we must remember that education is the key to achieving greater opportunity, prosperity, stability, and equality both here and around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;A high-quality education develops the mind, opens the heart, nurtures our talents, and fortifies our character.&nbsp;&nbsp;Through education, we learn to recognize ourselves in our neighbors and cherish the dignity of our shared human experience.&nbsp;&nbsp;No one understood this better than the man whose life and legacy we celebrate on this day:&nbsp;&nbsp;Rabbi Menachem Mendel Schneerson, the Lubavitcher Rebbe and leader of the Chabad-Lubavitch movement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Rebbe&#8217;s devotion to educating people worldwide and his profound respect for diversity, inclusiveness, and equal justice have set a strong example for generations of Americans and people across the globe.  Having survived one of history&#8217;s cruelest chapters, the Rebbe emerged determined to help heal the soul of humanity.  He left his mark as a thinker, leader, and teacher who recognized the limitless potential of every human being regardless of their background.  His outreach is still felt today in countless houses of worship, centers of education, cultural exchanges, and service communities worldwide.</p>



<p>The Rebbe&#8217;s work reminds us, in the words of the Prophet Amos, to &#8220;hate evil, love good, and establish justice in the gate.&#8221;  We each share a responsibility to live up to those words &#8212; in and out of the classroom &#8212; and to plant the seeds of love, kindness, and empathy in the hearts and minds of every child in America.  </p>



<p>To ensure that our children are provided every opportunity to learn and grow, my Administration provided resources through the American Rescue Plan for schools to safely reopen for in-person instruction.  Today, thanks to our COVID-19 strategy and the resilience of local communities, more than 99 percent of America&#8217;s schools are open again.  But if we are truly going to build a better America, we must continue to make transformational investments in education &#8212; including making high-quality pre-school available to every 3- and 4-year old in America and coming together to address the invisible toll on children&#8217;s mental health that was exacerbated by the pandemic.</p>



<p>Today &#8212; on what would have been the Rebbe&#8217;s 120th birthday &#8212; let us celebrate all the educators, advocates, and pioneers who teach young people the lessons that create caring neighbors and closer communities.  Let us commit to learning together, sharing the best we have to offer, and working in unity for the common good. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 12, 2022, as Education and Sharing Day, USA.&nbsp;&nbsp;I call upon all government officials, educators, volunteers, and all the people of the United States to observe this day with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eleventh day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden Administration Releases Rural Playbook, Launches Building A Better America Rural Infrastructure Tour to Highlight Impact of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law on Rural&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/biden-administration-releases-rural-playbook-launches-building-a-better-america-rural-infrastructure-tour-to-highlight-impact-of-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-on-rural-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50856</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House released a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Rural Playbook to help state, local, Tribal and territorial governments in rural areas unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure and launched a rural infrastructure tour led by the President and other senior administration officials to engage rural communities across the country.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House released a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law <a href="https://build.gov/rural">Rural Playbook</a> to help state, local, Tribal and territorial governments in rural areas unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure and launched a rural infrastructure tour led by the President and other senior administration officials to engage rural communities across the country.</p>



<p>The Rural Playbook, found at build.gov/rural, builds on the release of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Guidebook and provides rural communities with information on the “what, when, where, and how to apply” for funding under the law – so no community needs to hire a lobbyist to access their government. The Playbook also identifies over 100 programs funded under the law with federal cost share flexibilities and matching requirement waivers.</p>



<p>During the month of April, Biden Administration officials will travel to dozens of rural communities as part of a Building A Better America rural infrastructure tour to talk about the impact of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments, as well as the President’s broader commitment to ensure federal resources reach all communities in rural America. Agriculture Secretary Tom Vilsack, Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo, Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm, EPA Administrator Michael Regan, Interior Secretary Deb Haaland, Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg and Infrastructure Coordinator Mitch Landrieu will take part in events, along with other senior administration officials.</p>



<p>President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will send billions of dollars to rural communities across the country. Supporting Americans living in rural areas remains a top priority for the Biden Administration, and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers on the President’s promises to provide high speed internet, safe roads and bridges, modern wastewater systems, clean drinking water, reliable and affordable electricity, and good paying jobs in every rural community. As part of this effort, the Biden Administration is also committed to working with communities to help them access federal resources and improving transparency.</p>



<p>“This Rural Playbook and our rural infrastructure tour are a critical part of our extensive outreach to state, local, tribal and territorial governments to ensure the people of America can benefit from this once-in-a-generation investment,” said <strong>Mitch Landrieu, Senior Advisor &amp; Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator.</strong> “Building a better America requires these funds to reach rural communities that have been left behind for far too long.&nbsp; We see you, and major investments are on the way. With these investments in infrastructure in rural communities, President Biden is delivering for rural America.”</p>



<p>Across the month of April, the Biden-Harris administration will announce billions for rural areas including rural water projects, flood mitigation, transportation, healthcare, and tribal community grants, along with new technical assistance programs for rural and tribal communities.&nbsp; Earlier this month, the Department of the Interior <a href="https://doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-420-million-rural-water-funding-president-bidens">announced $420 million for rural water systems</a> across six states: Iowa, Minnesota, Montana, New Mexico, North Dakota and South Dakota. Today, the President is also announcing a $1 billion America the Beautiful Challenge that will leverage Federal conservation and restoration investments with private and philanthropic contributions to accelerate land, water, and wildlife conservation efforts across the country. The America the Beautiful Challenge is anchored by an initial commitment of $440 million of Federal resources over the next five years to a new public-private grant program, administered by the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (NFWF), that will support locally led ecosystem restoration projects that invest in watershed restoration, resilience, equitable access, workforce development, corridors and connectivity, and collaborative conservation, consistent with the America the Beautiful Initiative. The America the Beautiful Challenge will offer states, Tribes, territories, local groups, non-governmental organizations, and others the opportunity to apply for multiple grant programs through a single application that is managed by NFWF.</p>



<p>Since President Biden signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law nearly five months ago, the Biden-Harris Administration has hit the ground running to deliver results. The Administration has made key progress towards implementing the largest long-term investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. More than $100 billion has been announced and allocated to states from formula and competitive programs for roads and highways, bridges, ports, airports, electric vehicle charging stations, water systems, high speed internet, weatherization and clean energy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Rural Infrastructure&#160;Tour</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-rural-infrastructure-tour/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have always believed that for America to succeed, rural America must succeed. Since taking office, my Administration has focused on building pathways to the middle class for rural Americans in rural America – including investing in rural infrastructure and rebuilding the communities that feed and fuel our country. For far too long, opportunity has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I have always believed that for America to succeed, rural America must succeed. Since taking office, my Administration has focused on building pathways to the middle class for rural Americans in rural America – including investing in rural infrastructure and rebuilding the communities that feed and fuel our country.</p>



<p>For far too long, opportunity has been out of reach for rural communities. My Administration is changing that. Through the American Rescue Plan, we supported rural families and provided rural communities with the tools and resources that made them central to America’s strong economic recovery. I also secured historic investments for rural America through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to make sure we revitalize and rebuild rural communities for years to come. These generational infrastructure investments will provide rural communities across America affordable high-speed internet, clean drinking water, reliable electricity, better roads and bridges, and good-paying jobs. Strong infrastructure in rural communities is good for jobs, good for keeping the economy moving, good for lowering prices, and good for America.</p>



<p>I am proud today that my Administration is launching a rural infrastructure tour to double down on our unwavering commitment to building a better America where rural communities thrive. In the coming weeks and beyond, Cabinet members and senior administration officials will crisscross the country to meet with, listen to, and deliver infrastructure investments to rural communities. As we unlock federal resources and generate results for these communities, we are unlocking opportunity – job opportunities, educational opportunities, and the opportunity for a better future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Announces New Actions to Lessen the Burden of Medical Debt and Increase Consumer&#160;Protection</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-announces-new-actions-to-lessen-the-burden-of-medical-debt-and-increase-consumer-protection/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris to announce reforms across four areas to ease the burden of medical debt,&#160;giving more American families the opportunity to thrive Today,&#160;as part of the fight to help Americans deal with high costs,&#160;the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions to protect consumers and lessen the burden of medical debt on American families.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Kamala Harris to announce reforms across four areas to ease the burden of medical debt,</em>&nbsp;<em>giving more American families the opportunity to thrive</em></p>



<p>Today,&nbsp;as part of the fight to help Americans deal with high costs,&nbsp;the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new actions to protect consumers and lessen the burden of medical debt on American families. Together, these actions will help:</p>



<ul><li>Hold medical providers and debt collectors accountable for harmful practices;</li><li>Reduce the role that medical debt plays in determining whether Americans can access credit – which will open up new opportunities for people with medical debt to buy a home or get a small business loan;</li><li>Help over half a million of low-income American veterans get their medical debt forgiven; and,</li><li>Inform consumers of their rights.</li></ul>



<p>One-in-three adults in the United States have medical debt. It is now the largest source of debt in collections—more than credit cards, utilities, and auto loans combined.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2021/04/who-had-medical-debt-in-united-states.html">Black and Hispanic households</a>&nbsp;are more likely to hold medical debt than white households.</p>



<p>Medical debt is not just a financial issue—it can have negative health effects too. One&nbsp;<a href="https://nmahoney.people.stanford.edu/sites/g/files/sbiybj23976/files/media/file/kaiser_20210831.pdf">study</a>&nbsp;found that almost half of individuals with medical debt intentionally avoided seeking care.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Getting sick or taking care of loved ones should not mean financial hardship for American families. That is why the Administration is taking new action to ease the burden of medical debt and protect consumers from predatory collection policies. These actions build upon the President’s April 5<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/05/executive-order-on-continuing-to-strengthen-americans-access-to-affordable-quality-health-coverage/?msclkid=887ba3d9b67111ec81e80c7ddd11167b">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;on strengthening access to affordable, quality health care coverage, which directed federal agencies to take action to reduce the burden of medical debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, Vice President Harris is announcing reforms in four areas that will lessen the burden of medical debt, protect consumers, and open up new opportunities for Americans looking to buy a home or start a small business.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Holding Providers and Collectors Accountable&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>When families cannot afford to pay the cost of care—often because they are uninsured or underinsured—<a href="https://finhealthnetwork.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Medical-Debt-and-Financial-Health-Executive-Summary.pdf">providers have a responsibility</a> to offer non-predatory payment plans or financial assistance to all eligible patients. While many do, far too many eligible patients report not receiving help. Worse, lawsuits against patients over medical bills <a href="https://news.yale.edu/2021/12/06/study-finds-spike-hospitals-suing-patients-over-unpaid-medical-bills?msclkid=a446f5ebb6cc11ecbc00812a3db42912">are on the rise</a>. And when hospitals sell outstanding bills to third party debt collectors, patients can be subjected to persistent and aggressive collections practices. </p>



<p>The federal government pays roughly $1.5 trillion a year into the health care system to provide patients with quality care and services. Providers receiving that funding should make it easy for eligible patients to receive the financial assistance they are entitled to, and should not directly or indirectly subject patients to illegal and harassing debt collection practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, Secretary Becerra is directing the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to evaluate how providers’ billing practices impact access and affordability of care and the accrual of medical debt. HHS will request data from more than 2,000 providers on medical bill collection practices, lawsuits against patients, financial assistance, financial product offerings, and 3<sup>rd</sup>&nbsp;party contracting or debt buying practices.&nbsp;The Department will, for the first time, weigh this information in their grantmaking decisions, publish topline data and policy recommendations for the public, and share potential violations with the relevant enforcement agencies of jurisdiction.</p>



<p>Separately, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) will investigate credit reporting companies and debt collectors that violate patients’ and families’ rights, and hold violators accountable. The CFPB has already issued a&nbsp;<a href="https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.consumerfinance.gov%2Fabout-us%2Fnewsroom%2Fcfpb-issues-bulletin-to-prevent-unlawful-medical-debt-collection-and-credit-reporting%2F&amp;data=04%7C01%7CDiane.Thompson%40cfpb.gov%7C1fafc34fb3d945dfc6ef08da17e3e25d%7Cc817bf69ef414ed6ac5f1f44da3798c0%7C0%7C0%7C637848564786280189%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000&amp;sdata=piCtFykML5hUkeNWUupGnfZeQ9utyxObMhdlYbdiVDo%3D&amp;reserved=0">bulletin</a>&nbsp;to prevent unlawful medical debt collection and reporting. The CFPB will target coercive credit reporting and determine whether unpaid medical billing data should ever be included in credit reports.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Improve Government Underwriting Practices</strong></p>



<p>The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Batty-Gibbs-Ippolito-health-insurance-medical-debt-financial-well-being-WP.pdf?x91208">latest research</a>&nbsp;finds that owing medical debt is not a reliable predictor of overall financial health. An&nbsp;<a href="https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201405_cfpb_report_data-point_medical-debt-credit-scores.pdf">analysis</a>&nbsp;of 5 million anonymized credit records found that consumers who owed medical debt paid their bills at the same rate as those who did not. In fact, including paid-off medical debt causes credit scores to&nbsp;<a href="https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/201405_cfpb_report_data-point_medical-debt-credit-scores.pdf">underestimate</a>&nbsp;creditworthiness by as much as 22 points. As a result, the inclusion of medical debt on credit reports and in credit scores and loan underwriting can hold American’s back from financial opportunities while failing to improve the accuracy and predictiveness of lending programs.</p>



<p>The private sector has taken important steps to address this problem. Last month, the three largest credit reporting agencies—Equifax, Experian, and Transunion—announced that they will no longer include certain forms of medical debt on credit reports, removing billions of dollars in debt from consumer reports. This change covers borrowers with already paid debts, unpaid debts less than a year old, and debts paid or unpaid under $500.</p>



<p>However, this change leaves out a third of Americans with medical debt over $500. For example, 11 million Americans have medical debt above $2000 and 3 million Americans have debt over $10,000. Further action is needed to help families struggling with medical debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to leading the way. The federal government is one of the largest actors in consumer credit markets, directly providing tens of billions of loans annually to millions of Americans, and guaranteeing or holding up to&nbsp;70% of all mortgages. Government action matters.&nbsp;Americans with medical debt can apply for an FHA-backed mortgage without fear that medical debt will keep them from being able to buy a home. FHA – which&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/Housing/images/FHASFMarketShare2021Q4.pdf">backs over 12 % of new home purchases</a>&nbsp;in America &#8212; has eliminated medical debt from consideration when evaluating a borrower’s creditworthiness.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is why, today, the Administration is announcing actions that&nbsp;go beyond recent private sector announcements.</p>



<p><em><u>The Biden-Harris Administration is providing guidance to all agencies to eliminate medical debt as a factor for underwriting in credit programs</u></em>, whenever possible and consistent with law. Medical debt is not a reliable indicator of credit quality, and its impact should be reduced or eliminated to give more American families the opportunity to thrive:&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Americans with medical debt can apply for USDA rural housing service loans without fear that their medical debt could keep them from getting a mortgage. Today, USDA is announcing that it will discontinue the inclusion of any recurring medical debts into borrower repayment calculations, which measure a borrower’s ability to repay for its homeownership programs—<a href="https://crsreports.congress.gov/product/pdf/R/R47044">over $20 billion</a> in lending activity. <br> </li><li>The Department of Veteran Affairs has taken multiple steps to ensure credit reporting and underwriting regarding medical debt, including finalizing a rule to virtually cease reporting of medical debt for veterans with bills from VA Care. VA will also review its underwriting guidelines to ensure we minimize or eliminate medical debt reporting as a proxy for creditworthiness, wherever possible.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Small Business Administration has a demonstrated commitment to ensuring credit access and a vested interest in accurate credit reporting and underwriting.&nbsp;&nbsp;To further this commitment, SBA will work with its colleagues and partners to lessen the financial burden of medical debt for families and to review SBA lending programs to identify ways to reduce the negative impact of medical debt on small business access to capital.</li></ul>



<ul><li>FHFA is reviewing the credit models that Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac use and looking at ways to ensure that measures of creditworthiness are accurate, reliable, and predictive.</li></ul>



<p>To reinforce these measures, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) will be issuing new guidance to agencies to, whenever possible and consistent with law, eliminate medical debt as a factor for underwriting in credit programs, or reduce its impact.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Support Veterans in Financial Hardship</strong></p>



<p>Since the start of the pandemic, VA has&nbsp;<strong>cancelled or refunded approximately $1 billion in copayments to over 1.5 million veterans.</strong>&nbsp;The&nbsp;American Rescue Plan (ARP) eliminated all out-of-pocket medical cost for veterans enrolled in VA health care and provided much needed financial relief to veterans experiencing economic hardship during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Veterans Affairs (VA) will now make it easier and faster for lower-income veterans to get their VA medical debt forgiven. Currently, veterans in financial hardship who need medical debt relief from VA must fill out a complex, paper form with complicated eligibility requirements. The application process is confusing, time-consuming, and as a result, veterans may be deterred from applying for much-needed relief.&nbsp;To address these problems and ensure that veterans get the relief they deserve, VA will streamline the request process, including offering an online option to apply, and set a simple income threshold to qualify for relief.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5758">VA has also published a final rule</a>&nbsp;under which it will virtually cease reporting unfavorable debt, including medical debt, to consumer reporting agencies. The new rule ensures that debt reported better reflects creditworthiness, while saving veterans from further financial struggles simply because they had to take on medical debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Help Consumers Know Their Rights</strong></p>



<p>The CFPB will ramp-up its consumer education tools aimed at helping American families navigate the complex and often confusing medical billing landscape, including more materials specifically designed to help patients access the financial assistance they are entitled to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CFPB has a wide range of tools available to help patients and their families confronting medical billing and collections, particularly problems relating to debt collection and credit reporting, at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/consumer-tools/">consumerfinance.gov</a>. People experiencing aggressive debt collection, coercive credit reporting, or other problems with a consumer financial product or service related to medical billing and collections can submit a complaint to the CFPB at&nbsp;<a href="https://www.consumerfinance.gov/complaint/">consumerfinance.gov/complaint.</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Cracks Down on Ghost Guns, Ensures That ATF Has the Leadership it Needs to Enforce Our Gun&#160;Laws</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-cracks-down-on-ghost-guns-ensures-that-atf-has-the-leadership-it-needs-to-enforce-our-gun-laws/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden and Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco will deliver remarks in the Rose Garden to announce additional steps the Administration is taking to combat gun crime. Ensuring that ATF has the leadership it needs to enforce our commonsense gun laws and fight gun crime. The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden and Deputy Attorney General Lisa Monaco will deliver remarks in the Rose Garden to announce additional steps the Administration is taking to combat gun crime.</p>



<p><strong>Ensuring that ATF has the leadership it needs to enforce our commonsense gun laws and fight gun crime.</strong></p>



<p>The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) is our top federal law enforcement agency responsible for enforcing our commonsense gun laws. Today, the President is nominating Steve Dettelbach to serve as Director of ATF.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dettelbach is a highly respected former U.S. Attorney and career prosecutor who spent over two decades as a prosecutor at the U.S. Department of Justice. He has received bipartisan praise and support from law enforcement for his work. In 2009, he was unanimously confirmed for his position as U.S. Attorney for the Northern District of Ohio. He has a proven track record of working with federal, state, and local law enforcement to fight violent crime&nbsp;and combat domestic violent extremism and religious violence – including through partnerships with the ATF to prosecute complex cases and take down violent criminal gangs. Dettelbach also worked closely with local law enforcement and community leaders to develop and implement data-driven and neighborhood-based efforts to prevent and fight violent crime. His leadership and his record of innovation in fighting crime and violence make him ready from day one to aggressively and creatively address these pressing issues at the Director of ATF.</p>



<p><strong>Cracking down on ghost guns – the weapon of choice for many violent criminals</strong></p>



<p>Today, the President and Deputy Attorney General will also announce that the U.S. Department of Justice has issued a final rule to rein in the proliferation of “ghost guns” – unserialized, privately-made firearms that law enforcement are increasingly recovering at crime scenes in cities across the country. Last year alone, there were approximately 20,000 suspected ghost guns reported to ATF as having been recovered by law enforcement in criminal investigations – a ten-fold increase from 2016.<a href="//990DAAC7-E8DC-47C2-AECE-F4A3C5AC88E6#_ftn1"><sup>[1]</sup></a>&nbsp;Because ghost guns lack the serial numbers marked on other firearms, law enforcement has an exceedingly difficult time tracing a ghost gun found at a crime scene back to an individual purchaser.</p>



<p>This final rule bans the business of manufacturing the most accessible ghost guns, such as unserialized “buy build shoot” kits that individuals can buy online or at a store without a background check and can readily assemble into a working firearm in as little as 30 minutes with equipment they have at home. This rule clarifies that these kits qualify as “firearms” under the Gun Control Act, and that commercial manufacturers of such kits must therefore become licensed and include serial numbers on the kits’ frame or receiver, and commercial sellers of these kits must become federally licensed and run background checks prior to a sale – just like they have to do with other commercially-made firearms.</p>



<p>The final rule will also help turn some ghost guns already in circulation into serialized firearms. Through this rule, the Justice Department is requiring federally licensed dealers and gunsmiths taking any unserialized firearm into inventory to serialize that weapon. For example, if an individual builds a firearm at home and then sells it to a pawn broker or another federally licensed dealer, that dealer must put a serial number on the weapon before selling it to a customer. This requirement will apply regardless of how the firearm was made, meaning it includes ghost guns made from individual parts, kits, or by 3D-printers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This rule builds on the Biden Administration’s prior executive action to rein in the proliferation of ghost guns. In February 2022, the U.S. Department of Justice launched a National Ghost Gun Enforcement Initiative, which is training a national cadre of prosecutors and disseminating investigation and prosecution tool to help bring cases against those who use ghost guns to commit crimes. As President Biden&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/03/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-gun-violence-prevention-task-force-meeting/">said</a>&nbsp;during an event at the New York Police Department headquarters, if you use a ghost gun to commit a crime “not only are state and local prosecutors going to come after you, but expect federal charges and federal prosecution as well.”&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Additional executive action to reduce gun violence</strong></p>



<p>Today’s final rule includes two additional actions to make our communities safer.</p>



<p>First, the final rule ensures that firearms with split receivers are subject to regulations requiring serial numbers and background checks when purchased from a licensed dealer, manufacturer or importer. Decades ago, ATF issued a regulation defining the “frame or receiver” of a firearm as the part that is regulated by the Gun Control Act – meaning that is the part that triggers federal serialization, background check, and other requirements. At that time, many firearms in the United States were single-framed firearms, like revolvers, that house key components in a single structure. However, we have seen the increasing popularity of firearms using split or multi-part receivers that house key components in multiple structures. Some courts have recently interpreted decades-old regulatory text in a way that, if broadly applied, could mean that as many as 90 percent of firearms in the United States today would not have a frame or receiver subject to federal regulation. The final rule updates the regulatory definitions of “frame” and “receiver” to ensure that firearms using split or multi-part receivers continue to be covered by our common-sense gun laws.</p>



<p>Second, the final rule requires federally licensed firearms dealers to retain key records until they shut down their business or licensed activity. At that time, these dealers must transfer the records to ATF, just as they are currently required to do at the end of licensed activity. Previously, these dealers were permitted to destroy most records after 20 years, making it harder for law enforcement to trace firearms found at crime scenes. According to ATF’s National Tracing Center, on average more than 1,300 firearms a year are untraceable because the federally licensed firearms dealer destroyed the relevant records that were more than 20 years old.</p>



<p><strong>Implementing the President’s comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy</strong></p>



<p>This final rule is part of the President’s comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy. President Biden made more progress on executive actions to reduce gun violence than any other President during their first year in office. You can read more about the Administration’s whole-of-government approach to reduce gun crime&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-bidens-historic-actions-to-make-our-communities-safer-by-reducing-gun-crime/">here</a>.</p>



<p>President Biden’s fiscal year 2023 budget calls on Congress to deliver the funding needed to implement the President’s comprehensive strategy to reduce gun crime and make our communities safer. These additional resources will fund accountable policing, including by putting more police officers on the beat, and making essential investments in crime prevention and community violence intervention.</p>



<p>Congress needs to do its job by passing this budget and other essential legislation to reduce gun crime, including legislation to&nbsp;require background checks for all gun sales, ensure that no terrorist can buy a weapon in the United States, ban the sale and possession of unserialized firearms &#8212; ghost guns, ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and repeal gun manufacturers’ protection from liability.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Virtual Meeting with Prime Minister Modi of&#160;India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/10/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-virtual-meeting-with-prime-minister-modi-of-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will meet virtually with Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India on Monday, April 11 to further deepen ties between our governments, economies, and our people. President Biden and Prime Minister Modi will discuss cooperation on a range of issues including ending the COVID-19 pandemic, countering the climate crisis, strengthening the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will meet virtually with Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India on Monday, April 11 to further deepen ties between our governments, economies, and our people. President Biden and Prime Minister Modi will discuss cooperation on a range of issues including ending the COVID-19 pandemic, countering the climate crisis, strengthening the global economy, and upholding a free, open, rules-based international order to bolster security, democracy, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific. The Leaders will advance ongoing conversations about the development of an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework and delivering high-quality infrastructure. President Biden will continue our close consultations on the consequences of Russia’s brutal war against Ukraine and mitigating its destabilizing impact on global food supply and commodity markets. Biden last spoke to Prime Minister Modi with other Quad Leaders in March. This meeting will precede the U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial between Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin, and External Affairs Minister Dr. Subrahmanyam Jaishankar and Defense Minister Rajnath Singh of India.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South&#160;Africa</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/08/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-cyril-ramaphosa-of-south-africa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 01:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa. President Biden emphasized the strength of the bilateral partnership, as well as global challenges brought on by Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, addressing climate change, and enhancing our partnership on trade, health security, and the Covid-19 pandemic. President Biden emphasized the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa. President Biden emphasized the strength of the bilateral partnership, as well as global challenges brought on by Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, addressing climate change, and enhancing our partnership on trade, health security, and the Covid-19 pandemic. President Biden emphasized the need for a clear, unified international response to Russian aggression in Ukraine. The leaders also shared views on the ongoing humanitarian crisis in Ukraine and the impact of the crisis on supply chains, commodity prices, and food security in Africa. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 8,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/08/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-8-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 23:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50822</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:38 P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Happy Friday.&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Happy Friday.&#160; Is there more to say on this historic day?&#160; (Laughter.) Okay.&#160; So, I want to first start by outlining our security assistance to Ukraine, and there&#8217;s been a lot of good questions about this, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:38 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Happy Friday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Happy Friday.&nbsp; Is there more to say on this historic day?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; So, I want to first start by outlining our security assistance to Ukraine, and there&#8217;s been a lot of good questions about this, and we thought this would be a helpful rundown for all of you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; the Department of Defense also put out a factsheet that has this detailed as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The security assistance the Biden administration is providing to Ukraine is enabling critical success on the battlefield against the Russian-invading force.&nbsp; The number one reason that they&#8217;re able to fight back is their bravery and courage.&nbsp; The number two reason is the security assistance that we are providing and we are providing in coordination with our allies and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re working around the clock to fulfill Ukraine&#8217;s priority security assistance requests, delivering weapons from U.S. stocks when they are available, and facilitating the delivery of weapons by allies and partners when their systems better suit Ukraine&#8217;s needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of the anti-armor and anti-air systems from the two packages of security assistance the President approved in March have been delivered.&nbsp; We are continuing work with allies and partners to identify additional weapons systems to help the Ukrainian military defend its country.&nbsp; Obviously, there was the announcement about the S-300s earlier today, and our efforts to work to backfill that.</p>



<p>At President Zelenskyy’s request, this includes helping Ukraine acquire long-range anti-aircraft systems and munitions that they are trained to use.&nbsp; More than 30 nations have sent Ukraine security assistance, thanks in part to the leadership of President Biden and diplomacy that he has been implementing for months now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On April 5th, we announced an additional $100 million in security assistance to Ukraine through a presidential drawdown authority.&nbsp; We also announced $300 million in security assistance on April 1st under authorities provided by the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative.&nbsp; These announcements bring the U.S. commitment to more than $1.7 billion in security assistance since Russia&#8217;s February 24th invasion, and $2.4 billion since the beginning of the administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will not read through all of this for you.&nbsp; You can all, of course, read it yourself.&nbsp; And we will provide all of the list to all of you should &#8212; if you did not receive the Department of Defense factsheet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also wanted to note that, today, according to a new independent study, the Biden administration&#8217;s historic vaccination program saved 2.3 million lives in the United States, prevented 17 million hospitalizations and 66 million cases, and avoided $900 billion in healthcare costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the past 15 months, the President has mounted a successful nationwide vaccination effort while executing a comprehensive strategy on treatments, testing, and more.&nbsp; As a result, schools are open, our economy is booming.&nbsp; And importantly, today&#8217;s report shows we&#8217;ve spared millions of families the immeasurable loss that too many others have suffered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And because of the President&#8217;s comprehensive response, we&#8217;ve entered a new moment in our fight against the virus.&nbsp; While COVID isn&#8217;t over, Americans now have more tools than ever before to protect themselves and this country is moving forward safely, back to many of our more normal routines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unfortunately, Republicans in Congress are holding up critical funding we need to make even more progress to save even more lives and to stay prepared against any potential surges or variants.&nbsp; Inaction will leave our nation less prepared for future surges and variants.&nbsp; It will mean fewer vaccines, treatments, and tests for the American people.&nbsp; This is deeply disappointing, and it should be unacceptable to every American.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also wanted to give you a sense of the week ahead.&nbsp; Just one trip next week that we announced earlier today &#8212; at this point.&nbsp; There could be more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Thursday, the President will travel to Greensboro, North Carolina, to discuss his administration&#8217;s efforts to make more in America, rebuild our supply chains here at home, and bring down costs for the American people as part of building a better America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Following that trip, he will travel to Camp David, where he will remain over the Easter weekend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, finally, as I&#8217;ve been doing a little bit this week, I just want to shout out some amazing colleagues I have: Lewis, who we have stolen from FEMA &#8212; not really stolen; he&#8217;s a detailee.&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s a fellow, actually.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had him since November.&nbsp; Soon, they will steal him back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Lewis has been remarkable.&nbsp; Lewis has been reading Russian media, which comes in use &#8212; in great use.&nbsp; He has been tracking down a range of coverage about the war in Ukraine.&nbsp; He has been relentless in giving us updates and providing us information.&nbsp; And we’re incredibly grateful to Lewis, and we’ll be sad to see you go back to FEMA to do very important work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many of you know Amanda Finney.&nbsp; I call her “the mayor” because she knows every person, seemingly, who works in the building and on the complex, which is about 2,000 people.&nbsp; I would not survive this job without Amanda Finney.&nbsp; You probably would all not have received all the help you have received about a range of things without Amanda Finney.&nbsp; She is smart, sassy, levelheaded, stable.&nbsp; She&#8217;s remarkable.&nbsp; And we may all work for her one day in some capacity.&nbsp; I certainly may.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m very grateful to her.&nbsp; So, I just wanted to shout that out.&nbsp; And her yellow suit is very joyful for a joyful day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, with that &#8212; it&#8217;s a Friday!&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s Friday.&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got a couple things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First on this &#8212; the missile attack at this train station.&nbsp; Does the administration think that Russia might have intentionally targeted the train station, knowing that there will be a lot of civilians there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what we&#8217;ve seen over the course of the last six weeks &#8212; or more than that &#8212; has been what the President himself has characterized as war crimes, which is the intentional targeting of civilians.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is yet another horrific atrocity committed by Russia, striking civilians who were trying to evacuate and reach safety.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Where we are now is we&#8217;re going to support efforts to investigate this attack as we document Russia&#8217;s actions, hold them accountable.&nbsp; And we will continue to surge security assistance and weapons deliveries to help Ukraine defend their country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, the targeting of civilians would certainly be a war crime. &nbsp;And we&#8217;ve already called a range of the actions we&#8217;ve seen to date a war crime, but we&#8217;re going to be supporting efforts to investigate exactly what happened here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Changing topics.&nbsp; Senior administration officials have said publicly on TV, suggesting it&#8217;s possible the President could get COVID.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: Is the administration attempting to prepare the public for the possibility of the President getting the &#8212; testing positive?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what we&#8217;re trying to do is be as transparent and direct with the American people as possible about the fact that while the President is &#8212; takes a range of protocols, we have a range of protocols in place here that are aligned and even beyond the CDC requirements.&nbsp; Those include, as we&#8217;ve outlined here many times in the past, testing before you see the President, testing before you travel with him, social distancing when possible.</p>



<p>We believe we have the tools and protocol to address this point we are in the virus.&nbsp; But like anyone else, the President may at some point test positive for COVID.&nbsp; And while we have seen an increase in recent &#8212; I would just note: While we have seen an increase in cases around people, I should just say, that some of us may know, I would also note that cases remain down 95 percent since the height of Omicron.&nbsp; That is fact, that is data, even as we&#8217;ve seen cases of people we know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what is important for the American people to know is that he has taken a range of precautions, as we all have.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s also taken steps &#8212; like getting the second booster, as he did last week in public.&nbsp; And his doctors are comfortable that he could continue to carry out his duties because of all these steps and precautions and protections he&#8217;s taken.&nbsp; And we &#8212; certainly, that&#8217;s one of the reasons we encourage the rest of the American public to do the same.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212; this is the first time that we&#8217;ve heard a White House official sort of describe it as a certain possibility that the President could get COVID.&nbsp; Are you saying that you think it&#8217;s more possible now, given sort of the little outbreak that we&#8217;re seeing in D.C. right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just saying that it is a possibility.&nbsp; Again, we are &#8212; cases are down 95 percent across the country since the height of Omicron.&nbsp; While cases are up in Washington, D.C., they&#8217;re also far below the height of the cases and where they were in Omicron.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it is also the case that despite all the precautions we take.&nbsp; And even with the President being double boosted, he could still test positive for COVID, just as people in the &#8212; many people in the White House have, many people in the press corps have.&nbsp; That is a possibility.&nbsp; And we want to be transparent with the American public about that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By our rough count here, you have at least 18 politicians and people close to the President who have now tested positive this week, though.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve reiterated all the extra precautions that you are taking to try and keep him safe &#8212; some of the extra masking and testing protocol.&nbsp; But just to be safe, have you considered maybe cutting down some of the big indoor events or scaling back any &#8212; or changing, sort of, your tactic with some of these events?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, clearly, we did the event &#8212; the historic event today outside.&nbsp; That was, in part, to ensure that we could have a huge number of people on the South Lawn celebrating the confirmation of Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson.&nbsp; But also, we know that having events outside is better for safety protocols.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what&#8217;s important for the American people to know and understand is that because of all the steps we&#8217;ve taken, because the President is double boosted, because of &#8212; you know, obviously he has access to the best healthcare in the world, but his doctors have assessed that these are risks that can be taken.&nbsp; We risk-assess just like everybody out in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s important for him to be able to continue his presidential duties now and even if he tests positive in the future, just like Americans out there in the country are taking their kids to school, they go to the grocery store, maybe they&#8217;re making a decision to go to dinner.&nbsp;&nbsp;This is a time where we are certainly living with the virus, but we have a range of tools at our disposal to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A couple of quick questions on oil, and then one on the French election.&nbsp; We have some reporting showing that the administration is considering easing sanctions to allow some oil imports from Venezuela as a way to replace banned energy shipments from Russia.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about any such considerations?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of that being under consideration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; At the moment, is it &#8212; is it going to perhaps be considered for &#8212; going forward?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It has not been, so I&#8217;m not aware of it being under consideration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And one other one on when Daleep was in India.&nbsp; He delivered this warning to India to not raise purchases of Russian oil.&nbsp; And we were wondering if perhaps sanctions along similar lines are being considered for other nations, asking them to keep purchases of Russian oil only limited to previous levels and, perhaps, not raise (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, I wouldn&#8217;t characterize it as a warning, nor did we at the time.&nbsp; He went and had a constructive conversation and made clear that while it&#8217;s the decision of each individual country, including India, to determine whether they&#8217;re going to import Russian oil, it is only 1 to 2 percent of their imports.&nbsp; About 10 percent of their imports is from the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so he conveyed, of course, they should abide by sanctions, which are not related to that decision, but also, we would be here to help them diversify and move towards even reducing further beyond the 1 to 2 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that decision, perhaps, being relayed also to other countries, asking them to perhaps follow the same guidelines?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we convey to every country to abide by sanctions.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve conveyed to a range of European countries, as you know and as we&#8217;ve talked about, that as they work to diversify their energy sources, that we are here to assist in those efforts.</p>



<p>And there are a range of steps we&#8217;ve taken, including efforts on LNG &#8212; I mean, that&#8217;s natural gas, of course &#8212; but efforts on LNG and moving some resources from Asia and other places, and ensuring that there are options to &#8212; for any country that wants to, to diversify their energy sources.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And one on the French elections.&nbsp; Are you watching the French elections coming up this Sunday, perhaps, with any concerns &#8212; especially with the rise of Le Pen, who is a far-right candidate, running against Macron?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are certainly watching the elections, but I don&#8217;t have any prediction of what the outcome will be.&nbsp; And once there is an outcome, I&#8217;m sure we will speak to it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Understanding it’s a fluid situation, but I think the atrocities in Bucha serve as an accelerant towards the latest sanctions package, the coordination between the G7 &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That we announced two days ago?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any sense that the strike that we saw this morning will also accelerate talks on additional sanctions between the coordinated allies?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say just go &#8212; to go back to a couple of days ago, that obviously the sanctions package we announced on Wednesday, with some &#8212; the biggest bank in Russia, Sberbank, certainly that was augmented as a result of the atrocities that we were seeing in Bucha.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we have done to date and we will continue to do is look at, unfortunately, the continued atrocities that we&#8217;re seeing in the country and assess how that&#8217;s going to impact sanctions, consequences, and, obviously, additional security assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s how we&#8217;ve been evaluating and working with our allies to date.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m certain, given the video footage we&#8217;ve seen on airwaves across the world and photos, that this will be a part of the discussion that our national security officials are having with their counterparts moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On the S-300 &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; it&#8217;s been fairly apparent for the last several weeks that that was a process that you guys were engaged in.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you are deliberately ambiguous as to some of the other processes that may be taking place, but is it fair to say that there are multiple other tracks that are similarly far down the line for other weapons systems?&nbsp; Or how can you characterize how far along you are, compared to where you are now with the S-300, on other systems?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So &#8212; well, one, I mean, part of our objective here &#8212; and the S-300s are an example of that &#8212; is to see that we can get defensive equipment that Ukrainians are trained on and that we know can be effective moved to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are, of course, grateful to Slovakia and we work closely with Slovakia to also meet their defense needs.&nbsp; And part of our considerations here as we&#8217;re looking at the list of requests that the Ukrainians have is: What do we have access to here in the United States?&nbsp; What military equipment do we have access to?&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are systems we may not have access &#8212; access to or we may not even have those systems.&nbsp; So how can we work with countries around the world, like Slovakia, to meet those needs?</p>



<p>So there are a range of those conversations happening with our partners and allies at the same time.&nbsp; I will tell you that often it is the preference of these partners and allies not to be public about these conversations.&nbsp; And at times, it is the preference of the Ukrainians.&nbsp; And we certainly respect that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one final one.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a pretty historic 24 hours &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for the history of the Supreme Court, for the country.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen the President speak publicly.&nbsp; Can you talk about &#8212; do you have any color in terms of what he&#8217;s been like behind the scenes, delivering on a campaign pledge &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; putting the first African American woman on the Court &#8212; how he&#8217;s been with staff, with the justice, all that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to try not to ugly cry about this day, because &#8212; which we were all &#8212; we were all doing on the South Lawn.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I was with the President before he went out.&nbsp; I was there on time; I didn&#8217;t run out, as you would have seen.&nbsp; I was with him before, when he was reviewing his &#8212; doing his final review of his remarks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what he was reflecting on is &#8212; and you saw some of this in his speech &#8212; were the number of people, whether it is people who work at the White House; people who are part of his every day; you know, stewards or others who have commented to him how significant this moment is and how &#8212; you know, in a place where you are just trying to &#8212; trying to make it through every day &#8212; and every day is history, in many ways.</p>



<p>History can be heartbreaking.&nbsp; And many days, it has been.&nbsp; History can be exhausting.&nbsp; And many days, it has been.&nbsp; And history can be joyful.&nbsp; And today was a joyful day in history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is certainly how the President was.&nbsp; You saw his granddaughter, Naomi, who he talked about in the speech, come out.&nbsp; She was there also for a brief greet with &#8212; with Justice Jackson beforehand.&nbsp; And he made a &#8212; made an effort to also introduce the new associate justice to some members of his close staff who just were inspired by the significance of today as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I would say there was a deep recognition of this moment of history, a joy in reaching it.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;ve all been saying to each other in the hallways, &#8220;No one can speal [sic] our &#8212; steal our sunshine today,&#8221; because that&#8217;s how everybody is feeling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; To follow up on that, did the President spend any time with the Jackson family before the formal event or afterward (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as we confirmed, she signed her commission &#8212; or he signed her commission, and her family was with her for that.&nbsp; So, it was briefly before he came out to do the remarks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, got it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to follow up on a question from Katie earlier this week about other precautions that the President may or may not be taking, do you know or he is taking any monoclonal antibodies to help prevent catching COVID?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Evusheld is for immunocompromised.&nbsp; That would be the preemptive step.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s not immunocompromised, so he&#8217;s not taking Evusheld.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is taking any other medication that might help?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Like what?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t actually know.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; Other than the booster &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve heard other people taking other kinds of prophylactics to prevent it.&nbsp; Is he taking anything, that you know of?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are not other &#8212; this is why I asked.&nbsp; There are not other &#8212; Evusheld is obviously one that, if you’re immunocompromised, is something that has been approved and recommended.&nbsp; Since he is not categorized that way, he isn’t taking it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But other than that, the precautions we’re taking are &#8212; he obviously got the booster when he was eligible last week, and, you know, we take additional steps, including testing, socially distanced meetings when possible as well, in order to protect him as much as possible.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then just one more on something that Samantha Power shared.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She said that Russian forces have killed at least seven journalists in Ukraine in six weeks and that Putin soldiers are killing journalists at an unprecedented rate.&nbsp; Is there any intelligence, any information that Putin is targeting journalists?&nbsp; And do you have any warning that you&#8217;re sharing with American journalists covering the war?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, we &#8212; we value the role that American journalists and journalists from around the world &#8212; (cell phone disruption) &#8212; that felt like a direction to somewhere &#8212; have played in &#8212; in bringing light &#8212; bringing to light for a lot of people in this country this war: what&#8217;s happening, the devastation, the horrors.&nbsp; It has been a &#8212; had a direct impact on people&#8217;s emotional response in the United States.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question about that.</p>



<p>We recognize the work of journalists in war zones, of course, and value it.&nbsp; And as you all know, we also work very closely with leaders of news organizations to ensure that they have up-to-date information to keep members of their media organization safe.</p>



<p>It is still a war zone &#8212; an active war zone, and we&#8217;re still conveying that Americans should not be there &#8212; right? &#8212; including journalists.</p>



<p>In terms of specific targeting, we knew from the beginning &#8212; and we&#8217;ve talked publicly about this, of course &#8212; that President Putin and the Russian military was going to target &#8212; was intending to target or could target civilians and others, including journalists could be part of that.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; any new intelligence or anything beyond that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Is there a carve-out in CDC regulations for COVID for the Vice President?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tell me more, Peter.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure this is going somewhere.&nbsp; Let’s see.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you know, the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What do you got for me on a Friday?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The CDC says, for people exposed to COVID, up to date on their COVID-19 vaccinations: Do not go to places where you are unable to wear a well-fitting mask.&nbsp; So why is she here at the White House today giving the new Supreme Court justice a big hug with no mask?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean when she gave her a ma- &#8212; a hug outside?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She was outside.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the CDC say that people who are close contact can give people hugs outside?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We know, Peter, that outside it is &#8212; it is &#8212; you are &#8212; you can benefit significantly being outside.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have &#8212; we had the event outside today.</p>



<p>I will tell you that the Vice President has been wearing a mask inside.&nbsp; When there was a private greet, they were all wearing masks, before they went out &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We saw she was wearing a mask yesterday at the Senate.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She was playing an important role in confirming or overseeing the confirmation of the first Black woman to the Supreme Court.&nbsp; The vast majority, as was on camera, Peter &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a public health carve-out for that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;As was on camera.&nbsp; Let me finish my answer here.&nbsp; Because Fox and other &#8212; I don’t know actually that Fox carried it, but others did &#8212; saw that she was socially distanced from people for the vast, vast majority of her time overseeing that confirmation yesterday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So this is not a case of rules for thee but not for VP?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In fact, the Vice President wore a mask inside today when she was both with the President, with her staff, other people.&nbsp; She was outside at the event.&nbsp; She was socially distanced for 99.9 percent of the event today.&nbsp; And she had an emotional moment, which is understandable.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And one other topic.&nbsp; Following up on the smartphones that are being given to border crossers with technology so they can be tracked or so they can check in: Is there any plan to give free smartphones to U.S. citizens that want them?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Should we not be tracking migrants who irregularly cross the border?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m asking if the same &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Or do you have an alternative suggestion for how they should be tracked?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I, unfortunately, have not been asked to make U.S. immigration policy.&nbsp; That’s not my &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Today’s your moment.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, it’d be great if anybody that wanted a free phone and a free monthly plan could get one.&nbsp; So, is that going to be an offer for everybody or just people that walk into the country illegally?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, as &#8212; when we talked about this the other day, what I noted to you is that we have a range of means of tracking individuals who irregularly migrate to the country, as &#8212; in order to ensure that they are meeting their Notice to Appear obligations and that they are appearing in court when they should appear in court.&nbsp; Phones is one of them.&nbsp; There are also ankle devices and a range of tracking devices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Eighty percent of individuals have &#8212; of non-citizens released at the border from DHS custody under prosecutorial discretion have either received a Notice to Appear or are still within the window to report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, yes, there is telephonic reporting.&nbsp; There is SmartLink, which enables participant monitoring via smartphone.&nbsp; There’s the Global Positioning System.&nbsp; These are the range of means with modern technology that we monitor.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last one on this: Does the President have any plans to figure out what these small towns who are bracing for a major influx in migrants next month need by making his first-ever trip to the border?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have nothing to predict for you in terms of additional trips.&nbsp; The President will be traveling the country, but I don’t have any more specifics for you at this point.&nbsp; Thanks for the question.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just for clarity: Earlier &#8212; earlier, you guys told us, via pool, that the President was tested &#8212; tested negative.&nbsp; That was today, for clarity?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yup.&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, the cadence has clearly changed.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We know there was one on Wednesday; he was negative.&nbsp; Today is Friday; he tested negative.&nbsp; Just for keeping track of his &#8212; is it now three times a week, two times a week?&nbsp; Is there a way to describe it?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; His doctor makes an assessment on how many times he should be tested, and we do our best to provide that information to you as he’s tested.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And aside from the time he spent with Ketanji Brown Jackson and her family, there was no &#8212; because there’s precedent to this &#8212; there was no indoor reception, indoor ceremony that existed of some kind that the cameras didn’t see before?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let me &#8212; if I can, during his remarks today, the President said something that was a bit striking.&nbsp; He was condemning some of the conservative Republicans and their criticisms of Judge Jackson when she was testifying recently.&nbsp; He said: “There was verbal abuse.&nbsp; The anger.&nbsp; The constant interruptions.&nbsp; The most vile, baseless, [vile] assertions and accusations.”&nbsp; Whoo.&nbsp; Is that a preview of messaging that we’re going to hear from the President heading into the midterms?&nbsp; Was that &#8212; was that &#8212; is that a message that the White House wants to deliver and will be repeating?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t believe that the conduct of senators at a hearing is going to be central to the President’s remarks when he’s out in &#8212; out traveling the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>But I think what he was speaking to, on a historic day, is that while Judge Jackson was the picture &#8212; now Justice Jackson </a>&#8212; was the picture of dignity in her hearings, some others in the room decided to be the opposite.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he is somebody who has more experience overseeing Supreme Court hearings than anyone living.&nbsp; He has overseen them during Republican and Democratic Presidents and expects a certain level of conduct, professionalism, and decorum.&nbsp; And that is not what we saw.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that was more of a one-off for today, as opposed to, like, a central theme that we’ll see in terms of contrast?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that I think the American people can expect that he’ll continue to talk when he’s out in the country &#8212; for whatever reason &#8212; about how to bring down their costs, how to make sure that he is fighting for them, and bringing them relief, and how’s going to get the COVID pandemic under control &#8212; less about the conduct of senators at a hearing.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask a very quick question, then, on costs, if I can.&nbsp; Right now, the cost of gas in this country, on average, is $4.14. &nbsp;Does the White House want a gas tax holiday?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Is it certainly on the table and certainly something we continue to consider.&nbsp; We have seen a number of states do that.&nbsp; And while, you know, it can have an impact &#8212; about 18 cents, I believe, if I remember correctly &#8212; one of the reasons why we’re considering it &#8212; our primary focus, to date, as you all know, has been taking steps to increase supply and get it &#8212; get more supply into the global marketplace.&nbsp; But it remains an option under consideration.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The U.N. today put out a report saying that global food prices in March reached a record high.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the U.S. doing, if anything, to mitigate possible additional increases here?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Here in the United States?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it is something that we are certainly watching very closely.&nbsp; While we continue to believe that the impact will largely be in the Middle East and in Africa, I believe, and a lot of, you know, other parts of the world &#8212; less in the United States &#8212; we are continuing to work &#8212; our Department of Agriculture is continuing to work with farmers and suppliers about any needs we have here.&nbsp; And the President is continuing to work to bring down costs in a range of areas for the American people, as we prepare for the impacts of this war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was pretty widely reported yesterday, prior to her COVID diagnosis, that Speaker Pelosi was planning a trip to Taiwan.&nbsp; Beijing reacted very negatively to that.&nbsp; Is the U.S. &#8212; is the Biden administration comfortable if she were to do that &#8212; such a high-ranking U.S. official?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I think we’ve understood her trip.&nbsp; I don’t have any further comment on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions for you.&nbsp; The first: Today, my colleagues in the UK reported that the Chancellor of the Exchequer Rishi Sunak had a U.S. green card, which he surrendered this past October.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been an MP since 2015.&nbsp; And USCIS manual says that serving in a foreign government while standing for election in a foreign government is not compatible with lawful permanent resident status.&nbsp; Why was this not flagged earlier?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would point you to the State Department or the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more comment from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it &#8212; I mean, is it a problem?&nbsp; Does the President see it as a problem that &#8212; possible for someone to serve at high level in a foreign government and maintain lawful permanent resident status in the U.S?&nbsp; I mean, what if this were someone who was serving in the Russian Duma?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t.&nbsp; But I would also, again, point you to the portions of the government that oversee green cards and oversee, you know &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They haven’t responded.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; the status of documents.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to bump it for them as well and see if there&#8217;s more we can provide.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s fine.&nbsp; The second question: There&#8217;s a death row inmate in Texas, Melissa Lucio.&nbsp; She&#8217;s set to be executed soon.&nbsp; Many experts believe her confession was coerced and is false.&nbsp; She has bipartisan support for clemency and support from the EU and many other foreign allies.&nbsp; Would the President consider asking Governor Abbott to intervene?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you know the President&#8217;s position and view on the death penalty.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s an ongoing review at the Department of Justice at a federal level.&nbsp; This is obviously at a state level.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a follow-up: Given his commitment to police reform, would he consider asking the DOJ to prohibit police departments that receive federal funds from using the Reid technique for interrogations?&nbsp; It&#8217;s considered to create a lot of false confessions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I know the Department of Justice has taken a number of steps, including on chokeholds and other actions that needed to be reformed in police departments across the country.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview or predict in terms of additional steps.</p>



<p>The President supports their efforts to do more.&nbsp; Many of them have talked about their desire to do more.&nbsp; And obviously, we are continuing to consider an executive order on police reform here, given there has been an inability of Congress to move forward.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; There&#8217;s some pretty desperate images coming out of Shanghai right now, which is under lockdown for COVID &#8212; people begging for food and medicine.&nbsp; Is the White House monitoring that?&nbsp; Is there anything the U.S. can do to help the humanitarian situation there?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, on the supply chain front, is the administration aware of any further supply chain snags coming as a result of this?&nbsp; And how are you prepared to address them?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, the &#8212; on the first part of your question, the State Department is closely monitoring the situation.&nbsp; They&#8217;re providing consistent updates of the situation on the ground.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll certainly assess, with USAID and others, if there&#8217;s additional assistance that could be provided.</p>



<p>On the supply chain component: What we know is that the port is continuing to operate normally.&nbsp; And where we&#8217;re seeing the impacts &#8212; which still could have an impact over the course of time, of course &#8212; is factories, warehouses, and trucking, where we are seeing shutdowns within the region, which we know could cause delays, especially for air cargo, as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because this is just happening, we don&#8217;t have a prediction at this point on how that could impact bigger global supply chain issues.&nbsp; It depends on a lot of factors &#8212; how long, et cetera &#8212; but it is something we are closely monitoring, and it is something we will continue to work to &#8212; to address if it extends farther.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more &#8212; housekeeping item.&nbsp; Do you have a timing update on when the President might sign the trade preference bill on Russia that passed?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I don&#8217;t.&nbsp; And I know you and others have been looking for this.&nbsp; And let me see if I can get an answer before we all wrap up today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, could you speak to the efficacy of sanctions?&nbsp; I know there was a new sanctions package rolled out this week.</p>



<p>And initially, we heard a lot from administration officials about this being a deterrent.&nbsp; I know that has changed.&nbsp; And so, can you speak to sort of the end goal and what is the efficacy of sanctions?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that it has &#8212; we have a couple of objectives at this point as it relates to the war in Ukraine.&nbsp; One is to impose severe consequences, send a marker for the world and for history about the horrific nature of these atrocities &#8212; these consequences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the second part of our objective is to ensure that these consequences are having a significant impact on the economy in Russia.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing an inflationary rate of about 15 percent &#8212; a projection of a contraction of 15 percent in the Russian economy.&nbsp; Six hundred private-sector companies have left Russia.&nbsp; We know it is having the impact that the world intended.&nbsp; This is the most significant coordinated set of sanctions ever done in history on this large of an economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The third objective here is to make it much more difficult for President Putin to fund his war.&nbsp; And if you look back &#8212; say, earlier this week, at the example of the bond payments and how Russia has basically been put in a decision of &#8212; in a place where they either have to use their limited resources they have that are also being used to fund the war to prevent a default or default &#8212; that is the position they&#8217;re in at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also, because we have cut them off, through export controls and a number of other means, from having access to materials and technology but also access to funds, it makes it more difficult for them to fund the war.&nbsp; That is part of it.</p>



<p>And the last objective is to continue to make it clear that this is a strategic blunder &#8212; their decision to invade Ukraine &#8212; and one that will make President Putin a pariah in the world.</p>



<p>So those are why and what we are hoping to achieve.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask one follow-up?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything being done in terms of either monitoring or actually just &#8212; I guess, monitoring to take a look at the effects of sanctions on ordinary Russians or anything the administration is thinking to just deal with that population of people who are being affected?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The Russian people, you mean?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, correct.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Cert- &#8212; I mean, certainly, we are looking at how this is impacting the Russian economy writ large.&nbsp; And it is &#8212; certainly, as inflation is going up and as the economy is contracting, that means prices will go up.&nbsp; And we do know there will be a broad impact.&nbsp; That is the fault of President Putin, and the fault of President Putin invading a sovereign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it is important also for the Russian people to know and understand that.&nbsp; And we have been working through a range of means to communicate about the realities of the war and the facts of the war through Telegram, through YouTube, through a range of channels as well.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; General Milley, earlier this week, talked about the possibility of building permanent U.S. bases on NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.&nbsp; I wonder what seriousness the White House has given that &#8212; or, as you look long term at the war in Ukraine, whether shoring up the eastern flank with permanent bases is something that&#8217;s been considered.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They&#8217;ll continue to be a range of discussions, but I have nothing beyond what General Milley said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you one more question?&nbsp; I want to dig a little deeper on the French elections.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House worry that the election of Le Pen could, you know, destabilize the NATO Alliance or make it difficult, being that she&#8217;s, you know, come up with pro-Russian statements?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m just not going to get ahead of an election in a foreign country.&nbsp; And obviously, we will watch it closely, and I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have more to speak to once the results are concluded.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; What can you tell us about the multiple Secret Service agents who have been suspended or removed from the President, Vice President, and First Lady&#8217;s detail pending this investigation of two men impersonating officers of law enforcement?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not much from here.&nbsp; I can point you to the Secret Service.&nbsp; And obviously, the FBI is overseeing the investigation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a broader concern in the administration that these principals &#8212; is there concern that they&#8217;re not being protected effectively?&nbsp; Is &#8212; can you speak at all to that?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As I said, yesterday, we &#8212; the President remains confident in the leader of the Secret Service.&nbsp; And beyond that, I would point you to the Secret Service and to the FBI.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, I guess, just on the invitations you issued to Republicans who voted to confirm Justice Jackson.&nbsp; I know one of them has COVID, but did you hear from the other two &#8212; Senator Murkowski and Romney?&nbsp; I know the President went a little further to talk about Senator Romney&#8217;s father today in his speech.&nbsp; Did the White House hear from the Republicans who were invited today?&nbsp; Why didn’t they come?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would point you to their offices to speak to that.&nbsp; I mean, it doesn&#8217;t change the President&#8217;s gratitude to them for, you know, bucking the trend in their party of not supporting an <a></a></p>



<p>eminently qualified nominee.&nbsp; And they &#8212; they did that, and it was something he wanted to call out today and express his gratitude.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering what the White House&#8217;s reaction is to yesterday&#8217;s U.N. vote to suspend Russia from the U.N. Human Rights Council &#8212; the fact that there were 58 nations that abstained from taking a vote and then on top of the other 24 nations that voted against it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although there was, you know, more &#8212; obviously, the majority of countries did vote to suspend Russia, do you think that this &#8212; you know, that many abstains &#8212; abstentions, that many people sitting on the sidelines of this shows that the entire world really isn&#8217;t unified around condemning these actions by Russia?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, a win required two thirds present and voting, and that is exactly what happened, and far beyond that.&nbsp; And we know that there were abstentions.&nbsp; And only 24 countries, including North Korea, voted with Russia.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the outcome, which is what is most important to us, is what we wanted, which is Russia has been suspended from the U.N. Human Rights Council.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Suspension &#8212; just so everybody knows; somebody asked me this question the other day &#8212; but it is the only method provided for in the U.N. resolution that established the Human Rights Council back in 2005 &#8212; is the most serious action available.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s only been applied once in history.&nbsp; This is only the second time in history that a country has been kicked out of the U.N. Human Rights Council.&nbsp; The last example was Libya.&nbsp; So that obviously speaks to the significance.&nbsp; And it also speaks to the fact that two thirds &#8212; more than two thirds of countries who are members are &#8212; believe that they should not have a leadership role on global human rights as they work to subvert and violate global human rights.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This also means that, once suspended, Russia will not be able to vote against future actions during subsequent Human Rights Council sessions.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, to us, it is significant &#8212; only the secs [sic] time &#8212; second time in second time in history.&nbsp; And it speaks to the global outrage in response to these atrocities.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But are there any concerns that nearly 60 nations decided not to weigh in on this matter?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, our focus is on the fact that it was a win.&nbsp; For only the second time in history was a country kicked out of &#8212; suspended from the U.N. Human Rights Council.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one other question: Does President Biden still intend to attend the White House Correspondents Association dinner here later this month, in a couple of weeks?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t announced his plans to attend or anything about his schedule, so I don&#8217;t have any update on that today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just some follow-ups to things that came up.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on Peter’s question about the testing cadence &#8212; you guys have told us about negative tests on Monday, Wednesday, and Friday.&nbsp; Should we expect that the President would get tested on Sunday, two days later?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say I don&#8217;t have a prediction of that.&nbsp; His doctor makes an assessment of when he should be tested and how often and what the cadence should be.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not always exactly the same.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we will provide information to you when he tests negative &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; or either way, of course.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to follow up on Katie&#8217;s question: Did the President talk to any of the senators &#8212; Romney, Murkowski, and Collins &#8212; after their vote yesterday on Ketanji Brown Jackson?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on that from here.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And when he said he hoped he didn&#8217;t get them in trouble today when he referenced them, what did he mean by that?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He meant he recognizes that the vast majority of the other members of their party voted a different way.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On India: Next week, Secretary of State Blinken and Defense Secretary are hosting their Indian counterparts &#8212; External Affairs Minister S. Jaishankar and Defence Minister Rajnath Singh &#8212; for the first India-U.S. 2+2 dialogue under this administration.&nbsp; What is President’s message to the meeting?&nbsp; What is his expectations?&nbsp; Is he sending any concrete ideas to this meeting as well?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden believes our partnership with India is one of the most important relationships we have in the world.&nbsp; As you know, he met with Presi- &#8212; Prime Minister Modi and other Quad leaders in March.&nbsp; He expects that at this 2+2, Secretary Blinken and Secretary Austin will continue driving forward our work with India and our shared goals in the Indo-Pacific region and around the world.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also believe both sides will continue our close consultations on the consequences of President Putin&#8217;s brutal war against Ukraine and mitigating the impact by addressing energy and food prices.&nbsp; Obviously, it could cover a range of topics, but we expect that to be a central one.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And secondly, given the U.S.’s frustrating experience having the U.N. Security Council (inaudible) coming out and doing all they should do with Ukraine, what is President’s thoughts on the reforms to the U.N. Security Council itself?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know a question has been asked about whether Russia could be kicked out of being a permanent member; we don&#8217;t anticipate that happening.&nbsp; But obviously, the step taken yesterday to suspend Russia from the U.N. Human Rights Council is an indication of the global response and horror at the atrocities we&#8217;ve seen happen on the ground in Ukraine.&nbsp; But beyond that, I don&#8217;t have any other predictions of reforms.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should there be individual veto or group veto inside the Security Council?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I understand your questions, but I don&#8217;t have any predictions or calls for that at this point.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead, Francesca.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, we&#8217;ll just do a few more.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Since his State of the Union Address, the President has only made a handful of domestic trips.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked in here before about how he&#8217;d like to get back into the community and have a chance to interact with the American people.&nbsp; Is the current COVID wave getting in the way of his travel plans?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; I expect he&#8217;s going to travel a bunch in the next few weeks.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And you had mentioned that you will be going to North Carolina and you didn&#8217;t have too much more to add on that.&nbsp; But might the President, while he&#8217;s in Greensboro, be visiting one of the area’s two Historically Black Colleges and Universities?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more details at this point in time.&nbsp; As they get finalized, I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll share them with all of you.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I have a two-part question on student loans.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, President Biden directed the Department of Education to create a report on whether he has presidential authority to unilaterally do a broad cancellation of debt.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe that&#8217;s ever been made public.&nbsp; And as you&#8217;re looking at loan extensions &#8212; or loan pause extensions, will we &#8212; can we anticipate seeing a release of that report?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And secondly, as &#8212; you&#8217;ve talked about how the President wants to lower costs for Americans.&nbsp; Borrowers have expressed stress, anxiety about these short-term extensions.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your message to them?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think our message to them is that not a single person has paid a dime on their student loans since the President took office.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s continued to evaluate and assess with the Department of Education and other policymakers in the administration what the needs are to lower costs for people, including people who have student loans and are &#8212; do feel stressed, even as the economy is continuing to recover but as we see costs too high in some areas.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the first question, I don&#8217;t have any update on that.&nbsp; I would tell you that if Congress were to send him a bill to cancel $10,000 in student loans &#8212; in student debt, he&#8217;d be happy to sign it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp; Last one.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, Rachel Wallace, who was the general counsel of the science office who the White House found had been bullied by Dr. Lander, has been told that she will not be getting her job back as general counsel.&nbsp; Why?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I am not aware of this personnel update.&nbsp; I&#8217;d have to check on it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that.&nbsp; And we will get you back a comment.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Then a follow-up: Yesterday, you said &#8212; when asked about Vice President Harris and the mask at the Senate &#8212; you said that she would follow CDC protocols at the event today.&nbsp; CDC protocols clearly say you should be wearing a mask.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t distinguish between outside and inside.&nbsp; So why didn&#8217;t she wear a mask?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And she was socially distanced for the vast majority of the event today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She was sitting &#8212; standing next to the President.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; About six feet away.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.</p>



<p> 3:19 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 6968 and H.R.&#160;7108</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/04/08/bills-signed-h-r-6968-and-h-r-7108/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 21:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, April 8, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 6968, the &#8220;Ending Importation of Russian Oil Act,&#8221; which statutorily prohibits the importation of energy products from the Russian Federation; and H.R. 7108, the &#8220;Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act,&#8221; which suspends normal trade relations with the Russian Federation and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, April 8, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 6968, the &#8220;Ending Importation of Russian Oil Act,&#8221; which statutorily prohibits the importation of energy products from the Russian Federation; and</p>



<p>H.R. 7108, the &#8220;Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act,&#8221; which suspends normal trade relations with the Russian Federation and the Republic of Belarus and seeks to further leverage trade and human rights sanctions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>IPEC Annual Intellectual Property Report to&#160;Congress</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/08/ipec-annual-intellectual-property-report-to-congress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 20:25:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Office of the Intellectual Property Enforcement Coordinator (IPEC) has issued its Annual Intellectual Property Report to Congress, which brings together the combined and coordinated efforts of the White House, the Departments of Agriculture, Commerce, Defense, Health and Human Services, Homeland Security, State, and Treasury, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the U.S.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Office of the Intellectual Property Enforcement Coordinator (IPEC) has issued its <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/FY21-IPEC-Annual-Report-Final.pdf">Annual Intellectual Property Report to Congress</a>, which brings together the combined and coordinated efforts of the White House, the Departments of Agriculture, Commerce, Defense, Health and Human Services, Homeland Security, State, and Treasury, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative, and the U.S. Copyright Office. The report provides an overview of the intellectual property enforcement strategy and related efforts undertaken by departments and agencies during fiscal year 2021.</p>



<p>To view the Annual Intellectual Property Report to Congress, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/FY21-IPEC-Annual-Report-Final.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/FY21-IPEC-Annual-Report-Final.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
