<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 21:02:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>January 2022 Visitor Log Records&#160;Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2022/05/04/january-2022-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Disclosures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in January 2022. This set includes 1185 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 42597. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in January 2022. This set includes 1185 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 42597.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Day of Prayer,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/04/a-proclamation-on-national-day-of-prayer-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 20:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout our history, prayer has been an anchor for countless Americans searching for strength and wisdom in times of struggle and sharing hope and gratitude in seasons of joy. &#160;In public reflections on life&#8217;s many blessings and in quiet moments during life&#8217;s most difficult trials, Americans of nearly every background and faith have turned to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Throughout our history, prayer has been an anchor for countless Americans searching for strength and wisdom in times of struggle and sharing hope and gratitude in seasons of joy. &nbsp;In public reflections on life&#8217;s many blessings and in quiet moments during life&#8217;s most difficult trials, Americans of nearly every background and faith have turned to prayer for comfort and inspiration.&nbsp; Prayer is a sacred right protected by free speech and religious liberty enshrined in our Constitution, and it continues to lift our spirits as we navigate the challenges of&nbsp;our time.<br><br>On this day, we recognize the healing power of prayer, especially as we recover from the trauma and loss of the COVID‑19 pandemic.&nbsp; Today we find ourselves in a moment of renewal &#8212; of lives saved, of new jobs created, and of new hope for rebuilding America.&nbsp; Today is also a moment of reflection when we are called to address some of the greatest challenges humanity has ever faced &#8212; saving our planet from the existential threat of climate change; responding to attacks on democracy at home and abroad; and living up to our Nation&#8217;s promise of liberty, justice, and equality for all.<br><br>As the late President Dwight D. Eisenhower once said, &#8220;There is a need we all have in these days and times for some help which comes from outside ourselves.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp;Across our diverse and cherished beliefs, on this National Day of Prayer, no matter how or whether we pray, we are all called to look outside ourselves.&nbsp;&nbsp;Let us find in our hearts and prayers the determination to put aside our differences, come together, and truly see one another as fellow Americans.<br><br>The Congress, by Public Law 100-307, as amended, has called on the President to issue each year a proclamation designating the first Thursday in May as a &#8220;National Day of Prayer.&#8221;<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 5, 2022, as a National Day of Prayer.&nbsp; I&nbsp;call upon the citizens of our Nation to give thanks, in accordance with their own faiths and consciences, for our many freedoms and blessings, and I invite all people of faith to join me in asking for God&#8217;s continued guidance, mercy, and protection.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fourth day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Missing Or Murdered Indigenous Persons Awareness Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/04/a-proclamation-on-missing-or-murdered-indigenous-persons-awareness-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 20:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For generations, Indigenous persons, including American Indians, Alaska Natives and Native Hawaiians, have been forced to mourn a missing or murdered loved one without the answers and support they deserve.  On Missing or Murdered Indigenous Persons Awareness Day, we remember these victims and their families, and commit to working with Tribal Nations and Native communities to achieve&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>     For generations, Indigenous persons, including American Indians, Alaska Natives and Native Hawaiians, have been forced to mourn a missing or murdered loved one without the answers and support they deserve.  On Missing or Murdered Indigenous Persons Awareness Day, we remember these victims and their families, and commit to working with Tribal Nations and Native communities to achieve justice and healing.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Federal Government has an obligation to ensure that cases of missing or murdered persons are met with swift and&nbsp;effective action.&nbsp;&nbsp;My Administration is fully committed to investigating and resolving these cases through a coordinated law enforcement response, as well as intervention and prevention efforts.&nbsp;&nbsp;We are also dedicated to researching the underlying causes of this violence and to working with Native communities to address them.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The safety and well-being of all Native Americans continues to be a top priority for my Administration.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is why during my first year in office, at the first White House Tribal Nations Summit, I issued an Executive Order directing Federal agencies to improve public safety and criminal justice for Native Americans and to address the crisis of missing or murdered Indigenous people.&nbsp;&nbsp;This includes&nbsp;implementing a coordinated Federal law enforcement strategy that supports Tribal and other local law enforcement efforts.&nbsp;&nbsp;It also strengthens prevention, early intervention, and survivor services while improving&nbsp;data collection, analysis, and information sharing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;For far too long, justice for Indigenous communities has&nbsp;been elusive.&nbsp;&nbsp;We must improve our investigations to resolve missing or murdered cases while supporting victims and their families.&nbsp;&nbsp;Toward that aim, the Department of Justice is working closely with Tribal Nations to develop regionally appropriate guidelines for these cases.&nbsp;&nbsp;The&nbsp;Department of Justice has created a dedicated steering committee to oversee and coordinate this critical work, including an outreach services liaison for Federal criminal cases in Indian Country.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;This March, I signed into law the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022.&nbsp;&nbsp;This important law expands special criminal jurisdiction of Tribal courts to cover non-Native perpetrators of sexual assault, child abuse, stalking, sex trafficking, and assaults on Tribal law enforcement officers on Tribal lands and supports the development of a pilot project to enhance access to safety for survivors in Alaska Native villages.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;My Administration understands that Native people, particularly survivors of violence, know best what their communities need to feel safe.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is why we must work hand in&nbsp;hand with Tribal partners through each phase of the justice system to create solutions that are victim-centered, trauma-informed, and culturally appropriate.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Our Nation&#8217;s failure to address this ongoing tragedy not&nbsp;only demeans the dignity of each Indigenous person who goes missing or is murdered &#8212; it undermines the humanity of us all.&nbsp;&nbsp;Today and every day, we must continue to stand up for Indigenous people, and we must never forget the thousands of unsolved cases that continue to cry out for justice and healing.&nbsp;&nbsp;As a Nation, we must answer that call and work together to achieve the promise of America for all Americans.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim May 5, 2022, as Missing or Murdered Indigenous Persons Awareness Day.&nbsp;&nbsp;I call on all Americans and ask all levels of government to support Tribal governments and Tribal communities&#8217; efforts to increase awareness of the issue of missing or murdered Indigenous persons through appropriate programs and activities.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fourth day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at TEAM USA Olympic and Paralympic Athletes&#160;Visit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/04/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-team-usa-olympic-and-paralympic-athletes-visit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 19:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The White House 11:43 A.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY:  Thank you so much.  And I &#8212; I would like to say thank you to the band, who has been playing since 8:30 this morning.  Can we say thank you?  (Applause.) So, hello, Olympians and Paralympians.  Welcome to the White House!  (Applause.) Doug and I were&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The White House</p>



<p>11:43 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:  Thank you so much.  And I &#8212; I would like to say thank you to the band, who has been playing since 8:30 this morning.  Can we say thank you?  (Applause.)<br><br>So, hello, Olympians and Paralympians.  Welcome to the White House!  (Applause.)<br><br>Doug and I were so grateful to see your Games in Japan.  And Tokyo was the first time I had the opportunity to see a three-on-three women’s basketball game, and I was on the edge of my seat the whole time.  It was everything I love about sports.<br><br>Oh, you guys can sit down.  (Laughter.)<br><br>I&#8217;ll start again: It was everything I love about sports &#8212; the moment when the team shows to &#8212; seems to know each other’s thoughts; the air is electric with that connection; when the crowd is breathing with one breath, our hearts racing to the rhythm of each thump of the ball; every basket pure joy.<br><br>As I watched Stefanie, Allisha, Kelsey, and Jackie on &#8212; fly back and forth on that court, only one thing mattered to the crowd: We were all Team USA.  (Applause.)<br><br>That’s the power of what all of you do.  You don’t just play a game, run a race, hit a target, or win a competition. With every step, jump, roll, kick, and twirl, you show us the heights of our human potential.  You show us how to fail and then get back up.  You teach us that hard work and sacrifice and determination can push us beyond what we ever thought was in our reach.<br><br>When we cheer you on, we are more than our cities or our states or our backgrounds.  We are a part of something bigger than ourselves.  You help us believe in the impossible and leave our differences behind.<br><br>Now, I know that these games may not have been exactly as you once imagined &#8212; with stadiums packed with people and all of your loved ones screaming from the sidelines.<br><br>But you are all champions just the same.  (Applause.)  Becoming an Olympian or a Paralympian is a rare accomplishment in a normal time, but you did it during a global pandemic.  You are forever one of the most elite, most celebrated athletes in this world.<br><br>I hope that you are proud of everything you have accomplished, because we all are.  We are so proud of you.  (Applause.)<br><br>And we are grateful for the gifts you’ve given us: the hope, the joy, the unity &#8212; and, most of all, the chance to see you soar.<br><br>Thank you.  (Applause.)  <br><br>And now, an even greater fan of Team USA, my husband, our President, Joe Biden.  (Applause.)<br><br>                        END                11:47 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Appointments to the  President’s Intelligence Advisory Board and the National Science&#160;Board</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/04/president-biden-announces-appointments-to-the-presidents-intelligence-advisory-board-and-the-national-science-board/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 19:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Admiral James A. “Sandy” Winnefeld, Jr., USN (Ret.), Chair, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board  Gilman G. Louie, Member, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board Secretary Janet A. Napolitano, Member, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board Ambassador Richard R. Verma, Member, President’s Intelligence&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Admiral James A. “Sandy” Winnefeld, Jr., USN (Ret.), Chair, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board </li></ul>



<ul><li>Gilman G. Louie, Member, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board</li></ul>



<ul><li>Secretary Janet A. Napolitano, Member, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board</li></ul>



<ul><li>Ambassador Richard R. Verma, Member, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board</li></ul>



<ul><li>Dr. Victor R. McCrary, Jr., Member, National Science Board</li></ul>



<ul><li>Dr. Julia M. Phillips, Member, National Science Board</li></ul>



<p>The President&#8217;s Intelligence Advisory Board is an independent element within the Executive Office of the President. The President’s Intelligence Advisory Board exists exclusively to assist the President by providing the President with an independent source of advice on the effectiveness with which the Intelligence Community is meeting the nation’s intelligence needs and the vigor and insight with which the community plans for the future. The President is able to appoint up to 16 members of the Board.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The National Science Board establishes the policies of the National Science Foundation (NSF) and serves as advisor to Congress and the President. The Board approves major NSF awards, provides congressional testimony and issues statements relevant to the nation’s science and engineering enterprise. The President is able to appoint up to 24 members to the Board, each for a term of six years.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>President’s Intelligence Advisory Board</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Admiral James A. “Sandy” Winnefeld, Jr., USN (Ret.), Chair, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Admiral Winnefeld graduated from Georgia Tech with a degree in Aerospace Engineering and served for 37 years in the United States Navy. He flew the F-14 Tomcat, and served as an instructor at TOPGUN and as senior aide-de-camp to General Colin L. Powell. He commanded a fighter squadron, the amphibious ship USS CLEVELAND, the aircraft carrier USS ENTERPRISE, a carrier strike group, two NATO commands, the United States SIXTH Fleet, United States NORTHERN Command, and the North American Aerospace Defense Command. He retired after serving as the ninth Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. Admiral Winnefeld is a frequently published author and a director or advisor to companies operating in a broad spectrum of business sectors. He co-founded SAFEProject.US, a national nonprofit committed to helping reverse the epidemic of drug overdose fatalities in the United States.</p>



<p><strong>Gilman G. Louie, Member, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board</strong></p>



<p>Gilman Louie is Chief Executive Officer and Co-Founder of America’s Frontier Fund, the public private partnership created to ensure that America leads the next wave of technology innovation. As the early CEO of In-Q-Tel, Louie has over 30 years of national security and investment experience, serving as an advisor to the Defense Innovation Board and as Commissioner to both the National Security Commission on Artificial Intelligence (NSCAI) and the National Commission for Review of Research and Development Programs of the United States Intelligence Community. He is co-founder of Alsop Louie Partners and Chairman of LookingGlass Cyber Solutions, Chairman of the Board of Visitors of National Intelligence University, and the Chairman of the Federation of American Scientists. His awards include CIA Agency Seal Medallions and the CIA Director’s Award. Louie received his B.S. from San Francisco State University.</p>



<p><strong>Secretary Janet A. Napolitano, Member, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board</strong></p>



<p>Janet Napolitano is a Professor of Public Policy at the Goldman School of Public Policy and the Founder and Faculty Director of the Center for Security in Politics at UC Berkeley. She served as the twentieth president of the University of California, the nation’s largest public research university with ten campuses, five medical centers, three affiliated national laboratories, and a statewide agriculture and natural resources program. Prior to joining the University of California, Professor Napolitano served as Secretary of Homeland Security from 2009 to 2013. She is a former two-term Governor of Arizona, a former Attorney General of Arizona, and a former U.S. Attorney for the District of Arizona. In 2019, Napolitano published&nbsp;<em>How Safe Are We? Homeland Security Since 9/11</em>. Professor Napolitano earned her B.S. degree, summa cum laude, in Political Science from Santa Clara University and her J.D. from the University of Virginia. She is based in Berkeley, CA.</p>



<p><strong>Ambassador Richard R. Verma, Member, President’s Intelligence Advisory Board</strong></p>



<p>Richard Verma is the General Counsel and Head of Global Public Policy for Mastercard.&nbsp;&nbsp;In this role, he oversees the company’s law and policy functions in the United States and around the world. He previously served as the U.S. Ambassador to India, where he led one of the largest U.S. diplomatic missions and championed historic progress in bilateral ties. Verma is a former Assistant Secretary of State and the former National Security Advisor to the Senate Majority Leader. Verma is a veteran of the U.S. Air Force, and the recipient of numerous military awards and civilian decorations, including the Meritorious Service Medal and the State Department’s Distinguished Service Award. He was a member of the WMD and Terrorism Commission, and he currently serves on a number of boards including the Ford Foundation, Lehigh University and the National Endowment for Democracy. Verma is a Senior Fellow at Harvard University’s Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs, and he holds multiple academic degrees, including his doctorate (Ph.D.) from Georgetown University and his law degree (J.D.) from American University.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>National Science Board</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Dr. Victor R. McCrary, Jr., Member,&nbsp;</strong><strong>National Science Board</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Victor R. McCrary is the Vice President for Research and Graduate Programs at the University of the District of Columbia, where his team leads the growth, development, oversight and strategic direction of the University’s research enterprise. He has held similar research leadership positions at the Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics Laboratory, Morgan State University, and the University of Tennessee. He has received numerous honors and awards including co-recipient of the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Gold Medal in 2000 for the development of the first global electronic book industry standards and the 2002 Percy Julian Award by the National Organization of Black Chemists and Chemical Engineers. In 2011, he was honored as Scientist of the Year by the Annual Black Engineer of the Year Award (BEYA) STEM Conference. In 2016, President Barack Obama appointed Dr. McCrary to serve on the National Science Board. As a member of the Board, Dr. McCrary chaired a task force which recently produced the report “The Skilled Technical Workforce: Crafting America’s Science and Engineering Enterprise.” In 2020, he was elected Vice-Chair of the Board.</p>



<p><strong>Dr. Julia M. Phillips, Member,&nbsp;</strong><strong>National Science Board</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Julia Phillips is a materials physicist. She retired in 2015 from Sandia National Laboratories in Albuquerque, New Mexico and is currently Executive Emeritus. As Vice President and Chief Technology Officer at Sandia, she managed the Laboratory’s $160 million Laboratory Directed Research and Development Program. She was also responsible for research strategy development, implementation and intellectual property protection and deployment. Her previous roles at Sandia include Vice President of Research and Chief Technology Officer (2013-2014). Prior to that, she was a member of the technical staff and a manager at AT&amp;T Bell Laboratories from 1981 to 1995. She is a member of the National Academy of Engineering and a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Dr. Phillips received a B.S. from William &amp; Mary and a Ph.D. from Yale University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Team USA Olympic and Paralympic Athletes&#160;Visit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/04/remarks-by-president-biden-at-team-usa-olympic-and-paralympic-athletes-visit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 18:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52407</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 11:47 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you.&#160; Thank you, Jilly. You know, as the guy who heads up the Veterans Affairs for America &#8212; the big guy standing there &#8212; please sit down, guys &#8212; knows, I&#8217;m glad the Lord didn&#8217;t come down and give me a choice between being President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>11:47 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jilly.</p>



<p>You know, as the guy who heads up the Veterans Affairs for America &#8212; the big guy standing there &#8212; please sit down, guys &#8212; knows, I&#8217;m glad the Lord didn&#8217;t come down and give me a choice between being President and an Olympian.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I &#8212; I had all those Walter Mitty dreams, you know.&nbsp; And they weren&#8217;t about being President; they were about being a great athlete.&nbsp; I thought I was, you know, in high school and college.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But I tell you what, you all are incredible.&nbsp; You&#8217;re absolutely incredible.&nbsp; Welcome to the White House.&nbsp; Welcome to the White House.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; This is your house.&nbsp; This is the People&#8217;s House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Bidens are a big sports family, and we love watching the Olympics.&nbsp; And Jill came home from Tokyo &#8212; all she could do was talk about you all constantly.&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And we know that, no matter the results, we wanted to honor you here at the White House.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going &#8212; and I&#8217;m sorry you had to wait that year between the time it was set and the time to go.&nbsp; I mean, you&#8217;ve been through so damn &#8212; darn much.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; You&#8217;ve been through so much.</p>



<p>Six hundred American Olympians and Paralympians from the Summer Games in Tokyo and the Winter Games in Beijing.&nbsp; Athletes from all across America, from all kinds of backgrounds &#8212; including 18 veterans of the United States Armed Forces who are here today.&nbsp; They&#8217;re here today.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And more than 260 medals across a dozen sports, weighing a million pounds.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thanks for letting me hold those medals, man.&nbsp; It made me feel important for a second.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; They are something else.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>We also know the pride your families felt and how hard it was for them and for you that they couldn’t be there in person with you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our favorite part of the Olympics &#8212; Jill and my family &#8212; was watching your families watch you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking &#8212; watching your families watch you, learning about who you are.&nbsp; Because we learn about how big and diverse and talented &#8212; how great this nation is, just how diverse we are.</p>



<p>The pandemic made training and competing especially difficult and draining.&nbsp; But you did it.&nbsp; You all did it.&nbsp; And we were in awe not just of your incredible athleticism but your endurance and your state of mind &#8212; but most of all your character.&nbsp; You all have such incredible character.</p>



<p>No matter what event you compete in, you draw inspiration from your work &#8212; your hard work, your courage, your discipline as you watch it &#8212; as we watch you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m serious.</p>



<p>Whether you&#8217;re a would-be athlete like me or you&#8217;ve never played a sport &#8212; I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; You&#8217;re just &#8212; I &#8212; look at you.&nbsp; Look how you handle victory and defeat.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just astounding.&nbsp; Astounding.</p>



<p>And as I was saying to a couple of the Paralympians, you inspire people.&nbsp; You inspire people around the world.&nbsp; You inspire them to pursue &#8212; to pursue their hopes and their dreams not just in sport but in life.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve had kids come up to me and say, &#8220;Did you see?&nbsp; Did you see?&nbsp; I think I can.&#8221;&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; You all know it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s real.</p>



<p>There are people you’ll never meet who witnessed how hard you competed, trained, and pushed yourself.&nbsp;&nbsp; And you helped them believe in themselves.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve helped them believe that they can do things that, &#8220;Maybe, maybe &#8212; just maybe I can.&#8221;</p>



<p>They look at you and see that despite the emotional, mental, and financial, and physical toll, you&#8217;ve never gave up.&nbsp;&nbsp; You just don&#8217;t quit.</p>



<p>As I said to our foreign leaders &#8212; my counterparts: There&#8217;s no quit in America.&nbsp; There&#8217;s just no quit.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re the quintessential example of that.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no quit in America.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The power of your example gives so many people strength to never give up as well.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It particularly matters today.&nbsp; Because of the pandemic, so much turmoil has occurred.&nbsp; So many people are dealing with problems, particularly little kids, in terms of health, mental health problems, and the like.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve given people so much hope.</p>



<p>In you, I see who we are as a nation.&nbsp; The only nar- &#8212; nation in the world that can be defined by one word &#8212; one word. I was asked when I was in the Tibetan Plateau with Xi Jinping &#8212; and he looked at me.&nbsp; We had just &#8212; I had a simultaneous interpreter, and he had one.&nbsp; And he looked at me and he said, “Can you define America for me?”&nbsp; It&#8217;s a true story; it’s been published all over the world by now.&nbsp; And I said, “Yes, I can, in one word: possibilities.”</p>



<p>We believe: In America, anything is possible.&nbsp; And you are the explanation of what we mean.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You are &#8212; it’s all about possibility, breaking limits.&nbsp; You represent the very soul of America, and that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; You genuinely do.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve been told this a thousand times since you&#8217;ve been home when the people talk to you and tell you about what they thought when they were watching you.</p>



<p>You know, and as sports does like few things, you helped us unite the nation.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been a very divided nation philosophically of late, but you brought us together.&nbsp; For no matter the divisions, when we see you compete, we feel a common pride in those three letters: U-S-A.&nbsp; I mean that.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a common pride.&nbsp; It crosses all political spectrums.</p>



<p>You know, through the lows and the highs and the tears and the joy, we were with you every moment &#8212; with all of you &#8212; whether it was your first time competing or the culmination of your career.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank you for showing what we can do together as one America and one Team USA.&nbsp; And now &#8212; now it&#8217;s my honor to introduce one of our amazing athletes, Elana Meyers Taylor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Hometown: Douglasville, Georgia.&nbsp; Her dad, a star football player at the Naval Academy before becoming a Marine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like so many of you, she grew up playing sports: college softball here in D.C. at G.W. &#8212; George Washington University &#8212; as a pitcher and a shortstop.&nbsp; She came close to making the Olympic Softball Team, but never gave up on her Olympic dream.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the 2002 Winter Games in Salt Lake, she watched the American bobsledder Vonetta Flowers become the first Black athlete to win a gold medal at a Winter Games.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And this is what I mean by inspiration.&nbsp; With her mom and her dad’s support, she switched sports, trained hard.&nbsp; You know she&#8217;s devoted &#8212; she even married a bobsledder.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trained harder after becoming a mom.&nbsp; And after a silver and bronze in Beijing, she became the most decorated woman to ever compete in Olympic bobsled and the most decorated Black athlete in the Winter Olympics history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And she dedicated her medals to her beautiful baby boy, Nico.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She carried our flag during the Closing Ceremonies.&nbsp; Today, she&#8217;s here to represent her fellow Olympians and our country at the White House.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Elana, the podium is yours.&nbsp; You earned it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p> 11:55 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden On Economic Growth, Jobs, and Deficit&#160;Reduction</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/04/remarks-by-president-biden-on-economic-growth-jobs-and-deficit-reduction/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 17:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 11:01 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good afternoon.&#160; Before I begin, let me tell you, I’ll be around to answer questions on a lot of things, but I got 600 Olympians waiting out there for me.&#160; If you keep me too long, they’ll rush the place.&#160; And &#8212; all kidding aside, I &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>11:01 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good afternoon.&nbsp; Before I begin, let me tell you, I’ll be around to answer questions on a lot of things, but I got 600 Olympians waiting out there for me.&nbsp; If you keep me too long, they’ll rush the place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; all kidding aside, I &#8212; this week, my administration released new information that contains that we’re on track to cut the federal deficit by another &#8212; another $1.5 trillion by the end of this fiscal year &#8212; the biggest decline in a single year ever in American history.&nbsp; And the biggest decline on top of us having a $350 billion drop in the deficit last year, my first year as President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also learned that for the first time since 2016, the Treasury Department is planning to pay down the national debt issued to the public this quarter.&nbsp; And for all the talk that Republicans make about deficits, it didn’t happen a single quarter under my predecessor.&nbsp; Not once.</p>



<p>The bottom line is the deficit went up every year under my predecessor, before the pandemic and during the pandemic.&nbsp; And it’s gone down both years since I’ve been here &#8212; period.&nbsp; That’s &#8212; they’re the facts.</p>



<p>And why is it important?  Because bringing down the deficit is one way to ease inflationary pressures in an economy where a consequence of a war and gas prices and oil and food and &#8212; it all &#8212; it’s just a different world right this moment because of Ukraine and Russia.  We reduce federal borrowing and we help combat inflation. </p>



<p>This <s>process</s> [progress] is a great deal &#8212; is good news, but it didn’t happen by itself.&nbsp; The previous administration increased the deficit every year it was in office, in part because of its reckless $2 trillion tax cut.&nbsp; I know you’re tired of hearing me saying that, but a $2 trillion tax cut that was not paid for.&nbsp; Was not paid for.&nbsp; And a tax cut that largely benefited the biggest corporations &#8212; 55 of which earned $40 billion in profits and paid not a single penny in income tax in 2020 &#8212; and wealthiest Americans, like the billionaires who on average pay just 8 percent in federal taxes.</p>



<p>The previous administration not only ballooned the deficit, it undermined the watchdogs, the inspector generals, whose job it was to keep the pandemic relief funds from being wasted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, at the time, I kept saying they’re going fire this &#8212; the inspector generals.&nbsp; Well, they fired the inspector general.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in my administration, those watchdogs are back.&nbsp; The Justice Department has a chief prosecutor for pandemic fraud who is going to go after the criminals who stole billions &#8212; billions in relief money meant for small businesses and American families but never got to them &#8212; got in the pockets of criminals.</p>



<p>When I came to office, we took a different approach across the board.&nbsp; With the American Rescue Plan and other actions, we started to grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out: rescue checks and tax cuts for working families that gave them just a little bit of breathing room and put food on the table and a roof over their heads. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember the first year &#8212; all those long lines of automobiles lined up and going through a parking lot just to get a box of food in their trunk?&nbsp; Those &#8212; all that &#8212; we put &#8212; we got vaccine shots in arms that helped us go from 2 million Americans who had been vaccinated to more than 220 million Americans fully vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we made it easier for millions of Americans to sign up for coverage under the Affordable Care Act, saving them an average of $2,400 a year.</p>



<p>As a result of these and other economic recovery plans, we recovered faster than projected. &nbsp;A record 6.7 million jobs created last year &#8212; the most in the first year of any president in American history, and the fastest economic growth in any year in nearly four decades.&nbsp; And, looking ahead, I have a plan to reduce the deficit even more, which will help reduce inflationary pressures and lower everyone&#8217;s costs for families.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, it’s a plan that lets Medicare negotiate the price of prescription drugs, as they do with the Department of Veterans Affairs.&nbsp; We can cap the price of insulin at $35 instead of the hundreds of dollars or even $1,000 a month for some families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And my plan provides tax credits to utility companies to generate clean energy and those companies are required to pass those savings on to families.&nbsp; I met with about a dozen of those utility CEOs here in the White House, and they confirmed this plan will lower energy bills for families immediately.</p>



<p>My plan includes tax credits for consumers to purchase electric or fuel-cell vehicles, new or used, which will save the typical driver about $80 a month not having to pay for gas at the pump; tax credits for folks to buy solar panels and heat pumps and more efficient windows and doors for their homes &#8212; estimated savings: $500 per year on average.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we can do these things by making sure that no one earning less than $400,000 a year will pay a single penny more in federal taxes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All we’re asking is that the very wealthiest Americans and largest corporations begin to pay their fair share &#8212; at least part of their fair share.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve heard me say it before: I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; I believe you should be able to make as much as you legally can, but just pay your fair share.&nbsp; There’s no reason why a billionaire should be paying a lower tax rate than a teacher or a firefighter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that’s in sharp contrast to what today’s Republican Party is offering.&nbsp; And if I &#8212; and if they hadn’t put this in print, you&#8217;d think I was making it up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senator Rick Scott of Florida, a United States senator who is leading the Republican National Senatorial Campaign Committee, released what he calls the “Ultra-MAGA Agenda.”&nbsp; It&#8217;s a MAGA agenda all right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me tell you about this Ultra-MAGA Agenda.&nbsp; It’s extreme, as most MAGA things are.&nbsp; It will actually raise taxes on 75 million American families, over 95 percent of whom make less than $100,000 a year.</p>



<p><a>Among the hardest hit: working families, kids with folks.&nbsp;&nbsp; Imagine you&#8217;re a family of four and you don’t pay &#8212; you don’t make enough money to have federal taxes.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not technically &#8212; because you don’t &#8212; you don’t make enough money to pay them.&nbsp; You pay all your taxes, but you &#8212; you just don’t make enough.</a></p>



<p>And under this new plan, this tax plan &#8212; the Ultra-MAGA Agenda &#8212; while big corporations and billionaires are going to pay nothing more, the working-class folks are going to pay a hell of a lot more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it goes further than that.&nbsp; This extreme Republican agenda calls for Congress &#8212; now, this is &#8212; I&#8217;m not making this up either.&nbsp; You got to really think about this.&nbsp; It requires a vote if it were to pass.&nbsp; Every five years, the Congress would have to vote to reinstate or eliminate Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid.&nbsp; Social Security &#8212; something seniors have paid in for their whole life, and it has to be reauthorized?&nbsp; It has to be reauthorized every five years?</p>



<p>Look, again, it’s hard to make this up, but then again, it’s a MAGA agenda.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, meanwhile, millionaires and billionaires and corporations skate by.&nbsp; Imagine that.&nbsp; Just imagine that.&nbsp; I think it is truly outrageous.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve offered a different plan &#8212; a plan rooted in American values of fairness and decency.&nbsp; Wealthy folks and corporations will pay a little more.&nbsp; Billionaires will have to pay a minimum tax.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, most importantly, no one making less than $400,000 will pay a penny more in federal taxes.&nbsp; We’re going to protect and strengthen Social Security and Medicare, not put it on the block every five years.</p>



<p>Let me remind you again: I reduced the federal deficit.&nbsp; All the talk about the deficit from my Republican friends, I love it.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve reduced $350 billion in my first year in office.&nbsp; And we’re on track to reduce it by the end of September by another 1 trillion 500 billion dollars &#8212; the largest drop ever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don’t want to hear Republicans talk about deficits and their Ultra-MAGA Agenda.&nbsp; I want to hear about fairness.&nbsp; I want to hear about decency.&nbsp; I want to hear about help on ordinary people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bottom line is that, for decades, the trickle-down economics has failed as income inequity grew to historic levels under the Republicans &#8212; the MEGA [sic] Republicans &#8212; the MAGA Republicans &#8212; excuse me, I don’t want to mispronounce it.&nbsp; The MAGA Republicans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This &#8212; it’s time to grow the economy but from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; Because here’s the deal: When the poor have a ladder up and the middle class grows, the wealthy always do very well.&nbsp; They do very well.&nbsp; That’s what this is about.&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s what this is about: everybody doing better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I want you to understand: Again, first year, $350 billion reduction deficit; this year, a trillion-five.&nbsp; It’s going to bring some relief.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ll take a few questions quickly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, may I ask you &#8212; may I ask you a question about sanctions that the EU &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; About what?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About sanctions against &#8212; or about further sanctions in Europe.&nbsp; The European Union today announced new sanctions against oil against Russia.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the next round for the U.S.?</p>



<p>And also, on a separate issue, what&#8217;s the next step on abortion once this case gets settled?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No one asked about deficits, huh?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ve got one of those too.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You want to make sure this doesn’t get covered.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Here we go.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to answer those two questions and then go out to talk to the Olympians.&nbsp; With regard to the additional sanctions: We&#8217;re always open to additional sanctions, and I&#8217;ve been in consultation &#8212; I&#8217;ll be speaking with the members of the G7 this week about what we&#8217;re going to do or not do, number one.</p>



<p>Number two &#8212; what was the second one?&nbsp; You want &#8212; oh, look &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oil.&nbsp; And the second one was on abortion.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; As I said when I &#8212; when this hit, as I was getting on the plane to go down to Alabama, this is about a lot more than abortion.&nbsp; I haven’t &#8212; I hadn&#8217;t read the whole opinion at that time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this reminds me of the debate with Robert Bork.&nbsp; Bork believed the only reason you had any inherent rights was because the government gave them to you.&nbsp; If you go back and look at the opening comments from &#8212; by the Bork-Biden &#8212; when I was questioning him as chairman, I said, “I believe I have the rights that I have not because the government gave it to me, which you believe, but because I&#8217;m just a child of God; I exist.”&nbsp; I delegated, by joining this union here, to delegate some obligati- &#8212; some rights I have to the government for &#8212; for social good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the idea that somehow there is a inherent right &#8212; that there is no right of privacy, that there is no right &#8212; and remember the debate we &#8212; you don&#8217;t remember, but we had a debate about Griswold vs. Connecticut.&nbsp; There&#8217;d been a law saying a married couple could not purchase birth control in the privacy of their own bedroom and use it.&nbsp; Well, that got struck down.&nbsp; Griswold was thought to be a bad decision by Bork and I &#8212; my guess is the guys on the Supreme Court now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What happens if you have &#8212; a state changes the law saying that &#8212; that children who are LGBTQ can&#8217;t be in classrooms with other children?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that legit under the way the decision is written?&nbsp;</p>



<p>What are the next things that are going to be attacked? Because this MAGA crowd is really the most extreme political organization that&#8217;s existed in American history &#8212; in recent American history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p> 11:14 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on Shontel Brown’s Primary Victory in&#160;Ohio</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/04/statement-from-president-biden-on-shontel-browns-primary-victory-in-ohio/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shontel Brown’s primary victory last night was an important step forward toward building a better Ohio and a better America. I was proud to endorse Shontel in her primary bid for re-election because she has been a strong leader in Congress and a partner in the work to cut costs and create jobs. She is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Shontel Brown’s primary victory last night was an important step forward toward building a better Ohio and a better America. I was proud to endorse Shontel in her primary bid for re-election because she has been a strong leader in Congress and a partner in the work to cut costs and create jobs. She is focused on solutions that will matter most to Middle Class and working families, such as passing legislation like the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. I’m proud of Shontel and her demonstrated record of fighting for the people of Ohio, and I thank her for her continued work in service to the American people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Enhancing the National Quantum Initiative Advisory&#160;Committee</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/04/executive-order-on-enhancing-the-national-quantum-initiative-advisory-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 13:20:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 104(a) of the National Quantum Initiative Act (Public Law 115-368) (NQI Act), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code, and in order to ensure continued American leadership in quantum information science&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 104(a) of the National Quantum Initiative Act (Public Law 115-368) (NQI Act), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code, and in order to ensure continued American leadership in quantum information science and its technology applications, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Purpose.&nbsp; Quantum information science (QIS) can enable transformative advances in knowledge and technology for industry, academia, and government.&nbsp; Accordingly, the National Quantum Initiative (NQI), which aims to ensure the continued leadership of the United States in QIS and its technology applications, is a substantial and sustained national priority. &nbsp;The NQI Program, established pursuant to section 101 of the NQI Act, encompasses contributions from across the Federal Government, as exemplified by the QIS research, development, demonstration, and training activities pursued by executive departments and agencies (agencies) with membership on either the National Science and Technology Council (NSTC) Subcommittee on Quantum Information Science (SCQIS) or the NSTC Subcommittee on Economic and Security Implications of Quantum Science (ESIX).</p>



<p>Sec. 2. &nbsp;Establishment. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;To ensure that the NQI Program and the Nation are informed by evidence, data, and perspectives from a diverse group of experts and stakeholders, the National Quantum Initiative Advisory Committee (Committee) is hereby established. &nbsp;Consistent with the NQI Act, the Committee shall advise the President, the SCQIS, and the ESIX on the NQI Program.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Committee shall consist of the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (Director) or the Director&#8217;s designee and not more than 26 members, appointed by the President, who are United&nbsp;States citizens representative of industry, universities, and Federal laboratories, and who are qualified to provide advice and information on QIS and technology research, development, demonstrations, standards, education, technology transfer, commercial application, or national security and economic concerns.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The Committee shall have two Co-Chairs. &nbsp;The Director or the Director&#8217;s designee shall serve as one Co-Chair of the Committee. &nbsp;The President shall designate another Co-Chair from among the appointed members to serve as Co-Chair with the Director.</p>



<p>Sec. 3. &nbsp;Functions. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Committee shall advise the President and the SCQIS and the ESIX (Subcommittees) and make recommendations for the President to consider when reviewing and revising the NQI Program. &nbsp;The Committee shall also carry out all responsibilities set forth in section 104 of the NQI Act.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Committee shall meet at least twice a year and shall:</p>



<p>          (i)    respond to requests from the President or the Co-Chairs of the Committee for information, analysis, evaluation, or advice relating to QIS and its technology applications;</p>



<p>          (ii)   solicit information and ideas from a broad range of stakeholders on QIS, including the research community, the private sector, academia, national laboratories, agencies, State and local governments, foundations, and nonprofit organizations;</p>



<p>        (iii)  review the national strategy for QIS; and</p>



<p>          (iv)   respond to requests from the Subcommittees.</p>



<p>Sec. 4. &nbsp;Administration. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The heads of agencies shall, to the extent permitted by law, provide the Committee with information concerning QIS and its technology applications when requested by a Committee Co-Chair.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Co-Chairs of the Committee may establish standing subcommittees and ad hoc groups, including technical advisory groups, to assist and provide information to the Committee.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The Director may request that members of the Committee, standing subcommittees, or ad hoc groups who do not hold a current clearance for access to classified information receive appropriate clearances and access determinations pursuant to Executive Order 13526 of December 29, 2009 (Classified National Security Information), as amended, or any successor order.</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;The National Quantum Coordination Office shall provide technical and administrative support to the Committee, pursuant to section 102(b) of the NQI Act.</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;Committee members shall serve without any compensation for their work on the Committee, but may receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by law for persons serving intermittently in the Government service (5 U.S.C. 5701-5707).</p>



<p>Sec. 5. &nbsp;Revocation. &nbsp;Executive Order 13885 of August 30, 2019 (Establishing the National Quantum Initiative Advisory Committee), is hereby revoked.</p>



<p>Sec. 6. &nbsp;General Provisions. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Insofar as the Federal Advisory Committee Act, as amended (5 U.S.C. App.) (FACA), may apply to the Committee, any functions of the President under the FACA, except for those in section 6 of the FACA, shall be performed by the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Director, in accordance with the guidelines and procedures established by the Administrator of General Services.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May 4, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Security Memorandum on Promoting United&#160;States Leadership in Quantum Computing While Mitigating Risks to Vulnerable Cryptographic&#160;Systems</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/04/national-security-memorandum-on-promoting-united-states-leadership-in-quantum-computing-while-mitigating-risks-to-vulnerable-cryptographic-systems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 13:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATIONAL SECURITY MEMORANDUM/NSM-10 MEMORANDUM FOR THE VICE PRESIDENT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF STATE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE ATTORNEY GENERAL &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY                THE ASSISTANT&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NATIONAL SECURITY MEMORANDUM/NSM-10</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE VICE PRESIDENT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE ATTORNEY GENERAL</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY</p>



<p>               THE ASSISTANT TO THE PRESIDENT AND CHIEF OF STAFF</p>



<p>               THE DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF MANAGEMENT BUDGET</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE DIRECTOR OF NATIONAL INTELLIGENCE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE DIRECTOR OF THE CENTRAL INTELLIGENCE AGENCY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE ASSISTANT TO THE PRESIDENT FOR NATIONAL</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; SECURITY AFFAIRS</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE COUNSEL TO THE PRESIDENT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE ASSISTANT TO THE PRESIDENT FOR ECONOMIC</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; POLICY AND DIRECTOR OF THE NATIONAL ECONOMIC</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; COUNCIL</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF SCIENCE AND</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; TECHNOLOGY POLICY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE NATIONAL CYBER DIRECTOR</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE CHAIRMAN OF THE JOINT CHIEFS OF STAFF</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE DIRECTOR OF THE FEDERAL BUREAU OF</p>



<p>                 INVESTIGATION</p>



<p>                 THE DIRECTOR OF THE NATIONAL SECURITY AGENCY<br><br>                 THE DIRECTOR OF THE NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF<br><br>                 STANDARDS AND TECHNOLOGY<br><br>                 THE DIRECTOR OF THE CYBERSECURITY AND<br><br>                 INFRASTRUCTURE SECURITY AGENCY</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Promoting United States Leadership in Quantum</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Computing While Mitigating Risks to Vulnerable</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Cryptographic Systems</p>



<p>This memorandum outlines my Administration&#8217;s policies and initiatives related to quantum computing. &nbsp;It identifies key steps needed to maintain the Nation&#8217;s competitive advantage in quantum information science (QIS), while mitigating the risks of quantum computers to the Nation&#8217;s cyber, economic, and national security. &nbsp;It directs specific actions for agencies to take as the United States begins the multi-year process of migrating vulnerable computer systems to quantum-resistant cryptography. &nbsp;A classified annex to this memorandum addresses sensitive national security issues.</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Policy.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Quantum computers hold the potential to drive innovations across the American economy, from fields as diverse as materials science and pharmaceuticals to finance and energy. &nbsp;While the full range of applications of quantum computers is still unknown, it is nevertheless clear that America&#8217;s continued technological and scientific leadership will depend, at least in part, on the Nation&#8217;s ability to maintain a competitive advantage in quantum computing and QIS.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;Yet alongside its potential benefits, quantum computing also poses significant risks to the economic and national security of the United States. &nbsp;Most notably, a quantum computer of sufficient size and sophistication &#8212; also known as a cryptanalytically relevant quantum computer (CRQC) &#8212; will be capable of breaking much of the public-key cryptography used on digital systems across the United States and around the world. &nbsp;When it becomes available, a CRQC could jeopardize civilian and military communications, undermine supervisory and control systems for critical infrastructure, and defeat security protocols for most Internet-based financial transactions.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;In order to balance the competing opportunities and risks of quantum computers, it is the policy of my Administration: &nbsp;(1) to maintain United States leadership in QIS, through continued investment, partnerships, and a balanced approach to technology promotion and protection; and (2) to mitigate the threat of CRQCs through a timely and equitable transition of the Nation&#8217;s cryptographic systems to interoperable quantum‑resistant cryptography.</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;Additional guidance and directives may be required in the future as quantum computing technologies and their associated risks mature.</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Promoting United States Leadership.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The United States must pursue a whole-of-government and whole‑of‑society strategy to harness the economic and scientific benefits of QIS, and the security enhancements provided by quantum-resistant cryptography. &nbsp;This strategy will require a coordinated, proactive approach to QIS research and development (R&amp;D), an expansion of education and workforce programs, and a focus on developing and strengthening partnerships with industry, academic institutions, allies, and like-minded nations.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The United States must seek to encourage transformative and fundamental scientific discoveries through investments in core QIS research programs. &nbsp;Investments should target the discovery of new quantum applications, new approaches to quantum-component manufacturing, and advances in quantum‑enabling technologies, such as photonics, nanofabrication, and cryogenic and semiconductor systems.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The United States must seek to foster the next generation of scientists and engineers with quantum-relevant skill sets, including those relevant to quantum-resistant cryptography. &nbsp;Education in QIS and related cybersecurity principles should be incorporated into academic curricula at all levels of schooling to support the growth of a diverse domestic workforce. &nbsp;Furthermore, it is vital that we attract and retain talent and encourage career opportunities that keep quantum experts employed domestically.</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;To promote the development of quantum technology and the effective deployment of quantum-resistant cryptography, the&nbsp;United States must establish partnerships with industry; academia; and State, local, Tribal, and territorial (SLTT) governments. &nbsp;These partnerships should advance joint R&amp;D initiatives and streamline mechanisms for technology transfer between industry and government.</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;The United States must promote professional and academic collaborations with overseas allies and partners. &nbsp;This international engagement is essential for identifying and following global QIS trends and for harmonizing quantum security and protection programs.</p>



<p>(f) &nbsp;In support of these goals, within 90 days of the date of this memorandum, agencies that fund research in, develop, or acquire quantum computers shall coordinate with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to ensure a coherent national strategy for QIS promotion and technology protection, including for workforce issues.&nbsp; To facilitate this coordination, all such agencies shall identify a liaison to the National Quantum Coordination Office to share information and best practices, consistent with section 102(b)(3) of the National Quantum Initiative Act (Public Law 115-368) and section 6606 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (Public Law 117-81).&nbsp; All coordination efforts shall be undertaken with appropriate protections for sensitive and classified information and intelligence sources and methods.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; Mitigating the Risks to Encryption. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Any digital system that uses existing public standards for public‑key cryptography, or that is planning to transition to such cryptography, could be vulnerable to an attack by a CRQC. &nbsp;To mitigate this risk, the United States must prioritize the timely and equitable transition of cryptographic systems to quantum-resistant cryptography, with the goal of mitigating as much of the quantum risk as is feasible by 2035. &nbsp;Currently, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and the Director of the National Security Agency (NSA), in their capacity as the National Manager for National Security Systems (National Manager), are each developing technical standards for quantum‑resistant cryptography for their respective jurisdictions. &nbsp;The first sets of these standards are expected to be released publicly by 2024.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;Central to this migration effort will be an emphasis on cryptographic agility, both to reduce the time required to transition and to allow for seamless updates for future cryptographic standards. &nbsp;This effort is an imperative across all sectors of the United States economy, from government to critical infrastructure, commercial services to cloud providers, and everywhere else that vulnerable public-key cryptography is used.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;Consistent with these goals:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 90 days of the date of this memorandum, the Secretary of Commerce, through the Director of NIST, shall initiate an open working group with industry, including critical infrastructure owners and operators, and other stakeholders, as determined by the Director of NIST, to further advance adoption of quantum-resistant cryptography. &nbsp;This working group shall identify needed tools and data sets, and other considerations to inform the development by NIST of guidance and best practices to assist with quantum‑resistant cryptography planning and prioritization. &nbsp;Findings of this working group shall be provided, on an ongoing basis, to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (APNSA), and the National Cyber Director to incorporate into planning efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 90 days of the date of this memorandum, the Secretary of Commerce, through the Director of NIST, shall establish a &#8220;Migration to Post-Quantum Cryptography Project&#8221; at the National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence to work with the private sector to address cybersecurity challenges posed by the transition to quantum-resistant cryptography. &nbsp;This project shall develop programs for discovery and remediation of any system that does not use quantum-resistant cryptography or that remains dependent on vulnerable systems.</p>



<p>(iii) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this memorandum, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security, through the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), and in coordination with Sector Risk Management Agencies, shall engage with critical infrastructure and SLTT partners regarding the risks posed by quantum computers, and shall provide an annual report to the Director of OMB, the APNSA, and the National Cyber Director that includes recommendations for accelerating those entities&#8217; migration to quantum-resistant cryptography.</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this memorandum, and on an ongoing basis, the Director of OMB, in consultation with the Director of CISA, the Director of NIST, the National Cyber Director, and the Director of NSA, shall establish requirements for inventorying all currently deployed cryptographic systems, excluding National Security Systems (NSS). &nbsp;These requirements shall include a list of key information technology (IT) assets to prioritize, interim benchmarks, and a common (and preferably automated) assessment process for evaluating progress on quantum-resistant cryptographic migration in IT systems.</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 1 year of the date of this memorandum, and on an annual basis thereafter, the heads of all Federal Civilian Executive Branch (FCEB) Agencies shall deliver to the Director of CISA and the National Cyber Director an inventory of their IT systems that remain vulnerable to CRQCs, with a particular focus on High Value Assets and High Impact Systems. &nbsp;Inventories should include current cryptographic methods used on IT systems, including system administrator protocols, non-security software and firmware that require upgraded digital signatures, and information on other key assets.</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;By October 18, 2023, and on an annual basis thereafter, the National Cyber Director shall, based on the inventories described in subsection 3(c)(v) of this memorandum and in coordination with the Director of CISA and the Director of NIST, deliver a status report to the APNSA and the Director of OMB on progress made by FCEB Agencies on their migration of non-NSS IT systems to quantum-resistant cryptography. &nbsp;This status report shall include an assessment of the funding necessary to secure vulnerable IT systems from the threat posed by adversarial access to quantum computers, a description and analysis of ongoing coordination efforts, and a strategy and timeline for meeting proposed milestones.</p>



<p>(vii) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 90 days of the release of the first set of NIST standards for quantum-resistant cryptography referenced in subsection 3(a) of this memorandum, and&nbsp;on an annual basis thereafter, as needed, the Secretary of Commerce, through the Director of NIST, shall release a proposed timeline for the deprecation of quantum-vulnerable cryptography in standards, with the goal of moving the maximum number of systems off quantum-vulnerable cryptography within a decade of the publication of the initial set of standards. &nbsp;The Director of NIST shall work with the appropriate technical standards bodies to encourage interoperability of commercial cryptographic approaches.</p>



<p>(viii) &nbsp;Within 1 year of the release of the first set of NIST standards for quantum-resistant cryptography referenced in subsection 3(a) of this memorandum, the Director of OMB, in coordination with the Director of CISA and the Director of NIST, shall issue a policy memorandum requiring FCEB Agencies to develop a plan to upgrade their non-NSS IT systems to quantum-resistant cryptography. &nbsp;These plans shall be expeditiously developed and be designed to address the most significant risks first. &nbsp;The Director of OMB shall work with the head of each FCEB Agency to estimate the costs to upgrade vulnerable systems beyond already planned expenditures, ensure that each plan is coordinated and shared among relevant agencies to assess interoperability between solutions, and coordinate with the National Cyber Director to ensure plans are updated accordingly.</p>



<p>(ix) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Until the release of the first set of NIST standards for quantum-resistant cryptography referenced in subsection 3(a) of this memorandum, the heads of FCEB Agencies shall not procure any commercial quantum-resistant cryptographic solutions for use in IT systems supporting enterprise and mission operations. &nbsp;However, to assist with anticipating potential compatibility issues, the heads of such FCEB Agencies should conduct tests of commercial solutions that have implemented pre-standardized quantum-resistant cryptographic algorithms. &nbsp;These tests will help identify interoperability or performance issues that may occur in Federal environments at an early stage and will contribute to the mitigation of those issues. &nbsp;The heads of such FCEB Agencies should continue to implement and, where needed, upgrade existing cryptographic implementations, but should transition to quantum-resistant cryptography only once the first set of NIST standards for quantum-resistant cryptography is complete and implemented in commercial products. &nbsp;Conformance with international standards should be encouraged, and may be required for interoperability.</p>



<p>(x) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 1 year of the date of this memorandum, and annually thereafter, the Director of NSA, serving in its capacity as the National Manager, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Director of National Intelligence, shall provide guidance on quantum-resistant cryptography migration, implementation, and oversight for NSS. &nbsp;This guidance shall be consistent with National Security Memorandum/NSM-8 (Improving the Cybersecurity of National Security, Department of Defense, and Intelligence Community Systems). &nbsp;The National Manager shall share best practices and lessons learned with the Director of OMB and the National Cyber Director, as appropriate.</p>



<p>(xi) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 1 year of the date of this memorandum, and on an ongoing basis, and consistent with section 1 of NSM-8, the heads of agencies operating NSS shall identify and document all instances where quantum-vulnerable cryptography is used by NSS and shall provide this information to the National Manager.</p>



<p>(xii) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of issuance by the National Manager of its standards on quantum-resistant cryptography referenced in section 3(a) of this memorandum, and annually thereafter, the National Manager shall release an official timeline for the deprecation of vulnerable cryptography in NSS, until the migration to quantum-resistant cryptography is completed.</p>



<p>(xiii) &nbsp;Within 1 year of issuance by the National Manager of its standards on quantum-resistant cryptography for referenced in subsection 3(a) of this memorandum, and annually thereafter, the heads of agencies operating or maintaining NSS shall submit to the National Manager, and, as appropriate, the Department of Defense Chief Information Officer or the Intelligence Community Chief Information Officer, depending on their respective jurisdictions, an initial plan to transition to quantum‑resistant cryptography in all NSS. &nbsp;These plans shall be updated annually and shall include relevant milestones, schedules, authorities, impediments, funding requirements, and exceptions authorized by the head of the agency in accordance with section 3 of NSM-8 and guidance from the National Manager. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(xiv) &nbsp;&nbsp;By December 31, 2023, agencies maintaining NSS shall implement symmetric-key protections (e.g., High Assurance Internet Protocol Encryptor (HAIPE) exclusion keys or VPN symmetric key solutions) to provide additional protection for quantum-vulnerable key exchanges, where appropriate and in consultation with the National Manager. &nbsp;Implementation should seek to avoid interference with interoperability or other cryptographic modernization efforts.</p>



<p>(xv) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;By December 31, 2023, the Secretary of Defense shall deliver to the APNSA and the Director of OMB an assessment of the risks of quantum computing to the defense industrial base and to defense supply chains, along with a plan to engage with key commercial entities to upgrade their IT systems to achieve quantum resistance.</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; Protecting United States Technology. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;In addition to promoting quantum leadership and mitigating the risks of CRQCs, the United States Government must work to safeguard relevant quantum R&amp;D and intellectual property (IP) and to protect relevant enabling technologies and materials. &nbsp;Protection mechanisms will vary, but may include counterintelligence measures, well-targeted export controls, and campaigns to educate industry and academia on the threat of cybercrime and IP theft.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;All agencies responsible for either promoting or protecting QIS and related technologies should understand the security implications of adversarial use and consider those security implications when implementing new policies, programs, and projects.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The United States should ensure the protection of U.S.‑developed quantum technologies from theft by our adversaries. &nbsp;This will require campaigns to educate industry, academia, and SLTT partners on the threat of IP theft and on the importance of strong compliance, insider threat detection, and cybersecurity programs for quantum technologies. &nbsp;As appropriate, Federal law enforcement agencies and other relevant agencies should investigate and prosecute actors who engage in the theft of quantum trade secrets or who violate United States export control laws. &nbsp;To support efforts to safeguard sensitive information, Federal law enforcement agencies should exchange relevant threat information with agencies responsible for developing and promoting quantum technologies. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;Consistent with these goals, by December 31, 2022, the heads of agencies that fund research in, develop, or acquire quantum computers or related QIS technologies shall develop comprehensive technology protection plans to safeguard QIS R&amp;D, acquisition, and user access. &nbsp;Plans shall be coordinated across agencies, including with Federal law enforcement, to safeguard quantum computing R&amp;D and IP, acquisition, and user access. &nbsp;These plans shall be updated annually and provided to the APNSA, the Director of OMB, and the Co-Chairs of the National Science and Technology Council Subcommittee on Economic and Security Implications of Quantum Science.</p>



<p>Sec. 5.&nbsp; Definitions.&nbsp; For purposes of this memorandum:</p>



<p>(a) &nbsp;the term &#8220;agency&#8221; has the meaning ascribed to it under 44 U.S.C. 3502;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;the term &#8220;critical infrastructure&#8221; means systems and assets, whether physical or virtual, so vital to the United&nbsp;States that their incapacitation or destruction would have a debilitating effect on the Nation&#8217;s security, economy, public health and safety, or any combination thereof;</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;the term &#8220;cryptographic agility&#8221; means a design feature that enables future updates to cryptographic algorithms and standards without the need to modify or replace the surrounding infrastructure;</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;the term &#8220;cryptanalytically relevant quantum computer&#8221; or &#8220;CRQC&#8221; means a quantum computer capable of undermining current public-key cryptographic algorithms;</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;the term &#8220;Federal Civilian Executive Branch Agency&#8221; or &#8220;FCEB Agency&#8221; means any agency except the Department of Defense or agencies in the Intelligence Community;</p>



<p>(f) &nbsp;the term &#8220;high value asset&#8221; means information or an information system that is so critical to an organization that the loss or corruption of this information, or loss of access to the system, would have serious impacts on the organization&#8217;s ability to perform its mission or conduct business;</p>



<p>(g) &nbsp;the term &#8220;high impact system&#8221; means an information system in which at least one security objective (i.e., confidentiality, integrity, or availability) is assigned a Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) 199 potential impact value of &#8220;high&#8221;;</p>



<p>(h) &nbsp;the term &#8220;information technology&#8221; or &#8220;IT&#8221; has the meaning ascribed to it under 44 U.S.C. 3502;</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;the term &#8220;National Security Systems&#8221; or &#8220;NSS&#8221; has the meaning ascribed to it in 44 U.S.C 3552(b)(6) and shall also include other Department of Defense and Intelligence Community systems, as described in 44 U.S.C. 3553(e)(2) and 44 U.S.C.&nbsp;3553(e)(3);</p>



<p>(j) &nbsp;the term &#8220;quantum computer&#8221; means a computer utilizing the collective properties of quantum states, such as superposition, interference and entanglement, to perform calculations. &nbsp;The foundations in quantum physics give a quantum computer the ability to solve a subset of hard mathematical problems at a much faster rate than a classical (i.e., non‑quantum) computer;</p>



<p>(k) &nbsp;the term &#8220;quantum information sciences&#8221; or &#8220;QIS&#8221; has the meaning ascribed to it under 15 U.S.C. 8801(6) and means the study and application of the laws of quantum physics for the storage, transmission, manipulation, computing, or measurement of information; and</p>



<p>(l) &nbsp;the term &#8220;quantum-resistant cryptography&#8221; means those cryptographic algorithms or methods that are assessed not to be specifically vulnerable to attack by either a CRQC or classical computer. &nbsp;This is also referred to as post-quantum cryptography.</p>



<p>Sec. 6.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof, to include the protection of intelligence sources and methods; or</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of OMB relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;This memorandum shall also be implemented without impeding the conduct or support of intelligence activities, and all implementation measures shall be designed to be consistent with appropriate protections for sensitive information and intelligence sources and methods.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
