<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:53:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Administration Announces Additional Actions to Help Kids Go Back to School&#160;Safely</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-biden-administration-announces-additional-actions-to-help-kids-go-back-to-school-safely/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the next six weeks, more than 50 million students will head back to school, and more than 20 million students will return to undergraduate and graduate studies. For young people, getting vaccinated right away is the best way back to the things they love – like playing sports, completing their studies, and spending time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Over the next six weeks, more than 50 million students will head back to school, and more than 20 million students will return to undergraduate and graduate studies. For young people, getting vaccinated right away is the best way back to the things they love – like playing sports, completing their studies, and spending time with friends and loved ones. Today, the Biden Administration announced additional actions to get students ages 12 and above vaccinated and to ensure all students can go back to school safely this fall:<br><br>Today, the Administration is highlighting the following efforts to get more young people vaccinated:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Incorporating COVID-19 vaccination into sports physicals for student athletes this summer and fall</strong>: Today, the American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP), the American Medical Society for Sports Medicine (AMSSM), and ten other sports and medicine organizations are issuing a consensus statement to all their members urging all medical providers to ask about COVID-19 vaccine status during sports physicals, and where available to also administer the COVID-19 vaccine. Both AAP and AMSSM have issued updated guidance for physicians incorporating COVID-19 vaccination into sports physical protocols, and AAP has issued revised forms for doctors, parents, and student athletes to use to document their pre-participation examination including language on COVID-19 vaccination. The AAP estimates that approximately 60 to 70 percent of children and adolescents participate in organized sports across the country. Each year, millions of these student athletes receive a pre-participation exam, also known as a sports physical, in order to participate. This action will help elevate the importance of getting vaccinated against COVID-19 as a key part of safe competitive play. The organizations signing onto the consensus statement are:<br></li><li>American Academy of Pediatrics</li><li>American Academy of Family Physicians</li><li>American Academy of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</li><li>American College of Emergency Physicians</li><li>American College of Sports Medicine</li><li>American Medical Society for Sports Medicine</li><li>American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine</li><li>American Osteopathic Academy of Sports Medicine</li><li>National Athletic Trainers’ Association</li><li>National Federation of State High School Associations</li><li>National Collegiate Athletic Association</li><li>U.S. Olympic &amp; Paralympic Committee<br></li><li><strong>Sending pediatricians to ‘Back to School Nights’ to get communities vaccinated against COVID-19</strong>: The National Parent Teacher Association (PTA) is calling on its 22,000 local member PTAs and parent leaders nationwide to host community conversations about getting vaccinated at Back to School parent meetings this summer and fall. National PTA will partner with the American Academy of Pediatrics to deploy local pediatricians to be a part of these Back to School parent meetings, so parents can have their questions answered by doctors who know and treat their children. AAP will also produce digital materials on the vaccine and kids that parent leaders can use as they convene community conversations. Alongside other trusted partners like teachers and school nurses, pediatricians around the country have been active in showing up to parent meetings and other events this summer to talk about the vaccine and how to keep kids safe in school this fall.<br></li><li><strong>Providing schools and colleges with additional resources to host pop-up vaccine clinics as students come back to school and back to campus</strong>: In an effort to get more kids 12 and older vaccinated, last week President Biden called on school districts nationwide to host at least one pop-up vaccination clinic over the coming weeks, and the Administration directed pharmacies in the federal pharmacy program to work with school districts and colleges across the country to host vaccination clinics on-site. Today, the Administration will release additional resources to help schools host pop-up vaccine clinics, including a detailed guide for hosting school-based clinics, template letters and text messages for district and school leaders to use in sending messages home to students and families about the vaccine, resources for teachers to use in discussing the vaccine with students and their parents, and materials parent leaders can use as part of community conversations on the vaccine. The Administration also released a “Vax to School” College Checklist, detailing eight ways that colleges and universities can increase awareness of and access to the vaccine as students come back to campus – building off of the work of the nearly 900 colleges in the COVID-19 College Challenge who have committed to building vaccination rates on their campuses this summer and fall. The American Rescue Plan has provided billions of dollars that school districts and institutions of higher education can use to create awareness and build vaccine confidence, host vaccine clinics, and provide incentives such as paid time off for staff to get vaccinated.<br></li><li><strong>Launching the Back to School “Week of Action”&nbsp;with partners nationwide to get young people vaccinated: </strong>Beginning August 7th and ending August 15th, the Health and Human Services’ We Can Do This campaign and Made to Save are launching a Week of Action to encourage vaccinations for young people and support parents and schools as they get kids back to safe, in-person learning.&nbsp; The Week of Action will mobilize school districts, students, teachers, national organizations, local government leaders, businesses, social media influencers, celebrities, and thousands of volunteers to kick off the school year by encouraging young people to get vaccinated and offering accessible ways to do it in their community. More than 90 youth-based organizations, faith-based organizations, and schools are committed to hosting over 200 vaccination events focused on school and campus-based COVID-19 vaccination drives for students, their families, and their communities, with hundreds more events taking place throughout the month of August. Events will take place all over the country, including canvassing, phone banks, text banks and more. As part of the Week of Action, Second Gentleman Douglas Emhoff and Education Secretary Miguel Cardona will travel to Topeka, KS to visit a back-to-school vaccine clinic; and trainings will be provided for teachers, parents, and student organizations on how to engage young people and their families on the vaccine. To kick off the Back to School Week of Action, the Second Gentleman and National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases Director Dr. Anthony Fauci will host a virtual discussion with youth leaders who expanded access to the vaccine for young people and their communities. The Second Gentleman and Dr. Fauci will ask the young leaders about why they got involved in vaccine efforts, and how they have responded to the needs of their peers and their communities in getting more young people vaccinated. The virtual event will be livestreamed on the White House YouTube channel.<br></li></ul>



<p>Today’s announcements build on the Administration’s release earlier this week of the “Return to School Roadmap,” a resource to support students, schools, educators, and communities as they prepare to return to safe, healthy in-person learning this fall and emerge from the pandemic stronger than before. The Roadmap provides key resources and supports for students, parents, educators, and school communities to build excitement around returning to classrooms this school year and outlines how federal funding can support the safe and sustained return to in-person learning. Over the course of the next several weeks as schools reopen nationwide, the Roadmap will lay out actionable strategies to implement the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s (CDC) updated guidance for K-12 schools, so that schools can minimize transmission and sustain in-person learning all school-year long.<br><br>The Roadmap includes three “Landmark” priorities that schools, districts, and communities are encouraged to focus on to ensure all students are set up for success in the 2021-2022 school year. These include: (1) prioritizing the health and safety of students, staff, and educators, (2) building school communities and supporting students’ social, emotional, and mental health, and (3) accelerating academic achievement. As part of the Roadmap, the Department will release resources for practitioners and parents on each of these priorities, and will highlight schools and districts that are using innovative practices to address these priorities. The Department will also lift up ways that the American Rescue Plan and other federal funds can be used to address these priorities in schools and communities across the country, as well as outline additional investments from President Biden’s Build Back Better agenda that are needed to ensure our schools and communities can rebuild from the pandemic even stronger than they were before and address inequities exacerbated by the pandemic, particularly for students in underserved communities.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Deferred Enforced Departure for Certain Hong Kong&#160;Residents</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-deferred-enforced-departure-for-certain-hong-kong-residents/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. signed a memorandum directing the deferral of removal of certain Hong Kong residents who are present in the United States, giving them a temporary safe haven. This action demonstrates President Biden’s strong support for people in Hong Kong in the face of ongoing repression by the People’s Republic of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. signed a memorandum directing the deferral of removal of certain Hong Kong residents who are present in the United States, giving them a temporary safe haven. This action demonstrates President Biden’s strong support for people in Hong Kong in the face of ongoing repression by the People’s Republic of China (PRC), and makes clear we will not stand idly by as the PRC breaks its promises to Hong Kong and to the international community. Since taking office, the Biden Administration has been clear that we, alongside our allies and partners, strongly oppose the PRC’s wielding of the National Security Law to deny basic rights and freedoms, assault Hong Kong’s autonomy, and undermine its remaining democratic processes and institutions. Given the politically motivated arrests and trials, the silencing of the media, and the diminishing the space for elections and democratic opposition, we will continue to take steps in support of people in Hong Kong.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Deferred Enforced Departure for Certain Hong Kong&#160;Residents</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/memorandum-on-the-deferred-enforced-departure-for-certain-hong-kong-residents/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 13:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY SUBJECT:       Deferred Enforced Departure for Certain Hong Kong Residents The United States supports the human rights and fundamental freedoms of the residents of Hong Kong.  Recognizing the significant erosion of those rights and freedoms in Hong Kong by the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC), I am&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE                                                                                                THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY<br><br>SUBJECT:       Deferred Enforced Departure for Certain Hong Kong Residents<br><br>The United States supports the human rights and fundamental freedoms of the residents of Hong Kong.  Recognizing the significant erosion of those rights and freedoms in Hong Kong by the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC), I am directing the deferral of removal of certain Hong Kong residents who are present in the United States.<br><br>By unilaterally imposing on Hong Kong the Law of the People&#8217;s Republic of China on Safeguarding National Security in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (NSL), the PRC has undermined the enjoyment of rights and freedoms in Hong Kong, including those protected under the Basic Law and the Sino-British Joint Declaration.  Since the imposition of the NSL in June 2020, Hong Kong police have continued a campaign of politically motivated arrests, taking into custody at least 100 opposition politicians, activists, and protesters on NSL-related charges including secession, subversion, terrorist activities, and collusion with a foreign country or external elements.  Over 10,000 individuals have been arrested for other charges in connection with anti-government protests.  Over the last year, the PRC has continued its assault on Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, undermining its remaining democratic processes and institutions, imposing limits on academic freedom, and cracking down on freedom of the press.  <br><br>There are compelling foreign policy reasons to defer enforced departure for Hong Kong residents presently in the United States.  The United States is committed to a foreign policy that unites our democratic values with our foreign policy goals, which is centered on the defense of democracy and the promotion of human rights around the world.  Offering safe haven for Hong Kong residents who have been deprived of their guaranteed freedoms in Hong Kong furthers United States interests in the region.  The United States will not waver in our support of people in Hong Kong.<br><br>Pursuant to my constitutional authority to conduct the foreign relations of the United States, I have determined that it is in the foreign policy interest of the United States to defer for 18 months the removal of any Hong Kong resident subject to the conditions and exceptions provided below.<br><br>Accordingly, I hereby direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to take appropriate measures to defer for 18 months the removal of any Hong Kong resident who is present in the United States on the date of this memorandum, except for those: <br><br>(1)  who have voluntarily returned to Hong Kong or the PRC after the date of this memorandum; <br><br>(2)  who have not continuously resided in the United States since the date of this memorandum; <br><br>(3)  who are inadmissible under section 212(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) (8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)) or deportable under section 237(a)(4) of the INA (8 U.S.C. 1227(a)(4)); <br><br>(4)  who have been convicted of any felony or two or more misdemeanors committed in the United States, or who meet any of the criteria set forth in section 208(b)(2)(A) of the INA (8 U.S.C. 1158(b)(2)(A));<br><br>(5)  who are subject to extradition; <br><br>(6)  whose presence in the United States the Secretary of Homeland Security has determined is not in the interest of the United States or presents a danger to public safety; or<br><br>(7)  whose presence in the United States the Secretary of State has reasonable grounds to believe would have potentially serious adverse foreign policy consequences for the United States. <br><br>I further direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to take appropriate measures to authorize employment for noncitizens whose removal has been deferred, as provided by this memorandum, for the duration of such deferral, and to consider suspending regulatory requirements with respect to F-1 nonimmigrant students who are Hong Kong residents as the Secretary of Homeland Security determines to be appropriate.<br><br>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Sixth Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/president-biden-names-sixth-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing three new candidates for the federal bench and one new nominee to the D.C. Court of Appeals, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing three new candidates for the federal bench and one new nominee to the D.C. Court of Appeals, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, this slate includes:</p>



<ul><li>A woman currently serving as Vermont’s first openly LGBT Supreme Court justice, who would also be the first openly LGBT woman to serve on any federal circuit court.</li><li>A woman who would be the first openly LGBT federal judge in Colorado and the first openly LGBT woman to serve as a federal district court judge in any state west of the Mississippi.</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s sixth round of names for federal judicial positions, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 35.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move at an unparalleled speed with respect to judicial nominations. His first judicial nominations announcement was made faster than that of any new President in modern American history, and today’s announcement continues that trend.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>CIRCUIT COURT</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Justice Beth Robinson: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit</strong><br></span><br>Justice Beth Robinson has served as an Associate Justice on the Vermont Supreme Court since 2011. Prior to her appointment, Justice Robinson served as counsel to Vermont Governor Peter Shumlin from 2010 to 2011. From 1993 to 2010, Justice Robinson was a civil litigator in private practice at Langrock Sperry &amp; Wool where she focused on civil litigation including employment law, workers’ compensation, contract disputes, and family law.&nbsp; She also represented LGBTQ+ individuals in civil and civil rights cases, including leading the freedom to marry movement in Vermont.&nbsp; From 1990 to 1991, Justice Robinson was an associate at Skadden, Arps, Slate, Meagher &amp; Flom in Washington, D.C., focusing on white-collar criminal defense. Justice Robinson served as a law clerk for Judge David B. Sentelle on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia from 1989 to 1990.<br><br>Justice Robinson received her J.D. from the University of Chicago Law School in 1989 and her B.A. from Dartmouth College in 1986.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>DISTRICT COURTS</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Judge Mary Katherine Dimke: Nominee for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Washington</strong><br></span><br>Judge Mary Katherine Dimke has served as a U.S. Magistrate Judge for the Eastern District of Washington since 2016. Prior to becoming a judge, she was an Assistant U.S. Attorney for the Eastern District of Washington from 2012 to 2016 and for the Western District of Washington from 2008 to 2012. Judge Dimke joined the U.S. Department of Justice through its Honors Program in 2004 where she served as an attorney in the Fraud Section of the Criminal Division in Washington, D.C. until 2007. Judge Dimke served as a law clerk for Judge Richard C. Tallman on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit in Seattle, Washington from 2003 to 2004. She also served as a law clerk for Judge Alan B. Johnson on the U.S. District Court for the District of Wyoming in Cheyenne from 2002 to 2003.<br><br>Judge Dimke received her J.D. from Vanderbilt University Law School in 2002 as a member of the Order of the Coif and her B.A.,&nbsp;<em>magna cum laude</em>, from Pepperdine University in 1999.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Charlotte Sweeney: Nominee for the United States District Court for the District of Colorado</strong><br></span><br>Charlotte Sweeney is currently a partner at Sweeney &amp; Bechtold, LLC, where she has practiced since 2008. Her law practice is devoted to representing individuals in employment law cases. Ms. Sweeney was previously a partner with LaFond &amp; Sweeney, LLC from 1999 to 2008 and LaFond &amp; Bove, LLC from 1997 from 1999. Ms. Sweeney began her career as an associate with LaFond &amp; Clausen, LLC in 1995 and was named a partner at the firm in 1998.<br><br>Ms. Sweeney received her J.D. from the University of Denver College of Law in 1995 and her B.S. from California Lutheran University in 1991.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>D.C. COURT OF APPEALS</u></strong></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>John P. Howard III: Nominee for the District of Columbia Court of Appeals</strong><br></span><br>Judge John P. Howard III currently serves as an Administrative Law Judge with the District of Columbia Office of Administrative Hearings. Prior to his appointment to the bench in 2018, Judge Howard served as an Administrative Law Judge with the District of Columbia Commission on Human Rights from 2014 to 2018, where he adjudicated discrimination claims in the areas of employment, housing, education, and public accommodations. From 2012 to 2014, Judge Howard practiced law as a solo practitioner and with a small firm, where he focused on civil litigation and family law. Judge Howard was previously an associate in the D.C. office of Akin, Gump, Strauss, Hauer &amp; Feld LLP from 2011 to 2012. Judge Howard served as a law clerk for Judge Alexander Williams, Jr. on the U.S. District Court for the District of Maryland, and for the Honorable David C. Simmons of the D.C. Commission on Human Rights in 2010.<br><br>Judge Howard received his J.D. from the Georgetown University Law Center in 2010 and his B.A. from Howard University in 2006.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statements on the Biden Administration’s Steps to Strengthen American Leadership on Clean Cars and&#160;Trucks</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/statements-on-the-biden-administrations-steps-to-strengthen-american-leadership-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, automakers, the United Autoworkers (UAW), and other leaders, released statements on the Biden Administration’s steps to strengthen American leadership on clean cars and trucks: Joint Statement of Ford, GM, and Stellantis:“Today, Ford, GM and Stellantis announce their shared aspiration to achieve sales of 40-50% of annual U.S. volumes of electric vehicles (battery electric, fuel&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, automakers, the United Autoworkers (UAW), and other leaders, released statements on the Biden Administration’s steps to strengthen American leadership on clean cars and trucks:<br><br><strong>Joint Statement of Ford, GM, and Stellantis:</strong><br>“Today, Ford, GM and Stellantis announce their shared aspiration to achieve sales of 40-50% of annual U.S. volumes of electric vehicles (battery electric, fuel cell and plug-in hybrid vehicles) by 2030 in order to move the nation closer to a zero-emissions future consistent with Paris climate goals.  Our recent product, technology, and investment announcements highlight our collective commitment to be leaders in the U.S. transition to electric vehicles.  This represents a dramatic shift from the U.S. market today that can be achieved only with the timely deployment of the full suite of electrification policies committed to by the Administration in the Build Back Better Plan, including purchase incentives, a comprehensive charging network of sufficient density to support the millions of vehicles these targets represent, investments in R&amp;D, and incentives to expand the electric vehicle manufacturing and supply chains in the United States.  With the UAW at our side in transforming the workforce and partnering with us on this journey, we believe we can strengthen continued American leadership in clean transportation technology through electric vehicle innovation and manufacturing.  We look forward to working with the Biden Administration, Congress and state and local governments to enact policies that will enable these ambitious objectives.”<br><br><strong>Statement of UAW President Ray Curry:</strong><br>“We are at a critical time for the auto industry as countries compete to build the vehicles of the future. We are falling behind China and Europe as manufacturers pour billions into growing their markets and expanding their manufacturing. We need to make investments here in the United States.  Fortunately, President Biden recognizes the importance of this moment, and his Build Back Better Plan makes the bold investments in manufacturing, consumer incentives, and infrastructure needed to ensure vehicles of the future are made in our country.  Investments alone are not enough.  Today’s announcement on emissions standards brings more certainty and better planning for the auto industry and UAW member future jobs.  While the UAW notes that the companies have made voluntary commitments on Electric Vehicles, the UAW focus is not on hard deadlines or percentages, but on preserving the wages and benefits that have been the heart and soul of the American middle class.<br><br>“We must be ambitious not just about retaining good union jobs, but growing them, and about expanding U.S. manufacturing of electric vehicles, from parts to assembly. It is incumbent that these future jobs will be good-paying American union scale wage and benefit jobs that protect salaries and our critical health and safety standards.  The members of the UAW, current and future, are ready to build these electric cars and trucks and the batteries that go in them. Our members are America’s secret weapon in winning this global race.  That is why, today we stand with the President and support his ambition not just to grow electric vehicles but also our capacity to produce them domestically with good wages and benefits and the right to bargain and urge Congress to seize this opportunity for the sake of working people and our country’s future.<br><br>“Any auto industry transition to alternative fueled engines must be paired with passage of the Stabenow Amendment and passage or an agreement to adhere to the policies of the PRO Act to ensure these jobs of the future will protect UAW members, their families, and our American middle class. The Senate needs to pass the PRO Act and get it to the President’s desk for signature.”<br><br><strong>Joint Statement of BMW, Ford, Honda, Volkswagen, and Volvo</strong><br>“We were proud to stand with California to establish progressive new greenhouse gas regulations, and we remain committed to leading the industry in fighting against climate change. That’s why we support the Administration’s goal of reaching an electric vehicle future and applaud President Biden’s leadership on reducing emissions and investing in critical infrastructure to achieve these reductions. While the California framework companies are driving towards 40-50% of our sales being EVs in the next nine years, bold action from our partners in the federal government is crucial to build consumer demand for electric vehicles and put us on track to achieve the global commitments of the Paris Climate Agreement. That includes a strong nationwide greenhouse gas emissions standard, continued investments in charging infrastructure, and broad consumer incentives for all electric vehicle purchases.”<br><br><strong>Statement of Alliance for Automotive Innovation President and CEO John Bozzella:</strong><br>“Auto manufacturers are committed to a net-zero carbon transportation future, and we look forward to working with the Administration as we evaluate EPA’s proposed changes to light-duty vehicle standards for Model Years 2023-2026.<br><br>“Collectively, the auto industry has committed to investing more than $330 billion to bring exciting new electric vehicles (EVs) to market, including plug-in hybrid, battery and fuel cell EVs. And we support stringent GHG and fuel economy standards that are aligned and encourage continued improvements. As we look beyond 2026, the industry’s shift to electrified cars, trucks and SUVs will drive significant GHG reductions to fight climate change and make a better world for future generations. With the right complementary policies in place, the auto industry is poised to accept the challenge of driving EV purchases to between 40 and 50 percent of new vehicle sales by the end of the decade. Federal and state governments—and all stakeholders—will need to provide significant support for consumers, infrastructure and innovation. The auto industry has stepped up—investments in electrification globally will exceed $330 billion by 2025. But all levels of government will need to do their part for this challenge to succeed.<br><br>“The U.S. needs to rapidly expand its charging and hydrogen fueling infrastructure, retool existing manufacturing facilities and build new ones, prepare and position our workforce to lead this transition, and provide consumer incentives to make these vehicles affordable and accessible to a wide range of customers. Future GHG rules aligned with industry investment, and supportive governmental policies will be essential to significantly reducing GHG emissions, while maintaining a vital U.S. auto manufacturing sector and the millions of jobs it supports. We urge the Biden Administration and policymakers to continue advancing measures that will support the broad and equitable consumer adoption of electric-drive vehicles and that align environmental progress, vehicle affordability, and U.S. economic competitiveness.”<br><br><strong>Statement of California Governor Gavin Newsom:</strong><br>&#8220;California applauds the Biden Administration’s move to boldly reduce climate pollution from cars, inspired by California’s nation-leading framework. The climate emergency demands no less. Today’s proposal will help to clean the air and create a healthier future for our children and our planet. We look forward to continuing our decades-long collaboration with federal partners to build on California’s clean car leadership and deliver the investments needed to support the nationwide build-out of clean vehicle infrastructure.&#8221;<br><br><strong>Statement of Julie Cerqueira, Executive Director, U.S. Climate Alliance:</strong><br>“Strong vehicle standards protect our communities from unnecessary air pollution and fuel costs, and address the largest source of greenhouse gas emissions in the U.S. There’s much more work to do, but these new proposed rules are a critical step forward and will benefit our health, economy, and planet. Our states have been driving the transition to clean cars for many years and we look forward to working with the administration and continuing to lead.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces Steps to Drive American Leadership Forward on Clean Cars and&#160;Trucks</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26081</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden Outlines Target of 50% Electric Vehicle Sales Share in 2030 to Unleash Full Economic Benefits of Build Back Better Agenda and Advance Smart Fuel Efficiency and Emission Standards President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal invest in the infrastructure, manufacturing, and incentives that we need to grow good-paying, union&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>President Biden Outlines Target of 50% Electric Vehicle Sales Share in 2030 to Unleash Full Economic Benefits of Build Back Better Agenda and Advance Smart Fuel Efficiency and Emission Standards</em></p>



<p>President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal invest in the infrastructure, manufacturing, and incentives that we need to grow good-paying, union jobs at home, lead on electric vehicles around the world, and save American consumers money. Today, the President will announce a set of new actions aimed at advancing these goals and increasing the impact of his proposed Build Back Better investments – positioning America to drive the electric vehicle future forward, outcompete China, and tackle the climate crisis.<br><br>Specifically, the President will sign an Executive Order that sets an ambitious new target to make half of all new vehicles sold in 2030 zero-emissions vehicles, including battery electric, plug-in hybrid electric, or fuel cell electric vehicles. The Executive Order also kicks off development of long-term fuel efficiency and emissions standards to save consumers money, cut pollution, boost public health, advance environmental justice, and tackle the climate crisis.<br><br>In addition, and consistent with the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/20/fact-sheet-president-elect-bidens-day-one-executive-actions-deliver-relief-for-families-across-america-amid-converging-crises/">Day One Executive Order</a>, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and U.S. Department of Transportation (USDOT) will announce how they are addressing the previous administration’s harmful rollbacks of near-term fuel efficiency and emissions standards. Through these coordinated notices of proposed rulemaking, the two agencies are advancing smart fuel efficiency and emissions standards that would deliver around $140 billion in net benefits over the life of the program, save about 200 billion gallons of gasoline, and reduce around two billion metric tons of carbon pollution. For the average consumer, this means net benefits of up to $900 over the life of the vehicle in fuel savings.<br><br>These new actions – paired with the investments in the President’s Build Back Better Agenda – will strengthen American leadership in clean cars and trucks by accelerating innovation and manufacturing in the auto sector, bolstering the auto sector domestic supply chain, and growing auto jobs with good pay and benefits. That is why today, American automakers Ford, GM, and Stellantis and the United Auto Workers (UAW), will stand with President Biden at the White House with aligned ambition: supporting the President’s Build Back Better Agenda and the automakers’ need to invest in and grow good-paying union jobs in the United States.<br><br><strong><em>Build Back Better Investment Agenda</em></strong><br><br>The global market is shifting to electric vehicles and tapping their potential to save families money, lower pollution, and make the air we breathe cleaner. Despite pioneering the technology, the U.S. is behind in the race to manufacture these vehicles and the batteries that go in them.&nbsp; Today, the U.S. market share of electric vehicle sales is only one-third that of the Chinese electric vehicle market. The President believes it is time for the U.S. to lead in electric vehicle manufacturing, infrastructure, and innovation, by investing in:</p>



<ul><li>Installing the first-ever national network of electric vehicle charging stations.</li><li>Delivering point-of-sale consumer incentives to spur U.S. manufacturing and union jobs.</li><li>Financing the retooling and expansion of the full domestic manufacturing supply chain.</li><li>Innovating the next generation of clean technologies to maintain our competitive edge.</li></ul>



<p>Through the investments in the Build Back Better Agenda and Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal, we can strengthen U.S. leadership in electric vehicles and batteries. These once-in-a-generation investments will position America to win the future of transportation and manufacturing and create good-paying, union jobs, dramatically expand American manufacturing, make electric vehicles more affordable for families, and export our electric vehicles around the world.<br><br>And, the President has already made a down payment on his vision for U.S. leadership in auto manufacturing. Last month, the Department of Commerce announced $3 billion in currently available American Rescue Plan funds that can be used to advance the domestic electric vehicle industry in communities that have historically been the backbone of our auto industry.<br><br><strong><em>Electric Vehicles Ambition for 2030</em></strong><br><br>Over the last decade, we have seen a transformation in the technology costs, performance, and availability of electric vehicles. Since 2010:</p>



<ul><li>Battery pack costs dropped by 85 percent, paving the way to sticker price parity with gasoline-powered vehicles.</li><li>Average vehicle range increased dramatically as charging times shortened.</li><li>Electric models available to U.S. consumers expanded to over 40 last year – and growing.</li></ul>



<p>Seeing this shift, countries are sprinting to lead. For example, China is increasingly cornering the global supply chain for electric vehicles and batteries with its fast-growing electric vehicle market. By setting clear targets for electric vehicle sale trajectories, these countries are becoming magnets for private investment into their manufacturing sectors – from parts and materials to final assembly. &nbsp;<br><br>President Biden is committed to changing that and delivering for the American people. That is why he will sign an Executive Order that sets a new target of electric vehicles representing half of new vehicles sold in 2030. This builds on the announcements today from automakers, representing nearly the entire U.S. auto market who have positioned around the goal of reaching 40 to 50 percent electric vehicle sales share in 2030. More than a deployment target, it is a goal to leverage once-in-generation investments and a whole-of-government effort to lift up the American autoworker and strengthen American leadership in clean cars and trucks. The 2030 target is calibrated to provide time for existing manufacturing facilities to upgrade without stranding assets, upgrades that will be catalyzed by the Build Back Better Agenda, and lean into a path that expands domestic U.S. manufacturing with union workers.<br><br><strong><em>Smart Fuel Efficiency and Emissions Standards&nbsp;</em></strong><br><br>Consistent with the President’s Day One Executive Order, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and U.S. Department of Transportation’s National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) will announce how they are addressing the previous administration’s harmful rollbacks of near-term fuel efficiency and emissions standards. The two agencies’ standards work in a compatible fashion through model year 2026, with the NHTSA proposed rule starting in model year 2024 and the EPA proposed rule taking effect a year sooner with model year 2023. &nbsp;The standards build on the momentum from “California Framework Agreement” – an agreement between the State of California and five automakers: Ford, Honda, Volkswagen Group, BMW, and Volvo.<br><br>Through these coordinated notices of proposed rulemaking, the two agencies are advancing smart fuel efficiency and emissions standards that would deliver around $140 billion in net benefits over the life of the standards, including asthma attacks avoided and lives saved, save about 200 billion gallons of gasoline, and reduce around two billion metric tons of carbon pollution. &nbsp;For the average consumer, this means net savings of up to $900 over the life of the vehicle from fuel savings.<br><br>Building on these near-term steps, the Executive Order that the President will sign kicks off development of long-term fuel efficiency and emissions standards to save consumers money, cut pollution, boost public health, advance environmental justice, and tackle the climate crisis.&nbsp; Specifically, the Executive Order lays out a robust schedule for development of fuel efficiency and multi-pollutant emissions standards through at least model year 2030 for light-duty vehicles and for medium- and heavy-duty vehicles starting as early as model year 2027. The Executive Order also directs agencies to:</p>



<ul><li>Consult with the Secretaries of Commerce, Labor, and Energy on ways to accelerate innovation and manufacturing in the automotive sector, to strengthen the domestic supply chain for that sector, and to grow jobs that provide good pay and benefits.&nbsp;</li><li>Engage with California and other states leading the way in reducing vehicle emissions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Secure input from a diverse range of stakeholders, including representatives from labor unions, industry, environmental justice organizations, and public health experts.</li></ul>



<p>Together, today’s announcements would put us on track to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from new passenger vehicle sales by more than 60 percent in 2030 compared to vehicles sold last year, and facilitate achieving the President’s goal of 50-52 percent net economy-wide greenhouse gas emission reductions below 2005 levels in 2030.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces 11 Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/president-biden-announces-11-key-nominations-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:55:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26067</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 11 individuals to serve in key roles: Biniam Gebre, Nominee for Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, Office of Management and Budget Andrew Fois, Nominee for Chair of the Administrative Conference of the United States Susan Tsui Grundmann, Nominee for Member of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following 11 individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Biniam Gebre, Nominee for Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Andrew Fois, Nominee for Chair of the Administrative Conference of the United States</li><li>Susan Tsui Grundmann, Nominee for Member of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</li><li>Kurt Rumsfeld, Nominee for General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</li><li>Javier Saade, Nominee for Chair of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</li><li>Dana Bilyeu, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</li><li>Leona Bridges, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</li><li>Stacey Olivares, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</li><li>Kathy Im, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</li><li>Tom Rothman, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</li><li>Elizabeth Sembler, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Biniam Gebre, Nominee for Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, Office of Management and Budget</u></strong></p>



<p>Biniam Gebre is a Senior Managing Director at Accenture and Head of Management Consulting for Accenture Federal Services. He has spent the past two decades helping dozens of organizations within both the public sector and private sector address management, operational, and technology issues ranging from agriculture to banking to artificial intelligence. He served in the Obama-Biden administration at the Department of Housing and Urban Development, where he focused on access to credit for low-income families, FHA’s financial health, and revitalizing public housing properties.</p>



<p>Gebre came to the United States as a refugee at the age of nine and grew up in public housing and on government assistance. He graduated with Highest Honors from Williams College, where he earned a B.A. in Chemistry and was a Goldwater Scholar. He also earned an M.B.A in Finance and Economics from Northwestern University. Gebre sits on the Board of Pathfinder International.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Andrew Fois, Nominee for Chair of the Administrative Conference of the United States</u></strong></p>



<p>Andrew Fois is an attorney with a 36-year legal career in public service, the non-profit sector, and private practice. He is an Attorney Advisor in the Office of Legislative Affairs in the Administrative Office of U.S. Courts. Prior to that position, he was the Deputy Attorney General for Public Safety in the Office of the Attorney General for Washington, D.C.&nbsp; In 2020, Mr. Fois was appointed by the Mayor to the D.C. Clemency Board.&nbsp; He has served at the Department of Justice on three occasions in five positions, including the Assistant Attorney General for Legislative Affairs and Assistant United States Attorney for the District of Columbia, where he prosecuted hundreds of cases.&nbsp; His experience on Capitol Hill includes service as the Chief Counsel of the House Judiciary Committee’s Subcommittee on Crime.&nbsp; He has worked for the National Crime Prevention Council as a solo practitioner and as a partner in the Venable law firm.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Fois also serves on the board of directors of the Catholic Coalition for Special Education.&nbsp; He has previously served on the boards of the Washington Regional Alcohol Program and the National Association of Children of Addiction. He served as Chairman of the D.C. Commission on Motor Vehicle Theft Prevention and the D.C. Coalition against Drugs and Violence.&nbsp; He has been a frequent author, legal adjunct professor and commentator on radio and television.&nbsp; He is active in his parish as a lector and Eucharistic Minister and was a founding member of the disabilities ministry and a member of the parish council.&nbsp; Mr. Fois earned his J.D. from the Georgetown University Law Center and his B.A. from Georgetown University.&nbsp; He also holds a master’s degree in American Government from the University of Essex in the U.K.&nbsp; He lives in Washington, D.C. with his wife and has two adult sons.</p>



<p><strong><u>Susan Tsui Grundmann, Nominee for Member of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</u></strong></p>



<p>Susan Tsui Grundmann currently serves as the Executive Director and Chief Operating Officer of the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights, where she oversees the administrative dispute resolution process and provides education to both employing offices and labor unions that represent employees in the legislative branch.&nbsp; Previously, she was nominated by President Obama to serve as a Member and Chairman of the MSPB.</p>



<p>Ms. Grundmann has served as General Counsel to the National Federation of Federal Employees (NFFE), which represents 100,000 Federal workers nationwide and is affiliated with the International Association of Machinist and Aerospace Workers. At NFFE, she successfully litigated cases in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia and the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia. She represented NFFE and the United Department of Defense Workers Coalition, which consists of 36 labor unions, and served on the Coalition’s litigation team in a coordinated response to proposed personnel changes at the Department of Defense (DoD). In addition to DoD employees, Ms. Grundmann represented employees in the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture, Passport Service, Veterans Administration, General Services Administration, and some 25 additional Federal agencies.</p>



<p>From 2003 to 2009, she was a regular instructor on Federal sector labor and employment law at the William W. Winpisinger Education and Technology Center in Hollywood, Maryland. Prior to joining NFFE, Ms. Grundmann served as General Counsel to the National Air Traffic Controllers Association. She began her legal career as a law clerk to the judges of the Nineteenth Judicial Circuit of Virginia, and later worked in both private practice and at the Sheet Metal Workers’ National Pension Fund. Chairman Grundmann earned her undergraduate degree at American University and her law degree at Georgetown University Law Center.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kurt Rumsfeld, Nominee for General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</u></strong></p>



<p>Kurt Rumsfeld is currently the Chief Counsel to Ernie DuBester, the Chairman of the Federal Labor Relations Authority.&nbsp; From September 2013 through February 2019, Mr. Rumsfeld served as the Assistant General Counsel for Operations and Legal Policy for the FLRA’s Office of General Counsel.&nbsp; His responsibilities in that role included assisting the General Counsel and Deputy General Counsel in managing the OGC’s regional operations and providing legal advice pertaining to the administration of the FLRA’s governing Statute.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before joining the FLRA, Mr. Rumsfeld practiced labor and employment law with a private law firm for over 17 years, and he began his career in labor law as an attorney-advisor with the U.S. Department of Labor.&nbsp;Mr. Rumsfeld received his B.A. in political science from Williams College, and his law degree from Northeastern University Law School.&nbsp; He also has an LL.M degree in Labor and Employment Law from Georgetown University Law Center.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Javier Saade, Nominee for Chair of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Javier E. Saade is a principled leader with three decades of broad experience as an investor, board member, founder, operating executive and economic policymaker. He served on the Biden Transition’s Agency Review Team for the Department of Treasury and served as Associate Administrator of Investment &amp; Innovation of the U.S. Small Business Administration during the Obama Administration. He led programs that, since their inception, have invested over $120 billion in hundreds of thousands of American small businesses that have created millions of jobs. Javier also served in the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commissions’ Advisory Committee on Small and Emerging Companies.</p>



<p>Javier is Managing Partner of Impact Master Holdings and Venture Partner at Fenway Summer. He has served on several corporate and non-profit boards. Prior to public service, he spent over twenty years in finance, management and advisory roles at organizations that include McKinsey &amp; Company, Booz Allen &amp; Hamilton, Bridgewater Associates and Abbott Laboratories. He holds an MBA from Harvard Business School, an MS in Operations &amp; Technology from Illinois Institute of Technology, and a BS in Industrial Management from Purdue University.</p>



<p>Javier grew up in Puerto Rico and resides with his family in Washington, DC.</p>



<p><strong><u>Dana Bilyeu, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Dana Bilyeu is the Executive Director of the National Association of State Retirement Administrators (NASRA) and has been in that role since 2013. Before joining NASRA, she served as the Executive Officer of the Public Employees&#8217; Retirement System of Nevada (2003 &#8211; 2013). As Executive Officer, she was responsible for all aspects of fund management, including analysis of plan funding, investment oversight, operational and strategic planning, and fiduciary and governance issues. Prior to her appointment as the Executive Officer, Ms. Bilyeu served eight years as the Operations Officer for the System, overseeing benefit administration, including survivor, disability, and retirement programs. Before joining Nevada PERS, Ms. Bilyeu was the System&#8217;s general counsel in the Office of the Nevada Attorney General, representing the System in benefits litigation, contracts analysis, board governance and fiduciary issues.</p>



<p>Ms. Bilyeu is in her second term on the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board (FRTIB). Ms. Bilyeu also served as a member of the Social Security Advisory Board from 2007 through 2010. The Advisory Board is an independent, bipartisan board created by Congress and appointed by the President and the Congress to advise the President, the Congress, and the Commissioner of Social Security on matters related to Social Security and Supplemental Security Income programs.</p>



<p>Ms. Bilyeu is a public employee board member of the International Foundation of Employee Benefit Plans and also serves as a board member for the National Institute on Retirement Security. She received her juris doctor from California Western School of Law and her bachelor’s degree from the University of Arizona.</p>



<p><strong><u>Leona Bridges, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Leona M. Bridges is a Commissioner for the San Francisco Employees’ Retirement System, where she serves as chair of the deferred compensation committee. She is a former Director for the Municipal Transportation Agency and Commissioner for the San Francisco Parking Authority of the City &amp; County of San Francisco, where she continues to serve on the Bond Oversight Committee. For more than two decades, Ms. Bridges was a Managing Director at Barclays Global Investors (acquired by BlackRock in 2009), becoming the world’s largest asset manager of combined assets. During her career in the financial services industry, she focused on asset management as it related to global securities lending/trading, collateral management, custody services, client service, and business development. Additionally, she was responsible for establishing and maintaining civic and community relationships.</p>



<p>Ms. Bridges holds an MBA from Golden Gate University Ageno School of Business and a Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration from San Francisco State University. She established an endowed scholarship in the College of Business to support economically and educationally disadvantaged students at San Francisco State University. Ms. Bridges serves on various community and non-profit boards. She is the recipient of many professional, community, and prestigious national awards.</p>



<p><strong><u>Stacey Olivares, Nominee for Member of the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Stacie Olivares is on the board of directors of the Mission Advancement Corporation (NYSE: MACC) as its Audit Committee Chair, the Kroll Bond Rating Agency (KBRA), and CalPERS. At the nexus of capital markets, technology, and policy, Olivares works to expand markets, optimize returns, and democratize capital to advance environmental, social, and governance (ESG) and diversity, equity, and inclusion outcomes in our global economy. She is one of the few Latina Chief Investment Officers in the United States.</p>



<p>Olivares was the Chief Investment Officer of Lendistry, a fintech small business lender, from 2019 through 2020, and senior advisor on blockchain and impact investment to the world’s four-largest insurance market from 2018 to 2019. Earlier, Stacie led ESG investments as the Chief Investment Officer of COIN, a $29 billion ESG investment fund of the insurance industry, from 2011 through 2018, and as an ESG-focused portfolio manager at Morgan Stanley from 2008 through 2011. She entered capital markets with a global lens after leading the State of California’s economic advisory board from 2002 to 2007 and advancing global licensing and business development for Palm, Inc., from 2000 to 2002. Olivares serves on the advisory board of SUMA Wealth and on the board of directors of the University of California at Berkeley, College of Letters &amp; Science, the Hispanic Heritage Foundation, and the Latino Community Foundation. She holds a bachelor’s degree in economics from the University of California at Berkeley and a master’s degree in business and government from Harvard University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kathy Im, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</u></strong></p>



<p>Kathy Im is the Director of Journalism and Media at the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation. She manages a $25 million annual portfolio that is best known for supporting public media, nonprofit journalism, and documentary storytelling. During Im’s tenure, the program has deepened and expanded its investments in the creation, dissemination, and amplification of accurate, just, and inclusive news and narratives across three areas of media &#8212; professional nonprofit reporting, nonfiction multimedia storytelling, and participatory civic media &#8212; with the goal of informing, engaging, and activating Americans to build a more equitable future.</p>



<p>Im is a recognized leader in philanthropy and media. She is a member of the Board of Jurors for the Peabody Awards, a member of the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, and a former board member of Media Impact Funders, the Center for Asian American Media, and Asian Americans/Pacific Islanders in Philanthropy. She is the author of several editorials and essays about press freedom, diversity in media and journalism, and the connection between media and democracy. Kathy earned her Master’s in Public Policy from the Harris School of Public Policy Studies at the University of Chicago, where she is currently a member of the Harris Council, which advises the Dean. She earned her Bachelor’s in Government Studies from Smith College. Im lives in Chicago with her husband, Young B. Im, and their three children.</p>



<p><strong><u>Tom Rothman, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</u></strong></p>



<p>Tom Rothman, one of the global media sector’s most experienced executives, is Chairman and CEO of Sony Pictures Entertainment’s Motion Picture Group. Chairman since 2015, he oversees all of the studio’s worldwide businesses, including historic Columbia Pictures. Previously, Rothman served as Chairman and CEO of Fox Filmed Entertainment, having spent 17 years in various positions at 20th CenturyFox, including founding Fox Searchlight Pictures.&nbsp; Earlier in his career, Rothman was President of Worldwide Production for the Samuel Goldwyn Company and Executive Vice President for Columbia Pictures.&nbsp; Before joining Columbia, Rothman was a partner at the New York law firm Frankfurt, Kurnit, Klein and Selz, having clerked on the Second Circuit Court of Appeals.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since 2013, Rothman has served on the Board of Directors of Booking Holdings Inc., the world’s largest online travel agency. He is a member of the National Council on the Arts and has received The Corwin Award for Human Relations from the American Jewish Committee.&nbsp; He is a member of the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences and serves on multiple non-profit boards.&nbsp; Rothman received lifetime achievement recognitions from the Producers Guild of America and the IFP East, and Columbia University honored him with the Arthur B. Krim Award for outstanding leadership.&nbsp; He graduated magna cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa, from Brown University in 1976 and from Columbia Law School in 1980 as a two-time James Kent Scholar, the school’s highest academic honor.</p>



<p><strong><u>Elizabeth Sembler, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting</u></strong></p>



<p>Elizabeth Sembler of Seminole, Florida is a retired Jewish educator and school administrator.&nbsp; She most recently served as the director of engagement at Congregation B’nai Israel in St. Petersburg, Florida. Ms. Sembler has previously served on the board of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, appointed by Presidents George W. Bush and Barack Obama. She served as chair of the board from 2014-16. She has served on the board of Tampa, Florida public television station WEDU-TV since 1993 and was the chair of its board from 2001-2003. From 2006-2008, she served on the board of the America’s Public Television Stations (APTS), a nonprofit group that supports the continued growth and development of a strong and financially sound noncommercial television service.</p>



<p>Ms. Sembler co-chairs the board of advisors of the Davidson Graduate School of Education at the Jewish Theological Seminary in New York, New York, and serves on the board of directors and is past board chair of the Academy Prep Center of St. Petersburg in Florida, a privately funded middle school for students qualifying for needs-based scholarships. She serves as vice chair of the board of directors of the Florida Orchestra, and recently joined the boards of Congregation B’nai Israel in St. Petersburg, the Institute for Strategic Policy Solutions at St. Petersburg College, and the Tampa Orlando Pinellas [TOP] Jewish Foundation in Tampa, FL.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Intent to Nominate Nine Foreign Policy and National Security&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/president-biden-announces-intent-to-nominate-nine-foreign-policy-and-national-security-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve in key roles promoting U.S. foreign policy and national security: Mark Brzezinski, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Poland Elizabeth Anne Noseworthy Fitzsimmons, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve in key roles promoting U.S. foreign policy and national security:</p>



<ul><li>Mark Brzezinski, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Poland</li><li>Elizabeth Anne Noseworthy Fitzsimmons, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Togolese Republic</li><li>Rebecca Eliza Gonzales, Nominee for Director of the Office of Foreign Missions, with the rank of Ambassador, Department of State</li><li>Brian Wesley Shukan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Benin</li><li>David John Young, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Malawi</li><li>Adriana Kugler, Nominee for U.S. Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</li><li>Oren Whyche-Shaw, Nominee for U.S. Director of the African Development Bank</li><li>Corey Hinderstein, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Department of Energy</li><li>David Honey, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary for Research and Engineering, Department of Defense</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Mark Brzezinski, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Poland</u></strong></p>



<p>Mark Brzezinski is founder and principal of Brzezinski Strategies LLC. Previously, he was Managing Director at Makena Capital Management, where he focused on responding to the growing demand for environmentally and socially responsible investment portfolios. Prior to Makena, Brzezinski served as the first Executive Director of the White House&#8217;s Arctic Executive Steering Committee and before that was the U.S. Ambassador to Sweden between 2011-2015.&nbsp; Earlier, Brzezinski was a partner at McGuireWoods LLP in Washington, D.C. From 1999 to 2001, he served on President Clinton&#8217;s National Security Council, first as a Director for Russia and Eurasia, and then as a Director for the Balkans.&nbsp; He was a Fulbright Scholar in Poland and is the author of “The Struggle for Constitutionalism in Poland.” He is a member of both the Council on Foreign Relations and the Trilateral Commission.</p>



<p>Brzezinski received a BA from Dartmouth College, a JD from the University of Virginia, and a PhD in Political Science from Oxford University. His foreign languages are Polish and French. He was awarded the Royal Order of the Polar Star by the King of Sweden and is a recipient of the Commander’s Cross of the Order of Merit of the Republic of Poland.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Elizabeth Anne Noseworthy Fitzsimmons, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Togolese Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Elizabeth Anne Noseworthy Fitzsimmons, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of African Affairs.&nbsp; From 2018-2021, she served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Central Africa and Public Diplomacy.&nbsp; Prior to that, she was Acting Deputy Spokesperson for the Department.&nbsp; Previous assignments include Deputy Executive Secretary to Secretaries Kerry and Tillerson, Senior Advisor at the Foreign Service Institute, Deputy Assistant Secretary for Public Diplomacy in the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs, and the Office of the Special Representative for Afghanistan and Pakistan.&nbsp; Fitzsimmons has served overseas in Taiwan, Hong Kong, Cambodia, India and Bulgaria.&nbsp; She has also worked in the State Department’s Operations Center and as Deputy Director of the State Department’s Executive Secretariat.&nbsp; She earned a B.A. from the University of Virginia.&nbsp; Fitzsimmons speaks Bulgarian, French and Chinese.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rebecca Eliza Gonzales, Nominee for Director of the Office of Foreign Missions, with the rank of Ambassador, Department of State</u></strong></p>



<p>Rebecca Gonzales, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the U.S. Ambassador to the Kingdom of Lesotho.&nbsp; Previously, she served as the Chief of Staff in the Bureau of Administration at the Department of State.&nbsp; She also served as the Deputy Executive Director of the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs; as Deputy Management Counselor at the U.S.&nbsp; Embassy in Pretoria, South Africa; Management Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Gaborone, Botswana; and Special Assistant in the Office of the Under Secretary for Management at the Department of State.&nbsp; Other assignments for Ambassador Gonzales include service in the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs and at U.S. embassies in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia; New Delhi, India; Bogota, Colombia; and Athens, Greece.&nbsp; Ambassador Gonzales earned a B.A. and an M.B.A. from The George Washington University and an M.S. from the Dwight D. Eisenhower School for National Security and Resource Strategy at Fort McNair, Washington, D.C.&nbsp; She speaks Spanish and Greek.</p>



<p><strong><u>Brian Wesley Shukan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Benin</u></strong></p>



<p>Brian W. Shukan, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Chargé d’Affaires a.i. and Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Khartoum, Sudan.&nbsp; He previously served as Director of the Office of the Special Envoy for Sudan and South Sudan at the Department of State.&nbsp; Shukan also served as Chargé d’Affaires a.i. and Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Port-au-Prince, Haiti, and as Principal Officer at the U.S. Consulate General in Casablanca, Morocco. His other overseas experience includes service at the U.S. embassies in Ghana, Iraq, Saudi Arabia, Luxembourg and Benin.&nbsp; Shukan is the recipient of numerous awards, including the James V. Forrestal Award for Excellence in Strategy and Force Planning at the U.S. Naval War College.&nbsp; He earned a Bachelors Degree from the University of Wisconsin-Madison, a J.D. from Washington University in St. Louis, Missouri, and an M.A. with distinction from the U.S. Naval War College.&nbsp; He speaks French and Arabic.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>David John Young, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Malawi</u></strong></p>



<p>David Young, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as Chargé d’Affaires, a.i. at the U.S. Embassy in Lusaka, Zambia.&nbsp; Previously he served as Chargé d’Affaires, a.i. at the U.S. Embassy in Pretoria, South Africa and Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Abuja, Nigeria. &nbsp;Prior to that, he was Deputy Director, Office of the Special Envoy for Sudan &amp; South Sudan, and he also served as Executive Assistant to the Under Secretary for Democracy and Global Affairs at the State Department.&nbsp; Among his other assignments, Young was a Pearson Fellow; a Public Affairs Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Guatemala; and Director, Office of International Religious Freedom in the Bureau of Democracy and Human Rights at the State Department. Young earned his B.A. degree in journalism from the University of Missouri; a Diploma from Trinity College, University of Dublin; and Master degrees in divinity and international relations from Boston University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Adriana Kugler, Nominee for </u></strong>U.S. Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development<strong><u> </u></strong>Dr. Adriana Kugler is a Full Professor at the McCourt School of Public Policy at Georgetown University. Dr. Kugler was Chief Economist at the U.S. Department of Labor under the Obama-Biden Administration between 2011 and 2013. Dr. Kugler served as Vice Provost for Faculty at Georgetown University between 2013 and 2016. Dr. Kugler was a member of the Board on Science, Technology and Economic Policy (STEP) of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine and served in the Technical Advisory Committee of the Bureau of Labor Statistics. Dr. Kugler was Chair and Chair-elect of the Business and Economics Statistics Section of the American Statistical Association in 2020 and 2019, respectively. She was an elected member of the Executive Committee of the European Association of Labor Economists and of the Executive Committee of the Latin American and Caribbean Economic Association.</p>



<p>Dr. Kugler completed her Ph.D. from the University of California at Berkeley and obtained a B.A. in Economics and Political Science from McGill University with first class honors. Dr. Kugler graduated high school in the public schools in Montgomery County, Maryland. She is married to Ignacio Donoso; they have two children − Daniel and Mireille.</p>



<p><strong><u>Oren Whyche-Shaw, Nominee for U.S. Director of the African Development Bank</u></strong></p>



<p>Until retirement in July 2020, Oren E. Whyche-Shaw was Deputy Assistant Administrator for the Africa Bureau and the Coordinator for President Obama’s Partnership in Growth and the Trade Africa Initiative at the U.S. Agency for International Development in Washington, DC. &nbsp;Prior to joining USAID in 2011, Ms. Whyche-Shaw served as the Director for the Office of African Nations and as Senior Advisor in the Multilateral Development Bank Office of the Department of Treasury.</p>



<p>Ms. Whyche-Shaw holds a Bachelor of Science degree in Theoretical Mathematics and French from Capital University in Columbus, OH. As the first Citibank Fellow, she received a master&#8217;s degree in Finance, Money and Financial Markets, and International Business from Columbia University’s Business School. Ms. Whyche-Shaw served as the Senior Special Advisor to the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission when selected as a White House Fellow in 1983. Ms. Whyche-Shaw has lived and worked internationally in more than 50 countries in over 30 years.</p>



<p><strong><u>Corey Hinderstein, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation, Department of Energy</u></strong></p>



<p>Corey Hinderstein is vice president of International Fuel Cycle Strategies at the Nuclear Threat Initiative based in Washington, DC, where she focuses on international nuclear fuel cycle and nonproliferation policy, global nuclear security, and arms control and nonproliferation monitoring and verification. From February 2015 through November 2017, Ms. Hinderstein was senior coordinator for nuclear security and nonproliferation policy affairs at the Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation office of the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA), U.S. Department of Energy (DOE). At NNSA, she led the DOE’s preparations for the 2016 Nuclear Security Summit and worked on other projects related to nuclear security and illicit trafficking, Iran’s nuclear program, and international monitoring and verification. Prior to her service at DOE, Ms. Hinderstein had been with NTI since 2006 and earlier was deputy director of the Institute for Science and International Security.</p>



<p>Ms. Hinderstein is a past president and Fellow of the Institute of Nuclear Materials Management (INMM) and serves on the board of directors for the World Institute for Nuclear Security. She also has served in advisory capacities for multiple national laboratories and has published widely on nuclear nonproliferation, verification and monitoring and nuclear security. Ms. Hinderstein graduated from Clark University in Worcester, MA where she was elected to Phi Beta Kappa.</p>



<p><strong><u>David Honey, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary for Research and Engineering, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. David Honey is a Special Assistant to the Director of the Defense Advanced Projects Agency (DARPA), where he helps guide collaborations with other agencies. In an earlier DARPA tour, he served as a Program Manager, Deputy Office Director, and Office Director. Dr. Honey previously served as the Director of Science and Technology in the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Research in the Department of Defense, and as senior vice president of a small business.</p>



<p>Dr. Honey is a retired U.S. Air Force officer who began his military career as a pilot and later transitioned into research and development. He holds a Doctorate from Syracuse University, Master of Science degrees from the University of Arizona and the Air Force Institute of Technology and a Bachelor of Science from the Rochester Institute of Technology.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/04/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-30/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Jamie L. Harpootlian, of South Carolina, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Slovenia. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Chavonda J. Jacobs-Young, of Georgia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Research, Education, and Economics, vice Catherine E. Woteki. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; John F. Plumb, of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jamie L. Harpootlian, of South Carolina, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Slovenia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Chavonda J. Jacobs-Young, of Georgia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Research, Education, and Economics, vice Catherine E. Woteki.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; John F. Plumb, of New York, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>     Jennifer Clyburn Reed, of South Carolina, to be Federal Cochairperson of the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission.  (New Position)</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, August 4,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/04/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-august-4-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 20:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:52 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; Happy Wednesday.&#160; I have a couple of notes for you at the top.&#160;Today, Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marcia Fudge released a statement committing to do everything in HUD’s power to stop evictions for families with HUD assistance or families who rent in housing that is insured&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:52 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Happy Wednesday.&nbsp; I have a couple of notes for you at the top.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marcia Fudge released a statement committing to do everything in HUD’s power to stop evictions for families with HUD assistance or families who rent in housing that is insured by the Federal Housing Administration.&nbsp; This is part of delivering on what the President announced &#8212; or we announced in our statement just a couple of days ago.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And while the Emergency Rental Assistance funds are in the hands of state and local governments, one of the critical roles that the administration can continue to play is to act as a leading hub to convene states and cities and to share best practices, as we have done at two major eviction prevention summits.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this morning, Treasury published examples of simplified forms that are being used effectively by Emergency Rental Assistance programs around the country.&nbsp; I think Ebony may have asked a version of this yesterday &#8212; a question about this.&nbsp; But Treasury has repeatedly discouraged undue documentation burdens that limit access for eligible families and is sharing these example forms to make it easier for state and local governments to put that into practice.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Places that have are seeing results.&nbsp; I mentioned Virginia yesterday, but, as an example, Virginia is the second-highest nationwide distributor of ERA funds in the nation and has given out $223 million to tenants and landlords in need.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Virginia followed Treasury&#8217;s guidance to eliminate documentation burdens that slow down application processing for eligible families.&nbsp; And the state was able to significantly cut down application processing times by streamlining what is often the most time-consuming part of the eligibility verification and a barrier for people applying.<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is a process that we&#8217;re trying to share best practices, and the Treasury Department is trying to simplify these forms to make it easier for families.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I mentioned yesterday, we&#8217;re going to continue to highlight what the bipartisan infrastructure deal will mean for families across the country, as we will digitally as well.&nbsp; Right now, there are up to 10 million homes with lead service lines and pipes.&nbsp; Children in up to 400,000 schools and childcare facilities are at risk of exposure to lead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For kids, high exposure to lead can negatively affect academic performance and can lead to cardiovascular disease later in life.&nbsp; And the President clearly thinks that&#8217;s unacceptable, as do a number of members of Congress.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the deal makes the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history, replacing all the nation&#8217;s lead pipes and service lines, from rural towns to struggling cities.&nbsp; The deal invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I wanted to also take a moment to recognize the passing of Pentagon Force Protection Officer George Gonzalez, who was tragically killed yesterday in the line of duty.&nbsp; His life was one of service, a veteran of both the police and the military.&nbsp; He served the Federal Bureau of Prisons, the Transportation Security Administration, and the United States Army where he was awarded the Army Commendation Medal for his service in Iraq.&nbsp; He lost his life protecting those who protect the nation.&nbsp; We mourn his loss and offer condolences to his family.<br>&nbsp;<br>Two more short notes &#8212; hopefully helpful.&nbsp; This morning at the White House, as part of our ongoing efforts to every &#8212; to do everything we can and engage everyone we can to encourage vaccinations, Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy and members of the White House COVID-19 Response Team convened a historic gathering of all living, former U.S. Surgeon Generals, including Dr. Antonia Novello, Dr. Joycelyn Elders, Dr. David Satcher, Dr. Richard Carmona, Dr. Regina Benjamin, and Dr. Jerome Adams.<br>&nbsp;<br>These esteemed public health leaders who served under both Republican and Democratic Presidents discussed the importance of ensuring that communities of color, those hardest hit by the virus have the information and access they need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; And they discussed how we can work together, of course, moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last point for all of you: The President spoke &#8212; or called, I should say &#8212; Shontel Brown last night and extended his congratulations to her.&nbsp; He is focused on delivering for the people of Ohio and across the country, as is she.&nbsp; We know his agenda, including investi- &#8212; investing in our country&#8217;s infrastructure; helping grow our economy, creating good-paying, middle-class jobs is broadly popular with the American people.&nbsp;&nbsp; He&#8217;s laser focused on delivering.&nbsp; More Democrats means more ability to deliver on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know you were up way too early this morning, based on my television.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been waiting to do that joke all week.<br>&nbsp;<br>Here we are.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I appreciate the pun, Jen.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>A few questions all on the same topic &#8212; short ones, perhaps.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, the President said Governor Cuomo should resign.&nbsp; The governor has not done so.&nbsp; Has the President called the governor?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has anyone from the White House called the governor or the governor’s staff?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not that I&#8217;m aware of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When was the last time the President and Governor Cuomo spoke?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to check on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s two more on this.&nbsp; If the governor refuses to resign, does the President want to see him impeached and removed from office?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President made clear yesterday that Governor Cuomo should resign, and believes &#8212; and I believe we should start with that.&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously a process that&#8217;s going to proceed, and leaders in New York spoke to that yesterday.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll leave it to them to speak to that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the President believes Governor Cuomo should do the right thing: resign and leave space for future leadership in New York.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then there&#8217;s been a lot of discussion in here, including from the President, in recent days, about the vital role that governors play in the nation’s COVID response.&nbsp; In this period, while Governor Cuomo is still in office, does the President have confidence in him leading New York State&#8217;s response to the pandemic?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, again, the President made clear, because of the abhorrent allegations that were made public yesterday, that it is time for Governor Cuomo to resign.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, we do not want the people of New York to be impacted in a negative way, as they&#8217;re working to fight COVID.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to work with the administration in New York, with leaders in New York, to continue to fight COVID.&nbsp; That will continue.&nbsp; And obviously, if leadership changes in the state, we will work with a different leader.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Can you walk us through what changed from Monday to Tuesday, when it comes to the eviction ban?&nbsp; On Monday, Gene Sperling stood here and said the CDC has been unable to find the legal authority for even new targeted eviction moratoriums.&nbsp; There are many people across the administration who said the same thing.&nbsp; And yet, the CDC did just that yesterday.&nbsp; So what changed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to take a step back a little bit before that, to Sunday, when we were engaged &#8212; the administration, the White House was engaged directly with the CDC, at the direction of the President, to ask them to look into what legal options, if any &#8212; if any existed &#8212; there were to extend the eviction moratorium.<br>&nbsp;<br>That process was underway for a couple of days.&nbsp; The announcement yesterday was a reflection of exactly that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And when we put out a statement on Monday, right before Gene Sperling came out to the briefing, right before we came out to talk with all of you, that also made clear in there that at that time they had not yet found a legal pathway forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What was announced yesterday was not an extension of the existing moratorium, which was, of course, national; it was a more limited moratorium that was going to be impacting and helping areas that were hardest hit by COVID.&nbsp; So, different than the last moratorium.&nbsp; That was also reflected in the statement that we issued on Monday, that that was the President&#8217;s ask &#8212; to look into a more limited moratorium.<br>&nbsp;<br>They did that.&nbsp; They &#8212; and yesterday&#8217;s announcement was a reflection of that process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, what&#8217;s your message to progressives who say they&#8217;re worried that President Biden&#8217;s concerns about the constitutionality of this move will end up being a self-fulfilling prophecy and motivate opponents to go ahead and file suit now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I would first say the President shares their desire, their commitment, and their interest in keeping renters and people in their homes, and that is exactly why he took the step of asking the CDC to look into what legal pathways forward there were.&nbsp; And yesterday&#8217;s announcement was a reflection of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t control the courts; we don&#8217;t know what they will do.&nbsp; We are all aware of the Supreme Court decision at the end of June and what was outlined in their decision at the end of June.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is also going to be a temporary &#8212; temporary solution regardless, and a longer-term solution will require legislative action.&nbsp; But his message to anyone who’s been a passionate advocate is that he shares their concern, he shares their commitment.&nbsp; He wants renters to be able to stay in their home, and that&#8217;s why we took this step over the last few days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on one other topic, if you don’t mind.&nbsp; I know that the President has asked the Defense Secretary to look into the possibility of making the COVID vaccine mandatory for servicemembers, but according to the U.S. Code, it’s actually the President who has to grant a waiver to the military to make vaccines mandatory.&nbsp; Has he granted that waiver yet?&nbsp; And if not, does he plan to do so?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President is looking for a recommendation from the Secretary of Defense.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t been made yet.&nbsp; And when &#8212; if and when that is made, I would expect he would respond accordingly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The earlier moratorium used the same legal justification that the new one is using, which, in layman&#8217;s terms, is about preventing the spread of disease if you evict people at a time of pandemic.&nbsp; So the only real difference is narrowing location, but the rationale is the same.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, after the President was clear that it wasn&#8217;t legal, Gene Sperling was clear that it wasn&#8217;t legal, is this a “roll the dice and see if it gets challenged” position from an administration that may be doing something it knows is not on legal standing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President would not have supported moving forward with any action where he wasn&#8217;t &#8212; didn&#8217;t feel there was legal standing and legal support.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We obviously don&#8217;t control what the courts do.&nbsp; And we have, of course, seen what the Supreme Court decided and how they ruled, which was not related to public health &#8212; as you well know, Kelly &#8212; and was related to the relationship between the landlord and the renter.<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is different in that it is more targeted, it is focused on counties with higher substantial case rates to protect renters, and the CDC ultimately decided to adopt it.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that the conditions have changed.&nbsp; The rise of the Delta variant, especially in communities where there are large numbers of unvaccinated individuals, where there are growing case numbers, is certainly something that has raised the alarm for us, it has raised the alarm for members of Congress, and it has certainly added to the need to take this additional step.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We were in the event with Dr. Murthy earlier, and he talked about the likelihood that boosters would eventually be required.&nbsp; For Americans who are sort of taking it on their &#8212; themselves and trying to seek out a third shot, what is the administration&#8217;s view of those who are trying to, you know, &#8220;self-boost,&#8221; for lack of a better term?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ve never heard that term before, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I am &#8212; it&#8217;s interesting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, I would say that what we&#8217;ve been conveying to officials around the country who have implemented this in some places is that this is not in alignment with the guidance of the public health &#8212; of public health officials, whether that is the CDC or the FDA.&nbsp; And we are certainly in touch with local officials on that matter and conveying exactly that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also, at the same time, are prepared if the FDA decides that they are going to recommend a booster.&nbsp; That is why we ordered the number of doses we did order several months ago, because we are like Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts and always want to be prepared.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re prepared for that, but it is not what the FDA and the CDC are recommending, and we are conveying that directly to officials.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a major push here recently to protect tenants from being evicted right now.&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t more being done to help the landlords who are struggling to pay their bills because they&#8217;re not being paid?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, actually, the landlords can benefit from exactly the same emergency rental assistance that renters can benefit from.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, right now, as we understand it, many states are not distributing that money.&nbsp; The Washington Post says that this measure could drive thousands of minor landlords to bankruptcy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s exactly why &#8212; and I&#8217;m happy to have you as a partner in this effort &#8212; we are trying to advocate for states, localities to get this money out.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no reason it&#8217;s not going out to landlords, to renters; no reason that people who are eligible are not benefiting.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve seen a number of states &#8212; red states and blue states &#8212; do this very effectively.&nbsp; Texas is an example I used yesterday.&nbsp; Virginia is one I highlighted today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is why we&#8217;re doing as much of this outreach and engagement as we&#8217;re doing, and simplifying forms, making it easier for people to understand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on immigration, it&#8217;s been almost four months since the President told migrants, &#8220;Don&#8217;t come.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t leave your town.&#8221;&nbsp; Almost two months since the Vice President went to Central America to say, &#8220;Do not come.&#8221;&nbsp; But people are coming in record numbers.&nbsp; Does the President think his immigration plan is working?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President continues to convey to anyone, as you&#8217;ve said, who wants to come to the United States: Now is not the time to come.&nbsp; It is not the time to come and try to go through irregular migration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We want to have an effective process where you can apply for asylum, where you can apply for legal status.&nbsp; We have increased our investment in areas like the Central American Minors Program, allowing people to apply from within country so they are not making that dangerous trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s more that needs to be done.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also instituted a number of additional steps recently, including expedited removals, to move people out of the country more quickly.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s a &#8212; we&#8217;re still at work on improving a process and improving a system that was very broken when we took office.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the message to migrants is the same, even though they are coming &#8212; a 21-year high, 210,000 encounters at the border last month?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And I would also note the number of people who were &#8212; who were removed from the border, which is an important part of the context, which is almost half of that number.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he&#8217;s saying, &#8220;Don&#8217;t come.&#8221;&nbsp; And they&#8217;re coming.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there are a number of factors, as you well know, that are happening in these countries.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working to address those as well, and the Vice President is leading those efforts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t expect that to be a switch, but addressing root causes in these countries &#8212; corruption, economic downturn, people are fleeing a range of challenges, persecution &#8212; those are issues we need to address at the same time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Sort of a housekeeping question.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given the status of COVID and the Delta variant, what is the status on the permanent pick for an FDA commissioner?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update for you.&nbsp; Obviously, the President would love to have a permanent pick in place and wants to nominate the right person, but I don&#8217;t have an update on the timeline for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what&#8217;s taking so long?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s not going to get &#8212; he&#8217;s not going to expedite it if he does not &#8212; has not identified the right person to nominate quite yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Governor Cuomo issue: If this is potentially such a stain on the party, the President &#8212; as the leader of this party &#8212; why not pick up the phone and ask him to resign at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President was pretty clear publicly; he asked him to resign yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No plans to call him, though?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; no plans to call him to preview, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jeff.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, sort of picking up on Kelly’s question: The WHO today called on countries basically to put a halt on booster shots of the COVID vaccine.&nbsp; I know that&#8217;s not the policy yet of the United States, but it does appear as though we&#8217;re moving in that direction &#8212; at least for people who are immunocompromised.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House reaction to his call to put that off until at least the end of September so that poorer countries can get more vaccine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Jeff, we feel that it&#8217;s a false choice and that we can do both.&nbsp; We announced just yesterday that we hit an important milestone of over 110 million vaccines donated to the world.&nbsp; That is more than any other country has shared, combined.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also made clear that that is the beginning, and we also started to donate the 500 million doses of Pfizer we&#8217;ve purchased.&nbsp; We will start to donate those later this month.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ve taken action on the global level far more than any country around the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re asking the global community to also step up.&nbsp; We saw some action at the G7; more needs to happen.&nbsp; But we believe we can do both.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also, in this country, have enough supply to ensure that every American has access to a vaccine.&nbsp; We will have enough supply to ensure.&nbsp; If the FDA decides that boosters are recommended for a portion of the population, to provide those as well.&nbsp; We believe we can do both, and we don&#8217;t need to make that choice.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; On a separate topic, is the White House tracking the case of the Belarus Olympian who was forced to go to the airport and then ended up going to Austria instead of back to her own country?&nbsp; And is the U.S. providing any assistance to her or anyone else from the Belarusian team?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are aware of the case.&nbsp; I would have to check if there&#8217;s direct assistance.&nbsp; The State Department may be the best source for that, but I will check with them and see if there&#8217;s anything to provide to all of you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who inside the administration signed off on the legality of what the CDC proposed yesterday?&nbsp; Is that the CDC&#8217;s lawyers, the Justice Department?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The CDC’s lawyers, as well as our Counsel&#8217;s Office &#8212; yes.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of the Department of Justice&#8217;s engagement, but of course, that might make sense.&nbsp; I would have to check on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, you know, the President alluded yesterday to &#8212; &#8220;Look, if this gets struck down in court, if nothing else, it buys time for the federal funds from the state level to be kicked out and disbursed.&#8221;&nbsp; How much of that was a driving force behind the decision to move forward with this?&nbsp; Like, “We need to figure out some way to buy time as states figure this out.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s just go ahead with this.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President would not have supported moving forward if he did not support the legal justification.&nbsp; He is old school in that way.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would tell you that regardless of what is decided by any court &#8212; if anything is decided by any court &#8212; this is not a permanent solution.&nbsp; It is extended through the beginning of October.&nbsp; And I think you&#8217;ve seen that recognition by a range of members of Congress and leaders and advocates who have been so passionately talking about the need to extend the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; It would require legislative action.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The other piece of this that I know we keep talking about but is really a solution here, and that&#8217;s why we keep talking about it, is getting this money out to states and localities.&nbsp; This is really about money &#8212; right?&nbsp;&#8212; and funding.&nbsp; And all these states and localities have money to extend the moratorium in their states by a month or two months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There have been challenges that are understandable, including the fact that there&#8217;s no federal infrastructure for distributing this money.&nbsp; The states are doing it on their own.&nbsp; There are challenges where even well-meaning landlords and others are trying to figure out how to accept applications.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re working through those challenges, but that is a solution for the short term, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve talked about it and why we&#8217;ve spent so much time investing in that as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more quick one.&nbsp; The President was very sharp on just, kind of, his perspective on Republican governors put &#8212; or blocked, I guess, specific potential public health options, and echoed something you said yesterday in a very sharp tone: Either you&#8217;re with it or move out the way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Is that an intentional shift?&nbsp; What&#8217;s driving kind of a very sharp tone in regards to these specific actions by Republican governors?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me be also clear that, as the President said yesterday, the vast majority of leaders &#8212; and as I&#8217;ve said too &#8212; continue to step up and do the right thing.&nbsp; People like Governor Hutchinson have been traveling their state, hearing from their communities, and answering questions about the vaccine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re also in constant communication with our nation&#8217;s governor.&nbsp; So even as we called out steps that &#8212; and he called out steps that we felt should’ve been taken by the governors of Florida and Texas &#8212; we&#8217;re in touch with those offices about providing additional assistance and seeing if we can figure out what their needs are and how we can help meet them.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we had our first FEMA team on the ground in West Virginia just days after entering government.&nbsp; Right now, our Surge Response Teams are working hand in hand with the hardest-hit states that are not traditionally blue and Democratic states &#8212; Arkansas, Missouri, Louisiana &#8212; focusing on everything from contact tracing, technical expertise, and vaccine confidence.<br>&nbsp;<br>But at the same time, that wasn&#8217;t an evaluation &#8212; a partisan evaluation or assessment; that was an assessment of what isn&#8217;t happening that would help protect people&#8217;s lives and save people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; And there are leaders who are not stepping up and are getting in the way of the American people &#8212; companies and others &#8212; who are trying to save lives and stop the spread of Delta.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are going to keep calling that out.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not meant to be partisan.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not meant to be political.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just meant to convey that more action is needed in some parts of the country, even where there are many states where positive action is being taken.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, you mentioned that the new moratorium is a targeted one and not one that&#8217;s nationwide as justification of why this is &#8212; meets the legal threshold.&nbsp; But Gene Sperling, earlier, actually pointed out &#8212; he said, “To date, the CDC Director and her team have been unable to find legal authority, even for a more targeted eviction moratorium that would [just] focus…on counties with higher rates of COVID spread.”&nbsp; So I&#8217;m trying to just pinpoint what exactly is different than what they were looking at then that makes this now a &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That was also in our statement.&nbsp; We said, “to date,” and we looked at all the &#8212; and we were continuing to look at all of the legal authorities and options, as were the lawyers at the CDC and our lawyers, to see what we felt was legally viable.&nbsp; That process was a couple-day process.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t concluded on Monday when Gene Sperling came to the briefing room.&nbsp; Yesterday it concluded, and of course, they made the announcement as a result.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more question. &nbsp;What is the White House doing to push forward the nomination of David Chipman at the ATF?&nbsp; The vote could hinge on the vote of Senator Angus King, in Maine, who has been pushed by the local Maine sportsman groups and national gun rights advocates.&nbsp; Has the White House reached out specifically to Senator King on this issue?&nbsp; And is the White House fully committed to Chipman, or might it go with a different nominee at some point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to read out private conversations with members of Congress, but I will tell you that we knew this wouldn&#8217;t be easy.&nbsp; ATF hasn&#8217;t had a confirmed director in six years and only one confirmed director since the position became Senate-confirmable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;ve been eyes wide open into the challenge from the beginning.&nbsp; But we are disappointed by the fact that many Republicans are moving in lockstep to try to hold up his nomination and handcuff the chief federal law enforcement agency tasked with fighting gun crimes.&nbsp; It speaks volumes to their complete refusal to tackle the spike in crime we&#8217;ve seen over the last 18 months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is someone who has 25 years in distinguished service to our country as an ATF agent.&nbsp; He has the exact set of skills and experience we need to revitalize the bureau&#8217;s work to crack down on gun trafficking, keep guns out of the hands of criminals.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So certainly, yes, we stand by his strong qualifications and nomination.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m just going to jump around and then I’ll come back.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; In the middle.&nbsp; In the middle.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Question on &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, oh, sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead, right there.&nbsp; In the middle, right there.&nbsp; In the middle.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I’m trying to get to people I haven&#8217;t gotten to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I appreciate it.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; And then right in front of you.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; You&#8217;re good.&nbsp; You&#8217;re good.&nbsp; It&#8217;s fine.&nbsp; We can do everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infrastructure, when you talk to local officials about this, they&#8217;re really excited about the possibilities of what might happen, but they can&#8217;t say with any certainty what they&#8217;re actually going receive and what they&#8217;re actually going to be able to do.&nbsp; So as this bill advances, you know, what would you say to folks who are wondering how much of these big pots of money are actually coming to our community?&nbsp; And how quickly, assuming it passes, might they find out and see those benefits?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, one, we have put out state-by-state factsheets.&nbsp; And if different businesses or communities haven&#8217;t seen those, we&#8217;re happy to provide them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is true that, as is true with any piece of legislation, there are components of these &#8212; the project funding that would be through grants and some through applications that &#8212; where communities will have to apply for funding.&nbsp; Obviously, it would be in our interest to get that going as quickly as possible, and the Department of Transportation and others will implement that.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have been pretty clear about benefits that will help every community: replacing lead pipes, making sure people have access to broadband, making a historic investment in climate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know people are asking &#8212; and I think you&#8217;re asking specifically about people who are &#8212; who want to know if their specific bridge is going to be repaired.&nbsp; Some of that will be through grant funding; some of it will be through, you know, funding that will be designated in the piece of &#8212; in the bill. But, you know, it will, of course, take a little bit of time to implement, but we&#8217;ll be eager to get that done as quickly as the bill is signed into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, two questions &#8212; one about gun violence.&nbsp; And you just alluded to efforts to combat gun violence.&nbsp; The White House has recently touted these strike forces that are going into a few cities, talking about that.&nbsp; Are there any plans to expand that?&nbsp; Kansas City, for example, has had 91 homicides this year, most of them gun related.&nbsp; And how do these DOJ efforts differ from the ones that were going on in the Trump administration when there was a lot of ballyhooed effort about going into cities to fight crime?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not as familiar nor can I speak to the Trump administration efforts.&nbsp; What I can tell you is that the Department of Justice identified these five or six cities where officials from our team, who are experts, could work in lockstep to help crack down on gun trafficking and preventing guns from getting into the hands of people who shouldn&#8217;t have them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we will see.&nbsp; It&#8217;s early stages of the process.&nbsp; We will see what the success looks like.&nbsp; We&#8217;re quite hopeful.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of whether they have intention or plans to expand, I would point you to the Department of Justice and see what they have to say about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my question on evictions is: What role did Congresswoman Bush&#8217;s protests play?&nbsp; A number of Democratic leaders were giving her a lot of credit for raising the issue.&nbsp; I know the Vice President spoke to her Monday.&nbsp; What role did that play in the ultimate decision of the White House to move forward with the new order?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think anyone could hear Congresswoman Bush&#8217;s own personal story and experience and see her advocacy and her passion, and not be moved by that.&nbsp; I know a number of members of Congress were moved by that as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I will tell you is that the President had a number of calls with Speaker Pelosi over the weekend.&nbsp; Her advocacy, her commitment to looking to see &#8212; kicking every tire, just to go back to the analogy of yesterday &#8212; to see what was possible is something that was certainly impactful and influential with the President.&nbsp; But I would just reiterate that the President called for the extension of the moratorium&nbsp;&nbsp;back in January. &nbsp;CDC extended it three times. &nbsp;We also have spoken to this over the course of the past several months, and we&#8217;ve been in close touch with a range of members of Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, absolutely, the passion, the advocacy of a number of members is something that I think everybody watched closely, but I think it&#8217;s important to note that we all share the same objective and have from the beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a while, so I&#8217;m hoping to ask you two questions if that’s all right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First about the coronavirus pandemic, and then about &#8212; a follow-up to Governor Cuomo, the report on him.<br>&nbsp;<br>On COVID-19, former President Trump has called for China to pay the United States more than $10 trillion in reparations as a result of letting the coronavirus escape Wuhan and infect other countries causing, of course, 600,000 American deaths and economic devastation.&nbsp; President Biden hasn&#8217;t called for reparations from China.&nbsp; Does he support them?&nbsp; Does he think that China should pay us financially for what it has allowed to spread?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our policy hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, is he open to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Did you have another question?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; In a follow-up to the report on Governor Cuomo’s sexual harassment, a lot of men in politics have been accused of sexual harassment.&nbsp; President Biden was accused by female Secret Service agents of skinny dipping in front of them, offending them, according to former Washington Post reporter Ronald Kessler, who&#8217;s an author as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>His former Senate aide, Tara Reade, accused him of sexual assault.&nbsp; The Washington Post and The New York Times published multiple accounts of women who objected to the way President Biden touched them.&nbsp; Should there be an independent investigation of allegations into the President as there was into Governor Cuomo?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, the President has been clear and outspoken about the importance of women being respected and having their voices heard and being allowed to tell their stories and people treating them with respect.&nbsp; That has long been his policy, continues to be his policy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That &#8212; those were &#8212; that was heavily litigated during the campaign.&nbsp; I understand you&#8217;re eager to come back to it, but I don&#8217;t have anything further other than to repeat that he has called for the governor to resign.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If and when the Senate passes the bipartisan infrastructure deal, would President Biden like to see the House come immediately back into session, or is he okay waiting until the recess ends at the beginning of next month?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He certainly is going to be guided and be talking regularly with Speaker Pelosi about what she recommends and what she thinks is the best path forward looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you guys have said you guys are not going to return to lockdowns.&nbsp; Now, is that based just on current COVID conditions or &#8212; Dr. Fauci, today, in an interview warned that he is worried about a potentially worse variant that could more effect vaccinated people.&nbsp; So, is the guidance on lockdowns just based on current conditions or is that just a &#8212; and could change &#8212; or is it forever more are there not going to be lockdowns?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think Dr. Fauci and Dr. Collins have both spoken to this in recent days.&nbsp; And what they have conveyed and what it&#8217;s based on is the fact that we have made a significant amount of progress in the past six months &#8212; even as we are fighting the Delta variant, the most transmissible variant we have seen &#8212; and that includes 70 percent of the American people getting their first shot &#8212; 160 &#8212; more than 162 million Americans at this point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s progress.&nbsp; That ensures that a lot of communities are going to have a great deal of protection, and we&#8217;re in a different place than we were when there was the period of lockdown, so it&#8217;s a reflection of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Katie.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; The President, sort of, dismissed a question yesterday about whether he would call Governor DeSantis to discuss the situation on the ground in Florida.&nbsp; Does he feel that there is no point in personally reaching out to leaders in Texas and Florida?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, just to give you an understanding of how this works: Our team, led by COVID Coordinator Jeff Zients, is in touch with all of the governors and is &#8212; we are working closely with the Florida &#8212; Florida public health officials and the governor&#8217;s team to see if we can send a team down there to help address their needs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that is ongoing.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean we aren&#8217;t going to call out when we think there&#8217;s more steps that can be taken, but that&#8217;s an ongoing process, and we&#8217;re hopeful about making progress there moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And the President had a meeting earlier today about preventing future pandemics.&nbsp; Can you give us a readout on what he heard or discussed?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the administration learning about &#8212; about that issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the President&#8217;s view is that, even as we&#8217;re fighting the pandemic and we&#8217;re continuing to fight it, we need to do everything we can to prepare for future pandemics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That means making sure we have the funding we need, and we&#8217;re headed toward a historic number in this infrastructure bill on that front, but also making sure that he engages with our nation&#8217;s top scientists and experts &#8212; and Dr. Lander is certainly one of them &#8212; about how we should prepare, how we should think about preparing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it is part of an ongoing discussion and ongoing focus that we can&#8217;t keep our eye off of that, even as we&#8217;re fighting the current pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So does the President feel strongly that that funding should be preserved in the reconciliation package?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He feels confident there&#8217;s going to be a historic amount of funding in the reconciliation package and is pleased to see that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To go back to Cori Bush for a second, can I just confirm or ask: Did the President himself personally ever speak with Representative Bush?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe so, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And in terms of vaccines, what does the White House &#8212; or what does the administration intend to do to get other countries to step up and meet some of those vaccination goals?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know it was a part of the discussion at the G7, and there was a significant announcement made by G7 countries about their contribution to the global effort.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an important step forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think you&#8217;ve also seen international public health experts convey that we&#8217;re going to need 10 million &#8212; 10 billion, 11 billion &#8212; more doses than we currently have in the global community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think our effort is going to be continuing to make this a front-and-center discussion at global engagements, at global meetings, whether it&#8217;s UNGA or the G20 or meetings we will have in the future, because it is going to require all of the richest countries in the world, including the United States, to step up, to increase vaccine donations, to increase manufacturing capacity.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think it&#8217;s more about making it front and center in the global agenda, which the President is indicating he will intend to do &#8212; continue to do moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just two questions, Jen.&nbsp; The President &#8212; we know President Biden has called on Cuomo to resign &#8212; Governor Cuomo &#8212; but in the meantime, does the White House intend to strip him of his leadership position on those biweekly governor COVID calls?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure when the next one is scheduled.&nbsp; But again, I would convey that our objective is not to hurt the people of New York in the fight against COVID.&nbsp; If he is no longer the governor of New York, which is certainly what the President made clear of his &#8212; is his preference, then we will engage with other people.&nbsp; But we are not going to take steps to hurt the people of New York in the fight against COVID.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a second question.&nbsp; Should renters be prepared for the eviction moratorium to end for good on October 3rd?&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s thinking on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it really depends on whether there is legislative action or not.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more question on the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; I’ll approach it this way: The President may support the legal justification, but he also publicly gave voice to doubts about the constitutionality.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House&#8217;s message then to Americans who heard what happened yesterday, heard what was said at this podium on Monday, can’t square the two, and are now disappointed that the President is signaling that he doesn&#8217;t respect the rule of law.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure there are Americans evaluating it to that degree; maybe there are some of you have talked to, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; What the President has &#8212; his message to the American people, especially those who are concerned about losing their homes, being kicked out of their homes, is that he&#8217;s going to do everything in his power to make sure they can stay in their homes as long as possible.&nbsp; That is not just an extension of the eviction moratorium &#8212; which, obviously, a step was taken yesterday; it is also about using every tool at our disposal to get this money out.<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, states have the funding to extend the eviction moratorium in their own states.&nbsp; That&#8217;s because there was funding in the American Rescue Plan to get that done.&nbsp; So that includes asking his team, members of his Cabinet, whether it&#8217;s &#8212; whether it&#8217;s Secretary Fudge, who obviously made an announcement today, or the Department of Treasury, who made an announcement about the simplification of forms &#8212; that this is a priority, that they are to use all resources at their disposal to make sure they&#8217;re communicating with Americans, that we&#8217;re making it easy to get this funding out because that&#8217;s the overall objective.<br>&nbsp;<br>The overall objective is not about one tool; it is about keeping people in their homes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the President is a lawyer; spent 36 years in the Senate, was chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, eight years as Vice President, half a year as President.&nbsp; He speaks often about democracy versus autocracy.&nbsp; He&#8217;s issuing or overseeing this order from the CDC in the face of doubts about its constitutionality, which he seemed to echo yesterday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If there&#8217;s no inconsistency here, the President is &#8212; I mean, there are many people out there who say that the President is essentially not giving voice to the ethic that he campaigned on.&nbsp; He didn’t call Congress back.&nbsp;&nbsp; He asked Congress to act; it didn&#8217;t.&nbsp; How do you square all that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know I&#8217;m going to ask you who&#8217;s saying that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, there are plenty of people who are saying it.&nbsp; They are not just Republicans.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, I&#8217;ll leave that to others to figure out.&nbsp; But I think what&#8217;s important to note here is that the President would not have moved forward with a step where he didn&#8217;t feel comfortable and confident in the legal justification.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is also a reality that there are legal steps that have been taken by the Supreme Court in the last few months, and we have spoken to that publicly.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to hide from that.&nbsp; But he asked the CDC and his legal experts to look at what is possible.&nbsp; This is a narrow, targeted moratorium that is different from the national moratorium; it&#8217;s not an extension of that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a different moratorium, from a policy and legal standpoint.&nbsp; So, he felt comfortable in the justification and the legal approach to this effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A quick follow-up on that, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Uh-huh, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;You mentioned that the President is &#8220;old school,&#8221; and Steve noted that the President spent a significant amount of time in the Senate and is also a lawyer. &nbsp;When &#8212; what was the moment that the President became certain that he was on solid legal standing to move forward with this extension? &nbsp;And what was the argument &#8212; specific legal argument that won out and changed his mind? &nbsp;Because yesterday he seemed to be weighing the two &#8212; the two options.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, as I&#8217;ve been discussing, the justification from the legal team is that this is a different moratorium.&nbsp; It&#8217;s narrow.&nbsp; It&#8217;s targeted at the highest &#8212; at the areas highest impacted.&nbsp; It is not an extension of the national moratorium that was struck down just six weeks ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is the sense here that, you know, this is temporary, it&#8217;s still an open question about the constitutionality, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is temporary.&nbsp; It was extended until Oct- &#8212; or October 3rd.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, so it&#8217;s still a question of whether or not it&#8217;s constitutional but it&#8217;s worth it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t say that.&nbsp; I would &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know, but is that the sentiment?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He would not have advocated for and supported moving forward with something if he was not comfortable with the legal justification.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me just go around.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead to the middle here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two quick questions.&nbsp; First, I was hoping you could preview a little bit the President&#8217;s meeting tomorrow with the AAPI leaders.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just curious what they&#8217;ll be discussing and why you chose to invite them to the White House this week.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Well, I should have had more of a preview for you, but I will tell you that the President looks forward to meeting with leaders of the AAPI community tomorrow.&nbsp; They will discuss a range of topics including, of course, economic investment; the fight against COVID; voting rights, which is certainly an issue that is of great importance to a range of communities who have been quite active on this issue; and, obviously, continuing discrimination that members of the AAPI community experience.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve also &#8212; proud of the number of nominees from the AAPI community that we have put forward for a range of important jobs in the administration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But those are some of the topics on his agenda, and I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll come ready with a number of topics they also want to discuss.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one, quickly, just on COVID.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President, yesterday, was asked whether he thinks more cities and states should follow New York City&#8217;s lead and institute rules, you know, essentially requiring people to &#8212; who have been vaccinated to go to their restaurants and stuff like that.&nbsp; And he said, &#8220;I do,&#8221; but then he later seemed to suggest maybe it should fall more on those businesses.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I was just hoping you could clarify: Does the President &#8212; would he urge, you know, cities and states to follow New York City&#8217;s lead?&nbsp; Or does he feel that it&#8217;s more, sort of, a private-sector matter, where businesses should be the ones, you know, taking the lead on this type of thing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, both.&nbsp; I mean, there are steps that are going to be taken by localities.&nbsp; There will be steps taken by businesses.&nbsp; The President supports local efforts to keep communities safe; they&#8217;re going to be different from community to community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our view is that any verification program should meet a few standards: accessibility &#8212; it needs to be free and available in paper and digital formats; it should be secure and private; nondiscriminatory, given equity is at the center of our agenda.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But he does &#8212; we know &#8212; we will see more local communities do more and more things in this space, including verification and employee mandates that will incentivize vaccinations.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re encouraged and supportive of innovative steps at the local level.<br>&nbsp;<br>I just want to jump around.&nbsp; Go ahead, to the back.&nbsp; Yeah, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;ll go after.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Give &#8212; go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; One on Quad.&nbsp; Earlier this year, during the virtual summit, Quad countries decided on vaccine production.&nbsp; Has the President set a deadline or timeline for when these vaccines will be produced for the rest of the world?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe there&#8217;s a deadline that has been set.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; Let me see if there&#8217;s anything more specific.<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, working with the Quad on COVID vaccines is an important part of our &#8212; oh, let me see.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you for the question because I was like, I know something more on this.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our Quad partnership is on track to help produce at least 1 billion doses of COVID vaccines in India for the Asia region by the end of 2022.&nbsp; So, that is the timeline.&nbsp; Obviously, more &#8212; hopefully more sooner rather than later, but that&#8217;s the timeline for the work with the Quad.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My other question is about the kids of legal immigrants.&nbsp; Because of the aging-out process, many of them feel that they will be deported back to a country where they have never lived.&nbsp; Some of them have been moving around the city, meeting the congressmen, at the White House as well.&nbsp; One of them, at least, has met the President in Pennsylvania.&nbsp; Has the President given any assurance to these kids that, instead of focusing on their studies, they&#8217;ve &#8212; they are now right to focusing on (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; For DACA recipients?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The legal immigrants &#8212; kids of legal immigrants, not the DACA recipients.&nbsp; Because the aging-out process, they might be forced to go back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll have to check.&nbsp; Obviously, taking steps to ensure we are providing a legal pathway to citizenship, and especially for kids who came into this country, as you referenced, you know, innocently with their family members.&nbsp; But I will see if there&#8217;s anything new to report on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask about a different moratorium &#8212; the payments of student loans &#8212; that expires at the end of September.&nbsp; What is the White House doing, at this point, to get ready for that date and figure out next steps?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any preview for you on what determination will be made on that front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any information on how you&#8217;re preparing?&nbsp; I mean, we got to the point of the moratorium that we&#8217;ve been talking about earlier, where you&#8217;re at the date. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are you doing between now and that date?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are certainly well aware of the date, well aware of the impact.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview in terms of a decision.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I wanted to ask one more question about the Justice Department.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The slot for Solicitor General is still open.&nbsp; With<br>the Supreme Court ending &#8212; first session ending several months ago, at this point, and going into some cases that I&#8217;m sure the administration really cares about, where are you at on picking someone?&nbsp; And what are you doing to get ready for that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you on any personnel announcements or decisions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Shelby.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about a Harris Poll released this week that indicates the majority of Americans believe&nbsp;the worst of the pandemic is still ahead.&nbsp; And this is a big change from a few weeks ago.&nbsp; And so this is despite, as you said, 70 percent of Americans being vaccinated and CDC data showing that the vaccine is protecting vaccinated Americans from serious illness.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, why is the American public so panicked?&nbsp; And is the White House concerned at all that it&#8217;s fueled this dramatic shift in public sentiment?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That we have fueled it?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, through &#8212; you know, like returning the mask recommendations for vaccinated Americans.&nbsp; Is there &#8212; is it concerned at all?&nbsp; What can it point to as a reason for Americans &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t really taken a close look at this poll.<br>&nbsp;<br>What I will tell you is that a poll before this &#8212; I believe it was a CBS poll &#8212; showed that more vaccinated Americans were concerned about the rise of Delta than unvaccinated.&nbsp; So, it was &#8212; that was even prior to the mask guidance putting &#8212; being put in place.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly, as people see, you know, the rise in cases in certain communities &#8212; unvaccinated communities &#8212; of course that&#8217;s concerning.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp; But we also believe that it is our responsibility to provide accurate public health information and also make clear to people the impact of being vaccinated and the fact that the vaccines are doing exactly what they should do, which is protect the vast majority of people from serious illness and hospitalization.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, yes, we are &#8212; we know that it is a &#8212; it is a challenge.&nbsp; And fighting a pandemic and communicating about it is a challenge.&nbsp; But certainly, that&#8217;s why we do as many briefings as we do, why we come out here every day as we do, and why we’ll continue to allow our public health guidance to be &#8212; to be in the lead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, on infrastructure: The House Speaker is still saying that the reconciliation bill and the infrastructure bill should be connected.&nbsp; Which bill would the President like to see on his desk first: the bipartisan infrastructure bill or the reconciliation bill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President looks forward to signing both into law, and he&#8217;s eager to do that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve certainly made progress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ll also note that, on the reconciliation package &#8212; which I know we haven&#8217;t talked about a lot because the infrastructure bill has been front and center &#8212; but in the meantime, behind the scenes &#8212; which is, by the way, where most of the work happens in places like the White House &#8212; our legislative affairs team has had over 375 meetings and calls with members and senior congressional staff about just the reconciliation package.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there&#8217;s no preference from the President whether he wants to see the reconciliation first?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to stay in close coordination and rely on the guidance and leadership of Leader Schumer and Speaker Pelosi.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how does &#8212; as the leader of the Democratic Party, how does he get House Speaker Pelosi on the same page that they&#8217;re not connected?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think the President has been clear that he wants to sign both into law.&nbsp; We&#8217;re encouraged by the movement of the infrastructure package forward.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been doing a lot of work behind the scenes, and the President will continue to advocate for, publicly, the reconciliation package, given how important his Build Back Better agenda is to him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re told you have a hard out shortly.&nbsp; Just one or two more.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President made an announcement on Lebanon recovery today.&nbsp; Can you outline that for us?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, give us a sense &#8212; given the fact this is the one-year anniversary of that blast that devastated Beirut,<br>how important is Lebanon&#8217;s political and economic stability to the United States, given the crisis it’s in right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; It’s very important.&nbsp; On behalf of the country, the President sent his deepest condolences to all those who were injured, lost loved ones, and still struggle to recover from the trauma from the catastrophic explosion at the Port of Beirut one year ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, we actually did a video from him that we&#8217;re happy to provide to anyone who is interested.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also recognize that the people of Lebanon have suffered more over the past year because of avoidable political and economic crises.<br>&nbsp;<br>So what we announced today is &#8212; we &#8212; nearly $100 million in new humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; That is on top of the almost $560 million in humanitarian aid that we have provided to Lebanon over the last two years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We recognize the important role Lebanon has played in the region, as you referenced, and also their role in hosting over 1 million Syrian refugees for a number of years.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re quite proud of our longstanding support for the Lebanese people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President urges his fellow leaders in capitals around the world to also step up their support for the Lebanese people.&nbsp; No amount of outside assistance, of course, will be enough to repair the pain from the blast just last year.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Nikki, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Are there any plans for the President to hold a press conference before he goes to the beach?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect he might take some questions at some point, but no plans for a formal press conference.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got a lot going on here, as you all know.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, also any chance that Team USA might be visiting post-Olympics?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I hope so.&nbsp; They&#8217;re invited.&nbsp; I&#8217;m inviting them here to my house &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; anywhere you want to come.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I hope so.&nbsp; I have nothing to pre- &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything on the schedule, but certainly that&#8217;s a tradition and the President is probably as obsessed with the Olympics as I am, if not more, so I expect there&#8217;ll be an invitation at some point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we have to wrap it up to &#8212; thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Have a great day.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:41 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
