<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:40:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Roundtable with Transgender Women of Color Advocates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-transgender-women-of-color-advocates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council Julissa Reynoso hosted a roundtable at the White House with transgender women of color advocates from around the country. This event was the first in a series of listening sessions that will be convened by the White House-led Interagency Working Group&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council Julissa Reynoso hosted a roundtable at the White House with transgender women of color advocates from around the country. This event was the first in a series of listening sessions that will be convened by the White House-led Interagency Working Group on Safety, Inclusion, and Opportunity for Transgender Individuals, which was <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-advances-equality-for-transgender-americans/">announced</a> by the White House in June.</p>



<p>Participants discussed the epidemic levels of violence and harassment faced by transgender women and girls of color. They noted that discrimination, homelessness, intimate partner violence, poverty, unemployment, immigration and other systemic barriers take a disproportionate toll on transgender women and girls of color and are drivers of the violence visited upon transgender women of color. Participants shared their policy recommendations for advancing economic justice, opportunity, health equity, and safety for transgender individuals. They also highlighted the strength, resilience, and hope that drive their advocacy and the importance of creating more opportunities to lift up diverse voices from the transgender community and support their leadership.</p>



<p>Ambassador Rice and Co-Chair Reynoso shared their appreciation for the advocacy and policy recommendations provided by the participants. They reiterated that the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to advancing justice, opportunity, and safety for transgender women of color and all LGBTQ+ people and families in America. They emphasized that the Domestic Policy Council and Gender Policy Council will take an intersectional approach to advancing gender equity and racial justice as they lead the Interagency Working Group on Safety, Inclusion, and Opportunity for Transgender Individuals.</p>



<p>Participants in today’s roundtable included:</p>



<ul><li>Tori Cooper, Director of Community Engagement for the Transgender Justice Initiative, Human Rights Campaign</li><li>Ruby Corado, Founder, Casa Ruby</li><li>Sage Dolan-Sandrino, youth advocate, National Black Justice Institute</li><li>Andrea “Andy” Marra, Executive Director, Transgender Legal Defense &amp; Education Fund</li><li>Bamby Salcedo, President and CEO, TransLatin@</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Iranian-American Journalist and Activist Masih Alinejad</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/readout-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-iranian-american-journalist-and-activist-masih-alinejad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Iranian-American journalist and activist Masih Alinejad and her husband Kambiz Foroohar. During the meeting, Mr. Sullivan expressed concern for Ms. Alinejad’s family and colleagues who are detained in Iran. He affirmed the U.S. Government’s strong continued support for Ms. Alinejad’s work to advance universal human rights, particularly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Iranian-American journalist and activist Masih Alinejad and her husband Kambiz Foroohar. During the meeting, Mr. Sullivan expressed concern for Ms. Alinejad’s family and colleagues who are detained in Iran. He affirmed the U.S. Government’s strong continued support for Ms. Alinejad’s work to advance universal human rights, particularly her tireless efforts on behalf of women, the Iranian people, and all those unjustly detained by the Iranian government. Mr. Sullivan noted with concern the growing practice of authoritarian regimes such as Iran targeting dissidents, activists, and journalists across international borders, including within the United States. The U.S. Government will continue to strenuously oppose these illegal actions, which violate human rights and threaten the rules-based international order.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/memorandum-on-unexpected-urgent-refugee-and-migration-needs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 2(c)(1) of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (22 U.S.C. 2601(c)(1)) (MRAA), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 2(c)(1) of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs<br><br><br>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 2(c)(1) of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (22 U.S.C. 2601(c)(1)) (MRAA), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 2(c)(1) of the MRAA, that it is important to furnish assistance under the MRAA in an amount of up to $100 million from the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund for the purpose of meeting unexpected urgent refugee and migration needs, victims of conflict, and other persons at risk as a result of the situation in Afghanistan, including applicants for Special Immigrant Visas.  Such assistance may be provided on a bilateral or multilateral basis as appropriate, including through contributions to international organizations and through funding to other nongovernmental organizations, governments, and United States departments and agencies.<br><br>This determination supersedes Presidential Determination 2021-08 of June 11, 2021. <br><br>You are authorized and directed to submit this determination to the Congress, along with the accompanying Justification, and to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum for the Secretary of State on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/23/memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-state-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a2-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 21:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 652 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), and in order to provide assistance for refugees, victims of conflict,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 652 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), and in order to provide assistance for refugees, victims of conflict, and other persons at risk as a result of the situation in Afghanistan, including applicants for Special Immigrant Visas, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(1) &nbsp;the authority under section 506(a)(2) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $200,000,000 in articles and services from the inventory and resources of any agency of the United States Government and military education and training from the Department of Defense for the purposes and under the authorities of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(2) &nbsp;the authority to make the determination under section&nbsp;506(a)(2) of the FAA to direct such drawdown; and<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(3) &nbsp;the authority under section 652 of the FAA to make, before any such drawdown, the required notifications to the&nbsp;Congress.<br><br>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 23, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/23/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-23-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:14 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:  Hi everyone.  Happy Friday.  Okay, a couple of notes for you at the top. Today, the Biden-Harris administration took additional steps to provide stability and relief to homeowners who are still feeling the economic effects of the COVID-19 pandemic. HUD, USDA, and the VA announced details to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:14 P.M. EDT<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Hi everyone.  Happy Friday.  Okay, a couple of notes for you at the top.<br> <br>Today, the Biden-Harris administration took additional steps to provide stability and relief to homeowners who are still feeling the economic effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.<br> <br>HUD, USDA, and the VA announced details to help people with government-backed mortgages stay in their homes through monthly payment reductions and potential loan modifications.<br> <br>Homeowners could see reductions in their monthly payments of roughly 20 to 25 percent, allowing them to remain in their homes and build long-term equity.<br> <br>We&#8217;re working hard to get the word out to Americans who may benefit from these new programs.  And thanks to the work of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau and today’s actions, most servicers of mortgages are required to provide borrowers information about these options.<br> <br>Homeowners can visit ConsumerFinance.gov/Housing for up-to-date information and more details.<br> <br>Also would note, on our delegation in Haiti, the presidential delegation is safe and accounted for in light of the reported shootings outside of the funeral.  They’re on their way back to the United States. <br> <br>We are deeply concerned about unrest in Haiti.  In this critical moment, Haiti’s leaders must come together to chart a united path that reflects the will of the Haitian people. <br> <br>We remain committed to supporting the people of Haiti in this challenging time.<br> <br>Also, a vaccine-sharing update for you:  We shipped a record number of doses to a record number of countries this week.  Twenty-two million doses went out to 23 countries, including Guatemala, Senegal, Zambia, Niger, Gambia, El Salvador, Honduras, the Central African Republic, Cameroon, Lesotho, Panama, Vietnam, Georgia, Pakistan, Tanzania, Mozambique, Benin, Morocco, Tajikistan, Colombia, Madagascar, Liberia, and Eswatini. <br> <br>Our teams across the government are working to get more and more doses out every day, but this was a record week for our efforts to provide supply to the global community.<br> <br>Finally, week ahead: On Monday, the President will host an event in the Rose Garden to celebrate the 31st anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act, which the President proudly cosponsored as a senator.  While we have much work to do to realize the full aspiration of the ADA, our country has made progress toward its goals of equality of opportunity, full participation, self-sufficiency, and respect for the 61 million Americans with disabilities.<br> <br>Also Monday, the President will welcome Prime Min- &#8212; the Prime Minister of Iraq to the White House.  The Prime Minister’s visit will highlight the strategic partnership between the United States and Iraq, and advance bilateral cooperation under a Strategic &#8212; the Strategic Framework Agreement. <br> <br>The visit will also focus on key areas of shared interest, including through education, health, cultural, economic, energy, and climate initiatives.  President Biden looks forward to strengthening bilateral cooperation with Iraq on political, economic, and security issues, including joint efforts to ensure the enduring defeat of ISIS.<br> <br>On Wednesday, the President will travel to Pennsylvania and Lehigh Valley &#8212; in the Lehigh Valley area, where he will emphasize the importance of American manufacturing, buying products made in America, and supporting good-paying jobs for American workers.<br> <br>We&#8217;ll have more details for you over the weekend as things get finalized.<br> <br>Josh, why don&#8217;t you kick us off.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Two subject areas.  First, an AP-NORC  survey found that 45 percent of the unvaccinated say they would definitely not get vaccinated.   Another 35 percent say they probably won&#8217;t get vaccinated.   Why does this opposition still exist after all the public outreach?  And should more governments and employers mandate vaccinations?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, Josh, I think &#8212; let&#8217;s take a step back first.   In December, before the President took office, the percentage of Americans willing to get a shot was in the 30s.   Today, over 68 percent of adult Americans have taken a shot.  <br> <br>So, what that shows you is that, in a relatively short period of time, we&#8217;ve been able to influence a whole lot of people to change their minds, taken ac- &#8212; take action, get a shot, save their lives and the lives of people around them.<br> <br>I&#8217;d also note that we&#8217;ve seen some encouraging data over the last couple of weeks.  The five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, Missouri, and Nevada &#8212; had a higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average.   That is a good sign.  This is the second week in a row &#8212; I noted this last week.<br> <br>And finally, in the past 10 days, more than 5.2 million Americans have gotten a shot.  <br> <br>Now, there will be institutions, there will be private-sector companies, and others who make decisions about how to keep their communities safe.   That&#8217;s certainly appropriate, but I would just note that we&#8217;re going to continue our efforts to go community by community, case by case to convey the accurate information about the efficacy of vaccines.  <br> <br>Q    Gotcha.  Secondly, the Taliban has said that, as a condition for peace in Afghanistan, Ashraf Ghani has to be removed as President and a new negotiated government formed.  Does the administration believe that that&#8217;s in the best interest of the Afghan people and U.S. national security?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, the President and the administration supports the leadership of the Afghan people, including Ashraf Ghani.  The President was scheduled to speak with him today, I believe, and I don&#8217;t believe there&#8217;s a readout that&#8217;s come out about that call quite yet.  It may while we&#8217;re speaking here.  <br> <br>I would note that there are ongoing political negotiations and discussions that we certainly support between Afghan leaders, members of the Afghan government, and the Taliban.  And we believe a political solution is the only outcome to lasting peace in Afghanistan, but we will continue to provide support to the government in the form of humanitarian support, security support, training.  And we&#8217;ll also continue to encourage them to take a leading role in defending and protecting their own people.  <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Alabama&#8217;s Republican governor says it is &#8220;time to start blaming the unvaccinated folks&#8221; who &#8220;are letting us down.&#8221;   What do you think about that take?  Should the administration be taking a sharper tone against unvaccinated people for putting vaccinated people at risk?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I don&#8217;t think our role is to place blame, but what we can do is provide accurate information to people who are not yet vaccinated about the risks they are incurring not only among &#8212; on themselves, but also the people around them.  <br> <br>And while, if you are a young person, you may think you&#8217;re Superman or Superwoman and immune from the &#8212; from getting the virus, that is not true.   That is not accurate.   You can get very sick.  You can die from the virus.   You can also make your grandparents sick and your parents sick.  That is factual information.<br> <br>We&#8217;re not &#8212; but we&#8217;re not here to place blame or threats; we&#8217;re here to provide accurate information.<br> <br>Q    She says that she doesn&#8217;t know what else she can do at this point, that she&#8217;s hit a brick wall with trying to convince people to get vaccinated.  Is that a sign that perhaps the federal government should step in and issue mandates?  And if not, are you putting the needs of unvaccinated people ahead of the needs of vaccinated people?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think the question here &#8212; one, that&#8217;s not the role of the federal government; that is the role that institutions, private-sector entities, and others may take.  That certainly is appropriate.  Also, local communities are going to take steps they need to take in order to protect people in their communities.  <br> <br>I will say: We understand her frustration, and we understand the frustration of leaders out there and public voices who are trying to say the right thing, advocate for the efficacy of the virus, save people in their communities.<br> <br>What our role is and what we are going to continue to do is make the vaccine available.  We&#8217;re going to continue to work in partnership to fight misinformation.  And we&#8217;re going to continue to advocate and work in partnership with local officials and &#8212; and trusted voices to get the word out.<br> <br>Q    And is there something to be learned from our neighbors to the north &#8212; Canada?  They got a much slower start.  They didn&#8217;t have nearly as many vaccines as we did early on.  And yet, now they&#8217;ve shot past us, and 70 percent of their population is at least partially vaccinated.  What&#8217;s the difference between the two countries?  What can we learn from their experience?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would say 162 million Americans are now vaccinated.  That certainly is a positive step.  We&#8217;re the first to say and we have long said that that&#8217;s not enough.  We need to ensure more people and more communities are vaccinated.  And it is now &#8212; we reached a point where there are some communities, even states, where there are 70 percent, 80 percent, or higher vaccination rates. <br> <br>Other communities where there&#8217;s 40 percent, 50 percent, or otherwise, that&#8217;s not just a health issue &#8212; it&#8217;s a huge health issue &#8212; it&#8217;s an economic issue.  We&#8217;ve seen how that can impact local communities, as it may lead to shutdowns of different businesses.  That can have &#8212; it&#8217;s an economic issue as well.<br> <br>So, of course, we work in close partnership with our neighbors, but we have 162 million Americans vaccinated.  We&#8217;re the world&#8217;s largest provider of vaccines to the global community.  That&#8217;s progress, in our view, even as we&#8217;ve said from the beginning there&#8217;s more work to be done.<br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thank you.  About the economics of COVID that you just mentioned: Now that daily doses administered of the vaccine are down below 300,000 for the first time since December, we&#8217;ve heard talk about maybe updating the mask guidance.  Do you know if there&#8217;s been any talk here about updating guidance to start shutting businesses down in places that have very low vaccination rates?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No.  There has not been, no.<br> <br>Q    Okay.  And then on crime, generally &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Can I note, though, two things &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Yeah.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; just for your public information purposes?  One is that, while we have seen &#8212; while we don&#8217;t look at one week of data as an indication of &#8212; as you know, we talk about weekly averages &#8212; we did see larger numbers of unemployment claims in areas where there are lower vaccination rates.  We &#8212; it&#8217;s not enough data to draw a conclusion; I&#8217;m just noting it for all of you. <br> <br>I would also note that, on the American Rescue Plan, the way we designed that is for the impact and the assistance that we&#8217;re providing to communities across the country to be long-lasting &#8212; not to stop all in July or all in September.  It extends far beyond.  It was &#8212; that is a lesson learned from the past.  And so, there are different components of that package that&#8217;s providing assistance to businesses, to organizations, to communities that is going to be lasting for months to come.<br> <br>Q    Okay.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Proceed.<br> <br>Q    And then, on crime: The intersection in D.C. that was shot up last night, only about a mile and a half from here,  President Biden had lunch in that neighborhood this summer.  What is your message to innocent people who live in cities like this one who might start to get worried about getting caught in the crossfire?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I &#8212; the message is that the cornerstone of the President&#8217;s comprehensive plan to reduce gun violence is providing communities with the tools and resources they need to reduce gun crime, including in Washington, D.C.<br> <br>And there are a couple of steps specific to Washington D.C.  I mean, a lot of us live there or live in the neighboring communities, or know people who are on 14th street or in the neighboring areas.  And for people who are not &#8212; who are watching or hearing this who are not from those neighborhoods, there&#8217;s a lot of restaurants there, a lot of foot traffic.  This is a pretty popular part of &#8212; of the city many of us live in. <br> <br>It&#8217;s one of &#8212; D.C. is one of the five areas nationwide where DOJ launched gun trafficking strike forces just yesterday, which are going to for- &#8212; focus law enforcement resources across jurisdictions to keep guns out of the hands of criminals.<br> <br>D.C. is also a part of our 16 City Community Violence Intervention Collaborative, which is helping cities implement evidence-based strategies and which have been shown to reduce violence by as much as 60 percent.<br> <br>And Washington D.C. is also taking advantage of the historic funding that they&#8217;ve gotten through the Rescue Plan to bolster public safety.  So, Mayor Bowser&#8217;s budget proposal would invest $59 million from the Rescue Plan to reduce violent crime.  It would add 100 new slots to the cadet program and add $14 million for youth safety initiatives. <br> <br>So we&#8217;re certainly seeing this and feeling this, even in our community here, and it is one of the cities that DOJ is focused on.<br> <br>Q    And you just mentioned the White House is working with D.C. as part of this collaborative.  But just in the last week and a half or so since the mayor of D.C. was here, a six-year-old girl was shot and killed, a Nationals game had to be evacuated, and then there&#8217;s this incident last night where diners are diving for cover.  So, at what point would the President maybe reconsider his strategy?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say we&#8217;re just implementing our strategy, which is a multi-pronged effort to work in partnership with local leaders &#8212; including Mayor Bowser, who has been a great partner to us in this effort &#8212; to address gun violence that&#8217;s rising in cities across the country, including Washington.  And the events of the last week are just examples of that. <br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Secretary Yellen just said, before you came to the podium, that the Treasury Department will need to take extraordinary measures if the debt limit isn&#8217;t raised by August.  And she indicated those could run out shortly after lawmakers return, possibly as soon as October.  So, does the White House &#8212; are you guys setting a deadline?  Before recess, do you want to see that debt limit raised?  And what is the White House doing to urge lawmakers to address the debt limit?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  This is like the Olympics for Bloomberg, these days.  (Laughter.)  So, I would say &#8212;<br> <br>Q    And Reuters.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  And Reuters, sorry.  And other financial outlets in the room. <br> <br>Let me give you just a little bit of context, for those of you who have not seen the letter that just went from Secretary Yellen to the Hill. <br> <br>So, this is a letter that’s standard practice for Treasury Secretaries when a debt limit is going to be reimposed, which there&#8217;s a timeline coming up at the end of this month.  That is diff- &#8212; I&#8217;m not saying you&#8217;re suggesting this &#8212; that is different from defaulting, which has never happened in the history of the United States and would clearly be a catastrophic event.  But it is a timeline for the debt limit to be &#8212; to be raised or extended.<br> <br>So, during the previous two administrations, the Treasury Secretary sent nearly 50 letters to the Hill on the debt limit, some of which were very similar in wording and asks and updates to this letter.  And raising or suspending the debt limit does not authorize new spending commitments; it simply enables the government to pay for obligations that Congresses and Presidents of both parties have already approved. <br> <br>And Congress &#8212; finally the last piece of history &#8212; has raised or suspended the debt limit approximately 80 times, which has happened under both Republican and Democratic Presidents &#8212; I will say, just for historical fact, more often under Republican Presidents.<br> <br>But it has happened under both, and it has been supported in a bipartisan way.  So, we expect Congress to act promptly to raise or suspend the debt limit and protect the full faith and credit of the United States.<br> <br>Now, it is not &#8212; I gave you all the context because it is not out of the ordinary, even though they&#8217;re called “extraordinary measures,” for Treasury Secretaries to present to Capitol Hill steps that they are going to take, even as this is being litigated on Capitol Hill.  That was the &#8212; this is what &#8212; that was what this update was to provide.<br> <br>In that letter, she also noted that the period of time that extraordinary measures may last is subject to considerable uncertainty due to a variety of factors, which are exacerbated this year by uncertainty related to the pandemic and calculations about inflows and outflows.<br> <br>So, the October timeline that she &#8212; was referenced in there &#8212; or the October 1st date, I should say, was referenced &#8212; was because there&#8217;s a very large reduction in the cash balance on October 1st &#8212; or we&#8217;re projecting that &#8212; due to outflows on that day to meet our obligations to the Department of Defense.<br> <br>So, she was giving a sense of what the timeline looks like, while not &#8212; while also conveying that we can&#8217;t give a sense, at this point, on the length of time for extraordinary measures.  We certainly expect Congress to act in a bipartisan manner, as they did three times under the prior administration, to raise the debt limit.<br> <br>Q    But given that uncertainty, is the White House communicating to congressional leaders that you&#8217;d like to see this debt limit extended before the recess for August?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not here to set a new deadline.  I&#8217;m conveying to you the history and conveying to you that we think it&#8217;s clear Congress should act in a bipartisan manner to raise the debt limit as they have in the past.<br> <br>Q    And then just one more on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.  Is the White House getting involved in this dispute between Democrats and Republicans over transit funding?  And are you recommending any solutions as to how that should be resolved?  Are you backing Democrats who say it should remain with the 80/20 highway transit split? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Oh, transit funding is obviously extremely important to the President &#8212; the “Amtrak President,” as we may call him.  And &#8212; but we believe that &#8212; that members can get this work done and can work through these issues quite quickly.  <br> <br>And as you know, the issue is about the balance of funding and how it would be allocated between different forms of infrastructure.  But we&#8217;re encouraged by their progress, they&#8217;re having conversations, and we believe they can work through any disagreement. <br> <br>I&#8217;m just going to go to the back because I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m not always good at that. <br> <br>Mike Memoli, do you have a question today?<br> <br>Q    Yes, Jen.  Thank you.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.<br> <br>Q    We&#8217;ve talked a lot with &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You didn&#8217;t raise your hand, but usually have a question.<br> <br>Q    I often do.  We&#8217;ve talked about &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;ll go to the back, back too.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>Q    Now everyone is into it.  We&#8217;ve talked a lot about this, this week &#8212; the protocols that are in place at the White House &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yep.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; to ensure the President&#8217;s safety in &#8212; with COVID-19.  But we&#8217;ve seen over the last few weeks the President has been traveling the country quite a bit.  He&#8217;s been engaging in more uncontrolled environments.  He went to an ice cream stop.  He was on a rope line for almost an hour in Philly last week.  He&#8217;s doing a campaign event today.  And we &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Best hour he&#8217;s spent probably in probably a while.<br> <br>Q    Given &#8212; I remember well how COVID changed the way he would campaign &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; last year, what &#8212; to what extent is the rise in cases that we&#8217;re seeing in this country leading any discussions behind the scenes about whether the President would continue to engage in this kind of activity in public settings where you can&#8217;t control for people&#8217;s vaccinations?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  Well, first, we&#8217;re always going to abide by public health guidelines.  And right now, the public health guidelines continue to be that if you&#8217;re vaccinated &#8212; and we expect them to continue to be &#8212; if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you&#8217;re very much protected from severe illness from the virus. <br> <br>And the President will continue to be a model in following those guidelines and also engaging with the public in a manner that, one, is his role as President of the United States and is certainly aligned with and appropriate according to those guidelines.<br> <br>As you all know, he has an event later this evening with Governor &#8212; future governor, maybe &#8212; former Governor Terry McAuliffe in Virginia, where he will be certainly engaging with people and &#8212; with people of Virginia who are making decisions about their future leadership.  But I expect he&#8217;ll be engaging as he did at events last week.<br> <br>So, nothing has changed about our approach or protocols over the past week or how you&#8217;ve seen him engage at the ice cream shop or at larger crowd events we&#8217;ve had.<br> <br>Q    And then a question about infrastructure.  With some key votes coming up, obviously, next week, again, we&#8217;ve seen the President not necessarily engaging in the kind of meetings at the White House with lawmakers on this specific set of proposals in the way we have earlier on in the process.  He&#8217;s been meeting more with outside stakeholders.  It seems like there&#8217;s an outside-in pressure campaign.  But can you give us an update on what his specific conversations might be with lawmakers involved in this process?  We haven&#8217;t really heard much about that.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He has had a range of conversations with lawmakers over the phone.  And he&#8217;s always conveyed to his team that if it would be helpful to bring members down here, as he has continued to do, he&#8217;s always happy to do that.  The door to the Oval Office is always open.  And he is available and will be through the course of the weekend, but also through the coming pivotal weeks as we work to get the infrastructure package across the finish line in the Senate and also the reconciliation bill moving forward.<br> <br>Okay, we&#8217;re going to go all the way to the very back.  Todd Gillman, I see you somewhere there. <br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  So, the Texas Democrats who broke quorum from the legislature have &#8212; they&#8217;re about halfway through their one-month quorum break.  They&#8217;ve been trying really hard to get into a meeting, even if it&#8217;s a Zoom meeting, with the President.  Is he going to meet with them?  Is he specifically not meeting with them because of fears that they are spreading COVID?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No, he &#8212; the Vice President, who is leading our voting rights effort and our voting rights movement we&#8217;re building across the country, met with these lawmakers last week, as you all know.  And the President is very proud of their activism, their vocal support and advocacy for voting rights, but I don&#8217;t have any meetings scheduled for him. <br> <br>Q    And in a kind of similar vein regarding COVID: Will the First Lady be quarantined away from the President when she gets back from Japan? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  The First Lady will ca- &#8212; follow all public health guidelines.  I don&#8217;t believe that&#8217;s part of the protocols. <br> <br>All right, let&#8217;s go &#8212; let&#8217;s see &#8212; to the middle here.  I&#8217;m just jumping around today because, you know, trying better.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.   Does the White House have a reaction to Mississippi&#8217;s decision ask the Supreme Court to overturn Roe v. Wade? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, certainly, we are prominent sup- &#8212; or we are supporters &#8212; the President is a supporter of preserving Roe v. Wade.  That is our position.  In terms of a legisla- &#8212; or a legal reaction, I would point you to the Department of Justice.<br> <br>Let&#8217;s go to you, Patsy.  Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.   I have a question on China.  China just announced sanctions &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; against six individuals and an entity in the U.S. in retaliation of sanctions imposed by the Biden administration on Chinese officials over Hong Kong.  Do you think that this announcement will complicate or impact any plans for Deputy Secretary of State Wendy Sherman&#8217;s visit to Tianjin?  And is the administration concerned on the escalating sanctions &#8212; a potential escalating sanctions war?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I&#8217;m not aware of any changes to her planned trip.  And certainly, we discussed not only areas where we agree, but areas where we disagree when we have engagements and diplomatic meetings.<br> <br>In terms of the sanctions, we are aware, of course, of the reports that the PRC has imposed sanctions on several individuals and NGOs, including at least one official from the previous administration.  We’re undeterred by these actions and we remain fully committed to implementing all relevant U.S. sanctions authorities. <br> <br>These actions are the latest examples of how Beijing punishes private citizens, companies, and civil society organizations as a way to send political signals and further illustrate the PRC’s deteriorating &#8212; deteriorating investment climate and rising political risk. <br> <br>These actions would follow the baseless sanctioning in March of two commissioners from the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom.  The PRC’s January sanctions on 21 &#8212; 28 U.S. officials and their July 2020 sanctions on U.S. officials and organizations promoting democracy and human rights around the world.<br> <br>Americans of both parties oppose these outrageous moves to target those who defend universal human rights and fundamental freedoms.  And Beijing&#8217;s attempt to intimidate and bully internationally respected NGOs only demonstrate its further isolation from the world.<br> <br>Q    I do have another question on vaccine sharing.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Let&#8217;s keep going &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to keep going around because &#8212; go ahead.  Go ahead, in the back.  I&#8217;m just going to keep going around so I get to more people.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  On vaccines.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah. <br> <br>Q    You’ve been asked about the travel restrictions for international travel before &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; but I&#8217;m going to try something different.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.<br> <br>Q    Would the President drop those restrictions if airlines adopted vaccine passports or vaccine mandates?  I know you&#8217;ve, you know, sort of encouraged businesses to take steps to get everyone vaccinated that they possibly can. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say, first, that there are ongoing working groups that are having discussions about how to, hopefully, move forward to a point where there is international travel and is returning something we would all like to see &#8212; not just for tourism, but for families to be reunited. <br> <br>There are a range of topics in those discussions that are ongoing.  The President receives regular briefings on them, but we rely on public health and medical advice on when we&#8217;re going to determine changes to be made.<br> <br>Q    Has the President continued engaging with Chancellor Merkel on the subject?  I know they talked about that at the bilateral press conference the other week.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  That was raised.  He has not had another follow-up conversation with her since that point in time. <br> <br>Why don&#8217;t I go to the young man next to you.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  You know, a lot of parents are concerned about the upcoming school year.  What&#8217;s the White House doing to sort of make sure that we&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re not doing remote learning again nationwide? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, our plan and our objective and our desire and commitment is to push for and ensure 100 percent of schools are open across the country.  That&#8217;s also, of course, up to school districts to implement.<br> <br>But from the federal government, the role we have played is by work &#8212; advocating for funding in the American Rescue Plan that can help provide funding for mitigation measures for schools so that they can invest in social distancing opportunities or repairing vents that need to improve ventilation. <br> <br>We&#8217;re also &#8212; we&#8217;ve also put out public health guidance from the CDC that includes specific mitigation measures that schools can take. <br> <br>And our Secretary of Education has been focused on this issue from the first day he was sworn into office &#8212; working across school districts to share best practices and ensure we can work towards returning kids to in-school learning.<br> <br>Q    The Delta doesn&#8217;t change that, right?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Delta has not changed our public health guidelines, no. <br> <br>Okay, let&#8217;s go back to the front, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Just a quick follow-up on infrastructure.  On the transit spending &#8212; we know that&#8217;s important to the President &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; is that a red line for him?  If that is dropped from this package, would he still support it? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not setting red lines here, but we are confident that they can work through the funding issues and that &#8212; the breakdown of funding issues between Democrats and Republicans over the coming days. <br> <br>Q    And then one other question just on Alabama, and then I have one on Hunter Biden. <br> <br>On Alabama, the big concern here &#8212; and the reason why these comments from the governor are so alarming is because of the low vaccination rates.  Right?  So, is there some concern from the White House?  And does the administration fear that some elected leaders may just get so frustrated and accept this fact that there are just some people in this country that just may not want to get vaccinated?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I didn&#8217;t hear those comments as accepting the fact.  I heard those comments as being frustrated that &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s an effort to protect the citizens in your state and trying to figure out what steps you can take to encourage people to get vaccinated and save their lives and the lives of their loved ones. <br> <br>We always knew it would be harder as more people got vaccinated.  That&#8217;s the stage we&#8217;re in now.  But we also believe that there is still opportunity through a range of approaches and tactics and partnerships with governors and leaders and civic leaders to get more people vaccinated. There a range of factors &#8212; you all &#8212; many of you have reported on &#8212; that are leading individuals in these five states with lower vaccination rates to get vaccinated. <br> <br>Some are &#8212; is the Delta variant; and reporting, frankly; and fears of the transmissibility of the Delta variant.  Some is, unfortunately, individuals are experiencing people in their communities, family members who are getting sick and getting hospitalized because of the transmissibility of the Delta variant. <br> <br>I don’t think we have com- &#8212; complex data quite yet to determine what is leading to the increase in vaccination rates in some of these states, but we think that&#8217;s an encouraging sign.  We know it&#8217;s frustrating.  We get it.  But we have to stay at it to save people&#8217;s lives.<br> <br>Q    And last, on Hunter Biden: You confirmed yesterday that he will be meeting with prospective buyers, but you also said that he&#8217;s not going to have any conversation related &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Not that he&#8217;s meeting with prospective buyers &#8212; that he is attending gallery events that had been prior me- &#8212; prior planned and announced.<br> <br>Q    There could be prospective buyers there.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He&#8217;s not &#8212; those discussions will be happening with the gallerist.  But that is different than meeting with prospective buyers.<br> <br>Q    If there are prospective buyers there, you said, yesterday, that he is not going to have any conversations related to the selling of art.  How can the administration guarantee that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  The selling of his art will all happen through galler- &#8212; the gallerist, and the names and individuals will be kept confidential.  We will not be aware of, neither will he be aware of.<br> <br>Q    Is there anything stopping anyone from directly telling, though, Hunter Biden that they&#8217;re going to purchase his art?  And if they do, the American people won&#8217;t know who they are.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He will not know, we will not know who purchases his art.<br> <br>Go ahead, Jeff.<br> <br>Q    The President said yesterday that the 25-person COVID group is quote, &#8220;investigating every aspect of any change.&#8221;   What specifically are they doing or is he looking for them to do in regards to the Delta variant?  What information is he looking for them to bring back to him?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You mean the CDC &#8212; or discussions with our public health experts? <br> <br>I think what he was conveying, Jeff, is that he gets regular weekly, if not more frequent, updates from his COVID team about what is happening with the virus, the rise of certain variants, including the Delta variant, and certainly steps that they suggest we take as a result.  That&#8217;s an ongoing process. That&#8217;s not new. <br> <br>So, I think he&#8217;s, of course, looking for their updates and guidance on what the spread is, where we&#8217;re seeing the spread, what impacts we&#8217;re having, and any mitigation measures they recommend we take from a public health and data-driven perspective.<br> <br>Q    On testing specifically, does the President believe that more testing should be done?  It&#8217;s fallen some 75 percent or so since November.  What specifically do you think should be done or does he think should be done on testing?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He relies on the guidance of his health and medical experts.  If they are advising that that is a factor, then certainly his role would be to advocate for expanding it if &#8212; in his role as President, but that they obviously provide recommendations publicly as well.<br> <br>Q    And final thing here: You said it&#8217;s not your role to place blame, but a President has a remarkable ability to use the bully pulpit, pick up the telephone.  It happens all the time with &#8212; with corporations and things.  What is he doing specifically with celebrities, perhaps, or with business leaders &#8212; like we saw the NFL this week &#8212; to use his power of the office to try and get some companies or groups to do mandates or make changes?  Is he doing anything himself &#8212; reaching out like this?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You mean, aside from getting &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Aside from public speeches.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; aside from getting enough vaccine to &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Right.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; make sure every American is vaccinated; and donating more to the world than any other country; and ensuring we&#8217;re expanding accessibility to pharmacies, to community groups; and giving $3 billion to empower local voices to get into local communities to get people vaccinated?  I&#8217;d say that&#8217;s a fair amount that he&#8217;s done.<br> <br>Q    But you said, several times, that it&#8217;s not the role of the government to, essentially, you know, talk to private corporations.  But a President talks to corporations and leaders all the time, certainly during the Rescue Plan, when he was Vice President.  It happened all the time &#8212; talking to private corporations. <br> <br>If a corner is to be turned here on the hesitancy, is there anything that he believes that he personally can do among some different leaders &#8212; not giving a public speech, but that he can do?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I think, I referenced the $3 billion because the most powerful and impactful role we&#8217;ve seen across the country, from community to community, is engaging, educating, and empowering those trusted local voices.<br> <br>We know the President, the Vice President, Olivia Rodrigo, who we&#8217;re very grateful to, and others have been out there advocating for the efficacy of the vaccine, and we&#8217;re hopeful that&#8217;s effective.  And it can be.  And he&#8217;ll continue to do that, and we&#8217;ll continue to look to partner with more voices and more creative, you know, well-known individuals to elevate the issue of vaccine &#8212; of the effectiveness of the vaccine.<br> <br>But we&#8217;ve seen that’s &#8212; that, actually, local voices &#8212; people you may not know, who may not have a Twitter following &#8212; are actually the most powerful people in this fight, and we&#8217;ll continue to empower and fund those efforts.<br> <br>Go ahead.  Oh, Jeff, go ahead.  And then, I&#8217;ll go to Karen.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  Pfizer says the U.S. government is purchasing another 200 million doses of its vaccine &#8212; <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Mm-hmm.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; for children and for potential booster shots.  Can you confirm the purchase?  And can you say whether the thinking about the need for booster shots is crystallized within the administration?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  First, HHS has all the specifics, but, yes, we have made that purchase.  Here&#8217;s the bottom line: We&#8217;ve always prepared for every scenario.  The federal government is exercising an option in its contract with Pfizer to purchase these 200 million doses of the Pfizer vaccine to be delivered between the fall of 2021 and the spring of 2022 to prepare for future vaccination needs, including &#8212; as you referenced, Jeff &#8212; vaccines for children under 12 and possible booster shots, if studies show they are necessary.<br> <br>I will note, I have said from the podium many times that we were like Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts, and we were going to prepare for every contingency.  That&#8217;s the job of the federal government &#8212; right? &#8212; to ensure we have maximum flexibility.<br> <br>We don&#8217;t know if we&#8217;ll need a booster shot.  That&#8217;s going to be up to the research that&#8217;s ongoing with the FDA.  That&#8217;s not a recommendation that&#8217;s currently made. <br> <br>We also don&#8217;t know &#8212; we also can&#8217;t predict what the outcome will be of research on kids under 12.  We&#8217;re certainly hopeful.  And we don&#8217;t know which vaccine will be most effective, but we want to have maximum flexibility, so this is an effort to provide us with that.<br> <br>Q    All right.  And just one on infrastructure.  We understand that Senate negotiators are looking at repurposing COVID relief funds for hospitals and nursing homes to pay for the &#8212; parts of the bill.  Is that something the White House would support?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, there&#8217;s a range of final nitty-gritty discussions between both sides, but I&#8217;m not going to give feedback on each of the discussions from here.<br> <br>Okay, Asma, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Karen’s turn.<br> <br>Q    Karen, go.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Oh, Karen, sorry.  Go ahead, Karen.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Apologies.<br> <br>Q    Sort of keying off of what Jeff Zeleny was asking &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; the NFL is telling teams that they could potentially forfeit games for a COVID outbreak among unvaccinated players, and the players could lose their pay for any missed games.  Does the administration support a policy where players &#8212; or more broadly, employees &#8212; could lose pay if they are unvaccinated and cause a COVID outbreak at their place of work?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I&#8217;m not going to make a sweeping private-sector conclusion here.  What I will say is the NFL policy is making clear how they&#8217;re going to proceed with their season.  That&#8217;s their role to do.  Right?<br> <br>We certainly believe the biggest takeaway is that getting vaccinated is our ticket back to normal, and that vaccines are effective and allow all of us a high degree of protection, importantly, avoid hospitalization or death.  So, this provides &#8212; this is guidance they determined &#8212; the NFL &#8212; about how they&#8217;re going to proceed with their season.  That is their role to do.<br> <br>Q    And there&#8217;s a new model out from an organization that consults with the CDC, and it&#8217;s predicting that the current surge in cases right now could continue until a peak in mid-October.  The daily deaths potentially more than tripling where they are right now.  What can the President do right now to prepare Americans for that possibility?  He talked so much about the long winter last year.  What about a potentially long fall?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think the President&#8217;s role right now is to continue to encourage people to get vaccinated because it is incredibly effective in prodect [sic] &#8212; protecting them from serious illness, from death, from hospitalization from the virus.  That&#8217;s the most powerful role he can play at this point in time.<br> <br>George, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Hi, Jen.  This morning, the Cleveland Indians announced they&#8217;re changing their name to &#8220;Guardians,&#8221; and that&#8217;s already become an issue in the Ohio Senate race.  And the former President, just minutes ago, attacked it.  Any reaction by the President or the White House?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We certainly support their change of name.  We may be on the other side of the President &#8212; former President &#8212; on that front, I would guess.  I haven&#8217;t seen his tweet, or however he&#8217;s communicating these days.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Two questions on the vaccine.  First, you had mentioned yesterday that every individual at this White House has been, quote, &#8220;offered&#8221; a vaccine.  So, can you clarify, is the administration not mandating vaccines for White House staff?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No, we have not mandated.<br> <br>Q    Okay.  And do you have a count or can you offer any confirmation to us on the percentage of employees who are vaccinated?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I’m not going to provide that.  I will see if there is more information to provide.<br> <br>Q    Can you offer any guidance then on how you&#8217;re confirming vaccination status of employees?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, they&#8217;re vaccinated here in the White House Medical Unit, for the most part.<br> <br>Go ahead.  Oh, Kelly, I&#8217;m sorry.  I&#8217;ll come to you next.<br> <br>Q    Two questions: One, this administration has long claimed that you&#8217;re trying to be the most transparent in history.  If that&#8217;s the case, why won&#8217;t you just release the number of breakthrough cases that you&#8217;ve had of vaccinated staffers?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think, first, we&#8217;re in a very different place than we were six to seven months ago as it relates to the virus.  And as many medical experts have said &#8212; inside and outside of the government &#8212; those who are vaccinated are protected from serious illness, most are asymptomatic &#8212; if they are individuals who are vaccinated who get the virus.  And, you know, we are in a different place in terms of the impact of individuals who may have, as you said, breakthrough cases.<br> <br>Q    But why not just provide the number?  Are you trying to hide something?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No, but what is the &#8212; why do you need to have that information?<br> <br>Q    It&#8217;s a case of transparency, in the interest of the public, knowing &#8212; having a better understanding of how breakthrough cases work here in the White House.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, there are &#8212; the CDC tracks &#8212; and let me give you this information, too: The CDC tracks, across the country, of course, hospitalizations and deaths, as we have seen.  They also do a great deal of tracking in cohorts and ensure that &#8212; so, let me give you a little more information on this, which I think &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if it &#8212; hopefully, it&#8217;s of interest.<br> <br>So, the way that &#8212; because people have asked this before &#8212; so, the way the CDC is actively tracking breakthrough cases &#8212; there are tens of thousands of people across the country, in course, who are in what we are &#8212; what they call &#8220;cohort studies,&#8221; which the CDC is actively monitoring.<br> <br>For example, the CDC has a long-term care facility study where it is getting data from more than 14,000 long-term care facilities.  CDC has a healthcare worker study where they monitor vaccinated healthcare workers who got tested &#8212; who get tested with PCR tests every single week.  And CDC also collects what they call &#8220;passive surveillance,&#8221; which is where hospitals provide CDC with data when they identify someone who is hospitalized but has been vaccinated.<br> <br>So there&#8217;s a range of means our public health officials are tracking, across the country, across D.C., across any individuals here about who is vaccinated, who is getting the virus, getting hospitalized &#8212; hopefully not; it remains a small percentage.<br> <br>Q    And following up on the questions about Hunter Biden and his art shows.  Are there any specific procedures you can tell us that are being put in place to ensure that these conversations remain, as you say, not about the sales.  Will he get ethics training?  Will he have to report afterwards about the conversations?  Anything specific you can tell us about how you are monitoring this?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, again, I think it is certainly a commitment that has been made by all parties involved.  He is not involved in the sale or discussions about the sale of his art.  And he will not be informed of the sale &#8212; of the sale of his art and who is purchasing that art.  That is a commitment that&#8217;s been made, and we expect that all parties would abide by it.<br> <br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br> <br>Q    I wanted to ask about the CDC tracking &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; because &#8212; and you gave us some information just now, but &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; as of May 1st, they stopped tracking breakthrough cases that did not result in hospitalization or death, with the exception of those kinds of tests that you just described. Should there be a more broader net on breakthrough cases?  Would the President support that to get a better picture of breakthrough? <br> <br>And those White House employees, staff &#8212; EOP, on the campus in any capacity &#8212; who are not vaccinated, are they working here or are they working from home?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, any individual who has chosen not to be vaccinated, same as in the press corps, the public health guidance is to wear a mask.  That is the public health guidance that&#8217;s provided to employees as well.<br> <br>In terms of the &#8212; it is much more expensive than hospitalizations that &#8212; that was what I was trying to convey.  What the CDC does is they have these &#8212; they tra- &#8212; actively track breakthrough cases through these cohorts of individuals who are vulnerable populations, who are hi- &#8212; have high risks of exposure. And they, of course, incl- &#8212; as I noted &#8212; long-term care facilities, healthcare workers, and others who would be in those cohorts and categories.<br> <br>I would also note that because the vast majority of individuals who are vaccinated who get &#8212; test positive for COVID may be asymptomatic or have moderate or minimal cases, those are cases we may not know &#8212; we may not know about, right? <br> <br>Q    But they&#8217;re &#8212; the CDC says, as of May 1st, they stopped tracking breakthrough cases that don’t result in hospitalizations.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  They do track through these cohorts, which is a large swath of people who would be vulnerable or on the frontlines of exposure.<br> <br>Q    My periodic question: It’s now past &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; six months.  When can we expect to know about a physical exam for the President?  And what are the plans for that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  There is &#8212; absolutely he will have a physical exam.  Absolutely you will know about the physical exam.  I don’t have a date for you at this point in time.  And I expect you will continue to ask, as you should.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Yeah, Jen, thank you.  This is sort of a rhetorical question &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Oh.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; following up on vaccinations.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.<br> <br>Q    It is a shame that people have to get very sick and some people have to die in order to increase the vaccination rate in many parts of this country. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Mm-hmm.<br> <br>Q    But isn&#8217;t that, I guess, a logical order of how this would play out?  Or is there a political component to it, do you think? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m following your question.  Try again.  Or tell me more about what you&#8217;re looking for.<br> <br>Q    Well, wouldn&#8217;t it be standard practice that people, if more people are getting sick in a certain area, that the people in that area who are unvaccinated would say, “Gee, I really need to go get vaccinated.”  Isn&#8217;t that a logical order for this?  Or is there a political component, do you think, that has kept people away from being vaccinated? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Look, I think there are a range of reasons we&#8217;ve seen across the country why individuals have not yet been vaccinated.  Some of it is misinformation &#8212; a large amount, in our view.  Some of it is fear.  Some of it is, they may feel, time.  Some of it is they&#8217;re young, and they feel they&#8217;re Superman or Superwoman, and they&#8217;re not going to get sick. <br> <br>That shouldn&#8217;t be; we don&#8217;t want that to be the order of events.  It shouldn&#8217;t be that someone should have to know a neighbor who gets sick and hospitalized to motivate them to go to a hospital &#8212; I mean to go to get vaccinated.  We don&#8217;t want that to be the case. <br> <br>We have seen anecdotally and through some of your &#8212; all of your reporting that that has been the case in some communities.  But certainly, our objective is to communicate to people this is not a political issue, it is not a partisan issue; this is about protecting lives.  The virus does not discriminate between political party affiliation.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    The White House noted yesterday that 40 percent of cases are coming from three states with low vaccination rates: Florida, Texas, and Missouri. <br> <br>All three of those states have governors who, in recent weeks, have criticized the White House&#8217;s strategy.  One of them is even fundraising off of it, as you are probably aware. <br> <br>What&#8217;s being done to engage those governors, come up with a common message, common strategy to try and be one team with those governors in terms of fighting this virus? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, first, our public health experts work with governors from across the country and work with local health officials from across the country in all of these states, especially the ones at this point in time where there are lower vaccination rates and we&#8217;re seeing the Delta variant spread. <br> <br>And this is one of the reasons we rely so much on &#8212; hold on, I’m going to sneeze.  Okay, hold on.  Okay, maybe it will come back.  (Laughter.)  This is wh- &#8212; sorry, (inaudible) &#8212;<br> <br>This is why we rely on local messengers and why we rely on trusted voices.  Because whether it&#8217;s the President of the United States or the governor, sometimes those aren&#8217;t the people you trust.   Sometimes that is too political or partisan for people.  We understand that. <br> <br>That&#8217;s why we rely on and we&#8217;re funding and empowering local, trusted voices who aren&#8217;t seen through a political prism.<br> <br>Q    And then on the West Coast right now, we’re seeing wildfires in Oregon and Northern California. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    What steps is the administration taking to combat the current fires and also prevent additional fires this summer?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I appreciate you asking about this because I know this has gotten a lot of attention across the country, and we just haven&#8217;t talked about it a lot.  There&#8217;s so much going on.<br> <br>One, the President receives regular reports on the wildfire situation; he&#8217;s quite focused on it.  As I think you&#8217;re probably aware but others may not be, the National Wild- &#8212; Wildland Fire Preparedness Level is at a five, which is the highest level due to significant fire activity. <br> <br>And as of today, 2.5 million acres have burned across the United States. In the past two weeks alone the number of large, uncontained fires across the United States has increased by nearly 90 percent. <br> <br>So, right now, what we&#8217;re doing: One, the President is very focused on this and wants regular updates.  He&#8217;s regularly met with Western governors, and I expect we&#8217;ll do that again soon. <br> <br>The FEMA Administrator is visiting Idaho, Oregon, and California this week to meet with state, federal, and Tribal partners and emergency groups about worsen &#8212; the worsening wildfire situation, to coordinate response efforts and discuss how the regions are addressing climate change and ongoing resilience work. <br> <br>We are also closely coordinating with officials on the frontlines to provide federal assistance as needed, including by recently approving Fire Management Assistance Grants for fire departments in Oregon, California, and Washington, which are where there&#8217;s the collective threat to homes and major communities. <br> <br>And we&#8217;re also continuing to monitor the &#8212; monitor these fires from here.  Again, the President receives regular updates and he&#8217;s quite focused on this. <br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    On Cuba &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; Congresswoman Salazar says that the administration could turn the Internet back on for Cubans within minutes.  I guess there&#8217;s this technology to allow high-tech balloons to float over Cuba to act as towers.  What&#8217;s being done?  Or can you provide an update on restoring Internet services to Cuba? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I wish it was that easy.  We are exploring a range of options.  We are quite focused and interested in restoring Internet access to the people of Cuba, which we actually &#8212; which we absolutely believe, and agree, I would say, would provide information, would allow individuals to communicate.  And we feel if we can get it done, that would be a great step forward and beneficial to the people of Cuba.<br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thank you, ma’am.  You mentioned at the top that  Republicans had also increased the debt ceiling and certainly, you know, spending has been bipartisan for many years.  I&#8217;m wondering what the President&#8217;s long-term view of the country&#8217;s balance sheets are, given that under current long-term CBO estimates, debt is never again expected to dip below 100 percent of gross domestic product, and then, within 30 years, it is projected to hit 202 percent of gross domestic product. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would say the President has proposed a way to pay for his proposals, which is something that is a fiscally responsible step some of his predecessors &#8212; the most recent one &#8212; did not do when he worked and advocated to support the passing of $2 trillion in tax cuts that did not bear out the financial benefit he promised and also certainly added to the deficit.<br> <br>The President takes these issues seriously.  He is focused on being a President who cares about the future of our &#8212; the next generations.  And I think his actions have borne that out. <br> <br>Q    And then a quick follow-up:  There was a lot of discussion about masking the other day.  This administration has always followed CDC guidance. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    If the CDC was to say, “We need to return to masking,” would this administration follow suit?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We&#8217;re always going to follow the guidance of our health and medical experts. <br> <br>Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  On the vaccine immunity: Given that Pfizer&#8217;s now seeing waning immunity and separate from who is vaccinated and who is not, is the White House looking at models and projections that say, in the next year, as everyone who has been vaccinated could start to lose that immunity, what does that look like for hospitalizations and deaths, et cetera? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, I would certainly point to our health and medical experts to answer questions about future projections about the impact of waning immunity.  I will say that as they look at this data and assess from our &#8212; from the CDC and other public health entities in the government, they certainly talked to private-sector companies like Pfizer, but that&#8217;s only one source of data and engagement.  They look at a range of data across the board as they make projections.  So we really rely on their broad data and projections as we assess what the future looks like. <br> <br>Q    Just a follow-up on Afghanistan as well: You mentioned continuing U.S. support.  Does that include continuing military support?  I mean, we&#8217;ve seen a number of airstrikes that the U.S. has launched on Taliban targets over the last 30 days.  Could that continue past the end of the military mission at the end of August?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have anything on that for you.  I&#8217;d certainly point to the Department of Defense.  But what I&#8217;m &#8212; what I was communicating about was, you know, over the coming weeks, we maintain our authorities, as you know, and we provide &#8212; we’ve provided a range of training and security assistance equipment to the Afghans and the leaders of Afghanistan as we transition to bringing our men and women home. <br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Thanks so much, everyone.  Have a great weekend.<br> <br>2:04 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 19:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Presidential Delegation to the funeral of President Moise is safe and accounted for, and those traveling from Washington, D.C. have arrived safely back in the United States.&#160; The United States remains deeply concerned about the situation on the ground in Haiti. We strongly urge all parties to express themselves peacefully, and call on Haiti’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Presidential Delegation to the funeral of President Moise is safe and accounted for, and those traveling from Washington, D.C. have arrived safely back in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States remains deeply concerned about the situation on the ground in Haiti. We strongly urge all parties to express themselves peacefully, and call on Haiti’s leaders to be clear that their supporters must refrain from violence. In this critical moment, Haiti’s leaders must work together and engage in a broad and inclusive dialogue that is reflective of the will of the Haitian people. The Presidential Delegation, led by Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenfield, and joined by Representative Meeks and Representative Fortenberry, met with senior Haitian officials and civil society leaders and shared this message directly.<br><br>The United States will continue to provide requested assistance, including equipment and training, to the Haitian National Police and the Government of Haiti amid ongoing security challenges. Additionally, the Departments of Justice and Homeland Security are providing investigative assistance to the Haitian authorities at the request of the Government of Haiti, and will keep working closely with our international partners to support the Haitian government as it seeks to hold accountable those responsible for the assassination of President Moïse.<br><br>The United States stands with the people of Haiti in this challenging time.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How the Biden-Harris Administration Is Advancing Educational Equity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-how-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-educational-equity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As Schools Reopen, Vital PK-12 Investments Will Address Disparities, Build Back Our Schools on a Stronger and More Equitable Foundation, and Enable America to Compete Globally The last year and a half have been extraordinarily challenging for America’s students. As we prepare for the 2021-2022 school year, the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to helping every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>As Schools Reopen, Vital PK-12 Investments Will Address Disparities, Build Back Our Schools on a Stronger and More Equitable Foundation, and Enable America to Compete Globally</em></p>



<p><br>The last year and a half have been extraordinarily challenging for America’s students. As we prepare for the 2021-2022 school year, the Biden-Harris Administration is committed to helping every school safely open for full-time, in-person instruction; accelerate academic achievement; and build school communities where all students feel they belong. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, President Biden understands that addressing the immediate impact of the pandemic is not enough. For too many Americans—including students of color, children with disabilities, English learners, LGBTQ+ students, students from low-income families, and other underserved students—the promise of a high-quality education has gone unfulfilled for generations. Studies show the <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Gormley_et_al-2017-Journal_of_Policy_Analysis_and_Management.pdf">remarkable benefits of preschool programs</a>, but such programs are too often <a href="https://s3-us-east-2.amazonaws.com/edtrustmain/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/05162154/Young-Learners-Missed-Opportunities.pdf">out of reach</a> for children of color and low-income children. <a href="https://edtrust.org/resource/funding-gaps-2018/">Dramatically unequal funding</a> between school districts means some children learn in gleaming new classrooms, while students just down the road navigate <a href="https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED498100">unsafe and rundown facilities</a>. Amid a <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">nationwide teacher shortage</a>, high-poverty school districts struggle to attract certified staff and experienced educators. And students of color and children with disabilities face disproportionately high rates&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/crdc-exclusionary-school-discipline.pdf">of school discipline</a> that removes them from the classroom, with lasting consequences.<br><br><a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/cge">With 53 percent of our public school students</a> now students of color, addressing these disparities is critical for not only all our children, but for our nation’s collective health, happiness, and economic security. Consistent with the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/">Executive Order</a>, the Administration is committed to advancing educational equity for every child—so that schools and students not only recover from the pandemic, but Build Back Better. As First Lady Dr. Biden says, “Any country that out-educates us is going to outcompete us.” We will meet the challenges of the coming decades only by harnessing the full potential of every young person.<br><br>Taken together, the unprecedented investments already made in the American Rescue Plan—along with those proposed in the Build Back Better Agenda—will devote historic and vitally-needed resources that unlock opportunity for millions of Americans. These investments in evidence-based approaches will shore up schools struggling with the aftermath of COVID-19, tackle inter-generational educational disparities, address the holistic needs of children, and incentivize states to help our schools rebuild on a stronger and more equitable foundation.<br><br>To support the equitable education of every child at every step, the Administration will:</p>



<ul><li>Safely reopen schools and support students, particularly those disproportionately impacted by the pandemic;<br></li><li>Invest in high-quality early childhood education, including providing universal pre-school for all three and four-year-olds and access to affordable child care;<br></li><li>Address the national teacher shortage by improving teacher preparation, strengthening pipelines for underrepresented teachers, and supporting current teachers;<br></li><li>Upgrade and build new public schools and child care centers;<br></li><li>Expand college and career pathways for middle and high school students;<br></li><li>Make a historic $20 billion investment in high-poverty Title I schools;<br></li><li>Fund additional transformational investments to support the needs of the whole child, including community schools that provide wraparound services like afterschool programs, and hiring more counselors, social workers and school psychologists.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>ADVANCING EDUCATIONAL EQUITY IN THE AMERICAN RESCUE PLAN</u></strong><br><br>The President made clear on <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/21/executive-order-supporting-the-reopening-and-continuing-operation-of-schools-and-early-childhood-education-providers/">Day One of this Administration</a> that safely reopening schools was a national priority, signing an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/21/executive-order-supporting-the-reopening-and-continuing-operation-of-schools-and-early-childhood-education-providers/">Executive Order</a> that launched a comprehensive effort across the White House, Department of Education, and Department of Health and Human Services to safely reopen schools. The Department of Education has worked to support states and school districts in implementing CDC guidance for safe operations, and engaged education leaders across the country to collect and share best practices. The Administration has prioritized K-12 educator, staff, and child care vaccinations, and increased access to and awareness of vaccines among adolescents and their parents.<br><br>States, school districts, and schools are supported in this work by the American Rescue Plan’s historic and needed investment in our schools. This included $130 billion to support the safe reopening of schools and address the academic, social, emotional, and mental health needs of students—including $122 billion through the American Rescue Plan’s Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief Fund (ARP ESSER). This funding is being used to help schools safely operate, implement high-quality summer learning and enrichment programs, hire nurses and counselors, support the vaccination of students and staff, and invest in other measures to take care of students. Thanks to these efforts—combined with the Administration’s aggressive vaccination push and the hard work of state, district, school leaders, educators, and parents—the percentage of K-8 schools offering only remote instruction dropped from 23 percent in January to only 2 percent in May.<br><br>The American Rescue Plan recognizes and addresses <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/20210608-impacts-of-covid19.pdf">the disproportionate impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on underserved students</a>. Districts and states must spend a combined minimum of 24 percent of total ARP ESSER funds on evidence-based practices to address lost instructional time and the impact of the coronavirus on underserved students, such as summer learning and enrichment programs, comprehensive afterschool programs, and tutoring. School and district leaders must ensure that these efforts respond to students’ social and emotional needs as well. ARP ESSER includes a first-of-its-kind maintenance of equity requirement to ensure that high-poverty school districts and schools are protected from funding cuts. The American Rescue Plan also includes additional funding for students with disabilities, students experiencing homelessness, Tribal education, nutrition security, broadband access, and child care for low-income families.<br><br><strong><u>ADVANCING EDUCATIONAL EQUITY IN THE BUILD BACK BETTER AGENDA</u></strong><br><br>The resources in the American Rescue Plan, however, are not enough to address the deep educational inequities that have existed in our country since its founding. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda directly addresses longstanding educational inequities and will revitalize our education system so that students have the opportunities to learn and prepare for jobs in tomorrow’s economy, which includes ensuring the needs of the whole child are addressed.<br><br><strong><u>Make a historic investment to support students in high-poverty schools</u></strong>.<br>To ensure that every student—including those from underserved and under-resourced communities—can learn and thrive, the President’s discretionary budget request provides an additional $20 billion in funding for Title I schools. These investments will help address long-standing funding disparities between under-resourced school districts and wealthier districts:</p>



<ul><li><strong><em>Providing meaningful incentives to examine and address inequalities in school funding systems.</em></strong> There is a <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/overview/budget/budget22/justifications/a-ed.pdf">$23 billion annual funding gap</a> between white and nonwhite districts, and gaps between high- and low-poverty districts as well. A <a href="https://edtrust.org/resource/funding-gaps-2018/">2018 report from The Education Trust</a> found that the highest poverty districts receive 7 percent less per pupil in State and local funding than the lowest poverty districts.<br></li><li><strong><em>Promoting competitive teacher pay.</em></strong> In 2017, public school teachers <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/teacher-pay-gap-2018/">earned 18.7 percent less</a> in weekly wages than their peer group of college educated workers, up from only 1.8&nbsp;percent less in 1994. <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/education-k-12/reports/2014/07/23/94168/mid-and-late-career-teachers-struggle-with-paltry-incomes/">In many states, teachers with ten years of experience who head a household of four may qualify for public assistance.<br></a></li><li><strong><em>Increasing preparation for, access to, and success in rigorous coursework.</em></strong> Black and Native American students <a href="https://sites.ed.gov/underservedyouth/files/2017/01/MS3-Lead-Higher-Initiative-Finding-Americas-Missing-AP-and-IB-Students.pdf">participate in AP coursework at half</a> the national average<strong>.</strong> <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/crdc-course-access-report">While 87% of low-poverty schools provide calculus, only 45 percent of high-poverty schools do.</a> Lack of access to and preparation for success in mathematics and science coursework ultimately has a <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/education-k-12/news/2019/08/28/473876/advancing-racial-equity-career-technical-education-enrollment/">negative impact on the outcomes achieved by Black and Latino students in high-paying, in-demand STEM fields</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Boost early childhood care and education</u></strong><br>The President’s Build Back Better Agenda makes historic investments in our youngest learners, so that every child can succeed, paving the way for the best-educated generation in U.S. history.<br><br><strong><em>Establishing universal preschool</em></strong><br>Preschool is critical to ensuring that children start kindergarten with the skills and supports that set them up for success in school. However, <a href="https://s3-us-east-2.amazonaws.com/edtrustmain/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/05162154/Young-Learners-Missed-Opportunities.pdf">children of color are less likely to have access to high-quality preschool programs,</a><a href="https://nieer.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/NIEER-AchievementGaps-report.pdf%20with%20a%20furtherhttps:/nces.ed.gov/ecls/kindergarten2011.asp">resulting in disparate educational outcomes before students even enter kindergarten</a>. <a href="https://www.future-ed.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/Gormley_et_al-2017-Journal_of_Policy_Analysis_and_Management.pdf">Research shows</a> that kids who attend preschool programs are more likely to take honors classes and less likely to repeat a grade, do better in <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/bpea-articles/the-impacts-of-expanding-access-to-high-quality-preschool-education/">math and reading</a>, <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28756/w28756.pdf?utm_campaign=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_medium=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_source=PANTHEON_STRIPPED">and are more likely to graduate from high school and enroll in college</a>. Impacts are particularly strong for <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w23215/w23215.pdf">children from low-income families</a>, and children with disabilities benefit from inclusive, accessible preschool programs with their peers<a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w23215/w23215.pdf">.</a><br><br>President Biden’s plan would establish a national partnership with states to offer free, high-quality, accessible, and inclusive preschool for all three-and four-year-olds. This will benefit five million children, and save the average family $13,000 a year on preschool tuition. This historic investment in America’s future will prioritize high-need areas first, establishing universal programs in these communities, so that all students can access them, facilitating the creation of diverse classrooms that are best for all students. It will also enable communities and families to choose the setting that works best for them, whether that’s a preschool classroom in a public school, family child care provider or child care center, or a Head Start program. The President’s plan supports low student-to-teacher ratios, high quality standards, and inclusive classroom environments.<br><br><strong><em>Make high-quality child care affordable and accessible</em></strong><br>High-quality early care and education helps ensure that children can take full advantage of education and training opportunities later in life, especially for children from low-income families and children of color, who disproportionately <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/digest/d19/tables/dt19_202.30b.asp">lack access</a> to good child care options and who face <a href="https://rhyclearinghouse.acf.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/docs/18755-Disparities_in_Early_Learning_and_Development%5Bfull%5D.pdf">learning disparities</a> before they even can go to preschool. President Biden’s proposal will ensure that low- and middle-income families can access affordable, high-quality, child care. The most hard-pressed working families would pay nothing, and families earning 1.5 times their state’s median income would spend no more than 7 percent of their income on child care for their young children. The plan will also provide families with a range of inclusive and accessible options to choose from, from child care centers to family child care providers to Early Head Start programs. Child care providers will receive funding to support the true cost of quality early childhood education, which will allow them to provide care that is accessible and inclusive of children with disabilities.<br><br>The President’s investments in child care and preschool will also support early childhood educators, more <a href="https://nwlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ChildCareWorkersFS.pdf">than nine in ten</a> of whom are women and more than <a href="https://nwlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ChildCareWorkersFS.pdf">four in ten</a> of whom are women of color. <a href="https://cscce.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/ReportFINAL.pdf">One report found that nearly half</a> rely on public income support programs. The President’s plan establishes a $15 minimum wage for these educators and ensures those with similar qualifications as kindergarten teachers receive comparable compensation and benefits.<br><br>And the President’s proposal will extend the American Rescue Plan’s expanded Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit so that families can instead choose to get a credit for up to half of their child care expenses, saving up to $8,000 per year.<br><br><strong><u>Invest in our teachers.</u></strong> Few people have a bigger impact on a child’s life than a great teacher. Unfortunately, the U.S. faces a <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">large and growing teacher shortage</a>. Before the pandemic, <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">schools needed an estimated additional 100,000 certified teachers</a>, resulting in key positions going unfilled, the granting of emergency certifications, or teachers teaching out of their certification area. Shortages disproportionately impact <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf">students of color </a>and rural communities. In schools with the highest percentage of students of color, the percentage of teachers who are uncertified is more than <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/understanding-teacher-shortages-interactive?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIlZbktfGP8AIVg-DICh10CQyXEAAYAiAAEgJgV_D_BwE">three times as large</a> as in schools with the lowest percentage of students of color. The percentage of teachers in their first or second year of teaching is <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/understanding-teacher-shortages-interactive?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIlZbktfGP8AIVg-DICh10CQyXEAAYAiAAEgJgV_D_BwE">70 percent higher</a>. While access to <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">teachers of color benefits all students and has a particularly strong impact on students of color</a>, only around <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat11.htm">one in five</a> teachers are people of color, compared to <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator_cge.asp">more than half</a> of public school students.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda will increase support for teacher preparation and invest in Grow Your Own programs and year-long, paid teacher residency programs. These programs have a significant impact on <a href="https://www.aft.org/sites/default/files/ae_spring2017guha_hyler_and_darling-hammond.pdf">student outcomes and teacher retention</a>, and <a href="https://www.aft.org/sites/default/files/ae_spring2017guha_hyler_and_darling-hammond.pdf">are more likely to enroll underrepresented teacher candidates, including candidates of color</a>. The plan would also invest in teacher preparation at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and Minority-Serving Institutions. The President has also called for increased investments in certifications in high-demand areas like special education and bilingual education, and is urging Congress to invest in programs that leverage teachers as leaders, such as high-quality mentorship programs for new teachers. These investments will improve the quality of new teachers, increase retention rates, and grow the number of teachers of color—all of which will improve student outcomes like <a href="https://mrbartonmaths.com/resourcesnew/8.%20Research/Improving%20Teaching/Teaching%20Experience.pdf">academic achievement</a> and <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">high school graduation rates</a>, resulting in <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/Diversifying_Teaching_Profession_REPORT_0.pdf">higher long-term earnings, job creation, and a boost to the economy</a>. As more teachers stay in the profession, districts will <a href="https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/product/the-cost-of-teacher-turnover">save money</a> on recruiting and training, and can invest more in programs that directly impact students.<br><br><strong><u>Expand career pathways for middle and high school students.</u></strong><a href="https://ies.ed.gov/ncee/wwc/interventionreport/671">Strong dual enrollment programs</a> increase college enrollment, and graduation. High-quality career and technical education models have significant positive effects on <a href="https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED570132.pdf">high school graduation, increase college enrollment, and improve wages</a>. The President’s plan would provide more students with access to high-quality career and technical education programs that expand access to computer science; connect underrepresented students to careers in STEM and in in-demand, high-growth industry sectors; that include partnerships with institutions of higher education, employers, and other stakeholders; and that allow students to engage in quality work-based learning opportunities, earn a credential, and/or earn college credit.<br><br><strong><u>Eliminate inequitable school infrastructure conditions</u>. </strong>According to one national study, <a href="https://infrastructurereportcard.org/cat-item/schools/">there is a $38 billion gap</a> between the current infrastructure spending on schools and actual infrastructure needs. The <a href="https://infrastructurereportcard.org/cat-item/schools/">American Society of Civil Engineers gives American school infrastructure a grade of D+.</a><a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/letters/colleague-resourcecomp-201410.pdf">Students of color are more likely to attend schools with rundown and unsafe facilities</a>. <a href="https://ajph.aphapublications.org/doi/pdfplus/10.2105/AJPH.2009.165324">Poor physical school conditions are associated with increased rates of student absenteeism, with one study finding poor ventilation associated with a 10 to 20 percent increase in student absences</a>. While the American Rescue Plan provides critical resources for improving ventilation systems, it does not provide sufficient resources to address all health and safety needs, let alone long-overdue investments to increase energy efficiency, ensure our schools have the technology and labs to prepare students for jobs in tomorrow’s economy, or build new buildings where needed. President Biden’s plan supports investments to upgrade and build new public schools, ensuring that all our children have equal access to healthy learning environments that prepare them for success. It also invests in upgrading child care facilities and increasing the supply of child care in areas that need it most.<br><br><strong><u>Addressing lead in schools</u>. </strong>There is no safe level of lead exposure for children. Lead can slow development and cause learning, behavior, and hearing problems in children, as well as lasting kidney and brain damage. Communities of color are <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nceh/lead/prevention/populations.htm">at a higher risk</a> of lead exposure. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make significant investments towards the elimination of all lead pipes and service lines in the country, and reduce lead exposure in our schools and child care facilities, improving the health of our country’s children, including in communities of color.<br><br><strong><u>Increasing broadband access for students and families</u>. </strong>Broadband internet is critical to learning. Yet, by one definition, more than 30 million Americans live in areas where there is no broadband infrastructure that provides minimally acceptable speeds. <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/internet/fact-sheet/internet-broadband/?menuItem=d5edf003-5858-4269-89c5-f2889ecf7951">In urban areas, there is a stark digital divide: a much higher percentage of white families report having a home broadband internet than Black, or Latino families</a>. <a href="https://aipi.asu.edu/sites/default/files/tribal_digital_divide_stimulus_bill_advocacy_04032020.pdf">Native families in their tribal communities also lack sufficient access to high-speed internet.</a><a href="https://msutoday.msu.edu/news/2020/poor-internet-connection-leaves-rural-students-behind"> One Michigan study</a> found that 47 percent of students who lived in rural areas had broadband access at home, compared to 77 percent of those in suburban areas. The last year made painfully clear the cost of these disparities, particularly for students who struggled to connect while learning remotely. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make historic investments in building “future proof” broadband infrastructure in unserved and underserved areas, so that we finally reach 100 percent high-speed broadband coverage.<br><br><strong><u>Electrifying school buses for safe student travel</u>. </strong><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4476560/">One study finds</a> that when children ride buses with clean air technologies, they experience lower exposures to air pollution, less pulmonary inflammation, and reduced absenteeism. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework would make a down payment on electrifying our yellow school bus fleet.<br><br><strong><u>Increase support for children with disabilities.</u></strong> All children, including those with disabilities, should be provided the services and support they need to thrive in school and graduate ready for college or a career. The discretionary request provides an historic $2.6 billion increase for Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) grants that support special education and related services for children with disabilities in grades preschool through 12. This funding would, for the first time in eight years, increase the federal share of the cost of providing services to children with disabilities, and is a significant first step toward fully funding IDEA. The discretionary request also includes an additional $250 million for IDEA Part C, which supports early intervention services for infants and toddlers with disabilities or delays, and funds services that have a proven track record of improving academic and developmental outcomes. This increase in funding would be paired with reforms to improve access to these vital services for underserved children, including children of color and children from low-income families.<br><br><strong><u>Prioritize the physical and mental well-being of students.</u></strong> The discretionary request provides $1 billion to increase the number of counselors, nurses, and mental health professionals in schools, prioritizing high-poverty schools.<br><br><strong><u>Support full-service community schools.</u></strong> Community schools play a critical role in providing comprehensive wrap-around services to students and their families, from afterschool to adult education opportunities to health and nutrition services. The discretionary request increases funding for these schools from $30 million to $443 million, an over ten-fold increase.<br><br><strong><u>Foster diverse schools.</u></strong> Schools play vital roles in bringing communities together. But, too many of the nation’s schools are <a href="https://cepa.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/wp19-06-v092019.pdf">still largely segregated by race and class</a>, mirroring their communities. The discretionary request includes $100 million for a new voluntary grant program to help communities develop and implement strategies to build more diverse student bodies. As part of their application, applicants would be required to demonstrate strong student, family, teacher, and community involvement in their plans. Applicants would have flexibility to develop and implement school diversity plans that reflect their individual needs and circumstances, and improve educational opportunities and outcomes for students.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Administration Announces Additional Actions to Prevent Foreclosures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-announces-additional-actions-to-prevent-foreclosures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Across America, a strong economic recovery is taking hold. Since President Biden took office, more than 3 million jobs have been created—600,000 a month on average. The American Rescue Plan is working, jumpstarting the economy and getting Americans back to work. And critically, over two-thirds of adults are vaccinated, with our most vulnerable populations protected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Across America, a strong economic recovery is taking hold. Since President Biden took office, more than 3 million jobs have been created—600,000 a month on average. The American Rescue Plan is working, jumpstarting the economy and getting Americans back to work. And critically, over two-thirds of adults are vaccinated, with our most vulnerable populations protected at even higher rates. In every state, jobs are up and American workers and families are looking ahead to a brighter future.<br><br>Shortly after taking office, the Biden-Harris Administration extended the foreclosure moratorium and mortgage forbearance enrollment period for homeowners with government-backed mortgages to provide relief to struggling homeowners. On June 24<sup>th</sup>, the Administration extended the foreclosure moratorium for a final, additional month until July 31, 2021 and the forbearance enrollment window through September 30, 2021, and provided up to three months of additional forbearance for certain borrowers. These actions were taken by three federal agencies that back mortgages – the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), and Department of Agriculture (USDA). The Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA) provided similar relief for mortgages backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac.<br><br>This helped ensure that American families did not lose their homes during the pandemic. Those policies prevented foreclosures and allowed some homeowners with government-backed loans to pause their mortgage payments for up to eighteen months. Nearly 7.2 million American households took advantage of forbearance options.<br><br>Thanks in part to President Biden’s strategy to get Americans vaccinated and the economy back on track, the number of American households in forbearance has fallen by more than 50% from its pandemic peak. Today, approximately 1.75 million Americans remain in forbearance. In order to ensure a stable and equitable recovery from the disruptions of the COVID-19 pandemic and prepare for homeowners to exit mortgage forbearance, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking action to keep Americans in their homes and support a return to a more stable housing market. &nbsp;<br><br>Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration is:<br><br><em>Offering Borrowers Loan Modifications and Payment Reductions that Will Help Them Stay in Their Homes</em><br><br>With over 160 million Americans fully vaccinated and every American offered the opportunity to get vaccinated, along with an improving economy and more Americans getting back to work, many homeowners exiting mortgage forbearance are returning to their pre-pandemic earnings and are no longer facing financial hardship associated with the pandemic. For homeowners who can resume their pre-pandemic monthly mortgage payment and where agencies have the authority, agencies will continue requiring mortgage servicers to offer options that allow borrowers to move missed payments to the end of the mortgage at no additional cost to the borrower.<br><br>However, many homeowners will need deeper assistance due to pandemic-related income loss. For example, due to the economic crisis caused by the pandemic, some homeowners are earning less than they were before the pandemic. Homeowners with government-backed mortgages that have been negatively impacted by the pandemic will now receive enhanced assistance, especially if they are looking for work, re-training, having trouble catching up on back taxes and insurance, or are continuing to experience hardship for another reason. The new steps the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Department of Agriculture (USDA), and Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) are announcing will aim to provide homeowners with a roughly 25% reduction in borrowers’ monthly principal and interest (P&amp;I) payments to ensure they can afford to remain in their homes and build equity long-term. This brings options for homeowners with mortgages backed by HUD, USDA, and VA closer in alignment with options for homeowners with mortgages backed by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac.<br><br>Specifically, where agencies have the authority and depending on homeowners’ financial conditions, agencies will require or encourage mortgage servicers to offer borrowers new payment reduction options to help them remain in their home.</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>HUD:&nbsp;</u></strong>The Federal Housing Administration (FHA) announced enhanced loss mitigation tools and simplified a COVID-19 Recovery Modification to help homeowners with FHA-insured mortgages who have been financially impacted by the COVID-19 pandemic. These options will offer borrowers appropriate relief while preserving flexibility for future crises. FHA will require mortgage servicers to offer a no cost option to eligible homeowners who can resume their current mortgage payments. For all borrowers that cannot resume their monthly mortgage, HUD will enhance servicers’ ability to provide all eligible borrowers with a 25% P&amp;I reduction. Based on recent analyses, the Administration believes that the additional payment reduction offered to struggling borrowers will result in fewer foreclosures. To achieve those goals, HUD will implement the following options over the next few months:<br><br><strong>COVID-19 Recovery Standalone Partial Claim:&nbsp;</strong>For homeowners who can resume their current mortgage payments, HUD will provide borrowers with an option to continue these payments by offering a zero interest, subordinate lien (also known as a partial claim) that is repaid when the mortgage insurance or mortgage terminates, such as upon sale or refinance;<br><br><strong>COVID-19 Recovery Modification:&nbsp;</strong>For homeowners who cannot resume making their current monthly mortgage payments, the COVID-19 Recovery Modification extends the term of the mortgage to 360 months at market rate and targets reducing the borrowers’ monthly P&amp;I portion of their monthly mortgage payment by 25 percent. This will achieve significant payment reduction for many struggling homeowners by extending the term of the mortgage at a low interest rate, combined with a partial claim, if partial claims are available.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>These options augment additional COVID protections HUD published last month. These included the foreclosure moratorium extension, forbearance enrollment extension, and the COVID-19 Advance Loan Modification: a product that is directly mailed to eligible borrowers who can achieve a 25% reduction to the P&amp;I of their monthly mortgage payment through a 30-year loan modification.&nbsp; HUD believes that the additional payment reduction will help more borrowers retain their homes, prevent future re-defaults, help more low-income and underserved borrowers build wealth through homeownership, and assist in the broader COVID-19 recovery.</p>



<ul><li><strong>USDA:</strong>&nbsp;The USDA COVID-19 Special Relief Measure provides new alternatives for borrowers to help them achieve up to a 20% reduction in their monthly P&amp;I payments.&nbsp; New options include an interest rate reduction, term extension and a mortgage recovery advance, which can help cover past due mortgage payments and related costs.&nbsp; Borrowers will first be assessed for an interest rate reduction and if additional relief is still needed, the borrowers will be considered for a combination rate reduction and term extension. In cases where a combination of rate reduction and term extension is not enough to achieve a 20% payment reduction, a third option combining the rate reduction and term extension with a mortgage recovery advance will be used to reach the target payment.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>VA:</u></strong>&nbsp;VA’s new COVID-19 Refund Modification provides multiple tools to assist certain borrowers in achieving a 20% reduction in the dollar amount for monthly P&amp;I mortgage payments. In some cases, even larger reductions are possible. One such tool is the new COVID-19 Refund option, where VA can purchase from the servicer a borrower’s COVID-19 arrearages and, if needed, additional amounts of loan principal (subject to an overall cap corresponding to 30% of the borrower’s unpaid principal balance as of the first day of the borrower’s COVID-19 forbearance). Similar to VA’s COVID-19 partial claim option, the COVID-19 Refund will be established as a junior lien, payable to VA at 0% interest. In addition, servicers can now achieve significant reductions in the dollar amount for monthly payments by modifying the loan and adding up to 120 months to the original maturity date (meaning the total repayment term can be up to 480 months).<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>FHFA</u></strong>: HUD, USDA, and VA’s steps bring federal agency options closer in alignment with payment reduction and loan modification options for borrowers with Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac mortgages. FHFA’s existing COVID loss mitigation options provide servicers with homeownership retention tools for borrowers. The tools include a payment deferral option that allows borrowers to resume their pre-COVID monthly payment after deferring up to 18 months of missed mortgage payments into a non-interest-bearing balloon. The missed payments do not have to be repaid until the homeowner sells or refinances the property. Borrowers requiring more significant help may receive a loan modification that targets up to a 20% reduction in their monthly mortgage payments. The Flex Modification (Flex) capitalizes all past due amounts, extends the mortgage up to 40 years and in some cases lowers the interest rate and provides for principal forbearance.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Additional Assistance</strong><br><br>In addition to these new opportunities for borrowers, agencies across the federal government are also taking other steps to support borrowers as our economic and public health recovery continues. &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Homeowner Assistance Fund</u></strong>: In addition, the Homeowner Assistance Fund (HAF), a critical component of President Biden’s American Rescue Plan, provides $9.961 billion to states, D.C., territories, and Tribes for relief to homeowners impacted by the COVID-19 economic crisis. These funds can be used for assistance with mortgage payments, homeowner’s insurance, utility payments, and other specified purposes – and homeowners can access these funds in addition to the payment reduction options discussed above. And they will be integrated into the payment reduction options outlined above – providing additional payment reduction to borrowers who need it and to borrowers whose mortgages are not backed by federal agencies.</li><li><strong><u>Extended Term Option: </u></strong>Finally, the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae) recently announced it is creating a new security product for modified loans that would provide government agencies the flexibility to extend mortgage terms to up to 40 years, if they choose to do so, for borrowers who are behind on their mortgages and would benefit from the monthly payment reduction associated with this option.  Ginnie Mae expects this extended term product will be available for use in late 2021.</li></ul>



<p><em>Giving Borrowers the Information They Need to Understand their Options</em><br><br><strong>These new loan modification and payment reduction options will only give borrowers the relief they need if borrowers have the information to understand their options.</strong></p>



<ul><li>Homeowners can visit <a href="http://www.consumerfinance.gov/housing">consumerfinance.gov/housing</a> for up-to-date information on their relief options, protections, and key deadlines.</li><li>As federal agencies continue working to implement housing assistance for American families, CFPB offers this website as a one-stop shop for homeowners to learn about programs and resources that can help them stay in their homes by reducing the risk of eviction and foreclosure.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Borrowers should contact their servicer or housing counselor as soon as possible to learn more about the options available.</strong></p>



<ul><li>Last month, HUD, VA, and USDA announced steps to ensure that no new foreclosures are filed on mortgages backed by those agencies until borrowers are reviewed for new and improved options to make their monthly payments more affordable.</li><li>In addition, FHFA will continue to work with Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac to ensure that borrowers are evaluated for home retention solutions prior to any referral to foreclosure.</li><li>The CFPB finalized a mortgage servicing rule that requires most servicers to meet temporary procedural safeguards before filing foreclosures for most mortgages through the end of the year. The CFPB’s rules also require that mortgage servicers provide information to borrowers about their options.</li></ul>



<p><strong>For borrowers not currently in forbearance, there is still an opportunity to access relief.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li>HUD, VA, and USDA announced that they will continue to allow homeowners who have not taken advantage of forbearance to date to enter into COVID-related forbearance through September 30, 2021.</li><li>Homeowners with Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac-backed mortgages who have COVID-related hardships will also continue to be eligible for COVID-related forbearance.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Haiti to Pay Respects upon the Death of His Excellency Jovenel Moïse, Former President of the Republic of Haiti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-haiti-to-pay-respects-upon-the-death-of-his-excellency-jovenel-moise-former-president-of-the-republic-of-haiti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Haiti to pay respects upon the death of His Excellency Jovenel Moïse, Former President of the Republic of Haiti The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation. Members of the Presidential&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Haiti to pay respects upon the death of His Excellency Jovenel Moïse, Former President of the Republic of Haiti</p>



<p>The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong></p>



<p>The Honorable Michele J. Sison, U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Haiti</p>



<p>The Honorable Gregory Meeks, Chairman of the House Foreign Affairs Committee</p>



<p>The Honorable Jeff Fortenberry, Member of Congress, U.S. House of Representatives</p>



<p>The Honorable Daniel Foote, Special Envoy to Haiti, U.S. Department of State</p>



<p>The Honorable Juan S. Gonzalez, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere, National Security Council</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before a Meeting With Business and Labor Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-meeting-with-business-and-labor-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 4:43 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, I’m delighted you’re all here.&#160; I’m meeting with a group of labor and business leaders who &#8212; and this is one of those meetings I’ve been looking forward to. They&#8217;re not here to negotiate with one another.&#160; The good news is they&#8217;ve been here negotiating &#8212; not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>4:43 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I’m delighted you’re all here.&nbsp; I’m meeting with a group of labor and business leaders who &#8212; and this is one of those meetings I’ve been looking forward to.</p>



<p>They&#8217;re not here to negotiate with one another.&nbsp; The good news is they&#8217;ve been here negotiating &#8212; not negotiating &#8212; supporting what we’re trying to get done on the infrastructure bill.</p>



<p>And I know that we&#8217;re looking for this bipartisan effort to get this infrastructure bill passed.&nbsp; As you all know, and they share my belief that it&#8217;s both in the interest of business and labor to get this done.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and it’s about &#8212; not about energy versus environment, it’s not about business versus labor; it’s all about, basically, a race to the future.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve been traveling the world lately and &#8212; back out where I used to spend a lot of time, in the G7 and meeting with the summits with the Russians, as well as NATO.&nbsp; And I tell you, the rest of the world is looking to see whether we can get something done.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The single-biggest issue &#8212; I know you’ve travelled the world, all of you &#8212; and the fact is that they’re trying to figure out whether we&#8217;re so divided that we can&#8217;t get something done.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I&#8217;m convinced that they&#8217;re convinced now that we have an opportunity to make some real fundamental changes that generate growth in the future.</p>



<p>You know, the days used to be that we were in a position where the United States invested more money in research and development three, four decades ago than any nation in the world.&nbsp; Now we’re number eight.&nbsp; And it used to be that China was &#8212; was number nine, and now they&#8217;re number two.</p>



<p>This is about a race for the 21st century.&nbsp; And you know &#8212; and what we&#8217;re doing here is, in this race for the future, it&#8217;s about connecting Americans &#8212; all Americans, rural and urban &#8212; to high-speed Internet, repairing our roads and our bridges so that we can, in fact, no longer be ranked number 9 or 10 in terms of infrastructure in America.&nbsp; Back to what we used to be &#8212; we used to lead the world.</p>



<p>You know, electrify our school buses and our transit systems.&nbsp; And we’re going to build national charging networks for electric vehicles; eliminate the nation&#8217;s lead service pipes.&nbsp; We got 400,000 home- &#8212;</p>



<p>I mean, there&#8217;s just a whole lot we can do that&#8217;s going to put a lot of people to work.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to improve the life of a lot of people.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to update our power grid &#8212; which, as you saw what happened to Texas last year, there&#8217;s a lot we can do.&nbsp; It’s going to generate &#8212; and, Lonnie, your (inaudible) is going be awful busy, and &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. STEPHENSON:&nbsp; We&#8217;re ready.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going &#8212; we have to win the comp- &#8212; we really do.&nbsp; This is not hyperbole.&nbsp; We have to win the competition for the 21st century.&nbsp; That’s really what&#8217;s at stake, and I think you all know that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the Bipartisan Infrastructure does, in my view.</p>



<p>I want to thank everyone here for supporting it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to get into the details, among all of us, about what we think about what needs to be improved, what can be made better or worse.&nbsp; You know, so, we want everybody to be engaged.</p>



<p>So, thank you all, folks, for being here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to now get down to business.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what conversations have you had with public health officials about possibly changing the mask mandate for vaccinated Americans?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll respond to the COVID question quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We follow the science.&nbsp; What&#8217;s happening now is all the major scientific operations in this country and the 25-person group we put together are looking at all the possibilities of what&#8217;s happening now.</p>



<p>We have a pandemic among the nonvaccinated &#8212; those who are not vaccinated.</p>



<p>If you are vaccinated, you are safe.&nbsp; If you are vaccinated, you have over a 98 percent chance of never catching the virus at all.&nbsp; And if you catch it, you&#8217;re likely to &#8212; overwhelming proof, so far, is you&#8217;re not going to be hospitalized, you&#8217;re not going to be sick, you&#8217;re going to probably have no signs that you had it, and you are not going to die.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a simple proposition.</p>



<p>And what they&#8217;re doing is they&#8217;re going into &#8212; investigating every aspect of any change that could or might take place.</p>



<p>But the vaccines are good against all of the variants that are out there, including the Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you so much for being here.</p>



<p>4:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
