<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 20:12:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on FTC Vote to Protect Children’s&#160;Privacy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-from-president-biden-on-ftc-vote-to-protect-childrens-privacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 20:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the State of the Union I said that it is time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children and demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children.  I want to commend the Federal Trade Commission for unanimously taking a big step in that direction today.    When children and parents access&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In the State of the Union I said that it is time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children and demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children.  I want to commend the Federal Trade Commission for unanimously taking a big step in that direction today.    When children and parents access online educational products, they shouldn’t be forced to accept tracking and surveillance to do so.   The FTC is making it clear that such requirements would violate the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, and that the agency will be cracking down on companies that persist in exploiting our children to make money.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Regional Appointments for USDA, EPA, and&#160;HHS</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/president-biden-announces-key-regional-appointments-for-usda-epa-and-hhs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and Department of Health and Human Services (HHS): Joy Kono, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Hawaii Maria Herrera, USDA State Director, Rural Development, California&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and Department of Health and Human Services (HHS):</p>



<ul><li>Joy Kono, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Hawaii</li><li>Maria Herrera, USDA State Director, Rural Development, California</li><li>Casey Sixkiller, EPA Regional Administrator, Region 10</li><li>Joseph Palm, HHS Regional Director, Region 7</li></ul>



<p>These regional appointees will be critical to the President’s efforts to rebuild communities most impacted by the pandemic, the economic recovery, and climate change. They bring deep expertise in their issue areas as well as critical relationships with federal, state, tribal, and local leaders. And, consistent with the President’s commitment to building an administration that looks like America, these regional appointees represent the diversity of America and the communities they serve.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE (USDA)</u></strong></p>



<p>The USDA’s Farm Service Agency implements agricultural policy, administers credit and loan programs, and manages conservation, commodity, disaster, and farm marketing programs in each U.S. State. Its mission is to equitably serve all farmers, ranchers, and agricultural partners through the delivery of effective, efficient agricultural programs for all Americans. State Executive Directors oversee this work, ensuring the needs of local constituents are met and that USDA resources are distributed equitably and fairly.</p>



<p>USDA’s Rural Development mission area is committed to helping improve the economy and quality of life in rural America. State Directors lead offices that offer grants, loans, and loan guarantees to help create jobs and support economic development and essential services.</p>



<p><strong><u>Joy Kono, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Hawaii</u></strong></p>



<p>Joy Kono has over 30 years of managerial and administrative experience in support programs, along with a first-hand understanding of the challenging and diverse agricultural industry of Hawaii. Kono comes from a rural community on the island of Kauai, where her family farmed a variety of vegetables and livestock, ranging from chickens, pigs, and cattle, to truck crops and leafy greens. Kono began work on the farm at 12 years old, spending her college summers working on a ranch. As a dedicated farm family on Kauai, they were awarded Hawaii Farm Bureau’s Farm Family of the Year.</p>



<p>Kono earned a Bachelor’s degree in Agriculture Economics from the University of Hawaii at Manoa and then obtained a Master’s degree in Agribusiness from Santa Clara University.</p>



<p>Kono worked for Kamehameha Schools for the last 20 years; her current position oversees four teams that process over 30,000 applications annually for various programs. Appointed as Senior Director of Education Support Services in 2015, Kono has administered numerous programs that provides crucial support across the state of Hawaii to families and students that apply for over $30 million in aid each year. Kono is currently the board chair for the Hawaii Commission for National and Community Services and has served on the Agriculture Leadership Foundation of Hawaii Board and the Hawaii Farm Bureau Board.</p>



<p><strong><u>Maria Herrera, USDA State Director, Rural Development, California</u></strong></p>



<p>Maria Gallegos Herrera<a> </a>is a proud daughter of farmworker parents who grew up in the rural agricultural communities in the heart of California’s San Joaquin Valley. She joined the Office of Governor Gavin Newsom in 2019 as the Central California Deputy Regional Director of External Affairs and in July of 2021 was promoted to Central California Regional Director.</p>



<p>Herrera previously served as a Community Development Manager at Self-Help Enterprises, a nationally recognized community development organization dedicated to working with low-income families to build and sustain healthy communities. She previously held positions at the Community Water Center and the California Department of Food and Agriculture. Throughout her career, Herrera has tackled water contamination and shortages, improved access to government, and worked to create resilient and sustainable communities through relationship building, community organizing, advocacy, legislation, and technical assistance. Herrera also served on the California Water Commission from 2015 to 2019 and was the recipient of the 2019 Rachel’s Network Inaugural Catalyst Award.</p>



<p><strong><u>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY (EPA)</u></strong></p>



<p>Regional Administrators lead the EPA’s 10 regional offices around the country, each of which is responsible for the execution of EPA programs within a set of several states and territories. EPA regional offices also ensure the views and needs of each region are incorporated into the formulation of agency and national policy.</p>



<p><strong><u>Casey Sixkiller, EPA Regional Administrator, Region 10</u></strong></p>



<p>Casey Sixkiller previously served as Deputy Mayor of the City of Seattle and prior to that as Chief Operating Officer of King County, overseeing the daily operations of the largest city and the largest county in Washington state, each with more than 12,000 employees and an annual budget of $6.5 billion. While at the City, Sixkiller oversaw key elements of the City’s pandemic response including support for vulnerable families, mitigating the impact of the pandemic on city services, and helping scale nation-leading testing and vaccination efforts. At King County, Sixkiller worked to embed measurable equity and social justice deliverables across departments, increase equitable access to public space and transit, and lift up the voices of BIPOC communities in decision making. Sixkiller was the founder and managing partner of Sixkiller Consulting, a Washington, D.C.-based national strategic advisory, public policy, and business development firm.</p>



<p>Sixkiller began his career in public service in Washington, D.C., first working for then-Representative Jim McDermott (D-WA) and later Senator Patty Murray (D-WA). An enrolled citizen of the Cherokee Nation, Sixkiller helped launch the Cherokee Nation’s Washington Office in 2001, serving as the Nation’s lead advocate before Congress and federal agencies. Born and raised in Seattle, Sixkiller is a graduate of Seattle Public Schools and Dartmouth College, and the proud father of Anna, Sam, and Will.</p>



<p>Region 10 serves Alaska, Idaho, Oregon and Washington.</p>



<p><strong><u>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES (HHS)</u></strong><br>Regional Directors lead HHS’s 10 Regional Offices that directly serve state and local organizations. Regional Directors ensure the Department maintains close contact with state, local, and tribal partners and addresses the needs of communities and individuals served through HHS programs and policies.</p>



<p><strong><u>Joseph Palm, HHS Regional Director, Region 7</u></strong></p>



<p>Joseph Palm is a native of Saint Louis, Missouri, with family roots in Wardell, Missouri. Palm received his Bachelors of Communications Studies and Masters in Public Health from Saint Louis University. In 2009, Palm became the Chief of the Office of Minority Health at the Missouri Department of Health and Senior Services. As the Chief, Palm was the key advisor to the Director on various health matters that affect minorities; he also served as a liaison to the Missouri General Assembly and worked with all statewide local public health agencies and elected officials. Palm supervised the Centers for Disease Control (CDC) grant-funded opioid and homicide prevention program, and he has also advised and facilitated the creation of hundreds of mobile COVID-19 testing and vaccination sites across the State of Missouri in uninsured and underserved communities. Palm has also worked on the ground during the Ferguson and Joplin daily recovery operations.</p>



<p>Palm previously worked as the Assistant to the Chief of Staff in the City of Saint Louis Mayor’s Office, as a Legislative Researcher in the Missouri State Capitol, and as an assistant to the Chief of Staff in Missouri’s 1<sup>st</sup> Congressional District Office.</p>



<p>Region 7 serves Iowa, Kansas, Missouri, and Nebraska.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meeting with Prime Minister Andersson Of Sweden and President Niinistӧ of&#160;Finland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-andersson-of-sweden-and-president-niinist%d3%a7-of-finland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland and warmly welcomed their applications for NATO membership, which will strengthen our collective security.  At this historic moment for both Finland and Sweden, the President underscored his commitment to support both countries as they seek&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland and warmly welcomed their applications for NATO membership, which will strengthen our collective security.  At this historic moment for both Finland and Sweden, the President underscored his commitment to support both countries as they seek formal NATO accession, including by working with NATO Allies and Congress to welcome them into the Alliance as quickly as possible.  The leaders also discussed their ongoing cooperation on shared global challenges, and their commitment to continued strong support for Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on New Actions to Address Infant Formula&#160;Shortage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/19/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-new-actions-to-address-infant-formula-shortage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 12:09 P.M. EDT MR. MUNOZ:&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Thank you for joining us this afternoon for a background press call to discuss yesterday&#8217;s new actions that are going to address the infant formula shortage in the United States and expand access to safe infant formula. This call will be on background, attributable to “senior&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>12:09 P.M. EDT<br><br>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us this afternoon for a background press call to discuss yesterday&#8217;s new actions that are going to address the infant formula shortage in the United States and expand access to safe infant formula.<br><br>This call will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; It&#8217;ll be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.<br><br>On today&#8217;s call, we have [senior administration officials].<br><br>We have a, you know, download at the top on yesterday&#8217;s actions, and then we&#8217;ll take a few questions.<br><br>With that, I&#8217;ll kick it to [senior administration official].</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; President Biden knows that parents across the country are worried about finding enough infant formula to feed their baby.&nbsp; That is why he directed his administration to do everything possible to ensure that there is enough safe infant formula in the country available for families that need it.<br><br></p>



<p>Yesterday, the President invoked the Defense Production Act to ensure that manufacturers have the necessary ingredients to make safe, healthy infant formula here at home.</p>



<p><br>The DPA empowers the government to require suppliers to direct needed resources to infant formula manufacturers before any other customer who may have ordered that good.<br><br>Yesterday, the President gave HHS the authority to order suppliers to direct needed resources to infant formula manufacturers before any other customer who may have ordered that good.<br><br>So with this authority, we can direct firms to prioritize and allocate the production of key infant formula inputs as needed.&nbsp; This can and will help increase production and speed up supply chains.<br><br>Just an example of how this works: There are a range of things needed to make formula &#8212; oil, fat blend, labels, cans.&nbsp; The company that makes one of those items, like a label, have a lot of customers, one of which happens to be infant formula manufacturers.&nbsp; And they are likely a very small share &#8212; those infant formula manufacturers are likely a very small share of the overall market for that good.<br><br>By having DPA authority available for infant formula, we make sure formula manufacturers are at the top of the list for that item and can maintain the higher levels of production that the companies put in place in February to address the shortage caused by the Abbott plant being shut down.<br><br>Additionally, as the Abbott plant in Sturgis, Michigan, ramps up production over the coming weeks and months, there could be a tightening of supplies across key infant formula inputs.&nbsp; DPA authorities, for example, can be used to prioritize production of key equipment that can help suppliers expand.<br><br>And last, with some important context, DPA authorities were invoked similarly at the outset of the COVID-19 pandemic to prioritize needed supplies to fight the pandemic.<br><br>Yesterday, President Biden also announced Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible.<br><br>Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services and U.S. Department of Agriculture will use Department of Defense contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards so it can get to store shelves faster.<br><br>Bypassing traditional cargo routes will speed up the importation and distribution of formula and serve as an immediate support as manufacturers continue to ramp up production.<br><br>These announcements build on previous administration actions, including an agreement by the FDA and Abbott Nutrition detailing next steps to reopen Abbott Sturgis plant, FDA guidance that will allow major formula manufacturers to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market, efforts to cut red tape and provide consumer flexibility on types of formula they can provide, and calling on the Federal Trade Commission and State Attorney General to crack down on price gouging or unfair market practices.<br><br>This is one of the President&#8217;s top priorities, and the administration will continue working overtime to get more formula to stores as soon as possible.<br><br>Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Let&#8217;s take a few questions.&nbsp; Ali Rogan, PBS.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this call.&nbsp; What have formula companies been telling you about what they need in terms of these raw materials and in terms of flight support?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; <a>So, what the companies have told us is that they have been able to ramp up production quite rapidly since February, and in some instances, 50 percent to 30 percent above their normal production levels.&nbsp; And that is why today we are making more formula in America than we were back in February.</a><br><br>And they &#8212; and, in addition, they have said that they want to be able to maintain this kind of high-octane, high-tempo production level through &#8212; for the months ahead to make sure that we are &#8212; we have adequate supply coming out to the market.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Alex Alper at Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you guys so much for doing this call.&nbsp; You gave examples of products that this could be used for, but could you say specifically which ones the DPA invocation will be used for?<br><br>And as a second sort of follow-up, you mentioned that there could be a tightening of supply for some of these items.&nbsp; Does that mean that currently there is no tightness of supply and that the real issue is just ramping up production capacity and not a lack of these key ingredients?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We are still having active and ongoing conversations with the companies, so I have nothing more specific to report at this time about the specific instances in which we&#8217;re going to be using the authority.&nbsp; What the authority does is empower the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make these individual decisions on a case-by-case basis.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, as to the second point, could you clarify whether there currently is any tightness of supply on these ingredients or if, really, it&#8217;s a, you know, potential future issue?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We are still having active, ongoing conversations with the companies.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Alyssa Rosenberg at Washington Post.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much, Kevin.&nbsp; I know earlier in the week one of the things that the administration was discussing was efforts to monitor supply throughout the country and to attempt to work with retailers to prioritize rural areas or other areas where customers didn&#8217;t have as many options to shop around for formula at multiple stores.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Can you give us an update on what, if any, progress you&#8217;ve made there, or anything you&#8217;ve learned about areas that are in particular need, and what actions are underway to try and get formula to those areas?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We continue to work closely with governors, state WIC agencies, and with retailers to both understand &#8212; for the &#8212; with the retailers.&nbsp; They have been working very closely with us to help us understand where &#8212; where supply is distributed currently in the country.&nbsp; And with the &#8212; with the governors and with the WIC agencies at the state level, they have done tremendous work to provide regulatory flexibility so that customers can access any product that is available in their state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The situation, based on the conversations we&#8217;re having, is very different all around the country.&nbsp; It seems to be very state by state.&nbsp; There are some states in which the local authority, the retailers are saying they are not seeing challenges.&nbsp; And there are some states where, you know, people have identified, have &#8212; have suggested that there could be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it has been interesting to hear the number of states who suggest that they are not actually seeing (inaudible) in their market (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on that &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, Kevin.&nbsp; Can I follow up on that quickly?&nbsp;</p>



<p>In situations where formula is, in fact, short, is the government anticipating asking retailers to shift their stocking plans to try and serve those areas where customers may not have as many choices or options to shop around?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The data has not suggested to us that there is that kind of shortness in any of those geographies at this point, so I have nothing further to report on that.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let&#8217;s go to Maegan Vazquez at CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, can I &#8212; can I just offer one more point on the shelves &#8212; stocking?&nbsp; The data &#8212; there is data out there that &#8212; it is a little bit difficult to interpret the data on shelf availability that retailers and industry analysts typically rely on because the manufacturers have changed the types of products that they are offering out in the market.&nbsp; And so, that is why we are working closely with the retailers and the manufacturers to make &#8212; to understand the distribution right now.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go back to Maegan, CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; On Operation Fly Formula, can you all walk us through some of the logistics in terms of where is this formula being flown into, what communities will get the formula, how is that determined?&nbsp; And generally speaking, when will we see planes start to land with this formula?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to take that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to take that.&nbsp; So, once we have identified a manufacturer that has available formula, we work with them to secure the specifics.&nbsp; Because enabled &#8212; if we&#8217;re going to use DOD-contracted commercial aircraft, we need to have a pick-up place and a drop-off place, and the amount, and other specifics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it requires some negotiations, again, with the manufacturer of the formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We work with DOD to identify contracted commercial air &#8212; you know, get them up in the air.&nbsp; And often, they are &#8212; I shouldn’t say “often” &#8212; but they will land at airfields that are close to the factory or a manufacturing facility.&nbsp; It gets loaded onto the aircraft.&nbsp; The manufacturer actually tells us where it needs to be delivered, and that is to one of their facilities here in the United States &#8212; because a portion of it, actually, when it gets offloaded, has to go through FDA inspection.&nbsp; And then we will, from there, work through vendors and retailers to come to that manufacturing facility to pick it up and hopefully get it out to the communities that are most in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And we are actively in conversations and discussions with manufacturers about where there might be cargo around the world that would be suitable for their procedures that [senior administration official] just laid out.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; A couple more questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Michael Shear with New York Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;I&#8217;d like to push just a little bit more on the question of the &#8212; of the DPA and the materials that you&#8217;re hoping to facilitate to the manufacturers.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s almost impossible to judge whether this has &#8212; is going to do anything until you know whether there is actually a shortage of formula, materials, and ingredients to help prioritize.</p>



<p>So, I mean, I guess the question is: I don&#8217;t see how you can expect us to write about this without telling us if you actually know whether there is a shortage of any materials &#8212; cans, labels, or anything else.&nbsp; And if you don&#8217;t know that there&#8217;s such a shortage, how is this &#8212; why are you even invoking this?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I want to clarify one piece of the DPA authority.&nbsp; This isn&#8217;t just about a situation about shortages, it&#8217;s also about speeding up the delivery through the supply chain.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>A supplier has a lot of different customers, and they may not realize that the infant formula manufacturer is one of those suppliers, especially if they are a second-, third-tier supplier to that infant formula manufacturer.&nbsp; So that gives us the authority to work closer with the infant formula manufacturers and pull stuff through the supply chain faster.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not a situation where you have to identify a shortage; it can also be used to make things faster.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Zeke Miller with AP.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to add one more point, sorry, on the, like &#8212; on the making things faster.&nbsp; As we have said, we will do things to cut days off of production schedules and timelines to make sure that we are urgently moving quickly to get supply to store shelves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; To follow up to Mike&#8217;s question there: If the DPA is &#8212; is as significant as you&#8217;re saying, why wait until now to invoke that authority to speed up any &#8212; some of those bottlenecks?&nbsp; And then, you know, why couldn&#8217;t this have been done a couple of months ago?</p>



<p>And then secondly, can you name the states that haven&#8217;t issued WIC waivers yet, please?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on DPA, we have been clear from the outset that we are going to pull every lever that we can find when we need to deploy a lever to make sure that there is safe infant formula available to the American people.</p>



<p>The invoking of the DPA builds upon a lot of actions and steps that we have already taken.&nbsp; And we continue to look and execute on a range of options that can meaningfully expedite production and speed up supply chains for producing baby formula.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And on your question about the WIC waiver, USDA has a &#8212; has a detailed website that lists what states have taken which actions.&nbsp; Kevin can &#8212; can get that to you, but it&#8217;s on USDA&#8217;s website.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s do one more question.&nbsp; Josh Lederman at NBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Senators Patty Murray and Casey are calling on the administration to appoint basically a &#8220;Baby Formula Czar.&#8221;&nbsp; They say they really want to see a point person who&#8217;s focused exclusively on this issue.</p>



<p>Is the White House open to that idea?&nbsp; Do you have any thoughts on whether that would be useful to further ramping up these efforts at this time?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; As you know, we have been taking really urgent action for the last several months and in recent weeks to do everything we can to get more formula onto U.S. shelves and into the country and coming off of manufacturing lines.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on that today.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp; You know where to find me if you have follow-ups.&nbsp; And have a good day, guys.</p>



<p>12:26 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/19/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-and-section-614a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE<br><br>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961<br><br>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the following authorities, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 614(a)(3) and section 652 of the FAA, in order to provide assistance to Ukraine:</p>



<p>      (1)  the authority under section 614(a)(1) of the FAA to determine whether it is important to the security interests of the United States to furnish up to $100 million in assistance without regard to any provision of law within the purview of section 614(a)(1) of the FAA; and<br><br>     (2)  the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $100 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.<br><br>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-67/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 18:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Rubydee Calvert, of Wyoming, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting for a term expiring January 31, 2028.&#160; (Reappointment) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Kathryn Wheelbarger, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rubydee Calvert, of Wyoming, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting for a term expiring January 31, 2028.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kathryn Wheelbarger, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice Stephen D. Krasner, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael K. Singh, of Illinois, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice J. Robinson West, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jonathan Wingate Burks, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice Eric S. Edelman, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lara E. Montecalvo, of Rhode Island, to be United States Circuit Judge for the First Circuit, vice O. Rogeriee Thompson, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sarah A. L. Merriam, of Connecticut, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Second Circuit, vice Susan L. Carney, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Elizabeth Wilson Hanes, of Virginia, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Virginia, vice John A. Gibney, Jr., retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Anne M. Nardacci, of New York, to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of New York, vice Gary L. Sharpe, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ana C. Reyes, of the District of Columbia, to be United States District Judge for the District of Columbia, vice Colleen Kollar-Kotelly, retiring.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Senate Passage of Ukraine&#160;Supplemental</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-senate-passage-of-ukraine-supplemental/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 17:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I applaud the Congress for sending a clear&#160;bipartisan&#160;message to the world that the people of the&#160;United States&#160;stand together with the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their democracy and freedom.&#160;The resources that I requested will&#160;allow us to&#160;send even more weapons&#160;and ammunition to Ukraine,&#160;replenish our own stockpile, and support U.S. troops stationed on NATO territory.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I applaud the Congress for sending a clear&nbsp;bipartisan&nbsp;message to the world that the people of the&nbsp;United States&nbsp;stand together with the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their democracy and freedom.&nbsp;The resources that I requested will&nbsp;allow us to&nbsp;send even more weapons&nbsp;and ammunition to Ukraine,&nbsp;replenish our own stockpile, and support U.S. troops stationed on NATO territory. And, I want to thank Leader Schumer, Speaker Pelosi, Leader McConnell, and Leader McCarthy for moving this bill quickly to ensure there is no lapse in funding for these important needs. Together with the contributions of our Allies and partners,&nbsp;we will keep security, economic, food, and humanitarian assistance flowing to Ukraine, across the region, and around the world, and&nbsp;further strengthen Ukraine — both on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.</p>



<p>We have provided a&nbsp;historic amount of security assistance to&nbsp;Ukraine&nbsp;to date, and my Administration will continue to expedite the delivery of additional&nbsp;weapons and equipment for which Congress has provided authority.&nbsp; And today, I am announcing another package of security assistance&nbsp;that will provide additional&nbsp;artillery, radars, and other equipment&nbsp;to Ukraine, which they are already using so effectively on the battlefield. These&nbsp;weapons and equipment&nbsp;will&nbsp;go&nbsp;directly to the front lines of freedom in Ukraine, and reiterate&nbsp;our strong support for the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their country against Russia’s ongoing aggression.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to Certain Congressional Committees on the report on the Kingdom of Sweden&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty&#160;Organization</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/letter-to-certain-congressional-committees-on-the-report-on-the-kingdom-of-swedens-accession-to-the-north-atlantic-treaty-organization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 17:44:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Mr. Chairman:&#160; (Dear Madam Chair:) I am providing the report on the Kingdom of Sweden&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, prepared consistent with section 3(2)(E) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Mr. Chairman:&nbsp; (Dear Madam Chair:)</p>



<p>I am providing the report on the Kingdom of Sweden&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, prepared consistent with section 3(2)(E) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the Czech Republic of April 30, 1998.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to Certain Congressional Committees on the report on the Republic of Finland&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty&#160;Organization</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/letter-to-certain-congressional-committees-on-the-report-on-the-republic-of-finlands-accession-to-the-north-atlantic-treaty-organization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 17:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Mr. Chairman:&#160; (Dear Madam Chair:) I am providing the report on the Republic of Finland&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, prepared consistent with section 3(2)(E) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Mr. Chairman:&nbsp; (Dear Madam Chair:)</p>



<p>I am providing the report on the Republic of Finland&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, prepared consistent with section 3(2)(E) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the Czech Republic of April 30, 1998.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden, President Niinistö of Finland, and Prime Minister Andersson of Sweden after Trilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/19/remarks-by-president-biden-president-niinisto-of-finland-and-prime-minister-andersson-of-sweden-after-trilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 17:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 10:45 A.M. EDT&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Please &#8212; please, be seated.&#160; Thank you.&#160;&#160;It’s not only a beautiful day, this is, in my view and the view of my team, a momentous day.&#160; It’s a very, very good day.&#160;Today, I am proud to welcome and offer the strong support of the United States for the applications&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>10:45 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Please &#8212; please, be seated.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It’s not only a beautiful day, this is, in my view and the view of my team, a momentous day.&nbsp; It’s a very, very good day.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, I am proud to welcome and offer the strong support of the United States for the applications of two great democracies and two close, highly capable partners to join the strongest, most powerful defensive alliance in the history of the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Two proud, independent countries exercising their sovereign right all states possess to decide their own security.</p>



<p>President Niinistö, you are &#8212; and Prime Minister Anderssen [sic] &#8212; Andersson:&nbsp; You’re &#8212; it’s a great honor to have both of you here at the White House as Finland and Sweden begin the process of joining NATO.<br>&nbsp;<br>It was out of the wreckage of World War Two that NATO was formed.&nbsp; And in the seven decades that followed, NATO has proved itself an indispensable alliance committed to a Europe whole, free, and at peace.<br>&nbsp;<br>But in recent years, doubts began to arise.&nbsp; Was NATO still relevant?&nbsp; Was it still effective?&nbsp; Is it still needed in the 21st century world?<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, there is no question: NATO is relevant, it is effective, and it is more needed now than ever.<br>&nbsp;<br>The indispensable alliance of decades past is still the indispensable alliance for the world we face today and, I would argue, tomorrow as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the decision of Sweden and Finland, the one they have made, is testament to that commitment.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is about the future.&nbsp; It’s about a revived NATO that has the tools and resources, the clarity and conviction to defend our shared values and lead the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Sweden and Finland are already among our closest partners on a range of issues, from strengthening peace and stability to advancing human rights, to taking on clim- &#8212; the climate crisis and addressing food insecurity, from strengthening the global health to promoting development.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finnish and Swedish troops &#8212; Finnish and Swedish troops have already served shoulder-to-shoulder with U.S. and NATO forces in Kosovo, in Afghanistan, and in Iraq.<br>&nbsp;<br>And both Finland and Sweden are already working in coordination with the United States and our other Allies and partners to support the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their freedom against Russia’s invasion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Sweden and Finland have strong democratic institutions, strong militaries, and strong and transparent economies, and a strong moral sense of what is right.<br>&nbsp;<br>They meet every NATO requirement, and then some.&nbsp; And having two new NATO members in the High North will enhance the security of our Alliance and deepen our security cooperation across the board.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, the President, the Prime Minister, and I had a very good discussion about NATO accession, about the war in Ukraine, and strengthening transatlantic security.&nbsp; But our conversations began well before today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Niinistö and I spoke last December and again in January in the weeks leading up to Russia’s unjust and unprovoked assault on Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In March, the President came to the White House &#8212; came to the White House to see me, to discuss this brutal conflict and the rupture it&#8217;s causing in Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>While we were in the Oval Office together, we picked up the phone and we called the Prime Minister.&nbsp; And the three of us all spoke &#8212; and we spoke again last week when I invited them to come to the White House today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have consulted closely at every stage as Sweden and Finland made their de- &#8212; their determinations.<br>&nbsp;<br>And today, I&#8217;m proud to assure them that they have the full, total, complete backing of the United States of America.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, my administration is submitting to the United States Congress reports on NATO accession for both countries so the Senate can efficiently and quickly move on advising and consenting to the treaty.<br>&nbsp;<br>I greatly appreciate Senator Schumer and McConnell’s support, as well as Senator Menendez and Risch, to move this through the Senate as quickly as possible once the perspective of all Allies are addressed and NATO adopts the accession protocols.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The bottom line is simple, quite straightforward: Finland and Sweden make NATO stronger, not just because of their capacity but because they&#8217;re strong, strong democracies.&nbsp; And a strong, united NATO is the foundation of America’s security.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>By joining NATO, Allies make a sacred commitment to one another that an attack on one is an attack against all.&nbsp; It’s Article 5 of the Washington Treaty and the core building block of our Alliance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the only time in history Article 5 has been invoked was after 9/11, when the United States was attacked and all our Allies rallied to our side.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The United States will never forget that.&nbsp; And we will never fail in our pledge to defend every single inch of NATO territory.&nbsp; I welcome Sweden and Fi- &#8212; and Finland choosing that responsibility as well.&nbsp; This is going to benefit all of our people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And today, the President, Prime Minister, and I committed that we&#8217;re going to work together to remain vigilant against the threats to our shared security and to deter and confront any aggression while Finland and Sweden are in this accession process.<br>&nbsp;<br>&#8220;There&#8217;s nothing going to be missed,&#8221; as my mother would say, &#8220;between the cup and lip.&#8221;&nbsp; We&#8217;re in, once it is moving forward.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I really mean it.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let me be clear: New members joining NATO is not a threat to any nation.&nbsp; It never has been.&nbsp; NATO’s purpose is to defend against aggression.&nbsp; That’s its purpose: to defend.&nbsp; And let make &#8212; let me make &#8212; let no one make a mistake the meaning of this historic day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the face of aggression, NATO has not grown weaker or more divided; it has grown stronger, more united.<br>&nbsp;<br>With Finland and Sweden’s decision to request membership in NATO, it’ll be enhanced for all time.&nbsp; Standing together today, we reject the bloody creed that “might makes right,” and we declare a more &#8212; a more powerful creed: “All for one, and one for all.”&nbsp; Because what makes NATO strong isn’t just our enormous military capacity, but our commitment to each other, to its values.<br>&nbsp;<br>NATO is an alliance of choice, not coercion.&nbsp; This is a victory for democracy in action.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finland and Sweden are seeking to join NATO because their citizens demanded it, and their elected leaders heard them.&nbsp; That’s how it works when leaders derive their power from the consent of the government &#8212; from consent of the governed.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that’s why NATO’s Open Door has always been so important.&nbsp; It allows nations to choose for themselves to ask to be part of a group of nations that value freedom, democracy, and human dignity above all else.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Countries must demonstrate that they meet NATO’s high standards for military interoperability, economic transparency, and democratic accountability.<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s what Sweden and Finland have done.&nbsp; And so today, it’s an affirmation of those countries in Europe that share our values that we’re willing and able to do what it takes to be part of the Alliance.&nbsp; NATO’s door remains open.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In just a few minutes, I’ll be leaving to spend time with two of our Indo-Pacific allies.&nbsp; In a half hour or so, I’ll be flying to the Republic of Korea and Japan.<br>&nbsp;<br>I thank &#8212; I thank the President and the Prime Minister for traveling here on this meet- &#8212; for this meeting before I take off because it is so important.<br>&nbsp;<br>America’s alliances in Europe and in Asia keep us &#8212; and, I would argue, the world &#8212; strong and secure.&nbsp; They’re how we confront the challenges of our time and deliver &#8212; deliver for our people today, and harness &#8212; harness opportunities for a better tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I look forward soon calling Sweden and Finland our friends, partners, and NATO Allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank you both for being here, and I’m going to invite each of you to say a few words.&nbsp; And we’ll start &#8212; Mr. President, the podium is yours.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT NIINISTÖ:&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you so very much.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT NIINISTÖ:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Mr. President, it is with great pleasure and honor to be standing here today with you, together with the Swedish Prime Minister, Magdalena Andersson.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are here for a very good reason.&nbsp; Together, we are taking a historic step by seeking to join the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finland has made its decision after a rapid but a very thorough process.&nbsp; The process has once again revealed the strength of Finnish democracy.&nbsp; Starting from the strong public support, the decision was made with an overwhelming parliamentary majority.&nbsp; And it also enjoys huge, strong popular support.<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank you, Mr. President, for your steadfast support throughout this process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In early March, I visited White House and you encouraged us to go further.&nbsp; That was of vital importance to our process.<br>&nbsp;<br>Your statement yesterday and our trilateral meeting today are a testimony of enduring commitment the United States has made to European and transatlantic security.<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to assure that Finland will become a strong NATO Ally.&nbsp; We take our security very seriously.&nbsp; The Finnish armed forces are one of the strongest in Europe.&nbsp; We have also consistently invested in developing our capabilities.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Finns’ willingness to defend their country is one of the highest in the whole world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are ready to contribute to the security of the whole Alliance, making the commitment to mutual security guarantees that being a NATO Ally entails.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now that we have taken this first decisive step, it is time for NATO Allies to weigh in.&nbsp; We hope for strong support from all Allies and for a swift ratification of our membership once it&#8217;s agreed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I believe that the United States can set a crucially important example to others.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Turkish leadership has recently expressed concerns about our membership application.&nbsp; I want to address these concerns today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finland has always had proud and good bilateral relations to Turkey.&nbsp; As NATO Allies, we will commit to Turkey’s security, just as Turkey will commit to our security.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We take terrorism seriously.&nbsp; We condemn terrorism in all its forms, and we are actively engaged in combating it.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are open to discussing all the concerns Turkey may have concerning our membership in an open and constructive manner.<br>&nbsp;<br>These discussions have already taken place, and they will continue in the next days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Twenty-fourth February, I said that the masks have fallen, and we see only the cold faces of war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Russia&#8217;s war in Ukraine has changed Europe and our security environment.&nbsp; Finland takes the step of NATO membership in order to strengthen not only its own security, but also in order to strengthen wider transatlantic security.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not away from anybody.&nbsp; Like you, Mr. President, said, NATO is protective, defensive &#8212; not a threat to anybody.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, we must not forget that at this very moment, the brave people of Ukraine are fighting not only for their own freedom and democracy, but for our common security.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finland, together with the EU and the United States, stands firmly behind Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, Mr. President, once again, I want to thank you for making history with us.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you. Prime Minister.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRIME MINISTER ANDERSSON:&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you for welcoming President Niinistö and me to the White House.<br>&nbsp;<br>The bonds between Sweden and the United States, they are strong and longstanding.&nbsp; And as you know, Swedes first set foot in your home state of Delaware in 1638.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And we were one of the first countries to recognize the United States as an independent nation in 1783.<br>&nbsp;<br>And since then, our countries have developed a deep and longstanding friendship through family ties, trade, and mutual intere- &#8212; interests.&nbsp; And I personally is very much one part of this.<br>&nbsp;<br>But most of all, our shared values and beliefs in democracy and freedom &#8212; values and beliefs that are now being put to the test.<br>&nbsp;<br>And today, the situation in Ukraine reminds us of the darkest days of European history.&nbsp; And I must say that, during dark times, it is great to be among close friends.<br>&nbsp;<br>And over these past months, we have shown transatlantic unity and strength at its best.&nbsp; Together, we have responded forcefully to Russia&#8217;s aggression and provided unprecedented support to Ukraine.&nbsp; We have not flinched.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, Mr. President, I want to thank you for the massive U.S. support to Ukraine and for your sustained engagements in European society.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Niinistö and I have come here at a historic moment for our countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And for Sweden, after 200 years of military non-alignment, Sweden has chosen a new path.&nbsp; Yesterday, Sweden and Finland submitted our formal requests to join NATO.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And Russia&#8217;s full-scale aggression against a sovereign and democratic neighbor &#8212; that was a watershed moment for Sweden.&nbsp; And my government has come to the &#8212; to the conclusion that the security of the Swedish people will be best protected within the NATO Alliance.&nbsp; And this is backed by very broad support in the Swedish parliament.</p>



<p>And with Sweden and Finland as members, NATO will also be stronger.&nbsp; We are security providers with sophisticated defense capabilities.&nbsp; And we are champions of freedom, democracy, and human rights.</p>



<p>We have a long tradition of extensive military cooperation with NATO, including all missions.&nbsp; And we are right now ramping up our defense spending, and we will reach 2 percent of GDP as soon as practically possible.</p>



<p>And, Mr. President, your support for our country&#8217;s NATO aspirations for our security are of fundamental importance.&nbsp; And we look forward to a swift ratification process by NATO members.&nbsp; And we are right now having a dialogue with all NATO member countries, including Turkey, on different levels to sort out any issues at hand.</p>



<p>In the United States, the Senate is crucial in this regard.&nbsp; And last Sat- &#8212; Sunday, I hosted a delegation headed by Senate Republican Leader Mc- &#8212; McConnell in Sweden.&nbsp; And later today, President Niinistö and I will meet Senate Majority Leader Schumer and other leading members of Congress.&nbsp; And we greatly appreciate the broad and strong support expressed by both parties in Congress.</p>



<p>But, Mr. President, our countries also work closer together when tackling global challenges.&nbsp; And Sweden, like other Nordic countries, has shown that emissions reductions can go hand-in-hand with economic growth.</p>



<p>And in Sweden right now, the green transition creates thousands of jobs through investments in battery factories, green mining, and fossil-free steel production.&nbsp; And I actually brought the President a unique example of this: a candle holde-&nbsp;&#8212; holder made of the world&#8217;s first fossil-free steel.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It’s important.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ANDERSSON:&nbsp; And what we see in Sweden right now is that previously neglected areas are no longer struggling with unemployment or depopulation but how to build housing, infrastructure, and schools quick enough to meet up with the expansion.&nbsp; And here, I see fantastic opportunities to cooperate between the Nordic countries and United States.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m also proud that Sweden contributes to the U.S. economy and the prosperity of the American people.</p>



<p>Swedish companies are active in every single state, creating more than 350,000 jobs in the United States.&nbsp; And we are the 15th-largest investor.</p>



<p>Mr. President, I want to thank you for your leadership in our joint efforts to promote democracy throughout the world.&nbsp; Because democracy requires constant work and safeguarding, we have to win every new generation.</p>



<p>And let me conclude where I started: Peace and stability in our part of the world is a common security interest for us, for you, and for the rest of Europe.&nbsp; And we stand here today more united than ever, and we are committed to strengthening our bonds even further.&nbsp; And Sweden is prepared to shoulder its responsibility as an Ally in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>11:08 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
