<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:58:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: NATO Summit: Revitalizing the Transatlantic Alliance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/fact-sheet-nato-summit-revitalizing-the-transatlantic-alliance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The transatlantic alliance is the strong foundation on which our collective security and our shared prosperity are built.&#160; The partnership between Europe and the United States, in my view, is and must remain the cornerstone of all that we hope to accomplish in the 21st century, just as we did in the 20th century… The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>“The transatlantic alliance is the strong foundation on which our collective security and our shared prosperity are built.&nbsp; The partnership between Europe and the United States, in my view, is and must remain the cornerstone of all that we hope to accomplish in the 21<sup>st</sup> century, just as we did in the 20<sup>th</sup> century… The United States is fully committed to our NATO Alliance… we’ll keep faith with Article 5.”</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;–<em> President Biden, February 19, 2021</em></p>



<p>President Biden will participate on June 14 in the NATO Summit in Brussels that brings together the leaders of all 30 Allied nations. &nbsp;During the Summit, the President will reaffirm the enduring Transatlantic bond through NATO and underscore the United States’ ironclad commitment to Article 5 – an attack on one is an attack on all and will be met with a collective response.&nbsp; Allied leaders will launch an ambitious set of initiatives to ensure NATO continues to provide security to our citizens through 2030 and beyond.</p>



<p>The Transatlantic relationship is built on a foundation of shared democratic values.&nbsp; NATO’s strength comes not only from its military might, but also its unity and common purpose founded on respect for democracy, individual liberty, and the rule of law, as enshrined in the Washington Treaty.&nbsp; Now in its 73rd year, NATO is the most powerful and successful Alliance in history.&nbsp; NATO faced down the Communist bloc in the Cold War and today provides security for approximately one billion people in Europe and North America.&nbsp; As NATO winds down its military presence in Afghanistan after nearly 20 years, the United States and our NATO Allies and partners will continue supporting the people of Afghanistan through civilian and security assistance.&nbsp; The United States will also continue to stand shoulder to shoulder with our Allies and partners in NATO’s non-combat advisory mission in Iraq.</p>



<p>NATO played a pivotal role in coordinating the civilian response to COVID-19, airlifting hundreds of tons of critical supplies around the world and building almost 100 field hospitals, while maintaining its deterrence and defense posture.&nbsp; This assistance is saving lives and proves that defense investment and capacity building increase our nations’ resilience in the face of all kinds of crises, not only against military threats.</p>



<p><strong><u>Key Summit Outcomes</u></strong>:</p>



<p><strong>A New Strategic Concept</strong>:&nbsp; Allies will agree to revise NATO’s Strategic Concept, a framework that will guide the Alliance’s approach to the evolving strategic environment, which includes Russia’s aggressive policies and actions; challenges posed by the People’s Republic of China to our collective security, prosperity, and values; and transnational threats such as terrorism, cyber threats, and climate change. &nbsp;The new Strategic Concept will be prepared for adoption at the NATO Summit in 2022.</p>



<p><strong>Updating Cyber Defenses</strong>: Leaders will endorse a new Cyber Defense Policy for NATO that will strengthen Allied coordination to ensure the Alliance is resilient against the increasingly frequent and severe threats we face from malicious cyber activity perpetrated by state and non-state actors, including disruptive ransomware attacks against critical infrastructure.&nbsp; This updated policy will also provide strategic guidance for NATO’s political, military, and technical cyber efforts to deter, defend against, and counter the full spectrum of cyber threats.&nbsp; Leaders will also affirm the importance of defending our networks and ensuring Allies rely on trustworthy providers for next generation telecommunication networks.</p>



<p><strong>Preserving our Technological Edge</strong>:&nbsp; Leaders will affirm that NATO’s ability to ensure our common defense relies on maintaining our technological edge. &nbsp;Allies will launch a Defense Innovation Accelerator to facilitate their technological cooperation and speed the adoption of emerging technologies that will enhance the Alliance’s defense and security.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Combatting Climate Change</strong>:&nbsp; Leaders will agree to a Climate Security Action Plan and set the ambition for NATO to become the leading international organization for understanding and adapting to the impact of climate change on security. &nbsp;They will agree to reduce greenhouse gases from military activities and installations in line with national commitments under the Paris Agreement, and agree to initiate a regular high-level global climate and security dialogue.</p>



<p><strong>Strengthened Deterrence and Defense</strong>:&nbsp; Allies will commit to implementation of new military concepts and strategies that strengthen NATO’s deterrence and defense posture to meet threats from Russia and elsewhere.&nbsp; NATO also continues to monitor the Russian deployments in and around Ukraine.</p>



<p><strong>Greater Sharing of Responsibility</strong>:  Non-U.S. defense spending has risen for seven consecutive years since the Wales Defense Investment Pledge adopted during the Obama-Biden Administration in 2014.  Allied leaders will recommit to the Wales Pledge in its entirety and to providing NATO with cash, capabilities, and contributions of ready forces.</p>



<p><strong>Investing in NATO:</strong>&nbsp; Allies will also commit to ensuring NATO is led, staffed, and resourced at levels necessary to deliver on the decisions taken at the Summit.&nbsp; Leaders will agree to identify the additional resources, including through NATO common funding, to enhance NATO’s ability to meet security challenges today and in the future.</p>



<p><strong>Increased Consultation and Cohesion</strong>:&nbsp; Allies will commit to enhance political coordination at NATO on all matters related to their individual and collective security.&nbsp; Leaders will also reaffirm their commitment to their common values, including individual liberty, human rights, democracy, and the rule of law.</p>



<p><strong>Stronger Societies</strong>:&nbsp; Recognizing the increasingly complex threats to our security, Allied leaders will affirm that national and collective resilience are essential for credible deterrence and defense, and vital to safeguard our societies, citizens, and shared values.&nbsp; Allied leaders will issue a Strengthened Resilience Commitment to outline future priorities, including on the security of supply chains, critical infrastructure, and energy networks, as well as preparedness for pandemics and natural disasters.</p>



<p><strong>Deeper Partnerships</strong>:&nbsp; Allies will enhance NATO’s ability to strengthen the rules-based international order by increasing dialogue and practical cooperation with the Alliance’s partners, including the European Union and those in the Indo-Pacific (Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the Republic of Korea).&nbsp; Leaders will recommit to NATO’s Open Door Policy, which provides a path to membership for any European country that shares our values and meets the necessary responsibilities and obligations.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the New Government of the State of Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/statement-from-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-new-government-of-the-state-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 18:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On behalf of the American people, I congratulate Prime Minister Naftali Bennett, Alternate Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Yair Lapid, and all the members of the new Israeli cabinet.&#160; I look forward to working with Prime Minister Bennett to strengthen all aspects of the close and enduring relationship between our two nations.&#160; Israel has no&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On behalf of the American people, I congratulate Prime Minister Naftali Bennett, Alternate Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Yair Lapid, and all the members of the new Israeli cabinet.&nbsp; I look forward to working with Prime Minister Bennett to strengthen all aspects of the close and enduring relationship between our two nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Israel has no better friend than the United States.&nbsp; The bond that unites our people is evidence of our shared values and decades of close cooperation and as we continue to strengthen our partnership, the United States remains unwavering in its support for Israel’s security.&nbsp; My administration is fully committed to working with the new Israeli government to advance security, stability, and peace for Israelis, Palestinians, and people throughout the broader region.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in Press Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/13/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 17:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20639</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cornwall Airport NewquayCornwall, United Kingdom 2:52 P.M. BST&#160;THE PRESIDENT: Well, good afternoon. And let me start by thanking Prime Minister Johnson for the incredible hospitality and welcome that he provided for all of us at the G7. I’d like to take &#8212; thank Yael Lempert, who is our chargé at the embassy, filling in for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cornwall Airport Newquay<br>Cornwall, United Kingdom</p>



<p>2:52 P.M. BST<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Well, good afternoon. And let me start by thanking Prime Minister Johnson for the incredible hospitality and welcome that he provided for all of us at the G7. I’d like to take &#8212; thank Yael Lempert, who is our chargé at the embassy, filling in for the ambassador &#8212; an ambassador; we&#8217;ll have one soon. But she did a great job supporting the entire team, and Yael is vital to keeping this UK-U.S. partnership going and moving smoothly as it is now.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve just wrapped up what has been an extraordinary, collaborative, and productive meeting at the G7. Everyone at the table understood and understands both the seriousness and the challenges that we&#8217;re up against, and the responsibility of our proud democracies to step up and deliver for the rest of the world. That&#8217;s what the G7 is all about. And rallying the world&#8217;s democracies to meet the challenges that the world faces, and deliver for our people and for people, quite frankly, everywhere.<br>&nbsp;<br>Ending the pandemic and maintaining robust support for an equitable, inclusive global economic recovery were the top priorities of our nations as we got together. We know we can&#8217;t achieve one without the other; that is, we have to deal with the pandemic and &#8212; in order to be able to deal with economic recovery, which &#8212; as we&#8217;re doing in the States, but we committed that we&#8217;re going to do more for the rest of the world as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>The fact is that we &#8212; the U.S. contribution is the foundation &#8212; the foundation to work out how we&#8217;re going to deal with the 100 nations that are poor and having trouble finding vaccines and having trouble dealing with reviving their economies if they were, in the first place, in good shape.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we &#8212; I committed that we would provide a half a billion &#8212; a half a billion beyond the 80 million we&#8217;ve already done &#8212; half a billion doses of Pfizer vaccine, which we contracted to pay for, in addition to money we put into the COVID [COVAX] project, which is that COVID [COVAX] is &#8212; and I know you all know, but a lot of people may not know what COVID [COVAX] is &#8212; that is a system whereby they&#8217;re going to provide funding for states to be able to get access to vaccines on their own, as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the bottom line is: What that generated was a commitment by the rest of our colleagues at the G7 that they would provide another half billion. So we&#8217;re going to have a billion doses of vaccine.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, in our case, this includes sharing more than &#8212; not just the one billion doses overall, but we&#8217;re going to provide for 200 million of those doses by the end of the year, another 300 million by the first half of next year. And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; it was greeted with some enthusiasm.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve agreed to work together so that the world is better prepared to detect and deal with future pandemics, because there will be future pandemics.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have a &#8212; I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve seen it; if you haven&#8217;t, you&#8217;ll get it &#8212; a joint statement we put out of the G7. You&#8217;ve seen it, I&#8217;m sure. And we are committed to follow on to do some significant work, including not only how we deal with the distribution and help in getting shots in arms to the rest of the world, but how we&#8217;re going to deal with putting together a mechanism to anticipate and deal with and be aware of the next &#8212; the next pandemic when it comes along. And there will be others.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we also agreed to take important steps that are going to support global economic recovery by laying the foundation for an equitable global economy. Critically, the G7 leaders endorsed a global minimum tax of 15 percent. So many corporations have been engaged in what are essentially tax havens, deciding that they would pay considerably less than other &#8212; in other environs around the world. And &#8212; but this is going to make sure there&#8217;s a minimum tax, and I&#8217;m going to have &#8212; I&#8217;m going to move on this at home as well &#8212; a minimum tax for corporations to pay for the profits they make anywhere in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>And this agreement is going to help arrest the race to the bottom that&#8217;s been going on among nations attracting corporate investment at the expense of priorities like protecting our workers and investing in infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also made a momentous commitment at the G7 to help meet more than a $40 trillion need that exists for infrastructure in the developing world. I put forward an idea that was called &#8212; we named the &#8220;Build Back Better World Partnership,&#8221; which is &#8212; we&#8217;re calling it the &#8220;B3W.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>The point is that what&#8217;s happening is that China has this Belt and Road Initiative, and we think that there&#8217;s a much more equitable way to provide for the needs of countries around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so it&#8217;s been &#8212; it&#8217;s a values-driven, high-standard, transparent financing mechanism we&#8217;re going to provide and support projects in four key are- &#8212; key areas: climate, health, digital technology, and gender equity. And we believe that will not only be good for the countries, but it’ll be good for the entire world and represent values that our democracies represent, and not autocratic lack of values. By harassing the full potential of those who are harassing, we&#8217;re going to have to try and change things. That&#8217;s the whole idea.<br>&nbsp;<br>But here&#8217;s the deal: We&#8217;re going to make sure that we are able to pull together the ability to use the development financing institutions and other development tools to expect the bold, new infrastructure investment in low- and middle-income countries over the coming years, much of it coming from the private sector, which will generate the capital put in; will generate significantly more capital from the private sector.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also made a historic commitment to permanently eliminate the use of our public finance to support unabated coal projects around the world, and to end &#8212; and to end them by this year. The G7 agreed to that. And those who are not members, but visiting members who are participating in the G7, who have coal-fired facilities have also agreed that they would work in that direction as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, transitioning the world to cleaner energy sources is urgent, it&#8217;s essential if we&#8217;re going to beat the climate. And there is &#8212; one of the things I &#8212; some of my colleagues said to me when I was there was, “Well, the United States is &#8212; their leadership recognizes there is global warming.” And I know that sounds silly, but, you know, we had a President who last &#8212; who basically said it&#8217;s not a problem &#8212; global warming. It is the existential problem facing humanity, and it&#8217;s being treated that way. So we&#8217;re going to provide up to $2 billion to support developing company [sic] &#8212; countries as they transition away from unabated coal-fired power.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, we also agreed to tackle corruption, which is a threat to societies everywhere. I pointed out in a conversation I had with &#8212; with one of the leaders of &#8212; well, actually with China. And that was &#8212; it was a request for me not to try to &#8212; when I was asked what I was going to be doing after being elected, I said we&#8217;re going to reestablish the strength of American relationships so we can be counted on again &#8212; alliances &#8212; and suggested that, “Well, maybe you shouldn&#8217;t get the Quad…” &#8212; meaning India, Japan, Australia, and the United States &#8212; &#8220;…working together, and maybe you shouldn&#8217;t be pushing on strengthening the European Union to deal with the West not just to have…&#8221; &#8212; and so on.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I said, for an American president to &#8212; every president to be sustained, or prime minister, has to represent the values of their country. And I pointed out &#8212; and I mean this sincerely: We&#8217;re unique as a country. We&#8217;re built on &#8212; we&#8217;re unique in a sense that we&#8217;re not based on ethnicity or geography or religion; we’re one nation that said we organized on an idea: &#8220;We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men and women are created equal.&#8221; It sounds corny, but it&#8217;s real.<br>&nbsp;<br>And any President who doesn&#8217;t act consistent with what the &#8212; the raison d&#8217;état for the nation is cannot be sustained that &#8212; the support of that country.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so what we were able to do is: We know that corruption undermines the trust in governments, siphons off public resources, makes economies much less competitive, and constitutes a threat to our security. So we&#8217;re going to work together to address issues like the abuse of shell companies and money laundering through real estate transactions. And we&#8217;ve agreed that we’re going to work together to address cyber threats from state and non-state actors like criminal ransomware networks, and hold count- &#8212; countries accountable that harbor criminal ransomware actors who don&#8217;t hold them accountable.<br>&nbsp;<br>And over the past few weeks, the nations of the G7 have affirmed that democratic values that underpin everything we hope to achieve in our shared future, that we&#8217;re committed to put them to work: One, delivering vaccines and ending the pandemic. Two, driving substantial, inclusive economic recovery around the world. Three, in fueling infrastructure development in places that most badly need it. And, four, in fighting climate change.<br>&nbsp;<br>The only way we&#8217;re going to meet the global threats that we&#8217;re &#8212; is by working together, and with our partners and our allies. And I conveyed to each of my G7 counterparts that the United States is going to do our part. America is back at the table. It’s &#8212; America is back at the table.<br>&nbsp;<br>The lack of participation in the past and full engagement was noticed significantly, not only by the leaders of those countries, but by the people in the G7 countries. And America is back in the business of leading the world alongside nations who share our most deeply held values.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so the bottom line is: I was very pleased with the &#8212; with the outcome of the &#8212; of the entire conference. And, you know, I noticed there was a lot of coverage of my individual comments made by my colleagues about how we were all getting along together. But the truth of the matter is: We did. It wasn’t &#8212; I felt it wasn&#8217;t about me, but it was about America. I felt a genuine sense of enthusiasm that America was back at the table and fully, fully engaged.<br>&nbsp;<br>And now I&#8217;m going to be heading off to &#8212; to Brussels, to NATO. And the same &#8212; many of the same people are going to be at that table, and &#8212; in NATO &#8212; and to make the case we are back, as well. We do not view NATO as a sort of a protection racket. We believe that NATO is vital to our ability to maintain American security for the next &#8212; next &#8212; the remainder of the century. And there&#8217;s a real enthusiasm.<br>&nbsp;<br>I made it clear &#8212; and I pointed out, and I thanked them &#8212; you know, Article 5 is, “An attack on one is an attack on all.” Well, what Americans sometimes &#8212; don&#8217;t forget &#8212; remember what happened on 9/11. We were attacked. Immediately, NATO supported us. NATO supported us. NATO went until we got bin Laden. NATO was part of the process. And I want them to know, unlike &#8212; whether they doubt it &#8212; that we believe NATO and Section [Article] 5 is a sacred obligation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Bottom line is: I think &#8212; I think we&#8217;ve made some progress in reestablishing American credibility among our closest friends and our &#8212; our values.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, why don&#8217;t I take some of your questions? And I&#8217;m told, Jonathan, I&#8217;m supposed to talk &#8212; recognize you first.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Well, I appreciate &#8212; I appreciate that, sir. Thank you very much. Mr. President, Vladimir Putin &#8212; (a microphone is brought to Mr. Lemire) &#8212; thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Vladimir Putin, who you&#8217;ll be seeing in a few days in Geneva, said just a couple of days ago that he believed that U.S.-Russia relations were at a low point. In what concrete ways could your summit change that?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, secondly, on the same topic: You have said previously, and in the run-up to the summit, that you would be unafraid to call out Russia&#8217;s disruptive actions &#8212; like cyber hacks, Ukraine, election interference &#8212; but you&#8217;re not having a joint press conference with Putin. Why not take the chance to stand side by side with him and say those things to him with the world watching?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: (Laughs.) Well, let me make it clear: I think he&#8217;s right that it&#8217;s a low point, and it depends on how he responds to acting consistent with international norms, which, in many cases, he has not.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I told him when I was running and when I got elected, before it was &#8212; I was sworn in, that I was going to find out whether or not he, in fact, did engage in trying to interfere in our election; that I was going to take a look at whether he was involved in the &#8212; a cybersecurity breach that occurred, et cetera; and if I did, I was going to respond.<br>&nbsp;<br>I did; I checked it out. So, I had access to all the intelligence. He was engaged in those activities. I did respond and made it clear that I&#8217;d respond again.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to &#8212; I always found &#8212; and I don&#8217;t mean to suggest that the press should not know &#8212; but this is not a contest about who can do better in front of a press conference to try to embarrass each other. It&#8217;s about making myself very clear what the conditions are to get a better relationship are &#8212; with Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re not looking for conflict. We are looking to resolve those actions which we think are inconsistent with international norms, number one. Number two, where we can work together, we may be able to do that in terms of some strategic doctrine that &#8212; that may be able to be worked together. We&#8217;re ready to do it. And there may be other areas. There&#8217;s even talk there may be the ability to work together on climate.<br>&nbsp;<br>So the bottom line is that I think the best way to deal with this is for he and I to meet, he and I to have our discussion. I know you don&#8217;t doubt that I&#8217;ll be very straightforward &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; with him about our concerns. And I will make clear my view of how that meeting turned out, and he&#8217;ll make clear how &#8212; from his perspective, how it turned out.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I don&#8217;t want to get into being diverted by, &#8220;Did they shake hands? How far did they ta- &#8212; who talked the most,” and the rest. Now,&nbsp;he can say what he said the meeting was about, and I will say what I think the meeting was about.<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s how I&#8217;m going to handle it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Okay, thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: I&#8217;m sorry, I&#8217;m going to get in trouble with staff if I don’t do this the right way.<br>&nbsp;<br>Jennifer Jacobs, Bloomberg.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, sir. On China, you &#8212; sorry &#8212; China seems to be to doing exactly what it wants to do with regard to Hong Kong, with regard to Xinjiang, with the South China Sea, and many other issues, despite pressure from you and from allies.<br>&nbsp;<br>The final language in the G7 communiqué does have some mentions of China, which is different from past years, but I know it&#8217;s not as tough as you and your team wanted it to be. We&#8217;ve saw &#8212; we saw a draft of the communiqué, and it&#8217;s not quite as tough.<br>&nbsp;<br>So why isn&#8217;t it as tough? There isn&#8217;t very much action in it. There&#8217;s some calls for China to be respectful. But why isn&#8217;t that communiqué a little bit tougher? Are you disappointed in that? And what can you do to change some of these actions by China?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Well, first of all, I think it &#8212; as you know, last time the G7 met, there was no mention of China. But this time, there is mention of China. The G7 explicitly agreed to call out human rights abuses in Xinjiang and in Hong Kong explicitly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Two, to coordinate a common strategy to deal with China non-market policies that undermine competition. They&#8217;ve agreed &#8212; and that&#8217;s underway now &#8212; how to do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Three, to take serious actions against forced labor in solar, agriculture, and the garment industries because that&#8217;s where it&#8217;s happening. And they&#8217;ve agreed we will do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>To launch &#8212; what I said earlier; I really feel very strongly &#8212; I proposed that we have a democratic alternative to the Belt and Road Initiative: the Build Back Better. And they&#8217;ve agreed to that, and that&#8217;s underway as the details of that &#8212; we agreed that we’d put together a committee to do that and come up with that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And thirdly, that we are going to insist on a high-standards to be &#8212; for a climate-friendly, transparent alternative to the Belt and Road Initiative. And &#8212; but, in the meantime, we&#8217;re going to move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, I think it&#8217;s always &#8212; let me put it this way: I know this is going sound somewhat prosaic, but I think we&#8217;re in a contest &#8212; not with China per se, but a contest with autocrats, autocratic governments around the world, as to whether or not democracies can compete with them in the rapidly changing 21st century.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think how we act and whether we pull together as democracies is going to determine whether our grandkids look back 15 years from now and say, &#8220;Did they step up? Are democracies as relevant and as powerful as they have been?&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I walked away from the meeting with all my colleagues believing that they are convinced that that is correct now too. Not &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t say &#8220;now”. Not just because of me, but they believe that to be the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I think you&#8217;re going to see just straightforward dealing with China. And again, we&#8217;re not looking &#8212; as I&#8217;ve told Xi Jinping myself, I&#8217;m not looking for conflict. Where we can cooperate, we&#8217;ll cooperate. Where we disagree, I&#8217;m going to state it frankly, and we are going to respond to actions that are inconsistent.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, we talked about trade. It&#8217;s one thing to talk about whether or not our agricultural policy makes sense. It’s another thing to say, “By the way, you&#8217;re demanding that if I do business with your country, I&#8217;ve got to give you all my trade secrets and have the &#8212; the Chinese partner have 51 percent of that?” No. Not us.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; So, are you saying, Mr. President &#8212; are you satisfied with what came out in the communiqué?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Or do you wish it were tougher? Do you wish there was more &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; action on China?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: I think there&#8217;s plenty of action on China, and there&#8217;s always something that you can &#8212; I&#8217;m sure my colleagues think there&#8217;s things they think they can improve that they wanted. But I&#8217;m satisfied.<br>&nbsp;<br>Steve Holland, Reuters.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, sir. Just to follow up on Jennifer’s question: The communiqué cited a variety of fronts on China, everything from human rights, the origin of the COVID virus, Taiwan. What do you think China needs to do to ease tensions?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: I think China has to start to act more responsibly in terms of international norms on human rights and transparency.<br>&nbsp;<br>Transparency matters across the board. And I think the idea that &#8212; for example, one of the things I raised and others raised &#8212; I wasn&#8217;t the only one who raised this at the G7 &#8212; is that we don&#8217;t know &#8212; we haven&#8217;t had access to the laboratories to determine whether or not &#8212; and I have not reached a conclusion because our intelligence community is not certain yet whether or not this was a consequence of a &#8212; from the marketplace of a bat, you know, interfacing with &#8212; with animals in the environment that caused this &#8212; this COVID-19, or whether it was an experiment gone awry in a laboratory.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s important to know the answer to that because we have to have access &#8212; we have to build a system whereby we can know what &#8212; when we see another transparent &#8212; lack of transparency that might produce another vac- &#8212; another pandemic. We have to have access. The world has to have access.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re trying to figure out, at the G7, whether we could put together an international basis upon which we could have a bottom line with what the transparency accounted for.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; And you mentioned &#8212; you mentioned that the argument behind the scenes, that you had not mentioned China in three years in one of these communiqués. What did you argue behind the scenes to try to bring people to the point where they got?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: To answer that question &#8212; there&#8217;s no way to answer without sounding self-serving. Let me just say this: I just laid out what I thought was the need for us to be consistent to protect our economies and to see to it that other struggling economies, who needed help, got the help and were not held captive by other nations.<br>&nbsp;<br>But you might ask that to others. I&#8217;m not trying to be a wise guy, but I &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>And Wall Street Journal. Andrew.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; As you said, the G7 countries committed to send 1 billion coronavirus doses overseas, but the World Health Organization says 11 billion doses are needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; How are you going to bridge that gap? Will the U.S. commit to send additional doses overseas? And given the gap, is it actually realistic to end the pandemic by 2022?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: It is &#8212; it may take slightly longer than &#8212; worldwide. But the United States is going to continue &#8212; I think there&#8217;s a possibility, over 2022 going into 2023, that we would be able to be in a position to provide another billion &#8212; us. But that&#8217;s not done yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>I only &#8212; I&#8217;ve been very careful, as I&#8217;ve dealt with this pandemic, to tell you what I know and say what I thought could be done, and when I&#8217;ve announced that I&#8217;ve gone and done it. What I don&#8217;t want to do is be getting too far ahead in suggesting that we can do things and I can do things &#8212; the United States can do things that I don&#8217;t have done yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I &#8212; there was a clear consensus among all our colleagues at the G7 that this wasn&#8217;t the end; we were going to stay at it until we&#8217;re able to provide for &#8212; able to provide for the needs of the whole world, in terms &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Because, look, it&#8217;s not just the right thing to do. And from a &#8212; from a &#8212; how can I say it? From a &#8212; from a moral standpoint. But it is also the correct thing to do, in terms of our own health, our own security. You can&#8217;t build a wall high enough to keep out new strains. You can&#8217;t do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I think this is going to be a constant project for a long time. And there may be other pandemics. We &#8212; again, setting up a system whereby we can detect &#8212; before it gets out of control &#8212; one, a pandemic, that may be on the horizon &#8212; a virus &#8212; is important.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we are not going to &#8212; as long as there&#8217;s nations in need that &#8212; being able to be vaccinated, we in fact &#8212; not &#8212; not only that: We&#8217;ve been engaged in helping &#8212; which I&#8217;ve made clear, and most of our &#8212; my colleagues understood it. I mean, they understood it &#8212; knew it from trying it themselves. This is a gigantic logistical effort. It&#8217;s one thing to send nation X, X number &#8212; Y number of vaccines. It&#8217;s another thing to have the people that can actually get it in somebody&#8217;s arm. And so, we are also providing the ability for other countries to manufacture their vaccines. We&#8217;ve all agreed on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>India has the capacity to do that. They don&#8217;t have the material capacity thus far to do the manufacturing. But there&#8217;s a lot going on to provide &#8212; not only to, quote, &#8220;give&#8221; vaccines, but to provide the ability of the countries in question to produce their own vaccines.<br>&nbsp;<br>AIDE: Last question. Last question.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: I&#8217;m not going to answer anything. No, I&#8217;m joking. Last question. Peter Alexander, NBC News.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you very much. About Vladimir Putin and your meeting this week: As you&#8217;re well aware, the U.S. has been slapping sanctions on Russia for years for its malign activities, and Russia has not stopped. So what specifically will you do differently to change Vladimir Putin&#8217;s behavior?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Well, first of all, there&#8217;s no guarantee you can change a person&#8217;s behavior or the behavior of his country. Autocrats have enormous power and they don&#8217;t have to answer to a public. &nbsp;And the fact is that it may very well be, if I respond in kind &#8212; which I will &#8212; that it doesn&#8217;t dissuade him and he wants to keep going.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think that we&#8217;re going to be moving in a direction where Russia has &#8212; has its own dilemmas, let us say, dealing with its economy, dealing with its &#8212; dealing with COVID, and dealing with not only the United States, but Europe writ large and in the Middle East.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, there&#8217;s a lot going on where we can work together with Russia. For example, in Libya, we should be opening up the passes to be able to go through and provide &#8212; provide food assistance and economic &#8212; I mean, vital assistance to a population that&#8217;s in real trouble.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think I&#8217;m going to try very much &#8212; hard to &#8212; it is &#8212; and, by the way, there&#8217;s places where &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t be starting off on negotiating in public here. But let me say it this way: Russia has engaged in activities which are &#8212; we believe are contrary to international norms, but they have also bitten off some real problems they&#8217;re going to have trouble chewing on.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, for example, the rebuilding of &#8212; of Syria, of Libya, of &#8212; you know, this is &#8212; they&#8217;re there. And as long as they&#8217;re there without the ability to bring about some order in the &#8212; in the region, and you can&#8217;t do that very well without providing for the basic economic needs of people.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I&#8217;m hopeful that we can find an accommodation that &#8211;where we can save the lives of people in &#8212; for example, in &#8212; in Libya, that &#8212; consistent with the interest of &#8212; maybe for different reasons &#8212; but reached it for the same reason &#8212; the same result.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; I want to ask you about a comment that Vladimir Putin said today. But why do you think he hasn&#8217;t changed his behavior in spite of everything the U.S. has done to this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: (Laughs.) He&#8217;s Vladimir Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to get into much more than that, because I&#8217;ve got to sit down with him. And I&#8217;ll be happy to talk to you after that. But &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; But he said &#8212; then, just to conclude &#8212; today, he said that Russia would be ready to hand over cyber criminals to the United States if the U.S. would do the same to Russia and an agreement came out of this meeting coming up. So, are you open to that kind of a trade with Vladimir Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Yes, I&#8217;m open to &#8212; if there&#8217;s crimes committed against Russia that, in fact, are &#8212; and the people committing those crimes are being harbored in the United States &#8212; I&#8217;m committed to holding them accountable. And I&#8217;m &#8212; I heard that; I was told, as I was flying here, that he said that. I think that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s potentially a good sign and progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all very, very much. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; May I ask, sir, (inaudible) &#8212; (off mic.) The European allies &#8212; can I ask a question about the European allies?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: (Laughs.) I&#8217;m going to get in trouble with my pre- &#8212; my staff. Yeah, go ahead. But pretend that I didn&#8217;t answer you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you very much, sir. You have often said repeatedly that &#8220;America is back.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; At the same time, you&#8217;ve kept in play some Trump-era steel and aluminum sanctions. And I wanted to ask you: When you&#8217;re having these conversations with European allies who are very concerned about these sanctions, how do you justify that? And what are your plans for &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: A hundred and twenty days. Give me a break. Need time.<br>&nbsp;<br>3:22 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CARBIS BAY G7 SUMMIT COMMUNIQUÉ</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/carbis-bay-g7-summit-communique/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 13:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the leaders of the Group of Seven, met in Cornwall on 11-13 June 2021 determined to beat COVID-19 and build back better.&#160; We remembered everyone who has been lost to the pandemic and paid tribute to those still striving to overcome it. Inspired by their example of collaboration and determination, we gathered united by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We, the leaders of the Group of Seven, met in Cornwall on 11-13 June 2021 determined to beat COVID-19 and build back better.&nbsp; We remembered everyone who has been lost to the pandemic and paid tribute to those still striving to overcome it. Inspired by their example of collaboration and determination, we gathered united by the principle that brought us together originally, that shared beliefs and shared responsibilities are the bedrock of leadership and prosperity.&nbsp; Guided by this, our enduring ideals as free open societies and democracies, and by our commitment to multilateralism, we have agreed a shared G7 agenda for global action to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>End the pandemic and prepare for the future </strong>by driving an intensified international effort, starting immediately, to vaccinate the world by getting as many safe vaccines to as many people as possible as fast as possible. Total G7 commitments since the start of the pandemic provide for a total of over two billion vaccine doses, with the commitments since we last met in February 2021, including here in Carbis Bay, providing for one billion doses over the next year. At the same time we will create the appropriate frameworks to strengthen our collective defences against threats to global health by: increasing and coordinating on global manufacturing capacity on all continents; improving early warning systems; and support science in a mission to shorten the cycle for the development of safe and effective vaccines, treatments and tests from 300 to 100 days.<br></li><li><strong>Reinvigorate our economies</strong> by advancing recovery plans that build on the $12 trillion of support we have put in place during the pandemic. We will continue to support our economies for as long as is necessary, shifting the focus of our support from crisis response to promoting growth into the future, with plans that create jobs, invest in infrastructure, drive innovation, support people, and level up so that no place or person, irrespective of age, ethnicity or gender is left behind. This has not been the case with past global crises, and we are determined that this time it will be different.<br></li><li><strong>Secure our future prosperity </strong>by championing freer, fairer trade within a reformed trading system, a more resilient global economy, and a fairer global tax system that reverses the race to the bottom. We will collaborate to ensure future frontiers of the global economy and society, from cyber space to outer space, increase the prosperity and wellbeing of all people while upholding our values as open societies. We are convinced of the potential of technological transformation for the common good in accordance with our shared values.<br></li><li><strong>Protect our planet </strong>by supporting a green revolution that creates jobs, cuts emissions and seeks to limit the rise in global temperatures to 1.5 degrees. We commit to net zero no later than 2050, halving our collective emissions over the two decades to 2030, increasing and improving climate finance to 2025; and to conserve or protect at least 30 percent of our land and oceans by 2030. We acknowledge our duty to safeguard the planet for future generations.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Strengthen our partnerships </strong>with others around the world. We will develop a new partnership to build back better for the world, through a step change in our approach to investment for infrastructure, including through an initiative for clean and green growth. We are resolved to deepen our current partnership to a new deal with Africa, including by magnifying support from the International Monetary Fund for countries most in need to support our aim to reach a total global ambition of $100 billion.<br></li><li><strong>Embrace our values</strong> as an enduring foundation for success in an ever changing world. We will harness the power of democracy, freedom, equality, the rule of law and respect for human rights to answer the biggest questions and overcome the greatest challenges. We will do this in a way that values the individual and promotes equality, especially gender equality, including by supporting a target to get 40 million more girls into education and with at least $2¾ billion for the Global Partnership for Education.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>We shall seek to advance this open agenda in collaboration with other countries and within the multilateral rules-based system. In particular, we look forward to working alongside our G20 partners and with all relevant International Organisations to secure a cleaner, greener, freer, fairer and safer future for our people and planet.<br><br><strong>INTRODUCTION</strong><br><br>1. We, the Leaders of the Group of Seven, met together in Cornwall, United Kingdom on 11-13 June 2021 at a critical juncture for our people and planet.&nbsp;<br><br>2. We acknowledge the ongoing impacts of COVID-19 in our own societies and around the world, and that those impacts have not been felt evenly. We remember all those who have died as a result of the pandemic and pay tribute to all those continuing to work to overcome the virus.<br><br>3. United as open societies and economies and guided by our shared values of democracy, freedom, equality, the rule of law and respect for human rights, we commit to beating COVID-19 everywhere and building back better for all. We are firmly convinced that these values remain the best foundation for the social and economic advancement of all humanity. We affirm that by investing in our people, tackling inequalities, including gender inequality, promoting dignity and championing freedoms, we will release innovation capable of tackling the great challenges of our time.<br><br>4. Our agenda for global action is built on our commitment to international cooperation, multilateralism and an open, resilient, rules-based world order. As democratic societies we support global institutions in their efforts to protect human rights, respect the rule of law, advance gender equality, manage tensions between states, address conflict, instability and climate change, and share prosperity through trade and investment. That open and resilient international order is in turn the best guarantor of security and prosperity for our own citizens.<br><br>5. We were joined in Cornwall by the Leaders of Australia, India, the Republic of Korea and South Africa, with whom we have agreed a shared statement on the value and role of open societies. We will continue to work together with these and all our partners in tackling global challenges. We reaffirm our commitment to multilateralism and to working with the G20, UN and wider multilateral system to deliver a strong, sustainable, resilient and inclusive recovery.<br><br><strong>HEALTH</strong><br><br>6. Our immediate focus is beating COVID-19 and we set a collective goal of ending the pandemic in 2022. The COVID-19 pandemic is not under control anywhere until it is under control everywhere. In an interconnected world global health and health security threats respect no borders. We therefore commit both to strengthen global action now to fight COVID-19, and to take further tangible steps to improve our collective defences against future threats and to bolster global health and health security. This includes strengthening the World Health Organization (WHO) and supporting it in its leading and coordinating role in the global health system.<br><br>7. We recognise that the pandemic has left no one untouched, impacting not only physical health but also mental health and social wellbeing. We pay tribute to the extraordinary efforts of first responders, health workers, paid and unpaid care workers, scientists, and manufacturers who have developed and deployed COVID-19 medical tools at a pace few thought possible, opening up a path out of the pandemic. At the same time, we recognise that we have a long way to go to achieve global equitable access to these medical tools, and to manage the risks from new COVID-19 variants which have the potential to reverse our progress.<br><br>8. Recognising that ending the pandemic in 2022 will require vaccinating at least 60 per cent of the global population, we will intensify our action to save lives. Our international priority is to&nbsp; accelerate the rollout of safe and effective, accessible and affordable vaccines for the poorest countries, noting the role of extensive immunisation as a global public good. We reiterate our endorsement of the G20 Rome Declaration and the statement agreed by our Foreign and Development Ministers on equitable access. We will work together and with others, leveraging the full spectrum of the capability and capacity we can each deploy to support the global vaccination effort, through finance for and sharing of doses, science, ensuring accessibility through voluntary licensing, manufacturing and ensuring availability through exports, opening supply chains, and supporting final mile delivery.<br><br>9. We reaffirm our support for the ACT-A and its COVAX Facility as the primary route for providing vaccines to the poorest countries. Since the start of the pandemic, we have committed $8.6 billion to the vaccines pillar of ACT-A to finance the procurement of vaccines, including $1.9 billion since we last met in February.&nbsp; This provides for the equivalent of over one billion doses. We welcome the recent successful COVAX Summit co-hosted by Japan and Gavi which mobilised financing pledges exceeding the COVAX AMC target. Recognising the urgent need to speed up delivery of doses, we are committing to share at least 870 million doses directly over the next year. We will make these doses available as soon as possible and aim to deliver at least half by the end of 2021 primarily channelled through COVAX towards those in greatest need. Taken together, the dose equivalent of our financial contributions and our direct dose sharing mean that the G7’s commitments since the start of the pandemic provide for a total of over two billion vaccine doses. The commitments since we last met in February 2021 including here in Carbis Bay provide for one billion doses over the next year. We will work together with the private sector, the G20 and other countries to increase this contribution over the months to come.<br><br>10. These commitments build on our wider contributions to the global vaccination effort. These include exports from domestic production, with at least 700 million doses exported or to be exported this year, of which almost half have gone or will go to non-G7 countries, with a commitment to continue exporting in significant proportions; and the promotion of voluntary licensing and not-for-profit global production, which has so far accounted for over 95 per cent of the COVAX supply.<br><br>11. We reaffirm our support for all pillars of the ACT-A across, treatments, tests and strengthening public health systems as well as vaccines. As the G7, since our meeting in February, we have committed over $2 billion in total to the ACT-Accelerator (including vaccines), taking our collective commitment since the start of the pandemic to over $10 billion. We support discussions regarding the extension of the ACT-A mandate into 2022, noting the planned comprehensive review to optimise its effectiveness and accountability. Efforts on this scale require close monitoring of progress made by ACT-A with reliable, transparent, up-to-date and clear information on procurement and delivery to both donor and recipient countries in close partnership with regional organisations. Progress should be reported to the G20 in Rome.<br><br>12. In support of achieving our goal, we commit to an end-to-end approach to boost supply of COVID-19 tools, including vaccines, raw materials, tests, therapeutics, and personal protective equipment (PPE), through more production in more places&nbsp; to sustain a global supply network for this pandemic and the next. This will be based on the principles of open trade and transparency, including through terminating unnecessary trade restrictive measures and supporting open, diversified, secure and resilient supply chains. It will be backed up by a practical and pragmatic approach to breaking down bottlenecks that are holding back the efficient use of current production capacity, as well as promoting partnerships to increase capacity further. To this end, we will support the ACT-A Facilitation Council Working Group together with the World Health Organisation (WHO), the World Trade Organisation (WTO), Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI), Gavi, UNICEF and other partners such as the Medicines Patent Pool and the private sector, to coordinate a global vaccine supply network to optimise manufacturing capacities for safe and effective vaccines and other pandemic tools, and to share information about supply chains. Emphasising the need for equitable access to COVID-19 vaccines, we will support manufacturing in low income countries and, noting the importance of intellectual property in this regard, we will engage constructively with discussions at the WTO on the role of intellectual property, including by working consistently within the TRIPS agreement and the 2001 Doha Declaration on the TRIPS agreement and Public Health. We note the positive impact that voluntary licensing and technology transfer on mutually agreed terms have already made to increasing global supply. We note the positive impact that voluntary licensing and technology transfer on mutually agreed terms have already made to increasing global supply. We will explore all options to ensure affordable and accessible COVID-19 tools for the poorest countries, including non-profit production, tiered and transparent pricing, and sharing by manufacturers of a proportion of production with COVAX, noting the previous precedent of the 10 per cent target in relation to influenza. We support efforts to accelerate manufacturing capacities of COVID-19 tools on all continents, encouraging new partnerships based on voluntary licensing and technology transfer on mutually agreed terms and in particular will strive to support African efforts to establish regional manufacturing hubs. We will continue to work with partners, regional organisations and recipient countries, including through COVAX, to boost country-readiness, and will maintain our efforts to support vaccine confidence.<br><br>13. To get and stay ahead of the virus, we commit to continue our investment in cutting edge research and innovation, seeking to ensure that global vaccines remain effective against variants of concern, and that effective tests and treatments are available. To this end, we will boost global surveillance&nbsp; and genomic sequencing and swift information sharing needed to enable the rapid detection to combat the virus and its emerging variants. G7 countries should extend every effort to achieve, wherever possible, a level of genomic sequencing of at least 10 per cent of all new positive COVID-19 samples during the pandemic phase and share genomic sequencing information with existing global databases.<br><br>14. Alongside the above, we will continue and enhance our commitments to&nbsp; support fragile countries in dealing with the pandemic and other health challenges. This includes supporting ACT-A partners such as The Global Fund and Unitaid which have played a crucial role in delivering lifesaving medical and other supplies, including oxygen, tests, therapeutics and PPE, and assisting countries together with WHO to strengthen their health systems, build capacity, manage outbreaks and prevent disease spread. We call on the World Bank Group and the other Multilateral Development Banks (MDBs) to increase the speed of their financial support, and will continue to support ACT-A in this regard.<br><br>15. Alongside responding to the current pandemic, we must act now to strengthen the global health and health security system to be better prepared for future pandemics and to tackle long standing global health threats, including Antimicrobial Resistance. We welcome the Rome Declaration, the measures set out within the ‘Strengthening WHO preparedness for and response to health emergencies’ Resolution as adopted at the 74th World Health Assembly, acknowledge the bold recommendations of the Independent Panel for Pandemic Preparedness and Response (IPPPR), and the work of the International Health Regulations Review Committee (IHR Review Committee) and Independent Oversight and Advisory Committee (IOAC). We look forward to continuing to work with the G20, UN, WHO, WTO and other relevant international organisations, in accordance with their mandates and rules for decision making, to make progress in the swift implementation of recommendations, and to seek the necessary multilateral action, including exploring the potential value of a treaty. We look forward to the special session on pandemic preparedness in the Autumn, as agreed at the World Health Assembly.<br><br>16. As G7 countries, we acknowledge our particular role and responsibilities in international efforts to strengthen the global health system, and commit to harnessing our unique strengths to support this. We endorse the G7 Carbis Bay Health Declaration and the G7 Health Ministers’ Communique, and the concrete actions outlined to ensure all countries are better equipped to prevent, detect, respond to and recover from health crises including in alignment with the International Health Regulations (IHR). We place particular emphasis on:</p>



<ul><li>Improving integration, by strengthening a “One Health” approach across all aspects of pandemic prevention and preparedness, recognising the critical links between human and animal health and the environment.</li><li>Strengthening transparency and accountability, including reiterating our commitment to the full implementation of, and improved compliance with, the International Health Regulations 2005. This includes investigating, reporting and responding to outbreaks of unknown origin. We also call for a timely, transparent, expert-led, and science-based WHO-convened Phase 2 COVID-19 Origins study including, as recommended by the experts’ report, in China.</li><li>Improving the speed of response by developing global protocols which trigger collective action in the event of a future pandemic.</li><li>Ensuring fairness, inclusion and equity, including the empowerment and leadership of women and minorities in the health and care sectors, and addressing the links between health crises and wider social determinants of health such as poverty and structural inequalities, and leaving no one behind by advancing the achievement of Universal Health Coverage.</li><li>Increasing the resilience of global health systems to deal with outbreaks of emerging and enduring pathogens, including by investing in the health and care workforce worldwide to build capacity and keep health care workers safe.</li><li>Strengthening financing models to support longer-term preparedness, sustainable global health and health security, in particular but not limited to the WHO. We will explore options for building consensus this year, around sustainable global health and health security financing, supported by robust financial reporting, increased and defined accountability, and oversight. We ask our Finance Ministers to work with others, the G20 and its High Level Independent Panel (HLIP) to make progress in this regard. We will explore options to strengthen global accountability, tracking and allocation of global health security financing, including the IPPPR recommendation toward a Global Health Threats Council.</li></ul>



<p>17. The G7 has a leading role to play in deploying our collective scientific capabilities as part of an enhanced global health response. Data can play a transformative role in supporting effective early warning and rapid response to health crises. We therefore need to improve the quality and coverage of international, regional and national pathogen surveillance to enable us to gather, share and analyse data to identify new variants in our fight against the current pandemic, and to detect and monitor future pathogens with pandemic potential. We support the establishment of the international pathogen surveillance network &#8211; a global pandemic radar &#8211; and welcome the WHO’s commitment to work with experts and countries to help achieve this, based on a common framework, including standards and rules for sharing data, that builds on existing detection systems such as the influenza and polio programmes but with greater capacity for genomic sequencing and broader in coverage. We note the report to the Presidency on pathogen surveillance by Sir Jeremy Farrar. To this end we welcome the WHO’s Global Hub for Pandemic and Epidemic Intelligence, as well as additional centres as part of this network. This will also need to be supported by capability building at the regional level, thereby increasing global sequencing and pathogen surveillance capacities across the world. We ask that the WHO reports back to Leaders on the progress of the network by the end of this year as part of the G20 process.<br><br>18. It is essential that we maintain and build upon the extraordinary innovation, scientific power, and collaboration that we have seen in the response to this pandemic, including the development of COVID-19 vaccines in just over 300 days. As G7 members we have a particular role to play in seeking to make safe and effective diagnostics, therapeutics and vaccines even more quickly available in the future. Recognising the unpredictable nature of future health emergencies, in the event of a future pandemic we will seek to create an adequate framework to have safe and effective vaccines, therapeutics and diagnostics available within 100 days, consistent with our core principles around trade and transparency of equitable access, and high regulatory standards. We thank the UK’s Chief Scientific Adviser and his G7 counterparts, the international organisations, industry representatives and expert advisers involved in the partnership on pandemic preparedness convened by the UK Presidency and note their practical proposals. We welcome the 100 Days Mission, and recognise that this will require continued, concerted collaboration between the public and private sectors, and the leadership of international health organisations, to make what has been exceptional during this crisis become routine in the future. We invite G7 Chief Scientific Advisers or equivalents to review progress and report to Leaders before the end of the year.<br><br><strong>ECONOMIC RECOVERY AND JOBS</strong><br><br>19. Our plans for the recovery from COVID-19 need to put us on a path to strong, sustainable, balanced, inclusive and resilient growth by not only addressing the immediate challenges arising from the pandemic, but also the long-term shifts in the global economy and society, including demographic, technological, and environmental trends, and inequalities between and within countries, many of which have been magnified by the COVID-19 pandemic. Recognising the interconnected nature of these global challenges, we are taking an integrated approach to our shared commitments.<br><br>20. To mitigate the impact of the pandemic, we have provided unprecedented support to citizens and businesses, including to retain jobs and support incomes and keep businesses afloat, totalling over $12 trillion including fiscal support and liquidity measures. We will continue to support our economies for as long as is necessary, shifting the focus of our support from crisis response to promoting strong, resilient, sustainable, balanced and inclusive growth into the future. Once the recovery is firmly established, we need to ensure the long-term sustainability of public finances to enable us to respond to future crises and address longer-term structural challenges, including for the benefit of future generations.<br><br>21. We share key priorities including protecting, supporting and creating decent jobs, and investing in quality infrastructure, innovation, training and skills and addressing inequalities. We will continue to exchange ideas and share best practices to ensure we learn from each other and update our approaches through different phases of the recovery. We thank Lord Nick Stern for his paper on “G7 leadership for sustainable, resilient and inclusive economic recovery and growth” as commissioned by the UK G7 Presidency. At the heart of our agenda for economic growth and recovery is a green and digital transformation that will increase productivity, create new decent and quality jobs, cut greenhouse gas emissions, improve our resilience, and protect people and the planet as we aim for net zero by 2050.<br><br>22. We need a tax system that is fair across the world. We endorse the historic commitment made by the G7 on 5 June. We will now continue the discussion to reach consensus on a global agreement on an equitable solution on the allocation of taxing rights and an ambitious global minimum tax of at least 15 per cent on a country-by-country basis, through the G20/OECD inclusive framework and look forward to reaching an agreement at the July meeting of G20 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors. With this, we have taken a significant step towards creating a fairer tax system fit for the 21st century, and reversing a 40-year race to the bottom. Our collaboration will create a stronger <s>l</s>evel playing field, and it will help raise more tax revenue to support investment and it will crack down on tax avoidance.<br><br>23. We recognise the importance to the global economy of safely restarting international travel, by land, air and sea, and multilateral efforts to achieve this, including new public health guidance on international travel by the WHO, International Civil Aviation Organisation and International Maritime Organisation. We recognise that this will need a set of common standards for travel including interoperability and mutual recognition of digital applications,&nbsp; testing requirements, recognition of vaccination status including exemptions and comparable criteria for when responsive measures may be required. We welcome G7 Transport and Health Ministers’ ongoing discussions and ask them to deepen cooperation to support a safe reopening.<br><br>24. As leaders accountable to all our citizens, we are determined to ensure our plans for recovery build back better for all including by strengthening education and upskilling, and facilitating labour market participation and transitions to ‘level up’ our economies so that no geographic region or person, irrespective of their gender, age, disability, ethnicity, sexual orientation or economic status, is left behind. We recognise this has not always been the case with recoveries from previous global crises, and are together united in our resolve that this time our response should continue to be different.<br><br>25. While our support during the pandemic has helped to keep millions of people in employment, the crisis has meant that many have still lost their jobs, and the impact has not been felt equally, including with respect to young people, women and disadvantaged groups, as well as atypical and low-skilled workers. The crisis has also shown the importance of social protection systems and the critical role and incredible contribution of caregivers in our societies, often unpaid and often disproportionately women, and the importance of improving decent working conditions for these caregivers as part of our recovery plans. At the same time, technological change is profoundly changing our labour markets. We welcome the contributions of the G7 Employment Taskforce on building back better, greener and more inclusively, including their discussions with social partners and G7 Engagement Groups, including Labour 7, Youth 7, Women 7 and Business 7 covering how we can prepare our labour markets for the future. One of the highest priorities for our ongoing cooperation will be ensuring our labour markets continue to evolve to respond to these changes and deliver decent jobs and equal opportunities for everyone, while fully respecting the ILO Fundamental Principles and Rights at Work, and taking into account relevant international labour standards.<br><br>26. The COVID-19 pandemic has illustrated the risk to economic resilience posed by global crises and shocks. These can manifest from acute shocks, for example as a result of pandemics, and chronically, from challenges such as market imbalances and distortions. Our recoveries must ensure we build back more resilient. As we recover, these risks need addressing in a more coordinated way. We will collaborate more strongly between us and with allies on a new approach to economic resilience. We recognise climate change and growing inequalities as key risks for the global economy. We will consider mechanisms and share best practices to address risks to the resilience of the critical global supply chains, in areas such as critical minerals and semiconductors, reflecting on models used elsewhere such as stress-testing. We will also enhance our cooperation on investment security within our G7 Investment Screening Expert Group, to ensure we are resilient in our openness to all, able to tackle risks in keeping with our shared principles of open markets, transparency and competition. Our solutions will be built on our shared principles of openness, sustainability, inclusion, innovation and competition will help retain and reinforce the benefits of open markets; without them, we risk a future of normalised volatility and fragmentation in the global economy. To this end we appreciate the work by the G7 Panel on Economic Resilience, and thank the OECD for its work in support, and we will continue to work on the issues highlighted by the Panel.<br><br><strong>FREE AND FAIR TRADE</strong><br><br>27. We stand united in our commitment to free and fair trade as foundational principles and objectives of the rules-based multilateral system. We agree on the need for the world’s leading democratic nations to unite behind a shared vision to ensure the multilateral trading system is reformed, with a modernised rulebook and a reformed World Trade Organization (WTO) at its centre, to be free and fair for all, more sustainable, resilient and responsive to the needs of global citizens. We will maintain a particular focus on ensuring that the prosperity trade can bring is felt in all parts of our countries and by all peoples across the globe, especially the poor.<br><br>28. We support multilateral and plurilateral agendas to address issues in the global trading system itself and shared global challenges. We support G7 Trade Ministers’ efforts in this regard, and look forward to further work in the G20. Looking ahead to the 12th WTO Ministerial Conference (MC12) in November, we will work with other WTO members to make progress on immediate issues, including reaching a meaningful conclusion to the multilateral negotiation on fisheries subsidies and advancing negotiations on e-commerce. We also welcome the work undertaken towards the conclusion of the negotiations under the Joint Statement Initiative on Services Domestic Regulation by its participants. We support G7 Trade Ministers&#8217; commitments to review our trade policy to ensure it supports women’s economic empowerment, and recognise the importance of developing a strong evidence base of gender-disaggregated data and analysis. We invite Trade Ministers to support the wider WTO membership to deliver an ambitious outcome at MC12 to bolster women&#8217;s participation in trade and economic empowerment. We endorse the conclusions of G7 Trade Ministers on promoting the transition to sustainable supply chains, and acknowledge the risk of carbon leakage, and will work collaboratively to address this risk and to align our trading practices with our commitments under the Paris agreement. We also welcome G7 Trade Ministers’ call to work in the WTO to formulate pragmatic, effective and holistic solutions to support trade in health, as well as their support for open, diversified, secure, and resilient supply chains in the manufacture of COVID-19 critical goods and vaccines and their components.<br><br>29. We are concerned by the use of all forms of forced labour in global supply chains, including state-sponsored forced labour of vulnerable groups and minorities, including in the agricultural, solar, and garment sectors. We agree on the importance of upholding human rights and of international labour standards, including those deriving from International Labour Organisation membership, throughout global supply chains and tackling instances of forced labour. We commit to continue to work together including through our own available domestic means and multilateral institutions to protect individuals from forced labour and to ensure that global supply chains are free from the use of forced labour. We therefore task G7 Trade Ministers to identify areas for strengthened cooperation and collective efforts towards eradicating the use of all forms of forced labour in global supply chains, ahead of the G7 Trade Ministers&#8217; meeting in October 2021.<br><br>30. We will provide the sustained effort and momentum necessary to ensure progress is made in the modernisation of the WTO to promote fair competition and help secure shared prosperity for all. We will work together at the WTO and with the wider WTO membership ahead of MC12 to advance the following points:</p>



<ul><li>modernisation of the global trade rulebook so that it both better reflects, with new rules, the transformations underway in the global economy, such as digitalisation and the green transition; and strengthens rules to protect against unfair practices, such as forced technology transfer, intellectual property theft, lowering of labour and environmental standards to gain competitive advantage, market-distorting actions of state owned enterprises, and harmful industrial subsidies, including those that lead to excess capacity;</li><li>stronger adherence to the existing and modernised rulebook, including through greater respect for and compliance with transparency obligations, and a strengthened WTO monitoring and deliberating function;</li><li>a fairer approach to countries’ different responsibilities under the rulebook, including through addressing the arrangements for special and differential treatment so they reflect developments in the global economy but continue to account for the special needs of the least developed and low-income developing countries;</li><li>proper functioning of the WTO’s negotiating function and dispute settlement system, requiring addressing long-standing issues; and,</li><li>support for the interests of the least developed and low-income developing countries,&nbsp;including in the full implementation of WTO rules to integrate into the world trading system, so that any modernisation of the global trading system supports the social and economic growth and development of these countries.</li></ul>



<p><strong>FUTURE FRONTIERS</strong><br><br>31. Future frontiers of the global economy and society &#8211; from cyber space to outer space &#8211; will determine the future prosperity and wellbeing of people all over the world in the decades ahead. As we are witnessing an increasing divergence of models, this transformation raises important questions about the interaction between economic opportunity, security, ethics, and human rights, and the balance between the role of the state, businesses and individuals.<br><br>32. We will work together as part of an ongoing agenda towards a trusted, values-driven digital ecosystem for the common good that enhances prosperity in a way that is sustainable, inclusive, transparent and human-centric. In doing so we will make it a sustained strategic priority to update our regulatory frameworks and work together with other relevant stakeholders, including young people, to ensure digital ecosystems evolve in a way that reflects our shared values. We commit to preserve an open, interoperable, reliable and secure internet, one that is unfragmented, supports freedom, innovation and trust which empowers people. If used properly, technologies can help us strengthen health capacities, tackle environmental threats, widen access to education and open new economic opportunities. We will leverage these technologies to advance tech for the common good and promote digital literacy worldwide. We will strengthen coordination on and support for the implementation and development of global norms and standards to ensure that the use and evolution of new technologies reflects our shared democratic values and commitment to open and competitive markets, strong safeguards including for human rights and fundamental freedoms. We also affirm our opposition to measures which may undermine these democratic values, such as government-imposed internet shutdowns and network restrictions. We support the development of harmonised principles of data collection which encourage public and private organisations to act to address bias in their own systems, noting new forms of decision-making have surfaced examples where algorithms have entrenched or amplified historic biases, or even created new forms of bias or unfairness.<br><br>33. We call on the private sector to join us in our efforts and reaffirm our support for industry-led inclusive multi-stakeholder approaches to standard setting, in line with our values and principles which underpin these standards. As such, we welcome the Presidency&#8217;s initiative of a ‘Future Tech Forum’ in September 2021 with the support of the OECD. The Forum will convene like-minded democratic partners to discuss the role of technology in supporting open societies and tackling global challenges. The Forum will support efforts to mitigate the risk of regulatory fragmentation and to facilitate coherency of our emerging technology ecosystems, and it will invite proposals for Leaders to consider in appropriate global fora. We support the aim to facilitate dialogue between governments, industry, academia, civil society and other key stakeholders. As such we will continue to take bold action to build more transparency in our technologies, building on the Open Government Partnership. Building on the work of the Global Partnership for Artificial Intelligence (GPAI) advanced by the Canadian and French G7 Presidencies in 2018 and 2019, we will aim to rally all partners around our open and human centric approach to artificial intelligence looking forward to the GPAI Summit in Paris in November 2021. To support effective standard-setting that reflects our core values and principles, we will strengthen our coordination, including by consulting with industry, with regards to engagement with and appointments to Standard Developing Organisations, where appropriate. We commit to better sharing of information and best practice, including between our national standards bodies, enhanced capacity building and support for multi-stakeholder participation in standard-setting. To this end, we endorse the Framework for G7 Collaboration on Digital Technical Standards.<br><br>34. We will support cooperation on specific areas in relation to the evolution of future frontiers. Based on the work of our Digital and Technology Ministers, we agree the focus of our cooperation for this year will be a structured dialogue around specific areas:</p>



<ul><li>Championing data free flow with trust, to better leverage the potential of valuable data-driven technologies while continuing to address challenges related to data protection. To that end we endorse our Digital Ministers’ Roadmap for Cooperation on Data Free Flow with Trust.</li><li>Enabling businesses to use electronic transferable records in order to generate efficiencies and economic savings to support the global economic recovery. In support of this aim we endorse the Framework for G7 Collaboration on Electronic Transferable Records.</li><li>Taking further steps to improve internet safety and counter hate speech, while protecting human rights and fundamental freedoms, including free expression. We will protect our citizens online and offline, including children and vulnerable at-risk groups, and especially women and girls. We therefore endorse our Digital Ministers’ Internet Safety Principles which aim to set out common approaches to improving online safety. We invite Interior Ministers to work on a G7 agreement on sharing of information and best practice on tackling existing and emerging online forms of gender-based violence, including forms of online abuse. We affirm our support of the Christchurch Call, emphasising the need for respecting freedoms of speech and peoples’ reasonable expectation of privacy and further invite G7 Interior Ministers to continue work on preventing and countering Violent Extremist and Terrorist Use of the Internet begun in Ischia in 2017 and continued in Toronto in 2018 and Paris in 2019. We commit to work together to further a common understanding of how existing international law applies to cyberspace and welcome the work of our Foreign Ministers to promote this approach at the UN and other international fora. We also commit to work together to urgently address the escalating shared threat from criminal ransomware networks. We call on all states to urgently identify and disrupt ransomware criminal networks operating from within their borders, and hold those networks accountable for their actions.</li><li>Securing supply chains. Recognising the foundational role that telecommunications infrastructure, including 5G and future communication technologies, plays and will play in underpinning our wider digital and ICT infrastructure we will promote secure, resilient, competitive, transparent and sustainable and diverse digital, telecoms, and ICT infrastructure supply chains.</li><li>Deepening cooperation on Digital Competition in order to drive innovation across the global economy, enhancing consumer choice. We recognise that there is increasing international consensus that participants with significant market power can exploit their power to hold back digital markets and the wider economy. Therefore, building on the 2019 French G7 Presidency’s common understanding on ‘Competition and the Digital Economy’, we will work together through existing international and multilateral fora to find a coherent way to encourage competition and support innovation in digital markets.</li></ul>



<p>35. Beyond these priorities, we will review whether other areas of collaboration with respect to future frontiers are appropriate. We are committed to the safe and sustainable use of space to support humanity’s ambition now and in the future. We recognise the importance of developing common standards, best practices and guidelines related to sustainable space operations alongside the need for a collaborative approach for space traffic management and coordination. We call on all nations to work together, through groups like the United Nations Committee on the Peaceful Uses of Outer Space, the International Organization for Standardization and the Inter-Agency Space Debris Coordination Committee, to preserve the space environment for future generations.<br><br>36. Underpinning all of these future frontiers, and wider challenges of the coming century, is the importance of scientific discovery and its deployment. We will therefore work together to promote stronger collaboration on research and development, and promote principles of research security and integrity and open science building off the historical levels of collaboration seen in the past year to internationally beneficial results. Central to this should be building a diverse and resilient science and research community, inclusive for all groups&nbsp; including women. Domestically we will seek to redress the imbalance in women’s and girls’ under-representation in science, technology, engineering and mathematics (STEM) which acts as a barrier to access to these growing industries. We will explore how existing and potential new mechanisms and initiatives can support risk reduction, prevention and response to future systemic crises, natural disasters and pace of technological change. As such we endorse the G7 Compact on Research Collaboration and its commitment to: support policies, legal frameworks and programmes to promote research collaboration; promote sharing of research data; explore enhancements to research assessment and rewards for collaboration and knowledge sharing; and develop a common set of principles which will help protect research and innovation ecosystem across the G7 to open and reciprocal research collaboration.<br><br><strong>CLIMATE AND ENVIRONMENT</strong><br><br>37. The unprecedented and interdependent crises of climate change and biodiversity loss pose an existential threat to people, prosperity, security, and nature. Through global action and concerted leadership, 2021 should be a turning point for our planet as we commit to a green transition that cuts emissions, increases adaptation action worldwide, halts and reverses biodiversity loss, and, through policy and technological transformation, creates new high quality jobs and increases prosperity and wellbeing. Ahead of the 15th Conference of the Parties of the Convention on Biological Diversity (CBD COP15), the 26th UN Climate Change Conference of the Parties (UNFCCC COP26) and the fifteenth session of the Conference of the Parties to the UN Convention to Combat Desertification (CCD COP15), we commit to accelerating efforts to cut greenhouse gas emissions and keep the 1.5°C global warming threshold within reach, strengthening adaptation and resilience to protect people from the impacts of climate change, halting and reversing biodiversity loss, mobilising finance and leveraging innovation to reach these goals. We welcome and encourage business, civil society and regional commitments to global climate and biodiversity ambition through science based targets, including the Race to Resilience and Race to Zero campaigns. Together we welcome the active role and participation of vulnerable communities, underrepresented groups and will work towards achieving equality, including gender equality, in the climate and environment sector. We will continue our efforts to progress the Equal by 30 Campaign for gender equality in the energy sector.<br><br>38. As G7 members, we all reaffirm our commitment to the Paris Agreement and to strengthening and accelerating its implementation through robust national policies and measures and scaled up international cooperation. To this end we collectively commit to ambitious and accelerated efforts to achieve net zero greenhouse gas emissions as soon as possible and by 2050 at the latest, recognising the importance of significant action this decade. In line with this goal, we have each committed to increased 2030 targets and, where not done already, commit to submit aligned Nationally Determined Contributions (NDCs) as soon as possible ahead of COP26, which will cut our collective emissions by around half compared to 2010 or over half compared to 2005. We also commit to submit 2050 Long Term Strategies (LTSs) by COP26 and to regularly update these as needed in line with the Paris agreement to reflect the latest science, technological advances and market developments. Recognising the importance of adaptation in our own national planning, we also commit to submitting adaptation communications as soon as possible, and if feasible by COP26. In fulfilling these commitments we will continue to increase our efforts to keep a limit of 1.5°C temperature rise within reach and chart a G7 pathway towards Net Zero economies. We call on all countries, in particular major emitting economies, to join us in these goals as part of a global effort, stepping up their commitments to reflect the highest possible ambition and transparency on implementation under the Paris Agreement. We also note the value of supporting international initiatives such as the OECD’s International Programme for Action on Climate Mechanism (IPAC).<br><br>39. To be credible, ambitions need to be supported by tangible actions in all sectors of our economies and societies. We will lead a technology-driven transition to Net Zero, supported by relevant policies, noting the clear roadmap provided by the International Energy Agency and prioritising the most urgent and polluting sectors and activities:</p>



<ul><li>In our <strong>energy sectors</strong>, we will increase energy efficiency, accelerate renewable and other zero emissions energy deployment, reduce wasteful consumption, leverage innovation all whilst maintaining energy security. Domestically, we commit to achieve an overwhelmingly decarbonised power system in the 2030s and to actions to accelerate this. Internationally, we commit to aligning official international financing with the global achievement of net zero GHG emissions no later than 2050 and for deep emissions reductions in the 2020s. We will phase out new direct government support for international carbon-intensive fossil fuel energy as soon as possible, with limited exceptions consistent with an ambitious climate neutrality pathway, the Paris Agreement, 1.5°C goal and best available science. To be credible, ambitions need to be supported by tangible actions in all sectors of our economies and societies. We will lead a technology-driven transition to Net Zero, noting the clear roadmap provided by the International Energy Agency and prioritising the most urgent and polluting sectors and activities.</li><li>Recognising that <strong>coal</strong> power generation is the single biggest cause of greenhouse gas emissions, and consistent with this overall approach and our strengthened NDCs, domestically we have committed to rapidly scale-up technologies and policies that further accelerate the transition away from unabated coal capacity, consistent with our 2030 NDCs and net zero commitments. This transition must go hand in hand with policies and support for a just transition for affected workers, and sectors so that no person, group or geographic region is left behind. To accelerate the international transition away from coal, recognising that continued global investment in unabated coal power generation is incompatible with keeping 1.5°C within reach we stress that international investments in unabated coal must stop now and we commit now to an end to new direct government support for unabated international thermal coal power generation by the end of 2021, including through Official Development Assistance, export finance, investment, and financial and trade promotion support. This transition must also be complemented by support to deliver this, including coordinating&nbsp; through the Energy Transition Council. We welcome the work by the Climate Investment Funds (CIFs) and donors plan to commit up to $2 billion in the coming year to its Accelerating the Coal Transition and Integrating Renewable Energy programs. These concessional resources are expected to mobilize up to $10 billion in co-financing, including from the private sector, to support renewable energy deployment in developing and emerging economies. We call on other major economies to adopt such commitments and join us in phasing out the most polluting energy sources, and scaling up investment in the technology and infrastructure to facilitate the clean, green transition. More broadly, we reaffirm our existing commitment to eliminating inefficient fossil fuel subsidies by 2025, and call on all countries to join us, recognising the substantial financial resource this could unlock globally to support the transition and the need to commit to a clear timeline.</li><li>In our <strong>transport sectors</strong>, we commit to sustainable, decarbonised mobility and to scaling up zero emission vehicle technologies, including buses, trains, shipping and aviation. We recognise that this will require dramatically increasing the pace of the global decarbonisation of the road transport sector throughout the 2020s, and beyond. This includes support for accelerating the roll out of necessary infrastructure, such as charging and fueling infrastructure and enhancing the offer of more sustainable transport modes, including public transport, shared mobility, cycling and walking. We commit to accelerate the transition away from new sales of diesel and petrol cars to promote the uptake of zero emission vehicles.</li><li>In our <strong>industrial and innovation sectors</strong> we will take action to decarbonise areas such as iron and steel, cement, chemicals, and petrochemicals, in order to reach net zero emissions across the whole economy. To this end, we will harness our collective strengths in science, technological innovation, policy design, financing, and regulation including through our launch of the G7 Industrial Decarbonisation Agenda to complement, support and amplify ambition of existing initiatives. This includes further action on public procurement, standards and industrial efforts to define and stimulate demand for green products and enhance energy and resource efficiency in industry. We will focus on accelerating progress on electrification and batteries, hydrogen, carbon capture, usage and storage, zero emission aviation and shipping, and for those countries that opt to use it, nuclear power. We therefore fully support launching Mission Innovation phase two and the Clean Energy Ministerial third phase.</li><li>In our <strong>homes and buildings, </strong>and also industry, we recognise the need for an urgent step change in the deployment of renewable heating and cooling and reduction in energy demand. This complements required shifts in building design, sustainable materials and retrofits. We therefore welcome the Super-Efficient Equipment and Appliance Deployment (SEAD) initiative’s goal of doubling the efficiency of lighting, cooling, refrigeration and motor systems sold globally by 2030.</li><li>In our <strong>agricultural, forestry and other land use sectors</strong>, we commit to ensuring our policies encourage sustainable production, the protection, conservation, and regeneration of ecosystems, and the sequestration of carbon. We welcome the opportunity to discuss these issues at the COP26 Transition to Sustainable Agriculture Policy Dialogue and UN Food Systems Summit in September.</li></ul>



<p>40. Achieving our collective ambitions of a global green and resilient recovery offers the greatest economic opportunity of our time to boost income, innovation, jobs, productivity and growth while also accelerating action to tackle the existential threat of climate change and environmental degradation. To close the gap between the funds needed and actual finance flows requires mobilising and aligning finance and investment at scale towards the technologies, infrastructure, ecosystems, businesses, jobs and economies that will underpin a net-zero emissions resilient future that leaves no one behind. This includes the deployment and alignment of all sources of finance: public and private, national and multilateral. We recognise the particular challenges of financing the transition to net zero economies poses for developing countries and stand by our bilateral and multilateral commitments to support these partners, in the context of meaningful and transparent decarbonisation efforts. We reaffirm the collective developed country goal to jointly mobilise $100 billion per year from public and private sources, through to 2025 in the context of meaningful mitigation actions and transparency on implementation. Towards this end, we commit to each increase and improve our overall international public climate finance contributions for this period and call on other developed countries to join and enhance their contributions to this effort. We welcome the commitments already made by some of the G7 to increase climate finance and look forward to new commitments from others well ahead of COP26 in Glasgow. This increase in quantity and predictability is complemented by improved effectiveness and accessibility, and includes more finance contributing to adaptation and resilience, disaster risk and insurance, as well as support for nature and nature-based solutions. We are committed to further enhance synergies between finance for climate and biodiversity and to promote funding that has co-benefits for climate and nature and are working intensively towards increasing the quantity of finance to nature and nature-based solutions. We welcome efforts of the MDBs to scale up their climate and nature finance, urge them to mobilise increased finance including from the private sector, and call on them, Development Finance Institutions (DFIs), multilateral funds, public banks and relevant agencies to publish before COP26 a high-level plan and date by which all their operations will be fully aligned with and support the objectives of the Paris Agreement and the multilateral environmental agreements we support.<br><br>41. We also support the transformation underway to mobilise further private capital towards these objectives in particular to support developing countries and emerging markets in making the most of the opportunities in the transition; whilst mitigating and adapting to climate change. We call upon the MDBs and our DFIs to prioritise capital mobilization strategies, initiatives and incentives within their operations. The G7 commits to leverage different types of blended finance vehicles including through our greater strategic approach to development finance, greater collaboration between our DFIs and billions worth of planned commitments towards CIF and Green Climate Fund, all of which will mobilise billions more in private finance. We also encourage further development of disaster risk finance markets. Towards this, G7 members have committed hundreds of millions worth of new financing for early action, disaster risk and insurance in line with the InsuResilience Global Partnership and Risk-Informed Early Action Partnership (REAP). We commit to establishing the necessary market infrastructure for private finance to support and incentivise the net zero transition. Developing the global green finance market will help mobilise private sector finance, and reinforce government policy to meet our net zero commitments. We support the recently launched Glasgow Finance Alliance for Net Zero, and call on swift, robust delivery of their commitments to reduce real economy emissions. We emphasise the need to green the global financial system so that financial decisions take climate considerations into account. We support moving towards mandatory climate-related financial disclosures that provide consistent and decision-useful information for market participants and that are based on the Task Force on Climate-related Financial Disclosures (TCFD) framework, in line with domestic regulatory frameworks. We also look forward to the establishment of the Taskforce on Nature-related Financial Disclosures and its recommendations. These initiatives will help mobilise the trillions of dollars of private sector finance needed, and reinforce government policy to meet our net zero commitments. We recognise the potential of high integrity carbon markets and carbon pricing to foster cost-efficient reductions in emission levels, drive innovation and enable a transformation to net zero, through the optimal use of a range of policy levers to price carbon. We underline their importance towards the establishment of a fair and efficient carbon pricing trajectory to accelerate the decarbonisation of our economies, to achieve a net zero global emissions pathway. In all this, we will develop gender-responsive approaches to climate and nature financing, investment and policies, so that women and girls can participate fully in the future green economy.<br><br>42. Biodiversity loss is an intrinsically linked, mutually reinforcing, and equally important existential threat to our planet and our people alongside climate change. In this context, we acknowledge as the G7 our contribution to the decline of biodiversity and pledge to play our part in its restoration and conservation. We support an ambitious post-2020 global biodiversity framework to be adopted by parties at CBD COP15 which sets ambitious goals, strengthens implementation, and enhances regular reporting and review. We acknowledge our responsibility to support the world in reversing the trajectory of the loss of biodiversity and the natural environments that support it, alongside ensuring that the impact on nature is fully taken into account in our policy decision making.<br><br>43. In support of strong outcomes for nature at the Convention on Biological Diversity COP-15 in Kunming and COP26 this year, and noting the Leaders’ Pledge for Nature launched at the 75th session of the UN General Assembly 2020, we adopt the G7 2030 Nature Compact in support of the global mission to halt and reverse biodiversity loss by 2030. The Nature Compact commits us to take action across four key pillars:</p>



<ul><li>First, we commit to champion ambitious and effective global biodiversity targets, including conserving&nbsp; or protecting at least 30 per cent of global land and at least 30 per cent of the global ocean by 2030. We will contribute by conserving or protecting&nbsp; at least 30 per cent of our own land, including terrestrial and inland waters, and coastal and marine areas by 2030 according to national circumstances and approaches. These actions will help stem the extinction crisis, safeguard water and food supplies, absorb carbon pollution, and reduce the risks of future pandemics. We also fully support the commitment of the Commission for the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living Resources (CCAMLR) to develop a representative system of Marine Protected Areas (MPAs) in the Convention area in the Southern Ocean based on the best available scientific evidence.</li><li>Second, we will support the transition to sustainable management and use of natural resources, and use appropriate levers to address unsustainable and illegal activities negatively impacting nature, and therefore livelihoods. This includes stepping up action to tackle increasing levels of plastic pollution in the ocean, including working through the UN Environment Assembly (UNEA) on options including strengthening existing instruments and a potential new agreement or other instrument to address marine plastic litter, including at UNEA-5.2.</li><li>Third, we will work intensively towards increasing investment in the protection, conservation and restoration of nature, including committing to increase finance for nature based solutions through to 2025, maximising synergies of climate and biodiversity finance, and ensuring prominence of nature in both policy and economic decision-making.</li><li>Finally, we will prioritise strengthened accountability and implementation mechanisms of Multilateral Environmental Agreements to which we are parties. We will implement the Compact and review our progress against it regularly through existing G7 mechanisms, including at the G7 Leaders’ Summit in five years when we will review options to&nbsp; ratchet up our action and ambition, as needed, to ensure delivery of our 2030 vision. Those G7 members party to the CBD will also champion successful implementation of the post-2020 global biodiversity framework to be agreed at COP15.</li></ul>



<p><strong>GENDER EQUALITY</strong><br><br>44. Gender equality is at the heart of an open, inclusive, and just society. Persistent gaps in gender equality affect access to basic services as well as decent work, equal pay, social protection, education, technology and many other areas. Unequal division of unpaid care responsibilities in the home and low pay for paid care work also limits women’s empowerment, social and economic participation and leadership. Gender equality intersects with other characteristics and our actions need to take account of these intersections in a meaningful way, including tackling racism in all forms and violence and discrimination against LGBQTI+ populations. We recognise the devastating and disproportionate impact of COVID-19 on women and girls, which risks reversing hard-won gains especially with regards to gender-based violence, sexual and reproductive health and rights, education and jobs.<br><br>45. The advancement of gender equity and equality are a central pillar of our plans and policies to build back better, informed by three key priorities: educating girls, empowering women and ending violence against women and girls. Achieving gender equality needs to be underpinned by the full, equal and meaningful participation of women in all aspects of&nbsp; decision-making. We are committed to close alignment with the Generation Equality Forum (GEF) and commend the organisation of the first G20 Ministerial Conference on women’s empowerment. We thank the Gender Equality Advisory Council (GEAC) for its work and recommendations, and look forward to receiving the GEAC’s full report in the Autumn. We agree to a consistent and sustained focus on gender equality to project our global leadership on this issue, and intend to convene the GEAC as a standing feature of all G7 Presidencies. We know that we cannot make true progress towards gender equality without robust data and a way to track it over time. We invite the GEAC to work with existing accountability mechanisms such as the Accountability Working Group and the Taormina Roadmap to monitor G7 commitments to achieve gender equality on an annual basis.<br><br>46. We reaffirm our full commitment to promote and protect the sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) of all individuals, and recognise the essential and transformative role they play in gender equality and women’s and girls’ empowerment, and in supporting diversity, including of sexual orientations and gender identities. We commit to working together to prevent and address the negative impacts on access to SRHR from the COVID-19 pandemic, with specific attention to the most at risk, marginalised and inadequately served groups. In recognition of increased violence against women and girls during the COVID-19 crisis, we commit to preventing, responding to and eliminating all forms of sexual and gender-based violence (GBV). We will achieve this through women’s empowerment and by scaling-up implementation of evidence-based, accessible survivor and victim-centred policies, prevention and support programmes, including through our pandemic response and recovery at home, in partner countries and in conflict zones. We acknowledge our collective responsibility to beneficiaries and partners, their communities, and survivors to do more to address sexual exploitation and abuse in international aid. We condemn GBV against women and girls and denounce the use of sexual violence in conflict situations and underscore that such acts may constitute crimes against humanity or war crimes. We note the varied legal and institutional frameworks which currently address conflict and invite Foreign and Development Ministers to consider how best to strengthen international architecture around conflict-related sexual violence.<br><br>47. COVID-19 has exacerbated underlying inequalities, leading to one of the worst education crises in history for children around the world, but especially for the most marginalised and at risk girls. Around 11 million girls from pre-primary to secondary school are at risk of not returning to school. We commit to two new global SDG4 milestone girls’ education targets: 40 million more girls in education by 2026 in low and lower-middle income countries; and 20 million more girls reading by age 10 or the end of primary school by 2026, in low and lower-middle income countries. We endorse the G7 Foreign and Development Ministers’ Girls Education Declaration. These targets should be underpinned by sustainable financing and so today G7 members commit to a combined total pledge of at least $2¾ billion funding over the next 5 years for the Global Partnership for Education (GPE) ahead of its replenishment in July. We call on others to join with the G7 and make ambitious pledges to a fully funded GPE.<br><br><strong>GLOBAL RESPONSIBILITY AND INTERNATIONAL ACTION</strong><br><br>48. We will work together to promote our shared values as open societies in the international system, as reflected in the Statement on Open Societies signed with the Leaders of countries from the Indo-Pacific region and Africa, who have joined us at Carbis Bay, namely, Australia, India, South Africa and the Republic of Korea. Further to this, we commit to: increase cooperation on supporting democracy, including through strengthening the G7 Rapid Response Mechanism to counter foreign threats to democracy including disinformation; strengthen media freedom and ensure the protection of journalists; support freedom of religion or belief; condemn racism in all its forms; address human rights abuses, including the failure to protect civilians in conflict; oppose the practice of arbitrary detention, including by amplifying the Declaration Against Arbitrary Detention in State-to-State Relations and welcoming its Partnership Action Plan; and recognise the need for action on corruption, including by sharing information on illicit financial activities, tackling the misuse of shell companies, and curtailing the ability of illicit actors to hide wealth, including in real estate. We support the growth of peaceful, just and inclusive societies by ensuring safe and vibrant civic spaces. For our own part, our discussions have benefited from input from the perspectives and expertise of external engagement groups representing all sectors of society, including the Business 7, Civil Society 7, Labour 7, Science 7, Women 7 and Youth 7. We thank them for their consideration and recommendations across the breadth of our policy priorities.<br><br>49. We recognise the particular responsibility of the largest countries and economies in upholding the rules-based international system and international law. We commit to play our role in this, working with all partners and as members of the G20, UN and wider international community, and encourage others to do the same. We will do this based on our shared agenda and democratic values. With regard to China, and competition in the global economy, we will continue to consult on collective approaches to challenging non-market policies and practices which undermine the fair and transparent operation of the global economy. In the context of our respective responsibilities in the multilateral system, we will cooperate where it is in our mutual interest on shared global challenges, in particular addressing climate change and biodiversity loss in the context of COP26 and other multilateral discussions. At the same time and in so doing, we will promote our values, including by calling on China to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms, especially in relation to Xinjiang and those rights, freedoms and high degree of autonomy for Hong Kong enshrined in the Sino-British Joint Declaration and the Basic Law.<br><br>50. We endorse the statement made by our Foreign and Development Ministers in May. Building on this, in particular to reflect recent developments, we have reviewed the following live issues.<br><br>51. We reiterate our interest in stable and predictable relations with Russia, and will continue to engage where there are areas of mutual interest. We reaffirm our call on Russia to stop its destabilising behaviour and malign activities, including its interference in other countries’ democratic systems, and to fulfil its international human rights obligations and commitments. In particular, we call on Russia to urgently investigate and credibly explain the use of a chemical weapon on its soil, to end its systematic crackdown on independent civil society and media, and to identify, disrupt, and hold to account those within its borders who conduct ransomware attacks, abuse virtual currency to launder ransoms, and other cybercrimes.<br><br>52. We reiterate our support for the independence, sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognised borders. We call on Russia to alleviate tensions and act in accordance with its international obligations, and to withdraw the Russian military troops and materiel at the eastern border of Ukraine and on the Crimean peninsula. We remain firmly of the view that Russia is a party to the conflict in Eastern Ukraine, not a mediator. We affirm our support for the Normandy Process to secure the implementation of the Minsk agreements, and call on Russia and the armed formations it backs to engage constructively and recommit to the ceasefire. We reaffirm our efforts to strengthen Ukraine’s democracy and institutions, encouraging further progress on reform.<br><br>53. We are deeply concerned by the Belarusian authorities&#8217; continuing attacks on human rights, fundamental freedoms and international law, as exemplified by the forced landing of flight FR4978 and the arrest of an independent journalist and his partner. We will work together to hold those responsible to account, including through imposing sanctions, and to continue to support civil society, independent media and human rights in Belarus. We call on the regime to: change course and implement all the recommendations of the independent expert mission under the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe’s (OSCE) Moscow Mechanism; enter into meaningful dialogue with all sectors of society; and hold new free and fair elections.<br><br>54. We are deeply concerned by the ongoing conflict in Ethiopia’s Tigray region and reports of an unfolding major humanitarian tragedy, including potentially hundreds of thousands in famine conditions. We condemn ongoing atrocities, including widespread sexual violence, and we welcome the ongoing Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights (OHCHR) investigations and call for full accountability for reported human rights violations in Tigray and for the perpetrators to be brought to justice. We call for an immediate cessation of hostilities, unimpeded humanitarian access to all areas and the immediate withdrawal of Eritrean forces. We urge all parties to pursue a credible political process, which is the only solution to the crisis. We further call upon Ethiopia’s leaders to advance a broader inclusive political process to foster national reconciliation and consensus toward a future based on respect for the human and political rights of all Ethiopians.<br><br>55. While acknowledging the increased international mobilisation and the progress in the fight against terrorism in the Sahel, we express our concern about the continuing attacks targeting civilian populations, and the deepening humanitarian crisis. We urge all actors to respect human rights and international humanitarian law. We will deliver on our commitments to renew efforts to address drivers of instability, with a focus on political and civilian dimensions of the “civil surge” agreed upon by the governments of the G5 Sahel and their partners, gathered in the Sahel coalition, at the N’Djamena summit in February 2021. We support the efforts of the African Union and Economic Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) in response to recent events in Chad and Mali. We reiterate the necessity to create the conditions for timely civilian-led transitions to democratic, constitutional rule in both countries.<br><br>56. We confirm our full support for the interim executive authority as it pursues Libyan-led and Libyan-owned stabilisation, facilitated by the UN in the framework of the Berlin Process. We reaffirm the importance of free, fair and inclusive elections to be held on 24 December. We reiterate the urgent need to&nbsp; implement in full the 23 October ceasefire agreement, including through the withdrawal of all foreign fighters and mercenaries from Libya.&nbsp; All states must comply with UN Security Council Resolutions 2570 and 2571.<br><br>57. We call on all Afghan parties to reduce violence and agree on steps that enable the successful implementation of a permanent and comprehensive ceasefire and to engage fully with the peace process. In Afghanistan, a sustainable, inclusive political settlement is the only way to achieve a just and durable peace that benefits all Afghans. We are determined to maintain our support for the Afghan government to address the country&#8217;s urgent security and humanitarian needs, and to help the people of Afghanistan, including women, young people and minority groups, as they seek to preserve hard-won rights and freedoms.<br><br>58. We call for the complete denuclearisation of the Korean peninsula and the verifiable and irreversible abandonment of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s (DPRK) unlawful weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programmes in accordance with all relevant UN Security Council resolutions. We call on all states to fully implement these resolutions and their associated sanctions. We welcome the readiness of the United States to continue its diplomatic efforts in coordination with all relevant partners and call on the DPRK to engage and resume dialogue. We once again call on DPRK to respect human rights for all and to resolve the issue of abductions immediately.<br><br>59. We condemn in the strongest terms the military coup in Myanmar, and the violence committed by Myanmar’s security forces, and we call for the immediate release of those detained arbitrarily. We pledge our support to those advocating peacefully for a stable and inclusive democracy. Recalling ASEAN&#8217;s central role, we welcome its Five Point Consensus and urge swift implementation. We reiterate our commitment to ensuring that neither development assistance nor the sale of arms will benefit the military, and urge businesses to exercise due diligence in their trade and investment in the same vein. We reaffirm G7 unity on pursuing additional measures should they prove necessary. We are also deeply concerned by the humanitarian situation, call for unfettered humanitarian access to vulnerable and displaced populations, support the Humanitarian Response Plan, and encourage others to contribute.<br><br>60. We reiterate the importance of maintaining a free and open Indo Pacific, which is inclusive and based on the rule of law. We underscore the importance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait, and encourage the peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues. We remain seriously concerned about the situation in the East and South China Seas and strongly oppose any unilateral attempts to change the status quo and increase tensions.<br><br>61. We are committed to ensuring that Iran will never develop a nuclear weapon. We welcome the substantive discussions between Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPoA) participants, and separately with the United States, to accomplish a return of the United States and Iran to their JCPoA commitments. We support the goal of restoring the nonproliferation benefits of the JCPoA and of ensuring the exclusively peaceful nature of Iran’s nuclear programme. We urge Iran to stop and reverse all measures that reduce transparency and to ensure full and timely cooperation with the International Atomic Energy Agency. A restored and fully-implemented JCPoA could also pave the way to further address regional and security concerns. We condemn Iran’s support to proxy forces and non-state armed actors, including through financing, training and the proliferation of missile technology and weapons. We call on Iran to stop all ballistic missile activities and proliferation inconsistent with UNSCR 2231 and other relevant resolutions, refrain from destabilising actions and play a constructive role in fostering regional stability and peace. We support efforts to pursue transparency, accountability and justice for the victims of Ukraine International Airlines Flight 752, shot down by Iran in January 2020. We reiterate our deep concern over the continued human rights violations and abuses in Iran.<br><br>62. We commend the Iraqi Security Forces, including the Kurdish Peshmerga, and Government of Iraq in their success against ISIS and affirm continuing support for those efforts, including stabilisation in liberated areas. We also affirm our support for Iraq’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity. We fully endorse UNSCR 2576 and its call for election monitors to help ensure free and fair elections in October, and encourage all Iraqis to participate in those elections. Finally, we welcome the efforts of the Government of Iraq to hold illegal armed groups accountable for attacks against Iraqi citizens and Coalition personnel who are in Iraq at its invitation solely to train and advise Iraqi forces in their fight against ISIS.<br><br>63. We acknowledge the far-reaching impacts of COVID-19 on the poorest countries who already were grappling with the effects of conflict, climate change, socio-economic shocks and a chronic lack of resources and infrastructure. As we advance recovery plans to support our economies and build back better, in line with the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, including through innovative measures and massive budgetary support, developing partner countries, especially in Africa, cannot be left behind. We are deeply concerned that the pandemic has set back progress towards the Sustainable Development Goals and continues to exacerbate global inequalities, and therefore recommit to enhance our efforts to achieve the SDGs by 2030, including by supporting the Addis Ababa Action Agenda (AAAA) and aligning financial flows with the SDGs. We take note of the policy options developed through the Financing for Development in the Era of COVID-19 and Beyond Initiative.<br><br>64. The IMF estimates that, between now and 2025, low income countries will need around $200 billion to respond to the pandemic and $250 billion in investment spending for convergence with advanced economies. We reiterate our commitment to implement the G20 and Paris Club Common Framework for Debt Treatments beyond the Debt Service Suspension Initiative. We support fair and open lending practices, and call on all creditors to adhere to these. We underline the importance of information sharing, and reiterate the need for comparability of treatment for private and other official bilateral creditors in debt treatments. We urge the MDBs to explore all options to unlock additional financing for developing countries, including more efficient and effective use of their resources, further work on balance sheet optimisation and further analysis of their capital adequacy frameworks.<br><br>65. We welcome the agreement by G7 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors to support a new $650 billion allocation of IMF Special Drawing Rights, urging implementation by the end of August 2021 accompanied by transparency and accountability measures. We encourage the IMF to work quickly with all relevant stakeholders to explore a menu of options for channelling SDRs to further support health needs, including vaccinations, and to help enable greener, more robust recoveries in the most affected countries, supporting the poorest and most vulnerable countries in tackling these urgent challenges. G7 countries are actively considering options that we can take as part of a global effort to magnify the impact of this general allocation for countries most in need, especially in Africa, including through voluntarily channelling SDRs and/or budget loans, in line with national circumstances and legal requirements. This includes scaling up financing to the IMF&#8217;s Poverty Reduction and Growth Trust and the IMF’s review of concessional financing and policies to strengthen its capacity to support low income countries. To support our aim to reach a total global ambition of $100 billion, we call for contributions from other countries able to do so, alongside the G7. We task G7 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors to urgently consider the detail of this, including by working with the G20 and other stakeholders.<br><br>66. We note with grave concern that the world faces an unprecedented humanitarian crisis as the UN reports that over 34 million people are already facing emergency levels of food insecurity and are one step from catastrophe or famine. In this light, we endorse the G7 Famine Prevention and Humanitarian Crises Compact committed to by G7 Foreign and Development Ministers. We reaffirm our commitment to provide $7 billion in humanitarian assistance, take diplomatic action to promote humanitarian access and the protection of civilians, including women and girls, and strengthen anticipatory and early action in partnership with the UN and World Bank Group. We call attention to the rise in poverty, hunger and malnutrition globally, noting the exacerbating role of the COVID-19 pandemic, climate change, economic shocks, biodiversity loss and increased conflict, and agree further action is needed to reverse these trends and strengthen global food systems. We reaffirm our commitment to the Broad Food Security and Nutrition Development Approach made at Elmau in 2015, and note that responsible investments in food security, food systems, and nutrition are essential to support SDG2 and World Health Assembly nutrition targets. We further encourage strong commitments in these areas to be announced at the G20, the UN Food Systems Summit, COP26 and the Tokyo Nutrition for Growth Summit later this year.<br><br>67. We recognise the significant infrastructure needs across low and middle income countries, which have been exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic. Reflecting our shared values and shared vision, we will aim for a step change in our approach to infrastructure financing, notably on quality infrastructure and investment, to strengthen partnerships with developing countries and help meet their infrastructure needs. Working together and with others, and by building on and going beyond our existing action, we will develop a partnership to build back better for the world with the aim of maximising impact on the ground to meet the needs of our partners, and to ensure our collective effort is greater than the sum of its parts. This partnership will orient development finance tools toward the range of challenges faced by developing countries, including in resilient infrastructure and technologies to address the impacts of climate change; health systems and security; developing digital solutions; and advancing gender equality and education. A particular priority will be an initiative for clean and green growth to drive a sustainable and green transition in line with the Paris Agreement and Agenda 2030.&nbsp; Underpinning our approach will be the following key principles:</p>



<ul><li>values-driven vision: we believe that infrastructure development, implementation and maintenance &#8211; carried out in a transparent and financially, environmentally, and socially sustainable manner &#8211; will lead to beneficial outcomes for recipient countries and communities.</li><li>intensive collaboration: we will each pursue the necessary actions through our own DFIs, and other relevant bodies, while strengthening collaboration to determine how we can increase the scale and scope of our collective offer to developing partner countries.</li><li>market-led: we believe current funding and financing approaches are not adequate to address the infrastructure financing gap and are committed to enhancing the development finance tools at our disposal, including by mobilising private sector capital and expertise, through a strengthened and more integrated approach across the public and private sector, to reduce risk, strengthen local capacities, and support and catalyse a significant increase in responsible and market-based private capital in sectors with anticipated returns, and to strengthen local capacities, in a sustainable manner, in line with the Addis Ababa Action Agenda on Financing for Development.</li><li>strong standards: to ensure our approach and values are upheld, and to drive a race to the top, we will make high standards &#8211; across environmental, social, financial, labour, governance and transparency &#8211; a central plank of our approach, including by building on multilateral agreed standards on quality infrastructure such as the G20 Principles for Quality Infrastructure Investment. This will help to provide citizens of recipient communities with the long-run benefits they expect and deserve. We emphasise the importance of transparent, open, economically efficient, fair and competitive standards for lending and procurement, also in line with debt sustainability, and the adherence of international rules and standards for major creditor countries.</li><li>enhanced multilateral finance: we recognise that many MDBs and other International Financial Institutions (IFIs) have evolved to embody the highest standards for project planning, implementation, social and environmental safeguards, and analytical capability. We will work with the IFIs to enhance their catalytic impact and increase the mobilisation of capital needed for impactful and sustainable infrastructure investment, and ensure that the pace of project development and disbursement meets the needs of partner countries.</li><li>strategic partnerships: we will ground this initiative in strategic and substantial partnerships between countries, to support innovation and technological development, focused on the most pressing needs.</li></ul>



<p>We will work together to take forward an agenda based on these principles and work closely with others, including developing country partners, to ensure that it is developed in an open and collaborative way. We will establish a taskforce to develop practical proposals and report back to us in the Autumn.<br><br>68. A central focus of our new strategic approach will be supporting sustainable growth in Africa. Building on the conclusions of the Summit on Financing African Economies that was held in Paris on 18 May 2021 and on the needs expressed by our African partners, we are resolved to deepen our current partnership to a new deal with the African continent, with African states, institutions and expertise at its core. In line with these ambitions, our DFIs and multilateral partners intend to invest at least $80 billion into the private sector in Africa over the next five years to support sustainable economic recovery and growth in line with the AAAA. This builds on the 2X Challenge partnership between G7 DFIs launched in 2018 and the target of an additional $15 billion of new funding for this as announced by G7 Foreign and Development Ministers in May 2021 to help address the disproportionate barriers that women face to access capital, leadership roles, quality employment and affordable care. We welcome the Alliance for entrepreneurship in Africa that was launched on May 18 and look forward to its first meeting by the end of the year, under the auspices of the International Financing Corporation and in full partnership with all public and private partners willing to invest more in Africa’s future and to leverage its growth opportunities. We ask the MDBs and especially the World Bank to mobilise more private financing into Africa by developing and reinforcing the relevant risk sharing instruments for the benefit of African small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs). We reiterate our support to the G20 Compact with Africa as a key framework to enhance the business environment in Africa and call on reform orientated partners to join and strengthen this initiative. We invite G7 Foreign and Development ministers to continue to work with developing country partners and DFIs at the second Foreign and Development Ministers meeting.<br><br>69. As open societies we are committed to accountability and transparency, and to upholding the promises we have made. In this spirit, we endorse the 2021 Carbis Bay Progress Report from the G7 Accountability Working Group, reporting on G7 commitments to strengthen health systems to advance universal health coverage and global health. We look forward to the next Comprehensive Progress Report from the G7 Accountability working group in 2022.<br><br><strong>CONCLUSION</strong><br><br>70. In Cornwall we have revitalised our G7 partnership. Our Shared Agenda for Global Action is a statement of our shared vision and ambition as we continue to collaborate this year and under future Presidencies. As we do so we look forward to joining with others to ensure we build back better, in particular at the G20 Summit, COP26, and CBD15 and the UN General Assembly, and reiterate our support for the holding of the Olympic and Paralympic Games Tokyo 2020 in a safe and secure manner as a symbol of global unity in overcoming COVID-19.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: G7 to Announce Joint Actions on Forced Labor in Global Supply Chains, Anticorruption, and Ransomware</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/fact-sheet-g7-to-announce-joint-actions-on-forced-labor-in-global-supply-chains-anticorruption-and-ransomware/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 12:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is rallying the world’s democracies to deliver for our people, meet the world’s biggest challenges, and demonstrate our shared values Today President Biden and leaders from G7 will demonstrate that we are unified by our shared values and a collective resolve among major democracies to meet today’s challenges.  President Biden and leaders&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The United States is rallying the world’s democracies to deliver for our people, meet the world’s biggest challenges, and demonstrate our shared values</em></p>



<p>Today President Biden and leaders from G7 will demonstrate that we are unified by our shared values and a collective resolve among major democracies to meet today’s challenges.  President Biden and leaders agreed to a set of concrete actions around key priorities responding to forced labor in global supply chains, the ransomware threat, and fighting corruption.  <br><br><strong><strong>United States and G7 Commit to Removing Forced Labor from Global Supply Chains</strong>: </strong>The United States and our G7 partners remain deeply concerned by the use of all forms of forced labor in global supply chains, including state-sponsored forced labor of vulnerable groups and minorities and supply chains of the agricultural, solar, and garment sectors—the main supply chains of concern in Xinjiang.  Leaders agreed on the importance of upholding human rights and of international labor standards, and committed to protect individuals from forced labor.  We welcome the commitment of our G7 partners to ensure all global supply chains are free from the use of forced labor.  We look forward to identifying areas for strengthened cooperation and collective efforts to eradicate the use of all forms of forced labor in global supply chains, in accordance with international and national law.<br><br><strong>Commitment to Fight Ransomware: </strong>Ransomware is a longstanding global challenge, and the threat continues to escalate in both scale and sophistication. In just the last few weeks there have been several significant cyber intrusions affecting many G7 and other nations’ critical infrastructure, manufacturing and electronics firms, and hospitals. These transnational criminal enterprises leverage infrastructure, virtual currency, and money laundering networks, and target victims all over the globe, often operating from geographic locations that offer a permissive environment for carrying out such malicious cyber activities. The international community—both governments and private sector actors—must work together to ensure that critical infrastructure is resilient against this threat, that malicious cyber activity is investigated and prosecuted, that we bolster our collective cyber defenses, and that States address the criminal activity taking place within their borders. The United States and our G7 partners are committed to working together to urgently address the escalating shared threat from criminal ransomware networks.</p>



<p><strong>Taking Collective Action to Combat Corruption: </strong>On June 3, 2021 President Biden declared efforts to curb corruption a core U.S. national interest, and issued a National Security Study Memorandum on the Fight Against Corruption to elevate this vital work. Corruption corrodes public trust; makes government less effective; wastes public resources; and eats away at the foundations of democratic societies. Corruption exerts a massive cost on economies and is fundamentally unfair to citizens. As a group of the world’s leading economies, G7 members must do more to make sure that proceeds of corruption do not end up in untraceable accounts, obscured by shell companies or in real estate.<br><br>Together with our G7 partners, the United States is resolved to taking meaningful actions to effectively combat corruption, such as tackling the misuse of shell companies, limiting the ability of bad actors to launder dirty money in real estate purchases, improving corruption-related information sharing, and reforming foreign assistance to focus on anticorruption as a cross-cutting priority. We welcome the G7 commitment to take collective action in combatting corruption.<br><br>More detail will be included in the G7 Leaders’ Communique.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-cyril-ramaphosa-of-south-africa-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 11:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. yesterday met with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa on the margins of the G7 Summit. They discussed the U.S.-South Africa bilateral relationship and underscored the need to expand global COVID-19 vaccine supply and to cooperate on climate goals in Africa and on other bilateral and regional issues. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. yesterday met with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa on the margins of the G7 Summit. They discussed the U.S.-South Africa bilateral relationship and underscored the need to expand global COVID-19 vaccine supply and to cooperate on climate goals in Africa and on other bilateral and regional issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-cyril-ramaphosa-of-south-africa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 06:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. yesterday met with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa on the margins of the G7 Summit. They discussed the U.S.-South Africa bilateral relationship and underscored the need to expand global COVID-19 vaccine supply and to cooperate on climate goals in Africa and on other bilateral and regional issues. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. yesterday met with President Cyril Ramaphosa of South Africa on the margins of the G7 Summit. They discussed the U.S.-South Africa bilateral relationship and underscored the need to expand global COVID-19 vaccine supply and to cooperate on climate goals in Africa and on other bilateral and regional issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Suga Yoshihide of Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-suga-yoshihide-suga-of-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 23:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Suga Yoshihide of Japan at the G7 to discuss shared challenges in the Indo-Pacific and the world, including COVID-19, climate change, North Korea, China, and preserving peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait. President Biden affirmed his support for strengthening our alliance, extending U.S.-Japan cooperation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Suga Yoshihide of Japan at the G7 to discuss shared challenges in the Indo-Pacific and the world, including COVID-19, climate change, North Korea, China, and preserving peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait. President Biden affirmed his support for strengthening our alliance, extending U.S.-Japan cooperation to new areas like the Build Back Better World (B3W) initiative and strengthening our shared ties with other allies and partners. President Biden affirmed his support for the Tokyo Olympic Games moving forward with all public health measures necessary to protect athletes, staff and spectators. President Biden expressed pride in the U.S. athletes who have trained for the Tokyo Games and will be competing in the best traditions of the Olympic spirit.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout: Trilateral Meeting of Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom, President Joe Biden, and Prime Minister Scott Morrison of Australia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-trilateral-meeting-of-prime-minister-boris-johnson-of-the-united-kingdom-president-joe-biden-and-prime-minister-scott-morrison-of-australia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 21:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prime Minster Johnson, President Biden and Prime Minister Morrison met in the margins of the G7 summit in Carbis Bay on 12 June 2021. They discussed a number of issues of mutual concern, including the Indo-Pacific region. They agreed that the strategic context in the Indo-Pacific was changing and that there was a strong rationale&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Prime Minster Johnson, President Biden and Prime Minister Morrison met in the margins of the G7 summit in Carbis Bay on 12 June 2021. They discussed a number of issues of mutual concern, including the Indo-Pacific region. They agreed that the strategic context in the Indo-Pacific was changing and that there was a strong rationale for deepening strategic cooperation between the three governments. They welcomed the forthcoming visits and exercises in the Indo-Pacific by the Carrier Strike Group, led by HMS Queen Elizabeth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-mario-draghi-of-italy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 20:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Draghi of Italy on the margins of the G7 Summit.  President Biden pledged to further deepen our strong bilateral ties, highlighting this year’s 160th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the United States and Italy.  The President and the Prime Minister pledged to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Draghi of Italy on the margins of the G7 Summit.  President Biden pledged to further deepen our strong bilateral ties, highlighting this year’s 160th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the United States and Italy.  The President and the Prime Minister pledged to continue their close cooperation to overcome the pandemic, including through the G7 commitment to donate COVID-19 vaccines globally, and to build back better global health security for the future. He expressed appreciation for Italy’s continued support for Afghan peace and security.   President Biden welcomed Italy’s leadership of the G20 this year and commended its focus on people, planet and prosperity.   The two leaders agreed to work together on global challenges and shared foreign policy priorities, including China, Russia, and Libya.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
