<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 16:20:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in State of the Union&#160;Address</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/02/remarks-by-president-biden-in-state-of-the-union-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 16:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. CapitolWashington, D.C. (March 1, 2022) 9:08 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Madam Speaker, Madam Vice President, and our First Lady and Second Gentleman, members of Congress and the Cabinet, Justices of the Supreme Court, my fellow Americans: Last year, COVID-19 kept us apart.&#160; This year, we’re finally together again.&#160; Tonight &#8212; (applause) &#8212; tonight we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">U.S. Capitol<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(March 1, 2022)</p>



<p>9:08 P.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Madam Speaker, Madam Vice President, and our First Lady and Second Gentleman, members of Congress and the Cabinet, Justices of the Supreme Court, my fellow Americans: Last year, COVID-19 kept us apart.&nbsp; This year, we’re finally together again.&nbsp;<br><br>Tonight &#8212; (applause) &#8212; tonight we meet as Democrats, Republicans, and independents, but, most importantly, as Americans with a duty to one another, to America, to the American people, and to the Constitution, and an unwavering resolve that freedom will always triumph over tyranny.<br><br>Six &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; Six days ago, Russia’s Vladimir Putin sought to shake the very foundations of the free world, thinking he could make it bend to his menacing ways.&nbsp; But he badly miscalculated.&nbsp; He thought he could roll into Ukraine and the world would roll over.&nbsp; Instead, he met with a mal- &#8212; a wall of strength he never anticipated or imagined.&nbsp; He met the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>From President Zelenskyy to every Ukrainian, their fearlessness, their courage, their determination literally inspires the world.&nbsp; Groups of citizens blocking tanks with their bodies.&nbsp; Everyone from students to retirees, to teachers turned soldiers defending their homeland.<br><br>And in this struggle &#8212; President Zelenskyy said in his speech to the European Parliament, “Light will win over darkness.”<br><br>The Ukrainian Ambassador to the United States is here tonight sitting with the First Lady.&nbsp; Let each of us, if you’re able to stand, stand and send an unmistakable signal to the world and Ukraine.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>She’s bright, she’s strong, and she’s resolved.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Yes.&nbsp; We, the United States of America, stand with the Ukrainian people.<br><br>Throughout our history, we’ve learned this lesson: When dictators do not pay a price for their aggression, they cause more chaos; they keep moving; and the costs, the threats to the America &#8212; and America, to the world keeps rising.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why the NATO Alliance was created: to secure peace and stability in Europe after World War Two.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States is a member, along with 29 other nations.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; American diplomacy matters.&nbsp; American resolve matters.<br><br>Putin’s latest attack on Ukraine was premeditated and totally unprovoked.&nbsp; He rejected repeated &#8212; repeated efforts at diplomacy.<br><br>He thought the West and NATO wouldn’t respond.&nbsp; He thought he could divide us at home, in this chamber, in this nation.&nbsp; He thought he could divide us in Europe as well.<br><br>But Putin was wrong.&nbsp; We are ready.&nbsp; We are united.&nbsp; And that’s what we did: We stayed united.&nbsp;<br><br>We prepared extensively and carefully.&nbsp; We spent months building coalitions of other freedom-loving nations in Europe and the Americas to &#8212; from America to the Asian and African continents to confront Putin.<br><br>Like many of you, I spent countless hours unifying our European Allies.<br><br>We shared with the world, in advance, what we knew Putin was planning and precisely how he would try to falsely and justify his aggression.<br><br>We countered Russia’s lies with the truth.&nbsp; And now &#8212; now that he’s acted, the three wor- &#8212; free world is holding him accountable, along with 27 members of the European Union &#8212; including France, Germany, Italy &#8212; as well as countries like the United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, Korea, Australia, New Zealand, and many others.&nbsp; Even Switzerland are inflicting pain on Russia and supporting the people of Ukraine.<br><br>Putin is now isolated from the world more than he has ever been.&nbsp;<br><br>Together &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; Together &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; Together, along with our Allies, we are right now enforcing powerful economic sanctions.&nbsp; We’re cutting off Russia’s largest banks from the international financial system; preventing Russia’s Central Bank from defending the Russian rubil [sic] &#8212; ruble, making Putin’s $630 billion war fund worthless.&nbsp; We’re choking Russia’s access &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we’re choking Russia’s access to technology that will sap its economic strength and weaken its military for years to come.<br><br>Tonight, I say to the Russian oligarchs and the corrupt leaders who’ve bilked billions of dollars off this violent regime: No more.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The United States &#8212; I mean it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; The United States Department of Justice is assembling a dedicated task force to go after the crimes of the Russian oligarchs.<br><br>We’re joining with European Allies to find and seize their yachts, their luxury apartments, their private jets.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re coming for your ill-begotten gains.<br><br>And, tonight, I&#8217;m announcing that we will join our Allies in closing off American air space to all Russian flights, further isolating Russia and adding an additional squeeze on their economy.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>He has no idea what’s coming.<br><br>The ruble has already lost 30 percent of its value, the Russian stock market has lost 40 percent of its value, and trading remains suspended.<br><br>The Russian economy is reeling, and Putin alone is the one to blame.<br><br>Together with our Allies, we’re providing support to the Ukrainians in their fight for freedom: military assistance, economic assistance, humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; We’re giving more than a billion dollars in direct assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; And we’ll continue to aid the Ukrainian people as they defend their country and help ease their suffering.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But let me be clear: Our forces are not engaged and will not engage in the conflict with Russian forces in Ukraine.&nbsp; Our forces are not going to Europe to fight [in] Ukraine but to defend our NATO Allies in the event that Putin decides to keep moving west.<br><br>For that purpose, we have mobilized American ground forces, air squadrons, ship deployments to protect NATO countries, including Poland, Romania, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.<br><br>And as I&#8217;ve made crystal clear, the United States and our Allies will defend every inch of territory that is NATO territory with the full force of our collective power &#8212; every single inch.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And we’re clear-eyed.&nbsp; The Ukrainians are fighting back with pure courage.&nbsp; But the next few days, weeks, and months will be hard on them.&nbsp;<br><br>Putin has unleashed violence and chaos.&nbsp; But while he may make gains on the battlefield, he will pay a continuing high price over the long run.<br><br>And a pound of Ukrainian people &#8212; the proud, proud people &#8212; pound for pound, ready to fight with every inch of (inaudible) they have.&nbsp; They’ve known 30 years of independence &#8212; have repeatedly shown that they will not tolerate anyone who tries to take their country backwards.<br><br>To all Americans, I’ll be honest with you, as I’ve always promised I would be.&nbsp; A Russian dictator infa- &#8212; invading a foreign country has costs around the world.&nbsp; And I’m taking robust action to make sure the pain of our sanctions is targeted at the Russian economy and that we use every tool at our disposal to protect American businesses and consumers.<br><br>Tonight, I can announce the United States has worked with 30 other countries to release 60 million barrels of oil from reserves around the world.&nbsp; America &#8212; (applause) &#8212; will lead that effort, releasing 30 million barrels of our own Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; And we stand ready to do more if necessary, united with our Allies.<br><br>These steps will help blunt gas prices here at home.&nbsp; But I know news about what’s happening can seem alarming to all Americans.&nbsp; But I want you to know: We’re going to be okay.&nbsp; We’re going to be okay.<br><br>When the history of this era is written, Putin’s war on Ukraine will have left Russia weaker and the rest of the world stronger.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>While it shouldn’t &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and while it shouldn’t have taken &#8212; while it shouldn’t have taken something so terrible for people around the world to see what’s at stake, now everyone sees it clearly.<br><br>We see the unity among leaders of nations, a more unified Europe, a more unified West.<br><br>We see unity among the people who are gathering in cities in large crowds around the world, even in Russia, to demonstrate their support for the people of Ukraine.<br><br>In the battle between democracy and autocracies, democracies are rising to the moment and the world is clearly choosing the side of peace and security.<br><br>This is the real test, and it’s going to take time.&nbsp; So, let us continue to draw inspiration from the iron will of the Ukrainian people.<br><br>To our fellow Ukrainian Americans who forged a deep bond that connects our two nations: We stand with you.&nbsp; We stand with you.&nbsp;<br><br>Putin may circle Kyiv with tanks, but he’ll never gain the hearts and souls of the <s>Uranian</s> [Ukrainian] people.&nbsp; He’ll never &#8212; he’ll never extinguish their love of freedom.&nbsp; And he will never, never weaken the resolve of the free world.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We meet tonight in an America that has lived through two of the hardest years this nation has ever faced.&nbsp; The pandemic has been punishing.&nbsp; And so many families are living paycheck to paycheck, struggling to keep up with the rising cost of food, gas, housing, and so much more.<br><br>I understand, like many of you did.&nbsp; My dad had to leave his home in Scranton, Pennsylvania, to find work.&nbsp; So, like many of you, I grew up in a family when the price of food went up, it was felt throughout the family; it had an impact.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why one of the first things I did as President was fight to pass the American Rescue Plan, because people were hurting.&nbsp; We needed to act and we did.<br><br>Few pieces of legislation have done more at a critical moment in our history to lift us out of a crisis.&nbsp; It fueled our efforts to vaccinate the nation and combat COVID-19.&nbsp; It delivered immediate economic relief to tens of millions of Americans.&nbsp; It helped put food on the table.&nbsp; Remember those long lines of cars waiting for hours just to get a box of food put in their trunk?&nbsp; It cut the cost of healthcare insurance.&nbsp; And as my dad used to say, it gave the people “just a little bit of breathing room.”<br><br>And unlike the $2 trillion tax cut passed in the previous administration that benefitted the top 1 percent of Americans, the American Rescue Plan &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; the American Rescue Plan helped working people and left no one behind.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And, folks &#8212; and it worked.&nbsp; It worked.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>It &#8212; (applause) &#8212; it worked and created jobs &#8212; lots of jobs.&nbsp; In fact, our economy created over 6.5 million new jobs just last year, more jobs in one year than ever before in the history of the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>The economy grew at a rate of 5.7 last year &#8212; the strongest growth rate in 40 years and the first step in bringing fundamental change to our economy that hasn’t worked for working people in this nation for too long.<br><br>For the past 40 years, we were told that tax breaks for those at the top and benefits would trickle down and everyone would &#8212; would benefit.<br><br>But that trickle-down theory led to a weaker economic growth, lower wages, bigger deficits, and a widening gap between the top and everyone else in the &#8212; in nearly a century.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Look, Vice President Harris and I ran for office &#8212; and I realize we have fundamental disagreements on this &#8212; but ran for office with a new economic vision for America: invest in America; educate Americans; grow the workforce; build the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, not from the top down.&nbsp; Because we know &#8212; because we know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; because we know when the middle class grows &#8212; when the middle class grows, the poor go way up and the wealthy do very well.<br><br>America used to have the best roads, bridges, and airports on Earth.&nbsp; And now our infrastructure is ranked 13th in the world.&nbsp; We won’t be able to compete for the jobs of the 21st century if we don’t fix it.<br><br>That’s why it was so important to pass the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; And I thank my Republican friends who joined to invest and rebuild America &#8212; the single biggest investment in history.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>It was a bipartisan effort, and I want to thank the members of both parties who worked to make it happen.&nbsp; We’re done talking about infrastructure weeks.&nbsp; We’re now talking about an infrastructure decade.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And look, it’s going to &#8212; it’s going to transform America to put us on a path to win the economic competition of the 21st century that we face with the rest of the world, particularly China.<br><br>I’ve told Xi Jinping: It’s never been a good bet to bet against the American people.<br><br>We’ll create good jobs for millions of Americans &#8212; modernizing roads, airports, ports, waterways &#8212; all across America.&nbsp; And we’ll do it to withstand the devastating <s>emfects</s> [effects] of climate crisis and promote environmental justice.<br><br>We’ll build a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations; begin to replace the poisonous lead pipes, so every child, every American has clean water to drink at home and at school.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We’re going to provide &#8212; provide affordable high-speed Internet for every American &#8212; rural, suburban, urban, and Tribal communities.&nbsp; Four thousand projects have already been announced.&nbsp; Many of you have announced them in your districts.&nbsp;<br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing that, this year, we will start fixing over 65,000 miles of highway and 1,500 bridges in disrepair.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks, when we use taxpayers’ dollars to rebuild America, we’re going to do it by buying American.&nbsp; (Applause.) Buy American products.&nbsp; Support American jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The federal government spends about $600 billion a year to keep this country safe and secure.&nbsp; There’s been a law on the books for almost a century to make sure taxpayers’ dollars support American jobs and businesses.&nbsp; Every administration &#8212; Democrat and Republican &#8212; says they’ll do it, but we’re actu- &#8212; we’re actually doing it.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ll buy America to make sure every &#8212; everything from the deck of an aircraft carrier to the steel on highway guardrails is made in America from beginning to end.&nbsp; All of it.&nbsp; All of it.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>But, folks, to compete for the jobs of the future, we also need to level the playing field with China and other competitors.&nbsp; That’s why it’s so important to pass the bipartisan Innovation Act sitting in Congress that will make record investments in emerging technologies and American manufacturing.<br><br>We used to invest almost 2 percent of our GDP in research and development.&nbsp; We don’t now.&nbsp; Can’t &#8212; China is.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me give you one example why it&#8217;s so important to pass.<br><br>If you travel 20 miles east of Columbus, Ohio, you’ll find a thousand empty acres of land.&nbsp; It won’t look like much.&nbsp; But if you stop and look closely, you’ll see a “field of dreams&#8221; &#8212; the ground on which America’s future will be built.<br><br>That&#8217;s where Intel, the American company that helped build Silicon Valley, is going to build a $20 billion semiconductor “mega site.”&nbsp; Up to eight state-of-the-art factories in one place.&nbsp; Ten thousand new jobs.&nbsp; And in those factories, the average job &#8212; about $135 &#8212; $135,000 a year.<br><br>Some of the most sophisticated manufacturing in the world to make computer chips the size of a fingertip that power the world and everyday lives, from smartphones, technology that &#8212; the Internet &#8212; technology that&#8217;s yet to be invented.<br><br>But that’s just the beginning.<br><br>Intel’s CEO, Pat Gelsinger, who is here tonight &#8212; and I don&#8217;t know where Pat is.&nbsp; Pat?&nbsp; There you go, Pat.&nbsp; Stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Pat &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Pat came to see me, and he told me they&#8217;re ready to increase their investment from $20 billion to $100 billion.<br><br>That would be the biggest investment in manufacturing in American history.&nbsp; And all they’re waiting for is for you to pass this bill.<br><br>So, let’s not wait any longer.&nbsp; Send it to my desk, I’ll sign it, and we will really take off in a big way.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks, Intel is not alone.&nbsp; There’s something happening in America.&nbsp; Just look around, and you’ll see an amazing story &#8212; the rebirth of pride that comes from stamping products “Made in America,” the revitalization of American manufacturing.<br><br>Companies are choosing to build new factories here when just a few years ago, they would have gone overseas.&nbsp; That’s what is happening.<br><br>Ford is investing $11 billion in electric vehicles, creating 11,000 jobs across the country.<br><br>GM is making the largest investment in its history &#8212; $7 billion to build electric vehicles, creating 4,000 jobs in Michigan.<br><br>All told, 369,000 new manufacturing jobs were created in America last year alone.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, powered by people I’ve met &#8212; like JoJo Burgess from generations of union steelworkers in Pittsburgh, who’s here with us tonight.&nbsp; Where are you, JoJo?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Thanks, buddy.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>As Ohio &#8212; as Ohio Senator Sherrod Brown says &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as Sherrod Brown says, &#8220;It’s time to bury the label &#8216;Rust Belt.'&#8221;&nbsp; It’s time to see the &#8212; the &#8212; what used to be called the Rust Belt become the &#8212; the home of a significant resurgence of manufacturing.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And with all the bright spots in our economy &#8212; record job growth, higher wages &#8212; too many families are struggling to keep up with their bills.<br><br>Inflation is robbing them of gains they thought otherwise they would be able to feel.<br><br>I get it.&nbsp; That’s why my top priority is getting prices under control.<br><br>Look, our economy roared back faster than almost anyone predicted, but the pandemic meant that businesses had a hard time hiring enough people because of the pandemic to keep up production in their factories.&nbsp; So, you didn&#8217;t have people making those beams that went into buildings because they were out &#8212; the factory was closed.<br><br>The <s>panic</s> [pandemic] also disrupted the global supply chain.&nbsp; Factories close.&nbsp; When that happens, it takes longer to make goods and get them to the warehouses, to the stores, and go &#8212; prices go up.<br><br>Look at cars last year.&nbsp; One third of all the inflation was because of automobile sales.&nbsp; There weren’t enough semiconductors to make all the cars that people wanted to buy.<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; Prices of automobiles went way up, especially used vehicles as well.<br><br>And so, we have a choice.&nbsp;<br><br>One way to fight inflation is to drive down wages and make Americans poorer.<br><br>I think I have a better idea to fight inflation: Lower your costs, not your wages.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks, that means make more cars and semiconductors in America, more infrastructure and innovation in America, more goods moving faster and cheaper in America, more jobs where you can earn a good living in America.<br><br>Instead of relying on foreign supply chains, let’s make it in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Look, economists &#8212; (applause) &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; USA!&nbsp; USA!&nbsp; USA!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Economists &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; USA!&nbsp; USA!&nbsp; USA!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; call this increasing the productive capacity of our ecomony [sic] &#8212; of our economy.<br><br>I call it building a better America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>My plan to fight inflation will lower your costs and lower the deficit.&nbsp; Seventeen Nobel laureates in economics said my plan will ease long-term inflationary pressures.&nbsp; Top business leaders and, I believe, most Americans support the plan.<br><br>And here’s the plan.<br><br>First, cut the cost of prescription drugs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We pay more for the same drug produced by the same company in America than any other country in the world.<br><br>Just look at insulin.&nbsp; One in ten Americans has diabetes.&nbsp; In Virginia, I met a 13-year-old boy &#8212; the handsome young man standing up there, Joshua Davis.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; He and his dad both have Type 1 diabetes, which means they need insulin every single day.<br><br>Insulin costs about $10 a vial to make.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it costs the &#8212; the pharmaceutical company.&nbsp; But drug companies charge families like Joshua and his dad up to 30 times that amount.<br><br>I spoke with Joshua’s mom.&nbsp; Imagine what it’s like to look at your child who needs insulin to stay healthy and have no idea how in God&#8217;s name you’re going to be able to pay for it &#8212; what it does to your family, but what it does to your dignity, your ability to look your child in the eye, to be the parent you expect yourself to be.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I think about.<br>You know, yesterday &#8212; Joshua is here tonight, but yesterday was his birthday.&nbsp; Happy birthday, buddy, by the way.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>For Joshua and 200,000 other young people with Type 1 diabetes, let’s cap the cost of insulin at $35 a month so everyone can afford it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And drug companies will do very, very well &#8212; their profit margin.<br><br>And while we’re at it &#8212; I know we have great disagreements on this floor with this &#8212; let&#8217;s let Medicare negotiate the price of prescription drugs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; They already set the price for VA drugs.<br><br>Look, the American Rescue Plan is helping millions of families on Affordable Care Act plans to save them $2,400 a year on their health premiums.&nbsp; Let’s close the coverage gap and make those savings permanent.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And second, let&#8217;s cut energy costs for families an average of $500 a year by combatting climate change.<br><br>Let’s provide an investment and tax credit to weatherize your home and your business to be energy efficient and get a tax credit for it; double America’s clean energy production in solar, wind, and so much more; lower the price of electric vehicles, saving another $80 a month that you&#8217;ve not going to have to pay at the pump.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks &#8212; third &#8212; the third thing we can do to change the standard of living for hardworking folks is cut the cost of childcare.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Cut the cost of childcare.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, if you live in a major city in America, you can pay up to $14,000 a year for childcare per child.<br><br>I was a single dad for five years, raising two kids.&nbsp; I had a lot of help, though.&nbsp; I had a mom, a dad, a brother, and sister that really helped.<br><br>But middle-class and working folks shouldn’t have to pay more than 7 percent of their income to care for their young children.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>My plan &#8212; (applause) &#8212; my plan would cut the cost of childcare in half for most families and help parents, including millions of women who left the workforce during the pandemic because they couldn’t afford childcare to be able to get back to work, generating economic growth.<br><br>But my plan doesn’t stop there.&nbsp; It also includes home and long-term care, more affordable housing, pre-K for three- and four-year-olds.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; All of these will lower costs to families.<br><br>And under my plan, nobody &#8212; let me say this again &#8212; nobody earning less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional penny in new taxes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Not a single penny.&nbsp;<br><br>I may be wrong, but my guess is, if we took a secret ballot in this floor, that we’d all agree that the present tax system ain’t fair.&nbsp; We have to fix it.<br><br>I’m not looking to punish anybody, but let’s make corporations and wealthy Americans start paying their fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Look, last year &#8212; (applause) &#8212; last year &#8212; like Chris Coons and Tom Carper and my distinguished congresswoman &#8212; we come from the land of corporate America.&nbsp; There are more corporations incorporated in <s>America</s> [Delaware] than every other state in America combined.&nbsp; And I still won 36 years in a row.&nbsp; The point is: Even they understand they should pay just a fair share.<br><br>Last year, 55 of the Fortune 500 companies earned $40 billion in profit and paid zero in federal taxes.&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo –<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, look, it’s not fair.&nbsp; That’s why I proposed a 15 percent minimum tax rate for corporations.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We’ve got &#8212; and that’s why in the G7 and other meetings overseas we were able to put together &#8212; I was able to be somewhat helpful &#8212; 130 countries to agree on a global minimum tax rate &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so companies can’t get out of paying their taxes at home by shipping jobs and factories overseas.&nbsp; It’ll raise billions of dollars.<br><br>And that’s why I’ve proposed closing loopholes for the very wealthy who don’t pay &#8212; who pay a lower tax rate than a teacher and a firefighter.<br><br>So that’s my plan.&nbsp; But we have &#8212; we’ll go into more detail later.&nbsp;<br><br>I’m going to grow &#8212; we will grow the economy, lower the costs to families.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what are we waiting for?&nbsp; Let’s get this done.&nbsp; We all know we&#8217;ve got to make changes.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, and while you’re at it, confirm my nominees for the Federal Reserve &#8212; (applause) &#8212; which plays a critical role in fighting inflation.<br><br>My plan will not only lower costs and give families a fair shot, it will lower the deficit.<br><br>The previous administration not only ballooned the deficit with those tax cuts for the very wealthy and corporations, it undermined the watchdogs &#8212; the job of those to keep pandemic relief funds from being wasted.&nbsp; Remember we had those debates about whether or not those watchdogs should be able to see, every day, how much money was being spent, where it &#8212; was it going to the right place?&nbsp;<br><br>In my administration, the watchdogs are back.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;And we’re going after the criminals who stole billions of relief money meant for small business and millions of Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing that the Justice Department will soon name a chief prosecutor for pandemic fraud.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, look &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I think we all agree &#8212; thank you &#8212; by the end of this year, the deficit will be down to less than half what it was before I took office &#8212; the only President ever to cut the deficit by more than $1 trillion in a single year.<br><br>Lowering your costs also meant demanding more competition.&nbsp; I’m a capitalist, but capitalism without competition is not capitalism.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Capitalism without competition is exploitation.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It drives up <s>profits</s> [prices].<br><br>When corporations have to compete, their profits go up and your prices go up &#8212; when they don’t have to compete.&nbsp;<br><br>Small businesses and family farmers and ranchers &#8212; I need not tell some of my Republican friends from those states &#8212; guess what?&nbsp; You got four basic meatpacking facilities.&nbsp; That’s it.&nbsp; You play with them or you don’t get to play at all.&nbsp; And you pay a hell of a lot more &#8212; a hell of a lot more because there’s only four.</p>



<p>See what&#8217;s happening with ocean carriers moving goods in and out of America.  During the pandemic, about half a dozen or less foreign-owned companies raised prices by as much as 1,000 percent and made record profits.<br><br>Tonight, I’m announcing a crackdown on those companies overcharging American businesses and consumers.  (Applause) <br><br>Folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and as Wall Street firms take over more nursing homes, quality in those homes has gone down and costs have gone up.  That ends on my watch.<br><br>Medicare is going to set higher standards for nursing homes and make sure your loved ones get the care they deserve and that they expect, and they will look at that closely.<br><br>We’re also going to cut costs to keep the economy going strong and giving workers a fair shot; provide more training and apprenticeships; hire them based on skills, not just their degrees.<br><br>Let’s pass the Paycheck Fairness Act and paid leave &#8212; (applause); raise the minimum wage to $15 an hour &#8212; (applause); and extend the Child Tax Credit so no one has to raise a family in poverty.  (Applause.)<br><br>Let’s increase Pell Grants; increase our historic support for HBCUs; and invest &#8212; (applause) &#8212; in what Jill, our First Lady, who teaches full-time, calls America’s best-kept secret: community colleges.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look, let’s pass the PRO Act.  When a majority of workers want to form a union, they shouldn’t be able to be stopped.  (Applause.)<br><br>When we invest in our workers and we build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out, together we can do something we haven’t done in a long time: build a better America.<br><br>For more than two years, COVID has impacted every decision in our lives and the life of this nation.  And I know you’re tired, frustrated, and exhausted.  That doesn’t even count the close to a million people who sit at a dining room table or a kitchen table and look at an empty chair because they lost somebody.<br><br>But I also know this: Because of the progress we’ve made, because of your resilience and the tools that we have been provided by this Congress, tonight I can say we’re moving forward safely, back to a norm- &#8212; more normal routines.<br><br>We’ve reached a new moment in the fight against COVID-19 where severe cases are down to a level not seen since July of last year.<br><br>Just a few days ago, the Center for Disease Control and Prevention issued a new mask guidelines.  Under the new guidelines, most Americans in most of the country can now go mask free.  (Applause.) <br><br>And based on projections &#8212; and based on projections, more of the country will reach a point across &#8212; that point across the next couple of weeks.<br><br>And thanks to the progress we’ve made in the past year, COVID-19 no longer need control our lives.  I know some are talking about &#8220;living with COVID-19.&#8221;  But tonight, I say that we never will just accept living with COVID-19; we’ll continue to combat the virus as we do other diseases.<br><br>And because this virus mutates and spreads, we have to stay on guard.  And here are four commonsense steps as we move forward safely, in my view:<br><br>First, stay protected with vaccines and treatments.  We know how incredibly effective vaccines are.  If you’re vaccinated and boosted, you have the highest degree of protection, and we&#8217;ll never give up on vaccinating more Americans.<br><br>Now, I know parents with kids under five are eager to see their vaccines authorized for their children.  Scientists are working hard to get that done, and we’ll be ready with plenty of vaccines if and when they do.<br><br>We’re already &#8212; we are also ready with anti-viral treatments.  If you get COVID-19, the Pfizer pill reduces your chances of ending up in the hospital by 90 percent.<br><br>I’ve ordered more pills than anyone in the world has.  Pfizer is working overtime to get us a million pills this month and more than double that next month.<br><br>And now we’re launching the &#8220;Test to Treat&#8221; initiative so people can get tested at a pharmacy and, if they prove positive, receive the antiviral pills on the spot at no cost.  (Applause.)<br><br>And folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; if you’re immu- &#8212; (applause) &#8212; if you’re immunocompromised or have some other vulnerability, we have treatments and free high-quality masks.<br><br>We’re leaving no one behind or ignoring anyone’s needs as we move forward.<br><br>On testing, we&#8217;ve made hundreds of millions of tests available, and you can order them for free to your doorstep.<br><br>And we&#8217;ve already ordered free tests.  If you already ordered free tests, tonight I&#8217;m announcing you can order another group of tests.  COVID &#8212; go to COVIDTests.gov, starting next week, and you can get more tests. <br><br>Second, we must prepare for new variants.<br><br>Over the past &#8212; we’ve gotten much better at detecting new variants.  If necessary, we’ll be able to <s>develop</s> [deploy] new vaccines within 100 days instead of maybe months or years.  And if Congress <s>presides</s> [provides] the funds we need, we’ll have new stockpiles of tests, masks, pills ready if needed.<br><br>I can’t promise a new variant won’t come, but I ca- &#8212; I can promise you we’ll do everything within our power to be ready if it does.  (Applause.) <br><br>Third, we can end the shutdown of schools and businesses.  We have the tools we need.<br><br>It’s time for America to get back to work and fill our great downtowns again with people.  People working from home can feel safe and begin to return to their offices.  (Applause.) <br><br>We’re doing that here in the federal government.  The vast majority of federal workers will once again work in person.<br><br>Our schools are open.  Let’s keep it that way.  Our kids need to be in school.  (Applause.)<br><br>With 75 percel [sic] of adult &#8212; 75 percent of adult Americans fully vaccinated and hospitalizations down by 77 percent, most Americans can remove their masks and stay in the classroom and move forward safely.<br><br>We achieved this because we provided free vaccines, treatments, tests, and masks.  Of course, continuing this costs money, so it will not surprise you I&#8217;ll be back to see you all.  (Laughter.)  And re- &#8212; I&#8217;m going to soon send a request to Congress.<br><br>The vast majority of Americans have used these tools and may want to again &#8212; we may need them again.  So I expect Congress &#8212; and I hope you&#8217;ll pass that quickly. <br><br>Fourth, we&#8217;ll continue vaccinating the world.  We’ve sent 475 million vaccine doses to 112 countries &#8212; more than any nation on Earth.  (Applause.)  We won’t stop, because you can&#8217;t build a wall high enough to keep out a &#8212;<br><br>A vaccine &#8212; the vaccine can stop the spread of these diseases. <br><br>You know, we&#8217;ve lost so much in COVID-19.  Time with one another.  The worst of all, the much loss of life.<br><br>Let’s use this moment to reset.  So, stop looking at COVID as a partisan dividing line.  See it for what it is: a God-awful disease.<br><br>Let’s stop sending &#8212; seeing each other as enemies and start seeing each other for who we are: fellow Americans.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look &#8212; we &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we can’t change how divided we’ve been.  That was a long time in coming.  But we can change how to move forward on COVID-19 and other issues that we must face together.<br><br>I recently visited New York City Police Department days after the funerals of Officer Wilbert Mora and his partner, Officer Jason Rivera.<br><br>They were responding to a 911 call when a man shot and killed them with a stolen gun.<br><br>Officer Mora was 27 years old.  Officer Rivera was 22 years old.  Both Dominican Americans who grew up in the same streets that they later chose to parol [sic] &#8212; to patrol as police officers.<br><br>I spoke with their families, and I told them that we are forever in debt for their sacrifices and we&#8217;ll carry on their mission to restore the trust and safety in every community it deserves.<br><br>Like some of you that have been around for a while &#8212; I&#8217;ve worked with you on these issues for a long time.  I know what works: <s>Investigating</s> [Investing in] crime prevention and community policing &#8212; cops who walk the beat, who know the neighborhood, and who can restore trust and safety. <br><br>Let&#8217;s not abandon our streets or choose between safety and equal justice.  Let’s come together and protect our communities, restore trust, and hold law enforcement accountable.<br><br>That’s why the Justice Department has required body cameras, banned chokeholds, and restricted no-knock warrants for its officers.<br><br>That’s why the American Rescue Plan that you all provided $350 billion that cities, states, and counties can use to hire more police, invest in more proven strategies &#8212; (applause) &#8212; proven strategies like &#8212; proven strategies like community violence interruption, trusted messengers breaking the cycle of violence and trauma and giving young people some hope.<br><br>We should all agree the answer is not to defund the police.<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  That&#8217;s right!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  It&#8217;s to fund the police.  (Applause.)  Fund them.  Fund them.  (Applause.)  Fund them with the resources and training &#8212; resources and training they need to protect our communities.<br><br>I ask Democrats and Republicans alike to pass my budget and keep our neighborhoods safe.<br><br>And we&#8217;ll do everything in my power to crack down on gun trafficking of ghost guns that you can buy online, assemble at home &#8212; no serial numbers, can’t be traced. <br><br>I ask Congress to pass proven measures to reduce gun violence.  Pass universal background checks.  (Applause.)  Why should anyone on the terrorist list be able to purchase a weapon.  Why?  Why?  (Applause.)<br><br>AUDIENCE:  Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And, folks, ban assault weapons with high-capacity magazines that hold up to 100 rounds.  You think the deer are wearing Kevlar vests?  (Laughter.)<br><br>Look, repeal the liability shield that makes gun manufacturers the only industry in America that can’t be sued &#8212; the only one.  (Applause.)  Imagine had we done that with the tobacco manufactures.<br><br>These laws don’t infringe on the Second Amendment; they save lives.<br><br>The most fundamental right in America is the right to vote and have it counted.  (Applause.)  And look, it’s under assault.<br><br>In state after state, new laws have been passed not only to suppress the vote &#8212; we&#8217;ve been there before &#8212; but to subvert the entire election.  We can&#8217;t let this happen.<br><br>Tonight, I call on the Senate to pass &#8212; pass the Freedom to Vote Act.  (Applause.)  Pass the John Lewis Act &#8212; Voting Rights Act.  (Applause.)  And while you’re at it, pass the DISCLOSE Act so Americans know who is funding our elections.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look, tonight, I’d &#8212; I&#8217;d like to honor someone who has dedicated his life to serve this country: Justice Breyer &#8212; an Army veteran, Constitutional scholar, retiring Justice of the United States Supreme Court.<br><br>Justice Breyer, thank you for your service.  (Applause.)  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)  I mean it.  Get up.  Stand &#8212; let me see you.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br><br>And we all know &#8212; no matter what your ideology, we all know one of the most serious constitutional responsibilities a President has is nominating someone to serve on the United States Supreme Court.<br><br>As I did four days ago, I&#8217;ve nominated a Circuit Court of Appeals &#8212; Ketanji Brown Jackson.  (Applause.)  One of our nation’s top legal minds who will continue in just Brey- &#8212; Justice Breyer’s legacy of excellence.  (Applause.)  A former top litigator in private practice, a former federal public defender from a family of public-school educators and police officers &#8212; she&#8217;s a consensus builder.<br><br>Since she’s been nominated, she’s received a broad range of support, including the Fraternal Order of Police and former judges appointed by Democrats and Republicans.<br><br>Folks, if we are to advance liberty and justice, we need to secure our border and fix the immigration system.  (Applause.)<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBERS:  Build the wall!  Build the wall!  Build the wall!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And as you might guess, I think we can do both.  At our border, we’ve installed new technology, like cutting-edge scanners, to better detect drug smuggling.<br><br>We’ve set up joint patrols with Mexico and Guatemala to catch more human traffickers. <br><br>We’re putting in place dedicated immigration judges in significant larger number so families fleeing persecution and violence can have their cases &#8212; cases heard faster &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and those who <s>don&#8217;t</s> [aren’t] legitimately here can be sent back. <br><br>We’re screening &#8212; we’re securing commitments and supporting partners in South and Central America to host more refugees and secure their own borders.<br><br>We can do all this while keeping lit the torch of liberty that has led the generation of immigrants to this land &#8212; my forebearers and many of yours.<br><br>Provide a pathway to citizenship for Dreamers &#8212; (applause) &#8212; those with temporary status, farmworkers, essential workers.  To revise our laws so businesses have workers they need and families don’t wait decades to reunite.<br><br>It’s not only the right thing to do, it’s economically smart thing to do.  That’s why the immigration reform is supported by everyone from labor unions to religious leaders to the U.S. Chamber of Commerce.  (Applause.)  Let’s get it done once and for all.  (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, advancing liberty and justice also requires protecting the rights of women.  The constitutional right affirmed by Roe v. Wade, standing precedent for half a century, is under attack as never before.<br><br>If you want to go forward not backwards, we must protect access to healthcare &#8212; (applause); preserve a woman’s right to choose &#8212; (applause); and continue to advance maternal healthcare for all Americans.  (Applause.)<br><br>And folks, for our LGBTQ+ Americans, let’s finally get the bipartisan Equality Act to my desk.  (Applause.)  The onslaught of state laws targeting transgender Americans and their families &#8212; it’s simply wrong. <br><br>As I said last year, especially to our younger transgender Americans, I’ll always have your back as your President so you can be yourself and reach your God-given potential.  (Applause.)<br><br>Folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as I&#8217;ve just demonstrated, while it often appears we do not agree and that &#8212; we &#8212; we do agree on a lot more things than we acknowledge. <br><br>I signed 80 bipartisan bills into law last year, from preventing government shutdowns, to protecting Asian Americans from still-too-common hate crimes, to reforming military justice.  And we’ll soon be strengthening the Violence Against Women Act that I first wrote three decades ago.  (Applause.)<br><br>And it’s important &#8212; (applause) &#8212; it’s important for us to show &#8212; to show the nation that we can come together and do big things. <br><br>So tonight, I’m offering a &#8220;Unity Agenda for the Nation&#8221;: four big things we can do together, in my view.<br><br>First, beat the opioid epidemic.  (Applause.)  There’s so much we can do: increase funding for prevention, treatment, harm reduction, and recovery; get rid of outdated rules and stop doctors and &#8212; that stop doctors from prescribing treatments; stop the flow of illicit drugs by working with state and local law enforcement to go after the traffickers.  (Applause.)<br><br>And if you’re suffering from addiction, you know &#8212; you should know you’re not alone.  I believe in recovery, and I celebrate the 23 million &#8212; 23 million Americans in recovery.  (Applause.)<br><br>Second, let’s take on mental health &#8212; especially among our children, whose lives and education have been turned upside down.<br><br>The American Rescue Plan gave schools money to hire teachers and help students make up for lost learning.  I urge every parent to make sure your school &#8212; your school does just that.  They have the money.<br><br>We can all play a part.  Sign up to be a tutor or a mentor.<br><br>Children were also struggling before the pandemic: bullying, violence, trauma, and the harms of social media.<br><br>As Frances Haugen, who is here tonight with us, has shown, we must hold social media platforms accountable for the national experiment they’re conducting on our children for profit.  (Applause.)  Folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.  Thank you for the courage you showed.<br><br>It’s time to strengthen privacy protections; ban targeted advertising to children &#8212; (applause); demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children. <br><br>And let’s get all Americans the mental health services they need &#8212; (applause) &#8212; more people can turn for help and full parity between physical and mental healthcare if we treat it that way in our insurance.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look, the third piece of that agenda is support our veterans.  (Applause.)  Veterans are the backbone and the spine of this country.  They’re the best of us.  (Applause.)<br><br>I’ve always believed that we have a sacred obligation to equip those we send to war and care for those and their family when they come home.<br><br>My administration is providing assistance and job training and housing, and now helping lower-income veterans get VA care debt free.<br><br>And our troops in Iraq have faced &#8212; and Afghanistan &#8212; have faced many dangers.  One being stationed at bases, breathing in toxic smoke from burn pits.  (Applause.)  Many of you have been there.  I’ve been in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan over 40 times.  These burn pits that incinerate waste &#8212; the wastes of war, medical and hazardous material, jet fuel, and so much more.<br><br>And they come home &#8212; many of the world’s fittest and best trained warriors in the world &#8212; never the same: headaches, numbness, dizziness, a cancer that would put them in a flag-draped coffin.  I know. <br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  You put them in.  Thirteen of them.<br><br>AUDIENCE:  Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  One of those &#8212; one of those soldiers was my son, Major Beau Biden.  I don’t know for sure if the burn pit that he lived near &#8212; that his hooch was near in Iraq and, earlier than that, in Kosovo is the cause of his brain cancer and the disease of so many other troops.  But I’m committed to find out everything we can.<br><br>Committed to military families like Danielle Robinson from Ohio, the widow of Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson.  He was born a soldier.  Army National Guard.  Combat medic in Kosovo and Iraq.  Stationed near Baghdad, just yards from burn pits the size of football fields.<br><br>Danielle is here with us tonight.  They loved going to Ohio State football games.  (Applause.)  And he loved building Legos with their daughter.  But cancer from prolonged exposure to burn pits ravaged Heath’s lungs and body.<br><br>Danielle says Heath was a fighter to the very end.  He didn’t know how to stop fighting, and neither did she.<br><br>Through her pain, she found purpose to demand that we do better.  Tonight, Danielle, we are going to do better.  (Applause)<br><br>The VA &#8212; the VA is pioneering new ways of linking toxic exposures to disease, already helping more veterans get benefits.  And tonight, I’m announcing we&#8217;re expanding eligibility to veterans suffering from nine respiratory cancers.<br><br>I’m also calling on Congress to pass a law to make sure veterans devastated by toxic exposure in Iraq and Afghanistan finally get the benefits and the comprehensive healthcare they deserve.  (Applause.)<br><br>And fourth and last, let’s end cancer as we know it.  (Applause.)  This is personal.  (Applause.)  This is personal to me and to Jill and to Kamala and so many of you.  So many of you have lost someone you love &#8212; husband, wife, son, daughter, mom, dad.<br><br>Cancer is the number-two cause of death in America, second only to heart disease.<br><br>Last month, I announced the plan to supercharge the Cancer Moonshot that President Obama asked me to lead six years ago.<br><br>Our goal is to cut cancer death rates by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years.  And I think we can do better than that: turn cancers from death sentences into treatable diseases, more support for patients and families.<br><br>To get there, I call on Congress to fund what I called ARPA-H &#8212; (applause): Advanced &#8212; Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health.  Patterned after DARPA in the Defense Department, projects that led &#8212; in DARPA &#8212; to the Internet, GPS, and so much more that make our forces more safer and be able to wage war more &#8212; with more clarity.<br><br>ARPA[-H] will have a singular purpose to drive breakthroughs in cancer, Alzheimer’s, and diabetes, and more.<br><br>A Unity Agenda for the nation.  We can do these things.  It&#8217;s within our power.  And I don&#8217;t see a partisan edge to any one of those four things. <br><br>My fellow Americans &#8212; (applause) &#8212; tonight we&#8217;ve gathered in a sacred space: the citadel of democracy.  In this Capitol, generation after generation of Americans have debated great questions amid great strife and have done great things.<br><br>We have fought for freedom, expanded liberty, <s>debated</s> [defeated] totalitarianism  and terror.  We built the strongest, freest, and most prosperous nation the world has ever known.<br><br>Now is the hour: our moment of responsibility, our test of resolve and conscience of history itself.  It is in this moment that our character of this generation is formed, our purpose is found, our future is forged.<br><br>Well, I know this nation.  We&#8217;ll meet the test, protect freedom and liberty, expand fairness and opportunity.  And we will save democracy.<br><br>As hard as those times have been, I’m more optimistic about America today than I&#8217;ve been my whole life because I see the future that&#8217;s within our grasp, because I know there is simply nothing beyond our camas- &#8212; our capacity.<br><br>We&#8217;re the only nation on Earth that has always turned every crisis we&#8217;ve faced into an opportunity, the only nation that can be defined by a single word: possibilities.<br><br>So, on this night, on our 245th year as a nation, I&#8217;ve come to report on the state of the nation &#8212; the state of the union.  And my report is this: The State of the Union is strong because you, the American people, are strong.  (Applause.)<br><br>We are stronger today &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we are stronger today than we were a year ago.  And we&#8217;ll be stronger a year from now than we are today.<br><br>This is our moment to meet and overcome the challenges of our time.  And we will, as one people, one America &#8212; the United States of America.  (Applause.)<br><br>God bless you all.  (Applause.)  And may God protect our troops.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Go get &#8217;em.<br><br>10:10 P.M. EST </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/02/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 15:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660 of March 6, 2014, which was expanded in scope in Executive Order 13661 of March 16, 2014, Executive Order 13662 of March 20, 2014, and Executive Order 14065 of February 21, 2022, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13685 of December&nbsp;19, 2014 and Executive Order 13849 of September 20, 2018, is to continue in effect beyond March&nbsp;6, 2022.&nbsp;<br><br>The actions and policies of persons that undermine democratic processes and institutions in Ukraine; threaten its peace, security, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity; and contribute to the misappropriation of its assets, as well as the actions and policies of the Government of the Russian Federation, including its purported annexation of Crimea, its use of force in Ukraine, and its purported recognition of the so-called Donetsk People&#8217;s Republic or Luhansk People&#8217;s Republic regions of Ukraine, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and&nbsp;foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; Therefore, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660 with respect to Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; March 2, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/02/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-ukraine-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 15:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 6, 2014, by Executive Order 13660, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions and policies of persons that undermine democratic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On March 6, 2014, by Executive Order 13660, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions and policies of persons that undermine democratic processes and institutions in Ukraine; threaten its peace, security, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity; and&nbsp;contribute to the misappropriation of its assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On March 16, 2014, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13661, which expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660, and found that the actions and policies of the Government of the Russian Federation with respect to Ukraine undermine democratic processes and institutions in Ukraine; threaten its peace, security, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity; and contribute to the misappropriation of its assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On March 20, 2014, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13662, which further expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660, as expanded in scope in Executive Order 13661, and found that the actions and policies of the Government of the Russian Federation, including its purported annexation of Crimea and its use of force in Ukraine, continue to undermine democratic processes and institutions in Ukraine; threaten its peace, security, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity; and contribute to the misappropriation of its assets.</p>



<p>On December 19, 2014, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13685, to take additional steps to address the Russian occupation of the Crimea region of Ukraine.</p>



<p>On September 20, 2018, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13849, to take additional steps to implement certain statutory sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation.</p>



<p>On February 21, 2022, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;14065, which further expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660, as expanded in scope in Executive Orders 13661 and 13662, and relied on for additional steps taken in Executive Orders 13685 and 13849, and found that the Russian Federation&#8217;s purported recognition of the so-called Donetsk People&#8217;s Republic or Luhansk People&#8217;s Republic regions of Ukraine contradicts Russia&#8217;s commitments under the Minsk agreements and further threatens the&nbsp;peace, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of&nbsp;Ukraine, and thereby constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United&nbsp;States.</p>



<p>The actions and policies addressed in these Executive Orders continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660, which was expanded in scope in Executive Order&nbsp;13661, Executive Order 13662, and Executive Order 14065, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13685 and Executive Order 13849, must continue in effect beyond March&nbsp;6,&nbsp;2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of&nbsp;the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; March 2, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Addressing Addiction and the Overdose&#160;Epidemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-addressing-addiction-and-the-overdose-epidemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 03:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Drug overdose deaths have reached a historic high, devastating families and communities. More than 104,000 Americans died due to a drug overdose in the 12-month period ending in September 2021. We grieve these losses, and commit to continuing our work to save lives. Tonight, President Biden outlined the decisive actions his Administration is taking to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Drug overdose deaths have reached a historic high, devastating families and communities. More than 104,000 Americans died due to a drug overdose in the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nvss/vsrr/drug-overdose-data.htm">12-month period ending in September 2021</a>. We grieve these losses, and commit to continuing our work to save lives.</p>



<p>Tonight, President Biden outlined the decisive actions his Administration is taking to address addiction and the overdose epidemic and laid out a vision for how his Administration will continue to expand evidence-based prevention, harm reduction, treatment, recovery, and supply reduction approaches to save lives. <a>These efforts are bringing together Republicans and Democrats across the country because every community has been affected.</a></p>



<p>Specifically, the President outlined his comprehensive approach, including:</p>



<p><strong><em>Increasing Funding for Public Health and Supply Reduction</em></strong></p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/newsroom/press-announcements/202110260320#:~:text=The%20Substance%20Abuse%20and%20Mental%20Health%20Services%20Administration,had%20a%20negative%20impact%20on%20the%20nation%E2%80%99s%20well-being.">2020 National Survey on Drug Use and Health</a>, 40.3 million people aged 12 or older had a past-year substance use disorder. Meanwhile, more than four out of five Americans who need treatment for illicit drug use do not receive it. Mental health and substance use disorder services have been under-resourced for far too long, and the COVID-19 pandemic has placed an even greater burden on the system. The American Rescue Plan, which delivered nearly $4 billion to these services, was a down payment to support life-saving interventions. The President’s FY2022 budget request includes a historic $41 billion for drug policy efforts that will further these efforts. Specifically, the President is calling for:<br></p>



<ul><li>A historic proposed investment of $10.7 billion in discretionary funding for the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to fund research, prevention, harm reduction, treatment, and recovery support services, with a focus on meeting the needs of populations at greatest risk for overdose and substance use disorder. The President’s FY2022 budget proposes a total of $23.5 billion for public health approaches to reduce drug use and its consequences.</li></ul>



<ul><li>A proposed investment of $5.8 billion for interdiction efforts, which is an increase from the FY2021 enacted level. This funding would help reduce the availability of illicit drugs in the United States and abroad through air and maritime seizures; enhancement of drug source nations’ ability to interdict drugs; and efforts along the nation’s borders to stop the trafficking of illicit drugs, weapons, and bulk currency. The President’s FY2022 budget proposes a total of $17.5 billion for supply reduction efforts.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Removing Barriers to Treatment</em></strong></p>



<p>Medication for opioid use disorder (MOUD), such as buprenorphine and methadone, is a safe and effective treatment. However, <a>most Americans who need treatment for an opioid use disorder do not get it</a>. That is why President Biden has called for universal access to MOUD by 2025. To reach this goal, the Administration has advanced actions that remove unnecessary barriers that prevent medical providers from prescribing FDA-approved medications to their patients; lifted the moratorium on mobile vans providing methadone; supported states funding the purchase of such vans; and begun work on meeting individual treatment needs at times when people at high risk for an overdose need care and support.</p>



<ul><li>To further reduce burdens in accessing MOUD, the President supports eliminating outdated rules that place unnecessary administrative burdens on providers, discouraging them from prescribing effective treatments for addiction. The Administration will increase awareness and understanding of these medications so that patients and providers can make informed choices. This builds on last year’s action by HHS to <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/04/27/hhs-releases-new-buprenorphine-practice-guidelines-expanding-access-to-treatment-for-opioid-use-disorder.html">release</a>&nbsp;new Practice Guidelines for the Administration of Buprenorphine for Treating Opioid Use Disorder, which exempted eligible health care providers from Federal certification requirements related to training, counseling and other ancillary services that are part of the process for obtaining a waiver to treat up to 30 patients with buprenorphine. This action resulted in more providers registering to prescribe buprenorphine, thereby expanding access to evidence-based treatment.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Administration has extended and will propose making permanent the emergency provisions implemented during the COVID-19 pandemic concerning MOUD authorizations. This includes ongoing work allowing providers to begin treating patients with MOUD via telehealth, including by audio only, as well as the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/newsroom/press-announcements/202111181000">announcement</a> extending the methadone take-home flexibilities for one year, effective upon the eventual expiration of the COVID-19 Public Health Emergency.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Over the next year, the Administration plans to establish a set of hospital recommendations for overdose care and care coordination and create a model state law. Individuals who have experienced a non-fatal overdose are at greater risk of a fatal opioid overdose.&nbsp; Hospital emergency departments (EDs) offer a unique setting to initiate treatment, provide naloxone, and connect patients with peer support services.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Administration is working to expand MOUD throughout Federal incarcerated settings, in order to set an example for state and local jurisdictions. In conjunction with this effort, educational efforts will take place to support state and local jurisdictions in understanding the evidence and benefits of MOUD and community care connections upon release from incarceration – a time when individuals are at the highest risk for overdose. Recognizing that the prohibition of the use of federal funds for services behind bars acts is a barrier to states and counties in implementing evidence-based practices, an examination of federal funds usage and opportunities will take place during the coming year.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Reducing Harm and Saving Lives</em></strong></p>



<p>In reaction to the steep rise in overdose deaths and the increasingly lethal drug supply, the Biden-Harris Administration has prioritized engaging and building trust with people who use drugs in order to save lives and provide care. For the first time, harm reduction services – which include naloxone, fentanyl test strips, and syringe service programs – are a federal drug policy priority. These interventions are saving lives in red states and blue states, as years of research have demonstrated. People who use heroin and others who inject drugs who regularly utilize a Syringe Services Program (SSP) are <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9633030/">five times more likely to initiate substance use disorder treatment</a>, compared with those who have never used an SSP. <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19413790/">Syringe services sites can be effective platforms</a> to motivate people with opioid use disorder to enroll in substance use treatment and, over time, to reduce drug use and number of drug injections. Distribution of naloxone to reverse the effects of an opioid overdose <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32327162/">saves lives and is cost-effective</a>.</p>



<ul><li>The Administration has prioritized funds for harm reduction. The American Rescue Plan included <a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/grants/grant-announcements/sp-22-001">$30 million in support for harm reduction services</a> – a historic amount that will enhance interventions like syringe services programs. Additionally, CDC and the SAMHSA <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2021/p0407-Fentanyl-Test-Strips.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced&nbsp;</a>that federal funding may now be used to purchase fentanyl test strips in an effort to help curb the dramatic spike in drug overdose deaths.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Administration is including the input of people who use drugs in designing harm reduction interventions that will help save lives. In December, ONDCP, SAMHSA, and the CDC convened the first-ever Harm Reduction Summit. A steering committee made up entirely of people with lived experience is working to provide guidance and input on future Administration harm reduction efforts.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Administration plans to continue efforts to support syringe services programs through funding opportunities to provide these programs with needed supplies such as fentanyl test strips and sterile syringes, which have been proven to reduce diseases such as Hep-C and HIV.&nbsp; In addition, ensuring naloxone is easily and readily available to these programs will provide the overdose reversal medication to people who need it most.</li></ul>



<ul><li>In order to deliver resources to local communities, the Administration is working with states and communities to elevate harm reduction best practices. &nbsp;Last year, ONDCP released model laws for states to help expand access to naloxone and SSPs. This year, ONDCP plans to elevate best practices for harm reduction organizations initiating low-threshold treatment through warm hand-offs to care or colocation of treatment. The Administration plans to work with states to expand this strategy in communities most in need.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The overdose reversal medication naloxone is a critical tool for saving lives. However, equitable access to naloxone across the country is often defined by where you live. The Biden-Harris Administration is examining barriers to the acquisition and distribution of naloxone at the local level in order to increase access and availability where it is most needed.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Stopping the Trafficking of Illicit Drugs</em></strong></p>



<p>Transnational organized crime is a multi-billion-dollar enterprise that transcends geographical boundaries and threatens global stability.&nbsp; Every year, millions of lives are affected by transnational criminal organizations, including through drug overdose and addiction, violence, firearm deaths, human trafficking, and smuggling.&nbsp; Drug trafficking and transnational organized crime threatens our partners as well, especially in Latin America. It fuels corruption, unbalances economies, preys on the most vulnerable, and calls into question the very foundations of legitimate governance, all of which lead to internal population displacement and migration. Additionally, domestic drug trafficking organizations often contribute to public health challenges and violence in American communities. Addressing the core causes and sources of transnational and domestic criminal activities is an urgent priority for the Administration.</p>



<ul><li>In October, President Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/15/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-launches-new-efforts-to-counter-transnational-criminal-organizations-and-illicit-drugs/">announced</a> two Executive Orders to counter transnational criminal organizations and illicit drug trafficking: first, by formally establishing the U.S. Council on Transnational Organized Crime; and second, by modernizing and expanding the U.S. Government’s ability to target drug trafficking organizations, their enablers, and financial facilitators through sanctions and other related actions. With these new tools, the Administration will disrupt the drug traffickers’ ability to fund their business and deny them the benefits of their illicit activities.<br><br></li></ul>



<ul><li>Through its High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas (HIDTA) Program, ONDCP is funding new initiatives to reduce the violence associated with drug trafficking, refine interdiction efforts through enhanced data sharing and targeting, and go after illicit finance using innovative approaches, including cryptocurrency investigation. HIDTA baseline funds supporting these initiatives will be issued within 45 days of enactment of FY2022 appropriations. These efforts will leverage strategic partnerships with Federal agencies, academics, and private industry. ONDCP is evaluating emerging drug threats in a variety of geographic regions and is poised to expand the HIDTA Program, as needed, by designating new areas as HIDTAs to better equip these regions to disrupt and dismantle drug trafficking organizations. ONDCP plans to announce HIDTA designations this summer in the Federal Register.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The HIDTA Overdose Response Strategy, funded by ONDCP and CDC, brings together drug intelligence officers and public health analysts at the local and regional levels to share information and develop evidence-based intervention and support services that reduce overdoses.&nbsp; <a>The Strategy is piloting a range of innovative investigative, overdose prevention, and harm reduction approaches in all 50 states, Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and the District of Columbia.</a></li></ul>



<p>These actions build upon the significant efforts the Administration has advanced through its first-year drug policy priorities and the American Rescue Plan. These efforts delivered critical attention and resources to the communities that are tackling this crisis on the front lines. <strong>More information about </strong><strong>actions taken by the Biden-Harris Administration to address addiction and the overdose epidemic can be found&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ondcp/briefing-room/2022/01/18/white-house-releases-list-of-actions-taken-by-the-biden-harris-administration-since-january-2021-to-address-addiction-and-the-overdose-epidemic/"><strong>HERE</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks of President Joe&#160;Biden – State of the Union Address As Prepared for&#160;Delivery</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/01/remarks-of-president-joe-biden-state-of-the-union-address-as-delivered/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 02:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48125</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United States Capitol Madam Speaker, Madam Vice President, our First Lady and Second Gentleman. Members of Congress and the Cabinet.&#160;Justices of the Supreme Court. My fellow Americans.&#160;&#160; Last year COVID-19 kept us apart. This year we are finally together again.&#160; Tonight, we meet as Democrats&#160;Republicans&#160;and Independents.&#160;But most importantly as Americans.&#160; With a duty to one&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">United States Capitol</p>



<p>Madam Speaker, Madam Vice President, our First Lady and Second Gentleman. Members of Congress and the Cabinet.&nbsp;Justices of the Supreme Court. My fellow Americans.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Last year COVID-19 kept us apart. This year we are finally together again.&nbsp;<br><br>Tonight, we meet as Democrats&nbsp;Republicans&nbsp;and Independents.&nbsp;But most importantly as Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>With a duty to one another to the American people to the Constitution.&nbsp;<br><br>And with an unwavering resolve&nbsp;that freedom&nbsp;will always triumph over tyranny.&nbsp;<br><br>Six days ago, Russia’s Vladimir Putin sought to shake the foundations of the free world thinking he could make it bend to his menacing ways.&nbsp;But he badly miscalculated.&nbsp;<br><br>He thought he could roll into Ukraine and the world would roll over.&nbsp;Instead he met a wall of strength he never imagined.&nbsp;<br><br>He met the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;<br><br>From President&nbsp;Zelenskyy&nbsp;to every Ukrainian, their fearlessness, their courage, their&nbsp;determination, inspires the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Groups of citizens blocking tanks with their bodies.&nbsp;Everyone from students to retirees teachers turned soldiers defending their homeland.&nbsp;<br><br>In this struggle as President&nbsp;Zelenskyy&nbsp;said in his speech to the European Parliament “Light will win over darkness.”&nbsp;The Ukrainian Ambassador to the United States&nbsp;is here tonight.&nbsp;<br><br>Let each of us here tonight in this Chamber send an unmistakable signal to Ukraine and to the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Please rise if you are able and show that, Yes, we the United States of America&nbsp;stand with the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout our history we’ve learned this lesson&nbsp;when dictators do not pay a price for their aggression&nbsp;they cause more chaos.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>They keep moving.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And the costs and the threats&nbsp;to America and the world&nbsp;keep rising.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why the NATO Alliance&nbsp;was created&nbsp;to secure peace&nbsp;and stability in Europe&nbsp;after World War 2.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States&nbsp;is a member&nbsp;along with 29&nbsp;other nations.&nbsp;<br><br>It matters.&nbsp;American diplomacy matters.&nbsp;American resolve matters.&nbsp;<br><br>Putin’s latest attack on Ukraine&nbsp;was premeditated and unprovoked.&nbsp;<br><br>He rejected repeated efforts at diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>He thought the West&nbsp;and NATO&nbsp;wouldn’t respond.&nbsp;And he thought he could divide us at home. Putin was&nbsp;wrong. We were ready.&nbsp; Here is what we did.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We prepared extensively and carefully.&nbsp;<br><br>We spent months building a coalition of other freedom-loving nations from Europe and the Americas to Asia and Africa&nbsp;to confront Putin.&nbsp;<br><br>I spent countless hours unifying our European allies.&nbsp;We shared with the world in advance what we knew Putin was planning and precisely how he would try to falsely justify his aggression.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We countered Russia’s lies with truth.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And now that he has acted the free world is&nbsp;holding him&nbsp;accountable.&nbsp;<br><br>Along with twenty-seven members of the European Union including France, Germany, Italy, as well as countries like the United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, Korea, Australia, New Zealand, and many others, even Switzerland.&nbsp;<br><br>We are inflicting pain on Russia&nbsp;and supporting the people of Ukraine.&nbsp;Putin is now isolated from the world&nbsp;more than ever.&nbsp;<br><br>Together with our allies –we are right now&nbsp;enforcing powerful economic sanctions.&nbsp;<br><br>We are cutting off Russia’s largest banks from the international financial system.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Preventing Russia’s central bank from defending the Russian Ruble making Putin’s $630 Billion “war fund” worthless.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We are choking off Russia’s access to technology that will sap its economic strength and weaken its military for years to come.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Tonight I say to the Russian oligarchs and corrupt leaders who have bilked billions of dollars off this violent regime no more.&nbsp;<br><br>The U.S. Department of Justice is assembling a dedicated task force to go after the crimes of Russian oligarchs.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We are joining with our European allies to find and seize your yachts your luxury apartments your private jets. We are coming for your ill-begotten gains.&nbsp;<br><br>And tonight I am announcing that we will join our allies in closing off American air space to all Russian flights – further isolating Russia –&nbsp;and adding an additional squeeze –on their economy. The Ruble has lost 30% of its value.&nbsp;<br><br>The Russian stock market has lost 40% of its value&nbsp;and trading remains suspended. Russia’s economy is reeling and Putin alone is to blame.&nbsp;<br><br>Together with our allies we are providing support to the Ukrainians in their fight for freedom. Military assistance. Economic assistance.&nbsp;Humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>We are giving more than $1 Billion in direct assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>And we will continue to aid the Ukrainian people as they defend their country and to help ease their suffering.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Let me be clear, our forces are not engaged and will not engage in conflict with Russian forces&nbsp;in Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Our forces are&nbsp;not&nbsp;going to Europe to fight in Ukraine, but to defend our NATO Allies –&nbsp;in the event that Putin decides to keep moving west.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>For that purpose we’ve mobilized American ground forces, air squadrons, and ship deployments to protect NATO countries including Poland, Romania, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.&nbsp;<br><br>As I have made crystal clear the United States and our Allies will defend every inch of territory of NATO countries with the full force of our collective power.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we remain clear-eyed. The Ukrainians are fighting back with pure courage.&nbsp;But the next few days weeks,&nbsp;months, will be hard on them.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Putin has unleashed violence and chaos.&nbsp; But while he may make gains on the battlefield – he will pay a continuing high price over the long run.&nbsp;<br><br>And a proud Ukrainian people, who have known 30 years&nbsp; of independence, have repeatedly shown that they will not tolerate anyone who tries to take&nbsp;their country backwards.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>To all Americans, I will be honest with you, as I’ve always promised.&nbsp;A Russian dictator, invading a foreign country, has costs around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’m taking robust action to make sure the pain of our sanctions&nbsp; is targeted at Russia’s economy. And I will use every tool at our disposal to protect American businesses and consumers.&nbsp;<br><br>Tonight, I can announce that the United States has worked with 30 other countries to release&nbsp;60 Million&nbsp;barrels of oil from reserves around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>America will lead that effort, releasing 30 Million barrels from our own Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp;And we stand ready to do more if necessary, unified with our allies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>These steps will help blunt gas prices&nbsp;here at home.&nbsp;And I know the news about what’s happening&nbsp;can seem alarming.&nbsp;<br><br>But I want you to know that we are going to be okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When the history of this era is written Putin’s war on Ukraine will have left Russia weaker and the rest of the world stronger. <br><br>While it shouldn’t have taken something so terrible for people around the world to see what’s at stake now everyone sees it clearly. <br><br>We see the unity among leaders of nations and a more unified Europe a more unified West. And we see unity among the people who are gathering in cities in large crowds around the world even in Russia to demonstrate their support for Ukraine.  <br><br>In the battle between democracy and autocracy, democracies are rising to the moment, and the world is clearly choosing the side of peace and security. <br><br>This is a real test. It’s going to take time. So let us continue to draw inspiration from the iron will of the Ukrainian people. <br><br>To our fellow Ukrainian Americans who forge a deep bond that connects our two nations we stand with you. <br><br>Putin may circle Kyiv with tanks, but he will never gain the hearts and souls of the Ukrainian people. <br><br>He will never extinguish their love of freedom. He will never weaken the resolve of the free world. <br><br>We meet tonight in an America that has lived through two of the hardest years this nation has ever faced. <br><br>The pandemic has been punishing. <br><br>And so many families are living paycheck to paycheck, struggling to keep up with the rising cost of food, gas, housing, and so much more. <br><br>I understand. <br><br>I remember when my Dad had to leave our home in Scranton, Pennsylvania to find work. I grew up in a family where if the price of food went up, you felt it. <br><br>That’s why one of the first things I did as President was fight to pass the American Rescue Plan.  <br><br>Because people were hurting. We needed to act, and we did. <br><br>Few pieces of legislation have done more in a critical moment in our history to lift us out of crisis. <br><br>It fueled our efforts to vaccinate the nation and combat COVID-19. It delivered immediate economic relief for tens of millions of Americans.  <br><br>Helped put food on their table, keep a roof over their heads, and cut the cost of health insurance. <br><br>And as my Dad used to say, it gave people a little breathing room. <br><br>And unlike the $2 Trillion tax cut passed in the previous administration that benefitted the top 1% of Americans, the American Rescue Plan helped working people—and left no one behind. <br><br>And it worked. It created jobs. Lots of jobs. <br><br>In fact—our economy created over 6.5 Million new jobs just last year, more jobs created in one year  <br>than ever before in the history of America. <br><br>Our economy grew at a rate of 5.7% last year, the strongest growth in nearly 40 years, the first step in bringing fundamental change to an economy that hasn’t worked for the working people of this nation for too long.  <br><br>For the past 40 years we were told that if we gave tax breaks to those at the very top, the benefits would trickle down to everyone else. <br><br>But that trickle-down theory led to weaker economic growth, lower wages, bigger deficits, and the widest gap between those at the top and everyone else in nearly a century. <br><br>Vice President Harris and I ran for office with a new economic vision for America. <br><br>Invest in America. Educate Americans. Grow the workforce. Build the economy from the bottom up  <br>and the middle out, not from the top down.  <br><br>Because we know that when the middle class grows, the poor have a ladder up and the wealthy do very well. <br><br>America used to have the best roads, bridges, and airports on Earth. <br><br>Now our infrastructure is ranked 13<sup>th</sup> in the world. <br><br>We won’t be able to compete for the jobs of the 21<sup>st</sup> Century if we don’t fix that. <br><br>That’s why it was so important to pass the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law—the most sweeping investment to rebuild America in history. <br><br>This was a bipartisan effort, and I want to thank the members of both parties who worked to make it happen. <br><br>We’re done talking about infrastructure weeks. <br><br>We’re going to have an infrastructure decade. <br><br>It is going to transform America and put us on a path to win the economic competition of the 21st Century that we face with the rest of the world—particularly with China.  <br><br>As I’ve told Xi Jinping, it is never a good bet to bet against the American people. <br><br>We’ll create good jobs for millions of Americans, modernizing roads, airports, ports, and waterways all across America. <br><br>And we’ll do it all to withstand the devastating effects of the climate crisis and promote environmental justice. <br><br>We’ll build a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations, begin to replace poisonous lead pipes—so every child—and every American—has clean water to drink at home and at school, provide affordable high-speed internet for every American—urban, suburban, rural, and tribal communities. <br><br>4,000 projects have already been announced. <br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing that this year we will start fixing over 65,000 miles of highway and 1,500 bridges in disrepair. <br><br>When we use taxpayer dollars to rebuild America – we are going to Buy American: buy American products to support American jobs. <br><br>The federal government spends about $600 Billion a year to keep the country safe and secure. <br><br>There’s been a law on the books for almost a century <br>to make sure taxpayers’ dollars support American jobs and businesses. <br><br>Every Administration says they’ll do it, but we are actually doing it. <br><br>We will buy American to make sure everything from the deck of an aircraft carrier to the steel on highway guardrails are made in America. <br><br>But to compete for the best jobs of the future, we also need to level the playing field with China and other competitors. <br><br>That’s why it is so important to pass the Bipartisan Innovation Act sitting in Congress that will make record investments in emerging technologies and American manufacturing. <br><br>Let me give you one example of why it’s so important to pass it. <br><br>If you travel 20 miles east of Columbus, Ohio, you’ll find 1,000 empty acres of land. <br><br>It won’t look like much, but if you stop and look closely, you’ll see a “Field of dreams,” the ground on which America’s future will be built. <br><br>This is where Intel, the American company that helped build Silicon Valley, is going to build its $20 billion semiconductor “mega site”. <br><br>Up to eight state-of-the-art factories in one place. 10,000 new good-paying jobs. <br><br>Some of the most sophisticated manufacturing in the world to make computer chips the size of a fingertip that power the world and our everyday lives. <br><br>Smartphones. The Internet. Technology we have yet to invent. <br><br>But that’s just the beginning. <br><br>Intel’s CEO, Pat Gelsinger, who is here tonight, told me they are ready to increase their investment from  <br>$20 billion to $100 billion. <br><br>That would be one of the biggest investments in manufacturing in American history. <br><br>And all they’re waiting for is for you to pass this bill. <br><br>So let’s not wait any longer. Send it to my desk. I’ll sign it.  <br><br>And we will really take off. <br><br>And Intel is not alone. <br><br>There’s something happening in America. <br><br>Just look around and you’ll see an amazing story. <br><br>The rebirth of the pride that comes from stamping products “Made In America.&#8221; The revitalization of American manufacturing.   <br><br>Companies are choosing to build new factories here, when just a few years ago, they would have built them overseas. <br><br>That’s what is happening. Ford is investing $11 billion to build electric vehicles, creating 11,000 jobs across the country. <br><br>GM is making the largest investment in its history—$7 billion to build electric vehicles, creating 4,000 jobs in Michigan. <br><br>All told, we created 369,000 new manufacturing jobs in America just last year. <br><br>Powered by people I’ve met like JoJo Burgess, from generations of union steelworkers from Pittsburgh, who’s here with us tonight. <br><br>As Ohio Senator Sherrod Brown says, “It’s time to bury the label “Rust Belt.” <br><br>It’s time. <br><br>But with all the bright spots in our economy, record job growth and higher wages, too many families are struggling to keep up with the bills.  <br><br>Inflation is robbing them of the gains they might otherwise feel. <br><br>I get it. That’s why my top priority is getting prices under control. <br><br>Look, our economy roared back faster than most predicted, but the pandemic meant that businesses had a hard time hiring enough workers to keep up production in their factories. <br><br>The pandemic also disrupted global supply chains. <br><br>When factories close, it takes longer to make goods and get them from the warehouse to the store, and prices go up. <br><br>Look at cars. <br><br>Last year, there weren’t enough semiconductors to make all the cars that people wanted to buy. <br><br>And guess what, prices of automobiles went up. <br><br>So—we have a choice. <br><br>One way to fight inflation is to drive down wages and make Americans poorer.  <br><br>I have a better plan to fight inflation. <br><br>Lower your costs, not your wages. <br><br>Make more cars and semiconductors in America. <br><br>More infrastructure and innovation in America. <br><br>More goods moving faster and cheaper in America. <br><br>More jobs where you can earn a good living in America. <br><br>And instead of relying on foreign supply chains, let’s make it in America. <br><br>Economists call it “increasing the productive capacity of our economy.” <br><br>I call it building a better America. <br><br>My plan to fight inflation will lower your costs and lower the deficit. <br><br>17 Nobel laureates in economics say my plan will ease long-term inflationary pressures. Top business leaders and most Americans support my plan. And here’s the plan: <br><br>First – cut the cost of prescription drugs. Just look at insulin. One in ten Americans has diabetes. In Virginia, I met a 13-year-old boy named Joshua Davis.  <br><br>He and his Dad both have Type 1 diabetes, which means they need insulin every day. Insulin costs about $10 a vial to make.  <br><br>But drug companies charge families like Joshua and his Dad up to 30 times more. I spoke with Joshua’s mom. <br><br>Imagine what it’s like to look at your child who needs insulin and have no idea how you’re going to pay for it.  <br><br>What it does to your dignity, your ability to look your child in the eye, to be the parent you expect to be. <br><br>Joshua is here with us tonight. Yesterday was his birthday. Happy birthday, buddy.  <br><br>For Joshua, and for the 200,000 other young people with Type 1 diabetes, let’s cap the cost of insulin at $35 a month so everyone can afford it.  <br><br>Drug companies will still do very well. And while we’re at it let Medicare negotiate lower prices for prescription drugs, like the VA already does. <br><br>Look, the American Rescue Plan is helping millions of families on Affordable Care Act plans save $2,400 a year on their health care premiums. Let’s close the coverage gap and make those savings permanent. <br><br>Second &#8211; cut energy costs for families an average of $500 a year by combatting climate change.  <br><br>Let’s provide investments and tax credits to weatherize your homes and businesses to be energy efficient and you get a tax credit; double America’s clean energy production in solar, wind, and so much more;  lower the price of electric vehicles, saving you another $80 a month because you’ll never have to pay at the gas pump again. <br><br>Third – cut the cost of child care. Many families pay up to $14,000 a year for child care per child.  <br><br>Middle-class and working families shouldn’t have to pay more than 7% of their income for care of young children.  <br><br>My plan will cut the cost in half for most families and help parents, including millions of women, who left the workforce during the pandemic because they couldn’t afford child care, to be able to get back to work. <br><br>My plan doesn’t stop there. It also includes home and long-term care. More affordable housing. And Pre-K for every 3- and 4-year-old.  <br><br>All of these will lower costs. <br><br>And under my plan, nobody earning less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional penny in new taxes. Nobody.  <br><br>The one thing all Americans agree on is that the tax system is not fair. We have to fix it.  <br><br>I’m not looking to punish anyone. But let’s make sure corporations and the wealthiest Americans start paying their fair share. <br><br>Just last year, 55 Fortune 500 corporations earned $40 billion in profits and paid zero dollars in federal income tax.  <br><br>That’s simply not fair. That’s why I’ve proposed a 15% minimum tax rate for corporations. <br><br>We got more than 130 countries to agree on a global minimum tax rate so companies can’t get out of paying their taxes at home by shipping jobs and factories overseas. <br><br>That’s why I’ve proposed closing loopholes so the very wealthy don’t pay a lower tax rate than a teacher or a firefighter.  <br><br>So that’s my plan. It will grow the economy and lower costs for families. <br><br>So what are we waiting for? Let’s get this done. And while you’re at it, confirm my nominees to the Federal Reserve, which plays a critical role in fighting inflation.  <br><br>My plan will not only lower costs to give families a fair shot, it will lower the deficit. <br><br>The previous Administration not only ballooned the deficit with tax cuts for the very wealthy and corporations, it undermined the watchdogs whose job was to keep pandemic relief funds from being wasted. <br><br>But in my administration, the watchdogs have been welcomed back. <br><br>We’re going after the criminals who stole billions in relief money meant for small businesses and millions of Americans.  <br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing that the Justice Department will name a chief prosecutor for pandemic fraud. <br><br>By the end of this year, the deficit will be down to less than half what it was before I took office.  <br><br>The only president ever to cut the deficit by more than one trillion dollars in a single year. <br><br>Lowering your costs also means demanding more competition. <br><br>I’m a capitalist, but capitalism without competition isn’t capitalism. <br><br>It’s exploitation—and it drives up prices. <br><br>When corporations don’t have to compete, their profits go up, your prices go up, and small businesses and family farmers and ranchers go under. <br><br>We see it happening with ocean carriers moving goods in and out of America. <br><br>During the pandemic, these foreign-owned companies raised prices by as much as 1,000% and made record profits. <br><br>Tonight, I’m announcing a crackdown on these companies overcharging American businesses and consumers. <br><br>And as Wall Street firms take over more nursing homes, quality in those homes has gone down and costs have gone up.  <br><br>That ends on my watch. <br><br>Medicare is going to set higher standards for nursing homes and make sure your loved ones get the care they deserve and expect. <br><br>We’ll also cut costs and keep the economy going strong by giving workers a fair shot, provide more training and apprenticeships, hire them based on their skills not degrees. <br><br>Let’s pass the Paycheck Fairness Act and paid leave.  <br><br>Raise the minimum wage to $15 an hour and extend the Child Tax Credit, so no one has to raise a family in poverty. <br><br>Let’s increase Pell Grants and increase our historic support of HBCUs, and invest in what Jill—our First Lady who teaches full-time—calls America’s best-kept secret: community colleges. <br><br>And let’s pass the PRO Act when a majority of workers want to form a union—they shouldn’t be stopped.  <br><br>When we invest in our workers, when we build the economy from the bottom up and the middle out together, we can do something we haven’t done in a long time: build a better America. <br><br>For more than two years, COVID-19 has impacted every decision in our lives and the life of the nation. <br><br>And I know you’re tired, frustrated, and exhausted. <br><br>But I also know this. <br><br>Because of the progress we’ve made, because of your resilience and the tools we have, tonight I can say  <br>we are moving forward safely, back to more normal routines.  <br><br>We’ve reached a new moment in the fight against COVID-19, with severe cases down to a level not seen since last July.  <br><br>Just a few days ago, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention—the CDC—issued new mask guidelines. <br><br>Under these new guidelines, most Americans in most of the country can now be mask free.   <br><br>And based on the projections, more of the country will reach that point across the next couple of weeks. <br><br>Thanks to the progress we have made this past year, COVID-19 need no longer control our lives.  <br><br>I know some are talking about “living with COVID-19”. Tonight – I say that we will never just accept living with COVID-19. <br><br>We will continue to combat the virus as we do other diseases. And because this is a virus that mutates and spreads, we will stay on guard. <br><br>Here are four common sense steps as we move forward safely.  <br><br>First, stay protected with vaccines and treatments. We know how incredibly effective vaccines are. If you’re vaccinated and boosted you have the highest degree of protection. <br><br>We will never give up on vaccinating more Americans. Now, I know parents with kids under 5 are eager to see a vaccine authorized for their children. <br><br>The scientists are working hard to get that done and we’ll be ready with plenty of vaccines when they do. <br><br>We’re also ready with anti-viral treatments. If you get COVID-19, the Pfizer pill reduces your chances of ending up in the hospital by 90%.  <br><br>We’ve ordered more of these pills than anyone in the world. And Pfizer is working overtime to get us 1 Million pills this month and more than double that next month.  <br><br>And we’re launching the “Test to Treat” initiative so people can get tested at a pharmacy, and if they’re positive, receive antiviral pills on the spot at no cost.  <br><br>If you’re immunocompromised or have some other vulnerability, we have treatments and free high-quality masks. <br><br>We’re leaving no one behind or ignoring anyone’s needs as we move forward. <br><br>And on testing, we have made hundreds of millions of tests available for you to order for free.   <br><br>Even if you already ordered free tests tonight, I am announcing that you can order more from covidtests.gov starting next week. <br><br>Second – we must prepare for new variants. Over the past year, we’ve gotten much better at detecting new variants. <br><br>If necessary, we’ll be able to deploy new vaccines within 100 days instead of many more months or years.  <br><br>And, if Congress provides the funds we need, we’ll have new stockpiles of tests, masks, and pills ready if needed. <br><br>I cannot promise a new variant won’t come. But I can promise you we’ll do everything within our power to be ready if it does.  <br><br>Third – we can end the shutdown of schools and businesses. We have the tools we need. <br><br>It’s time for Americans to get back to work and fill our great downtowns again.  People working from home can feel safe to begin to return to the office.   <br><br>We’re doing that here in the federal government. The vast majority of federal workers will once again work in person. <br><br>Our schools are open. Let’s keep it that way. Our kids need to be in school. <br><br>And with 75% of adult Americans fully vaccinated and hospitalizations down by 77%, most Americans can remove their masks, return to work, stay in the classroom, and move forward safely. <br><br>We achieved this because we provided free vaccines, treatments, tests, and masks. <br><br>Of course, continuing this costs money. <br><br>I will soon send Congress a request. <br><br>The vast majority of Americans have used these tools and may want to again, so I expect Congress to pass it quickly.   <br><br>Fourth, we will continue vaccinating the world.     <br><br>We’ve sent 475 Million vaccine doses to 112 countries, more than any other nation. <br><br>And we won’t stop. <br><br>We have lost so much to COVID-19. Time with one another. And worst of all, so much loss of life. <br><br>Let’s use this moment to reset. Let’s stop looking at COVID-19 as a partisan dividing line and see it for what it is: A God-awful disease.  <br><br>Let’s stop seeing each other as enemies, and start seeing each other for who we really are: Fellow Americans.  <br><br>We can’t change how divided we’ve been. But we can change how we move forward—on COVID-19 and other issues we must face together. <br><br>I recently visited the New York City Police Department days after the funerals of Officer Wilbert Mora and his partner, Officer Jason Rivera. <br><br>They were responding to a 9-1-1 call when a man shot and killed them with a stolen gun. <br><br>Officer Mora was 27 years old. <br><br>Officer Rivera was 22. <br><br>Both Dominican Americans who’d grown up on the same streets they later chose to patrol as police officers. <br><br>I spoke with their families and told them that we are forever in debt for their sacrifice, and we will carry on their mission to restore the trust and safety every community deserves. <br><br>I’ve worked on these issues a long time. <br><br>I know what works: Investing in crime preventionand community police officers who’ll walk the beat, who’ll know the neighborhood, and who can restore trust and safety. <br><br>So let’s not abandon our streets. Or choose between safety and equal justice. <br><br>Let’s come together to protect our communities, restore trust, and hold law enforcement accountable. <br><br>That’s why the Justice Department required body cameras, banned chokeholds, and restricted no-knock warrants for its officers. <br><br>That’s why the American Rescue Plan provided $350 Billion that cities, states, and counties can use to hire more police and invest in proven strategies like community violence interruption—trusted messengers breaking the cycle of violence and trauma and giving young people hope.  <br><br>We should all agree: The answer is not to Defund the police. The answer is to FUND the police with the resources and training they need to protect our communities. <br><br>I ask Democrats and Republicans alike: Pass my budget and keep our neighborhoods safe.  <br><br>And I will keep doing everything in my power to crack down on gun trafficking and ghost guns you can buy online and make at home—they have no serial numbers and can’t be traced. <br><br>And I ask Congress to pass proven measures to reduce gun violence. Pass universal background checks. Why should anyone on a terrorist list be able to purchase a weapon? <br><br>Ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines. <br><br>Repeal the liability shield that makes gun manufacturers the only industry in America that can’t be sued. <br><br>These laws don’t infringe on the Second Amendment. They save lives. <br><br>The most fundamental right in America is the right to vote – and to have it counted. And it’s under assault. <br><br>In state after state, new laws have been passed, not only to suppress the vote, but to subvert entire elections. <br><br>We cannot let this happen. <br><br>Tonight. I call on the Senate to: Pass the Freedom to Vote Act. Pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act. And while you’re at it, pass the Disclose Act so Americans can know who is funding our elections. <br><br>Tonight, I’d like to honor someone who has dedicated his life to serve this country: Justice Stephen Breyer—an Army veteran, Constitutional scholar, and retiring Justice of the United States Supreme Court. Justice Breyer, thank you for your service. <br><br>One of the most serious constitutional responsibilities a President has is nominating someone to serve on the United States Supreme Court. <br><br>And I did that 4 days ago, when I nominated Circuit Court of Appeals Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson. One of our nation’s top legal minds, who will continue Justice Breyer’s legacy of excellence. <br><br>A former top litigator in private practice. A former federal public defender. And from a family of public school educators and police officers. A consensus builder. Since she’s been nominated, she’s received a broad range of support—from the Fraternal Order of Police to former judges appointed by Democrats and Republicans. <br><br>And if we are to advance liberty and justice, we need to secure the Border and fix the immigration system. <br><br>We can do both. At our border, we’ve installed new technology like cutting-edge scanners to better detect drug smuggling.  <br><br>We’ve set up joint patrols with Mexico and Guatemala to catch more human traffickers.  <br><br>We’re putting in place dedicated immigration judges so families fleeing persecution and violence can have their cases heard faster. <br><br>We’re securing commitments and supporting partners in South and Central America to host more refugees and secure their own borders. <br><br>We can do all this while keeping lit the torch of liberty that has led generations of immigrants to this land—my forefathers and so many of yours. <br><br>Provide a pathway to citizenship for Dreamers, those on temporary status, farm workers, and essential workers. <br><br>Revise our laws so businesses have the workers they need and families don’t wait decades to reunite. <br><br>It’s not only the right thing to do—it’s the economically smart thing to do. <br><br>That’s why immigration reform is supported by everyone from labor unions to religious leaders to the U.S. Chamber of Commerce. <br><br>Let’s get it done once and for all. <br><br>Advancing liberty and justice also requires protecting the rights of women. <br><br>The constitutional right affirmed in Roe v. Wade—standing precedent for half a century—is under attack as never before. <br><br>If we want to go forward—not backward—we must protect access to health care. Preserve a woman’s right to choose. And let’s continue to advance maternal health care in America. <br><br>And for our LGBTQ+ Americans, let’s finally get the bipartisan Equality Act to my desk. The onslaught of state laws targeting transgender Americans and their families is wrong. <br><br>As I said last year, especially to our younger transgender Americans, I will always have your back as your President, so you can be yourself and reach your God-given potential. <br><br>While it often appears that we never agree, that isn’t true. I signed 80 bipartisan bills into law last year. From preventing government shutdowns to protecting Asian-Americans from still-too-common hate crimes to reforming military justice. <br><br>And soon, we’ll strengthen the Violence Against Women Act that I first wrote three decades ago. It is important for us to show the nation that we can come together and do big things. <br><br>So tonight I’m offering a Unity Agenda for the Nation. Four big things we can do together.  <br><br>First, beat the opioid epidemic. <br><br>There is so much we can do. Increase funding for prevention, treatment, harm reduction, and recovery.  <br><br>Get rid of outdated rules that stop doctors from prescribing treatments. And stop the flow of illicit drugs by working with state and local law enforcement to go after traffickers. <br><br>If you’re suffering from addiction, know you are not alone. I believe in recovery, and I celebrate the 23 million Americans in recovery. <br><br>Second, let’s take on mental health. Especially among our children, whose lives and education have been turned upside down.  <br><br>The American Rescue Plan gave schools money to hire teachers and help students make up for lost learning.  <br><br>I urge every parent to make sure your school does just that. And we can all play a part—sign up to be a tutor or a mentor. <br><br>Children were also struggling before the pandemic. Bullying, violence, trauma, and the harms of social media. <br><br>As Frances Haugen, who is here with us tonight, has shown, we must hold social media platforms accountable for the national experiment they’re conducting on our children for profit. <br><br>It’s time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children, demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children. <br><br>And let’s get all Americans the mental health services they need. More people they can turn to for help, and full parity between physical and mental health care. <br><br>Third, support our veterans. <br><br>Veterans are the best of us. <br><br>I’ve always believed that we have a sacred obligation to equip all those we send to war and care for them and their families when they come home. <br><br>My administration is providing assistance with job training and housing, and now helping lower-income veterans get VA care debt-free.  <br><br>Our troops in Iraq and Afghanistan faced many dangers. <br><br>One was stationed at bases and breathing in toxic smoke from “burn pits&#8221; that incinerated wastes of war—medical and hazard material, jet fuel, and more. <br><br>When they came home, many of the world’s fittest and best trained warriors were never the same. <br><br>Headaches. Numbness. Dizziness. <br><br>A cancer that would put them in a flag-draped coffin. <br><br>I know. <br><br>One of those soldiers was my son Major Beau Biden. <br><br>We don’t know for sure if a burn pit was the cause of his brain cancer, or the diseases of so many of our troops. <br><br>But I’m committed to finding out everything we can. <br><br>Committed to military families like Danielle Robinson from Ohio. <br><br>The widow of Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson.  <br><br>He was born a soldier. Army National Guard. Combat medic in Kosovo and Iraq. <br><br>Stationed near Baghdad, just yards from burn pits the size of football fields. <br><br>Heath’s widow Danielle is here with us tonight. They loved going to Ohio State football games. He loved building Legos with their daughter. <br><br>But cancer from prolonged exposure to burn pits ravaged Heath’s lungs and body. <br><br>Danielle says Heath was a fighter to the very end. <br><br>He didn’t know how to stop fighting, and neither did she. <br><br>Through her pain she found purpose to demand we do better. <br><br>Tonight, Danielle—we are. <br><br>The VA is pioneering new ways of linking toxic exposures to diseases, already helping more veterans get benefits. <br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing we&#8217;re expanding eligibility to veterans suffering from nine respiratory cancers. <br><br>I’m also calling on Congress: pass a law to make sure veterans devastated by toxic exposures in Iraq and Afghanistan finally get the benefits and comprehensive health care they deserve. <br><br>And fourth, let’s end cancer as we know it. <br><br>This is personal to me and Jill, to Kamala, and to so many of you. <br><br>Cancer is the #2 cause of death in America–second only to heart disease. <br><br>Last month, I announced our plan to supercharge  <br>the Cancer Moonshot that President Obama asked me to lead six years ago. <br><br>Our goal is to cut the cancer death rate by at least 50% over the next 25 years, turn more cancers from death sentences into treatable diseases.  <br><br>More support for patients and families. <br><br>To get there, I call on Congress to fund ARPA-H, the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health. <br><br>It’s based on DARPA—the Defense Department project that led to the Internet, GPS, and so much more.  <br><br>ARPA-H will have a singular purpose—to drive breakthroughs in cancer, Alzheimer’s, diabetes, and more. <br><br>A unity agenda for the nation. <br><br>We can do this. <br><br>My fellow Americans—tonight , we have gathered in a sacred space—the citadel of our democracy. <br><br>In this Capitol, generation after generation, Americans have debated great questions amid great strife, and have done great things. <br><br>We have fought for freedom, expanded liberty, defeated totalitarianism and terror. <br><br>And built the strongest, freest, and most prosperous nation the world has ever known. <br><br>Now is the hour. <br><br>Our moment of responsibility. <br><br>Our test of resolve and conscience, of history itself. <br><br>It is in this moment that our character is formed. Our purpose is found. Our future is forged. <br><br>Well I know this nation.  <br><br>We will meet the test. <br><br>To protect freedom and liberty, to expand fairness and opportunity. <br><br>We will save democracy. <br><br>As hard as these times have been, I am more optimistic about America today than I have been my whole life. <br><br>Because I see the future that is within our grasp. <br><br>Because I know there is simply nothing beyond our capacity. <br><br>We are the only nation on Earth that has always turned every crisis we have faced into an opportunity. <br><br>The only nation that can be defined by a single word: possibilities. <br><br>So on this night, in our 245<sup>th</sup> year as a nation, I have come to report on the State of the Union. <br><br>And my report is this: the State of the Union is strong—because you, the American people, are strong. <br><br>We are stronger today than we were a year ago. <br><br>And we will be stronger a year from now than we are today. <br><br>Now is our moment to meet and overcome the challenges of our time. <br><br>And we will, as one people. <br><br>One America. <br><br>The United States of America. <br><br>May God bless you all. May God protect our troops. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: President&#160;Biden to Announce New Steps to Combat Criminal Fraud and Identity Theft in Pandemic Relief&#160;Programs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-announce-new-steps-to-combat-criminal-fraud-and-identity-theft-in-pandemic-relief-programs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of an ongoing Administration-wide effort to prevent, deter, and punish identity theft and other forms of pandemic fraud by serious criminal syndicates, the President will announce in the State of the Union tonight: The DOJ Will Appoint a Chief Prosecutor to Focus on the Most Egregious Forms of Pandemic Fraud Including Identity Theft&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As part of an ongoing Administration-wide effort to prevent, deter, and punish identity theft and other forms of pandemic fraud by serious criminal syndicates, the President will announce in the State of the Union tonight:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>The DOJ Will Appoint a Chief Prosecutor to Focus on the Most Egregious Forms of Pandemic Fraud Including Identity Theft by Criminal Syndicates:</u></strong>&nbsp;The Department of Justice’s (DOJ) COVID-19 Fraud Enforcement Task Force will expand its already robust efforts by appointing a Chief Prosecutor to lead teams of specialized prosecutors and agents focusing on major targets of pandemic fraud, such as those committing large-scale identity theft, including foreign-based actors. These strike force teams will also use state-of-the-art data analytics tools to connect the dots on identity theft and other complex fraud schemes committed across state lines or transnationally, as well as investigate major cases of criminal fraud in programs like the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) and Unemployment Insurance (UI).</li><li><strong><u>Heightened Resources and Enhanced Penalties for Egregious Pandemic Fraud in Areas Like PPP Loans and UI:</u></strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong>The President will call on Congress to provide the resources needed for the DOJ Task Force to expand prosecutions of egregious pandemic fraud, including in support of the strike force teams. The DOJ has already successfully prosecuted scores of cases where individuals fraudulently obtained loans from PPP meant for small businesses facing threats of layoffs and closure due to the pandemic, and where identity thieves stole unemployment insurance benefits meant for those who lost their jobs through no fault of their own. These criminal abuses took place at the same time that front-line essential workers were risking their lives to help us all get through the crisis. The Administration will call on Congress to heighten the penalties for criminals who commit egregious pandemic fraud.&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Executive Order on Preventing Identity Theft in Public Benefits Programs:</u></strong>&nbsp;In the coming weeks, the President will announce a new Executive Order with broad government-wide directives, building on steps taken in 2021, to prevent and detect identity theft involving public benefits, while protecting privacy and civil liberties and preventing bias that results in disparate outcomes.&nbsp;&nbsp;The EO will also direct new actions to support the victims of identity fraud.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Building on Existing Efforts&nbsp;to Crack Down on COVID-19 Fraud and Serious Identity Theft of Public Benefits:</u></strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong>The dramatic outpouring of pandemic relief in 2020 saw an expansion of foreign and domestic criminal syndicates defrauding unemployment insurance and other benefits programs to&nbsp;rob American taxpayers of billions of dollars that should have gone to support deserving small businesses and workers who had lost their jobs. The Federal Trade Commission reported a 3000% increase in reports of identity theft involving public benefits from 2019 to 2020. The Administration has taken significant actions already to respond to this inherited fraud.</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Interagency COVID-19 Fraud Enforcement Task Force:</u> </strong>In May 2021,<strong> </strong>the President welcomed the Attorney General Merrick B. Garland’s announcement that the DOJ had launched the COVID-19 Fraud Enforcement Task Force to prosecute and recover stolen funds from domestic and international criminals exploiting pandemic relief programs. The Task Force, which is organized and led by the Deputy Attorney General Lisa O. Monaco, includes nearly 30 agencies that administer and oversee pandemic relief funding, such as the Department of Justice, the Department of Labor, the Department of the Treasury, the Small Business Administration, the U.S. Postal Inspection Service, and the Pandemic Response Accountability Committee (PRAC). So far, members of the Task Force have charged over<em> </em>1,000 criminal cases and opened over 200 civil investigations across 1800 individuals and entities, together involving billions of dollars in suspected fraud. The Task Force will appoint a Chief Prosecutor to lead investigations and prosecutions on identity theft and other egregious patterns of pandemic fraud.  </li><li><strong><u>Initiative on Identity Theft Prevention and Public Benefits:</u></strong> On May 17, 2021, President Biden called for the ARP Coordinator and Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the National Security Council (NSC), PRAC, Inspectors General, and the U.S. Government Accountability Office (GAO) to take government-wide steps to prevent individuals from defrauding public benefits programs. This Initiative, working together with the cybersecurity team of the NSC, will be making government-wide recommendations as part of the President’s forthcoming Executive Order on preventing and detecting identity theft involving public benefits, while protecting privacy and civil liberties and preventing bias that results in disparate outcomes.  The Executive Order will also direct new actions to support victims of identity fraud. </li><li><strong><u>Re-established Respect for and Transparency with Oversight Community</u></strong>: This Administration has sought to re-establish respect and cooperation with the oversight community. The White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator meets weekly with the PRAC, bi-weekly with leadership at the GAO, and has held over 20 “Gold Standard” meetings across federal agencies, where agency officials discuss integrity controls with their Inspector General and PRAC leadership before programs are launched. This Administration has worked collaboratively to implement many recommendations from the oversight community, including strengthening controls for small business loan programs and directing multi-state data sharing to detect and fight UI fraud, while also screening a record number of benefits payments in programs across the government for potential fraud. The White House Infrastructure Coordinator has also met with all the relevant Inspectors General impacted by the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act and committed to working closely together on fraud prevention efforts.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: President&#160;Biden’s Historic Actions to Make Our Communities Safer by Reducing Gun&#160;Crime</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-bidens-historic-actions-to-make-our-communities-safer-by-reducing-gun-crime/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 23:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In his 2022 State of the Union Address, President Biden will highlight how his Administration is executing on his comprehensive strategy to make our communities safer and reduce gun crime. The President’s comprehensive strategy advances two foundational policies – investing in crime prevention and helping cities and towns hire additional community police officers to walk&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In his 2022 State of the Union Address, President Biden will highlight how his Administration is executing on his comprehensive strategy to make our communities safer and reduce gun crime. The President’s comprehensive strategy advances two foundational policies – investing in crime prevention and helping cities and towns hire additional community police officers to walk the streets, get to know their neighbors, and restore trust and safety. These are the two foundational policies that then-Senator Biden advanced when the United States faced record crime rates in the 1990s. At that time, he wrote a law to change how our country fights crime. We then experienced the sharpest drop in crime on record.</p>



<p><br>President Biden recognizes the important role that law enforcement plays in stopping the interstate flow of guns used in crimes and taking off our streets the small number of individuals responsible for a disproportionate amount of gun crimes. To support state and local law enforcement, the U.S. Department of Justice has launched five gun trafficking strike forces and is cracking down on the “Iron Pipeline” – the illegal flow of guns sold in the south, transported up the East Coast, and found at crime scenes in cities from Baltimore to New York City. In addition, the Justice Department has directed every U.S. Attorney’s Office nationwide to increase resources dedicated to district specific violent crime strategies. The Justice Department is working with state and local law enforcement to address the most significant drivers of violence in each district, including to get repeat gun violence offenders off of our streets. New&nbsp;York City’s Gun Violence Strategic Partnership – which the President and Attorney General visited in February 2022 – is one model of the strategies Justice will help expand nationwide.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>The President is committed to serving as a strong partner for state and local law enforcement on the frontlines of the fight against crime. That’s why his American Rescue Plan gives cities and states historic levels of funding that they can use to put more cops on the beat for community policing. That’s also why the President continues to urge Congress to act on his $300 million budget request to more than double the size of the Department of Justice’s COPS community policing grant program.</p>



<p>Stronger law enforcement is made more effective when we make real investments in making our communities stronger and in addressing the causes of crime before it spills over into violence. That’s why President Biden’s comprehensive approach makes sure cities and states have the funding, training, and know-how they need to invest in proven tactics including street outreach by credible messengers, hospital-based intervention, and youth programming. And it’s bolstered by additional funding to create economic opportunity with job training, expand after-school activities, and provide stable housing and other stabilizing supports necessary to reduce recidivism and help formerly incarcerated individuals reenter their communities. The President has proposed a $5 billion investment in community violence interventions, including a $200 million investment in Fiscal Year 2022.</p>



<p><br>Taken together, President Biden’s gun crime reduction strategy steps up and focuses law enforcement efforts on violent offenders, stems the trafficking of illegal guns, and makes real investments in communities to intervene in and prevent gun violence. The President knows a complex and devastating challenge like the surge of gun crime we’ve seen over the last two years requires an ambitious, evidence-based response that uses every tool at our disposal, and that’s exactly what his plan does.</p>



<p>At the same time, President Biden will use the State of the Union Address to reiterate his call for Congress to pass commonsense gun violence prevention legislation that will save lives. This legislation, which fully aligns with the Second Amendment, includes requiring background checks for all gun sales, ensuring that no terrorist can buy a weapon in the United States, banning assault weapons and high capacity magazines, repealing gun manufacturers’ protection from liability, and banning ghost guns.</p>



<p><strong>EXECUTING ON THE PRESIDENT’S COMPREHENSIVE GUN CRIME REDUCTION STRATEGY</strong></p>



<p>President Biden spent his first year in office executing on his <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">five-part comprehensive strategy</a> make our communities safer and reduce gun crime, which:</p>



<ul><li>Stems the flow of firearms used to commit violence,</li><li>Supports local law enforcement with federal tools and resources to address violent crime,</li><li>Invests in evidence-based community violence interventions,</li><li>Expands summer programming, employment opportunities, and other services and supports for teenagers and young adults, and</li><li>Helps formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities.</li></ul>



<p>In fact, during President Biden’s first year in office, the Biden-Harris Administration made more progress on executive actions to reduce gun violence than any other Administration has in its first year. Since taking office, President Biden has announced four packages of executive actions – <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/07/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initial-actions-to-address-the-gun-violence-public-health-epidemic/">an initial set of actions</a> during a Rose Garden address in April, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">a comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/02/fact-sheet-biden-administration-takes-steps-to-prevent-suicide-including-by-promoting-safe-storage-of-firearms/">steps to promote safe storage of firearms</a>, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/03/president-biden-announces-more-actions-to-reduce-gun-crime-and-calls-on-congress-to-fund-community-policing-and-community-violence-intervention/">additional Justice Department actions to enforce our gun laws and keep guns out of dangerous hands</a>. These executive actions represent a whole-of-government approach, mobilizing the Departments of Justice, Veterans Affairs, Defense, Transportation, Health and Human Services, Labor, Homeland Security, Education, and Housing and Urban Development toward the shared goal of reducing gun violence. Highlights of these actions include three significant Justice Department rulemakings, agency guidance encouraging the use of hundreds of billions of American Rescue Plan dollars for gun violence reduction, and historic progress to advance community violence interventions.</p>



<p><strong><em>Keeping Especially Dangerous Weapons and Repeat Shooters Off Our Streets</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Helping state and local law enforcement take repeat shooters off our streets. </strong>The Attorney General has directed every U.S. Attorney’s Office nationwide to increase resources dedicated to district specific violent crime strategies. The Justice Department will work with state and local law enforcement to address the most significant drivers of violence in each district, including to get repeat gun violence offenders off of our streets. &nbsp;New&nbsp;York City’s Gun Violence Strategic Partnership – which the President and Attorney General visited with Mayor Eric Adams in February 2022 – is one model of the strategies Justice will help expand nationwide.</p>



<p><strong>Reining in the proliferation of ghost guns. </strong>In May 2021, the Justice Department’s Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/05/21/2021-10058/definition-of-frame-or-receiver-and-identification-of-firearms">issued a proposed rule</a> to help stop the proliferation of “ghost guns,” which are unserialized, privately made firearms that are increasingly being recovered at crime scenes and have been identified by law enforcement officials as a serious threat to public safety. Today, criminals are buying kits containing nearly all of the components and directions for finishing a firearm within as little as 30 minutes and using these firearms to commit crimes. When these firearms turn up at crime scenes, they often cannot be traced by law enforcement due to the lack of a serial number – making it harder to catch the criminals behind shootings. ATF is reviewing public comments in response to the proposed rule, the next step in the regulatory process. In the meantime, the Justice Department launched a National Ghost Gun Enforcement Initiative, which will train a national cadre of prosecutors and disseminate investigation and prosecution tools to help bring cases against those who use ghost guns to commit crimes.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Better regulating devices marketed as stabilizing braces. </strong>In June 2021, ATF <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/06/10/2021-12176/factoring-criteria-for-firearms-with-attached-stabilizing-braces">issued a proposed rule</a> to better regulate when devices marketed as firearm stabilizing braces effectively turn pistols into short-barreled rifles subject to the National Firearms Act. These braces can make a firearm more stable and accurate while still being concealable. ATF is reviewing public comments in response to the proposed rule, the next step in the regulatory process.</p>



<p><strong><em>Keeping Guns out of the Wrong Hands</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Helping states enact model extreme risk protection order (“red flag”) legislation. </strong>In June 2021, the Justice Department <a href="https://www.justice.gov/doj/reducing-gun-violence/commentary-extreme-risk-protection-order-model-legislation">published model extreme risk protection order legislation</a> to make it easier for states that want to adopt these red flag laws to do so. These laws allow family members or law enforcement to petition for a court order temporarily barring people in crisis from accessing firearms if they present a danger to themselves or others.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Making progress on a report to give policymakers the information they need to help address firearms trafficking. </strong>In April 2021, the Justice Department announced that it will issue a new, comprehensive report on firearms commerce and trafficking and annual updates necessary to give policymakers the information they need to help address firearms trafficking today. To ensure the report is rigorous and helpful for policymakers, ATF has assembled a group of accomplished researchers and law enforcement subject matter experts. The academic team is currently undertaking such work as an independent analysis of ATF firearms commerce data to ensure accurate research that informs key policy findings and recommendations, and an analysis of technological developments over the past twenty years, including the use of polymers for the modular manufacture of firearms, the evolution of 3D printing of firearm components, and the pervasive availability of kits on the commercial market, facilitating the assembly of privately made firearms.</p>



<p><strong>Established zero tolerance for rogue gun dealers that willfully violate the law. </strong>In June 2021, the Justice Department announced a new policy to underscore zero tolerance for willful violations of the law by federally licensed firearms dealers that put public safety at risk. Absent extraordinary circumstances that would need to be justified to the Director, ATF will seek to revoke the licenses of dealers the first time that they violate federal law by willfully 1) transferring a firearm to a prohibited person, 2) failing to run a required background check, 3) falsifying records, such as a firearms transaction form, 4) failing to respond to an ATF tracing request, or 5) refusing to permit ATF to conduct an inspection in violation of the law.</p>



<p><strong>Launched multijurisdictional firearms trafficking strike forces.&nbsp;</strong>In July 2021, the Justice Department launched five new law enforcement strike forces focused on addressing significant firearms trafficking corridors that have diverted guns to New York, Chicago, Los Angeles, the Bay Area, and Washington, D.C. Those strike forces have already opened more than 540 investigations and taken custody of almost 3,100 crime guns. In February 2022, the Justice Department built on this commitment by announcing that it is cracking down on the “Iron Pipeline” – the illegal flow of guns sold in the south, transported up the East Coast, and found at crime scenes in cities from Baltimore to New York City – and other firearms trafficking by adding personnel and other resources to strengthen these strike forces.</p>



<p><strong>Launched a public education campaign to encourage firearm safe storage</strong>. In September, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) launched a new paid media campaign featuring a series of public service announcements to reinforce the key message that a simple gun lock can save lives. These PSAs appeared across multiple platforms, including TV, social media, and streaming services. The campaign also targeted specific venues and events and involved a diverse array of channels, yielding more than 1.8 billion impressions across all platforms in less than 3 months. Viewers were directed to KeepItSecure.net for additional resources. This campaign will continue through 2022.</p>



<p><strong>Launched an unprecedented focus on improving lethal means safety in the Military and Veteran Suicide Prevention Strategy.</strong> In November, the Departments of Defense (DOD), Health and Human Services (HHS), Homeland Security (DHS), Justice (DOJ), and Veterans Affairs (VA), as well as the Office of Emergency Medical Services within the Department of Transportation (DOT), announced that they will jointly create a plan for addressing lethal means safety awareness, education, training, and program evaluation. This coordinated campaign will build upon the VA launch in September and encourage safer storage practices, safety planning, and time and space behavioral measures for crisis response.</p>



<p><strong>Making it easier for customers to obtain secure gun storage or safety devices. </strong>In January 2022, ATF <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2022/01/04/2021-28398/secure-gun-storage-and-definition-of-antique-firearm#:~:text=This%20rule%20amends%20ATF%27s%20regulations%20to%20account%20for,are%20sold%20under%20the%20license%20to%20nonlicensed%20individuals.">issued</a> a final rule clarifying firearms dealers’ statutory obligations to make available for purchase compatible secure gun storage or safety devices. Additionally, ATF has now issued a best practices guide to all federal firearms dealers to reiterate the important steps they are legally required to take, and additional steps they are encouraged to take, to keep their customers and communities safe. The guide includes materials for Federal Firearms Licensees (FFLs) to distribute to customers to help them better understand their legal obligations as firearms owners, as well as practical steps they can take to facilitate the safe storage of firearms and keep firearms out of the hands of people prohibited from possessing firearms.</p>



<p><strong><em>Making Additional Progress to Reduce Community Violence</em></strong></p>



<p>Many actions listed above will directly reduce community violence disproportionately affecting Black and brown communities. The Administration has also taken a number of steps focused solely on advancing community violence interventions, proven strategies for reducing gun violence in urban communities. As part of his Build Back Better agenda, President Biden proposed $5 billion in funding for the Department of Justice and Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to invest in community violence interventions, evidence-based programs that are shown to help reduce violent crime. The President has proposed a $5 billion investment in community violence interventions, including a $200 million investment in Fiscal Year 2022.</p>



<p>But this Administration isn’t waiting on Congress to act; we have already invested in and expanded community violence interventions. These actions include:</p>



<p><strong>Investing historic levels of existing federal funding in community violence interventions, including American Rescue Plan funding. </strong>The Biden Administration made certain American Rescue Plan (ARP) funding – $350 billion in state and local funding, and $122 billion in K-12 funding – available as unprecedented resources for CVI. Senior White House advisors also issued a memo to state and local officials outlining how these elected leaders not only can – but should – use ARP funds for CVI. Cities across the country, such as Seattle, Washington; Buffalo, New York; and Atlanta, Georgia – have responded to this call by committing and deploying ARP funds for CVI. In addition, five federal agencies made changes to 26 different programs to direct vital support to community violence intervention programs as quickly as possible. For example, the National Institutes of Health announced funding through its Firearm Injury and Mortality Prevention Research grants for four community violence programs – including a place-based strategy involving repurposing vacant lots in Detroit, an evaluation of READI Chicago, a burnout prevention program for violence interrupters in Chicago, and a hospital-based violence intervention program focused on youth in Virginia. The Justice Department announced $187 million for states and $85 million for localities through the Byrne JAG Program to support coordinated violence prevention and intervention; the Department explicitly encouraged the use of these funds for CVI. In September, the Department of Housing and Urban Development published a guide explaining to localities how Community Development Block Grants–a $3.4 billion annual funding stream–can be used to fund CVI strategies. The Department of Education released a letter to state school associations on how 21<sup>st</sup> Century Learning Centers funds and Student Support and Academic enrichment programs – both billion-dollar formula grant funding streams – can be used to fund CVI strategies in schools.</p>



<p><strong>Making progress on state legislation to allow Medicaid to support community violence interventions. </strong>The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services hosted a webinar and <a href="https://www.medicaid.gov/state-resource-center/downloads/allstatecall-20210427.pdf">published information</a> to educate states on how they can use Medicaid to reimburse certain community violence intervention programs, like Hospital-Based Violence Interventions. Last year, Connecticut and Illinois enacted legislation that allows Medicaid to reimburse providers for hospital-based violence prevention services – the first two states in the country to pursue this approach. According to reporting by <a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/2021/09/17/medicaid-funds-tapped-combat-rise-crime-gun-debate-stalls/8326102002/?gnt-cfr=1">USA Today</a>, “[t]he idea has been in the works for years, advocates say, but not until the Biden administration signaled that states could – and should – use Medicaid dollars to support these violence prevention programs have state lawmakers stepped up.”</p>



<p><strong>Using the White House’s convening power to support community violence interventions. </strong>In July 2021, senior White House staff <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/16/readout-of-first-meeting-of-white-house-community-violence-intervention-collaborative/">established</a> The White House Community Violence Intervention Collaborative, a 16-jurisdiction cohort of mayors, law enforcement, CVI experts, and philanthropic leaders committed to using American Rescue Plan funding or other public funding to increase investment in their community violence intervention infrastructure. The Collaborative is spending 18 months strengthening and scaling the jurisdictions’ community violence intervention infrastructure to reduce gun crime and promote public safety. National experts and federal agencies are providing training and technical assistance to help communities assess their existing public safety ecosystem, identify gaps, and build the capacity to expand programming that saves lives. White House staff continue to regularly work with the Collaborative.</p>



<p><strong><em>Providing Law Enforcement with the Tools and Resources They need to Reduce Gun Violence</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Deploying federal law enforcement to support local communities in addressing gun violence. </strong>As part of the Justice Department’s <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/attorney-general-merrick-b-garland-announces-new-effort-reduce-violent-crime">Comprehensive Strategy for Reducing Violent Crime</a>, the Justice Department has supported law enforcement in local communities in addressing gun violence. In particular, the Justice Department has provided enforcement support from the Federal Bureau of Investigations (FBI), ATF, Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), and United States Marshals Service (USMS). In Fiscal Year 2021 alone, the USMS partnered with over 1,700 state and local agencies through district and regional task forces, apprehended more than 84,000 fugitives including more than 6,000 murder suspects, and seized more than 7,000 firearms during numerous violence reduction and counter gang operations. In 2021, ATF embedded with homicide and shooting investigation units in police and sheriff’s departments in more than 60 communities across the country, and expanded the reach of its National NIBIN Correlation and Training Center to an additional 35 sites. ATF now provides ballistic matching services and generates leads for more than 1,400 local police departments nationwide. In 2021, FBI partnered with nearly 2,000 state and local officers as part of its Violent Crime Task Forces and Safe Streets Task Forces, which together have confiscated more than 5,000 illegal firearms. Finally, DEA has strong partnerships with state and local law enforcement – 4,600 of whom served as DEA task force officers in 2021, disrupting the activity of some of the most violent drug trafficking organizations in the country. In 2021 alone, DEA was involved in the seizure of over 8,700 crime guns and opened 912 investigations with a nexus to violent crime.</p>



<p><strong>Investing American Rescue Plan funding in community-oriented policing to reduce gun violence. </strong>The Biden Administration made historic levels of funding from the American Rescue Plan – $350 billion in state and local funding – available for law enforcement purposes such as hiring law enforcement or paying overtime where the funds are directly focused on advancing community policing strategies in those communities experiencing an increase in gun violence associated with the pandemic. Funds were also made available for additional enforcement efforts to reduce gun violence exacerbated by the pandemic, including prosecuting gun traffickers, rogue dealers, and other parties contributing to the supply of crime guns, as well as collaborative federal/state/local efforts to identify and address gun trafficking channels. Cities across the country, such as Milwaukee, Wisconsin; Albuquerque, New Mexico; Syracuse, New York; and Mobile, Alabama, have responded to this call by committing and deploying ARP funds for advancing community-oriented policing. In addition, the Department of Justice continues to further the Administration’s support of community-oriented policing, including through the announcement of $139 million in grants to local law enforcement that will put over 1,000 police officers on the beat through the COPS Office Hiring Program. President Biden was instrumental in that program’s creation and has called for it to be doubled in size in his FY22 budget request.</p>



<p><strong>Keeping Guns Out of the Hands of Domestic Abusers. </strong>In 2021, the Department of Justice’s Office on Violence Against Women (OVW) expanded the Domestic Violence Homicide Prevention Firearms Technical Assistance Project (FTAP) to provide funding directly to those communities that participated in FTAP in the past, as well as choosing new communities to receive funding and technical assistance. FTAP helps communities identify challenges limiting a more robust implementation of domestic violence firearms laws in their jurisdictions and assists them in establishing a localized response that is best suited to their communities’ unique needs and characteristics.&nbsp; OVW will award an estimated $6 million for up to 12 sites and $4 million for training and technical assistance on firearms and domestic violence.</p>



<p><strong><em>Addressing the Root Causes of Gun Violence</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Investing American Rescue Plan funding in public safety strategies such as summer jobs for young adults and substance abuse and mental health services. </strong>The Biden Administration has made historic levels of funding from the American Rescue Plan&nbsp; – $350 billion in state and local funding and $122 billion in school funding&nbsp; – available for purposes such as hiring nurses, counselors, and social workers; providing court personnel and operations costs to return to pre-pandemic operation levels; providing and expanding employment services, including summer jobs for young people and programs that provide training and work experience for formerly incarcerated persons and other individuals who live in communities most impacted by high levels of violence; providing and expanding summer education and enrichment programs, including summer camp; and scaling up wraparound services, such as housing, medical and mental health care, trauma-informed care, substance use disorder treatment, food assistance, and job placement services, for victims of crime, young people, formerly incarcerated persons, and individuals and households facing economic insecurity due to the pandemic. Cities and counties across the country, including St. Louis, Missouri; Tucson, Arizona; and Los Angeles County, California, have responded to this call by committing and deploying ARP funds for these purposes.</p>



<p><strong>Providing meaningful work, education, or enrichment to keep young people safe and give them a path to success. </strong>For example, in June 2021, the Department of Labor awarded $89 million through its YouthBuild program to provide pre-apprenticeship opportunities for young people ages 16-24. The Department of Labor also awarded $20 million through its Workforce Pathways for Youth program to expand workforce development activities that serve youth ages 14-21 during “out of school” time (non-school hours).</p>



<p><strong>Helping formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities. </strong>Individualswho secure employment after release have much lower recidivism rates than those who do not. Good, stable jobs for the formerly incarcerated promote public safety and reduce violence. That is why the Administration is taking concrete steps to facilitate employment and associated services, such as housing assistance, for people who are formerly incarcerated. For example, in June 2021 the Department of Labor awarded $85.5 million to help formerly incarcerated adults and young people in 28 communities transition out of the criminal justice system and connect with quality jobs. The Department also awarded $25.5 million in Young Adult Reentry Partnership grants to organizations that will help provide education and training services to young adults between 18-24 who were previously involved with the justice system or who left high school before graduation. In addition, the President’s House-passed Build Back Better Act includes $1.5 billion for grants to help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting Survivors of Domestic Violence.</strong> Research shows that a male abusers’ access to a firearm increases the risk of intimate partner femicide by <a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/health/domestic-violence-shelters-are-swamped-experts-worry-surging-gun-sales-could-make-things-worse">1,000%.</a> The COVID-19 pandemic and economic crisis have increased the rates and risk for domestic violence nationwide.  For many women and children who experience abuse, home is not a safe place and there were increased barriers to accessing services and support. Last year, the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), through the Family Violence Prevention and Services Program, awarded nearly $1 billion in American Rescue Plan (ARP) supplemental funding to support services for survivors of domestic violence and sexual assault and their children.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Excerpts from President&#160;Biden&#8217;s State of the Union Address as Prepared for&#160;Delivery</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/01/excerpts-from-president-bidens-state-of-the-union-address-as-prepared-for-delivery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout our history we’ve learned this lesson – when dictators do not pay a price for their aggression, they cause more chaos.&#160;They keep moving. And, the costs and threats to America and the world keep rising. That’s why the NATO Alliance was created to secure peace and stability in Europe after World War 2. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Throughout our history we’ve learned this lesson – when dictators do not pay a price for their aggression, they cause more chaos.&nbsp;They keep moving. And, the costs and threats to America and the world keep rising.<br><br>That’s why the NATO Alliance was created to secure peace and stability in Europe after World War 2. The United States is a member along with 29 other nations.<br><br>It matters. American diplomacy matters.<br><br>Putin’s war was premeditated and unprovoked. He rejected efforts at diplomacy. He thought the West and NATO wouldn’t respond. And, he thought he could divide us here at home.<br><br>Putin was wrong. We were ready.</p>



<p>&#8212;</p>



<p>We have a choice. One way to fight inflation is to drive down wages and make Americans poorer. I have a better plan to fight inflation.<br><br>Lower your costs, not your wages. Make more cars and semiconductors in America. More infrastructure and innovation in America. More goods moving faster and cheaper in America. More jobs where you can earn a good living in America. And, instead of relying on foreign supply chains – let’s make it in America.<br><br>Economists call it “increasing the productive capacity of our economy.” I call it building a better America.<br><br>My plan to fight inflation will lower your costs and lower the deficit.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:   The Biden Administration’s Historic Investments To Create Opportunity and Build Wealth in Rural&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-historic-investments-to-create-opportunity-and-build-wealth-in-rural-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 20:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is committed to ensuring that rural Americans have the opportunity to succeed – and that they can find that opportunity&#160;in&#160;rural America. This commitment is not just vital for rural Americans, but vital for the country as a whole. For centuries, rural Americans have driven the country’s economic growth and provided the country and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is committed to ensuring that rural Americans have the opportunity to succeed – and that they can find that opportunity&nbsp;<em>in</em>&nbsp;rural America. This commitment is not just vital for rural Americans, but vital for the country as a whole. For centuries, rural Americans have driven the country’s economic growth and provided the country and the world with food and fuel—and they continue to do so today. They are small business owners revitalizing Main Streets. They care for our land, ensuring that all Americans have access to nature and recreation.<br><br>In its first year, the Biden Administration has made historic investments in rural communities through the American Rescue Plan: slashing poverty and lowering costs, creating jobs and new economic opportunities, and expanding access to health care. President Biden&#8217;s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides a once-in-a-generation federal investment so that all rural Americans gain access to clean drinking water, are able to use high-speed broadband internet for education and business, and have safe roads and bridges for both people and goods. In addition, the Administration has invested $2.8 billion in coal and power plant communities, ensuring that these communities that fueled our country’s industrial revolution will continue to thrive in decades to come.<br><br>In the year ahead, the Biden Administration will partner with rural America to determine how best to invest these unprecedented federal resources to support local priorities.<br><br><strong>Lowering costs for working families in rural America</strong><br><br>The Biden Administration is building a stronger, more equitable economy that does not leave anyone behind, including rural communities that for too long have faced underinvestment and persistent poverty. Already, because of the Administration&#8217;s support for working families through the American Rescue Plan, rural poverty is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.urban.org/sites/default/files/publication/104603/2021-poverty-projections_0_0.pdf">estimated</a>&nbsp;to have fallen by 70 percent in 2021. President Biden knows working families are the backbone of our economy, and is delivering for them in rural America.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Tax relief for rural working families.</strong>&nbsp;The American Rescue Plan increased the Child Tax Credit from $2,000 per child to $3,000 per child for children over the age of six, and from $2,000 to $3,600 for children under the age of six, while raising the age limit from 16 to 17 for 2021. The President’s plans call for extending this critical tax cut, which expired in December 2021. The American Rescue Plan also ensured that all lower- and moderate-income families were eligible for the full expanded child tax credit. In addition, the American Rescue Plan nearly tripled the maximum Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children to $1,500, benefitting about 2.7 million rural workers.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Lowering rural Americans’ rent and mortgage payments and energy and water bills.&nbsp;</strong>The American Rescue Plan enabled single-family, COVID-affected borrowers with mortgages backed by the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to refinance their mortgages and provided rental assistance to 26,000 rural tenants. Rural Americans have also benefitted from the Department of the Treasury&#8217;s Emergency Rental Assistance Program and Homeowner Assistance Fund, which together provided tens-of-billions of dollars to keep people safely housed during the pandemic. In addition, the American Rescue Plan provided $4.5 billion for the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program—more than doubling typical annual funding—and $500 million for the first-ever federal water assistance program, lowering water and wastewater bills for rural households.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Lower child care costs and support child care providers</strong><strong>.&nbsp;</strong>Even before the pandemic, nearly two-thirds of rural Americans lived in areas where there is a significant shortage of licensed child care slots, with nine infants and toddlers for every one child care slot in rural America. Rural children are less likely to be enrolled in pre-K programs than urban and suburban children. The pandemic made it harder for rural families to access these programs – with 1 in 11 licensed child care providers closing before between December 2020 and March 2021. The President secured $39 billion in American Rescue Plan funds to provide a lifeline to child care providers so they could stay open without raising prices for families. This funding has already reached more than 150,000 child care providers, including those across rural America. The American Rescue Plan also provided funding to all 1,600 Head Start grantees, which serve the vast majority of rural counties and sometimes serve as the only provider in a rural community. This funding helped allow these grantees to serve 91% of Head Start children fully in-person, compared to 38% in December 2020. Early care and education were out of reach for too many rural families before the pandemic, which is why the President has also called on Congress to cut child care spending in half for most families, offer every 3- and 4-year old free preschool, and boost the number of high-quality child care programs in high-need areas, including in rural America.</li><li><strong>Helping states and local governments – as well as tribes and territories – provide additional direct assistance to lower families’ costs.&nbsp;</strong>The American Rescue Plan delivered $350 billion for the State and Local Fiscal Recovery Fund, providing support for critical investments in 3,000 counties and 30,000 small towns. These funds offer the flexibility local governments need to address their communities&#8217; most pressing needs. Already, over 20 states and scores of counties have used these funds to directly help families, including critical food assistance, utility assistance, and other help with basics for the hardest hit families. For example, Macon-Bibb County, GA committed $2.5 million to fight food insecurity in the community, including funds to address food deserts and support local food banks; New Hanover County, NH has committed $1 million to support homeowners who are behind on their mortgage; and Doña Ana County, NM has committed $1.2 million in direct medical relief funds for COVID-19 medical bills.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Lowering costs and improving access to an education beyond high school for rural students.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Education (ED) is investing $198 million in American Rescue Plan funding for competitive grants for rural colleges and universities that serve a high percentage of low-income students and are experiencing enrollment declines. With this funding, rural institutions can cover the cost of COVID-19 mitigation efforts, such as testing and personal protective equipment; support their students’ ability to meet basic needs by providing meal vouchers, childcare subsidies, and mental health services; facilitate continued enrollment and re-enrollment through support services such as academic counseling; and expand workforce programs that lead to in-demand jobs. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Improved access to affordable, nutritious food for rural Americans.&nbsp;</strong>Through the American Rescue Plan, USDA expanded access to the Pandemic EBT (P-EBT) program, including through the summer, to allow families with children receiving school meals to purchase healthy food more easily. The American Rescue Plan also increased SNAP benefits by 15% through September 2021. Beginning on October 1, 2021, USDA&#8217;s Thrifty Food Plan update increased SNAP benefits by $36.30 per person per month on average. These updates will&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/food-assistance/usda-announces-important-snap-benefit-modernization">increase</a>&nbsp;the well-being of 2.9 million people in rural areas, including 800,000 children, reducing rural poverty by 11 percent and rural child poverty by 20 percent. USDA also invested $1 billion, including $500 million in American Rescue Plan funding, in The Emergency Food Assistance Program (TEFAP) to support and expand emergency food access so states, food banks, and local organizations can reliably serve their communities, with a focus on reaching rural and underserved areas.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Creating jobs in rural America and supporting rural-led economic development</strong></p>



<p>The Biden Administration is committed to expanding opportunity to all corners of the country. That means good-paying, union jobs and economic opportunity in rural communities so that today’s workers can live with dignity and security, and rural youth can see a bright future right in their hometowns. As of October 2021, the unemployment rate in rural counties that experience persistent poverty had&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/chart-gallery/gallery/chart-detail/?chartId=102922">returned</a>&nbsp;to pre-pandemic levels, ranging from 3.4 percent to 4.7 percent. President Biden will continue building on that progress and the many efforts across the Administration to create jobs and build wealth in rural America.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Build resilient rural economies.</strong>&nbsp;The American Rescue Plan invested a historic $3 billion in the Department of Commerce&#8217;s (DOC) Economic Development Administration (EDA) to build local economies that are resilient to future economic shocks, including a $300 million Coal Communities Commitment. In December 2021, EDA announced 60 finalists for its $1 billion Build Back Better Regional Challenge, which will support regional coalitions to develop transformative projects that strengthen regional industry clusters. These finalists include 12 coal communities, and more than 80% of the finalists propose to serve rural communities, including ten proposals focused on growing or developing agriculture and natural resource industries.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Revitalize America&#8217;s energy communities.</strong>&nbsp;In February 2021, President Biden established the Interagency Working Group on Coal and Power Plant Communities and Economic Revitalization to identify and deliver resources to the coal, oil and gas, and power plant communities that have powered our country for generations. The working group identified&nbsp;<a href="https://energycommunities.gov/priority-energy-communities/">25 communities</a>&nbsp;across the country for immediate strategic investment. Since then, member agencies have delivered more than $2.8 billion in federal investment to these communities, including $167 million through USDA&#8217;s Renewable Energy for America Program and the Electric Loan Program. The working group also established a&nbsp;<a href="https://energycommunities.gov/funding-opportunities/">resource clearinghouse</a>&nbsp;with more than $181 billion in open and planned funding opportunities for energy communities, to facilitate access to federal programs.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Invest in state and local workforce programs and small business support.</strong>&nbsp;More than half of all states are using the American Rescue Plan State and Local Fiscal Recovery Fund to retain and train workers for new and better jobs, and over 20 states have provided direct support to small businesses. Wisconsin’s $9.4 million investment in American Rescue Plan funds in University of Wisconsin-Eau Claire’s regional workforce development strategy recruits and connects rural workers and students with careers in healthcare, education, and social services – areas where the state has critical shortages. Gallatin County, MT is investing $2 million in American Rescue Plan funds to develop and expand programs in construction trades, welding, fabrication, manufacturing and healthcare. And, local governments are using American Rescue Plan funds to retain essential workers across the country, from Erie, NY to St. Croix County, WI to Umatilla County, OR.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Support outreach and technical assistance to rural businesses.</strong>&nbsp;The Small Business Administration&#8217;s (SBA) Community Navigator Pilot Program, funded by the American Rescue Plan, is reducing barriers that underrepresented and underserved entrepreneurs – including those in rural America &#8211; often face in accessing the resources they need to recover, grow, or start their businesses. The program is providing a total of $100 million to 51 nonprofits, state and local governments,&nbsp;universities,&nbsp;and tribal entities that will work with organizations in all 50 states and Puerto Rico to provide technical assistance to small businesses in underserved communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Advance workforce development solutions in rural communities.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Labor’s (DOL) Workforce Opportunity for Rural Communities Initiative (WORC) is a partnership with the Appalachian Regional Commission and the Delta Regional Authority to support workers in rural communities impacted by economic transitions, especially in the energy sector. WORC funds provide job training and support services to dislocated workers, incumbent workers, and new entrants to the workforce to help connect them with good jobs in high-demand occupations. In 2021, DOL announced a third round of WORC grants for $29 million to 23 organizations, demonstrating the Biden Administration’s ongoing commitment to strengthening economic stability and opportunities for workers in rural communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Grow rural America’s outdoor recreation economy by expanding hunting and fishing.</strong>&nbsp;To help expand rural America’s outdoor recreation economy, the Biden Administration last year opened new or expanded hunting and fishing opportunities on 2.1 million acres of public lands, the largest such expansion in U.S. history. The Administration also recently announced a record&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-over-15-billion-support-state-wildlife-conservation-and">$1.5 billion</a>&nbsp;in annual funding through the Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration Program to support state and local outdoor recreational opportunities, and wildlife and habitat conservation efforts. These efforts, along with a new Task Force on Collaborative Conservation that the Administration launched in partnership with the Western Governors Association, will support America’s hunting and fishing traditions and help power the continued growth of the nation’s outdoor economy. In addition, the Departments of Agriculture and the Interior are collaborating to invest&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2021/06/03/president-bidens-budget-invests-28-billion-support-economies">$2.8 billion</a>&nbsp;under the Great American Outdoors Act to improve access, experiences, and partnerships for outdoor recreation that not only promote tourism but also protect America’s public lands while creating jobs and opportunities in rural communities. EDA is also investing $750 million in American Rescue Plan funding through the Travel, Tourism &amp; Outdoor Recreation program, including $510 million that has already been provided to states.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Responding to the COVID-19 pandemic in rural communities</strong></p>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic spared no part of the country, but rural communities have faced additional challenges that impact the delivery of services and assistance, including limited health care infrastructure and clinicians. As our nation turned the tide of the pandemic from crisis to recovery, the Biden Administration worked to ensure rural communities have the tools they need to combat COVID-19, keep schools open and safe, and come back stronger than before.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Safely reopen rural schools and&nbsp;</strong><strong>help students make up for lost learning time</strong><strong>.&nbsp;</strong>The American Rescue Plan surged $130 billion to our states, territories, tribes, and local communities to help them safely reopen our schools and keep them open, while addressing the impacts of the pandemic on students, including on their learning and mental health. Roughly $16 billion of these funds went to rural communities and $850 million went to Bureau of Indian Education (BIE) schools and Tribally-controlled Colleges and Universities (TCCUs). These are critical resources that are helping rural communities and school districts meet key challenges, including funds that school districts can use to address staff shortages. In addition, investments in broadband in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will be critical to supporting the education of young people in rural communities and closing the homework gap. As part of the Biden Administration’s commitment to reopen healthy learning environments, USDA issued a broad range of flexibilities and provided significant additional resources to allow school meal programs across the country to return to serving nutritious meals in fall 2021.<br>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Dedicated COVID-19 testing for rural hospitals and clinics.&nbsp;</strong>The Biden Administration delivered $425 million in American Rescue Plan funding to support COVID-19 testing and mitigation in 4,200 rural health clinics, and $398 million in funding to support COVID-19 testing and mitigation for over 1,500 small rural hospitals. HHS provided up to $100,000 per clinic and up to $230,000 per hospital to increase COVID-19 testing, expand access to testing in rural communities, and broaden efforts to respond to and mitigate the spread of the virus in ways tailored to community needs.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Deliver rapid tests to rural health clinics.&nbsp;</strong>HHS is currently distributing millions of rapid over-the-counter at-home COVID-19 tests to rural health clinics that reach uninsured and underserved communities, often among those hardest-hit by the pandemic.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Increase vaccine education and outreach efforts in rural communities.</strong>&nbsp;The Biden Administration awarded over $100 million in American Rescue Plan funding to rural health clinics across the country to support vaccine outreach in rural communities. This funding is being used to assist rural residents in accessing vaccinations, as well as education and outreach efforts around the benefits of vaccination.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Expand access to COVID-19 vaccines, testing, and supplies, while strengthening rural health care providers.&nbsp;</strong>The American Rescue Plan provided $500 million for USDA to create the Emergency Rural Health Care Grant Program. The program provides $350 million to help rural hospitals and local communities increase access to COVID-19 vaccines and testing, medical supplies, telehealth, and food assistance, and support the construction or renovation of rural health care facilities. It also provides recovery funds that compensate for lost revenue or staffing expenses due to COVID-19. In addition, the program provides up to $125 million in grants to plan and implement models that help improve the long-term viability of rural health care providers, including health care networks that allow rural providers to collectively address community challenges and develop innovative solutions.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Improving access to health care and lowering health care costs for rural communities</strong></p>



<p>Rural communities face persistent disparities in health outcomes and access to care, including higher rates of uninsured individuals, health care workforce shortages, and often difficulty reaching the nearest hospital. In many rural communities, the hospital is the largest employer in the area, providing jobs and supporting the local economy. Yet, rural hospitals have increasingly closed their doors, including 19 in 2020 alone. And rural hospital closures have been pervasive in non-expansion states. Of the ten states with the most rural hospital closures since 2010, most are in non-expansion states —the only two that are not, Oklahoma and Missouri, just began their expansions in 2021. Moreover, rural counties in the South are&nbsp;<a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/the-avenue/2021/09/28/mapping-rural-americas-diversity-and-demographic-change/">racially and ethnically diverse</a>, and in some non-expansion states, rural hospitals that closed were more likely to be in counties with a higher share of Black residents. Similar&nbsp;<a href="https://www.shepscenter.unc.edu/wp-content/uploads/dlm_uploads/2017/11/Characteristics-of-Communities-Served-by-Hospitals-at-High-Risk-of-Financial-Distress-1.pdf">disparities</a>&nbsp;exist for rural hospitals&nbsp;<em>at risk</em>&nbsp;of closure. The Biden Administration is taking action to improve the health of rural communities by ensuring rural Americans have the health care and coverage they need and deserve and helping rural hospitals stay open.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Lower health care costs for rural Americans.</strong>&nbsp;The American Rescue Plan has done more to lower costs and expand access to health care than any action since the passage of the Affordable Care Act. It has made quality coverage more affordable than ever—with families saving an average of $2,400 on their annual premiums, and four out of five consumers finding quality coverage for under $10 a month. The President&#8217;s plan continues these savings, keeping health insurance affordable for millions of Americans, including those living in rural communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Expand rural health care coverage and keep rural hospitals open.&nbsp;</strong>Since President Biden took office, nearly 700,000 rural Americans have gained coverage through the Affordable Care Act and the American Rescue Plan. Throughout 2021, the Administration ensured that rural Americans who needed coverage could sign up for it, including through the most recent HealthCare.gov Open Enrollment period in which over 1.8 million rural Americans enrolled in coverage. The President&#8217;s plan builds on that progress, expanding Medicaid coverage in those states that have refused to expand it. Closing this gap is estimated to reduce the risk of rural hospital closure by 62%. Rural hospital closures deprive people living in rural areas of crucial services, including access to emergency care.&nbsp;To fill this gap, HHS&nbsp;will establish a new provider type, Rural Emergency Hospitals, which will allow facilities to offer emergency department services, observation care, and/or outpatient services in rural areas.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Support rural health care providers.</strong>&nbsp;The American Rescue Plan provided $8.5 billion in American Rescue Plan funding to help compensate health care providers who serve rural Medicare, Medicaid, and Children’s Health Insurance Plan (CHIP) patients for lost revenue and increased expenses associated with COVID-19. In December 2021, HHS announced that it distributed $7.5 billion of these funds to 40,000 providers in all 50 states, Washington, D.C., and six territories. These funds help ensure that providers can effectively respond to the COVID-19 pandemic, including supporting recruitment and retention efforts amidst workforce shortages and staff burnout, and place them on stable financial footing to continue serving their communities into the future.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Increase the number of health care providers in rural communities.</strong>&nbsp;The Administration made a historic $1.5 billion investment, including $1 billion from the American Rescue Plan, in its health workforce loan repayment and scholarship programs. More than 22,700 primary care clinicians funded by these programs now serve in underserved communities, including rural and tribal communities—the largest number ever. This group of health care providers includes nearly 20,000 National Health Service Corps members, more than 2,500 Nurse Corps nurses, and approximately 250 awardees under a new program, the Substance Use Disorder Treatment and Recovery Loan Repayment Program. Currently, one-third of HHS&#8217;s Health Resources and Services Administration workforce serves in a rural community where health care access may be especially limited or require patients to travel long distances to receive treatment. HHS is also making $48 million from the American Rescue Plan available to expand public health capacity in rural and tribal communities through health care job development, training, and placement. This will increase the number of well-trained health care professionals and connect them with future employers, including hospitals and clinics in rural areas.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Expand access to pulmonary rehabilitation services.&nbsp;</strong>This year, HHS will support a demonstration project to enhance access to pulmonary rehabilitation services in Critical Access Hospitals that serve rural communities with high rates of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). COPD is one of the leading causes of death in the U.S., and adults in rural areas are almost twice as likely to have it compared to those in urban areas.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Expand Veterans Affairs training programs for rural providers outside of the VA system.</strong>&nbsp;The Rural Interprofessional Faculty Development Initiative, developed by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), is an innovative two-year training program designed to provide teaching and training skills for clinicians in rural settings, preparing rural clinicians to take on faculty roles, mentor medical professionals to serve in rural America, and grow the healthcare workforce in rural communities. In 2021, VA launched a new joint initiative with HHS, adding non-VA community clinicians to the program. This joint initiative will benefit up to 40 rural communities each year and enable rural clinicians to better train the next generation of clinicians who will serve rural America.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Increase access to telehealth.</strong>&nbsp;Telehealth services greatly increased during the pandemic and the Biden-Harris Administration has issued several telehealth supports including research conducted by NIH; funding for broadband, smart phones and internet connectivity; and an expansion of eligible services that can be delivered via telehealth, including a new rule that expands access to tele-mental health services for Medicare beneficiaries. Medicare will also now pay for mental health visits furnished via telehealth when they are provided by Rural Health Clinics and Federally Qualified Health Centers. This policy expands access to Medicare beneficiaries, especially those living in rural and other underserved areas.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Ensure access to effective treatment and recovery for substance use disorders.</strong>&nbsp;In January, HHS announced the availability of $13 million in funding to increase access to behavioral health care services and address health inequities in rural America, including through evidence-based, trauma-informed treatment for substance use disorder.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Address America&#8217;s mental health crisis.</strong>&nbsp;Through the American Rescue Plan, the Administration has made significant investments in expanding access to mental health and substance use services. The President&#8217;s FY22 budget also calls for investments in the mental health care workforce that will help address the shortage of professionals in rural and underserved areas. The Administration is committed to additional actions to address the mental health crisis by building workforce capacity, connecting more people to care, and creating a continuum of support for all Americans.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Support states in making public health investments through the American Rescue Plan State and Local Fiscal Recovery Fund.&nbsp;</strong>Over two thirds of states and hundreds of communities have already committed funds from the American Rescue Plan State and Local Fiscal Recovery Fund to address public health needs in their communities. For example, the State of Colorado is investing in an online training curriculum for providers in rural areas on mental health and substance use disorders to improve behavioral health supports. Bowie County, TX partnered with Christus St. Michael Hospital to provide vaccines at the hospital facility and several mobile vaccine clinics throughout the county, to reach the rural area of the county.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Rebuilding rural America’s infrastructure with a once-in-a-generation investment</strong></p>



<p>For far too long, critical infrastructure needs in rural communities have been ignored. Building on an initial investment in the American Rescue Plan, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers on the President’s promises to provide high speed internet, safe roads and bridges, modern wastewater systems, clean drinking water, reliable and affordable electricity, and good paying jobs in every rural community. A generational investment in rural America, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will spend billions of dollars to revitalize and rebuild rural communities across the country.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Provide high-speed internet to every home and making internet affordable for low-income rural Americans.&nbsp;</strong>By one definition, more than 30 million Americans live in areas where there is no broadband infrastructure that provides minimally acceptable speeds – a particular problem in rural areas across the country. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests $65 billion to make high-speed internet available to all Americans, bring down high-speed internet prices across the board, and provide technical assistance to rural communities seeking to expand broadband. In addition, it will help families afford internet service by providing eligible households with a discount of up to $30 per month toward internet services, as well as a one-time discount of up to $100 to purchase a laptop, desktop or tablet.</li><li><strong>Invest in critical rural broadband and water infrastructure through&nbsp;the American Rescue Plan State and Local Fiscal Recovery Fund.</strong>&nbsp;Through the American Rescue Plan’s State and Local Fiscal Recovery Fund, 20 states have expanded access to high-speed internet and 21 states are improving water and sewer infrastructure, including lead removal. Additionally, many local communities are leveraging American Rescue Plan funds to expand broadband services in rural areas. For example, Kandiyohi County, MN made an initial $1.3 million investment in a project that will expand high-speed broadband to rural townships. Miami County, FL allocated $1.4 million to help fund an expansion of high-speed internet to rural parts of the county, including to underserved students in low-income areas. Oconto County, WI approved $2 million to provide high-speed wireless internet to underserved rural areas.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Create good-paying jobs cleaning up legacy pollution in rural communities.&nbsp;</strong>The President is committed to creating good-paying jobs in rural communities across the country and ensuring those communities are safe, high-quality places to live. Legacy pollution from industries that extracted natural resources from rural areas and left behind huge quantities of environmental degradation has held back the economic growth and success of rural communities. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is creating good-paying jobs cleaning up these sites by investing $4.7 billion through an interagency initiative to plug, remediate, and restore dangerous orphan well sites across the country; nearly $11.3 billion to create good-paying union jobs and catalyze economic opportunity by reclaiming abandoned mine lands; and $1 billion to initiate cleanup and clear the backlog of 49 previously unfunded Superfund sites and accelerate cleanup at dozens of other sites across the country.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Improve rural Americans’ access to transit systems and functional highway systems to they can get to school and work and bring their products to market.&nbsp;</strong>Limited access to transportation options in rural and remote areas impedes American’s access to jobs, basic services, and their communities. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests billions of dollars to make sure rural families can get where they need to go, including through a $4.58 billion investment in Rural Area Formula Grants at the Department of Transportation (DOT). This program will support 1,300 rural transit systems by enabling them to purchase transit vehicles and infrastructure, plan transit more effectively, and fund operations. This investment builds on $282 million in American Rescue Plan funding that helped rural transit systems maintain and restore service during the pandemic.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Ensure clean drinking water and basic sanitation in rural homes.&nbsp;</strong>Across the country, including in rural and Tribal communities, pipes and treatment plants are aging and polluted drinking water endanger public health. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s transformative $55 billion investment in our water and wastewater infrastructure will fundamentally change quality of life for millions of Americans by eliminating lead pipes, providing critical access to sanitation, ensuring access to affordable clean drinking water, and reducing drought.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Build rural communities resilient to natural disasters and the threats of climate change.&nbsp;</strong>Last year, the United States faced 22 extreme weather and climate-related disaster events with losses over $1 billion – a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion. These included damaging floods, wildfires, and wind storms across rural America. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will improve the resilience of rural communities by investing $3.5 billion to improve home energy efficiency for low-income families, reducing energy costs, improving household comfort and safety, and cutting pollution.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Invest in resilience and restoration on national forest lands.</strong>&nbsp;The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will restore our national forests through the planting of 1.2 billion trees over the next decade, coupled with landmark investments in science-based hazardous fuels treatments that will protect communities from wildfire. The resources in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will provide a critical down payment to implement the USDA Forest Service’s 10-year strategy to reduce wildfire, which has a goal of treating 50 million acres across Federal and non-Federal lands.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Provide high-quality, safe roads and bridges for rural communities.&nbsp;</strong>While Americans living in rural areas account for just 20% of the population, they comprise nearly half of all roadway fatalities. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will deliver safer roads, bridges, railway crossings, and other critical improvement to the quality and safety of our roadways. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law also invests $1.2 billion to complete the Appalachian Development Highway System, connecting the rural regions of Appalachia, creating jobs, and linking businesses with domestic and international markets.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Upgrade electric and transmission infrastructure in rural America.</strong>&nbsp;Power outages cost the U.S. economy up to $70 billion annually. For example, the recent Texas power outages caused estimated losses of up to $90 billion for the state. At times, rural communities can be without power for days during these outages. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests $1 billion in Energy Improvement in Rural or Remote Areas to support entities in rural or remote areas to increase environmental protection from the impacts of energy use and improve resilience, reliability, safety, and availability of energy.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Explore the use of materials made from bioproducts to open up new market opportunities for farmers.&nbsp;</strong>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests $10 million in grants to support research on the economic, social and environmental benefits of using materials derived from bioproducts in the development and manufacturing of construction and consumer products.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Strengthening the food system and creating market opportunities for America’s farmers, ranchers and foresters</strong></p>



<p>Throughout the COVID-19 pandemic, American farmers, ranchers, processors, farmworkers, and other workers across the supply chain continued to adapt and put food on the table for American families, despite disruptions and other challenges. The Biden-Harris Administration is building on lessons learned during the pandemic to transform the food system so that it is more competitive, balanced, and equitable for everyone working in food and agriculture.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Address supply chain disruptions for families and farmers.&nbsp;</strong>As part of a whole-of-government response to tackle new and emerging near-term supply chain disruptions arising from the COVID-19 pandemic and historic economic recovery, President Biden established a Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force in June, bringing together industry, labor, and federal partners to alleviate bottlenecks and higher input costs for farmers, address rising prices at the grocery store, and support agricultural exporters. For example, USDA is leveraging $100 million in American Rescue Plan funds to offer a Food Supply Chain Guaranteed Loan Program, making available nearly $1 billion in loan guarantees to back private investment in processing and food supply infrastructure that will strengthen the food supply chain for the American people and create jobs in rural communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Advance equity in agriculture.&nbsp;</strong>In February 2022, USDA held the first meeting of the new USDA Equity Commission, which is supported by the American Rescue Plan and will evaluate USDA programs and services and recommend how USDA can reduce barriers for accessing them.&nbsp; Additionally, USDA has begun to deploy American Rescue Plan funds to support technical assistance and access to land, credit, and markets for historically underserved producers. USDA provided $50 million in Natural Resource Conservation Funds to organizations working with underserved communities and another approximately $75 million in American Rescue Plan funding to 20 organizations to provide technical assistance to connect underserved producers with USDA programs and services. Additionally, in July 2021, USDA rolled out the Heirs’ Property Relending Program, which provides funds to assist heirs in resolving ownership and succession issues on farmland with multiple owners.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Support a fairer, more competitive, and more resilient meat and poultry supply chain.&nbsp;</strong>In, January 2022, the Biden-Harris Administration announced its&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/03/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-action-plan-for-a-fairer-more-competitive-and-more-resilient-meat-and-poultry-supply-chain/">Action Plan for a Fairer, More Competitive, and More Resilient Meat and Poultry Supply Chain</a>, outlining how USDA will invest an additional $900 million in American Rescue Plan funding. As part of this effort, USDA recently announced $150 million in grants for new and expanded processing through a new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.rd.usda.gov/mppep">Meat and Poultry Processing Expansion Program</a>, $25 million to provide technical assistance support, and $40 million to support workforce development and training, including at community and junior colleges and Minority-Serving Institutions.&nbsp;As part of the Action Plan, USDA will invest $500 million in additional grants and lending to further strengthen financing for independent processing, along with $85 million in additional funding&nbsp;for workforce development and to promote innovation in this sector. This work builds on the $100 million already available to reduce overtime and holiday inspection fees to help small processing plants keep up with unprecedented demand. This also builds on USDA’s December 2021 announcement of $32 million in pandemic assistance funds to more than 160 meat and poultry processors, helping them get federally inspected so they can reach more customers.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Issue stronger rules under the&nbsp;<em>Packers &amp; Stockyards Act</em>&nbsp;and new rulemaking on “Product of USA” labeling to protect farmers, ranchers, and consumers, as well as promote an all-of-government approach to strengthening competition.</strong>&nbsp;USDA has begun work on three proposed rules to provide greater clarity and strengthen enforcement under the Packers &amp; Stockyards Act, and USDA will also pursue rulemaking to ensure the “Product of USA” label for meat products meets consumer expectations and allows for fair and competitive markets. In February 2022, the Department of Justice (DOJ) and USDA launched a new joint initiative to better coordinate their enforcement efforts, including a new portal—FarmerFairness.gov—for reporting concerns about potential violations of competition laws. And today, the President is announcing an historic agreement between the DOJ and the Federal Maritime Commission to put more cops on the beat to ensure large, foreign ocean carriers cannot take advantage of U.S. farmers, businesses, and consumers.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Ensuring nutritious food gets to those who need it while opening up new market opportunities for farmers and ranchers.&nbsp;</strong>In December 2021, USDA committed $1.5 billion in funds from the Commodity Credit Corporation to help schools make direct food purchases and access food purchased by USDA and will also invest in cooperative agreements with state and Tribal governments to purchase foods from local underserved producers. All purchases will support domestic agriculture. Additionally, in December 2021, USDA announced a new Local Food Purchase Assistance Cooperative Agreement Program that will award up to $400 million for emergency food assistance purchases of domestic local foods. Utilizing American Rescue Plan funds, these purchases will expand local and regional markets and place an emphasis on purchasing from historically underserved farmers and ranchers.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Ensuring all of agriculture benefits from financial assistance to address the impacts of COVID-19</strong><strong>.</strong>&nbsp;The pandemic affected all of agriculture, but many farmers did not benefit from previous rounds of pandemic-related assistance under the previous administration’s Coronavirus Food Assistance Program (CFAP). The Biden-Harris Administration worked to fill those gaps to help get financial assistance to a broader set of producers, including to underserved communities, small and medium sized producers, and farmers and producers of less traditional crops. USDA&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2021/03/24/after-identifying-gaps-previous-aid-usda-announces-pandemic">announced</a>&nbsp;‘Pandemic Assistance for Producers’ to distribute resources more equitably and committed to directing at least $6 billion to the agricultural producers and sectors that needed assistance the most. This includes re-opening signup for CFAP2, $700 million in grants to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2021/09/07/usda-invests-700-million-grants-provide-relief-farm-and-food">provide relief</a>&nbsp;to farm and food workers affected by COVID-19; $700 million to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2021/09/09/usda-invests-700-million-provide-relief-small-producers-processors">provide relief</a>&nbsp;for small producers, processors, farmers markets and seafood vessels affected by COVID-19; and $2 million to establish partnerships with organizations to provide outreach and technical assistance to historically underserved farmers and ranchers. As a result, there was a fourfold increase in participation among historically underserved producers in CFAP2 since April 2021. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Invest in farmworker training.</strong>&nbsp;DOL’s National Farmworker Jobs Program provides grants to community-based organizations and public agencies to enable farmworkers to receive skills training, career services and other critical services like housing assistance to help them obtain, retain and advance in the agricultural sector. DOL awarded $87 million in career services and training grants across the United States and Puerto Rico and $6.2 million in housing grants.</li><li><strong>Pay farmers, ranchers, and forest landowners to be part of the solution to climate change.&nbsp;</strong>In February 2022, USDA launched a $1 billion investment in partnerships to support America’s climate-smart farmers, ranchers, and forest landowners. The new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/climate-solutions">Partnerships for Climate-Smart Commodities</a>&nbsp;opportunity will finance pilot projects that create market opportunities for U.S. agricultural and forestry products that use climate-smart production practices and include innovative, cost-effective ways to measure and verify greenhouse gas benefits. USDA has also invested $50 million in new 118 partnerships to expand access to conservation assistance for climate-smart agriculture and forestry. The new Equity Conservation Cooperative Agreements will fund two-year projects to expand the delivery of conservation assistance to farmers who are new to farming, low-income, historically underserved, or military veterans.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reward farmers, ranchers, and forest owners for their voluntary conservation efforts</strong>. Recognizing the critical role that America’s farmers, ranchers, and forest-owners play in the stewardship of the nation’s lands, waters, and wildlife, the Administration is, as part of the President’s America the Beautiful Initiative, expanding support for voluntary conservation efforts on private lands. USDA, for example, has made&nbsp;<a>changes</a>&nbsp;to its Conservation Reserve Enhancement Program to remove barriers to access and provide partners increased flexibility to participate in and benefit from the program.&nbsp; USDA enrolled 5.3 million new acres in the Conservation Reserve Program by raising rental payment rates and expanding the number of incentivized environmental practices allowed under the program.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Support renewable fuel producers and infrastructure.</strong>&nbsp;USDA has&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2021/12/07/usda-make-800-million-available-provide-economic-relief-biofuel">dedicated</a>&nbsp;$700 million to provide economic relief to biofuel producers and restore renewable fuel markets affected by the pandemic, and committed to $100 million to increase the sales and use of higher blends of bioethanol and biodiesel by expanding the infrastructure for renewable fuels derived from U.S. agricultural products.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Facilitate U.S. agricultural products in reaching export markets</strong><strong>.&nbsp;</strong>USDA is working with the Port of Oakland to set up a new “pop-up” site to make it easier for agricultural companies to fill empty shipping containers. The new site, supported by Commodity Credit Corporation funds, will provide access to equipment and provide trucks faster turns without having to wait for in-terminal space. The Port of Oakland is a potential model for other ports experiencing similar issues. The Administration also continues to call on ocean carriers to mitigate disruptions to agricultural shippers by restoring full and fair service to the Port of Oakland. In addition, over $600 million in American Rescue Plan resources have already been announced to strengthen the port workforce and improve facility efficiency at our most critical ports, from California and Florida to Massachusetts and Louisiana.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Ensure trade rules work for American farmers and ranchers.</strong>&nbsp;The United States&nbsp;<a href="https://ustr.gov/about-us/policy-offices/press-office/press-releases/2022/january/united-states-prevails-usmca-dispute-canadian-dairy-restrictions">prevailed</a>&nbsp;in the first dispute settlement panel proceeding under the U.S.-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA), bringing the U.S. dairy sector one step closer to realizing the full benefits of the USMCA. The Administration scored another trade policy win when Vice President Kamala Harris traveled to Hanoi in August 2021, securing a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.fas.usda.gov/newsroom/vietnam-lowers-mfn-tariffs-corn-wheat-pork">commitment</a>&nbsp;from the Vietnamese government to reduce tariffs on U.S. agricultural products. This will give U.S. corn, wheat, and pork producers greater access to our seventh-largest agricultural export market, in line with competitors from countries that have free trade agreements with Vietnam. These actions contributed to a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/02/08/american-agricultural-exports-shattered-records-2021">record-shattering</a>&nbsp;$177 billion in exports of U.S. farm and food products in 2021.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Finding that a Drawdown and Sale of Petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve is Required by U.S. Obligations Under the International Energy Program Implemented by the International Energy&#160;Agency</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/01/memorandum-on-the-finding-that-a-drawdown-and-sale-of-petroleum-from-the-strategic-petroleum-reserve-is-required-by-u-s-obligations-under-the-international-energy-program-implemented-by-the-internati/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 20:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48099</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Finding that a Drawdown and Sale of Petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve is Required by U.S. Obligations Under the International Energy Program Implemented by the International Energy Agency&#160; On February 21, 2022, the Russian government initiated a further invasion of Ukraine.&#160;&#160;On February 23, 2022, Russia launched missile strikes,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Finding that a Drawdown and Sale of Petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve is Required by U.S. Obligations Under the International Energy Program Implemented by the International Energy Agency&nbsp;</p>



<p>On February 21, 2022, the Russian government initiated a further invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;On February 23, 2022, Russia launched missile strikes, air raids, and the movement of tanks and troops into broad swaths of Ukrainian territory.&nbsp;&nbsp;Since then, fighting has intensified along Ukraine&#8217;s northern, eastern, and southern borders, and in major cities and at critical facilities.&nbsp;&nbsp;Russia&#8217;s actions in Ukraine have resulted in energy supply shortages of significant scope and duration and have already caused a substantial increase in oil prices worldwide that threatens to slow United States economic growth at this critical point in our economic recovery.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Based on information from and advice of the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) and on other information, I find, in accordance with section 161(d) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA), 42 U.S.C. 6241(d), that a drawdown and sale of petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) is required by U.S. obligations under the International Energy Program implemented by the International Energy Agency and created by the Agreement on an International Energy Program, signed by the United States on November 18, 1974.</p>



<p>For these reasons, the Secretary is authorized and directed to draw down and sell petroleum from the SPR at public sale to the highest qualified bidder at a rate the Secretary may determine, in accordance with section 161 of EPCA and the SPR competitive sales procedures in 10 CFR Part 625.&nbsp;&nbsp;The drawdown and sale authorized and directed by this finding will allow the United&nbsp;States to meet its obligations under the Agreement on an International Energy Program.&nbsp;&nbsp;If the Secretary determines the circumstances leading to this finding no longer support initiation or continuation of a drawdown and sale of petroleum from the SPR, the Secretary is authorized to cancel in whole or in part any offer to sell petroleum as a part of any drawdown and sale pursuant to this finding.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
