<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 16:24:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Zelenskyy of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-zelenskyy-of-ukraine-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50070</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke today with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine about the ongoing work by the United States and its allies and partners to deliver military, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and to impose severe costs on Russia for its brutal aggression against Ukraine. The leaders discussed how the United States is working around the clock to fulfill the main security&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke today with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine about the ongoing work by the United States and its allies and partners to deliver military, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and to impose severe costs on Russia for its brutal aggression against Ukraine. The leaders discussed how the United States is working around the clock to fulfill the main security assistance requests by Ukraine, the critical effects those weapons have had on the conflict, and continued efforts by the United States with allies and partners to identify additional capabilities to help the Ukrainian military defend its country. In addition, President Biden informed President Zelenskyy that the United States intends to provide the Ukrainian government with $500 million in direct budgetary aid. He also reviewed the additional sanctions and humanitarian assistance announced last week. President Zelenskyy updated President Biden on the status of Ukraine’s negotiations with Russia. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency With Respect to Significant Malicious Cyber-Enabled&#160;Activities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-significant-malicious-cyber-enabled-activities-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 15:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; On April 1, 2015, by Executive Order 13694, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701&#160;et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by the increasing prevalence and severity of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On April 1, 2015, by Executive Order 13694, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701&nbsp;<em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by the increasing prevalence and severity of malicious cyber‑enabled activities originating from, or directed by persons located, in whole or in substantial part, outside the United States.&nbsp; On December 28, 2016, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13757 to take additional steps to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13694.</p>



<p>These significant malicious cyber-enabled activities continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on April 1, 2015, must continue in effect beyond April 1, 2022. &nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1&nbsp;year the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13694.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><br>                                JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"> <br><br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>    March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress, on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to South&#160;Sudan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-south-sudan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 15:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50062</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:&#160;&#160;Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act, (50&#160;U.S.C.&#160;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&#160;a&#160;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&#160;the Federal&#160;Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act, (50&nbsp;U.S.C.&nbsp;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&nbsp;a&nbsp;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&nbsp;the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13664 of April 3, 2014, with respect to South Sudan is to continue in effect beyond April 3, 2022.</p>



<p>The situation in and in relation to South Sudan, which has been marked by activities that threaten the peace, security, or stability of South Sudan and the surrounding region, including widespread violence and atrocities, human rights abuses, recruitment and use of child soldiers, attacks on peacekeepers, and obstruction of humanitarian operations, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13664 with respect to South Sudan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to South&#160;Sudan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-south-sudan-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 15:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 3, 2014, by Executive Order 13664, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in and in relation to South Sudan,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 3, 2014, by Executive Order 13664, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the situation in and in relation to South Sudan, which has been marked by activities that threaten the peace, security, or stability of South Sudan and the surrounding region, including widespread violence and atrocities, human rights abuses, recruitment and use of child soldiers, attacks on peacekeepers, and obstruction of humanitarian operations.</p>



<p>The situation in and in relation to South Sudan continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on April 3, 2014, must continue in effect beyond April 3, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13664.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.<br>                                </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br> March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency With Respect to Significant Malicious Cyber-Enabled&#160;Activities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-significant-malicious-cyber-enabled-activities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 15:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C.&#160;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&#160;a&#160;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&#160;the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C.&nbsp;1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of&nbsp;a&nbsp;national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13694 of April 1, 2015, with respect to significant malicious cyber-enabled activities, is to continue in effect beyond April 1, 2022.</p>



<p>Significant malicious cyber-enabled activities originating from, or directed by persons located, in whole or in substantial part, outside the United States continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States. &nbsp;Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13694 with respect to significant malicious cyber-enabled activities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; March 30, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Administration Launches COVID.gov, a New One-Stop Shop Website for Vaccines, Tests, Treatments, Masks, and the Latest COVID-&#8288;19&#160;Information</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/30/fact-sheet-biden-administration-launches-covid-gov-a-new-one-stop-shop-website-for-vaccines-tests-treatments-masks-and-the-latest-covid-19-information/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50049</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Website will Feature a New Test-to-Treat Locator Tool to Help People Access the Over 2,000 Locations that Offer COVID-19 Tests and Antiviral Pills at One Convenient Location Administration Continues to Urge Congress to Provide Funding Immediately to Help Keep These Life-Saving Protections Readily Available to All Today, the Biden Administration is launching COVID.gov, a new&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Website will Feature a New Test-to-Treat Locator Tool to Help People Access the Over 2,000 Locations that Offer COVID-19 Tests and Antiviral Pills at One Convenient Location</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Administration Continues to Urge Congress to Provide Funding Immediately to Help Keep These Life-Saving Protections Readily Available to All</em></strong></p>



<p>Today, the Biden Administration is launching COVID.gov, a new one-stop shop website to help all people in the United States gain even better access to lifesaving tools like vaccines, tests, treatments, and masks, as well as get the latest updates on COVID-19 in their area. The Administration has worked over the past 14 months to set up over 90,000 vaccination sites, make more than 400 million high-quality masks available for free, send free tests to peoples’ homes, and stand up new test-to-treat sites where people can get tested and receive life-saving antivirals all in one place. Now, with a click of a button, people will be able to find where to access all of these tools, as well as receive the latest CDC data on the level of COVID-19 in their community.</p>



<p>As part of COVID.gov, a new Test-to-Treat locator will help people access pharmacies and community health centers across the nation where people can get tested for COVID-19 and receive appropriate treatments if they need them. President Biden announced the Test-to-Treat initiative in his State of the Union address earlier this month. Since that time, the Administration has already launched over 2,000 of these sites, plus more than 240 sites across Veteran’s Health Administration and Department of Defense facilities to serve veterans, military personnel, and their families. As has been the case throughout the pandemic, the Administration is ensuring locations are established in our most hard-hit and high-risk communities.</p>



<p>Because of the lifesaving tools we now have, America is in a new moment in the pandemic. The country is moving forward safely and people are getting back to their more normal routines. To ensure we’re sustaining and building on this progress and protecting and preparing for new variants, earlier this month, the President released his&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/covidplan/">National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan</a>. The President was clear that in order to execute on this plan and to stay ahead of the virus, the Administration needs additional funding from Congress—including $22.5 billion in immediate emergency funds. To date, Congress has failed to provide those funds and the country is already suffering the consequences. In the last two weeks, the Administration has had to stop reimbursing health care providers for treating the uninsured, cancel monoclonal antibody orders and cut states’ supply, reduce orders of treatments for the immunocompromised, and pull the U.S. out of line for future vaccine and next-generation treatment purchases. These issues disproportionately impact our hardest-hit and highest-risk populations, including communities of color and individuals with disabilities. The Administration continues to urge Congress to act quickly, as the consequences will continue to get worse in the coming weeks.</p>



<p>Protecting the American people from COVID-19 now and into the future relies on affordable and accessible tools like vaccines, treatments, tests and high-quality masks. Through efforts like COVID.gov and Test-to-Treat, the Administration continues to take steps to make these tools even more readily available. Now, we need Congress to do its part and continue to fund the COVID-19 response.</p>



<p>Today’s announcements include:</p>



<p><strong><u>Launch of COVID.gov, A New One-Stop-Shop Website Where Individuals Can Find Where to Access Vaccines, Tests, Treatments, and High-Quality Masks.&nbsp;</u></strong>Today, the Administration launched COVID.gov, a new website to help people access vaccines, tests, treatments, and high-quality masks. COVID.gov also provides people an easy way to find the level of COVID-19 in their community. Early last year, the Administration launched Vaccines.gov and an associated call line to help people locate and make appointments at vaccine sites near them. In January of this year, the Administration launched COVIDTests.gov where people could order tests and have them shipped to their homes for free. COVID.gov will allow individuals to access both of these services at one convenient, easy-to-use website. It will also offer information about where to find free high-quality masks and, for the first time, where to access COVID-19 treatments.</p>



<p>COVID.gov will be available in English, Spanish, and Simplified Chinese and is accessible for those using assistive technologies. The Administration is also making all of these COVID-19 tools available over the phone through the National Hotline at 1-800-232-0233 (TTY 1-888-720-7489), which supports over 150 languages. For individuals with disabilities who may need additional support, the Disability Information and Access Line (DIAL) is also available to help at 1-888-677-1199 or via email at DIAL@usaginganddisability.org. <br><br><strong><u>New Locator Tool to Help Individuals Access the Over 2,000 Test-to-Treat Sites Across the Country.</u> </strong>Today, as part of COVID.gov, the Administration launched a new Test-to-Treat locator tool to help the public access lifesaving drugs if they are sick with COVID-19. President Biden announced in his State of the Union address the creation of the Test-to-Treat initiative. This program creates one-stop-shop locations where people can get a COVID-19 test and receive an oral antiviral treatment, if appropriate for them because they test positive and face high risks from COVID. Since the launch earlier this month, there are now over 2,000 Test-to-Treat locations nationwide, including in pharmacy-based clinics, federally-qualified community health centers (FQHCs), and long-term care facilities. As has been the case since December, people can still be tested and treated by their own health care providers who can appropriately prescribe these oral antivirals at locations where they are being distributed, now more easily identified than ever by the Test to Treat locator.  <br><br><a><strong><u>Test-to-Treat Available for All Patients in Veteran’s Health Administration and Military Personnel and Their Families.</u></strong></a> Test-to-Treat is now available for all Veterans Affairs (VA) patients in VA clinics across the country. Linking patients who test positive with treatments that are appropriate for them is the standard of care in VA clinics. Each test done in the VA is linked to a care team, and accompanied by review, patient counseling, and consideration for treatment indication and eligibility. The VA also allows individuals with a positive home test result to have a virtual visit to connect with counseling and to receive oral medication if appropriate. VA sites have access to oral antiviral treatments for COVID-19, and treatment generally is provided on site or delivered via expedited mail. In addition, the Department of Defense (DoD) has made one-stop Test-to-Treat available at more than 60 DoD Medical Treatment Facilities (MTFs) across the country, with hundreds more primed to start operating soon. MTF patients across the country—including active duty service members and TRICARE beneficiaries—can access Test-to-Treat at facilities in their communities. </p>



<p><strong>Hundreds of Test-to-Treat Locations in FQHCs and Indian Health Service Facilities Across the Country to Protect Hard-Hit and High-Risk Communities from COVID-19.</strong><a>Test-to-Treat locations also are available in more than 240 FQHCs and Indian Health Service (IHS) Facilities across the country, ensuring access to lifesaving treatments in some of our hardest-hit and highest-risk communities. </a>The number of these locations will continue to grow in the coming weeks, as more and more FQHCs, Rural Health Clinics, and IHS locations come online with Test-to-Treat programs. These community providers will continue to serve as trusted messengers in raising awareness about the availability of lifesaving treatments, and also partner with community-based organizations to reach specific high-risk populations, including individuals with disabilities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Signing of H.R. 55, the &#8220;Emmett Till Antilynching&#160;Act&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/29/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-h-r-55-the-emmett-till-antilynching-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 4:11 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (The bill is signed.)&#160; All right.&#160; It’s law.&#160; (Applause.) (The President moves to the podium.) Thank you.&#160; It’s a little unusual to do the bill signing, not say anything and then speak, but that’s how we set it up.&#160; Well, ladies and gentlemen, good afternoon.&#160; I just signed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>4:11 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (The bill is signed.)&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; It’s law.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>(The President moves to the podium.)</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; It’s a little unusual to do the bill signing, not say anything and then speak, but that’s how we set it up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, ladies and gentlemen, good afternoon.&nbsp; I just signed into law the Emmett Till Antilynching Act, making lynching &#8212; (applause) &#8212; a federal hate crime for the first time in American history.</p>



<p>I want to thank Vice President Harris who was a key co-sponsor of this bill when she was a United States senator.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I also want to thank Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer and members of the Congress here today, especially Congressman Hoyer and Bobby Rush, Senator Dick Durbin and Cory Booker.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I &#8212; I also want to thank Senator Tim Scott, who couldn’t be here today.</p>



<p>And the civil rights leaders gathered here today and, most of all, the family of Emmett Till and Ida B. Wells: Thank you for never giving up.  Never, ever giving up.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>Matter of fact, her [great]-granddaughter told me that her mother was here &#8212; when? &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. DUSTER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; I mean, your [great]-grandmother was here &#8212; when? &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. DUSTER:&nbsp; It was in 1898.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; In 1898, in order to make a case for the antilynching law.&nbsp; It was over 100 years ago, in 1900, when a North Carolina Representative named George Henry White &#8212; the son of a slave; the only Black lawmaker in Congress at the time &#8212; who first introduced legislation to make lynching a federal crime.</p>



<p>Hundreds &#8212; hundreds of similar bills have failed to pass.</p>



<p>Over the years, several federal hate crime laws were enacted, including one I signed last year to combat COVID-19 hate crimes.&nbsp; But no federal law &#8212; no federal law expressly prohibited lynching.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; Until today.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>One of the leading chronicles of our history of lynching is Bryan Stevenson, who happens to be a Delawarean from my home state, who wanted very much to be here today but he could not.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He helped build the National Memorial for Peace and Justice in Montgomery, Alabama &#8212; America’s first site dedicated to understanding the legacy of lynching.</p>



<p>You know, his extensive research showed that between 1877 and 1950, more than 4,400 Black people were murdered by lynching, most in the South but some in the North as well.&nbsp; That’s a lot of folks, man, and a lot of silence for a long time.</p>



<p>Lynching was pure terror to enforce the lie that not everyone &#8212; not everyone belongs in America and not everyone is created equal; terror to systematically undermine hard &#8212; hard-fought civil rights; terror not just in the dark of the night</p>



<p>but in broad daylight.</p>



<p>Innocent men, women, and children hung by nooses from trees.&nbsp; Bodies burned and drowned and castrated.</p>



<p>Their crimes?&nbsp; Trying to vote.&nbsp; Trying to go to school.&nbsp; To try and own a business or preach the Gospel.&nbsp; False accusations of murder, arson, and robbery.&nbsp; Simply being Black.</p>



<p>Often the crowds of white families gathered to celebrate the spectacle, taking pictures of the bodies and mailing them as postcards.</p>



<p>Emmett Till was an only child.&nbsp; He grew up on the South Side of Chicago with his mother, Mamie, and grandparents and cousins.</p>



<p>In the summer of 1955, Emmett turned 14 years old, ready to start eighth grade in the fall.&nbsp; Before school started, he wanted to visit his cousins in Mississippi.&nbsp; So Emmett’s mom dropped him off at the train station in Chicago.&nbsp; Her own family fled the Delta decades earlier, so she told him &#8212; she told him the unwritten rules he had to follow.&nbsp; Quote, “Be very careful how you speak.&nbsp; Say ‘yes sir’ and ‘no ma’am’, and do not hesitate to be &#8212; to humble yourself if you have to get down on your knees”.&nbsp; End of quote.</p>



<p>That same speech, that same admonition &#8212; too many Black parents today still have to use that admonition.&nbsp; They have to tell their children when it comes to encounters with the law enforcement.&nbsp; You know, and so many other circumstances.</p>



<p>She kissed Emmett goodbye.&nbsp; It was the last time she saw her son alive.</p>



<p>Days after he arrived in Mississippi, Emmett’s mutilated body was found in a river, barbed wire tied around his neck and a 75-pound cotton gin fan attached to that wire as he was thrown into the river.</p>



<p>Emmett’s mother &#8212; his mother demanded that her son be sent home so that his funeral in Chicago could be an open casket.</p>



<p>Here’s what she said: “Let the people see what I’ve seen.”&nbsp; America and the world saw what she saw.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Emmett Till was born nearly 40 years ago after the first antilynching law was introduced.&nbsp; Although he was one of thousands who were lynched, his mother courage &#8212; his mother’s courage to show the world what was done to him energized the Civil Rights Movement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Exactly 100 days later, Rosa Parks was arrested on the bus in Montgomery.&nbsp; Her statue sits in my office.&nbsp; She said, “I thought of Emmett Till and I couldn’t go back.”&nbsp; “I thought of Emmett Till and I couldn’t go back.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. King often preached about, quote, “the crying voices of little Emmett Till, screaming from the rushes of the Mississippi.”</p>



<p>To the Till family: We remain in awe of your courage to find purpose through your pain.&nbsp; To find purpose to through your pain.&nbsp; But the law is not just about the past, it’s about the present and our future as well.</p>



<p>From the bullets in the back of Ahmaud Arbery to countless other acts of violence &#8212; countless victims known and unknown &#8212; the same racial hatred that drove the mob to hang a noose brought that mob carrying torches out of the fields of Charlottesville just a few years go.</p>



<p>Racial hate isn’t an old problem; it’s a persistent problem.&nbsp; A persistent problem.&nbsp; And I know many of the civil rights leaders here know, and you heard me say it a hundred times: Hate never goes away; it only hides.&nbsp; It hides under the rocks.&nbsp; And given just a little bit of oxygen, it comes roaring back out, screaming.&nbsp; But what stops it is all of us, not a few.&nbsp; All of us have to stop it.</p>



<p>People like Ida B. Wells, one of the founders of the NAACP, established 100 years ago in response to racial terror across the country.&nbsp; A brilliant, gifted writer, she exposed the barbaric nature of lyn- &#8212; of lynching as a tool to intimidate and subjugate Black Americans.</p>



<p>And her words, her courage, her convictions &#8212; she was trying to prevent the murders of Emmett Till and Ahmaud Arbery, and so many others &#8212; over 4,400 others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ida B. &#8212; Ida B. Wells once said, quote, “The way to right wrongs is to turn the light of truth upon the wrongs.”&nbsp; “Turn the light of truth upon the wrongs.”</p>



<p>That’s what all of you have done, gathered in this Rose Garden, with this bill and so much more, including Ida B. Wells’s great-granddaughter, Michelle Duster, whom I&#8217;m honored to introduce to mark this historic day.</p>



<p>Michelle, welcome to the White House, and welcome to the podium.&nbsp; And as my mother would say: God love you, dear.</p>



<p>4:22 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong of Singapore Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/29/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-lee-hsien-loong-of-singapore-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 23:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 11:26 A.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, Prime Minister, it’s great to have you back.&#160; We’ve &#8212; PRIME MINISTER LEE:&#160; Happy to be here.&#160; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; &#8212; spent a fair amount of time together.&#160; This is a critical moment for, I think, both our countries and the region that you so ably represent.&#160; And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>11:26 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Prime Minister, it’s great to have you back.&nbsp; We’ve &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LEE:&nbsp; Happy to be here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; spent a fair amount of time together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a critical moment for, I think, both our countries and the region that you so ably represent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the strength of the U.S.- &#8212; it seems to me, at least; I hope you think the same way &#8212; the Singapore Strategic Partnership for peace and &#8212; and prosperity throughout the Pacific these many years: Today, that partnership is as important as it’s ever been, in my opinion.&nbsp; As a matter of a fact, I think it’s growing in importance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And a rule-based order is facing unprecedented challenges.&nbsp; Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war against Ukraine is an urgent threat to both Europe and, I believe, to the Indo-Pacific as well.&nbsp; And it’s attacking the core tenets of a rule-based international order.&nbsp; And the borders can&#8217;t be changed by force.&nbsp; And all the nations, large and small, are equal in sovereign &#8212; in rights for their sovereignty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank you, Mr. Prime Minister, for Singapore&#8217;s principled leadership in supporting the people of Ukraine.&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s not easy, but I want to thank you for it.&nbsp; You’re a man of principle, and you’ve stepped up every time you&#8217;ve had to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And even as we address the crisis in Europe, my administration is strongly supportive of moving rapidly to implement the Indo-Pacific Strategy that we&#8217;ve talked about, as you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the United States is a proud Indo-Pacific nation.&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard for most other nations of the world to understand that, but we have a big country and a lot of Pacific territory.&nbsp; And I &#8212; it&#8217;s a free and open area that we want to make sure is &#8212; we want to maintain it that way and connect it in purpose and security and in terms of our resilience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, today, at the end of the day, we&#8217;re going to discuss a number of important issues: the U.S.-ASEAN relationship, upholding freedom of the seas, promoting the return of democracy in Burma, and advancing an inclusive and sustainable economic growth in both our areas.</p>



<p>And so I want to thank you, again, for making this journey.  And, Mr. Prime Minister, the floor is yours, good friend.<br><br>     PRIME MINISTER LEE:  Thank you, Mr. President.  Thank you, especially, for receiving me at this critical moment in &#8212; in world affairs.  And I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re completely seized with what&#8217;s happening in Europe right now.  But we doubly appreciate the time you are giving to the relationship with Singapore and the Southeast Asian countries generally, especially ASEAN.<br><br>     Singapore is a very good partner of the United States.  We are a major security cooperation partner of the U.S.  And our relations are doing very well economically, as well as in the security and defense realms, and they prosper and grow and venture into new areas continuously. <br><br>     And I hope to discuss that with the President today, as well as to further the relationship between the U.S. and ASEAN, which is an engagement which is important to the U.S. because it helps the U.S. to be present in the Asia-Pacific and to deepen its relations with many friends and to strengthen its strategic interest in the region.<br><br>     We will, of course, exchange views also on Ukraine and what that means for the Asia-Pacific region. <br><br>     Singapore hopes that the United States, amidst all its many preoccupations, will continue to deepen its relationship with countries in the Asia-Pacific &#8212; China, certainly, but also other countries besides China &#8212; and deepen it substantially in many different ways through the Indo-Pacific Strategy and, in doing so, to foster the peace, stability, and security of the region as you have done for so many decades since the war. <br><br>     Thank you very much.<br><br>     PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I assure you that’s our objective.  I assure you.<br><br>     PRIME MINISTER LEE:  Thank you.<br><br>     PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Thank you all.<br><br>11:30 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces Additional Infrastructure Funding for Ports and&#160;Waterways</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/29/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-additional-infrastructure-funding-for-ports-and-waterways/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Invests $2.7 Billion from President’s Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to Strengthen Port and Waterway Supply Chains and Climate Resilience Department of the Interior Invests $1.7 billion in Rural Infrastructure for FY 2023 Recognizing the vital role of modern, resilient infrastructure in reducing costs for American families and businesses, President Biden secured&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>U.S. Army Corps of Engineers Invests $2.7 Billion from President’s Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to Strengthen Port and Waterway Supply Chains and Climate Resilience</em><br> <br><em>Department of the Interior Invests $1.7 billion in Rural Infrastructure for FY 2023</em></p>



<p>Recognizing the vital role of modern, resilient infrastructure in reducing costs for American families and businesses, President Biden secured unprecedented investments through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to improve the country’s ports and waterways – critical links in our supply chains. President Biden’s infrastructure law provides the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers investments to modernize ports and waterways after decades of neglect. The funding will not only make them more resilient to climate change impacts, but strengthens supply chains, keeps goods moving through the economy, and enables the U.S. to compete.<br><br><strong>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing that it will invest more than $2.7 billion in funding to [300] Army Corps projects through the country focused on strengthening ports and waterways. </strong>The announcement follows the Biden Administration providing $14 billion from President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and other appropriations to strengthen port and waterway supply chains and bolster climate resilience earlier this year. With today’s announcement, the Biden Administration will have invested a total of nearly $17 billion in new Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding and other supplemental appropriations in fiscal year 2022 and 2023 for over 800 projects across 55 states and territories.<br><br>These key projects will strengthen the nation’s supply chain, provide significant new economic opportunities nationwide, and bolster our defenses against climate change, including investments for:</p>



<ul><li>The<strong> Upper Ohio River, Pennsylvania </strong>to construct new lock chambers at Emsworth Locks and Dams that will allow large cargo ships to reliably and efficiently pass through the upper Ohio River system, relieving landside congestion and facilitating timely delivery of goods.<br></li><li>The <strong>McClellan–Kerr Arkansas River Navigation System (MKARNS)</strong> which moves 12 million tons of agricultural commodities annually in commodities to American farmers and provides flood control to many communities in Arkansas and Oklahoma along the Mississippi River.<br></li><li><strong>Adams and Denver, Colorado</strong> for reducing flood risk and an aquatic ecosystem restoration project, which will serve disadvantaged communities surrounding the area.<br></li><li>A project in the <strong>City of Watsonville, Town of Pajaro, California </strong>and surrounding agricultural lands which have been subject to a long history of flooding.</li></ul>



<p>Additionally, today, the Department of the Interior announced Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding allocations by the Bureau of Reclamation for nearly $1.7 billion in rural infrastructure funding for FY 2023. The plan represents a blueprint for how Reclamation is investing in communities to address drought across the West, as well as greater water infrastructure throughout the country. The Infrastructure Law’s second year funding will be allocated to a number of priorities including:</p>



<ul><li>$649 million for the Aging Infrastructure Account for major repairs and rehabilitation of facilities;<br></li><li>$248 million for rural water projects that benefit various Tribal and non-Tribal underserved communities by increasing access to potable water;<br></li><li>$95 million for construction of water storage, groundwater storage and conveyance project infrastructure; and<br></li><li>$85 million for the St. Mary Canal diversion and headworks replacement project, which&nbsp; will include a large fish bypass structure.</li></ul>



<p>The investments announced today further advance the President’s Justice40 Initiative commitment to ensure that 40 percent of the overall benefits of certain Federal investments, including in the areas of climate change and critical clean water and wastewater infrastructure, flow to historically marginalized, underserved, and overburdened communities to build their economies&nbsp;and reduce their disproportionate environmental burden. The investments also underscore how President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/14/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-hits-the-ground-running-60-days-into-infrastructure-implementation/">delivering results</a> to communities across America, advancing racial equity, combatting climate change, and creating job opportunities for American workers.<br><br>The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers will initiate projects in fiscal years 2022 and 2023 that:<br><strong><br>STRENGTHEN DOMESTIC SUPPLY CHAINS&nbsp;<br></strong><br>American ports and waterways are a cornerstone of the U.S. economy. According to the 2021 Report Card for America’s Infrastructure Report issued by the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE), in 2018, America’s ports supported more than 30 million jobs and approximately 26% of our nation’s GDP. However, decades of neglect and underinvestment have strained their capacity and jeopardized supply chains.<br><br>Building on the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/10/13/fact-sheet-biden-administration-efforts-to-address-bottlenecks-at-ports-of-los-angeles-and-long-beach-moving-goods-from-ship-to-shelf/">work</a> this Administration has done this past year to get goods flowing from ships to shelves faster, including $6.6 billion in funding announced through the fiscal year 2023 Budget, today the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers is committing $321 million through the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to expand capacity at key ports and waterways to allow passage of larger vessels and further enhance the country’s ability to move goods. These waterside investments will compliment landside investments at our ports and across the goods movement chain such as the Port Infrastructure Development Grants announced in December. Specific projects announced today work to:<br><br><strong>Move More Goods Faster at One of the Nation’s Fastest Growing Ports:&nbsp;</strong>Investing in ports helps to create resilient supply chains and create jobs. The Administration will invest more than $72 million to widen and deepen the <strong>Norfolk Harbor, Virginia</strong> Federal navigation channel to increase the resilience of our nation&#8217;s supply chain.&nbsp; The Norfolk Harbor, Virginia, project handles 67 percent more containers in 2021 than it did 10 years ago. Work will improve navigation and enable safer access for larger commercial and naval vessels, and provide significant new economic opportunities to the region.<br><br>The Biden Administration is also investing nearly $11 million in the <strong>Port of Galveston in Texas</strong> by deepening a portion of the Galveston Harbor Channel to accommodate larger vessels throughout the Port that will increase capacity, while also enabling improved operational safety.<br><br>Further, the $68 million investment to deepen the <strong>Brazos Island Harbor Channel at the Port of Brownsville</strong><strong>in Texas</strong> will enable increased cargo movements, reduced transit times and improved operational safety.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Reduce Congestion on Inland Waterways</strong>. Investing in inland waterways creates and sustains jobs, relieves landside congestion, and provides more cost-effective transportation capacities. Recognizing the diverse benefits provided by investing in inland waterways, today, the Biden Administration is announcing it will invest an additional $77 million in the <strong>Upper Ohio River, Pennsylvania</strong> project to construct new lock chambers at Emsworth Locks and Dams that will allow large cargo ships to reliably and efficiently pass through the upper Ohio River system, relieving landside congestion and facilitating timely delivery of goods.<br><br>The Biden Administration is also investing $92.6 million in the <strong>McClellan–Kerr Arkansas River Navigation System</strong> (<strong>MKARNS</strong>) which moves 12 million tons of agricultural commodities annually in commodities to American farmers and provides flood control to many communities in Arkansas and Oklahoma along the Mississippi River. The investment will upgrade the locks along the system to ensure that much needed commodities are being delivered quickly and efficiently.<br><br><strong>BOLSTER RESILIENCE TO CLIMATE CHANGE</strong><br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration is leveraging the <strong>$17 billion</strong> provided by the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law through fiscal year 2024 to better protect communities from climate change, and protect vital ecosystems and the people and businesses throughout the country that rely on them. Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing more than $1.16 billion in invests to reduce coastal and inland flood risk.</p>



<p>Funding from the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law announced today will:<br><strong>Reduce Flood Risk and Restore Aquatic Ecosystems</strong>. The Army Corps will leverage funds from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to increase community resilience to flooding, including nearly $[482] million to reduce coastal flood risk through 12 projects and more than $[679] million to reduce inland flood risk through an additional 7 projects across the country.&nbsp; Projects include:</p>



<ul><li>$350 million to the <strong>Adams and Denver, Colorado</strong> for flood risk reduction and aquatic ecosystem restoration project, which will serve disadvantaged communities surrounding the area. Components of the project include ecosystem restoration for aquatic, wetland, and riparian habitat along 6.5 miles of the South Platte River, restoring critical habitat connectivity as well as providing recreational opportunities to underserved populations.&nbsp;<br></li><li>$220 million for the <strong>Howard Hanson Dam, WA</strong> to maintain flood risk management, increase municipal and industrial water supply to Tacoma Public Utility, and ecosystem restoration. The funding will advance work on the fish passage facility for migrating juvenile salmon and maintain dam performance to support the primary water needs for the citizens of Tacoma.&nbsp;<br></li><li>$150 million for floodwalls, storm surge barriers, levees, pump stations, and non-structural measures to reduce threats from seal-level rise and increasing storm risk to the City of <strong>Norfolk, Virginia</strong>. This project will reduce threats from ever-increasing storms and sea-level rise, and damages to residential, commercial, historic and critical infrastructure.<br></li><li>$77 million for <strong>Mississippi Coastal Improvement Program</strong> (MSCIP) to restore the Mississippi barrier islands to increase resilience to future storm events prevent saltwater intrusion and shoreline erosion, and preserve fish and wildlife habitat. The funding will advance the next phase of the project.<br></li><li>$26 million for <strong>Hudson Raritan Estuary</strong> to restore 381 acres of estuarine wetland habitat including 16 acres of tidal channels, 50 acres of freshwater riverine wetland habitat, 27 acres of coastal and maritime forest habitat, 39 acres of shallow water habitat and 53 acres of oyster habitat.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>ADVANCE ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE</strong><br><br>The investments announced today will further deliver on the President’s Justice40 Initiative commitment to ensure that 40 percent of the overall benefits from certain federal investments, including in the areas of climate change and critical clean water and wastewater infrastructure, flow to disadvantaged communities in building their local economies and reducing their disproportionate environmental burden.&nbsp;In addition to the projects mentioned above, the followings projects are examples of projects that will provide benefits to disadvantaged communities. The Administration will provide $115 million to the <strong>Southwest Coastal Louisiana Hurricane Protection project</strong>&nbsp;which will construct localized storm surge risk reduction features, including features to elevate and flood-proof structures, to reduce hurricane storm surge damage risks in Cameron, Calcasieu, and Vermilion Parishes, communities which are identified as disadvantaged and have been particularly hard hit by the effects of climate change.</p>



<p>In addition, the Administration will provide $67 million to the Pajaro, CA project to reduce flood risk in the <strong>City of Watsonville, Town of Pajaro</strong>, and surrounding agricultural lands which have been subject to a long history of flooding.</p>



<p>The Administration is also committed to the <strong>Espanola Valley, Rio Grande and Tributaries, New Mexico</strong> project by providing $2.2 million to complete the preconstruction engineering and design to restore and protect 958 acres of aquatic and riparian habitats. These habitats are critical to the functioning of the third longest river in the country, and are an integral part of constructing social identity and transmission and retention of traditional knowledge for both the Pueblo of Santa Clara and Ohkay Owingeh.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/omb/briefing-room/2022/03/28/fact-sheet-the-presidents-budget-for-fiscal-year-2023/">Budget for Fiscal Year 2023</a> will provide further opportunity to advance infrastructure needs of the nation through the Corps Civil Works program, including through $6.6 billion commercial navigation improvements, flood and storm damage reduction, and aquatic ecosystem restoration. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Director of Communications Kate&#160;Bedingfield</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/29/press-briefing-by-director-of-communications-kate-bedingfield/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 23:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50038</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:10 P.M. EDT MS. BEDINGFIELD:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; I know I am not the redhead you&#8217;re accustomed to seeing at this podium, but I hope you will hang with me nonetheless.&#160; So, thank you.&#160; Before we &#8212; before I take your questions, I wanted to start with a little bit&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:10 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; I know I am not the redhead you&#8217;re accustomed to seeing at this podium, but I hope you will hang with me nonetheless.&nbsp; So, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Before we &#8212; before I take your questions, I wanted to start with a little bit of a topper here.&nbsp; So, as you all know, today is Vietnam Veterans Day, and I&#8217;d like to take a moment to highlight critical investments that the President announced yesterday as part of his budget to uphold our sacred obligation to veterans and address the mental health crisis.<br><br>During his first State of the Union Address, President Biden outlined a four-part Unity Agenda focused on areas where members of both parties can come together and make additional progress for the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>The President&#8217;s budget advances this Unity Agenda through targeted investments to take on the mental health crisis, accelerate progress against cancer, deliver on our commitment to veterans, and combat the opioid epidemic &#8212; all while cutting the deficit and not raising taxes on anyone earning less than $400,000 a year.<br><br>The budget proposes transformative mental health reforms that would expand coverage, reduce costs, and increase the number of mental health providers.<br><br>As we commemorate Vietnam Veterans Day, I wanted to highlight how the budget proposes funding to improve VA services, reduce veteran suicide, end veteran homelessness, and address military toxic exposures.&nbsp; And it tackles the opioid and overdose epidemic with significant investments to reduce the illicit supply of drugs in our communities and prevent substance-use disorder, expand treatment, and help people recover.<br><br>Today, I also wanted to celebrate another example of the success of the President&#8217;s industrial policy with Governor Roy Cooper announcing the electric vehicle maker VinFast is investing $4 billion to build electric vehicles and batteries in North Carolina.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an investment that will create more than 7,000 jobs on top of the 423,000 manufacturing jobs created on the President&#8217;s watch in his first year in office &#8212; the most in a single year since the early 1990s.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re building on that momentum with the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law &#8212; which is making historic investments in our roads, bridges, airports, and more &#8212; along with things like EV charging stations that are critical for America to own emerging industries.&nbsp;<br><br>And we have a chance to redouble that progress with the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which cleared through the Senate last night with a massive bipartisan majority.&nbsp; This is legislation that will boost manufacturing, strengthen our supply chains, lower prices, and boost our economic and national security by making more critical components, like semiconductors, right here in America.<br><br>We look forward to the House of Representatives moving quickly to start the formal conference on that bill so we can get this to the President&#8217;s desk as soon as possible.<br><br>And with that, I&#8217;m happy to take your questions.<br><br>Darlene, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; And welcome.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to follow up with one question on the readout from the President&#8217;s call earlier today with the European leaders.&nbsp; Can you say if they spent any time at all talking about his comment that Putin cannot remain in power or should not remain in power?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; They did not.&nbsp; I spoke with the President about this earlier.&nbsp; They did not.&nbsp; They were incredibly aligned, however, and spoke to some of the key issues that we are focused on here, including supply to &#8212; supplying weapons to Ukraine, including increasing costs on Russia, continuing to increase sanctions, supporting stable energy markets, and, of course, the state of diplomatic negotiations.<br><br>And obviously, the conversation today came on the heels of the President&#8217;s successful trip to Europe last week, in which he stood with some of our European allies and announced efforts to redouble NATO forces on the eastern flank, to announce an additional $1 billion in humanitarian aid to Ukraine, and to &#8212; and to continue to show incredible unity with our European partners and Allies as we tackle this crisis in Russia.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A second question.&nbsp; Is there any comment or reaction to the FDA approving a fourth booster shot for people over 50?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, this is a good thing and it is a straightforward thing.&nbsp; The CDC and the FDA are now allowing and will make available booster shots &#8212; a fourth shot &#8212; for people over 50, for the &#8212; and for the immunocompromised.&nbsp; This is &#8212; we have plenty of supply to ensure that those populations can receive these shots.&nbsp;<br><br>But what I would say is that if it &#8212; at some point, it becomes recommended that the full &#8212; the full population requires a fourth shot, we&#8217;re going to need additional funding.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to need the additional funding we&#8217;ve requested of Congress to be able to provide &#8212; to provide those shots for the &#8212; for the broader population.&nbsp;<br><br>But we do have the supply, and people will be able to go &#8212; people in those populations, 50 and up, will be able to go and get those shots.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Mike Memoli.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; First, I wanted to ask about the Turks [sic] that are happening &#8212; talks that are happening underway in Turkey between the Russians and the Ukrainians.&nbsp; What is the White House’s visibility into those discussions?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And have U.S. officials seen any evidence to back up Russia’s claims that they’re pulling some of their forces back from Kyiv?&nbsp; Obviously, the President said he wanted to see what the Russians actually did versus what they say.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, we are in close contact with the Ukrainians and are supportive of their efforts to engage in diplomacy and to try to reach a ceasefire.&nbsp; We are prepared to be helpful however we can and are focused on putting Ukraine in the strongest possible position both on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.<br><br>We, obviously, continue to provide security assistance, to provide weapons to ensure that they are able to push back on Russian aggression.&nbsp; And we continue to increase pressure on Putin and on Russia by imposing severe costs in partnership with our Allies and partners.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we defer to the Ukrainians to discuss the specifics of the negotiations.&nbsp; But we are, of course, committed to a Ukraine that is &#8212; that is sovereign, independent, and secure.&nbsp; And we are in constant conversation with the Ukrainian government and our Allies and partners.&nbsp; But, as always, we keep those conversations private.<br><br>To your second question about Kyiv, obviously &#8212; and what we heard from the Russians today &#8212; you obviously heard the President address this and say that we&#8217;ll need to watch and see if their actions meet their words.&nbsp; But I think we should be clear-eyed about the reality of what&#8217;s happening on the ground and no one should be fooled by Russia&#8217;s announcements.&nbsp;<br><br>We believe any movement of forces from around Kyiv is a redeployment and not a withdrawal.&nbsp; And the world should be prepared for a major offensive against other areas of Ukraine.&nbsp; Everyone should expect that we&#8217;re going to continue to see attacks across Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, a key message that the President delivered on his trip to Eur- &#8212; in his trip to Europe last week was that we are in for a long slog; that our Allies and partners need to remain &#8212; that our resolve needs to remain strong; and that we need to continue to execute on the strategy of inflicting significant costs on the Russian economy and, again, strengthening Ukraine on the battlefields and at the negotiating table.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Kate, on the subject of the President&#8217;s remarks in Poland about President Putin: Obviously, yesterday, he tried to suggest that there was a distinction between his personal views of what he thought was a moral outrage versus an official policy position on the part of the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>But you know full well something that candidate Joe Biden said virtually every day on the campaign trail, which is that the words of a president matter; that they can, as he often put it, lead a country into war.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Is he not living up to the standard that he set himself during the campaign?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; I think the words of the President here were incredibly powerful.&nbsp; He spoke personally about the moral outrage that he felt, which is shared by people all across the world.&nbsp; It does not mean he&#8217;s articulating a change in policy.&nbsp; It does not mean he&#8217;s laying out a change in U.S. policy.<br><br>He met with refugees &#8212; as, again, many of you were on that trip and saw &#8212; and saw firsthand some of the pain that Vladimir Putin has inflicted on people who are fleeing their homes and who are seeing their country war-torn.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So this was an incredibly personal, powerful statement of moral outrage; it was not an articulation of a new U.S. policy.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think both of those things can be and are true.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you’ve spent some time with the President &#8212; last question, Kate &#8212; is he frustrated or does he regret that those words at the very end of the speech overshadowed a larger message, which obviously he put a lot of thought into in the days leading &#8212;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; He spoke from the heart.&nbsp; He, as he always does &#8212; as you know very well from having covered him for a long time, as many of you do, and as the American people know &#8212; he speaks from the heart.&nbsp; He says what he feels.&nbsp; And, no, he absolutely does not regret that in any way.<br><br>Justin Sink.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Kate.&nbsp; Following on Darlene’s question.&nbsp; Will the President and Vice President be receiving fourth booster shots?&nbsp; And do you have a sense of timeline on that?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, I can speak to the President, who will make this decision in consultation with his doctor.&nbsp; Obviously, if his doctor recommends that he receive a fourth booster, then he would.&nbsp; But he’ll make that decision in consultation with his doctor.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I will check on the Vice President.&nbsp; I don’t know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, earlier, you were talking about the call and supporting stable energy markets.&nbsp; During the President&#8217;s trip last week, there seemed to be momentum behind the idea of a coordinated Strategic Petroleum Reserve release.&nbsp; And so I&#8217;m wondering if you can provide any update on whether that topic came up in the conversation today or a timeframe or outlook for that.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I can only say that they spoke to the stability of energy markets writ large and the need to keep them stable.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any specifics to preview in terms of any coming announcements.<br><br>What I would say more broadly, of course, is that obviously President Biden is very focused on ensuring that we minimize fluctuations as much as possible at the gas &#8212; at the gas pump and prices in general for American families.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>He is doing everything he can to combat Putin’s price hike here at home.&nbsp; That’s why they &#8212; we did the initial coordinated release of 60 million barrels from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; And he will continue to focus on this, but I don&#8217;t have any specific preview that I can give you at this time.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one last one.&nbsp; Our friends over at the Journal yesterday reported that members of the Ukrainian peace negotiation team have exhibited signs of a potential poisoning.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if that was something the U.S. has been aware of, tracking, and if you, sort of, ascribe responsibility to the Russians.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, we are certainly aware.&nbsp; We are obviously alarmed by these reports, especially given the fact that this is something that historically has been in Russia&#8217;s playbook.&nbsp; But I do not have any confirmation at this time, except to say that we are aware.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Kaitlan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; You just said &#8212; and the Pentagon is also saying the same thing &#8212; that any movement of forces in Ukraine of Russian forces is not a withdrawal but a repositioning.&nbsp; Is that based on intelligence?&nbsp; Or what is &#8212; what is that based on?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That is based on the fact that we need to see what the Russians actually do before we trust solely what they&#8217;ve said.<br><br>We saw from the outset that they made an aggressive push toward Kyiv at the beginning of this conflict.&nbsp; And we have no reason to believe that they have adjusted &#8212; that they&#8217;ve adjusted that strategy.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, we continue to do everything we can to impose costs for this decision.&nbsp; We will continue to execute on our strategy.&nbsp; But as you heard the President say, we are not going to take their word for it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to wait to see what their actions look like.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the British Prime Minister said today that they won&#8217;t accept anything less than a full withdrawal of all Russian forces from Ukrainian territory.&nbsp; Does President Biden share that view that reduced military activity is not enough?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, we are going to allow the Ukrainians to &#8212; to execute on these negotiations.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not our role to begin the negotiation.&nbsp; Again, our role is to strengthen Ukraine on the battlefield, to try to strengthen Ukraine at the negotiating table by&nbsp;<s>implying</s>&nbsp;[employing] these sanctions and costs to Russia.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; to pre-judge or pre-determine an outcome for that conversation.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question for you.&nbsp; Jared Kushner is set to testify before the January 6th Committee on Thursday virtually.&nbsp; Has the White House had any communication with him about whether or not you&#8217;re going to waive any executive privilege claims that he could make?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, obviously, the President has spoken to the fact that January 6th was one of the darkest days in our country&#8217;s history and that we must have a full accounting of what happened to ensure that it never occurs again.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And he&#8217;s been quite clear that they posed a unique threat to our democracy and that the constitutional protections of executive privilege should not be used to shield from Congress or the public information about an attack on the Constitution itself.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, as a result, the White House has decided not to assert executive privilege over the testimony of Jared Kushner and Ivanka Trump.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And have you communicated that to Jared Kushner&#8217;s team?&nbsp; Or is this a communication error?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp;&nbsp;I won&#8217;t &#8212; I won&#8217;t spe- &#8212; I won&#8217;t speak to private communication between our attorneys and his.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; Just, sort of, with Russia redeploying to focus on eastern Ukraine, what is your view on whether Russia should be allowed to retain control of the Donbas region?&nbsp;<br><br>As you&#8217;re aware, they have, you know, just today said that, you know, that is what &#8212; that is what their demand is.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if the U.S. has a formalized position on that.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, again, I am not going to pre-judge where these negotiations ultimately net out.&nbsp; We are doing everything we can to provide weapons to the Ukrainian people so that they can turn back Russian aggression.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing everything we can to impose severe costs on Russia and on the Russian economy.&nbsp;<br><br>I am not going to pre-judge the ultimate outcome, certainly not from standing here at this podium.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a quick question on the Deputy Treasury Secretary.&nbsp; He spoke a little while earlier and said there were more sanctions coming; this time, they&#8217;ll be focused on Russian supply chains.&nbsp; Are there any more details that you can potentially share with us on what that looks like and when that will happen?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have additional specifics that I can provide in terms of announcements coming at this time, except to say, more broadly, you know, that certainly we have hit, in consu- &#8212; in concert with our Allies and partners, we have hit very hard at the things that Putin cares about the most: degrading his military, access to cutting-edge technology, chipping away at his chokehold on energy, and ability to project power and influence.&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, we will continue to intensify and we&#8217;re not going to run out of options anytime soon.&nbsp; There are plenty of things that we can do, including broadening sanctions to new targets, deepening the severity of sanctions that are existing.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t have any specifics to announce at this time, except to say that there are certainly other options should we decide to move forward with them.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask about &#8212; just follow up on the January 6th Committee.&nbsp; Liberals have suggested that they&#8217;re disappointed with the way that the Justice Department, under Attorney General Garland, has approached the former President.&nbsp; How does the President feel about this question?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; The President has the utmost respect for the independence of the Department of Justice and does not have any comment on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, the sense here is that the President has confidence in the way the Justice Department has been handling all of these cases?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to speak to specific handling of cases.&nbsp; Obviously, the President has full faith in Attorney General Garland to run his department the way he sees fit.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Cleve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, on the President and the coronavirus, you&#8217;ve said there&#8217;ll be consultations about a fourth shot.&nbsp; I wonder, with the President&#8217;s recent travel overseas, with several members of the White House staff coming down with coronavirus, are there any additional measures or medication &#8212; anything else that&#8217;s being done to sort of protect the President&#8217;s health and welfare?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, you know, let me talk a little bit about some of the procedures and give you an overview of our policy here.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the White House takes incredibly strong precautions in alignment and sometimes, as you all know, beyond CDC guidance to ensure that we&#8217;re keeping a safe workplace, especially for the President of United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, all EOP &#8212; Executive Office of the President &#8212; employees who surround the President are tested on a regular cadence here on campus to screen for COVID.&nbsp; That is a step beyond CDC guidance to help lower the risk of COVID on campus.&nbsp; We do regular &#8212; regular screening, testing.&nbsp;<br><br>The President&#8217;s doctor determines if additional testing is needed in any given week, in light of various considerations.&nbsp;<br><br>So, more specifically to your question, because of his travel this week, he will test in addition to his regular testing cadence.&nbsp;<br><br>Everyone going into a meeting with one of the four principals is required to test ahead of time.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how we know about some of these positive cases in the first place.&nbsp;<br><br>So, for those employees who test positive, they&#8217;re required to isolate in alignment with CDC guidance and must test negative before turning to &#8212; returning to work, which is also a step beyond CDC guidance.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we take every &#8212; every measure here to ensure that we are protecting the four principals and also protecting our staff and our workforce.&nbsp; But because of his travel, he will do some additional testing, in addition to his regular cadence.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, just to follow up &#8212; I want to make sure I&#8217;m clear &#8212; what about any medications?&nbsp; Is he taking any additional medications or any other treatments or anything like that?<br><br>I understand about the testing and about &#8212; we all get tested when we get near the President.&nbsp; But is there anything else?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not something that I &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get into private medical information from here, except to say that the President will receive additional testing as part of his cadence to ensure that &#8212; that COVID &#8212; that he doesn&#8217;t have COVID.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just to follow up on that, when was he last tested?&nbsp; And, I guess, we presume he was negative because he&#8217;s with the Prime Minister.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; You know, I will get you the date. &nbsp;I want to say &#8212; I actually want to say it was yesterday.&nbsp; But &#8212; because I think we announced it publicly yesterday.&nbsp;<br><br>So I believe his last test was yesterday.&nbsp; And, yes, it was negative.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He said yesterday that he would be willing to meet with President Putin again or talk to him.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering what specific circumstances need to be met for such a meeting to take place.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I think he articulated pretty clearly that it would depend on what President Putin wanted to talk about.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, I&#8217;m not going to set &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to set preconditions for a conversation between President Biden and President Putin, except to say that we have been very clear and President Biden has been very clear that there needs to be tangible de-escalation from Russia and a clear, genuine commitment to diplomacy before the President would have that kind of conversation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, and on the COVID funding: Do you have any update?&nbsp; I know you say you need the money, but do you have any update on the negotiations?&nbsp; It seems like there are serious conversations happening up on the Hill.&nbsp; Do you have any sense of when or how this might be resolved?&nbsp; Are you more optimistic than you were last week, for instance?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re continuing to push.&nbsp; I mean, this &#8212; this funding is important.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be important to ensure that we are well funded in the event that another variant comes along or in the event that we see another wave that we need to be prepared for.&nbsp; So, you know, we view this funding as really critical.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve been working with Congress, as you know well, for the last several months.&nbsp; They know that we need the funding to stay ahead of the virus.&nbsp; They&#8217;re also aware of some of the specific details &#8212; like, for example, that already the uninsured fund has stopped accepti- &#8212; accepting claims and we&#8217;ve been forced to cut monoclonal supply to states by a third this week.&nbsp; So, there are real, tangible impacts to not having this funding.&nbsp;<br><br>I think there is widespread agreement that funding for vaccines, tests, and treatments is urgent and critical.&nbsp; And we need to see this urgency from Congress, and we&#8217;re going to continue to push.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Ukraine is now asking for security guarantees as part of these negotiations.&nbsp; What kinds of guarantees is the U.S. willing to provide to ensure Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, these are not specifics that I&#8217;m prepared to be able to announce from this podium.&nbsp; Obviously, we are working&nbsp;very closely with Ukraine on a wide array of options, things to help ensure we are &#8212; ensure their sovereignty and ensure their security.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, some of that is providing the weapons that we&#8217;re providing; some of that is continuing to push on sanctions and costs on Russia.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any specifics to preview for you on any &#8212; on any discussions about security guarantees.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the concern over chemical weapons &#8212; you know, with Russia now seeming to make some concessions and at least promising to reduce military activity, are you still as concerned that Russia could use chemical weapons?&nbsp; Or is that threat seen as diminishing?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We continue to prepare for every contingency.&nbsp; We obviously take seriously a wide array of potential options.&nbsp; There has been reporting in the public &#8212; in the public sphere over the last weeks about all the work that our teams are doing to prepare for eventualities.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I&#8217;m not going to rate the likelihood of one or another outcome except to say that our teams are preparing for &#8212; for all eventualities.&nbsp; And, you know, the President has been very clear that, you know, we will respond with severe consequences, as we have responded with severe consequences to every action Russia has taken up until this point.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a similar question with regards to China: Do you see Russia&#8217;s promise to somehow pull back some of its forces as a sign that China is not willing to or will not be assisting them?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any updated guidance beyond what you all heard from Jake, for example, last week about us not having seen any evidence of China providing any sort of military assistance to Russia.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jacqui.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; There are reports that the administration is going to require COVID vaccines for undocumented migrants at the southwest border just as Title 42 is expected to end and right after the fourth shot got FDA approval.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You just highlighted the impacts of not having enough COVID funding when it comes to paying for shots for the uninsured and sending shipments of treatments to states.&nbsp; So why would the administration give out free vaccines to undocumented migrants but not to, for instance, uninsured Americans?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, to be clear, we have the supply that we need in this moment to vaccinate Americans here in this country.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to conflate those two things because I think that&#8217;s not a &#8212; that&#8217;s not an accurate representation of what I said.</p>



<p>We have &#8212; we have the supply that we need to vaccinate Americans.&nbsp; What we are asking for is funding to prepare for future eventualities and to ensure that we have what we need as we move forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, on your question about the border, this is nothing new.&nbsp; The effort to vaccinate migrants in our care and custody has been ongoing for months.&nbsp; ICE has been providing vaccines to migrants since the summer of 2021.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re always assessing the situation and addressing protocols based on changing CDC guidance.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, but in order to ensure the safety of border communities and the workforce and the migrants themselves, DHS is now requiring age-appropriate vaccinations for non-citizens who are taken into Border Patrol custody.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, this is consistent with overall CDC guidance for those entering the country, be it by air or land.&nbsp; And we know that vaccinating people is the best way to protect from the virus and to protect against the spread of the virus.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you clarify, though: The New York Times story framed it as something that was about to get underway in certain sectors of the southwest border.&nbsp; Is this some- &#8212; this requirement for a vaccine.&nbsp; Is &#8212; is that accurate?&nbsp; Is that something that is going to take place?&nbsp; Because &#8212; and the reason I ask is you&#8217;re talking about future supply and this is a future effort.&nbsp; How are those two things not sort of in conflict?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, as I said, it&#8217;s &#8212; it is actually nothing new.&nbsp; I mean, we have been vaccinating migrants in our care and custody for many, many months.&nbsp; So ICE, as I said, has been providing vaccines to migrants since the summer of 2021.&nbsp; So this is not anything new.&nbsp; As we know, that this is &#8212; again, the best way to protect people from the virus and to prevent the spread of the virus is to ensure that they&#8217;re vaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you confirm Title 42 is about to end then?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I have no announcement that I can make on Title &#8212; Title 42.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on Ukraine: Yesterday, did the President accidentally reveal a previously unknown effort for the U.S. to be training Ukrainian forces in Poland during his answer in the press conference?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; The troops that he met with in Poland routinely interact with Ukrainians.&nbsp; That is something that&#8217;s known.&nbsp; Many of you were, again, on the trip with us.&nbsp; That is something that&#8217;s known.&nbsp; That is in no way revealing compromised information.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That being said, there&#8217;s nothing further that I have to say on that beyond what the President said yesterday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up, I know you said just now you don&#8217;t have any news on Title 42, which expires on Friday &#8212; or at least the current use of it.&nbsp; When you were &#8212; when we were in Europe, the President announced that he&#8217;s admitting 100,000 Ukrainian asylum seekers.&nbsp; They are exempt from Title 42.&nbsp; Why?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, obviously, we are looking at an extreme crisis in Ukraine.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s &#8212; it is &#8212; it is easy to look at the incredible volume of displacement and the duress that people are under in Ukraine and understand that we need to make &#8212; we need to make efforts to ensure that we are moving to get them to places that are safe.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I can say more broadly about our efforts to &#8212; to bring 100,000 Ukrainian refugees into the country is that, you know, we anticipate that most of these refugees will want to stay closer to home, will want to stay in Europe.&nbsp; But we are making every &#8212; we are putting forward this effort to ensure that we&#8217;re able to &#8212; to accommodate 100,000.</p>



<p>Obviously, on the specifics of that, I would have to refer you to the State Department on the specific workings.&nbsp; But it is important &#8212; as you heard the President say when we were overseas, it&#8217;s important for the United States to do its part and for those countries bordering Ukraine to not be the only ones to shoulder the burden.&nbsp; You heard him talk about that while we were on the ground in Warsaw.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Understood.&nbsp; So the policy decision has been made that the war in Ukraine and the displacement of those people is more urgent to the United States than the displacement of millions of people due to earthquakes, hurricanes, and political strife in this hemisphere?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s a little bit putting words in my mouth.&nbsp; My point was only that we’re &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s how it would be interpreted though &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; &#8212; that that&#8217;s &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; by immigration advocates and others on this side of the world.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a little bit putting words in my mouth.&nbsp; All I&#8217;m saying is that we have put forward a process to allow a hundred thou- &#8212; to bring 100,000 Ukrainian refugees into the country, given the incredible duress and the crisis that they&#8217;re facing in their homeland.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two other quick follow-ups.&nbsp; You said to Cleve, on the question of any medications the President may be taking because of COVID, that that’s private medical information.&nbsp; Is that to say that if he is taking something currently, it will be revealed in his next medical report that we get at some point &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That’s to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the way that Eliquis and Crestor and Dymista had been revealed in the last one?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That&#8217;s simply to say that I don&#8217;t have anything in this moment to provide at this &#8212; at the podium.&nbsp; That&#8217;s medical information.&nbsp; If there is a moment in which it needs to be disclosed, it would obviously be disclosed.&nbsp; As you know, we put out an incredibly fulsome physical report on the President&#8217;s health every year.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s simply to say I don&#8217;t have anything to disclose from this podium at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gotcha.&nbsp; And then, on the Trump logs that appear to have hours of information missing, has the January 6th Committee asked this White House to try to find that information or implore the Archives to dig deeper for them?&nbsp; Has the White House Counsel&#8217;s Office attempted to help reconstruct that record at all?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I would refer you to &#8212; to the Archives on that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any additional information from the Counsel&#8217;s Office at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; Two ones on Ukraine again, if I may.&nbsp; So the sanctions are obviously the stick.&nbsp; Is there &#8212; is there some thinking already about what that carrot could be?&nbsp; You know, essentially, is there going to be some sort of schedule laid out like, you know, “You do this, this comes off”?&nbsp; You know, a roadmap, I suppose, is what it’s called.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t know that Russian activity at this time necessarily merits a carrot.&nbsp; We have been very focused on the stick.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, I am not going to prejudge or lay down any contours of any ultimate negotiation.&nbsp; That is not our role.&nbsp; Again, our role is to strengthen Ukraine on the battlefield, strengthen Ukraine at the negotiating table.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to prejudge any of the &#8212; what ultimately those diplomatic solutions may or may not look like.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just following up on your previous answer about the &#8212; the troops in Poland.&nbsp; Jen did say clearly, last week, there are no U.S. training programs for Ukrainians outside of Ukraine &#8212; obviously not in Ukraine, but nowhere else either.&nbsp; I actually asked the question; that’s what she said &#8212; “no.”</p>



<p>So the President, yesterday &#8212; and I&#8217;ve got his quote; he was very clear.&nbsp; He said when he was &#8212; when he had this chat with the U.S. troops, he said it was all about them “helping [to] train” Ukrainian troops that are in Poland.&nbsp; So are they training them in Poland or are they not training them in Poland?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, as I said, there is regular interaction between Ukrainian soldiers in Poland and the U.S. troops that the President saw on the trip.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing &#8212; no further detail that I can add on that, except to say that there is regular interaction.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you saw, we were there near the border.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s regular interaction between those troops that he saw and Ukrainians.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on Russian oligarch Abramovich, who was photographed today during the&nbsp;peace talks.&nbsp; Does the U.S. have a clear idea of what his role is during these talks?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more to say from this podium about his role.&nbsp; You know, that is something that I am simply not equipped to speak to in this moment, except to say, again, of course, that we are &#8212; we are looking at the allegations into potential harm to him and tracking very closely.&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to follow up on the refugees &#8212; the 100,000 announcement from last week.&nbsp; We were told that there would be a range of legal pathways for them and that would be announced.&nbsp; Is that something that you guys are still working on?&nbsp; Or are we &#8212; can we expect, you know, details about that program soon?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; It is.&nbsp; And, you know, to meet the commitment that the President laid out to welcome 100,000 Ukrainian refugees, we&#8217;re considering the full range of legal pathways to the United States.&nbsp; So, that includes the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program, that includes parole, that includes immigrant and non-immigrant visas.&nbsp; So we are continuing to work through those options.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, ultimately, I would refer you to the State Department for additional detail on how that will &#8212; how that will work.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you &#8212; can I ask you a follow-up question on refugees?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, many people have been advocating that what you are doing for Ukrainians right now is what you should also do for Ethiopia.&nbsp; As you know, tens of thousands of Ethiopians have been killed, millions have been displaced.&nbsp; Why not do the same thing that you do to Europeans to Africans &#8212; to Ethiopians and then to Cameroonians?<br><br>And then one second question.&nbsp; I want to talk about Will Smith and Chris Rock.&nbsp; You know, it’s the biggest story right now.&nbsp; You saw the level of violence that was on &#8212; was unleashed on Chris Rock.&nbsp; Is that something that the White House condones, the type &#8212; that type of violence?&nbsp; Do you condemn it?&nbsp; And do you do anything to support comedians who have been attacked and other artists?&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any official comment from the White House on the altercation.&nbsp; I know the President was not able to watch the Oscars &#8212; didn&#8217;t see it.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any official comment from him or from the White House on this.<br><br>Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate, are you going to answer the Ethiopian question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the question on Ethiopia &#8212;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the Ethiopia question, you didn&#8217;t &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Exactly.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don’t have &#8212; I’m sorry, I don’t have any &#8212; you’re right.&nbsp; I don’t have any additional detail on any plans there.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, you know, as we are focused on working to bring &#8212; to welcome 100,000 Ukrainian refugees here, that does not &#8212; you know, that does not eliminate work that&#8217;s being done in other areas.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t have any specifics to announce from this podium at this time on any plans there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But do you condemn the violence at the Oscars?&nbsp; Is it &#8212; is that something that you condemn, or you can’t &#8212;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I don’t have a White House comment on that.<br><br>Philip, yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The Washington Post reports that Anita Dunn was here at the White House on a special one-week assignment last month.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you could tell us a little bit more about, you know, what was so important for her to be brought in on a one-week assignment like that?&nbsp;<br><br>And then do any other staffers or former staffers in Biden world enjoy that sort of drop-in opportunity?<br><br>And finally, is it true that Dunn avoided any ethics rules that would restrict former White House officials from lobbying one year after leaving their post?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So what I would say to that is Anita is an incredibly trusted advisor who has known the President for a long time.&nbsp; And she did recently come back to the White House temporarily to bring her expertise and add capacity at a key time for the White House.&nbsp; She came to fill in for a staffer who needed to be out for personal reasons.&nbsp;<br><br>She did this as an SGE, as you know &#8212; a Special Government Employee &#8212; which is a temporary, short-term assignment and classification for employees who come to work for the White House in a temporary &#8212; in a temporary manner.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a designation that past administrations have used for the same purpose.&nbsp; And Anita is not the only person to have served in this administration as an SGE.<br><br>Anita and other SGEs receive rigorous counseling on their ethics obligations as an SGE, including avoiding any potential conflicts of interest.&nbsp; And Anita, of course, has always held herself to the highest standards, consistent with this administration&#8217;s commitment to ethics, abiding by all federal ethics laws and policies applicable to SGEs.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more.&nbsp; Forty-five minutes after the President&#8217;s remarks wrapped in Warsaw on Saturday, that was when a statement landed in everyone&#8217;s inboxes from an unnamed White House official saying that, no, the administration did not, in fact, change its policy with regards to Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m wondering if you can tell us anything about what happened in the interim &#8212; in that 45 minutes.&nbsp; Did the President himself conclude that perhaps there needed to be some further clarification?&nbsp; Or did White House advisors come to him and say, “Perhaps you should revisit your recent remarks”?&nbsp; Why was that statement issued?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I can tell you from working for President Biden for seven years that only President Biden decides what President Biden is going to say.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, the statement was simply a confirmation of what the President &#8212; of what you then heard from the President himself yesterday &#8212; that that statement did not represent a policy change &#8212; official policy change on behalf the United States.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But who prompted it?&nbsp; Who prompted it, Kate?&nbsp; I mean, did that come from the President?&nbsp; That particular statement that he&#8217;s referencing, did that come from him to you all?&nbsp; Or did you all go to him and say, “We have to put this out”?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into any further back-and-forth, except to say that I have worked for him for a long time and only he determines what he’s going to say.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a &#8212; and a quick follow-up?&nbsp; A real &#8212;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; quick follow-up.&nbsp; Have you all considered &#8212; when I spoke with authorities in Ukraine, they were saying the no &#8212; the no-fly zone or the cap &#8212; the fly cap that they&#8217;d like over their country would be &#8212; they could sustain that with lend-lease of aircraft and volunteer pilots.&nbsp; Has that been approached?&nbsp; Has the administration considered that?&nbsp; Would they consider &#8212; or would they consider that?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I think the President has been explicitly clear that he does not intend to engage U.S. troops in any way in direct conflict with the Russian military.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; But this wouldn’t be troops.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; And so &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This wouldn’t be troops.&nbsp; They’re talking about lend-lease for the aircraft, and they would supply the pilots.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; They’re &#8212; so, I guess, a couple of things: One is the assessment of our military is that the &#8212; the anti-air, anti-tank, the munitions that we&#8217;re providing to the Ukrainians are the most effective things that they can have on the battlefield.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the assessment of our military commanders and, of course, something that the President factors significantly into his decision making.&nbsp;<br><br>The second thing I would say is that, again, he has been very clear that he is not interested in engaging the U.S. military in direct conflict with Russia.&nbsp; And there are logist- &#8212; there’s &#8212; you know, for example, on the question of the MiGs, there are significant logistical challenges that may raise those issues.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as to whether there&#8217;s a specific discussion about lend-lease, I don&#8217;t have any further detail that I can provide on that, except to just lay out those, kind of, two key points that have really been driving the President&#8217;s thinking and decision making on this.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as far as the assessment of the sanctions, when they first went in, the President said, “Hey, give us a month” and then we&#8217;ll look at them.&nbsp; It’s been a month.&nbsp; Are you happy?&nbsp; Or what would you like to change?&nbsp; Or are you satisfied with where they&#8217;re going?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; With regard to the sanctions that have been &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; &#8212; applied to Russia?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I think you&#8217;ve seen us continue to escalate over the course of the last &#8212; since the invasion began on the 24th of February.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve seen unprecedented costs inflicted on the Russian economy.&nbsp; I think, again, even just last week, while he was in Europe, the President announced another round of sanctions in consultation with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; So we continue to increase the pressure and to ensure that we are inflicting maximum cost on Russia for its aggression.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you’re happy with them?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate, I wanted to know: What will President Biden&#8217;s response if Israel bombs Iran’s nuclear reactors?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I &#8212; I am not going to get into that kind of &#8212; that kind of hypothetical, but thank you &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; thank you for the question.<br><br>Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; So, there are reports that the administration is considering providing Ukraine with an additional $500 million in aid and is pushing European countries to make the same sort of effort.&nbsp; Can you confirm or provide &#8212; and provide more details on that?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, what I can say to that is we are in constant consultation with our Allies and partners about continued aid to Ukraine.&nbsp; But discussion of a specific dollar amount &#8212; there&#8217;s no discussion currently of a specific dollar amount.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate, a few questions on Singapore.&nbsp; The first question is: The Prime Minister welcomed the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp; When will see &#8212; when will we see the exact plan?&nbsp; And will the framework need to be ratified by the Congress?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have an update on timeline for you on that.&nbsp; I would &#8212; we’ll be happy to come back to you with further information, but I don&#8217;t have an update on when you can expect to see a timeline for that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I can certainly say that today&#8217;s meeting between the two leaders demonstrated the strong security, economic, and people-to-people ties shared by the United States and Singapore.&nbsp; And President Biden looks forward to continuing to deepen those ties.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also in the joint statement, the U.S. and Singapore reaffirmed the right of freedom of navigation accorded by international laws, including UNCLOS.&nbsp; Will the U.S. ratify UNCLOS under Biden administration?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an answer for you at this moment, but I&#8217;m happy to get more information and come back to you on it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I have a&nbsp;couple quick ones.&nbsp; I have a couple of quick ones for you before we go.&nbsp; Following up on what Tarini asked you with regards to the refugee programs, it can take years for refugees to be able to be vetted to come into the United States.&nbsp; So does the White House have a sense of how quickly the Ukrainian refugees will be able to come to the U.S.?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We’re working to move as quickly as possible.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a firm timeline that I can give you, but obviously, we&#8217;ll move as quickly as possible to bring in as many &#8212; up to that 100,000 as we possibly can.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And after Florida Governor Ron DeSantis, yesterday, signed the state&#8217;s Parental Rights in Education legislation, Education Secretary Miguel Cardona said the administration will be monitoring its implementation “to evaluate whether it violates federal civil rights law.”&nbsp;<br><br>Aside from monitoring the Florida law, is there any other actions that the White House plans to take?<br><br>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, both the President and Secretary Cardona spoke out very forcefully against the law.&nbsp; The President also put out a statement yesterday about the tragic impact of this kind of law on an incredibly vulnerable population.&nbsp; And he said that, you know, by signing this bill, the governor has chosen to target some of Florida&#8217;s most vulnerable students and families, all while under the guise of parents’ rights.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the Department of Education, as you noted, will continue &#8212; will monitor this law upon implementation to evaluate whether it violates federal civil rights law.&nbsp; And obviously, we will come back to you as we have more information on that.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>3:51 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
