<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 13:47:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Establishment of the White&#160;House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and&#160;Abuse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/16/memorandum-on-the-establishment-of-the-white-house-task-force-to-address-online-harassment-and-abuse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 13:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES SUBJECT:       Establishment of the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to improve efforts to prevent and address online harassment and abuse,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Establishment of the White House Task Force to <br>                           Address Online Harassment and Abuse</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to improve efforts to prevent and address online harassment and abuse, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1.  Policy.  Technology platforms and social media can be vital tools for expression, civic participation, and building a sense of community.  But the scale, reach, and amplification effects of technology platforms have also exacerbated gender-based violence, particularly through online harassment and abuse.  Online harassment and abuse include a broad array of harmful and sometimes illegal behaviors that are perpetrated through the use of technology.  Women, adolescent girls, and LGBTQI+ individuals, who may be additionally targeted because of their race, ethnicity, religion, and other factors, can experience more severe harms from online harassment and abuse.  Online harassment and abuse take many forms, including the non-consensual distribution of intimate digital images; cyberstalking; sextortion; doxing; malicious deep fakes; gendered disinformation; rape and death threats; the online recruitment and exploitation of victims of sex trafficking; and various forms of technology-facilitated intimate partner abuse.  In the United States, 1 in 3 women under the age of 35 reports having been sexually harassed online, and over half of LGBTQI+ individuals report having been the target of severe online abuse, including sustained harassment, physical threats, and stalking in addition to sexual harassment.  Globally, half of girls report that they are more likely to be harassed through social media than on the street.</p>



<p>In the United States and around the world, women and LGBTQI+ political leaders, public figures, activists, and journalists are especially targeted by sexualized forms of online harassment and abuse, undermining their ability to exercise their human rights and participate in democracy, governance, and civic life.&nbsp;&nbsp;Online abuse and harassment, which aim to preclude women from political decision-making about their own lives and communities, undermine the functioning of democracy.&nbsp;&nbsp;Growing evidence also demonstrates that online radicalization can be linked to gender-based violence, which, along with other forms of abuse and harassment, spans the digital and physical realms.&nbsp;&nbsp;Online harassment and abuse can result in a range of dire consequences for victims, from psychological distress and self-censorship to economic losses, disruptions to education, increased self-harm, suicide, homicide, and other forms of physical and sexual violence.&nbsp;&nbsp;Further, digital technologies are often used in concert with other forms of abuse and harassment, underscoring the urgency of addressing the interplay of in-person and online harms.&nbsp;&nbsp;More research is needed to fully understand the nature, magnitude, and costs of these harms and ways to address them in the United&nbsp;States and globally.</p>



<p>Therefore, I am directing the Director of the White House Gender Policy Council and the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to lead an interagency effort to address online harassment and abuse, specifically focused on technology-facilitated gender-based violence, and to&nbsp;develop concrete recommendations to improve prevention, response, and protection efforts through programs and policies in the United States and globally.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;2.&nbsp;&nbsp;Establishment.&nbsp;&nbsp;There&nbsp;is established within the Executive Office of the President the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse (Task Force).</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;3.&nbsp;&nbsp;Membership.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;The&nbsp;Director of the White House Gender Policy Council and the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs,&nbsp;or their designees, shall serve as Co-Chairs of the Task Force.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;In addition to the Co-Chairs, the Task Force shall consist of the following members:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of State;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Defense;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Attorney General;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Commerce;</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</p>



<p>(vi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Education;</p>



<p>(vii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</p>



<p>(viii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Homeland Security;</p>



<p>(ix)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy;</p>



<p>(x)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Assistant to the President and Director of the Domestic Policy Council;</p>



<p>(xi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Assistant to the President for Economic Policy and Director of the National Economic Council;</p>



<p>(xii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development;</p>



<p>(xiii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the Counsel to the President;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(xiv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the Counsel to the Vice President; and</p>



<p>(xv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the heads of such other executive departments, agencies, and offices as the Co-Chairs may, from time to time, designate.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;A member of the Task Force may designate, to perform the Task Force functions of the member, senior officials within the member&#8217;s executive department, agency, or office who are full-time officers or employees of the Federal Government.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;4.&nbsp;&nbsp;Mission and Function.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;The Task Force shall work across executive departments, agencies, and offices to assess and address online harassment and abuse that constitute technology-facilitated gender-based violence, including by:&nbsp;</p>



<p>(i)    improving coordination among executive departments, agencies, and offices to maximize the Federal Government&#8217;s effectiveness in preventing and addressing technology-facilitated gender-based violence in the United States and globally, including by developing policy solutions to enhance accountability for those who perpetrate online harms;</p>



<p>(ii)   enhancing and expanding data collection and research across the Federal Government to measure the costs, prevalence, exposure to, and impact of technology-facilitated gender-based violence, including by studying the mental health effects of abuse on social media, particularly affecting adolescents; </p>



<p>(iii)  increasing access to survivor-centered services, information, and support for victims, and increasing training and technical assistance for Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments as well as for global organizations and entities in the fields of criminal justice, health and mental health services, education, and victim services;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;developing programs and policies to address&nbsp;online&nbsp;harassment, abuse, and disinformation campaigns targeting women and LGBTQI+ individuals who are public and political figures, government and civic leaders, activists, and journalists in the United States and globally;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp;&nbsp;examining existing Federal laws, regulations, and policies to evaluate the adequacy of the current legal framework to address technology-facilitated gender-based violence; and</p>



<p>(vi)    identifying additional opportunities to improve efforts to prevent and address technology-facilitated gender-based violence in United States foreign policy and foreign assistance, including through the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;Consistent with the objectives of this memorandum and applicable law, the Task Force may consult with and gather relevant information from external stakeholders, including&nbsp;Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial government officials, as well as victim advocates, survivors, law enforcement personnel, researchers and academics, civil and human rights groups, philanthropic leaders, technology experts, legal and international policy experts, industry stakeholders, and other entities and persons the Task Force identifies that will assist the Task Force in accomplishing the objectives of this memorandum.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;5.&nbsp;&nbsp;Reporting on the Work and Recommendations of the Task Force.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this memorandum, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall submit to the President a blueprint (Initial Blueprint) outlining a whole-of-government approach to preventing and addressing technology-facilitated gender-based violence, including concrete actions that executive departments, agencies, and offices have committed to take to implement the Task Force&#8217;s recommendations.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Initial Blueprint shall include a synopsis of key lessons from stakeholder consultations and preliminary recommendations for advancing strategies to improve efforts to prevent and address technology-facilitated gender-based violence.&nbsp;&nbsp;Following submission of the Initial Blueprint to the President, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall make an executive summary of the Initial Blueprint publicly available.</p>



<p>(b)  Within 1 year of the date that the Initial Blueprint is submitted to the President, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall submit to the President and make publicly available an update and report (1-Year Report) with additional recommendations and actions that executive departments, agencies, and offices can take to advance how Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments; service providers; international organizations; technology platforms; schools; and other public and private entities can improve efforts to prevent and address technology-facilitated gender-based violence.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;Prior to issuing its Initial Blueprint and 1-Year Report, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall consolidate&nbsp;any input received and&nbsp;submit periodic recommendations to the President on policies, regulatory actions, and legislation&nbsp;on technology sector accountability to address systemic harms to people affected by online harassment and abuse.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp;&nbsp;Following the submission of the 1-Year Report to the President, the Co-Chairs of the Task Force shall, on an annual basis, submit a follow-up report to the President on implementation of this memorandum.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;6.&nbsp;&nbsp;Definition.&nbsp;&nbsp;For the purposes of this memorandum, the term &#8220;technology-facilitated gender-based violence&#8221; shall refer to any form of gender-based violence, including harassment and abuse, which takes place through, or is aided by, the use of digital technologies and devices.</p>



<p>Sec.&nbsp;7.&nbsp;&nbsp;General Provisions.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;This memorandum shall not apply to independent regulatory agencies as described in section 3502(5) of title 44, United States Code.&nbsp;&nbsp;Independent regulatory agencies are nevertheless strongly encouraged to participate in the work of the Task Force.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp;&nbsp;This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp;&nbsp;The Attorney General is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Presidential Memorandum Establishing the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and&#160;Abuse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/16/fact-sheet-presidential-memorandum-establishing-the-white-house-task-force-to-address-online-harassment-and-abuse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 12:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden will sign a Presidential Memorandum establishing the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse, responding to the need for government leadership to address online harms, which disproportionately affect women, girls, people of color, and LGBTQI+ individuals.&#160;Vice President Harris will launch the Task Force by hosting a survivor and expert&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden will sign a Presidential Memorandum establishing the White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse, responding to the need for government leadership to address online harms, which disproportionately affect women, girls, people of color, and LGBTQI+ individuals.&nbsp;Vice President Harris will launch the Task Force by hosting a survivor and expert roundtable this afternoon. The tragic events in Buffalo and Uvalde have underscored a fact known all too well by many Americans: the internet can fuel hate, misogyny, and abuse with spillover effects that threaten our communities and safety offline.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden has long championed efforts to prevent and address gender-based violence, including writing and passing the landmark Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) nearly three decades ago as a U.S. Senator and signing its&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/fact-sheet-reauthorization-of-the-violence-against-women-act-vawa/">reauthorization</a>&nbsp;into law earlier this year.&nbsp;&nbsp;The reauthorized VAWA includes historic new protections against online harassment and abuse. Vice President Harris, who is hosting today’s Task Force, has long been a champion of addressing online harassment and abuse throughout her career, including as United States Senator and California’s Attorney General.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Task Force will produce recommendations for the Federal government, state governments, technology platforms, schools, and other public and private entities to prevent and address technology-facilitated gender-based violence, including a focus on&nbsp;the nexus between online misogyny and radicalization to violence.&nbsp;&nbsp;Recommendations will focus particularly on: increasing support for survivors of online harassment and abuse; expanding research to better understand the impact and scope of the problem; enhancing prevention, including prevention focused on youth; and strengthening accountability for offenders and platforms. The Task Force will be co-chaired by the Gender Policy Council and the National Security Council, and will include the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and other heads of Federal agencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Strengthening the Federal Response to Online Harms: White House Task Force to Address Online Harassment and Abuse</strong><br></p>



<p>The Task Force is an interagency effort to address online harassment and abuse, specifically focused on technology-facilitated gender-based violence. In consultation with survivors, advocates, educators, experts from diverse fields, and the private sector, the Task Force will develop specific recommendations to improve prevention, response, and protection efforts through programs and policies in the United States and globally by:</p>



<ul><li>Improving coordination among executive departments, agencies, and offices to maximize the Federal Government&#8217;s effectiveness in preventing and addressing technology-facilitated gender-based violence in the United States and globally, including by developing policy solutions to enhance accountability for those who perpetrate online harms;</li><li>Enhancing and expanding data collection and research across the Federal Government to measure the costs, prevalence, exposure to, and impact of technology-facilitated gender-based violence, including by studying the mental health effects of harassment and abuse perpetrated through social media, particularly affecting adolescents;&nbsp;</li><li>Increasing access to survivor-centered services, information, and support for victims, and increasing training and technical assistance for Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial governments, as well as for global organizations and entities in the fields of criminal justice, health and mental health services, education, and victim services;</li><li>Developing programs and policies to address the disproportionate impact of online harassment, abuse, and disinformation campaigns targeting women and LGBTQI+ individuals who are public and political figures, government and civic leaders, activists, and journalists in the United States and globally;&nbsp;</li><li>Examining existing Federal laws, regulations, and policies to evaluate the adequacy of the current legal framework to address technology-facilitated gender-based violence and provide recommendations for strengthening it; and</li><li>Identifying additional opportunities to improve efforts to prevent and address technology-facilitated gender-based violence in United States foreign policy and foreign assistance, including through the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.state.gov/2022-roadmap-for-the-global-partnership-for-action-on-gender-based-online-harassment-and-abuse/">Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse.</a></li></ul>



<p><br><strong>Background<br></strong>When President Biden first wrote and championed the Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) in the early 1990s, the internet was still in its infancy. Today, the internet has transformed our ability to connect, communicate, and access services and support. At the same time, social media and other forms of technology are increasingly misused as tools of abuse, harassment, and exploitation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the United States, one in three women under the age of 35 report being sexually harassed online, and over half of LGBTQI+ individuals report being the target of severe online abuse. Individuals may also be disproportionately targeted because of their race, gender and gender identity, ethnicity, religion, age, disability, sexual orientation, or at the intersection of various identities.&nbsp;&nbsp;Online harassment and abuse take many forms, including the non-consensual distribution of intimate digital images; cyberstalking; sextortion; doxing; malicious deep fakes; gendered disinformation; rape and death threats; the distribution of child sexual abuse materials; online recruitment and exploitation of victims of sex trafficking, including youth; and various other forms of technology-facilitated intimate partner abuse.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Technology-facilitated gender-based violence can have serious consequences, ranging from psychological distress and negative health impacts, including self-harm and suicide, to self-censorship and disruptions to education and economic loss.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;It can also lead to physical and sexual violence, including homicide.&nbsp;&nbsp;In the United States and around the world, women and LGBTQI+ political leaders, public figures, activists, and journalists face virulent and often sexualized online harassment and abuse, which can undermine human rights and full participation in democracy, governance, and civic life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Recent mass shootings have also underscored the connections between online harassment, hate, misogyny, and extremist acts.&nbsp;&nbsp;For example, the Uvalde shooter had a history of threatening girls online, yet these violent, sexualized harms and threats were dismissed and ignored when reported.&nbsp;&nbsp;In their annual report on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.secretservice.gov/sites/default/files/reports/2020-09/MAPS2019.pdf">Mass Attacks in Public Spaces</a>,&nbsp;the U.S. Secret Service notes that special focus should be given to assessing threats and preventing violence related to “men who use digital platforms to voice misogynistic views and general animosity toward women.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The Biden-Harris Administration Efforts to Combat Online Harassment and Abuse&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris have long been committed to standing with survivors of gender-based violence wherever it occurs—including online. Through this Task Force, they will lead a strategic vision for countering online forms of violence, harassment and abuse. Alongside the launch of the Task Force, the Biden-Harris Administration is undertaking several key actions, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Advancing Technology to Assist Victims of Crime Program.</strong> The Department of Justice (DOJ) Office for Victims of Crime will award $3 million to victim services organizations through the <a href="https://ovc.ojp.gov/funding/opportunities/o-ovc-2022-171237">Advancing the Use of Technology to Assist Victims of Crime</a> program. This program will support initiatives that use technology to increase access to services and information about victims’ rights, enhance service providers’ understanding of technology-facilitated gender-based violence, and strengthen the responsiveness of victim service organizations supporting survivors of technology-facilitated gender-based violence.</li><li><strong>National Domestic Violence Hotline Survivor Survey</strong>. The National Domestic Violence Hotline, through funding from the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Family Violence Prevention and Services Program, will provide a preliminary report on its survivor survey research project, which was undertaken this spring and for the first-time asked survivors about their experiences of online harassment and abuse. The Hotline heard from approximately 1,000 survivors who completed the survey.  <em>Every</em> survivor reported they had experienced at least one form of online harassment or abuse, including 45% who said they experienced cyberstalking, 27% reported being threatened with the posting of intimate images without permission; 17% reported the posting of intimate pictures without permission; and 12% reported sextortion. These insights will help inform the work of the Task Force.</li><li><strong>Research from the National Threat Assessment Center</strong>. The U.S. Secret Service’s National Threat Assessment Center (NTAC), under the Department of Homeland Security, is adding to its research on the nexus between online misogyny and domestic terrorism by preparing a report examining the role of domestic violence as a motive and precursor to mass violence, including an analysis of the prior communications and online presence of the attackers. This report will build on its most recent report, <a href="https://www.secretservice.gov/sites/default/files/reports/2022-03/NTAC%20Case%20Study%20-%20Hot%20Yoga%20Tallahassee_0.pdf">Hot Yoga Tallahassee: A Case Study of Misogynistic Extremism</a>, which analyzes the background of a 2018 attacker who killed two women and injured four more at a yoga studio in Tallahassee, FL, and highlights the specific threat posed by misogynistic extremism.</li><li><strong>Research on Access to Services for Survivors of Cyberstalking</strong>. The Department of Justice Office on Violence Against Women has funded the National Opinion Research Center to collect nationally representative data on cyberstalking in the United States to assess its scope and nature, as well as determine survivors’ access to services and any unmet needs. Research is underway, and report findings will be published later this year. </li><li><strong>Expanded Focus on Technological Abuse in the Reauthorized Violence Against Women Act.</strong> The Department of Justice (DOJ) will implement new statutory provisions in the recent reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) of 2022, which includes for the first time a definition of “technological abuse,” recognizing the importance of addressing this form of abuse at the intersection with domestic violence, sexual assault, stalking, and dating violence.  Under VAWA 2022, the Attorney General will develop a national strategy to prevent and address cybercrimes against individuals, including cyberstalking and the non-consensual distribution of intimate images of adults, and directs the FBI to improve data collection regarding these crimes. DOJ will also help raise awareness among victim advocates of the new VAWA provision that establishes a federal civil cause of action for an individual who has an intimate visual depiction of themselves disclosed without their consent, with damages up to $150,000 and attorney’s fees.</li><li><strong>New Report on the Online Harassment of Women Political Figures.</strong> In partnership with the State Department&#8217;s Office of Global Women&#8217;s Issues, Texas A&amp;M University&#8217;s Program on Women, Peace, and Security are <a href="/bush.tamu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/WPS-Report-FINAL-draft.pdf">releasing a report</a> on &#8220;Technological Threats: How Online Harassment of Female Political Figures Undermines Democracy.&#8221; The report highlights research and policy on the intersection between online harassment, technology, women&#8217;s political participation, and democracy. </li><li><strong>Expansion of the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse.</strong>  To address online harassment and abuse globally, the State Department will expand the <a href="https://www.state.gov/2022-roadmap-for-the-global-partnership-for-action-on-gender-based-online-harassment-and-abuse/">Global Partnership for Action</a> on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse, announced at the Summit for Democracy in December and officially launched in March at the United Nations Commission on the Status of Women. The Global Partnership brings together countries, international organizations, civil society, and the private sector to better prioritize, understand, prevent, and address the growing scourge of technology-facilitated gender-based violence around the world. Since its launch, the Global Partnership has continued to grow its member countries, and recently welcomed the governments of Canada, Chile, and New Zealand, who joined the United States, along with Australia, Denmark, the Republic of Korea, Sweden, and the United Kingdom.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the President’s Meeting with Speaker Pelosi and Leader&#160;Schumer</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/15/readout-of-the-presidents-meeting-with-speaker-pelosi-and-leader-schumer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon, President Biden hosted Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer to talk about their shared agenda of tackling inflation and lowering prices and transitioning from a historic economic recovery to stable, steady growth. Thanks to their shared leadership, we&#8217;ve seen unprecedented job and small business creation. They discussed their plans for fighting the global problem&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This afternoon, President Biden hosted Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer to talk about their shared agenda of tackling inflation and lowering prices and transitioning from a historic economic recovery to stable, steady growth. Thanks to their shared leadership, we&#8217;ve seen unprecedented job and small business creation. They discussed their plans for fighting the global problem of inflation that is affecting every major economy, such as bringing down prescription drug and energy costs, and adding to the historic deficit reduction we have accomplished.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications John&#160;Kirby</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/15/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-nsc-coordinator-for-strategic-communications-john-kirby/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 22:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55615</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room  3:13 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Okay.&#160; As I’m sure you all have seen, there has been a few important foreign policy announcements over the last couple of days.&#160; And so, we were unable to have a full briefing yesterday, and I wanted to make sure you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p> 3:13 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; As I’m sure you all have seen, there has been a few important foreign policy announcements over the last couple of days.&nbsp; And so, we were unable to have a full briefing yesterday, and I wanted to make sure you all had an opportunity to ask some questions on all of our foreign policy news.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, today, we&#8217;re happy to have here, join me at the podium, Mr. John Kirby &#8212; Admiral Kirby.&nbsp; he likes to call me “Ma&#8217;am,” so I call him “Kirby.”&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;ll call you guys “sir” and “ma’ams” as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>He is the &#8212; as you all know, the National Security Council Coordinator for Strategic Communications.&nbsp; Not only does he have an extensive military background, but he also has experience at the State Department.</p>



<p>And he is happy to take a few questions.&nbsp; Kirby, I&#8217;m going to leave you to it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Hey, everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good to see you.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Pardon me?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good to see you.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, you too.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Listen, just a &#8212; just a note off the top.&nbsp; I think you saw the statement, but I think it&#8217;s worth reiterating: The President had a very good call today with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It was an opportunity for President Zelenskyy to update President Biden on what&#8217;s going on on the battlefield and on the ground, and to talk to the President about Ukraine&#8217;s security requirements and capabilities going forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President also, obviously, took this opportunity to inform President Zelenskyy that we&#8217;re announcing today, I think you saw, a billion dollars in additional security assistance to support Ukraine&#8217;s armed forces in their brave defense of their country.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, that includes a drawdown of security assistance valued up to $350 million &#8212; that&#8217;s where the Department of Defense pulls from their stocks; as well as $650 million in equipment that&#8217;s provided through the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative funds &#8212; that&#8217;s where the Pentagon will go out and procure material according &#8212; in that amount to then just provide directly to Ukraine.&nbsp; So, there are two different buckets of that billion dollars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, this is the 12th time that President Biden has authorized presidential drawdowns to help Ukraine defend its democracy.&nbsp; And that brings the total amount of security assistance that we’ve provided to Ukraine to approximately $5.6 billion just since Russia launched its assault in late February, and then approximately $6.3 billion since the beginning of the Biden-Harris administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President also informed President Zelenskyy that the United States is going to send an additional $225 million in lifesaving humanitarian assistance to help people inside Ukraine obtain safe drinking water, critical medical supplies, healthcare, food, shelter, and all kinds of other essential items.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think you all realize the scope of the numbers of internally displaced people just inside Ukraine, let alone the millions that have had to leave Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, since February 24th, the United States has now, then, provided more than $914 million in humanitarian assistance to address the needs of people in Ukraine and for those who have had to flee.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s almost a billion dollars just in humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Ready?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I&#8217;m ready.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Who had a question?</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; You bet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My question is more about the temperature in Europe surrounding as you guys are continuing to crank up aid.&nbsp; But today, President Macron said that, at some point, Ukraine&#8217;s President will have to negotiate with Russia.&nbsp; And that seems quite different from what President Biden and many administration officials &#8212; including, I think, you &#8212; have said about the need of stressing not telling the Ukrainians what to do.&nbsp; Would the administration prefer the French and also other Europeans to sort of dial down the nudging?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ll let other foreign leaders speak for themselves and &#8212; and for their countries and for their national interests.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s appropriate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But nothing has changed about President Biden&#8217;s view here &#8212; is that “nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine” and that Ukraine is a sovereign country.&nbsp; President Zelenskyy is the democratically elected leader of that country, and he gets to determine how this war ends.&nbsp; He gets to determine how he defines victory and how he gets at that outcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, just real quick, another small associated Russia question.&nbsp; Navalny confirmed today on Telegram that he was moved to a maximum-security prison in Vladimir, I believe.&nbsp; Have you guys been able to confirm that?</p>



<p>And second, is there any sort of response to the Russians moving him into even stricter confines?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, well, we&#8217;re not &#8212; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re in a position to absolutely confirm the reports.&nbsp; Certainly, we&#8217;re also in no position to refute them at this time.&nbsp; Obviously, Mr. Navalny is speaking for himself.</p>



<p>But I will tell you, we continue to reiterate our demand for his immediate and unconditional release from &#8212; from being imprisoned over spurious charges after a sham trial.&nbsp; And the Russian &#8212; Russian authorities ought to immediately end their harassment and intimidation against him and his supporters and, again, continue to call for his immediate and unconditional release.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Peter.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I had a question about U.S. national security.&nbsp; How is it that you guys have determined that it&#8217;s in the U.S. national security interest to ask Saudi Arabia to drill more oil instead of just letting oil companies drill more here in the U.S.?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: &nbsp;Well, I think you know, Peter, there&#8217;s some 9,000 unused drilling permits here in the United States as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>Look, the oil production issue is a global issue.&nbsp; And OPEC+<s>3</s>&nbsp;has already increased preset increases by more than 50 percent just for July and August.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re grateful to Saudi Arabia&#8217;s leadership on that.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve never said that &#8212; we&#8217;ve never said it&#8217;s a national security interest that somebody has to pump more oil.&nbsp;&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>And again, there&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s unused permits here in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And &#8212; but as a national strategic issue then, how is it in the &#8212; how much lower can we let the Strategic Petroleum Reserves get before that becomes a problem?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I think I would refer to the President&#8217;s energy advisors on something like that, Peter.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t know what the inventory is.&nbsp; But I do, you know, remind &#8212; and I think you know this &#8212; the President did tap into the Strategic Oil Reserves to try to relieve some of the pressure at the pump, and he&#8217;ll use a range of tools available to him going forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that&#8217;s about the best I can do on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; I have a Saudi question.&nbsp; But first, can you comment, or what does the White House have to say, about these two Americans that have been captured that were fighting alongside Ukrainian forces?&nbsp; They&#8217;re missing.&nbsp; They are feared captured by the Russians.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, I can&#8217;t confirm the reports, Kaitlan.&nbsp; Just was made aware of them before I came out here.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll do the best we can to monitor this and see what we can learn about it.&nbsp; And &#8212; well, without getting into a hypothetical, obviously, if it&#8217;s true, we&#8217;ll do everything we can to get them safely back home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do think, however, that this is an important point in time to remind that we discourage Americans from going to Ukraine and fighting in Ukraine.&nbsp; It is a war zone.&nbsp; It is &#8212; it’s combat.&nbsp; And if you feel passionate about supporting Ukraine, there&#8217;s any number of other ways to do that that are safer and just as effective.</p>



<p>I &#8212; we just &#8212; Ukraine is not the place for Americans to be traveling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has the President been made aware of these reports?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware that the President has been made aware of it.&nbsp; I mean, it just &#8212; it just broke &#8212; broke.&nbsp; So, I don’t know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my question on Saudi Arabia: Why not have the President go there and just not meet with the Crown Prince?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; The President is going to Saudi for the GCC &#8212; the GCC+3, to be honest.&nbsp; It&#8217;s nine states in the region.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a big agenda there, Kaitlan, on the Gulf Cooperation Council.&nbsp; It’s counterterrorism.&nbsp; It’s climate change.&nbsp; Certainly, it’s &#8212; oil production, obviously, is going to be on the agenda.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and a big item on the agenda is the war in Yemen.&nbsp; We got a ceasefire now that’s been in place for two months, got extended another two.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a big deal.&nbsp; That&#8217;s thousands of lives now in Yemen.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand there&#8217;s a lot to talk about.&nbsp; But why &#8212; if the President won&#8217;t even speak to the Crown Prince on the phone, why would he go and meet with him in person?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, I was kind of getting there.&nbsp; So, in addition to the GCC meeting, there&#8217;ll be a series of bilateral discussions, as there are on the sidelines of all cooperation councils and summits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He will have a bilateral meeting with King Salman and King Salman&#8217;s leadership team.&nbsp; And the Crown Prince is on that leadership team, so you can expect that he will see the Crown Prince while he&#8217;s there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he could ask for the Crown Prince not to be in the room, given the CIA has concluded he authorized the murder of a reporter that lived in Virginia.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to have a series of bilateral discussions with the kings &#8212; the King and his leadership team.&nbsp; The Crown Prince is the Defense Minister of Saudi Arabia, and one would expect that he would need to be in the room for those meetings.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Trevor Hunnicutt, from Reuters.&nbsp; Just wanted to close the loop first on the meeting that President Biden had with Bolsonaro of Brazil last week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There has been some reporting that suggested that Biden told Bolsonaro that he would reexamine steel tariffs &#8212; Brazilian steel tariffs &#8212; and that Bolsonaro asked him for support in the October election against Lula.&nbsp; Are either of those things true?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, I think we gave a pretty fulsome readout of that meeting when &#8212; the trip that Karine &#8212; Karine was on.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more to add than what was in the readout.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) about those two issues, but not &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;m not going to go beyond the readout.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on China tariffs, we know that that&#8217;s something that the President is looking at.&nbsp; Could you talk a little bit about, one, the scope of the tariffs that he is looking at and if you expect that that will be finalized by, say, the end of July?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I would just go so far as to say is the &#8212; the President wants to make sure that if we have tariffs in place, that they&#8217;re serving our interests and the interests of the American people.&nbsp; And &#8212; and he wants to make sure that as he reviews the &#8212; a tariff regime, that it&#8217;s &#8212; that it’s meeting those needs.&nbsp; And I think he&#8217;s going to keep his mind open, but I don&#8217;t have any more detail than that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’ll take some in the back.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; Two quick questions, please.&nbsp; One on &#8212; following the latest Xi-Putin call, where apparently Xi was talking about expanding cooperation with the Russians, has &#8212; has there been any sign so far and do you see any sign coming that China is actually helping Russia militarily in any shape or form?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t seen any indication that there&#8217;s been specific military assistance provided by China to Russia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the other question: Could you give a little bit more on the President&#8217;s comments yesterday about these grain silos being &#8212; the plans to build grain silos on the borders of Ukraine?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the timescale of that?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the scale of that?&nbsp; And how much difference would it make?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Look, I think we&#8217;re working real hard &#8211;not just with the leadership in Ukraine, but in the region &#8212; to try to relieve the pressure that has resulted from Mr. Putin literally weaponizing food.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the President is looking at a range of options here to &#8212; to try to see if we can get grain out and into the market.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s tricky business.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not going to be easy.&nbsp; I mean, he&#8217;s essentially got a blockade in the Black Sea where it&#8217;s not going out by &#8212; by sea.&nbsp; So that doesn&#8217;t leave you a whole lot of other options.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working through &#8212; with the international community to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have any additional information on options about temporary silos, but I can tell you that, again, the President is keeping an open mind here.&nbsp; He wants to do everything he can to try to get that grain to market.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Nadia.&nbsp; Nadia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Hi, John.&nbsp; Despite your &#8212; going back to Ukraine &#8212; despite your announcement today of the military aid to Ukraine, it seems that Europe is divided between two camps.&nbsp; They call it the “peace camp,” led by France and Germany, Italy; and the “justice camp,” led by Poland and others, which is &#8212; basically, some wants Ukraine to negotiate and others want them to continue fighting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Where does the United States stands?&nbsp; And the fact that you keep supplying them with weapons, does that mean that you are with Poland and the Baltic States and others?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Look, the President is on the side of the people of Ukraine, and he wants to make sure that &#8212; that we&#8217;re doing everything we can to help Ukraine&#8217;s armed forces succeed on the battlefield and to give them &#8212; if and when this gets to a negotiation &#8212; that they have the leverage and the position they need in that.</p>



<p>But ultimately, Nadia, that&#8217;s going to be up to Mr. Zelenskyy to determine.&nbsp; He is the democratically elected leader of a sovereign state, and their sovereignty is what&#8217;s at risk right now.&nbsp; And he wants to make sure that that sovereignty is preserved, that they &#8212; that they get to decide what that looks like here.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about this, sort of, ongoing question of an investigation around the death of Shireen Abu Akleh, the Al Jazeera journalist and U.S. citizen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know that Secretary of State Antony Blinken said last week that he would look for an independent investigation.&nbsp; And I was wondering if you all could explain what type of investigation this administration wants.&nbsp; I know a number of news outlets &#8212; Washington Post, CNN, AP &#8212; have come out for new investigations.&nbsp; And then also, we&#8217;ve seen Mitt Romney and I believe it was Jon Ossoff write a letter to the administration calling for an investigation.&nbsp; So what type of investigation would you want?&nbsp; What does an independent investigation look like?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; What &#8212; what we want is, obviously, for this to be fully investigated and if there needs to be accountability had, accountability had at the end of that investigation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve called for thorough, complete, transparent investigations into her death.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be watching this very, very closely.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any additional details on what an independent investigation would look like.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have that for you today.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t want you to walk away thinking that we don&#8217;t want this fully investigated and for that investigation to be thorough and transparent.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this something the President intends to discuss on his trip?&nbsp; I mean, he is going to two countries, as Kaitlan mentioned, where journalists have recently been killed and there has been a lot of public outcry.&nbsp; And I know you all talk a lot here about press freedoms &#8212; and I&#8217;m sure we all appreciate it &#8212; but I&#8217;m just curious how that&#8217;s going to come up both in Israel and Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; It means a lot to President Biden &#8212; press freedom.&nbsp; And I won&#8217;t get ahead of the President&#8217;s specific discussions on this trip.&nbsp; I can just tell you that &#8212; that his foreign policy is really rooted in values &#8212; values like freedom of the press; values like human rights, civil rights.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s not going to be bashful about raising those issues with any foreign leader anywhere in the world.</p>



<p><a>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Last two.&nbsp;&nbsp;<s>Justin</s>[Jordan] and then Ed.&nbsp;&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I want to ask you about &#8212; Turkish President Erdoğan today said that his concerns about Sweden and Finland joining NATO have not been assuaged.&nbsp; So how much less optimistic are you now that accession talks might begin before this month&#8217;s summit in Madrid?&nbsp; And does the U.S. plan to get more directly involved to try and resolve that dispute?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; We&#8217;re still optimistic that &#8212; that these issues will be able to be worked out, and that Finland and Sweden will be able to join NATO.&nbsp; Now, I couldn&#8217;t give you a date certain here and a time, but I think we&#8217;re still optimistic that they&#8217;ll be able to work this out.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we know that both countries are working directly with Turkey to try to address those concerns.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; we think, at this point, it&#8217;s better left to them as sovereign nations to do that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Ed, the last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two &#8212; two on Ukraine.&nbsp; And welcome to the room.&nbsp; Going back first to &#8212; you talked about food and how it&#8217;s being weaponized by Putin in Ukraine, and that there are U.S. officials starting to discuss how to get grain and whatnot out of &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Ukraine and to the areas of the world that need it.&nbsp; A big area of that world that needs it also happens to be countries that will be at that conference in Saudi Arabia and OPEC-producing countries.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say any more about what&#8217;s being considered or what&#8217;s being done, potentially, to get that out and whether &#8212; or to what extent that agreement stretches regionally, beyond Ukraine and the United States being concerned about it?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; What I can say is that we&#8217;re working very hard inside the international community here to try to find solutions.&nbsp; And, you know, you&#8217;ve heard us talk about this quite some time, and I talked about it even from my previous perch at the &#8212; at the Pentagon.&nbsp; It&#8217;s difficult to do when you&#8217;re talking about a country that&#8217;s at war.&nbsp; I mean &#8212; and we&#8217;ve already seen the ability of the Russians to strike long-range targets all the way to the west of &#8212; in the country.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this has to be &#8212; everybody has &#8212; everybody understands the sense of urgency here and the importance of it, but there also has to be some very careful thought put into how you&#8217;re going to do this.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re going to have to have international cooperation and support to do it, particularly if you&#8217;re looking at ground routes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, while I don&#8217;t have a specific plan to brief you today, or a set of, you know, options here, I can assure you that, again, the President is keeping an open mind.&nbsp; He&#8217;s working directly with his interlocutors around the world to try to find ways to get this grain to market.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We all understand how important it is.&nbsp; We&#8217;re all mindful of the sense of urgency here, not just from an economic perspective, but from &#8212; from a humanitarian perspective.&nbsp; I mean, this &#8212; this is food.&nbsp; This is &#8212; this is sustenance for people and their livelihoods.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re working it really, really hard.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Potentially (inaudible) especially in North Africa and the Middle East politically (inaudible).</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I mean, well, around the world, certainly, but in the region and in North Africa.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other.&nbsp; You mentioned all the money that&#8217;s being distributed and the &#8212; a billion more today.&nbsp; Does the White House currently foresee the need for Congress at some point to pass another major multi-billion-dollar aid package (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re there yet.&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;re just now beginning to spend on the $40 billion supplemental that Congress approved, and we&#8217;re grateful for that, of course.</p>



<p>You will see additional packages coming on &#8212; on a fairly routine basis here. &nbsp;And we want to meter it out so that we&#8217;re in lockstep with the Ukrainians and where they are on the battlefield and what they need in real time.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why conversations like today with President Zelenskyy are so important; the contact group that Secretary Austin is hosting right now in Brussels &#8212; 50-some odd nations;&nbsp; also putting forward other materials for security assistance.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you need to do it &#8212; because it&#8217;s a war and it&#8217;s active combat, and it changes from day to day, you kind of need to do it in almost real time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re going to meter these out over time to &#8212; so that we&#8217;re appropriately meeting what Ukraine needs.&nbsp; And right now, I just don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re at a stage where we think we need to go back for more at this time.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in terms of that $40 billion, none of it has been spent yet?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, we just announced &#8212; we just announced that &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that is part of it?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; This billion is coming right out of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s (inaudible) also part of (inaudible).</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yes, sir.&nbsp; Yes, sir.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Kirby, is the President tracking negotiation in Ethiopia?&nbsp; We know that more people have died there than in Ukraine.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;m going to have to take that question, and we&#8217;ll see if we can get you a better answer.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for coming.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; All right, guys.&nbsp; Okay, I have a couple of things for you at the top.</p>



<p>So, I wanted to provide you an update on our work to lower gas prices for American people.&nbsp; As you know, the President has taken historic actions to address Putin&#8217;s price hike at the pump.&nbsp; He is releasing &#8212; he is releasing a record 1 billion barrels of oil a day from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; He has rallied our partners to join releasing an additional 240 million barrels of oil.&nbsp; He expanded access to E-15, which will lower prices at thousands of gas stations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But oil companies need to step up too.&nbsp; And the President made that clear in a letter to major U.S. oil refiners today.&nbsp; And I have a chart behind me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a time of global crisis, oil companies should be doing everything they can to expand capacity and lower costs at the pump.&nbsp; Instead, they are charging record profits at the expense of American families.&nbsp; The last time the price of crude oil was $120 a barrel, the price of gas was<a></a><a></a>425 cents a gallon.&nbsp; Today, it&#8217;s about 75 cents higher.<br><br>As you can see through the chart behind me here, that difference is a result of company&#8217;s record-high profit margins for refining oil.&nbsp; Profit margins have tripled &#8212; you can see it right there at the end over here &#8212; since the beginning of &#8212; of the year.&nbsp; So right here, as you see, diesel and gas.<br><br>They should be putting those record profits into expanding refining capacity from &#8212; back to pre-pandemic levels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden is putting a spotlight on this and calling on oil refiners to invest those records &#8212; those record profits to increase capacity so cost at the pump could come down.<br><br>He is signaling that he is prepared to use any emergency tools he has, but these companies have a responsibility to step up too.  We are focused on getting to solutions.<br><br>We are also closely monitoring the extreme heat conditions impacting many Americans across the country, and the President has been briefed regularly, including today.<br><br>Federal agencies are working with state and local partners to provide clear, accessible, and timely information on extreme heat and how people can protect themselves.<br><br>We are also protecting workers, including through a new administration initiative to proactively inspect over 70 high-risk industries in areas under a heat warning or advisory.<br><br>Our team is also in contact with the Department of Interior on the horrific and catastrophic floods at Yellowstone National Park, and the President was briefed about this as well today.  <br><br>We are grateful for the brave and swift work of federal and state first responders to help get people in Yellowstone National Park and in surrounding communities to safety.<br><br>We know the impacts of extreme weather are intensifying and no one is immune from climate change, as you hear us talk about for this past year and a half.  That is why President Biden has made tackling climate crisis one of his top priorities.<br><br>Today as well, we are also commemorating the 10-year anniversary of DACA, which President Biden considers one of his proudest moments, accomplishments with President Obama when he was then Vice President.<br><br>President Biden shared a video messaging &#8212; message marking the anniversary.  And Vice President Harris, the First Lady, and Ambassador Susan Rice are also hosting meetings with DREAMers and DACA recipients here at the White House.<br><br>In 10 years, DACA has transformed the lives of hundreds of thousands of young people who were brought here as children who only know America as their home.<br><br>DREAMers contribute to their community in ways big and small.  They are on the frontlines of the pandemic.  Others are job creators and entrepreneurs.  Many serve in our military.<br><br>The President is committed to preserving and fortifying DACA.  But as he said in his State of the Union Address, we need to “provide a pathway to citizenship for DREAMers,” and he continues to call on Congress to pass a bill that does just that.  And he would be ready to sign it right away.<br><br>Finally &#8212; this is the last thing here &#8212; following today&#8217;s briefing &#8212; we know we have to gather at &#8212; for &#8212; you all have to gather at 3:45, so I’ll try and take as many questions as possible.  The President will sign an executive order advancing equality for LGBTQI+ individuals, which includes historic steps to support LGBTQI+ families and children.<br><br>The E- &#8212; the EO directs federal agencies to address extreme legislative attacks, help put an end to conversion therapy, improve mental health care and prevent youth suicide, launch a new initiative to protect foster youth and prevent homelessness, and more.<br><br>These are historic actions that build on the progress we have made advancing equality of LGBTQI+ Americans and people around the world, but the federal government can and most &#8212; it can and must do more &#8212; critically by Congress passing the Equality Act.<br><br>The President will renew his call for Congress to send a bill to his desk.<br><br>And with that, Aamer, you want to take this?<br><br>Q    Yes.  Fed officials expect the unemployment rate will rise to 3.9 percent next year as they move to lower inflation.  Does the White House think slightly higher unemployment is an acceptable trade-off to fix inflation?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So, I mean, here&#8217;s the reality that we&#8217;re in, and the facts are: We brought unemployment down below 4 per- &#8212; 4 percent.  You&#8217;ve heard, most recently, at 3.6.  Four years faster than forecasters thought was possible before we passed the American Rescue Plan, which was over a year ago, back in last April of 2021.<br><br>Part of that means a transition over the course of the next year.  We have added an average of more than 400,000 jobs per month in recent months to something closer &#8212; like a cooldown, if you will &#8212; to the range of 150,000 jobs per month.<br><br>That would be consistent with the unemployment rate as low as it is now, with the 3.6.  That will be a good thing and a sign of a healthy economy, and also a transition as we are going &#8212; as we are headed towards.<br><br>Let me just call people I haven&#8217;t called on yet.  Go ahead.  <br><br>Q    Thanks, Karine.  In the letter from the President to the oil refinery &#8212; the refiners, he said they need to work with the administration to bring about a near-term solution.  Is there an “or else” in there from the President?  Is there some way that the administration plans to try to hold these companies accountable?  You used the word “responsibility” in your message at the top here.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Right.  We see it as a patriotic duty, as we’re &#8212; as we are &#8212; as we&#8217;ve talked about.  There&#8217;s war happening right now in Ukraine that was caused by &#8212; caused by Russia, which is why we&#8217;re seeing these hikes in gas prices.  Especially since &#8212; since Russia has amassed &#8212; started amassing troops on the border, we saw a &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen a $2 increase of gas prices.<br><br>So, we know where to put the blame: on the war.  But oil companies, they have &#8212; oil refineries, they have a responsibility too.  What they have been doing is taking advantage of the war.<br><br>And as &#8212; as I showed earlier, they have tripled &#8212; tripled their &#8212; their income.  And so, this is a problem.  But what we&#8217;re trying to do &#8212; by putting out the letter, we’re saying, “Hey, we need you to act.  It is time to act.”  We want to have a conversation.  We want to come to a solution.  There is going to be a conversation later this &#8212; this week, I believe, with the Energy Department.  And so that&#8217;s going to happen.<br><br>So this is basically a bit of a “Hey, we want &#8212; we want you to act.  It&#8217;s time to act.”  We have done our part with the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; the one &#8212; the 1 million a day for the next six months, and so we need them to act.<br><br>So that&#8217;s where we are.  We want to come to solutions, which is why we say we want to have that conversation.  And we will see where it goes from there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there something the President is considering to compel them or a consequence if that does not happen?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything right now to preview as to what would come &#8212; what would come next.&nbsp; But what I will say is that we are &#8212; we are calling on them to do the right thing, to be patriots here, and not to use the war as an excuse or as a &#8212; as a reason to not put &#8212; to not put out a production, not &#8212; to not do the capacity that is needed out there so that the prices can &#8212; so that the prices can come down.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the economy &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I probably should have called on somebody who I haven&#8217;t called on, but go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just very quickly &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Really quickly.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Atlanta Fed economic forecast puts real GDP growth for the second quarter at 0.0 percent now.&nbsp; With the United States potentially on the knife&#8217;s edge of a ‘70s-style stagflation kind of period, I&#8217;m curious about, kind of, your policy preferences.<br><br>Do you expect that the administration will prioritize stimulus to get growth higher and curtail unemployment?&nbsp; Or do you think that you will &#8212; you will continue to favor deficit reduction to get inflation down?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, the President laid out in his &#8212; in his Wall Street Journal op-ed very recently what he&#8217;s doing, the points that he&#8217;s taking to make sure that we are fighting inflation, attacking inflation.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>One of them is giving the Fed its independence and &#8212; and allowing them to deal with inflation under their purview.&nbsp; They have the best monetary policies to do that.&nbsp; And so we want to give that independence there.<br><br>And, of course, he has taken actions, as I said early on in in the beginning of the briefing, on things that will help ease that &#8212; ease the cost for families.&nbsp; We understand gas prices are high.&nbsp; We understand &#8212; the President understands what it means to have food prices.<br><br>Again, that&#8217;s connected to Putin&#8217;s war against Ukraine and them attacking another country’s sovereignty.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing happening there.<br><br>And so we&#8217;re going to continue to do everything that we can.&nbsp; We feel that we are in a transition right now from a economic &#8212; historic economic growth &#8212; recovery.&nbsp; And so, going into that transition with stability and steady &#8212; steady growth, we feel that&#8217;s going to help with inflation.<br><br>So, we&#8217;re going to just focus on the points that the President laid out in his &#8212; in his op-ed.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I&#8217;m going to move on so I can get other people.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s okay.&nbsp; Go back.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You sure?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m fine.&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp; Okay, I&#8217;m going to &#8212; let me get &#8212; I&#8217;m going to get you, and then I&#8217;ll start moving around so I can be done with the first row.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there other industries that you think need to step up in a patriotic fashion to try to help reduce inflation or costs for Americans?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I &#8212; there&#8217;s not a list that I have right now for you.&nbsp; Right now, we want to focus on the oil refinery, which is why we put out the letter today, or yesterday.&nbsp; I&#8217;m losing my &#8212; my track of time.<br><br>And so, we see that as an important first step in making&nbsp;sure that the oil refineries are doing their &#8212; their part &#8212; again, patriotic duty &#8212; in making sure that they&#8217;re putting out capacity and they&#8217;re not taking advantage of a &#8212; of a war that is hurting the American public.</p>



<p>And so we&#8217;re going to have &#8212; hopefully, we&#8217;re going to have &#8212; we&#8217;re going to have a conversation, we&#8217;re going to get to a solution and move this forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President often talks about being a capitalist, and, obviously, market forces drive a lot of that.&nbsp; So how would he find the balance between trying to encourage them to do more without looking like he is trying to move a sector of the private industry?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, the facts are the facts, Kelly O.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; what we have seen is they are not &#8212; their capacity is not there.&nbsp; And they &#8212; from the chart &#8212; they are using this moment &#8212; using this moment of war where the American &#8212; where American families are feeling &#8212; are feeling the high costs with food and gas.&nbsp; I mean, that is not a patriotic thing to do.</p>



<p>And the person &#8212; the President has the right to call them out.&nbsp; And so, he&#8217;s using his perch.&nbsp; He&#8217;s using this opportunity that he has to make sure that &#8212; he always said he&#8217;s going to use every lever that he can to make sure he&#8217;s delivering for the American people.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s &#8212; he’s going to try and do at this point.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Progressives in Congress are calling for the passage of a windfall profits tax targeting the oil and gas sector.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s position on that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don’t have a position for you to share &#8212; to share at this time on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When we talk to oil analysts, they say that one thing we all ought to be concerned about is the prospect of a hurricane hitting refineries on the Gulf Coast.&nbsp; Are you aware of any steps the administration is taking now to gird against that possibility?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything on a hurricane at this moment &#8212; like what we&#8217;re going to do to take steps on hurricane and oil refinery.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check in with the team and get back to you to see if there&#8217;s a pla- &#8212; a plan in place.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything for you at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more quick thing because I know you got to go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Sure, sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The country&#8217;s refineries are aging.&nbsp; A major refinery really hasn&#8217;t been built in this country since the late 1970s.&nbsp; If one were to be proposed, would the President support the construction of a new refinery or oppose it?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That would &#8212; I have not seen any of that reporting.&nbsp; And that is not something that I can confirm from the podium at this time.&nbsp; Okay?</p>



<p>Do you want to go, Andrew?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Let’s just try one more time on the refinery issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the letter, the President said that he&#8217;s “prepared to use all reasonable and appropriate federal government tools and emergency authorities to increase refinery capacity.”&nbsp; What are those tools exactly that he has?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, he is open to all reasonable uses of the federal government&#8217;s tools to increase output and lower costs at the pump, including emergency authorities like the Defense Production Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Already, the President has demonstrated his willingness to use that emergency powers to lower costs for families.&nbsp; As I’ve mentioned, the petroleum &#8212; the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; as we’re using right now to get &#8212; to get oil every day to make sure we’re &#8212; we’re doing everything we can to lower costs; the ethanol 15 &#8212; the homegrown biofuels that is going to help many, many families across the country, including in the Midwest.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s a way that the President has acted.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, he is going to auth- &#8212; he authorized the use of DPA to accelerate domestic production of key energy technologies, as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the letter &#8212; just to put &#8212; put in context for a second &#8212; the letter is intended to solicit companies’ best ideas on how to increase capacity and how the government can help them do it in the spirit of the earnest and pragmatic dialogue.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we feel like this is a good step for us to move forward, and hopefully we&#8217;ll come and get some solutions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So are you saying he could use the Defense Production Act to expand capacity?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re &#8212; we &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to share specifically how we would use the DPA, but we&#8217;re saying that the President has used it before and he&#8217;s willing to do that again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the first &#8212; the first step that he wants to do is make sure to have the conversation and hear ideas &#8212; right? &#8212; from the oil refineries how we can be &#8212; how we can be helpful to them to actually get more capacity out.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you want to take one more.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll take &#8212; I&#8217;ll take like two more.&nbsp; I’ll take two more.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very &#8212; thanks very much.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just about to go into a Pride event, obviously.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We know that Saudi officials have been seizing rainbow-colored toys and clothing as part of an apparent crackdown on homosexuality in the country there.&nbsp; That&#8217;s according to state-run media.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wonder what the White House response is to that, given that the President is about to set up his Pride credentials in the next event.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I have not seen that reporting.&nbsp; But what I can say: Globally, we work around the globe to protect LGBTQI+ persons from violence and abuse, criminalization, discrimination, and stigma and &#8212; and empower local LGBTQI+ movements and persons.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>We do this through bilateral and multilateral channels, raising official concerns with governor &#8212; governments, both&nbsp;<s>principal</s>&nbsp;[publicly] and privately; coordinating our efforts with likeminded countries; and offering emergency assistance to LGBTQI+ persons at risk.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Through our foreign assistance program &#8212; programming, we support civil society in providing LGBTQI+ individuals and communities with tools and resources to prevent, mitigate, and recover from violence, discrimination, and stigma.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We see human rights as being universal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to take one last more.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>Well, I’m going to take one last one.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to take one last one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jamal Khashoggi’s fiancé said today she was, quote, “very disappointed” President Biden plans to meet with Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman.&nbsp; She said in a message to the President, quote, “If you have to put oil over principles and expediency over values, can you at least ask, ‘Where is Jamal&#8217;s body?’” and, quote, “‘What happened to his killers?’”</p>



<p>So will President Biden ask the Crown Prince these questions?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, first, I want to say &#8212; you know, just hearing that &#8212; it&#8217;s devastating, right?&nbsp; It is &#8212; it is Jamal Khashoggi’s widow.&nbsp; And so, clearly, our hearts go out to her and the pain that she&#8217;s currently going through.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, when it comes to human rights, this is not something &#8212; the President is a straight shooter.&nbsp; This is not something that he&#8217;s afraid to talk about.&nbsp; He has those conversations &#8212; leader-to-leader conversations on a regular basis.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I cannot read out right now or lay &#8212; or lay out what the agenda is going to be or what the conversations are going to be.&nbsp; But I can assure you &#8212; I can assure you that when it comes to human rights, this is something that is a priority for this President.</p>



<p>I just laid out how &#8212; at the end of talking about the LGBTQI+ community &#8212; how human rights is universal, and that is very, very true in &#8212; in many ways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I &#8212; once we have more to share, we&#8217;ll share more about what the trip will look like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, I have to go.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, can I just follow on that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I got to go, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>I got to go, guys.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>3:50 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at a Reception to Celebrate Pride&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/15/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-a-reception-to-celebrate-pride-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 21:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room &#124; The White House  4:21 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE FIRST LADY:&#160; Thank you, everyone.&#160; Finally!&#160; Finally, we’re all back at the White House together, and doesn’t this feel great?&#160; (Applause.) Kamala, Doug, Joe, and I are honored to welcome you to this year’s White House Pride celebration.&#160; And, truly, it’s so wonderful &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room | The White House </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">4:21 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Finally!&nbsp; Finally, we’re all back at the White House together, and doesn’t this feel great?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Kamala, Doug, Joe, and I are honored to welcome you to this year’s White House Pride celebration.&nbsp; And, truly, it’s so wonderful &#8212; wonderful to be with so many friends.<br><br>You know, early in the campaign, Doug, Chasten, and I had the chance to come together for a Pride event.&nbsp; Do you remember that?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECOND GENTLEMAN:&nbsp; I do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Yes!</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECOND GENTLEMAN:&nbsp; It was in Las Vegas.&nbsp; I remember.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; So, it was late on a warm October night in Las Vegas.&nbsp; And we were all candidates&#8217; spouses at the time, but there was an energy in the air that brought us all together, and we had the chance to get to know one another.&nbsp; And we made a promise then that our next Pride celebration would be on the South Lawn of the White House.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And now, here we are once again, but it was just a little too hot and humid out there &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to be on the lawn.&nbsp;<br><br>So, every year that we gather here in our nation’s capital is a reminder of just how far we’ve come.&nbsp; That we have LGBTQ leaders at some of the highest levels of our government.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That we can gather to celebrate all of you.&nbsp; That your President and I are proud to stand with you and fight beside you.<br><br>But we know that this progress hasn’t reached everyone in the same way.<br><br>We know that in places across the country &#8212; like Florida, Texas, or Alabama &#8212; rights are under attack.&nbsp; And we know that in small towns and big cities, prejudice and discrimination still lurk.<br><br>It shouldn’t take courage to be yourself.&nbsp; It shouldn’t take courage to go to school and walk down the halls as the person you know you are.<br><br>It shouldn’t take courage to hold the hand of the person you love on a bus, to kiss them goodbye on the sidewalk, to share one of the most fundamental and beautiful connections that any one of us can have in this life.<br><br>It shouldn’t but, too often and in too many places, it still does.<br><br>And in some way, all of you here today have called on that courage.&nbsp; And you’ve used your voice to say: We will not go back.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We will not let the progress that we’ve fought for slip away.<br><br>Pride is a celebration of the courage it takes to stand up for what’s right, to become the leaders we need, to live an authentic life.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We recognize it as an act of bravery and beauty, of daring and defiance.&nbsp; And we look forward to a time when that courage is no longer needed, when all people in all places can feel the freedom and the joy that we feel here today.<br><br>What Joe said 10 years ago was right: Love is love.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Joe &#8212; Joe and I are grateful for all of you, and we will never stop working for that future.<br><br>So, now, I’m so proud to introduce our next speaker.<br><br>I’m always impressed when young people are brave enough to come to the White House and speak in front of so many leaders.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But after organizing a walk-out at his high school to protest the “Don’t Say Gay” bill; leading a rally of his peers &#8212; (applause); and publicly sharing his own story, I’m pretty sure that speaking at today’s celebration is nothing he can’t handle.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Please welcome Javier Gomez!</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 4:26 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on  Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/15/memorandum-on-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 21:31:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $350 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Advancing Equality for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex&#160;Individuals</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/15/executive-order-on-advancing-equality-for-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-queer-and-intersex-individuals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 21:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it&#160;is&#160;hereby ordered as follows: Section 1.&#160; Policy.&#160; Our Nation has made great strides in fulfilling the fundamental promises of freedom and equality for&#160;lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex (LGBTQI+) Americans, owing to the leadership&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it&nbsp;is&nbsp;hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; Our Nation has made great strides in fulfilling the fundamental promises of freedom and equality for&nbsp;lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex (LGBTQI+) Americans, owing to the leadership of generations of&nbsp;LGBTQI+ individuals. &nbsp;In spite of this historic progress, LGBTQI+ individuals and families still face systemic discrimination and barriers to full participation in our Nation&#8217;s economic and civic life. &nbsp;These disparities and barriers can be the greatest for transgender people and LGBTQI+ people of color. &nbsp;Today, unrelenting political and legislative attacks at the State level &#8212; on LGBTQI+ children and families in particular &#8212; threaten the civil rights gains of the last half century and put LGBTQI+ people at risk. &nbsp;These attacks defy&nbsp;our American values of liberty and dignity, corrode our democracy, and threaten basic personal safety. &nbsp;They echo the criminalization that LGBTQI+ people continue to face in some 70&nbsp;countries around the world. &nbsp;The Federal Government must defend the rights and safety of LGBTQI+ individuals.</p>



<p>It is therefore the policy of my Administration to combat unlawful discrimination and eliminate disparities that harm LGBTQI+ individuals and their families, defend their rights and safety, and pursue a comprehensive approach to delivering the full promise of equality for LGBTQI+ individuals, consistent with Executive Order 13988 of January 20, 2021 (Preventing and Combating Discrimination on the Basis of Gender Identity or Sexual Orientation).</p>



<p>The Federal Government must take action to address the significant disparities that LGBTQI+ youth face in the foster care system, the misuse of State and local child welfare agencies to target LGBTQI+ youth and families, and the mental health needs of LGBTQI+ youth. &nbsp;My Administration must safeguard LGBTQI+ youth from dangerous practices like so-called &#8220;conversion therapy&#8221; &#8212; efforts to suppress or change an individual&#8217;s sexual orientation, gender identity, or gender expression &#8212; a discredited practice that research indicates can cause significant harm, including higher rates of suicide-related thoughts and behaviors by LGBTQI+ youth. &nbsp;The Federal Government must strengthen the supports for LGBTQI+ students in our Nation&#8217;s schools and other education and training programs. &nbsp;It must also address the discrimination and barriers that LGBTQI+ individuals and families face by expanding access to comprehensive health care, including reproductive health; protecting the rights of LGBTQI+ older adults; and preventing and addressing LGBTQI+ homelessness and housing instability. &nbsp;Through these actions, the Federal Government will help ensure that every person &#8212; regardless of who they are or whom they love &#8212; has the opportunity to live freely and with dignity.<br><br></p>



<p><a><u>Se</u></a><u>c</u>. 2.&nbsp; Addressing Harmful and Discriminatory Legislative Attacks on LGBTQI+ Children, Youth, and Families. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, use the Department of HHS&#8217;s authorities to protect LGBTQI+ individuals&#8217; access to medically necessary care from harmful State and local laws and practices, and shall promote the adoption of promising policies and practices to support health equity, including in the area of mental health care, for LGBTQI+ youth and adults. &nbsp;Within 200 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of HHS shall develop and release sample policies for States to safeguard and expand access to health care for LGBTQI+ individuals and their families, including mental health services.<br><br></p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretary of Education shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, use the Department of Education&#8217;s authorities to support LGBTQI+ students, their families, educators, and other school personnel targeted by harmful State and local laws and practices, and shall promote the adoption of promising policies and practices to support the safety, well-being, and rights of LGBTQI+ students. &nbsp;Within 200 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of Education shall develop and release sample policies for supporting LGBTQI+ students&#8217; well-being and academic success in schools and educational institutions.<br><br></p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; Addressing Exposure to So-Called Conversion Therapy.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp; The Secretary of HHS shall establish an initiative to reduce the risk of youth exposure to so-called conversion therapy. &nbsp;As part of that initiative, the Secretary of HHS shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;consider whether to issue guidance clarifying for HHS programs and services agencies that so-called conversion therapy does not meet criteria for use in federally funded health and human services programs;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;increase public awareness of the harms and risks associated with so-called conversion therapy for LGBTQI+ youth and their families; &nbsp;<br><br></p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; increase the availability of technical assistance and training to health care and social service providers on evidence-informed promising practices for supporting the health, including mental health, of LGBTQI+ youth, and on the dangers of so-called conversion therapy; and</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;seek funding opportunities for providers of evidence-based trauma-informed services to better support survivors of so-called conversion therapy.<br></p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Federal Trade Commission is encouraged to consider whether so-called conversion therapy constitutes an unfair or deceptive act or practice, and to issue such consumer warnings or notices as may be appropriate.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; To address so-called conversion therapy around the world, within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of State, in collaboration with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of HHS, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall develop an action plan to promote an end to its use around the world. &nbsp;In developing the action plan, the Secretary of State shall consider the use of United States foreign assistance programs and the United States voice and vote in multilateral development banks and international development institutions of which the United&nbsp;States is a shareholder or donor to take appropriate steps to prevent the use of so-called conversion therapy, as well as to help ensure that United States foreign assistance programs do not use foreign assistance funds for so-called conversion therapy. &nbsp;To further critical data collection, the Secretary of State shall instruct all United States Embassies and Missions worldwide to submit additional information on the practice and incidence of so-called conversion therapy as part of the Country Reports on Human Rights Practices.</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; Promoting Family Counseling and Support of LGBTQI+ Youth as a Public Health Priority of the United&nbsp;States. &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; &#8220;Family counseling and support programs&#8221; are defined for the purposes of this order as voluntary programs in which families and service providers may elect to participate that seek to prevent or reduce behaviors associated with family rejection of LGBTQI+ youth by providing developmentally appropriate support, counseling, or information to parents, families, caregivers, child welfare and school personnel, or health care professionals on how to support an LGBTQI+ youth&#8217;s safety and well-being.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretary of HHS shall seek to expand the availability of family counseling and support programs in federally funded health, human services, and child welfare programs by:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;considering whether to issue guidance regarding the extent to which Federal funding under Title IV-B and IV-E of the Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. Ch. 7, may be used to provide family counseling and support programs;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;considering funding opportunities for programs that implement family counseling and support models;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; considering opportunities through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and the National Institutes of Health to increase Federal research into the impacts of family rejection and family support on the mental health and long-term well-being of LGBTQI+ individuals; and</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;ensuring that HHS data, investments, resources, and partnerships related to the CDC Adverse Childhood Experiences program address the disparities faced by LGBTQI+ children and youth.</p>



<p>Sec. 5.&nbsp; Addressing Discrimination and Barriers Faced by LGBTQI+ Children, Youth, Parents, Caretakers, and Families in the Child Welfare System and Juvenile Justice Systems.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The Secretary of HHS shall consider how to use the Department&#8217;s authorities to strengthen non-discrimination protections on the basis of sex, including sexual orientation, gender identity, and sex characteristics, in its programs and services, consistent with Executive Order 13988 and applicable legal requirements.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretary of HHS shall direct the Assistant Secretary for Family Support to establish an initiative to partner with State child welfare agencies to help address and eliminate disparities in the child welfare system experienced by LGBTQI+ children, parents, and caregivers, including: &nbsp;the over-representation of LGBTQI+ youth in the child welfare system, including over-representation in congregate placements; disproportionately high rates of abuse, and placements in unsupportive or hostile environments faced by LGBTQI+ youth in foster care; disproportionately high rates of homelessness faced by LGBTQI+ youth who exit foster care; and discrimination faced by LGBTQI+ parents, kin, and foster and adoptive families. &nbsp;The initiative, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, shall also take actions to:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;seek funding opportunities for programs and services that improve outcomes for LGBTQI+ children in the child welfare system;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;provide increased training and technical assistance to State child welfare agencies and child welfare personnel on promising practices to support LGBTQI+ youth in foster care and LGBTQI+ parents and caregivers;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; develop sample policies for supporting LGBTQI+ children, parents, and caregivers in the child welfare system;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;promote equity and inclusion for LGBTQI+ foster and adoptive parents in their interactions with the child welfare system;</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;evaluate the rate of child removals from LGBTQI+ families of origin, in particular families that include LGBTQI+ women of color, and develop proposals to address any disproportionate rates of child removals faced by such families;</p>



<p>(vi)&nbsp; &nbsp;assess and improve the responsible collection and use of data on sexual orientation and gender identity in the child welfare system to measure and address inequities faced by LGBTQI+ children, parents, and caregivers, while safeguarding the privacy, safety, and civil rights of LGBTQI+ youth; and</p>



<p>(vii)&nbsp; advance policies that help to prevent the placement of LGBTQI+ youth in foster and congregate care environments that will be hostile to their gender identity or sexual orientation.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall establish a clearinghouse within the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to provide effective training, technical assistance, and other resources for jurisdictions seeking to better serve LGBTQI+ youth using a continuum-of-care framework. &nbsp;The clearinghouse shall include juvenile justice and delinquency prevention programs addressing the needs, including mental health needs, of LGBTQI+ youth.</p>



<p>Sec. 6.&nbsp; Reviewing Eligibility Standards for Federal Benefits and Programs.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of HHS shall conduct a study on the impact that current Federal statutory and regulatory eligibility standards have on the ability of LGBTQI+ and other households as determined by the Secretary to access Federal benefits and programs for families, and shall produce a public report with findings and recommendations that could increase LGBTQI+ and such other households&#8217; participation in and eligibility for Federal benefits and programs for families.<br><br></p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Within 100 days of the release of the recommendations required by subsection (a) of this section, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) shall coordinate with executive departments and agencies (agencies) that administer programs that establish eligibility standards for participation by families to complete a review of agencies&#8217; current eligibility standards for families.&nbsp; Such agencies shall seek opportunities, consistent with applicable law, to adopt more inclusive eligibility standards in line with the recommendations in the report produced pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</p>



<p>Sec. 7. &nbsp;Safeguarding Access to Health Care and Other Health Supports for LGBTQI+ Individuals.<strong> &nbsp;</strong>The Secretary of HHS shall establish an initiative to address the health disparities facing LGBTQI+ youth and adults, take steps to prevent LGBTQI+ suicide, and address the barriers and exclusionary policies that LGBTQI+ individuals and families face in accessing quality, affordable, comprehensive health care, including mental health care, reproductive health care, and HIV prevention and treatment. &nbsp;As part of that initiative, the Secretary of HHS shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; seek funding opportunities related to health, including mental health, for LGBTQI+ individuals, especially youth, including resources for the Nation&#8217;s suicide prevention and crisis support services to support LGBTQI+ individuals;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; promote expanded access to comprehensive health care for LGBTQI+ individuals, including by working with States on expanding access to gender-affirming care;</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; issue guidance through the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration and the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, within 100 days of the date of this order, on providing evidence-informed mental health care and substance use treatment and support services for LGBTQI+ youth; and</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; develop and issue a report, within 1 year of the date of this order, and after consultation with medical experts, medical associations, and individuals with lived expertise, on promising practices for advancing health equity for intersex individuals.</p>



<p>Sec. 8.&nbsp; Supporting LGBTQI+ Students in our Nation&#8217;s Schools and Educational Institutions. &nbsp;The Secretary of Education shall establish a Working Group on LGBTQI+ Students and Families, which shall lead an initiative to address discrimination against LGBTQI+ students and strengthen supports for LGBTQI+ students and families. &nbsp;Through that Working Group, the Secretary of Education shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; review, revise, develop, and promote guidance, technical assistance, training, promising practices, and sample policies for States, school districts, and other educational institutions to promote safe and inclusive learning environments in which all LGBTQI+ students thrive and to address bullying of LGBTQI+ students;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; identify promising practices for helping to ensure that school-based health services and supports, especially mental health services, are accessible to and supportive of LGBTQI+ students;</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; seek funding opportunities for grantees and programs that will improve educational and health outcomes, especially mental health outcomes, for LGBTQI+ students and other underserved students; and</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; seek to strengthen supportive services for LGBTQI+ students and families experiencing homelessness, including those provided by the National Center for Homeless Education. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 9.&nbsp; Preventing and Ending LGBTQI+ Homelessness and Housing Instability. &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) shall establish a Working Group on LGBTQI+ Homelessness and Housing Equity, which shall lead an initiative that aims to prevent and address homelessness and housing instability among LGBTQI+ individuals, including youth, and households. &nbsp;As part of that initiative, the Secretary of HUD shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;identify and address barriers to housing faced by LGBTQI+ individuals, including youth, and families that place them at high risk of housing instability and homelessness;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;provide guidance and technical assistance to HUD contractors, grantees, and programs on effectively and respectfully serving LGBTQI+ individuals, including youth, and families;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; develop and provide guidance, sample policies, technical assistance, and training to Continuums of Care, established pursuant to HUD&#8217;s Continuum of Care Program; homeless service providers; and housing providers to improve services and outcomes for LGBTQI+ individuals, including youth, and families who are experiencing or are at risk of homelessness, and to ensure compliance with the Fair Housing Act, 42 U.S.C. 3601 <em>et seq</em>., and HUD&#8217;s 2012 and 2016 Equal Access Rules; and</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;seek funding opportunities, including through the Youth Homelessness Demonstration Program, for culturally appropriate services that address barriers to housing for LGBTQI+ individuals, including youth, and families, and the high rates of LGBTQI+ youth homelessness.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretary of HHS, through the Assistant Secretary for Family Support, shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;use agency guidance, training, and technical assistance to implement non-discrimination protections on the basis of sexual orientation and gender identity in programs established pursuant to the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (Public Law 110-378), and ensure that such programs address LGBTQI+ youth homelessness; and</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; coordinate with youth advisory boards funded through the Runaway and Homeless Youth Training and Technical Assistance Center and the National Runaway Safeline to seek input from LGBTQI+ youth who have experienced homelessness on improving federally funded services and programs.</p>



<p>Sec. 10.&nbsp; Strengthening Supports for LGBTQI+ Older Adults.&nbsp;The Secretary of HHS shall address discrimination, social isolation, and health disparities faced by LGBTQI+ older adults, including by:</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; developing and publishing guidance on non-discrimination protections on the basis of sex, including sexual orientation, gender identity, and sex characteristics, and other rights of LGBTQI+ older adults in long-term care settings;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;developing and publishing a document parallel to the guidance required by subsection (a) of this section in plain language, titled &#8220;Bill of Rights for LGBTQI+ Older Adults,&#8221; to support LGBTQI+ older adults and providers in understanding the rights of LGBTQI+ older adults in long-term care settings;</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; considering whether to issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to clarify that LGBTQI+ individuals are included in the definition of &#8220;greatest social need&#8221; for purposes of targeting outreach, service provision, and funding under the Older Americans Act, 42 U.S.C. 3001 <em>et seq</em>.; and</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; considering ways to improve and increase appropriate data collection on sexual orientation and gender identity in surveys on older adults, including by providing technical assistance to States on the collection of such data.</p>



<p>Sec. 11.&nbsp; Promoting Inclusive and Responsible Federal Data Collection Practices. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Advancing equity and full inclusion for LGBTQI+ individuals requires that the Federal Government use evidence and data to measure and address the disparities that LGBTQI+ individuals, families, and households face, while safeguarding privacy, security, and civil rights. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; To advance the responsible and effective collection and use of data on sexual orientation, gender identity, and sex characteristics (SOGI data), the Co-Chairs of the Interagency Working Group on Equitable Data established in Executive Order 13985 of January 20, 2021 (Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government), shall, within 30 days of the date of this order, establish a subcommittee on SOGI data to coordinate with agencies on strengthening the Federal Government&#8217;s collection of SOGI data to advance equity for LGBTQI+ individuals.&nbsp; Within 120 days of the date of this order, the subcommittee shall, in coordination with the Director of OMB, develop and release a Federal Evidence Agenda on LGBTQI+ Equity, which shall:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;describe disparities faced by LGBTQI+ individuals that could be better understood through Federal statistics and data collection;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;identify, in coordination with agency Statistical Officials, Chief Science Officers, Chief Data Officers, and Evaluation Officers, Federal data collections where improved SOGI data collection may be important for advancing the Federal Government&#8217;s ability to measure disparities facing LGBTQI+ individuals; and</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; identify practices for all agencies engaging in SOGI data collection to follow in order to safeguard privacy, security, and civil rights, including with regard to appropriate and robust practices of consent for the collection of this data and restrictions on its use or transfer.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; Within 200 days of the date of this order, the head of each agency that conducts relevant programs or statistical surveys related to the Federal Evidence Agenda on LGBTQI+ Equity shall submit to the Co-Chairs of the Interagency Working Group on Equitable Data a SOGI Data Action Plan, which shall detail how the agency plans to use SOGI data to advance equity for LGBTQI+ individuals and shall identify how the agency plans to implement the recommendations in the Federal Evidence Agenda on LGBTQI+ Equity.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; To support implementation of agency SOGI Data Action Plans, the head of each agency shall include in the agency&#8217;s annual budget submission to the Director of OMB a request for any necessary funding increases to support improved SOGI data practices.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; Within 180 days of the date of this order, to support agencies in appropriately collecting and using SOGI data, the Director of OMB, through the Chief Statistician of the United States, shall publish a report with recommendations for agencies on the best practices for the collection of SOGI data on Federal statistical surveys, including strategies to preserve data privacy and safety.</p>



<p>(f)&nbsp; On an annual basis, the Director of OMB, through the Chief Statistician of the United States, shall evaluate the efficacy of SOGI data practices across agencies, and shall consider whether to update reports, guidance, or directives based upon the latest evidence and research as needed.<br><br></p>



<p>Sec. 12.&nbsp; Reporting. &nbsp;Within 1 year of the date of this order:</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; The Attorney General shall submit a report to the President through the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy (APDP) detailing progress in implementing section 5 of this order;<br><br></p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretary of HHS shall submit a report to the President through the APDP detailing progress in implementing sections 2 through 7 and 9 through 11 of this order;<br><br></p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Secretary of Education shall submit a report to the President through the APDP detailing progress in implementing sections 2, 8, and 11 of this order;<br><br></p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; The Secretary of HUD shall submit a report to the President through the APDP detailing progress in implementing sections 9 and 11 of this order;<br><br></p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;The Secretary of State shall submit a report to the President through the APDP detailing progress in implementing section 3 of this order;<br><br></p>



<p>(f) &nbsp;The Director of OMB shall submit a report to the President through the APDP detailing progress in implementing sections 6 and 11 of this order; and</p>



<p>(g) &nbsp;The Director of OMB, through the Chief Statistician of&nbsp;the United States, shall submit a report to the President through the APDP detailing progress in implementing section 11 of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 13.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br></p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br></p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; June 15, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/15/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-71/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 20:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Julie D. Fisher, of Tennessee, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Cyprus. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Christopher T. Robinson, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Julie D. Fisher, of Tennessee, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Cyprus.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Christopher T. Robinson, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Latvia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stephanie Sanders Sullivan, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Representative of the United States of America to the African Union, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Radha Iyengar Plumb, of New York, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense, vice Alan Ray Shaffer.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Bradley N. Garcia, of Maryland, to be United States Circuit Judge for the District of Columbia Circuit, vice Judith W. Rogers, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dana M. Douglas, of Louisiana, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Fifth Circuit, vice James L. Dennis, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Roopali H. Desai, of Arizona, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Ninth Circuit, vice Andrew David Hurwitz, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; María del R. Antongiorgi-Jordán, of Puerto Rico, to be United States District Judge for the District of Puerto Rico, vice Gustavo Antonio Gelpi, elevated.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Camille L. Vélez-Rivé, of Puerto Rico, to be United States District Judge for the District of Puerto Rico, vice Francisco Augusto Besosa, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;Gina R. Méndez-Miró, of Puerto Rico, to be United States District Judge for the District of Puerto Rico, vice Carmen Consuelo Cerezo, retired.</p>



<p>     Jerry W. Blackwell, of Minnesota, to be United States District Judge for the District of Minnesota, vice Susan Richard Nelson, retired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/15/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-20/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&#160; Radha Iyengar Plumb, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, U.S. Department of Defense Julie D. Fisher, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Cyprus Christopher T. Robinson,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><a></a>Radha Iyengar Plumb, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, U.S. Department of Defense</li><li>Julie D. Fisher, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Cyprus</li><li>Christopher T. Robinson, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Latvia</li><li>Stephanie Sanders Sullivan, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the African Union, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</li><li>L. Felice Gorordo, Nominee for United States Alternate Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</li></ul>



<p><strong>Radha Iyengar Plumb, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, U.S. Department of Defense</strong><br><br>Radha Iyengar Plumb currently serves as the Chief of Staff to the Deputy Secretary of Defense. Prior to her appointment as Chief of Staff, she was the Director of Research and Insights for Trust &amp; Safety at Google, leading their cross functional teams on business analytics, data science, and technical research. She previously served as the Global Head of Policy Analysis at Facebook where she focused on high risk/high harm safety and critical international security issues. Plumb previously was a Senior Economist at the RAND Corporation where she focused on improving measurement and evaluation of readiness and security efforts across the Department of Defense. She also held a number of senior staff positions on national security issues at the Department of Defense, Department of Energy, and the White House National Security Council. At the outset of her career, she was an Assistant Professor at the London School of Economics and did her postdoctoral work at Harvard. Plumb received her Ph.D. and M.S. in Economics from Princeton University, and she holds a B.S. from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.<br><br><strong>Julie D. Fisher, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Cyprus</strong><br><br>Julie D. Fisher, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the U.S. Special Envoy for Belarus based in Vilnius, Lithuania. In 2020 she was confirmed as the first U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Belarus since 2008. Fisher previously served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Western Europe and the European Union in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs. Before that, she was the Deputy Permanent Representative of the U.S. Mission to NATO. Earlier, she was the Chief of Staff to the Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources. Fisher also served as the Director of the State Department’s Operations Center. Other assignments include a detail to NATO’s international staff as Deputy Director of the Private Office and assignments at U.S. embassies in Georgia, Ukraine, and Russia, as well as tours at the National Security Council, the Bureaus for European and Eurasian Affairs and Near Eastern Affairs, and the Secretary of State’s Executive Secretariat Staff. Fisher earned a Bachelor’s degree from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and a Master’s degree from the School of International and Public Affairs at Princeton University. She speaks Russian and French.<br><br><strong>Christopher T. Robinson, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Latvia</strong><br><br>Christopher Robinson, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs. Prior to that, Robinson was Minister Counselor for Political Affairs at U.S. Embassy in Moscow, Russia. Previously, he served as Deputy Director for Russian Affairs at the State Department, as Political Counselor at the U.S. Mission to the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) in Vienna, Austria, and as Political Counselor in Managua, Nicaragua. Other assignments include Iraq, Belarus, Canada, Russia, and assignments in the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs and the Bureau of European Affairs. Robinson received an M.S. in Strategic Studies from the National War College and a B.A. in International Affairs from the George Washington University. He is the recipient of multiple State Department performance awards, including a Distinguished Honor Award. Robinson speaks Russian and Spanish. <br><br><strong>Stephanie Sanders Sullivan,Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the African Union, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</strong><br><br>Stephanie Sanders Sullivan, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister, served as Ambassador to the Republic of Ghana from 2018 – 2022. Previously, she was Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for the State Department’s Bureau of African Affairs. She served earlier as the U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Congo, and before that, as Chief of Staff for the Deputy Secretary of State. In earlier assignments, Sullivan was Managing Director of the Office of Management Policy, Rightsizing, and Innovation, and she also provided management support to posts in Africa, the Western Hemisphere, and Europe, as well as international organizations. She served multiple tours in the State Department Operations Center, including as Director, and as Duty Officer at the White House Situation Room. Her first diplomatic assignment was in Cameroon. Sullivan earned a Bachelor’s degree at Brown University and a Master’s degree at the National Defense University. She was a Peace Corps Volunteer in the Democratic Republic of Congo. She speaks French, Lingala, and basic Spanish. <br><br><strong>L. Felice Gorordo, Nominee for United States Alternate Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development</strong><br><br>Leonardo Felice Gorordo is a serial entrepreneur, investor, and advisor. Currently, Gorordo is CEO of eMerge Americas, a venture-backed platform focused on fostering innovation and entrepreneurship across the Americas and transforming Miami into the tech hub of the Americas. Gorordo is also a venture partner at I Squared Capital’s Global Infrastructure Technology Fund. Additionally, Gorordo co-founded and leads Roots of Hope, a non-profit focused on empowering Cuban youth to become the authors of their own futures.<br><br>Previously, Gorordo was President &amp; CEO of Clearpath, a venture-backed tech company focused on revolutionizing the immigration filing process. Gorordo also served as advisor to the Biden Cancer Initiative, and Global Director at StartUp Health. Prior to that, Gorordo was appointed by President Obama as one of fifteen White House Fellows and served in the White House Office of Public Engagement &amp; Intergovernmental Affairs. In President George W. Bush&#8217;s Administration, Gorordo served in various positions at the U.S. Departments of Commerce, State, and Homeland Security. Gorordo is a graduate of Georgetown University and served as a Senior Fellow at the Georgetown Beeck Center for Social Impact &amp; Innovation. Gorordo serves as a Lifetime Member of the Council on Foreign Relations, and also serves on the boards of several national and local nonprofits.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Appointments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/15/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden announced his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles: Senator Evan Bayh, Member, President&#8217;s Intelligence Advisory Board Donna Brazile, Member, J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board Ambassador James Costos, Member, J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board Stephen Schneck, Commissioner, United States Commission on International Religious Freedom President’s Intelligence&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden announced his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Senator Evan Bayh, Member, President&#8217;s Intelligence Advisory Board</li><li>Donna Brazile, Member, J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board</li><li>Ambassador James Costos, Member, J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board</li><li>Stephen Schneck, Commissioner, United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</li></ul>



<p><strong>President’s Intelligence Advisory Board</strong><br>The President&#8217;s Intelligence Advisory Board is an independent element within the Executive Office of the President. The President’s Intelligence Advisory Board exists exclusively to assist the President by providing the President with an independent source of advice on the effectiveness with which the Intelligence Community is meeting the nation’s intelligence needs and the vigor and insight with which the community plans for the future. The President is able to appoint up to 16 members of the Board.<br><br><strong>Senator Evan Bayh, Member, President&#8217;s Intelligence Advisory Board</strong><br>Evan Bayh is a former two-term United States Senator from Indiana. While in the Senate, he served on several committees including the Senate Armed Services Committee and Senate Intelligence Committee for 10 years.  Following his Senate service, Bayh served on the Central Intelligence Agency External Advisory Board, under both Presidents Obama and Trump.  Prior to being elected to the Senate, he was elected to two terms as governor of Indiana and also served as Secretary of State in Indiana. Bayh earned a B.S. in economics from the Kelley School at Indiana University and a J.D. from the University of Virginia. He was awarded an Honorary Doctor of Laws by Indiana University.<br><br><strong>J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board</strong><br>The J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board supervises the Fulbright Program and certain programs authorized by the Fulbright-Hays Act and for the purpose of selecting students, scholars, teachers, trainees, and other persons to participate in the educational exchange programs. Appointed by the President, the 12-member Board meets quarterly in Washington, DC. The Board establishes worldwide policies and procedures for the Program and issues an annual report on the state of the Program.<br><br><strong>Donna Brazile, Member, J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board</strong><br>Donna Brazile, ABC News contributor and veteran political strategist, is the former interim Chair of the Democratic National Committee. She became the first African American woman to serve as the manager of a major party presidential campaign, running the campaign of former Vice President Al Gore.  She is the author of several books, including the 2017 <em>New York Times </em>bestseller <em>Hacks: The Inside Story of the Break-Ins </em>and <em>Breakdowns That Put Donald Trump In The White House.</em><br><br>Brazile has lectured at over 237 colleges and universities across the country.  In 2013, Brazile was appointed by President Obama to serve on the J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board. Brazile has served as an adjunct professor at Georgetown University since 2002 and spent the fall of 2017 serving as a Joan Shorenstein fellow in Media, Politics and Public Policy at the Harvard Kennedy School.  She is currently the Gwendolyn S. and Colbert I. King Endowed Chair in Public Policy at Howard University. She is the proud recipient of more than ten honorary doctorate degrees from major colleges and universities, including her alma mater Louisiana State University. In October 2017, Brazile was the recipient of the W.E.B Du Bois Medal, Harvard’s highest honor in African American studies.  Brazile was the recipient of a Daytime Emmy Award for Outstanding Daytime Program, <em>Good Morning America</em> (2016-2017) in connection with her work with ABC and she was a member of the Peabody Award-winning “Best Political Team on Television” on CNN during the 2008 election cycle.<br><br><strong>Ambassador James Costos, Member, J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board</strong><br>Ambassador James Costos, a diplomat and former U.S. Ambassador to the Kingdom of Spain and Principality of Andorra, has dedicated himself to building the important relationship between the United States, Spain, and Andorra. Costos remains focused on supporting innovation and entrepreneurship, illustrated by the launch of the annual “IN3 -INCUBED” Innovation and Tech Conference he co-founded in 2014. Costos received the Sorolla Medal for excellence and contribution to Hispanic arts and culture from the Hispanic Society of America, the Medalla de Oro de Canarias, and the Navy Distinguished Public Service Award, and he currently sits on the International Council of The Hispanic Society in NYC and the Reina Sofia Museum in Madrid.<br><br>Costos is a passionate supporter of the creative and visual arts and cultural organizations, including the Hispanic Society of America and the Whistler House Museum, and is a strong advocate for cultural diplomacy and a defender of global human rights. He is currently President of Secuoya Studios in Madrid, a Senior Advisor at FC Barcelona, and Senior Managing Director in the Global Venture Technologies Group at Dentons. Costos sits on the Boards of Directors of PJT Partners, Grifols, and the Human Rights Campaign, and sits of the advisory boards of two early-stage tech enterprises focused on Consumer Retail Artificial Intelligence and XR/VR electronics experiences, and he also enjoys mentoring Fellows at the Obama Foundation and the Schmidt Science Fellows Foundation. He authored a book, <em>El Amigo Americano, El Hombre de Obama en España,</em> and has written numerous articles on business and politics. Costos splits his time between Los Angeles, California, New York City, and Madrid with his partner of 20 years, Michael S. Smith, and their three dogs.<br><br><strong>United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</strong><br>The United States Commission on International Religious Freedom is an independent, bipartisan U.S. federal government commission created by the 1998 International Religious Freedom Act that monitors the universal right to freedom of religion or belief abroad. USCIRF uses international standards to monitor religious freedom violations globally, and makes policy recommendations to the President, the Secretary of State, and Congress. USCIRF Commissioners are appointed by the President and Congressional leaders of both political parties.<br><br><strong>Stephen Schneck, Commissioner, United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</strong><br>Stephen Schneck is a political philosopher by training who retired from The Catholic University of America in 2018, after more than thirty years as a professor, department chair, and dean. At the university he was also the founder and long-time director of the Institute for Policy Research &amp; Catholic Studies. He received his doctorate from the University of Notre Dame.<br><br>As an activist, Schneck currently serves on the governing boards of Catholic Climate Covenant, which advocates for environmental justice and care for creation, and of Catholic Mobilizing Network, a Catholic organization working to end the death penalty and advance restorative justice. Previously, he was the executive director of Franciscan Action Network, which promotes environmental, economic, racial, and social justice on behalf of the Franciscan communities of the United States. He served the administration of President Barack Obama as a member of the White House Advisory Council for Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships. Born and raised in Clinton, Iowa, Schneck now lives with his wife, Suzanne, on Bald Head Island, North Carolina.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
