<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 16:17:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 2545 and S.&#160;321</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/14/bills-signed-h-r-2545-and-s-321/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 16:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, March 14, 2022, the President signed into law:&#160;H.R. 2545, which clarifies the roles and pay of doctors of podiatric medicine in the VA system.&#160; Thank you to Representatives Wenstrup, Mrvan, Suozzi and Schakowsky and Senators Cassidy and Sinema for their leadership. S. 321, the &#8220;Six Triple Eight&#8221; Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2022,&#8221;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, March 14, 2022, the President signed into law:<br>&nbsp;<br>H.R. 2545, which clarifies the roles and pay of doctors of podiatric medicine in the VA system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Wenstrup, Mrvan, Suozzi and Schakowsky and Senators Cassidy and Sinema for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 321, the &#8220;Six Triple Eight&#8221; Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2022,&#8221; which provides for the award of a Congressional Gold Medal to the members of the Women’s Army Corps who were assigned to the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion, known as the &#8220;Six Triple Eight&#8221;.</p>



<p>Thank you to and Senators Jerry Moran and Jacky Rosen and Representatives Gwen Moore and Jake LaTurner for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the 2022 International Women of Courage Award&#160;Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/14/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-2022-international-women-of-courage-award-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 15:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State Washington, D.C. From soft lullabies to battle cries for justice, women nurse and nurture, teach and build, lead and dream our world forward—each and every day.&#160; Women have never been silent, but women have been silenced:&#160;with violence, with hate, discrimination, and isolation, with work and care that is never done. Women&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">U.S. Department of State</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>From soft lullabies to battle cries for justice, women nurse and nurture, teach and build, lead and dream our world forward—each and every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Women have never been silent, but women have been silenced:&nbsp;with violence, with hate, discrimination, and isolation, with work and care that is never done.</p>



<p>Women have been told that they are dangerous. And that’s because they are—dangerous to corruption and injustice. When we raise our voices, we have the power to shatter the shields of oppression.</p>



<p>That’s why cowardly men stop girls from learning. It’s why women’s bodies become casualties of war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like all of us, my heart has ached watching videos of Ukraine. Sick kids fleeing on makeshift medical trains, the unthinkable bombing of a maternity ward. Parents weeping over their children’s broken bodies in the streets. The senselessness is staggering.<br><br>We also know that there are horrors happening around the globe that never make the evening news. There are children’s broken bodies and women who bear the scars of war all around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there are women everywhere whose voices need to be heard — because stories are powerful. They shape our lives —defining the shades of our joy and sorrow, dividing what matters from the rest. They’re how we understand and connect to each other—beyond language, and distance, and time. They foster empathy and compel each of us to act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I continue to teach writing at a nearby community college, and in my classes, I watch students find confidence when they lay their lives down on paper. I’ve seen them draw closer to one another when they share, realizing that their differences are precious and their similarities infinite. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The stories we tell matter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My husband, our President, knows that. He knows how the stories he heard from survivors of abuse kept him up at night, how they inspired him to write and champion the Violence Against Women Act.</p>



<p>He knows that women’s voices have been the heart of resistance to tyranny, and that no country that oppresses half of its population can thrive.</p>



<p>And he knows that the United States must lead a global community dedicated to stopping the corruption, and injustice, and brutality that silences women. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Because there can be no true democracy, no true peace, no true prosperity without women’s voices. There can be no history without our stories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why what we do here resonates far beyond these walls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For 16 years, these awards have lifted up the voices of women around the world. It has shined light on the struggles and strength of women in the global North, South, East, and West. It has declared to all: The United States stands with these heroes. They are not alone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, we honor twelve women—and we go further, giving them a platform to speak their truth in their own words. We recognize the power that they hold—to take on the most dire challenges of our time and move us all to do more.</p>



<p>When you hear their words, hold them close to your heart. Share them with your daughters and sons, and with everyone you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tell their stories because they can inspire our world to rise to their courage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tell them because women warriors everywhere need to hear what’s possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tell them because there is a sisterhood of girls who hold a universe of possibility within themselves, who need to know that the future belongs to them, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To all Women of Courage—those fighting injustice in Latin America or hoping to learn in the Middle East, working for democracy and stability in Europe, protecting their families in sub-Saharan Africa, or speaking out against gender violence in Asia—we will continue to work with passion and persistence, with development and democracy, to stop those who wish to silence you.</p>



<p>And we will tell your stories, even when you cannot.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Iran Missile Attack on Kurdistan Region of&#160;Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/13/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-iran-missile-attack-on-kurdistan-region-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 01:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States condemns in the strongest terms Iran’s missile attack on the Kurdistan Region of Iraq. This attack targeted a civilian residence in Erbil, the Kurdistan Region’s capital city, without any justification. The United States stands with Prime Minister Kadhimi and the leaders of the Kurdistan Region, President Nechirvan Barzani, and Prime Minister Masrour Barzani,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States condemns in the strongest terms Iran’s missile attack on the Kurdistan Region of Iraq. This attack targeted a civilian residence in Erbil, the Kurdistan Region’s capital city, without any justification. The United States stands with Prime Minister Kadhimi and the leaders of the Kurdistan Region, President Nechirvan Barzani, and Prime Minister Masrour Barzani, in condemning this assault on the sovereignty of Iraq and its Kurdistan region. We will support the Government of Iraq in holding Iran accountable, and we will support our partners throughout the Middle East in confronting similar threats from Iran. The United States of America stands behind the full sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of Iraq. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/13/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-macron-of-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France to discuss Russia’s war against Ukraine. They reviewed recent diplomatic engagements and underscored their commitment to hold Russia accountable for its actions and to support the government and people of Ukraine. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France to discuss Russia’s war against Ukraine. They reviewed recent diplomatic engagements and underscored their commitment to hold Russia accountable for its actions and to support the government and people of Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Bilateral Meeting between President Joe&#160;Biden and Micheál Martin, Taoiseach of&#160;Ireland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/13/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-bilateral-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-micheal-martin-taoiseach-of-ireland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 17, President Joe Biden will host Micheál Martin, Taoiseach of Ireland, for a bilateral meeting and Shamrock presentation at the White House, continuing a longstanding St. Patrick’s Day tradition. The leaders will reaffirm the close and historic partnership between the United States and Ireland and the extraordinary bonds between our people. They will discuss&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On March 17, President Joe Biden will host Micheál Martin, Taoiseach of Ireland, for a bilateral meeting and Shamrock presentation at the White House, continuing a longstanding St. Patrick’s Day tradition. The leaders will reaffirm the close and historic partnership between the United States and Ireland and the extraordinary bonds between our people. They will discuss their countries’ contributions to the international effort to support the people of Ukraine and to impose costs on Russia for its unprovoked and unjustified war. They will also talk about a range of global issues and shared priorities, including combatting the COVID-19 pandemic worldwide, strengthening global health security, tackling the climate crisis, and working together on the United Nations Security Council. In addition, they will discuss their continued support for the Good Friday Agreement (also known as the Belfast Agreement). Vice President Kamala Harris will host the Taoiseach for a breakfast at the Naval Observatory on March 17.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Travel to&#160;Rome</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/13/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-travel-to-rome/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and officials from the National Security Council and State Department will be in Rome. Sullivan will meet with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi as part of our ongoing efforts to maintain open lines of communication between&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and officials from the National Security Council and State Department will be in Rome. Sullivan will meet with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi as part of our ongoing efforts to maintain open lines of communication between the United States and the People’s Republic of China (PRC). The two sides will discuss ongoing efforts to manage the competition between our two countries and discuss the impact of Russia’s war against Ukraine on regional and global security. Sullivan will also meet with Luigi Mattiolo, Diplomatic Advisor to the Italian Prime Minister to continue coordinating a strong, united international response to President Putin’s war of choice. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the DNC Winter&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/12/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-dnc-winter-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 19:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Washington HiltonWashington, D.C. 12:41 P.M. EST THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone!  (Applause.)  Good afternoon, Democrats!  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Please, have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon. Jaime, thank you for those kind words and for your continuous leadership.  You’ve done such an outstanding job. And on behalf of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Washington Hilton<br><em>Washington, D.C.</em></em></p>



<p>12:41 P.M. EST<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone!  (Applause.)  Good afternoon, Democrats!  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Please, have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.<br><br>Jaime, thank you for those kind words and for your continuous leadership.  You’ve done such an outstanding job.<br><br>And on behalf of the first Second Gentleman of the United States and myself &#8212; (applause) &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I want to say thank you to everybody in this room.  It is wonderful to see this group of friends in person.  <br><br>This, of course, is the first time that we have been able to get together in person since the President and I were inaugurated.  And I can just feel the energy in the room, which, of course, is reflective of the extraordinary dedication, commitment, and work that each of you have been doing over the course of the last couple of years, which presented, of course, many challenges because of the pandemic. <br><br>But for so many of you, this is part of a lifetime of commitment to extraordinary work on behalf of so many people in our country.  So thank you all.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you.<br><br>And thank you for the work that you did to get us into the White House &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and to win control of the Senate, and to keep control of the House!  (Applause.) <br><br>You all did that work.  And, you know, sometimes you make it look easy, but it&#8217;s not.  It&#8217;s hard work.  It&#8217;s difficult work.  It&#8217;s around-the-clock work.  It&#8217;s work that requires great sacrifice in terms of the other commitments in your lives.<br><br>And you do this work on behalf of people sometimes that you meet, on behalf of people that you don&#8217;t meet.  You do this work on behalf of people that may never know your names, may never know my name, but will be forever impacted and, to our mission, uplifted because of the work of the people in this room.</p>



<p><br>And so when I think about where we are, based on the work that has already happened to get us here, I know it has been hard work and good work.  <br><br>I also want to give a special shout-out to the Californians in the room &#8212; (applause) &#8212; because how could I not.<br><br>But to everyone: Thank you again.<br><br>So I just returned this morning from Poland and Romania.  And I&#8217;ll tell you that everything that you were watching on television I know makes you understand and feel the importance of this moment on many levels. </p>



<p><br>When I was meeting with our allies, I emphasized that the greatest strength that we share is unity, especially at this moment, as we stand together in defense of democracy and stand together in defense of each other.  (Applause.)<br><br>And that unity and &#8212; to our collective resolve has been strengthened, of course, since Russians’ reinvasion of Ukraine and Putin&#8217;s war.<br><br>Russia&#8217;s invasion threatens not just Ukraine&#8217;s democracy, it threatens democracy and security across Europe.  And by extension, when democracy is threatened anywhere, it threatens us all.  And the ocean that separates us will not leave us untouched by this aggression.<br><br>So I will say what I know we all say, and I will say over and over again: The United States stands firmly with the Ukrainian people [and] in defense of the NATO Alliance.  (Applause.) <br><br>And I&#8217;ll tell you, while I was &#8212; while I was there these last couple of days, I met with the presidents of both nations, and I &#8212; and I met with refugees from Ukraine, some of who are Ukrainian citizens, others who were students studying in Ukraine from other countries.<br><br>And, you know, they feel very alone, of course, because of the experience they&#8217;ve been having.  One of them was a 22-year-old student from Morocco who fled by himself, doesn&#8217;t know anybody.<br><br>And because of the experience they&#8217;ve had, they&#8217;ve, of course, not been in a room like this among the population, the multitude of people who support them.  And I told them &#8212; and so what you did to stand and applaud them in this point means a lot.  I told them people around the world stand with them, and they are not alone.<br><br>When I was there, I met with a group of American troops who are there with a group of troops from Poland, working together, training together &#8212; attempting to understand each other&#8217;s language, but yet speaking the same language &#8212; in their fight for what is important about this moment.<br><br>So, again, I thank you all.<br><br>Days before I traveled to Poland, with many of you, I was in Selma to commemorate the 57th anniversary &#8212; (applause) &#8212; of the march across the Edmund Pettus Bridge, that historic place which is a stark reminder that we must always remain vigilant to safeguard freedom and democracy.  Because we all know, in this room, neither is assured without our vigilance.  And defending democracy, then, takes all of us.<br><br>As I said last week about the great Congressman John Lewis &#8212; (applause) &#8212; this fight for democracy, for freedom, for equality, for justice requires of all of us, like John Lewis modeled &#8212; it requires from all of us a clarity of purpose and a determination and diligence to always keep our eye on the ball, understanding that in this fight for democracy, we must appreciate its character and nature. <br><br>We must understand that when we have a democracy that reflects its values by treating people with a sense of equality and fairness and justice, we can see, when it works, it possesses great strengths. </p>



<p><br>And we must always remember the duality of a democracy in that, yes, there is strength.  But a democracy by its nature is also fragile, meaning it will only be intact if we fight for it and never take it for granted and be vigilant with a sense of clarity every day.  (Applause.)<br><br>And that&#8217;s what we in this room stand for &#8212; all of us fighting and marching and pushing forward together to reach our ideals in the constant effort to create a more perfect union. <br><br>You know, when the President and I took office, our country was facing the aftermath of a reckless president, the COVID-19 pandemic, and questions about America&#8217;s leadership on the world stage.  We had a plan to get America back on track with the support of the American people and the leaders in this room.<br><br>We knew, all of us, our election should herald a change in direction, not just a change in management.  And President Biden and I, then, with your help and leadership, chartered a new course for our nation&#8217;s future.  And we rebuilt relationships with our allies.  And the results of that effort are clear as we stand together in this unified rebuke of Russia.<br><br>The President and I also proposed, with your leadership, with your help, the American Rescue Plan &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to fight through the impact of COVID.  And since that plan was enacted last year, we went from 2 million people vaccinated to over 215 million vaccinated in our country.  (Applause.)<br><br>Businesses are back open, and 99 percent of our schools are no longer remote.  We went from 60,000 jobs created each month to 678,000 jobs created last month &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and over 7 million total jobs created since we took office.<br><br>Unemployment is down 3.8 percent.  Black unemployment is at an all-time low, and Hispanic unemployment has fallen by historic amounts.  (Applause.)<br><br>The Child Tax Credit cut childhood poverty for the children &#8212; the children &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Latino children, Black children, poor children, Appalachian children &#8212; by 40 percent.  (Applause.) <br><br>Because of your work, and with your help, we passed a once-in-a-generation infrastructure law.  (Applause.)  And it will create more jobs, it will rebuild communities.  I&#8217;m sorry, it will create more jobs, including good union jobs.  (Applause.)  That&#8217;s right.  That&#8217;s right.  Because we&#8217;re clear on who helped build the middle class of America.  We&#8217;re clear on that.<br><br>So, yes, it will create more jobs, it’ll rebuild communities and do so much more to help America&#8217;s families.<br><br>For example, just last week, we announced nearly one and a half billion dollars in grants to help cities and towns electrify their fleet of public buses, build infrastructure to support their fleet, and train workers. <br><br>Thank you, again, for all of the apprenticeships run by our unions that are training these workers &#8212; (applause) &#8212; with extraordinary skills to actually do the work.<br><br>And think about it on the issue of public transit: So, this will make public transit more reliable, more affordable, and more efficient.  So imagine, if you will, a mother or a father trying to get out of the house during the week, in the morning, trying to get the kids to school and get to work. <br><br>And then imagine for that parent, one of them kids don&#8217;t want to put on their shoes.  Familiar experience.  And so that parent misses the bus by just a few minutes.  If the bus only comes by once an hour, those kids are going to be late for school, mom or dad is going to be late for work.<br><br>And that might mean having their pay docked or potentially even losing their job. <br><br>Public transit: Working people in America, in so many places in our country, rely on it for all of their essential needs.  This is about to change with an investment of billion dollars &#8212; in billions of dollars in public transit.<br>So when we look at this issue, it is one of many. <br><br>But we&#8217;re not going to stop there, and we didn&#8217;t stop there.  More than 70 percent of the judicial nominees we have appointed are women.  (Applause.)  More than 70 percent. <br><br>And, of course, the President recently nominated Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson to the United States Supreme Court.  (Applause.)<br><br>And I&#8217;ll share with you guys &#8212; going off script &#8212; I’ll share with you guys: So, the President and I were there at the White House for the day of the &#8212; of the &#8212; that he announced his nomination, and many of you may have watched it on television.  And so we were in the back before we went out.  And before we walked out, I just looked at our President and I said, “You’re again making history.  You&#8217;re again making history.”  Think about that. <br><br>You know, when we &#8212; when we look at the job we have in the coming months, and people will look at all of us as leaders and they&#8217;ll say, “Well, why should I vote?  Why does it matter?”  There&#8217;s so much we have to talk about.  We have collectively, on many levels, achieved historic feats.  And let&#8217;s be proud of that &#8212; knowing, of course, that there is still more to do.  Let&#8217;s be proud of that.  Be proud of that.  (Applause.)<br><br>And so, on the issue of Judge Jackson, she will make an outstanding and extraordinary jurist.  And if confirmed, of course, she will be the first Black woman on the highest court in the land.  (Applause.) <br><br>And &#8212; don&#8217;t let this be lost in terms of this point in history: And for the first time in history, four women will sit on the United States Supreme Court at the same time.  (Applause.)  How about that?  How about that? <br><br>So there&#8217;s a whole long list I could go through, but you all know it.  And, you know, I know you&#8217;ve been meeting for a couple days, so I&#8217;m not going to do that to you.  But I will say that, together, we have accomplished so much.  And, of course, yes, there is more to do.<br><br>As the President laid out in his State of the Union, it&#8217;s time to bring down costs &#8212; the cost of living &#8212; even more.  It is time to create more union jobs.  It is time to ensure that everyone has an opportunity to succeed.  It is time to defend our democracy and be vigilant in its defense, and to safeguard our planet for generations to come.  It is time to do so much more.<br><br>And over the past year, I have traveled our country, talking with many leaders including those from, of course, this room, those from the Latino community, the Black community, AAPI community, LGBTQ+ community, the disability community, all around our country.<br><br>And we have talked about many of the issues that I know over the last couple of days this group has addressed.  We have talked about one of the most urgent issues as well, in terms of how the clock is ticking on a purposeful attack against our democracy being waged in states around our country.  And that is on the attack on the freedom to vote. <br><br>And we have talked about what we must do, us as leaders, all of us, understanding the intentions that are at play, which are to make it more difficult for people to vote &#8212; certain populations in particular &#8212; with an expectation that if you make it more difficult, then people won&#8217;t vote.<br><br>We have discussed together our frustrations and fears.  We&#8217;ve talked about the rights that we fought so hard to win and how they could be lost. <br><br>But I will say, as we talked about last week in Selma: We must fight on, because we know all of our rights and all of our progress depends on the freedom to vote &#8212; workers’ rights, women&#8217;s rights, immigrant rights, LGBTQ rights.<br><br>All of the rights that we hold so dear flow from the right to vote.<br><br>So the DNC, of course, has taken on a role of leadership on this issue, as well as all the others, and in this fight making substantial investments &#8212; and thank you &#8212; in organizing, in strengthening state party infrastructure and protecting voters.<br><br>Last summer, I was proud to announce that the DNC would invest $25 million in its I Will Vote initiative to make voting more accessible and to fight back against Republicans’ unprecedented voter suppression efforts. <br><br>As the tiebreaking vote in the Senate &#8212; I am the President of the Senate &#8212; I know, as you do &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I know, as you do, that protecting our majorities on Capitol Hill is critical.  And that is why President Biden announced that the DNC will transfer $15 million to the DCCC and the DSCC.  (Applause.)<br><br>So, the work ahead is not going to be easy.  Everybody knows that.  That&#8217;s why you all are here, knowing the work that must be done, knowing it&#8217;s not going to be easy, but knowing we are under one roof together, in solidarity, in our commitment to seeing this through.<br><br>I know, and I believe we know, when we show what we have accomplished just in a year, and when we show it as because the American people voted, I believe we will meet the moment again.  But that is our task.  Our task is to show people that, in many ways, they got what they ordered.  Right?  (Applause.)  They said this is what they wanted.  They stood in line.  They took time from work.  It was difficult.  And a lot of what they demanded, they got. <br><br>And so let&#8217;s get out there, as we do, and remind them of that.  Because we know that they will show up again and they will say, “Yes, we want better jobs at higher wages.”  They will say yes to extending the Child Tax Credit.  They will say, “Yes, we must fight climate change.”  They will say, “Yes, I wanted and got and want more diversity on the Court.”  They will say, “Yes, we must fight to protect reproductive rights.”  (Applause.) <br><br>We have faith in what they want and how much they want it and what they are prepared to do to get it.<br>So our job is the job of just supporting the people, supporting their voices, supporting their will and desire of what their government has a responsibility to deliver to uplift our nation and to strengthen it.  That&#8217;s at the core of the work we do.<br><br>When we fight for social justice, when we fight for equal rights, when we fight for all that is on our list of priorities, that&#8217;s our mission: to strengthen our nation &#8212; so that when I go overseas, when the President goes overseas, when you talk to folks, and we say, “America is a beacon, it is a model,” that we can actually back that up.  That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing.  (Applause.)  That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing. <br><br>We are, as Democrats, continuing to own the responsibility that comes with being a role model, which is, as a democracy, to take care of its people &#8212; to see them, to hear them, and to be reflective of their priorities and their needs.<br><br>So, DNC, we will keep working the phones, and we will keep registering the voters, and we will keep getting the souls to the polls.  (Applause.)  And we will keep doing all that is necessary to fight for the best of who we are.<br><br>Thank you, DNC.  (Applause.)  Thank you for your leadership.  Thank you all.<br><br>END                 1:05 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/12/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 15:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961         By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America,&#160;including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate to the Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961        </p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America,&nbsp;including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $200 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris to U.S. and Polish&#160;Troops</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/11/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-to-u-s-and-polish-troops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 23:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Warsaw Chopin International AirportWarsaw, Poland THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Good morning, good morning.  So it was very important for the President of the United States and me to be here on the ground to say hello and to say thank you to all of you for your service, for your sacrifice, for your dedication,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Warsaw Chopin International Airport<br><em>Warsaw, Poland</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Good morning, good morning.  So it was very important for the President of the United States and me to be here on the ground to say hello and to say thank you to all of you for your service, for your sacrifice, for your dedication, for your patriotism.<br><br>You know, I’ll just say that I start every morning reading what we call the Presidential Daily Brief, which is generated by our intelligence community, and where I read about hotspots around the world and, in the case of the United States, threats to our national security.  (Inaudible).<br><br>Then I got into the Oval Office and I sit down with the President and the Secretary of Defense and the Joint Chiefs, the Chairman.  And we talk about you guys, and how proud we are and your service. <br><br>We talked about the fact that Poland joined NATO in 1999.  And since 2014, the United States made a commitment to our friends in Poland to support you.  And that’s when we first sent troops on a rotational basis, averaging about 5,000, and then over the course of the last couple of months, another 4,700 to stand with you in the alliance that is the NATO Alliance. <br><br>I&#8217;ve said in many places, I will say again today, that part of being in the NATO Alliance means that we have a motto which we (inaudible): An attack against one is an attack against all.  And the United States takes that commitment very seriously.  It is part of the reason I am here.<br><br>In this moment of Russian aggression and Putin’s war, we take seriously our commitment to defend, if necessary, every inch of NATO territory.  So that is why I&#8217;m here, to reinforce and reaffirm that commitment.  But these men and women are on the ground to see it through as necessary. <br><br>I was with President Duda yesterday, and we spoke of this collaboration, this partnership, this friendship and what it means to our two nations, and what it symbolizes for us as nations that are grounded and founded in certain principles, including the importance of sovereignty and territorial integrity.  And that&#8217;s what&#8217;s at stake as much as anything in terms of Russia&#8217;s reinvasion of Ukraine. <br><br>So, we stand as partners.  We work together.  We train together.  We form friendships that are based on solidarity, mutual values, and shared principles. <br><br>All of you took an oath to protect and defend your country.  You have each decided to live a life of service, doing some of the most important work any individual could ever do, which is prepare to sacrifice for the sake of your nation.  That is some of the most noble work any human being (inaudible). <br><br>So, before I got on that plane, I wanted to come by and tell you all &#8212; all of you &#8212; thank you.  When we are in those rooms making decisions, it is you we have in mind, knowing that when we stand firm, we can back it up with you &#8212; some of the best fighting forces in the world.  So thank you all &#8212; all of you.  Thank you all. <br><br>And with that, I want to meet every one of you.  So let’s do that.   </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.J. Res.&#160;75</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/bill-signed-h-j-res-75/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 23:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On&#160;Friday,&#160;March&#160;11, 2022, the President signed into law: H.J.Res. 75, the &#8220;Extension of Continuing Appropriations Act, 2022,&#8221; which provides fiscal year 2022 appropriations to Federal agencies through March 15, 2022, for continuing projects and activities of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On&nbsp;Friday,&nbsp;March&nbsp;11, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.J.Res. 75, the &#8220;Extension of Continuing Appropriations Act, 2022,&#8221; which provides fiscal year 2022 appropriations to Federal agencies through March 15, 2022, for continuing projects and activities of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
