<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 20:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with Lead Financial Regulators</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/21/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-lead-financial-regulators/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 20:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President met with top financial regulators to discuss how to build on the rapid economic turnaround since his inauguration and ensure there is sustainable and equitable growth that benefits every American family. The regulators reported that the financial system is in strong condition. They further indicated that financial risks are being mitigated by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President met with top financial regulators to discuss how to build on the rapid economic turnaround since his inauguration and ensure there is sustainable and equitable growth that benefits every American family. The regulators reported that the financial system is in strong condition. They further indicated that financial risks are being mitigated by robust capital and liquidity levels in the banking system, and healthy household balance sheets stemming from fiscal support and the ongoing economic recovery. The regulators also said they were making steady progress on the President’s executive order on climate-related risk and discussed ideas for promoting financial inclusion and for responsibly increasing access to credit for potential homeowners and small businesses.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to North Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/21/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 19:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to North Korea that was declared in Executive Order 13466 of June 26, 2008, expanded in scope in Executive Order 13551 of August 30, 2010, addressed further in Executive Order 13570 of April 18, 2011, further expanded in scope in Executive Order 13687 of January 2, 2015, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13722 of March 15, 2016, and Executive Order 13810 of September 20, 2017, is to continue in effect beyond June 26, 2021. </p>



<p>The existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula; the actions and policies of the Government of North Korea that destabilize the&nbsp;Korean Peninsula and imperil United States Armed Forces, allies,&nbsp;and trading partners in the region, including its pursuit of nuclear and missile programs; and other provocative, destabilizing, and repressive actions and policies of the&nbsp;Government of North Korea, continue to constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 with respect to North Korea.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to North Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/21/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 19:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 26, 2008, by Executive Order 13466, the President declared a national emergency with respect to North Korea pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the existence and risk of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 26, 2008, by Executive Order 13466, the President declared a national emergency with respect to North Korea pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons-usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula.  The President also found that it was necessary to maintain certain restrictions with respect to North Korea that would otherwise have been lifted pursuant to Proclamation 8271 of June 26, 2008, which terminated the exercise of authorities under the Trading With the Enemy Act (50 U.S.C. App. 1-44) with respect to North Korea.</p>



<p>On August 30, 2010, the President signed Executive Order&nbsp;13551, which expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States posed by the continued actions and policies of the Government of North Korea, manifested by its unprovoked attack that resulted in the sinking of the Republic of Korea Navy ship <em>Cheonan</em> and the deaths of 46 sailors in March&nbsp;2010; its announced test of a nuclear device and its missile launches in 2009; its actions in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718 and 1874, including the procurement of luxury goods; and its illicit and deceptive activities in international markets through which it obtains financial and other support, including money laundering, the counterfeiting of goods and currency, bulk cash smuggling, and narcotics trafficking, which destabilize the Korean Peninsula and imperil United States Armed Forces, allies, and trading partners in the region.</p>



<p>On April 18, 2011, the President signed Executive Order 13570 to take additional steps to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 and expanded in Executive Order 13551 that would ensure implementation of the import restrictions contained in United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718 and 1874 and complement the import restrictions provided for in the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 <em>et</em><em>seq</em>.).</p>



<p>On January 2, 2015, the President signed Executive Order 13687 to expand the scope of, and to take further steps with respect to, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as expanded in Executive Order 13551, and addressed further in Executive Order 13570, to address the threat to the&nbsp;national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the provocative, destabilizing, and&nbsp;repressive actions and policies of the Government of North Korea, including its destructive, coercive cyber-related actions during November and December 2014, actions in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718, 1874, 2087, and 2094, and commission of serious human rights abuses.</p>



<p>On March 15, 2016, the President signed Executive Order 13722 to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as modified in scope and relied upon for additional steps in subsequent Executive Orders, to address the Government of North Korea&#8217;s continuing pursuit of its nuclear and missile programs, as evidenced by its February 7, 2016, launch using ballistic missile technology and its January 6, 2016, nuclear test in violation of its obligations pursuant to numerous United Nations Security Council resolutions and in contravention of its commitments under the September 19, 2005, Joint Statement of the Six-Party Talks, that increasingly imperils the United States and its allies.</p>



<p>On September 20, 2017, the President signed Executive Order&nbsp;13810 to take further steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as modified in scope and relied upon for additional steps in subsequent Executive Orders, to address the provocative, destabilizing, and&nbsp;repressive actions and policies of the Government of North&nbsp;Korea, including its intercontinental ballistic missile launches&nbsp;of July 3 and July 28, 2017, and its nuclear test of September&nbsp;2, 2017; its commission of serious human rights abuses; and its use of funds generated through international trade to support its nuclear and missile programs and weapons proliferation.</p>



<p>The existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons‑usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula and the actions and policies of the Government of North Korea continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; For&nbsp;this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, expanded in scope in Executive Order 13551, addressed further in Executive Order 13570, further expanded in scope in Executive Order 13687, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13722 and Executive Order 13810, must continue in effect beyond June 26, 2021.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 with respect to North Korea.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 21, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Child Tax Credit Awareness Day</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/21/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-child-tax-credit-awareness-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 16:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have repeatedly said that America’s middle class deserves a tax cut, and we’re providing a significant tax cut to America’s working families with children through the largest-ever child tax credit. Not only did the American Rescue Plan increase the child tax credit to $3000 for families whose children are between 6-17 years old and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I have repeatedly said that America’s middle class deserves a tax cut, and we’re providing a significant tax cut to America’s working families with children through the largest-ever child tax credit.</p>



<p>Not only did the American Rescue Plan increase the child tax credit to $3000 for families whose children are between 6-17 years old and $3600 for families with children under 6 years old, it allows half of that tax cut to be paid to families in advance through a monthly check or direct deposit. This year, a family with two young children would receive a tax cut of $7200, with a monthly payment of $600 starting in July. Almost all families who have filed taxes in the last two years will receive this tax cut automatically.</p>



<p>This tax cut will give our nation’s hardworking families with children a little more breathing room when it comes to putting food on the table, paying the bills, and making ends meet. Nearly every working family with children is going to feel this tax cut make a difference in their lives, and we need to spread the word so that all eligible families get the full credit.</p>



<p>Just as Americans came together in support of the American Rescue Plan, we’re asking Americans to come together to build support and awareness for this vital tax relief for families, to help us extend it for years to come, and to ensure we get all children in our nation’s low-income families signed up this year.</p>



<p>If we’re able to get every family signed up, it will mean significant tax relief for America’s working families, and will help bring us even closer to cutting child poverty in half. That is why we have designated today, June 21, as Child Tax Credit Awareness Day. Across the nation, organizations that advocate for children, faith-based organizations and elected officials are holding events, training volunteers, announcing strategies to sign up the lowest income families, and using social media to explain how the Child Tax Credit will cut child poverty and why we must extend it through the American Families Plan.</p>



<p>To help or sign up, please go to ChildTaxCredit.Gov. It provides simple, useful information, in both English and Spanish, as well as a link to help families sign up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For parents working to make ends meet and raise their children with greater security, dignity, and opportunity, help is here. On this Child Tax Credit Awareness day, let us all work together to make sure that the help that is here reaches those who most need it, this year and for years to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Announces Allocation Plan for 55 Million Doses to be Shared Globally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-allocation-plan-for-55-million-doses-to-be-shared-globally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21481</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[These doses are the remaining part of the 80 million President Biden pledged to allocate by the end of June Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing the distribution list for 55 million of the 80 million doses of America’s own vaccine supply President Biden has pledged to allocate by the end of June in service&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>These doses are the remaining part of the 80 million President Biden pledged to allocate by the end of June</em></p>



<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing the distribution list for 55 million of the 80 million doses of America’s own vaccine supply President Biden has pledged to allocate by the end of June in service of ending the pandemic globally.  As we continue to fight the COVID-19 pandemic at home and work to end the pandemic worldwide, President Biden has promised that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world. Part of that plan is donating vaccine from our domestic supply, and the President has pledged 80 million doses to be allocated by the end of June. Earlier this month, the Administration announced the plan for <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-unveils-strategy-for-global-vaccine-sharing-announcing-allocation-plan-for-the-first-25-million-doses-to-be-shared-globally/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the first 25 million</a> doses that we have begun shipping, and today’s announcement completes the list for the remaining 55 million doses. For all of these doses, those most at risk, such as health care workers, should be prioritized, based on national vaccine plans.<br><br>In addition to sharing doses from our own vaccine supply, the Biden-Harris Administration is also committed to working with our U.S. manufacturers to produce more vaccine to share with the world. To that end, ahead of the G7, President Biden announced that the U.S. will purchase <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/10/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-historic-vaccine-donation-half-a-billion-pfizer-vaccines-to-the-worlds-lowest-income-nations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">half a billion Pfizer doses</a> and donate them to 92 low- and lower middle-income countries and members of the African Union. In total, the G7+ agreed to provide an additional more than 1 billion doses starting summer 2021. In addition, the U.S. is committed to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/13/fact-sheet-united-states-and-g7-partners-will-provide-more-than-2-billion-vaccines-for-the-world/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">expanding local production of vaccines</a>, and through our Quad partnership and the International Development Finance Corporation’s support for vaccine manufacturing, more than 1 billion doses will be produced in Africa and India in 2021 and 2022. This vaccine strategy is a vital component of our overall global effort to lead the world in the fight to defeat COVID-19 and to achieve global health security.<br><br>For these 80 million doses, the U.S. will share 75% through COVAX and 25% will be targeted to help deal with surges around the world.  Our goals are to increase global COVID-19 vaccination coverage, prepare for surges and prioritize healthcare workers and other vulnerable populations based on public health data and acknowledged best practice, and help our neighbors and other countries in need.  And, as we have previously stated, the United States will not use its vaccines to secure favors from other countries. <br><br>Based on this framework and pending legal and regulatory approvals, <strong>the allocation plan for these 55 million doses will be as follows:  </strong></p>



<ul><li>Approximately 41 million will be shared through COVAX, with the following allocations:<ul><li>Approximately 14 million for Latin America and the Caribbean to the following: Brazil, Argentina, Colombia, Peru, Ecuador, Paraguay, Bolivia, Uruguay, Guatemala, El Salvador, Honduras, Haiti, and other Caribbean Community (CARICOM) countries, Dominican Republic, Panama, and Costa Rica.</li><li>Approximately 16 million for Asia to the following:  India, Nepal, Bangladesh, Pakistan, Sri Lanka, Afghanistan, Maldives, Bhutan, Philippines, Vietnam, Indonesia, Thailand, Malaysia, Laos, Papua New Guinea, Taiwan, Cambodia, and the Pacific Islands. </li><li>Approximately 10 million for Africa to be shared with countries that will be selected in coordination with the African Union. </li></ul></li><li>Approximately 14 million – or 25% of these 55 million vaccines – will be shared with regional priorities and other recipients, such as: Colombia, Argentina, Haiti, other CARICOM countries, Dominican Republic, Costa Rica, Panama, Afghanistan, Bangladesh, Pakistan, Philippines, Vietnam, Indonesia, South Africa, Nigeria, Kenya, Ghana, Cabo Verde, Egypt, Jordan, Iraq, Yemen, Tunisia, Oman, West Bank and Gaza, Ukraine, Kosovo, Georgia, Moldova, and Bosnia. </li></ul>



<p>Sharing millions of U.S. vaccines with other countries signals a major commitment by the U.S. Government.  Just like we have in our domestic response, we will move as expeditiously as possible, while abiding by U.S. and host country regulatory and legal requirements, to facilitate the safe and secure transport of vaccines across international borders.  This will take time, but the President has directed the Administration to use all the levers of the U.S. government to protect individuals from this virus as quickly as possible.  The specific vaccines and amounts will be determined and shared as the administration works through the logistical, regulatory and other parameters particular to each region and country.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White House Spokesperson Jen Psaki on the Visit of President Ashraf Ghani of Afghanistan and Dr. Abdullah Abdullah, Chairman of the High Council for National Reconciliation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/20/statement-by-white-house-spokesperson-jen-psaki-on-the-visit-of-president-ashraf-ghani-of-afghanistan-and-dr-abdullah-abdullah-chairman-of-the-high-council-for-national-reconciliation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden looks forward to welcoming Afghan President Ashraf Ghani and Dr. Abdullah Abdullah, Chairman of the High Council for National Reconciliation, to the White House on June 25, 2021. The visit by President Ghani and Dr. Abdullah will highlight the enduring partnership between the United States and Afghanistan as the military drawdown continues. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden looks forward to welcoming Afghan President Ashraf Ghani and Dr. Abdullah Abdullah, Chairman of the High Council for National Reconciliation, to the White House on June 25, 2021. The visit by President Ghani and Dr. Abdullah will highlight the enduring partnership between the United States and Afghanistan as the military drawdown continues. The United States is committed to supporting the Afghan people by providing diplomatic, economic, and humanitarian assistance to support the Afghan people, including Afghan women, girls and minorities. The United States will remain deeply engaged with the Government of Afghanistan to ensure the country never again becomes a safe haven for terrorist groups who pose a threat to the U.S. homeland. The United States continues to fully support the ongoing peace process and encourages all Afghan parties to participate meaningfully in negotiations to bring an end to the conflict.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on World Refugee Day </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/20/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-world-refugee-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, I join people around the globe in commemorating World Refugee Day, a day when we recognize the courage and humanity of the millions forced to flee violence, persecution, and war. It is also a moment to honor the generosity of communities welcoming refugees and the bravery and dedication of humanitarian workers who provide life-saving&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, I join people around the globe in commemorating World Refugee Day, a day when we recognize the courage and humanity of the millions forced to flee violence, persecution, and war. It is also a moment to honor the generosity of communities welcoming refugees and the bravery and dedication of humanitarian workers who provide life-saving assistance, often in challenging and dangerous conditions.</p>



<p>At a time when&nbsp;the number of refugees&nbsp;and other displaced persons&nbsp;has reached&nbsp;an&nbsp;alarming&nbsp;and&nbsp;historic high—more than 82 million&nbsp;worldwide—the United States&nbsp;has a moral obligation to ensure that refugees have access to life-saving care, opportunities to pursue an education, and livelihoods that allow them to live with dignity and hope for the future.&nbsp; On this day, we&nbsp;reaffirm our&nbsp;sacred&nbsp;commitment to alleviate suffering through humanitarian&nbsp;relief,&nbsp;and redouble our efforts to&nbsp;achieve&nbsp;lasting solutions for refugees—including through resettlement.&nbsp; We also recommit to engaging in diplomatic efforts to bring an end to the&nbsp;ongoing&nbsp;conflicts that compel refugees to seek safety elsewhere.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Protecting refugees is&nbsp;part of&nbsp;our DNA.&nbsp; Our nation was founded by those fleeing religious persecution.&nbsp; When we take action to help refugees around the world, we honor our past and live up to our highest values.&nbsp; We show our greatest strength as a nation.</p>



<p>We do this because it’s the right thing to do, but make no mistake:&nbsp; helping refugees helps the United States,&nbsp;too, bringing greater regional stability&nbsp;and making&nbsp;the world a safer place for all of us.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why I&nbsp;revised the United States’ annual refugee admissions cap to 62,500 for this fiscal year, and plan to raise it to 125,000 next year. While meeting these targets will be a challenge, I have directed my Administration to work as quickly as possible&nbsp;to rebuild and improve refugee processing and to expand our capacity to admit refugees.&nbsp;&nbsp;We&nbsp;need to&nbsp;lead by example. &nbsp;And the refugees who arrive at our shores will&nbsp;continue to strengthen our communities, as they always have, bringing&nbsp;new life, energy, and ideas&nbsp;to our great country. The United States&nbsp;is proud to stand as a beacon of liberty and refuge to the world, and whether it’s taking in&nbsp;those seeking safety&nbsp;or providing more humanitarian relief than any other nation, we’re going to do our part.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White House Spokesperson Jen Psaki on the Visit of President Reuven Rivlin of Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/19/statement-by-white-house-spokesperson-jen-psaki-on-the-visit-of-president-reuven-rivlin-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden looks forward to welcoming Israeli President Reuven Rivlin to the White House on June 28, 2021.  President Rivlin’s visit will highlight the enduring partnership between the United States and Israel and the deep ties between our governments and our people.  It will be an opportunity to consult about the many challenges and opportunities facing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden looks forward to welcoming Israeli President Reuven Rivlin to the White House on June 28, 2021.  President Rivlin’s visit will highlight the enduring partnership between the United States and Israel and the deep ties between our governments and our people.  It will be an opportunity to consult about the many challenges and opportunities facing the region.  As President Rivlin approaches the end of his term, this visit will honor the dedication he has shown to strengthening the friendship between the two countries over the course of many years.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by the President and the First Lady on the Passing of their Beloved German Shepherd, Champ</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/19/statement-by-the-president-and-the-first-lady-on-the-passing-of-their-beloved-german-shepherd-champ/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 15:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our hearts are heavy today as we let you all know that our beloved German Shepherd, Champ, passed away peacefully at home. He was our constant, cherished companion during the last 13 years and was adored by the entire Biden family. Even as Champ’s strength waned in his last months, when we came into a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Our hearts are heavy today as we let you all know that our beloved German Shepherd, Champ, passed away peacefully at home. He was our constant, cherished companion during the last 13 years and was adored by the entire Biden family. Even as Champ’s strength waned in his last months, when we came into a room, he would immediately pull himself up, his tail always wagging, and nuzzle us for an ear scratch or a belly rub. Wherever we were, he wanted to be, and everything was instantly better when he was next to us. He loved nothing more than curling up at our feet in front of a fire at the end of the day, joining us as a comforting presence in meetings, or sunning himself in the White House garden. In his younger days, he was happiest chasing golf balls on the front lawn of the Naval Observatory or racing to catch our grandchildren as they ran around our backyard in Delaware. In our most joyful moments and in our most grief-stricken days, he was there with us, sensitive to our every unspoken feeling and emotion. We love our sweet, good boy and will miss him always. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the COVID-19 Response and the Vaccination Program</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/18/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-covid-19-response-and-the-vaccination-program-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 2:53 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT: Good afternoon. (Clears throat.) Excuse me. I’m pleased to announce that today we will have reached the mark of 300 million shots in the arms in just 150 days. Let me say that again: 300 million shots in arms in under 150 days. It’s an important milestone&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>2:53 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Good afternoon. (Clears throat.) Excuse me. I’m pleased to announce that today we will have reached the mark of 300 million shots in the arms in just 150 days. Let me say that again: 300 million shots in arms in under 150 days.</p>



<p>It’s an important milestone that just didn’t happen on its own or by chance. It took the ingenuity of American scientists, the full capacity of American companies, and a whole-of-government response across federal, state, Tribal, and local governments.</p>



<p>Together, we built an unparalleled vaccination program and managed one of the biggest and most complicated logistical challenges in American history.</p>



<p>And above all, we got here because of the American people stepping up and getting vaccinated &#8212; helping family, friends, neighbors get vaccinated.</p>



<p>Just remember what the situation was like 150 days ago. We didn’t have enough vaccine supply for all Americans. We didn’t have the vaccine infrastructure or the people to administer the vaccines or the places where the people could get vaccinated. But we turned it around together by acting quickly and aggressively and equitably.</p>



<p>We secured enough vaccine supply for every American. And as I announced last week during my visit to Europe, we are now in a position to provide more than one half billion vaccine doses to the rest of the world &#8212; the 100 poorest nations.</p>



<p>We’ve developed and deployed over 9,000 federal personnel, including 5,100 active duty military, to support the vaccine effort and to get shots into arms. And now, we have more than 81,000 vaccination sites across the country, including over 42,000 local pharmacies.</p>



<p>Thanks to this wartime response, we have gotten 300 million shots in the arms of Americans in 150 days, months ahead of what most anyone thought was possible when we started.</p>



<p>In fact, if you remember, a lot of people were skeptical that we could even get 100 million shots in my first 100 days into people’s arms. But we did it. We kept going. And what we’re seeing is a truly American accomplishment.</p>



<p>Sixty-five percent &#8212; sixty-five percent &#8212; of American adults have gotten at least one shot, including eighty-seven percent of our seniors.</p>



<p>Just five months ago, we were at only 5 percent of adult Americans. Fifteen states and the District of Columbia have now reached at least 70 percent vaccination rate in their state. Twenty-six states and D.C. have fully vaccinated &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; 50 percent or more of the adults.</p>



<p>Nationwide, we have the lowest number of daily deaths<br>since the first days of the pandemic.</p>



<p>And we’ve built equity into the heart of our vaccination program from day one. Seventy-three percent of the shots administered at community health centers through the federal program and more than fifty-eight percent of the shots administered by federally-run vaccination sites have gone to people of color. And across the nation, people of color have accounted for more than half of all vaccinations in the last month. That’s important progress, but we have much more to do.</p>



<p>Vice President Harris is, as I speak &#8212; is in Atlanta, getting the word out about the vaccinations.</p>



<p>Yesterday, I signed a bill &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; into law making Juneteenth a federal holiday.</p>



<p>And this weekend, folks in communities across the country are going to be canvassing and hosting events to encourage their families, friends, and neighbors to get vaccinated. The more we close the racial gap in vaccination rates, the more lives we’ll save.</p>



<p>And as our vaccination program is saying &#8212; saving tens of thousands of lives, with that count growing each day, it’s also allowing millions of Americans to get back to living their lives. Grandparents hugging their kids. Kids back to school and getting ready for the summer. People going out to restaurants and traveling. Businesses are reopening.</p>



<p>Folks, we’re heading into a very different summer compared to last year. A bright summer. Prayerfully, a summer of joy.</p>



<p>But as I promised you from the beginning, I will always give it to you straight: the good, the bad, and the truth. And the truth is that deaths and hospitalizations are drastically down in places where people are getting vaccinated. But unfortunately, cases and hospitalizations are not going down<br>in many places in the lower-vaccination-rate states. They&#8217;re actually going up in some places.</p>



<p>A few days ago, we crossed 600,000 &#8212; 600,000 Americans dead from COVID, more than every death in World War One, World War Two, Vietnam, and 9/11 combined. So even while we’re making incredible progress, it remains a serious and deadly threat.</p>



<p>And the data is clear: If you are unvaccinated, you&#8217;re at risk of getting seriously ill or dying or spreading it. People getting seriously ill and being hospitalized due to COVID-19 are those who have not been fully vaccinated. The new variant will leave unvaccinated people even more vulnerable than they are a month ago &#8212; over a month ago.</p>



<p>This is a serious concern, especially because of what experts are calling the &#8220;Delta&#8221; vir- &#8212; the &#8220;Delta&#8221; variant. It’s a variant that is more easily transmissible, potentially deadlier, and particularly dangerous for young people.</p>



<p>But the good news is, we have the solution.The science and the data are clear: The best way to protect yourself against these variants are to get fully vaccinated.</p>



<p>So, please, please, if you have one shot, get the second shot as soon as you can so you&#8217;re fully vaccinated. And if you haven’t gotten vaccinated yet, get vaccinated now. Now. Don’t put it off. It’s free. It’s easy. It’s convenient.</p>



<p>And as I said many times, text your ZIP Code to the numbers 438829 &#8212; 438829 &#8212; to find the sites where you can get vaccinated closest to you. Get your free Uber or Lyft ride to and from vaccination sites. I want to thank Uber and Lyft for their cooperation.</p>



<p>Use the extended hours at thousands of pharmacies in June, including thousands that are open 24/7 on Friday of this month. Most pharmacies now offer walk-in vaccinations. No appointment is needed.</p>



<p>Employers with less than 500 employees: The federal government is providing you a tax credit to give your workers paid time off to get vaccinated and recover if they need be.</p>



<p>And for anyone who still questions, that’s okay if you still have questions. But act &#8212; act now. Act now. Talk to your family and friends who’ve gotten the vac- &#8212; gotten vaccinated. Talk to your doctor or pharmacist.</p>



<p>According to the American Medical Association, over 90 percent of physicians are fully vaccinated. They&#8217;re making the choice to protect themselves and their communities and their patients. Follow their lead and make the choice for yourself.</p>



<p>As I said, we’re heading into, God willing, the summer of joy, a summer of freedom. On July 4, we’re going to celebrate our independence from the virus as we celebrate our independence of our nation. We want everyone &#8212; everyone to be able to do that.</p>



<p>Let’s remember, we are the United States of America. Let’s get this done &#8212; all of us, together.</p>



<p>God bless you all. And may God protect our troops. Thank you.</p>



<p>Q Could the Delta variant force us back into lockdown?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I don&#8217;t think so because so many people have already been vaccinated, but the Delta variant can cause more people to die in areas where people have not been vaccinated. Where people have gotten the two shots, the Delta variant is highly unlikely to result in anything, other than &#8212; I mean, as &#8212; the existing vaccines are very effective.</p>



<p>So, no, it&#8217;s not a lockdown, but some areas will be very hurt.</p>



<p>Q Sir, any comment about (inaudible) what the Catholic Bishops have done? Are you concerned about this rift within the Catholic Church? And are you concerned about this action?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Say again.</p>



<p>Q The Catholic Bishops are moving on this resolution that would prevent you and others who&#8217;ve supported abortion from receiving communion. Are you concerned about the rift in the Catholic Church? And how do you feel personally about that?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: That&#8217;s a private matter, and I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s going to happen. Thank you.</p>



<p>Q Mr. President, have you seen the infrastructure plan on Capitol Hill &#8212; the bipartisan plan? Do you have any reaction to that?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: I&#8217;ll tell you Monday when I get a copy of it.</p>



<p>3:03 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
