<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 04:51:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Kentucky Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/27/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-kentucky-disaster-declaration-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 04:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47937</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Kentucky and ordered Federal assistance to supplement Commonwealth and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, flooding, landslides, and mudslides from December 31, 2021 to January 2, 2022. Federal funding is available to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Kentucky and ordered Federal assistance to supplement Commonwealth and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, flooding, landslides, and mudslides from December 31, 2021 to January 2, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to Commonwealth and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms, straight-line winds, tornadoes, flooding, landslides, and mudslides in the counties of Boyd, Breathitt, Carter, Christian, Clay, Floyd, Green, Johnson, Knott, Lawrence, Owsley, Pike, and Taylor.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures for the entire Commonwealth.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named John Brogan as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the Commonwealth and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on Imposing Additional Severe Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/27/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-imposing-additional-severe-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 17:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47931</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (February 26, 2022) MODERATOR:&#160; Thanks, everyone, for joining.&#160; As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&#160; We’re going to be discussing further restrictive economic measures we’re imposing on Russia today in coordination with Allies and partners. For your awareness and not for reporting, the speaker on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(February 26, 2022)</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&nbsp; We’re going to be discussing further restrictive economic measures we’re imposing on Russia today in coordination with Allies and partners.</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, the speaker on the call today is [senior administration official].</p>



<p>The contents of the call are embargoed until the end of this call.</p>



<p>So with that, [senior administration official], I’ll turn it over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; So as a result of Putin’s war of choice and ongoing assault on Ukraine and the core principles of peace and stability that have prevailed since the Second World War, President Biden and the leaders of the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, and the United Kingdom decided to take further measures to isolate Russia from the global financial system and the global economy.</p>



<p>In an unprecedented act of global sanctions coordination, our leaders decided to take three actions today: one, to apply the Iran model and disconnect sanctioned Russian banks from SWIFT; two, to undermine the Russian Central Bank’s ability to defend the ruble; and three, to launch a joint task force to collectively hunt down the physical assets of sanctioned Russian companies and oligarchs &#8212; their yachts, jets, fancy cars, and luxury homes.</p>



<p>Let me go into some detail on each of these three measures.</p>



<p>First, our leaders decided to follow the Iran model and disconnect key sanctioned Russian banks from SWIFT.&nbsp; The EU will implement a regulation that removes sanctioned Russian banks from the SWIFT international payments network, effectively shutting them out of the world’s most important financial system.</p>



<p>The reason de-SWIFTing is severe is that this is a network that almost all banks in the world use to transmit financial information to each other as they make payments or receive payments.&nbsp; The SWIFT code is on the bottom of every check you sign.&nbsp; About 11,000 banks across the world are members of the SWIFT network.&nbsp; If one of these de-SWIFTed Russian banks wants to make or receive a payment with a bank outside of Russia, such as a bank in Asia, it will now need to use the telephone or a fax machine.&nbsp; In all likelihood, most banks around the world will simply stop transacting altogether with Russian banks that are removed from SWIFT.</p>



<p>Two, leaders have committed to target the Russian Central Bank &#8212; the single-most important financial institution in Russia.&nbsp; We are collectively planning to impose measures to ensure Russia cannot use its Central Bank reserves to support its currency and thereby undermine the impact of our sanctions.</p>



<p>This will show that Russia’s supposed sanctions-proofing of its economy is a myth. The 600-billion-plus war chest of Russia’s foreign reserves is only powerful if Putin can use it and without being able to buy the Ruble from Western financial institutions, for example, Putin’s Central Bank will lose the ability to offset the impact of our sanctions.&nbsp; The Ruble will fall even further, inflation will spike, and the Central Bank will be left defenseless.</p>



<p>Third, this coming week, we will launch a multilateral transatlantic task force to identify, hunt down, and freeze the assets of sanctioned Russian companies and oligarchs &#8212; their yachts, their mansions, and any ill-gotten gains that we can find and freeze under the law.</p>



<p>We’ve already seen the impacts of transatlantic cooperation yesterday, when the French government seized a cargo ship owned by the sanctioned Russian bank Promsvyazbank.</p>



<p>As part of our new task force, we’re committed to fully implementing sanctions and other anti-money-laundering financial and enforcement measures to maximal effect on sanctioned Russian officials and elites close to the Russian government, as well as their families and their enablers, to identify and freeze the assets they hold in our jurisdictions.&nbsp; As I say, we’ll go after their yachts, their luxury apartments, their money, and their ability to send their kids to fancy colleges in the West.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ll also engage other governments so as to detect and disrupt the movement of ill-gotten gains and deny these individuals their ability to hide their assets in jurisdictions across the world.</p>



<p>We’re also announcing our commitment to take measures to limit the sale of citizenship &#8212; so-called golden passports that allow wealthy Russians connected to the Russian government to become citizens in certain countries and gain access to our financial systems.</p>



<p>Any current or future sanctioned individual trying to flee the impact of our sanctions by buying their way into Western citizenship will be forced to endure the consequences of supporting Putin’s war of choice.</p>



<p>These unprecedented actions we’re announcing today build on the swift and severe steps we’ve taken jointly with Allies and partners throughout the past week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In alignment with the decision by our European Allies yesterday, the United States sanctioned President Putin, Foreign Minister Lavrov, and members of the Russian national security team.</p>



<p>Yesterday, the President also directed the Secretary of the Treasury to impose full blocking sanctions on the Russian Direct Investment Fund in the coming days.&nbsp; This is a state-owned financial entity that functions as a sovereign wealth fund and attracts capital &#8212; is meant to attract capital into the Russian economy in high-growth and high-tech sectors.&nbsp; Sanctioning this entity will further curtail Putin’s strategic ambitions to expand the instruments of war and repression.</p>



<p>And, in total this week, as you reflect upon the financial sanctions we’ve implemented, we’ve now targeted all 10 of Russia’s largest financial institutions, holding nearly 80 percent of the Russian banking sector’s total assets.&nbsp; We’ve cut off Russia’s largest bank from the U.S. financial system, a very significant blow to its ability to function and process global trade.</p>



<p>The export control measures we took in lockstep with Allies and partners across the world, both in Europe and in Asia, will cut off more than half of Russia’s high-tech imports, restricting Russia’s access to vital technological inputs, atrophying its industrial base, and undercutting Russia’s strategic ambitions to exert influence on the world stage.</p>



<p>We’ve also sanctioned Russian oligarchs and Putin’s inner circle and their family members, including Putin’s cronies who sit atop Russia’s largest financial institutions and are responsible for providing the resources necessary to support Putin’s further invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>This has been the worst week for the Russian stock market on record.&nbsp; This has been the worst week for the Russian Ruble since March 2020, and the currency hit an all-time low against the Dollar earlier this week.&nbsp; Russia’s government borrowing costs have more than doubled to almost 17 percent.&nbsp; The S&amp;P credit rating agency has downgraded Russia to junk status.&nbsp; Within 24 hours of our actions, the demand for cash in Russia spiked 58-fold, according to reports, and the Russian government scrambled to deplete its own resources to try and shore up its banks and its currency.</p>



<p>In short, Russia has become a global, economic, and financial pariah.&nbsp; Over 30 countries representing well over half the world’s economy have announced sanctions and export controls on Russia.&nbsp; Putin’s government is getting kicked off the international financial system.</p>



<p>To be clear, this is a sad outcome for the people of Ukraine, the people of Russia, and many others.&nbsp; This is not where we wanted to be, but this is Putin’s war of choice, and only Putin can decide how much more cost he is willing to bear.&nbsp; The United States and our allies and partners are unified and will continue to impose costs.</p>



<p>Let me stop there.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great. Could we queue up the directions to ask a question please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you explain the move on the Central Bank?&nbsp; Are you putting it on the SDN lists?&nbsp; And if not, what mechanism are you using?</p>



<p>And then just more broadly, can you give us some sense about why everyone has moved quickly on Saturday to do this?&nbsp; Was there something that prompted you to go so quickly beyond what was happening in Ukraine in terms of Russia moving assets to avoid sanctions preemptively?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, thanks, Demetri.&nbsp; Well, we said all along: If Putin continues to escalate, we’ll escalate, and that all options remained on the table.&nbsp; We’re delivering on what we said.</p>



<p>And specifically, with respect to the Central Bank, today’s statement was a commitment by the leaders that I mentioned across the world to restrict the actions that the Russian Central Bank can take to undermine the impact of our sanctions.</p>



<p>So, as I mentioned at the outset, you heard about Fortress Russia &#8212; the war chest of 630 billion of foreign reserves.&nbsp; It’s impressive, but it’s only impressive if Russia can use those reserves.&nbsp; And that means Russia has to be able to sell those reserves and buy Ruble to support its currency.</p>



<p>And so, what we’re committing to do here is to disarm the Central Bank.&nbsp; And the way we can do that, for example, is by preventing U.S., EU, UK persons from selling Rubles to the Central Bank of Russia.&nbsp; That means very simply, the Russian Central Bank can’t support the Ruble, full stop, and that means our sanctions will have much greater force.</p>



<p>There are other measures, too, we could take against the Central Bank, and you’ll be hearing more about that later.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official]. And just to follow up on Demetri’s question: Are you, in fact, placing the Central Bank of Russia on the SDN list &#8212; or, in other words, are you freezing their assets?&nbsp; Or is it something less?</p>



<p>And does the SWIFT cutoff affect only banks that are already sanctioned, and which Russian banks are selected and how did you select them? Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, thanks, Ellen. We’re still finalizing the specific execution modality for the Central Bank sanctions, and it could involve both the flows that the Russian Central Bank is allowed to undertake, as well as the assets they have.</p>



<p>With respect to SWIFT and which banks will be de-SWIFTed, there’s a process underway, Ellen, to finalize the list of banks that will be cut off from the SWIFT system.&nbsp; There are several banks that Europe and the U.S. have sanctioned, and those will be the first ones considered.</p>



<p>And ultimately, as a matter of regulation, the list of banks that will be de-SWIFTed will be finalized by the EU, since SWIFT is under Belgian jurisdiction.</p>



<p>But we’re going to work very closely, as we have throughout this process, with our European partners to finalize that list.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing the call.&nbsp; Can you tell us if you have any indications from China or other countries that they’re going to help Russia soften the blow of these sanctions?&nbsp; Have you seen any sign of any transactions, for instance, that indicate &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Andrea.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what China is going to do?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I’m sorry to interrupt. Yeah, so, if anything, I would say, Andrea, the latest signs suggest that China is not coming to the rescue.&nbsp; I think it was reported yesterday or the day before that China was actually restricting some of its banks to provide credit to facilitate energy purchases from Russia, which suggests that, much like has been the pattern for years and years, China has tended to respect the force of U.S. sanctions.</p>



<p>And, you know, as we’ve said &#8212; just lifting up a little bit, as we said from the start, it really would be an unfortunate signal for China’s vision of the world if it gave tacit or explicit accommodation to Russia’s invasion of a sovereign country in the heart of Europe.&nbsp; It would do profound damage to its reputation in Europe, but really across the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; We have a question about energy carveouts in the de-SWIFTing process. Is there going to be carveouts for energy companies in Russia to still do business outside of Russia, similar to how Venezuela was de-SWIFTed a few years ago?</p>



<p>And also, how much of the 630 billion or -40 billion or so in reserves in the Central Bank do you think you’ll be able to really freeze?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so when an institution is de-SWIFTed, there tends not to be a carveout for the product type.&nbsp; And so, we are going to go institution by institution, in terms of those that are removed from the network, and we&#8217;ll pick those very carefully to maximize the impact on Russia and minimize the spillovers to Europe and the global economy.</p>



<p>I’m sorry, the second question?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Can we open up the line again, please, for Jordan Fabian?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, you know what?&nbsp; I just remembered.&nbsp; It was a question about how many of the 630 billion are subjected to the sanction, and &#8212; all of it.&nbsp; All of it.</p>



<p>So, right now, all 630 billion of Russia’s foreign reserves could be used theoretically to &#8212; they could sell those reserves and buy ruble.&nbsp; And that would offset some of the impact of our sanctions.&nbsp; I mean, as you know, the Russian ruble has already fallen 15 percent in this episode, and the Central Bank intervened already this week for the first time since 2014.</p>



<p>What this measure does, among other things, is it prevents Russia from transacting with Western banks, U.S. banks, European banks, UK banks, which it needs to do to actually intervene in foreign exchange markets.&nbsp; It must buy the ruble and sell its hard currency reserves to support its currency.&nbsp; That’s why I say we’re disarming &#8212; we’re disarming Fortress Russia by taking this action.</p>



<p>And there may be other actions, too, that are unveiled with respect to the Russian Central Bank, and we’ll be finalizing those over the weekend.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Can you say how quickly you believe that we will see the impact from these actions?&nbsp; I realize you’re still finalizing which banks will be impacted, but does this mean, on Monday, Moscow wakes up and feels the difference?&nbsp; And when you say you’re trying to minimize the impact to the global economy, what’s the risk you’re trying to minimize here, specifically?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I have great confidence the effects of these measures will be felt immediately in Russian financial markets.&nbsp; I think market participants understand that without Russia having the ability to defend its currency, it will go into free fall.</p>



<p>The actions with respect to SWIFT do require the Europeans to issue a directive that will then go to Belgium for a vote of the SWIFT Board of Directors.&nbsp; Those are the specific requirements under Belgian law.&nbsp; But with this decision made, I think you will immediately see a chilling effect fall over the Russian banking sector, even beyond what’s already occurred.</p>



<p>With respect to spillovers and costs and so forth, look, I mean, our judgment here, our calculus is that we have two choices: either we continue to ratchet costs higher to make this a strategic failure for President Putin, or, you know, the alternative, which is unacceptable &#8212; and that would be allowing unchecked aggression in the heart of Europe, in defiance of the core principles that have kept the peace and security across the continent for 70 years.</p>



<p>And those costs of doing nothing and allowing those uncertainties to fester, and the chilling effect to take hold, and the questions that will be asked about which country is next to be bullied and which autocrat is next to exert a sphere of influence &#8212; those costs are unacceptable to us.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this, [senior administration official].&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on Jordan’s question about the carveouts.&nbsp; The U.S. and Allies have been very careful to have carveouts on the previous sanctions to limit the impact on energy.&nbsp; Are you saying that it’s not going to be &#8212; that energy is not going to be &#8212; there’s not going to be a carveout with SWIFT for energy?&nbsp; Or is that the plan to go back and do one by one, and energy will be carved out?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, Franco.&nbsp; So, I mean, I’ll give you as much detail as I can.&nbsp; There are really two paths from here.&nbsp; One is we are trying, over this weekend and around the clock, to work with SWIFT to figure out if they have the capability of identifying the product type.</p>



<p>I mean, so let’s remember: SWIFT is like a &#8212; it’s like Gmail for banks.&nbsp; And what we’re trying to understand is: In those messages that are sent from one bank to another to make or receive payments, is there a marking which denotes that an energy payment is being made?&nbsp; If so, we could exempt those payments.&nbsp; So that’s one path.</p>



<p>But the second path is to choose our institution &#8212; choose the institutions that we de-SWIFT wisely.&nbsp; So, we know where most of the energy flows occur, through which banks they occur.&nbsp; And if we take that approach, we can simply choose the institutions where most of the energy flows do not occur.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well, thanks everyone for joining the call.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;&nbsp; The contents of the call are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>



<p>If you have any more questions, please feel free to reach out to me and we’ll make sure to get back to you.</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone. Have a good night.</p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Japan’s Announcement to Hold Russia&#160;Accountable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/27/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-japans-announcement-to-hold-russia-accountable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 15:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We welcome Japan’s announcement today that it will stand with the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States to isolate Russia from the international financial system and our economies. Following Japan’s announcement, the entire G7 now supports disconnecting selected Russian banks from SWIFT, restrictions on the Russian Central Bank,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">We welcome Japan’s announcement today that it will stand with the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States to isolate Russia from the international financial system and our economies. Following Japan’s announcement, the entire G7 now supports disconnecting selected Russian banks from SWIFT, restrictions on the Russian Central Bank, and sanctioning key Russian leaders, including President Putin. Prime Minister Kishida and the Government of Japan have been leaders in condemning President Putin’s attack on Ukraine and we will continue working closely together to impose further severe costs and make Putin’s war of choice a strategic failure.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on Further Restrictive Economic&#160;Measures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/26/joint-statement-on-further-restrictive-economic-measures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 22:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47925</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the leaders of the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States condemn Putin’s war of choice and attacks on the sovereign nation and people of Ukraine. We stand with the Ukrainian government and the Ukrainian people in their heroic efforts to resist Russia’s invasion. Russia’s war represents an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We, the leaders of the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, the United Kingdom, Canada, and the United States condemn Putin’s war of choice and attacks on the sovereign nation and people of Ukraine. We stand with the Ukrainian government and the Ukrainian people in their heroic efforts to resist Russia’s invasion. Russia’s war represents an assault on fundamental international rules and norms that have prevailed since the Second World War, which we are committed to defending. We will hold Russia to account and collectively ensure that this war is a strategic failure for Putin.</p>



<p>This past week, alongside our diplomatic efforts and collective work to defend our own borders and to assist the Ukrainian government and people in their fight, we, as well as our other allies and partners around the world, imposed severe measures on key Russian institutions and banks, and on the architects of this war, including Russian President Vladimir Putin.</p>



<p>As Russian forces unleash their assault on Kyiv and other Ukrainian cities, we are resolved to continue imposing costs on Russia that will further isolate Russia from the international financial system and our economies. We will implement these measures within the coming days.</p>



<p>Specifically, we commit to undertake the following measures:</p>



<p>First, we commit to ensuring that selected Russian banks are removed from the SWIFT messaging system. This will ensure that these banks are disconnected from the international financial system and harm their ability to operate globally.</p>



<p>Second, we commit to imposing restrictive measures that will prevent the Russian Central Bank from deploying its international reserves in ways that undermine the impact of our sanctions.</p>



<p>Third, we commit to acting against the people and entities who facilitate the war in Ukraine and the harmful activities of the Russian government. Specifically, we commit to taking measures to limit the sale of citizenship—so called golden passports—that let wealthy Russians connected to the Russian government become citizens of our countries and gain access to our financial systems.</p>



<p>Fourth, we commit to launching this coming week a transatlantic task force that will ensure the effective implementation of our financial sanctions by identifying and freezing the assets of sanctioned individuals and companies that exist within our jurisdictions. As a part of this effort we are committed to employing sanctions and other financial and enforcement measures on additional Russian officials and elites close to the Russian government, as well as their families, and their enablers to identify and freeze the assets they hold in our jurisdictions. We will also engage other governments and work to detect and disrupt the movement of ill-gotten gains, and to deny these individuals the ability to hide their assets in jurisdictions across the world.</p>



<p>Finally, we will step up or coordination against disinformation and other forms of hybrid warfare.</p>



<p>We stand with the Ukrainian people in this dark hour. Even beyond the measures we are announcing today, we are prepared to take further measures to hold Russia to account for its attack on Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino&#160;Heritage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/26/readout-of-white-house-virtual-celebration-of-afro-latino-heritage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 21:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, as part of Black History Month programming, the White House hosted a virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino Heritage, where Administration officials highlighted how President Biden has prioritized equity and diversity in his Administration. The program consisted of two panels and remarks from Ambassador to Spain Julissa Reynoso, Senior Advisor to the President and Director of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, as part of Black History Month programming, the White House hosted a virtual Celebration of Afro-Latino Heritage, where Administration officials highlighted how President Biden has prioritized equity and diversity in his Administration. The program consisted of two panels and remarks from Ambassador to Spain Julissa Reynoso, Senior Advisor to the President and Director of the White House Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond, Dean of the USC Rossier School of Education Dr. Pedro Noguera, as well as a spoken word by writer Melania Luisa Marte.</p>



<p>Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute CEO Marco Davis moderated a discussion focused on Afro-Latino representation with Chair of the National Endowment for the Arts Dr. Maria Rosario Jackson; Director of the Office of Intergovernmental and External Affairs at the Department of Health and Human Services Marvin Figueroa; and Hispanic Association on Corporate Responsibility CEO Cid Wilson. White House Senior Advisor for Public Engagement Carissa Smith later moderated a second discussion focused on achieving Black wellness, the theme for this year’s Black History Month, with Deputy Director for Energy Justice, Shalanda Baker, at the Department of Energy, and Acting National Director of the Minority Business Development Agency, Miguel Estién, from the Department of Commerce. Administration officials shared accomplishments from the first year of the Biden-Harris Administration and participants shared their own experiences as leaders in the Afro-Latino community.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on U.S. Support for the People of&#160;Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/26/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-u-s-support-for-the-people-of-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 05:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47919</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (February 25, 2022) 3:07 P.M. EST MODERATOR:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; And again, thank you for joining us for today’s background call on U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan. Today’s briefing is on background and attributable to “senior administration officials.”&#160; The briefing is embargoed until its conclusion. For your awareness only and for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(February 25, 2022)</p>



<p>3:07 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; And again, thank you for joining us for today’s background call on U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan.<br><br>Today’s briefing is on background and attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The briefing is embargoed until its conclusion.<br><br>For your awareness only and for not reporting, our senior administration officials are [senior administration officials].&nbsp; Again though, that’s for your information only; again, for the purposes of this call, they will be “senior administration officials.”<br><br>With that, I’ll turn it over to our senior administration official number one to give some opening remarks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you very much, and thank you all for joining us.<br><br>Over the course of the last several months, one area of focus for the Biden administration has been on ensuring that the Afghan people have access not only to humanitarian assistance but also to the ability to conduct regular commercial activity.<br><br>In order to make sure that the humanitarian crisis doesn’t get worse, one of the things we know that is critical is ensuring that the economy is able to function.&nbsp; And later today, we’re going to issue a new General License to expand authorizations for commercial and financial transactions in Afghanistan, including with Afghanistan’s governing institutions.</p>



<p>Treasury’s License authorizes all transactions involving Afghanistan and its governing institutions that would otherwise be prohibited by U.S. sanctions, to the extent required.&nbsp; However, it does not authorize financial transactions to the Taliban, Haqqani Network, associated entities, and any blocked individual who is in a leadership role of a governing institution in Afghanistan.</p>



<p>The License will ensure U.S. sanctions do not stand in the way of transactions and activities needed to provide aid and support the basic human needs of the people of Afghanistan.&nbsp; It reflects our deep commitment to support the people of Afghanistan during this ongoing humanitarian and economic crisis.</p>



<p>While sanctions relief alone cannot reverse longstanding structural challenges and the flight of technocratic and government experts due to the Taliban’s mismanagement, it can ensure that sanctions do not prevent economic activity that the people of Afghanistan rely on to meet their most fundamental needs.</p>



<p>This GL is in addition to the six other previously issued General Licenses, which also support the provision of humanitarian aid and support for basic human needs to the people of Afghanistan.<br><br>Today’s action is just the latest step in the Biden administration’s efforts to help address the substantial challenges facing Afghanistan’s economy.&nbsp; The administration has acted in full recognition of the challenging economic reality on the ground.</p>



<p>As many of you know, prior to the Taliban’s takeover, Afghanistan was dependent on external aid, receiving approximately $8.5 billion in grants each year, which financed 75 percent of public expenditures.&nbsp; Moreover, more than half of these foreign transfers were for military and security needs and have been terminated.</p>



<p>The poverty rate in 2020 stood at nearly 50 percent, and only 10 to 20 percent of Afghan adults had bank accounts.&nbsp; An underdeveloped financial sector also held back growth.&nbsp; Prior to 2021, Afghanistan’s loan-to-GDP ratio stood around 3 percent &#8212; the lowest in the world.</p>



<p>Overall, the IMF estimates that Afghanistan faces an economic contraction of up to 30 percent.</p>



<p>Our goal here is to make sure that we do everything we can to make sure that money is flowing to the Afghan people to help alleviate the humanitarian crisis that they face, but also to allow the commercial activity in Afghanistan to happen in order to build a (inaudible) cycle that will reinforce the livelihoods of the Afghan people.<br><br>In order to do this, it’s critical that Afghan institutions be put in a position where civil servants are allowed to function, including at the central bank, where we have made clear that in order for the international community to engage with the central bank, it’s important that it establishes independence, bring in a third party to validate that independence, and get the kind of technical assistance that is needed to ensure that they are able to put in place basic standards for the prevention of illicit finance, similar to what was done prior to August of 2021.</p>



<p>Our goal ultimately is to make sure that Afghanistan is a place where economic activity can happen and investments can happen in the long-term future of Afghanistan.&nbsp; This is why the U.S. government has partnered with NGOs to facilitate the provision and aid and financial resources to support humanitarian activities in Afghanistan.<br><br>Treasury and our interagency partners are working with the multilateral development banks, including the World Bank and Asian Development Bank, to provide substantial economic assistance to the people of Afghanistan.</p>



<p>In January, the administration announced an additional $308 million in USAID humanitarian assistance for Afghanistan, bringing total U.S. humanitarian aid for Afghanistan and Afghan refugees in the region to more than $780 million since October.</p>



<p>In December, the United States and other donors to the World Bank-administered Afghanistan Reconstruction Trust Fund decided to transfer $280 million.</p>



<p>To UNICEF &#8212; $100 million &#8212; 100 million of those dollars will go towards helping with things like paying teachers who have long needed support.</p>



<p>The World Food Programme will get another $180 million of that money.</p>



<p>These funds will enable UNICEF to provide essential health services, as well, to 12.5 million people, including 1 million vaccines, and allow the World Food Programme to provide food assistance to 2.7 million people in Afghanistan.</p>



<p>Treasury and our interagency partners are working to make additional resources available for the multilateral development banks, which together with the support &#8212; with support in December should result in approximately $1.75 billion in support from the multilateral development banks to meet critical basic human needs of the Afghan people.</p>



<p>Going forward, Treasury and the Biden administration will continue to apply rigorous sanctions to the Taliban and their collaborators until they halt their repressive actions, while providing necessary exemptions to facilitate the flow of legitimate aid to the Afghan people.<br><br>Our overall goal here is to ensure that the Afghan economy can function in the way that alleviates the humanitarian crisis and provides for opportunity going forward.<br><br>With that, let me turn it over to my colleague.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thank you very much, [senior administration official].  Hello, everybody.  This is the individual mentioned.<br><br>I want to zoom out just a bit and tick through a few of the efforts that we have to, sort of, place this General License in a broader context.<br><br>So, overall, I think the fundamental point I would make to you is that the most urgent priority animating both American diplomacy, as well as American decision-making on Afghanistan, is to meaningfully address the humanitarian and economic crises underway in Afghanistan.<br><br>There are too many Afghans starving today, too many Afghans who are cold.  We all need to act faster.  And that goes for the World Bank.  It goes for the region.  It goes for the Taliban as well.<br><br>But as [senior administration official] mentioned &#8212; as my colleague mentioned, we contributed over half a billion in humanitarian aid between August and December of last year.  We&#8217;ve already announced $308 million to a $4.4 billion appeal that the U.N. announced in January.<br><br>We&#8217;re very pleased that the United Kingdom, together with OCHA, will be hosting a pledging conference later in March. <br><br>We&#8217;re very glad that the OIC held an Extraordinary Ministerial in Islamabad, that they announced a trust fund that will be managed by the Islamic Development Bank.  And we hope that that trust fund results in pledges from OIC members as well.<br><br>As my colleague mentioned, we&#8217;re in very close touch with the World Bank.  We&#8217;re pleased that nearly $300 million is already supporting the health sector out of the Afghanistan Reconstruction Trust Fund. </p>



<p>There&#8217;s an upcoming board meeting where I think there will be an additional large amount under consideration by the board as well.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve worked with the private sector, particular actors in Europe, to see shipments of hundreds of millions of dollars into Afghanistan explicitly for the purpose of helping humanitarian relief efforts scale up.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m pleased to say that the Taliban have not interfered in the delivery of those dollars in any way to date, although we will watch it very closely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re in close touch right now with the World Bank and UNOPS on the establishment of something they&#8217;re calling a &#8220;humanitarian exchange facility,&#8221; which, for folks who follow this issue closely will know, could help to provide more general liquidity in the economy, including Afghanis&#8217;.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, I&#8217;d say that the President&#8217;s February 11th executive order, I think, was pretty widely misunderstood to begin with.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen some much more accurate coverage since then, but, fundamentally, that action was about protecting and preserving for the Afghan people $3.5 billion in assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, there&#8217;s an ongoing court process, and that court has not made any decisions on awards to litigants.&nbsp; But we were very glad to move ahead with an action that will protect and preserve for the Afghan people $3.5 billion in assets.</p>



<p>And then relatedly and finally, I&#8217;ll say that we have a range of really tough problems when it comes to fundamentally easing the economic crisis underway that we can&#8217;t solve by ourselves, and some are frankly unsolvable.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just mention two.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is that Afghanistan&#8217;s central bank lost a lot of capacity after the March military takeover by the Taliban.&nbsp; We saw some of the senior-most technocrats from that institution leave the country.&nbsp; And as a result, some of the functions that international financial institutions look to to ensure that their correspondent relationships are protected either atrophied or, in some cases, disappeared altogether.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, rather than just admire the problem, we have been engaging with technocrats at the central bank intensively since November and have made specific recommendations on measures and steps they can take to enhance both capacity as well as independence, and to stand up an AML/CFT architecture that, again, has largely disappeared.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the final thing I would say is that, you know, when we talk to banks &#8212; both foreign banks as well as American banks &#8212; they are reticent to engage in this market not just for concerns about our sanctions posture &#8212; it&#8217;s a matter of profitability.</p>



<p>They have shareholders.&nbsp; Afghanistan is not a profitable place to do business at the moment.&nbsp; And so, what I would tell you is that, as we take this action today, it&#8217;s incumbent on the Taliban to pursue policies that will attract investment to the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I look forward to questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, can you hear me?&nbsp; Hello?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Yes, we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, great.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry to be dense about this, but I&#8217;m having a hard time understanding what these new measures actually do that wasn&#8217;t being done before.&nbsp; You know, you said it will make it easier for civil servants that are not blocked persons to operate.&nbsp; Does that mean that you&#8217;re going to lift all restrictions on dealings with civil servants like central bank officers and the people beneath them and just anybody who&#8217;s not actually on the list as a &#8220;blocked person&#8221; or be free to engage in banking transactions?&nbsp; Is that what this does?&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I just &#8212; I don&#8217;t quite get the sort of shape of it.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, Karen, so let me just try and make it as clear as possible.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re saying is that the government of Afghanistan, as well as the country of Afghanistan isn&#8217;t blocked.&nbsp; If, before August of 2021, you were working closely with an Afghan civil servant in the DAB or in the Finance Ministry or in the Ministry of Education, you can continue doing that.&nbsp; You can continue to make regular payments as long as they are not going to the benefit of the Taliban, the Haqqani network, or named individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what we&#8217;re doing here is clarifying our stance, which is taking what we had done with regard to humanitarian assistance, in terms of the GLs, and largely matching that in terms of commercial activity, and clarifying that people can go back to doing exactly what they&#8217;ve been &#8212; what many have already been doing, but making it very clear that you can continue to make commercial transactions in Afghanistan, as well as transactions with government individuals who aren&#8217;t blocked.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for having this call.&nbsp; With respect to the frozen Afghan government accounts, you recently said there were &#8220;ongoing discussions&#8221; about the best use for about half the assets &#8212; the $3.5 billion.&nbsp; And you said that the money could be used to recapitalize the Afghan central bank?&nbsp; Can you give us an update on that situation &#8212; on those discussions?&nbsp; Have you made any kind of decision about recapitalizing the Afghan central bank?&nbsp; And can you say who&#8217;s involved with those discussions?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, maybe I can talk to the economics, and then I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk a little bit about some of the ongoing discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the truth of the matter is that the humanitarian situation is clearly interrelated with the economic situation on the ground.&nbsp; Getting the banking sector functioning is critical to this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think part of what we would like to do is make sure that the DAB is in a position where they can take back on normal central bank activity.&nbsp; And much of that is, frankly, in the hands of the Taliban.</p>



<p>Our General License puts them in a position where you can go back to interacting with Afghan government officials.&nbsp; But in order for the international community to be willing to interact with the DAB, they&#8217;re going to have to establish their independence, bring in a third party to help monitor that, and get back in some of &#8212; get in people to help with technical assistance given the number of technical officials who have left the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think one of the things we&#8217;re thinking through with my colleagues in the U.S. government and a number of our international partners and allies is how can we support the Afghan banking sector and the economy in order to make sure they can operate in a way that supports the Afghan people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk a little bit about those discussions.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, this was one thing that I thought some of the early coverage got wrong.&nbsp; And to be to be very clear, and I know I&#8217;ve said this before, but: No decisions have been made regarding specific uses of this $3.5 billion.&nbsp; And as we move ahead, a couple of things are happening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number one, we&#8217;ve begun discussions with a number of countries &#8212; I&#8217;m not in a position to share today with which countries &#8212; but regarding the establishment of a temporary financing mechanism. <br><br>And I think, as we look to set up that mechanism, we&#8217;re looking to be absolutely sure that &#8212; on its governance, as well as the potential uses of this money, which is, you know, Afghan reserves and for the benefit of the Afghan people &#8212; that we are talking to professional Afghans in this space, people who have served in leadership positions of the central bank, of the finance ministry; folks who&#8217;ve been technocrats; folks who have a strong opinion, as Afghans, about what would be a responsible use of these funds.<br><br>And so I&#8217;m not in a position today to get into more detail.  I think it&#8217;s a completely legitimate question to say, you know, who are those folks?  I hope we&#8217;re in a position to share that in the coming weeks, but I&#8217;m not in that spot today.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think the one thing that I will say is that we&#8217;re thinking broadly about how we address the humanitarian crisis and not in a narrow way.&nbsp; And we know that the humanitarian crisis is related to broader macroeconomic concerns.&nbsp; So working closely with [senior administration official] and others, we&#8217;re thinking through how best, in consultation with those that [senior administration official] mentioned, to address the broader economic challenges that Afghanistan faces.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; To clarify, just to make sure that I have a grasp of what you&#8217;re announcing today: If you&#8217;re an investor or a private company, you can work with Afghan civil servants again and not be penalized.&nbsp; Is that an accurate summation?<br><br>And then secondly, is this an iteration of what you &#8212; of what the Treasury put out earlier this month, in terms of licensing for humanitarian assistance and NGOs?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The simple answer is yes.&nbsp; And I think one of the things that we tried to do was we put out the humanitarian guidance because we had talked to a number of NGOs, and what they told us was they needed formal guidance, given their concerns about working in Afghanistan.&nbsp; And as we had conversations with commercial actors, people who were doing business there or small business in Afghanistan, they told us it would be helpful for us to provide more guidance that was similar to that for commercial activity as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So we also wanted to clarify that it&#8217;s possible for you to continue working with civil servants in Afghanistan.&nbsp; The key is to ensure that what you&#8217;re doing and the resources that you&#8217;re providing aren’t providing material support to people who are sanctioned.&nbsp;<br><br>So, if the individual is a civil servant who was working in the Afghan government in August of 2021, you can continue doing the same work you were doing with them at that point today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I do not understand one particular thing.&nbsp; It seems that you are saying that the General License will permit ordinary dealings with Afghan civil servants so long as those dealings do not ultimately provide material support to or inure to the benefit of specific designated Taliban or Haqqani Network figures.&nbsp;<br><br>But given the fact that the Taliban essentially is now the governing authority, how is it that permitting people to do ordinary transactions with civil servants does not intrinsically inure to the benefit of and potentially provide material support to members of the Taliban and/or the Haqqani Network?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Money is fungible.&nbsp; How can these transactions not indirectly, if not directly, benefit the Taliban and Haqqani Network officials who are in power?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s a great question, and I&#8217;ll turn it over to my colleague in a moment.&nbsp; But this isn&#8217;t the only country in which we have this kind of situation.</p>



<p>In Burma, where we have sanctioned members of the junta, people are still permitted to do business with government entities there as well.&nbsp; And the thing that we&#8217;re tr- &#8212; the thing that we are doing here is we are making a careful, consideration here, where we are saying that you cannot provide material support to certain sanctioned individuals but we don&#8217;t want to cut off the country of Afghanistan, the people of Afghanistan from the resources they need to live and to try and address the economic and humanitarian crisis there.&nbsp;<br><br>This is something that we&#8217;ve been able to do in other situations and in other countries using our sanctions regime.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re going to do here in Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br><br>But let me turn it over to my colleague to also respond.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, thank you very much.&nbsp; I mean, one thing &#8212; I think when you dig into the mountain of paper that will be released as attached to this GL, you&#8217;ll see a lot of this in black and white, and that&#8217;ll be helpful.&nbsp;<br><br>So the General Licenses is one thing.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see some very helpful Treasury FAQs.&nbsp; I&#8217;d say the second FAQ just gives very practical examples of what this &#8212; what this license now authorizes.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see statements by folks, including Secretary Blinken, where we make clear that this License is aimed at facilitating a broad range of commercial activity in Afghanistan that benefits the Afghan people.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;ll also make clear that, while sanctions on the Taliban remain in place, this action facilitates private companies and aid organizations working with Afghan governing institutions and paying customs, duties, fees, and taxes, even if those institutions are headed by sanctions &#8212; sanctioned individuals.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think a lot of the questions we&#8217;ve all gotten are around whether or not they can deal with sanctioned ministry &#8212; or ministries headed by sanctioned individuals, and this License makes very clear that they can.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, and I think I’ll just say it again that this is not something that we haven&#8217;t done in other sanctions programs that the Department of Treasury operates.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve able to do it in a way that allows us to allow government institutions to function while making sure that the benefit &#8212; that money is not provided and material support is not provided to sanctioned individuals.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hello, everybody.&nbsp; Just wanted to let everyone know that we&#8217;ve officially run to the end of our time.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, first and foremost, I want to thank everyone for joining us, again, for this call this afternoon.&nbsp; The call is on background and attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The embargo will be lifted at the conclusion of the call.&nbsp;<br><br>3:31 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 25,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/25/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-25-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 04:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:37 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; All right, I just have one item for all of you at the top, which is the week ahead.&#160; And I know there are a few topics to discuss today during our time together. &#160; On Monday, the President will host a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:37 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; All right, I just have one item for all of you at the top, which is the week ahead.&nbsp; And I know there are a few topics to discuss today during our time together. &nbsp;</p>



<p>On Monday, the President will host a celebration to mark Black History Month.&nbsp; He will be joined by the Vice President, Black members of the historically diverse Cabinet, members of the Congressional Black Caucus, state and local elected officials, civil rights leaders, and Divine Nine leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Tuesday, as you are all tracking, the President will deliver his first State of the Union Address.&nbsp; We will have more of his address to preview in the coming days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Wednesday, the President and the First Lady will travel to Superior, Wisconsin, to discuss how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers for the American people by rebuilding roads and bridges and creating good-paying union jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on Thursday, the President will hold a Cabinet meeting.</p>



<p>With that, Zeke, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The EU, earlier today, agreed to hold &#8212; put in place sanctions and asset freezes on the Russian President Vladimir Putin and the Russian foreign minister.&nbsp; Is the United States going to follow suit?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Following a televisi- &#8212; a telephone conversation President Biden held with European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen and in alignment with the decision by our European Allies, the United States will join them in sanctioning President Putin and Foreign Minister Lavrov and members of the Russian national security team.&nbsp; I expect we&#8217;ll have more specific details out later this afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And additionally, can you detail the level of support the United States government is currently providing operationally to the Ukrainian military and intelligence services as they try to fend off the Russian invasion?&nbsp; Is the U.S. continuing to send weaponry into Ukraine?&nbsp; Is it providing intelligence on Russian movements and tactical communications and the like?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without getting into too many specific details that are sensitive for a range of reasons, we are continuing to deliver on the security assistance package that was announced earlier last fall.&nbsp; All of that has not been delivered yet.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to provide that assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, we are &#8212; we remain in very close touch, of course, with &#8212; with President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; I think you may have just seen the readout that we just put out that included the President spoke with him earlier today again.&nbsp; And we are in very close touch, from our national security team, with members of his team as well.&nbsp; And we continue to &#8212; to consider a range of options to provide additional assistance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And President Zelenskyy, last night, said he was &#8220;target number one&#8221; of the Russian military.&nbsp; Does the United States have &#8212; sort of have a warning to Russia in the event that &#8212; in the event they were to target the Ukrainian president or attempt to capture him or to physically harm him?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Do we have a warning to them?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A warning to Russia, yes &#8212; specifically regarding the head of state.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that we have been warning for months that &#8212; for weeks, if not months &#8212; that Kyiv falling, that attempts to overturn the leadership of Ukraine is very much in the aspirations of President Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So his &#8212; their attempts to do exactly that and their continued progress in moving toward Kyiv and moving toward Ukrainian leadership is aligned with what we have predicted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, going after the head of state would be a significant, horrific act by Russian leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we remain in contact, as you all have seen from the readout we provided, with President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; He&#8217;s made clear that he&#8217;s still in Ukraine, proudly and courageously standing up in the face of the Russian attack.&nbsp; And we are &#8212; certainly continue to be concerned about the ongoing Russian assault on the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on a different topic: The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention right now is announcing new federal mask guidelines that &#8212; including, under them, 70 percent or so of Americans right now live in areas where they are no longer recommended to wear masks indoors in public settings.</p>



<p>Is that guidance that will be followed here in the White House as Washington, D.C., is now not an area recommended anymore for wearing masks indoors.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, we are evaluating our protocols.&nbsp; Obviously, this guidance is just going out now as we speak.&nbsp; I believe Dr. Walensky continues to provide a briefing call with some of your colleagues right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>D.C. currently has a mask mandate until March 1st.&nbsp; We have always followed the most stringent guidelines &#8212; that has typically been the CDC.&nbsp; So, we will plan to follow that.&nbsp; And in the meantime, we will &#8212; we are evaluating our protocols here at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On President Zelenskyy, did &#8212; in President Biden&#8217;s phone call with him, did it come up whether &#8212; did President Biden bring up whether President Zelenskyy &#8212; he thinks he should leave the country or not for his own safety?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is not &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any additional details to provide.&nbsp; President Zelenskyy continues to serve as President of Ukraine.&nbsp; He continues to do that courageously in the face of attacks from Russian military.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This was a call for the President to reiterate our strong support for him, for the Ukrainian people, and to reiterate and condemn the actions of the Russians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;And on sanctioning Putin and Lavrov: Yesterday, President Biden had said that that was on the table.&nbsp; What changed between yesterday and today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it has been under consideration and on the table for some time, as you know.&nbsp; And as I just conveyed, the President&#8217;s strong view and strong principle from the beginning of this conflict &#8212; and even before, I should say &#8212; has been to take actions and steps in alignment with our European partners, and this is certainly evidence of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just finally, on that one: What does sanctioning Putin himself do in this &#8212; in the opinion of this administration?&nbsp; A lot of analysts have said that this is more of a symbolic move than anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without getting into any specific details &#8212; I know you&#8217;re not exactly asking me this, but sort of &#8212; about financial assets, et cetera &#8212; I will leave that to others to speak to &#8212; certainly, the United &#8212; this step that we are doing in alignment and in coordination with Europeans just sends a clear message about the &#8212; the strength of the opposition to the actions by President Putin and the direction in his leadership of the Russian military.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Just wanted to ask &#8212; continuing the questions on sanctions &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, we saw that the Italian government and the German government both expre- &#8212; said very clearly that they would not veto a move to remove Russia from the SWIFT transaction system.</p>



<p>Can you say a word about how quickly you think something like that would happen and whether you believe that that would be another productive tool and perhaps another moment &#8212; you know, symbolic or, rather, an important measure?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, again, the President&#8217;s principle is doing &#8212; taking steps in alignment.&nbsp; We are stronger together, especially as we stand in the face of the Russian military&#8217;s actions and &#8212; and their invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>As it relates to SWIFT, we&#8217;ve never taken that off the table, of course, and I&#8217;m certainly not taking it off the table today.&nbsp; So, certainly, there&#8217;ll be ongoing discussions about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, SWIFT is a messaging service that connects 11,000 banks.&nbsp; And many would argue that there are ways that &#8212; that Russia &#8212; the Russian leadership could get around that over the course of time, but it certainly remains an option on the table.</p>



<p>In terms of the timeline, I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We were &#8212; also reported today that China has actually increased its reserves as opposed to releasing reserves, which could help, perhaps, with the energy price increases that we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; Have you had &#8212; you know, what do you &#8212; what do you think of that move?</p>



<p>And then also, has there been any further communication? Does President Biden intend to talk to President Xi?&nbsp; Or can you say a word about what &#8212; what you&#8217;re doing in terms of trying to convince the Chinese to be supportive?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would note that, also today, the I- &#8212; the IEA had an informal meeting where they discussed options they could take over the coming days and weeks to help address any volatility in the global markets and, you know, the heightening of price volatility.</p>



<p>And certainly, that meeting today was a chance to consult and continue coordination with partners on global energy supply and security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also continuing conversations that we have had from here with partners over the past day.&nbsp; Secretary Granholm spoke with French, German, EU, and UK counterparts yesterday and will continue those conversations.</p>



<p>As it relates to China, you know, I would say that the President&#8217;s view, of course, is that now is the time for leaders of the world to not just speak out clearly against President Putin&#8217;s flagrant aggression and to stand with the people of Ukraine, but this is not a moment for evo- &#8212; equivocation or hiding or waiting to see what happens next.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is already clear what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; And as a part of that, it&#8217;s also important to be a part of the effort to mitigate and minimize the impact on global markets and gloi- &#8212; global oil markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I don&#8217;t have any additional conversations to read out for you.&nbsp; But I would say, certainly, we all want to be a part of the solution here and stand up in the face of aggression to help address the problems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you saying that China is, in fact, equivocating?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;All I&#8217;m saying is that every country should think about what side of history they want to be on here, and they have the ability to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When did President Biden make the final decision to sanction President Putin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was made &#8212; it&#8217;s been on the table for some time, but through coordination and discussion with our European partners over the last day or so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he decided in the last 24 hours that he was going to do that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, it&#8217;s been on the table for some time.&nbsp; His priority and his focus has been on taking steps in coordination.&nbsp; And obviously, that decision was made over the course of the last 24 hours and in partnership with our European counterparts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does it include a travel ban, by chance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I believe that would be a part of the U.S. component.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So President Putin would be banned from traveling here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is more details of it that, again, will be out later today.&nbsp; There are very limited examples of this being done, as you all know, but that is a standard part.&nbsp; But again, there&#8217;ll be more details we will have available later today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another question on travel.&nbsp; The UK is banning civilian Russian aircraft from its airspace, saying that no aircraft on a service owned, operated, or chartered &#8212; chartered by a person connected with Russia shall fly in their airspace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Is the United States planning to do the same?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of that being in the plans, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And another question.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen these predictions from the Defense Department, from the State Department about Kyiv falling to Russia.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve made clear that they believe that is in Putin&#8217;s sights and that he wants to overthrow the government there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If that happens, what does the U.S. do?&nbsp; What is the response and the role that the United States takes after something like that happens?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just reiterate, as we&#8217;ve been warning for months, that Kyiv falling is a real possibility.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve continued to see Russia&#8217;s progression, even as we&#8217;ve seen resistance on the ground, Russians&#8217; military continu- &#8212; Russia&#8217;s military continues to advance toward Kyiv.&nbsp; So there is that real possibility. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just not going to get into, at this point, hypotheticals of what that will look like or what our response would be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I just want to follow up on the Putin sanctions again &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; based on what you&#8217;ve said so far.&nbsp; So, was this decision to coordinate with Allies meant to show unity, meant to show that Putin is a pariah?&nbsp; Or do you think it will actually have an impact on Putin in practice, given the uncertainty about the extent and location of his wealth?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, I understand what you&#8217;re asking; I&#8217;m just not going to get into specifics about his financial assets from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, I think what is important and what we are hoping the world takes away from this is the unity through which the United States, President Biden is working with our European partners and Allies.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without getting into details, can you even say if this will or will not impact him, other than showing that he&#8217;s, you know, an outlier?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to get into his personal financial assets.&nbsp; That&#8217;s typically not something we would do from here.&nbsp; But I would note, again, that the steps that were taken yesterday and announced yesterday &#8212; sanctioning the 10 largest financial &#8212; 10 of the largest financial institutions in Russia, accounting for a huge percentage of their banking capacity, what &#8212; of their financial system capacity, I should say &#8212; and even the anticipation of that has had enormous impact on Russia, whether it&#8217;s the currency &#8212; the Ruble &#8212; that has fallen, the markets, skyrocketing inflation in Russia.</p>



<p>And we also have taken steps to sanction oligarchs around President Putin &#8212; people who have benefited from corruption and cronyism in the system &#8212; and even their family members to prevent them from having the capacity to move around their assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Supreme Court today &#8212; news of the day: It was exactly two years ago today that the President made a pledge that he would nominate a Black woman to the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Did he factor the timing of that into his decision to announce it today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then can you share any details about the process &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; now that it&#8217;s over?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Finally, we&#8217;re free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like, you know, how long the interview or interviews were, what they talked about, what led the President to choose Judge Jackson over the other candidates.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, I will share with you the details that we&#8217;re comfortable sharing at this point in time.  And obviously, Judge Jackson will have &#8212; be filling out a range of questionnaires.  She will be testifying.  She will be considered by the full Senate, and she will be asked a range of questions there.<br><br>The President interviewed Judge Jackson, Judge Childs, and Judge Kruger on Monday, February 14th, in person.  He made his final decision and called Judge Jackson last night &#8212; last evening.  I would note it was after the press briefing last evening.<br><br>The President called Leader Schumer, Senator McConnell, Speaker Pelosi, and Whip Clyburn &#8212; all separately &#8212; this morning to inform them of his decision.<br><br>I&#8217;d also note that the Vice President has been very engaged not just in the decision-making process, as the President talked about during his remarks, but she called former President Obama and former President Clinton as well.  And she has also been calling a range of members of Congress as a part of the announcement process.<br><br>Q    Just one more.  Did he personally call Kruger and Childs to let them know that he had chosen Judge Jackson?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any other details on that.&nbsp; But I can tell you that he called Judge Jackson to offer her the &#8212; to tell her he was going to nominate her last evening.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The State Department just said, about the U.S. and Russia, that there are still some areas in which the fulfillment of our national security priorities and imperatives require us to engage and coexist.&nbsp; How is it that we are still engaging and coexisting with the Russians?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, I would say diplomacy around the world requires us to engage with countries, even where we have strong disagreements, strong opposition, strong condemnation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been very outspoken and taken actions against China&#8217;s human rights abuses, but we have worked with them in other capacities.&nbsp;<br><br>We are working &#8212; Russia is a part of the P5+1, as we&#8217;re working and making progress on an Iran nuclear deal.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question that achievement of that would make the world safer.&nbsp;<br><br>So it is our responsibility.&nbsp; And &#8212; and diplomacy means engaging even with countries where you have strong disagreement and strong opposition.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just so that we can understand, then, the approach: That means that you guys will sit here and sanction Vladimir Putin and then send diplomats to go sit on the same side of the table with the Russians to hash out the Iran deal.&nbsp; Is that what&#8217;s happening?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right, Peter, but I don&#8217;t know why you sound so skeptical.&nbsp; What our job here in the United States and from any government is to take steps that are in the interest of the American people and the United States of America.&nbsp; And part of that is &#8212; would certainly be reducing Iran&#8217;s capacity and ability to have a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s no question about that.&nbsp; Russia is a part of the P5+1.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a report in The New York Times that you guys kept asking China to help you stop Russia from invading Ukraine and they didn&#8217;t.&nbsp; So, what have you guys done throughout this slow-moving Russia crisis that has worked?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what capacity?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, the President talked to Putin.&nbsp; He talked to the G7.&nbsp; He threatened sanctions.&nbsp; He put sanctions in place.&nbsp; Now he says the sanctions are going to take 30 days or about a month.&nbsp; Do you guys think that people in Ukraine have about a month?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, let me just take a step back and explain to everyone how diplomacy works and how our approach from the United States has worked.&nbsp;<br><br>What the President has done is he has built a global coalition to stand up in the face of President Putin and President Putin&#8217;s aggression and invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; What he has done is he has rallied the world, our European partners &#8212; even at cost to them, in some capacities &#8212; to put in place significant sanctions, historic sanctions that would have a enormous impact on the Russian financial sector.&nbsp;<br><br>It is President Putin&#8217;s choice to go to war and invade Ukraine.&nbsp; That is what he has done.&nbsp; It is our choice and our responsibility and the role of the President and the United States to rally opposition and make sure they feel significant pain from that choice.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what we have done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I understand that you&#8217;re saying that these sanctions will have an impact on Russia, but what good does that do these people in Ukraine who are seeing the news and these U.S. intel assessments that Kyiv is going to fall any day?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, first of all, we are the largest provider of humanitarian assistance, of security assistance in the world to the Ukrainian &#8212; to the Ukrainian government, which still stands and support &#8212; and the biggest supporter of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; And we will continue to be.&nbsp; And we are leading this global effort to stand up against the aggression of President Putin.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we are doing &#8212; the President is doing nearly everything in his power to lead the world and stand up against the actions of President Putin.<br><br>What he will not do is send U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine, because he is not going to put the American public, the American people, or the United States in a position of fighting a war with Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I can ask you about &#8212; we&#8217;ve been watching a lot of pictures play out from overseas.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen anti-war protesters rounded up and arrested in Moscow and elsewhere throughout Russia.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen awful pictures coming from throughout Ukraine, including one today that was dramatic of a Russian tank literally rolling over a Ukrainian civilian vehicle.&nbsp; Can you just give us a sense &#8212; is the President watching this happen?&nbsp;&nbsp;His reaction to this?&nbsp; His message to those anti-war protesters?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean, it&#8217;s &#8212; there are &#8212; it&#8217;s horrific to watch.&nbsp; It&#8217;s heart wrenching to watch.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve all seen the images &#8212; the President, the Vice President, members of our national security team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it almost doesn&#8217;t matter how much you&#8217;ve been through or how many conflicts you&#8217;ve watched over time &#8212; and he has unfortunately watched many in a variety of national security roles &#8212; to feel heartbroken by what you&#8217;re seeing in &#8212; happen in Ukraine, in a sovereign country that is &#8212; is having its right to exist threatened by Russia &#8212; the aggressor in this case.<br><br>You know, I would say our message to the Ukrainian people continues to be that we stand with you; we support you; we are going to do everything &#8212; humanitarian assistance, economic assistance, continue to provide security assistance and rally the world to condemn the actions of President Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to the anti-war protesters in Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think we would say that we are &#8212; we are amazed by your courage &#8212; your remarkable courage in standing up against what President Putin is doing.&nbsp; It is not easy to protest in many scenarios, but it&#8217;s certainly not easy to protest against the actions of an autocratic leader.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what these protesters are doing.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a large room; I&#8217;ll ask only one last question, which is &#8212; as a relates to the Supreme Court &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; following up on the questions here: The President wanted it to be a bipartisan process.&nbsp; He’s met with many Republicans &#8212; Chuck Grassley, the top Republican on Senate Judiciary Committee; three Republicans helped confirm Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson in the spring of last year.&nbsp; One of them, Lindsey Graham, today said, among other things, that this selection “means the radical left has won President Biden over yet again.”&nbsp; The White House&#8217;s response?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what&#8217;s most important for everybody to know and understand is more about Judge Jackson&#8217;s record.&nbsp;<br><br>And what was very compelling to &#8212; and to go back to Weijia’s question &#8212; sorry, I didn&#8217;t answer this part &#8212; what was compelling to the President &#8212; I talked to him about &#8212; with him about this this morning, and you heard him lay this out in great detail in his remarks: You know, Judge Jackson is someone who very much is in the mold of Justice Breyer, having even clerked for him.&nbsp; She talked about that during his remarks.&nbsp; When she was confirmed as a district judge in 2013, Judge Breyer praised her for being a wise decision and swore her in, and even parts of their biography overlap &#8212; time on the Sentencing Commission, time as a federal judge.<br><br>But it&#8217;s also how she has approached her role as a judge that was very compelling to the President.&nbsp; She&#8217;s issued opinions without regard to partisan considerations.&nbsp; She&#8217;s ruled in favor of Republicans and Democrats.&nbsp; She&#8217;s ruled for and against the government, regardless of whether the government is led by a Democratic president or a Republican president.&nbsp; Litigants, lawyers, and judges across the ideological spectrum appreciate her ability to be an impartial adjudicator.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what you want as a judge.&nbsp; She&#8217;s even clerked for three different federal judges who were appointed by presidents of different political parties.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I would just note all of that to suggest that, you know, anyone who is already ruling her out, without even meeting with her, engaging with her, and reviewing her extensive record as a fair and just judge, you know, there may be other reasons for that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Does the U.S. &#8212; do you have any update on the hostages that were reported to be taken at Chernobyl (inaudible) yesterday &#8211;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In Chernobyl?&nbsp; I unfortunately don&#8217;t have an update on that from here at this point.&nbsp; I can check for you after the briefing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the U.S. have any plans to speed up the refugee processing for Ukrainians that do want to come to the U.S., as they did with Afghans that wanted to come to the U.S.?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s a slightly different circumstance, I will say, because our assessment is that the majority of refugees will want to go to neighboring countries in Europe, many of which have already conveyed publicly that they will accept any refugee who needs a home, whether it&#8217;s Poland or Germany, and there are probably others who have made those comments.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we are really working in close lockstep with our European counterparts about what the needs are and how to help, from our end, meet those needs.&nbsp; We &#8212; that certainly means an openness to accepting refugees from Ukraine but also making sure that all of these neighboring countries who are willing to welcome these refugees, you know, have our support in that effort.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I know the White House has said it won&#8217;t be sending &#8212; the U.S. won&#8217;t be sending troops into Ukraine to rescue Americans who are still there, so what is the U.S. doing about Americans who are still left in Ukraine as the situation gets more dire?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; I will first start by saying that we have been warning for months now about the dire circumstances developing in Ukraine and conveying very directly to American citizens they should leave.&nbsp; We have also been in touch, from the State Department, with every American we can reach.&nbsp; I would point you to them for more specifics on that.&nbsp; And we continue to have the capacity to, you know, help them in a range of ways, even as we don&#8217;t have a diplomatic presence in Ukraine in th- &#8212; I mean, we don&#8217;t have people in the country right now, obviously, but they are in neighboring countries.<br><br>I would really point you to the State Department for any more specifics.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the President is obviously now going to be in Delaware this weekend.&nbsp; Can you share what he will be doing there?&nbsp; Will he be traveling with members of his national security team?&nbsp; Will he be receiving regular updates on Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; He will have a meeting with members of his national security team tomorrow in Delaware.&nbsp; I will note that, while every president can work from anywhere they are, because that is how presidencies are equipped, he is traveling to Delaware for the memorial service of a family member.&nbsp; And he will be &#8212; that is why he&#8217;s traveling there this weekend.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on that question: Does the President have special secure facilities in Wilmington?&nbsp; We know that, obviously, at Camp David that is something available.&nbsp; Given the national security crisis, is that something that is also available?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has the capacity to make a secure call from anywhere he is, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on the Supreme Court: How important is it to the President that the &#8212; Judge Jackson receives bipartisan support if she is confirmed?&nbsp; And how much political capital and time and energy is he personally going to put into getting Republican support for her nomination?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think, Tyler, let me flip this around a little bit for you and just say the President&#8217;s view is that when you look at somebody like Judge Jackson, who has &#8212; is extraordinarily qualified, has impeccable credentials; she has been lauded by former Speaker of the House, Paul Ryan, who said on her behalf last &#8212; when she was put forward last year, “I know she&#8217;s clearly qualified.  But it bears repeating just how qualified she is… Our politics may differ, but my praise for Ketanji intellect, for her character, for her <s>intellect</s> [integrity] is unequivocal.” <br><br>That she is somebody who has &#8212; and I would also note, that former D.C. District Judge Thomas Griffith, appointed by President George W. Bush, publicly supported her D.C. Court nomination.  And she received a bipartisan letter of support from individuals who co-clerked along Judge Jackson.<br><br>So I think the bar here should not be what is the President going to do &#8212; of course, he&#8217;s going to engage with Democrats and Republicans; you&#8217;ve seen him operate in that way to date &#8212; it is what are Republicans going to do, in terms of considering an eminently qualified judge that the President has nominated, who, by many standards, has exhibited &#8212; has shown herself to issue opinions without regard to partisan considerations and ruled in a way that certainly anyone, regardless of their political affiliation, would be proud to see.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more quick one on the State of the Union.&nbsp; How much is that speech being changed by the Russia-Ukraine crisis?&nbsp; Can you just give us a little bit of a preview about what we may hear from the President on Tuesday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand the question, but I can&#8217;t give you a preview of a speech four days from now quite yet about &#8212; and how it will address a developing conflict.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, President Biden stated from the outset and you&#8217;ve reiterated today that he won’t send U.S. troops to Ukraine to fight Russians.&nbsp; Given the high stakes, you know, President Biden yesterday said Russia has aspirations beyond Ukraine.&nbsp; Why isn’t this a fight worth sending U.S. troops for?&nbsp; Why, in your as- &#8212; in &#8212; why has the President assessed that shouldn&#8217;t be an option?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first, it&#8217;s important to note that we have certainly made clear, not just by words but by actions, that we are going to continue to support and even plus up our support for NATO defense operations.&nbsp; And there was an announcement yesterday of an increase of additional 7,000 troops.&nbsp; And obviously, there was a significant announcement made today by NATO.&nbsp; We are firm &#8212; we will firmly stand behind our Article 5 obligations.&nbsp;<br><br>But I would say, as it relates to sending U.S. troops into Ukraine, the President &#8212; the role of the President of the United States &#8212; any president &#8212; is to make an assessment about what is in the interests of the United States, our national security interests, the American people, and certainly weigh very heavily how we&#8217;re leading the global community.&nbsp; But it is not in our interest to be in a war with Russia.&nbsp; And so, no, we are not sending U.S. troops to Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But by stating up front that this is not an option, didn’t President Biden take away what could have been a threat to deter Putin from invading and to further push into Ukraine?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President believes he has a responsibility to be very direct with the American people about what his intentions are and what his intentions are not, and that is his first priority as President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, what was the White House&#8217;s reaction to President Zelenskyy, today, in a video address, saying that Ukraine has, quote, “been left alone to defend itself against Russia”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, as you know, the President spoke with President Zelenskyy and made clear to him during that conversation that he &#8212; and he commended his brave leadership, his brave actions, the brave actions of the Ukrainian people who are fighting to defend their country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also conveyed our ongoing economic, humanitarian, and security support that we will continue to provide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that is hardly standing on the sidelines.&nbsp; We are providing &#8212; again, the largest provider of security, economic, humanitarian assistance of any country in the world.&nbsp; And we will continue to support President Zelenskyy and the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the White House doesn’t think he&#8217;s been left alone?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;ll leave it at that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks a lot, Jen.&nbsp; Does the administration have any plans to offer TPS to Ukrainians who are in the United States or who en- &#8212; who might end up coming to the United States?&nbsp; Does it support the idea?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there &#8212; it&#8217;s a process that would be overseen by the interagency through &#8212; go through an interagency process, led by the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; I know there are many advocates for that, but I don&#8217;t have an update on the process or if it will happen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What plans does the administra- &#8212; and on &#8212; in regard to refugees &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what plans does the administration have to take in &#8212; for the United States to take in some refugees in the United States?&nbsp; Have there been any planning discussions, perhaps with refugee groups, to prepare this?&nbsp; Do you &#8212; do you have an anticipated number of how many refugees may come to the U.S.?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an updated &#8212; an anticipated number to project.&nbsp; What I will convey to you is that we are always in constant contact with the refugee organizations, who do incredible work around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I would also reiterate that what we&#8217;ve seen happen over the last couple of days is countries like Poland, Germany, and others in Europe make clear that they are going &#8212; they are opening their arms to welcome refugees from Ukraine.&nbsp; Those are neighboring countries.&nbsp; So we do anticipate the vast majority will want to go to countries in Europe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you do anticipate that some would come to the United States?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are open to that, yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And if I could ask one more.&nbsp; Senator Coons floated the idea of 10 billion &#8212; a $10 billion emergency supplemental package.&nbsp; Just, does the administration support that proposal?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are having ongoing conversations with Congress about additional assistance to Ukraine. &nbsp;Our OMB leadership is having those conversations.&nbsp; And so, I will leave it to them to put out any updated specific number from our end, but they&#8217;re &#8212; those are underway.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why doesn’t President Biden want to talk to Vladimir Putin right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because he&#8217;s invading a sovereign country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he &#8212; isn&#8217;t he going to be potentially invading that for years on end?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that a moment where a leader is beginning and in the middle of invading a sovereign country is not the moment where diplomacy feels appropriate.&nbsp; It does not mean we have ruled out diplomacy forever.&nbsp; Obviously, the President remains open to engaging on &#8212; at a leader-to-leader level, but this is not the moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And why are you guys waiting to apply maximum pressure on Russia with &#8212; you know, sanctions on everything?&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t seem &#8212; you know, are you guys waiting for Kyiv to fall?&nbsp; Or (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sanctions on everything?&nbsp; How do you mean?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In &#8212; like sanctions on all Russian &#8212; you know, all Russian transactions and on oil and gas.&nbsp; Sort of &#8212; like do you think that Americans are not willing to take a hit at the gas pump?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well &#8212; well, I would say there&#8217;s a couple of principles through which the President has approached sanctions.&nbsp; One is maximizing the impact on Russian leadership and on the Russ- &#8212; Russian financial system so that there will be a particular squeeze.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve obviously taken steps already that have gone far and above what have ever been done &#8212; what has ever been done in the past.&nbsp; If you look at just 10 &#8212; the 10 financial institutions that we sanctioned, they hold a &#8212; you know, a huge percentage of &#8212; they are about 80 percent of the Russian banking sector.&nbsp; That is a significant step that was announced yesterday.</p>



<p>The export controls step that was announced yesterday means that they will be &#8212; they won&#8217;t have the ability to get access to the technology that &#8212; and semiconductors and AI &#8212; that President Putin desperately wants to continue to innovate his economy moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also &#8212; of course, Europeans are also looking at &#8212; European countries are also looking at some of their reliance on Russia, whether it&#8217;s for energy or other purposes, and they&#8217;re making their own decisions about diversifying.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I noted a little bit earlier, the Ruble remains about 10 percent weaker year to date and the worst-performing emerging market currency in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what should be clear here is that there are already huge impacts.&nbsp; There is already an enormous squeeze on the Russian financial system and economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are also &#8212; what the President is also focused on as a principle is not &#8212; is taking steps and making sure we are minimizing the impact on the American people, on the global economic system.&nbsp; And we, of course, weigh that, as we have a responsibility to do.&nbsp; And we want to, first and foremost &#8212; I should have said this first &#8212; take these steps, united with our partners and Allies in Europe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the administration have any message to American companies that do business in Russia with entities that are not necessarily on the sanction list?&nbsp; Would you like to see U.S. citizens not buy Russian products?&nbsp; Would you like to see U.S.-based CEOs not look for business in Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re not trying to hurt the people of Russia or the Russian people.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to que- &#8212; squeeze the financial system and sector to make sure there are significant consequences for the actions of the president.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So understanding there&#8217;s no plan for Presidents Biden and Putin to speak, is there any line of communication between the White House and the Kremlin right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have additional details on that at this point in time.&nbsp; Obviously, our national security team has a range of means of communicating with the Russians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Then should we take what you said earlier in your answer to mean that the President won’t speak with Putin unless Putin de-escalates or withdraws?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, it&#8217;s not the appropriate moment right now.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t give you &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to give you a “forever and ever” because that&#8217;s not how he feels. But they’re actively invading Ukraine.&nbsp; They are moving on the capital.&nbsp; They are looking to overturn leadership.&nbsp; This is not the moment for President Biden to have a diplomatic conversation with President Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on refugees.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been noted that the EU response to Ukrainian refugees has been quite different to the response to refugees from other nations, and I wonder what the White House view is on that, given that some countries like Poland and Hungary were actively trying to keep out many refugees largely from the Middle East.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think I have any further comment on that from here about the decisions of other countries and where they accept refugees from.&nbsp; What I can speak to is what our approach is here in the United States.&nbsp; And obviously, we have welcomed with open arms tens of thousands of Afghan refugees.&nbsp; And certainly, while it may be &#8212; to go to the earlier question &#8212; that the majority of refugees from Ukraine go to Europe, we are certainly open to accepting refugees from Ukraine as well.&nbsp; That is our policy and our approach and certainly what we will continue to implement.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just following up on the question and your discussion of sanctioning oil and gas and &#8212; and understanding that the President in any decisions he makes around sanctions or any other actions to take against Russia is thinking about the American people, is there a point at which he would consider doing that?&nbsp; That &#8212; that &#8212; is that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Like the energy sector?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Ener- &#8212; is the energy sector at some level on the table as Putin gets even more aggressive?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, you know, there are also some other countries that are &#8212; have worked for carveouts &#8212; for instance, Italy and luxury goods.&nbsp; What is the U.S. view of those kinds of exceptions being made for things that are maybe a lot less essential, as much as we might like them, than oil and gas?&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Speaking for yourself.&nbsp; So I would say, on the energy sector, no option is off the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, to go back to the princi- &#8212; some of the principles here, our sanctions are designed to harm Russia&#8217;s economy, not our economy, and that&#8217;s a key balance that we&#8217;re clearly trying to strike.&nbsp; And I think when Daleep &#8212; as Daleep has been in here a few times over the last week, he has conveyed we do risk assessments &#8212; right? &#8212; and impact assessments, and that&#8217;s a part of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The other factor here on the energy sector is that starting out with energy or &#8212; could actually benefit President Putin and pad his pockets because, given high oil and gas prices, cutting off Russian oil and gas could drive prices up to Putin&#8217;s benefit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s obviously a factor as well, but it&#8217;s not off the table.&nbsp; But we look at a range of issues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of how &#8212; what other countries have sought as far as carveouts of areas that they&#8217;re not sanctioning, does the administration have a view of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think &#8212; I think &#8212; look, our focus right now is that we are working in close coordination and in lockstep with our European counterparts.&nbsp; It does not mean everything is identical; it is not identical.&nbsp; But what you have seen across the board is very strong, impactful sanctions that the shared hope is that they will have significant economic and financial consequences.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212; does the administration have an estimate of how many Russian deaths or casualties there have been in Ukraine at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have that assessment from here.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t expect we would have that assessment from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So the Ukrainians have this number &#8212; 3,800 &#8212; that they&#8217;ve been putting out &#8212; or 2,800 that they&#8217;ve been putting out today.&nbsp; Do you have any sense of the accuracy or the order of magnitude or (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;I don&#8217;t have any assessment from here and I don&#8217;t anticipate we would.&nbsp; I know that the Department of Defense is providing &#8212; is doing regular or daily, nearly, briefings on kind of the movements and what they&#8217;re seeing on the ground, but I don&#8217;t believe even they were able to make an assessment of casualties earlier today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more quick question on the Supreme Court process.&nbsp; You mentioned three candidates that he interviewed in person.&nbsp; Just want to make sure: The &#8212; the only three candidates he interviewed in person?&nbsp; Did he interview any candidates virtually?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Those are the candidates he interviewed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, thank you.&nbsp; And &#8212; yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Did you have another one?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, no, no.&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jen.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Jen, does the White House stand by the support you guys gave to Brazil to become a global partner in NATO after President Bolsonaro met last week with President Putin.&nbsp; And still, President Bolsonaro didn&#8217;t condemn the invasion.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, as I said in relation to a question a little bit earlier, I mean, our view and our &#8212; our push for every country in the world is to stand up, in this moment, and decide what &#8212; where you stand, where you want to be in history as the history books look back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that doesn&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything in terms of our change of &#8212; our view of our overarching relationship.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, can I just follow up on that question in terms of building a global coalition against &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Russia, right?&nbsp; I mean, India, for example &#8212; a Quad member &#8212; it&#8217;s the only Quad member that&#8217;s not implementing export controls for example.&nbsp; I think the President yesterday mentioned that that issue still hasn&#8217;t been resolved.&nbsp; Is he planning to call &#8212; call Prime Minister Modi?&nbsp; I think Prime Minister Modi called President Putin yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just, can you speak more broadly, in terms of bringing all these other partners that maybe, you know, are not Europe, but, you know, the Quad, as well as perhaps ASEAN members who are pretty ambivalent and cautious about condemning the Russian invasion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say some were, but I wouldn&#8217;t say the majority were.&nbsp; And we continue to engage with the Indians, with other ASEAN partners on both what we&#8217;re seeing on the ground, our continued condemnation of the actions of President Putin in Ukraine.&nbsp; And we will continue to push others to follow suit.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to follow up, Delta announced today that they&#8217;re suspending codesharing with Aeroflot.&nbsp; Did the White House have anything to do with this decision?&nbsp; And are you urging other American companies to &#8212; urge them to do the same?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a decision by a private sector company.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any more comments on it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on the State of the Union, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you preview a little bit on the foreign policy portion of the President&#8217;s State of the Union?&nbsp; I mean, obviously, with the crisis in Ukraine, I know that you &#8212; you&#8217;re not going to be able to preview that.&nbsp; But just in general &#8212; now with Ukraine, before that with the Afghanistan withdrawal &#8212; what can the President say to show that his foreign policy doctrine is succeeding?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without previewing the State of the Union, which we&#8217;ll do later this evening &#8212; or later this weekend &#8212; sorry, it&#8217;s kind of all one day that&#8217;s running together &#8212; we will do later this weekend, I expect.&nbsp; So, look at &#8212; look ahead to that or we&#8217;ll have more to say later this weekend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, it&#8217;s also &#8212; as it relates to Russia-Ukraine: You know, we are unfortunately still in the middle of this conflict.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We&#8217;re in the middle of an active invasion.&nbsp; So I just can&#8217;t give you a preview of what that will look like in the State of the Union.</p>



<p>As it relates to how the President views his approach to foreign policy: You know, the President has ran &#8212; ran for President wanting to return America&#8217;s seat at the world, wanting to return to a time where other leaders around the world could trust the word and the commitments of the United States.&nbsp; And what you have seen, over the last few months, is the President deliver on exactly that.&nbsp; He has been leading the effort in the world to stand up to Russia, stand up to the efforts, the aggression, the invasion of a sovereign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While I&#8217;m not going to get into the specifics of what is going to be in the State of the Union, that&#8217;s exactly what he said he would do when he was running.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, so the President said he&#8217;s doing everything he can to bring down energy prices &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; gas prices here in the U.S.&nbsp; Is on the table then &#8212; or is he considering reversing some of the policies and regulations that he put into place that constricts the long-term supply of it to let Europe be more reliant on the U.S. for oil and natural gas?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean like LNG exports or something like that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; LNG &#8212; LNG exports, but also oil prices &#8212; allowing &#8212; you know, opening up drilling again, reversing the ban on leases on federal lands.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what&#8217;s important to note here &#8212; and I talked about this a little bit yesterday &#8212; is that there are a range of available oil leasing sites that oil companies are not utilizing, so you should ask them about that.</p>



<p>You know the President&#8217;s view on reducing our dependence on foreign oil.&nbsp; And actually, his view is that this makes that case even stronger and diversifying the range of means of energy production everywhere around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As it relates to LNG exports, I don&#8217;t have anything new on that.</p>



<p>Our focus right now is on working with &#8212; or engaging with a range of countries &#8212; I mentioned Japan yesterday &#8212; and having conversations with others who may have the availability of supply &#8212; natural gas supply that was coming from the United States to provide to Europe in this time where they need it.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re seeing some encouraging developments on that front.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more thing on OPEC.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; OPEC is making moves now to get ready to include Iranian oil in &#8212; if the U.S. is successful with the Iran nuclear deal.&nbsp; Would the President then welcome Iranian oil coming into the U.S. to lower gas prices?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we&#8217;re not quite at the point of a final deal on the nuclear deal.&nbsp; So, we will talk about that if we get to that point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You talked a couple times about the U.S. engaging in diplomacy with Russia going forward.&nbsp; When he announced the sanctions today against Putin and Lavrov, the British Prime Minister told NATO leaders that there could be &#8220;no normalization&#8221; with Russia after the attack on Ukraine.&nbsp; Does this administration share that view?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, in this moment, the &#8212; I&#8217;ve conveyed pretty clearly the President has no intentions at this moment to engage with President Putin.&nbsp; He was just sanctioned.&nbsp; We just made a decision in coordination &#8212; in close lockstep with the Europeans to sanction him; a head of state &#8212; that is a very rare step to take.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, obviously, we&#8217;ve issued significant sanctions that cover 80 percent of the financial sector.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, no, we&#8217;re not in a business-as-usual moment at this point in time.&nbsp; And, obviously, de-escalation would help return us to a state where that could proceed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the White House, right now, believe that President Zelenskyy is safe in Kyiv?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are in close touch with him.&nbsp; While I&#8217;m not going to give you updates on his security state, we &#8212; certainly, the President just spoke with him earlier today, and he continues to be the President of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; In regards to the new CDC guidance on the pandemic, which, of course, will then be the, you know, the new Biden administration guidance: What is the &#8212; what will the message be to Americans in regards to these new metrics and this &#8212; the new guidance as to where we are in the pandemic?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, if you look at the specific of them, we&#8217;re &#8212; we are moving &#8212; the President &#8212; we have talked a little bit about how we want to move to a time and a place where we are &#8212; you know, have the tools needed so that COVID and the pandemic do not disrupt our daily lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, they&#8217;ll have &#8212; there&#8217;s more &#8212; the President has been talking to his COVID team about exactly that.&nbsp; This is a part of that process, and we&#8217;re moving forward in that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a result of these &#8212; this announcement today and these updated recommendations, today more than half the country &#8212; 70 percent of Americans &#8212; live in areas where the CDC no longer recommends universal masking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, if people want to wear a mask, because they&#8217;re immunocompromised, because they have concerns about their safeties and their &#8212; safety in their communities, they should have the ability to do that.&nbsp; But that is certainly a step forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know that &#8212; this is part of that process.&nbsp; And I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there concern that this might imply or have folks think that then, therefore, the pandemic is over and can eschew all caution?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then secondly or kind of added on to that, are you confident that there will be an ability to reverse course if things get bad again?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if nobody is saying it&#8217;s &#8212; &#8220;it means it&#8217;s over,&#8221; including anybody who has a big platform, for example, then that &#8212; we&#8217;re not concerned about that.&nbsp; That is not what we&#8217;re conveying from here, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are conveying from here and what the CDC is conveying is that America is in a stronger place today as a nation.&nbsp; We have more tools ever &#8212; than ever before to protect ourselves from COVID-19: vaccination, boosters, treatments, testing, high-quality masks, improved ventilation.&nbsp; Over 200 million people are vaccinated.&nbsp; Nearly 100 million Americans have been boosted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the CDC is providing public health guidance that has a couple of different clear levels so that people can understand what their recommendation is as it relates to wearing a mask.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what this is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are still people dying every day of COVID.&nbsp; There are still immunocompromised populations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we are trying to work towards is a period of time where we are &#8212; where COVID is not disrupting our daily lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just wanted to know &#8212; you said that the President has done everything in his power.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen the sanctions, shoring up the NATO eastern flank, all of that.&nbsp; But no troops &#8212; you repeated that.&nbsp; Doesn&#8217;t that also send a message to Vladimir Putin &#8212; clearly, it hasn&#8217;t stopped him &#8212; that other nations in the region that are not NATO members are also free game for him since he&#8217;s not going to have that stop?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think the crippling sanctions that the President has issued &#8212; or approved and we announced yesterday &#8212; that cover 80 percent of the financial sector, that are having an impact already on the financial sector there or steps that the President has taken, including export &#8212; banning export controls; or steps he&#8217;s taken to sanction oligarchs and to rally the world to take not only significant financial steps, but also to treat President Putin as a pariah send a message that there&#8217;s a free walk for anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, President Putin is isolating himself further.&nbsp; He&#8217;s &#8212; if his objective here is to &#8212; as his stated objective is to divide NATO, if his stated objective is to divide the West, it&#8217;s having the opposite effect.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think that would be our assessment.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May I just &#8212; just a quick question on cyberattacks.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The NATO Secretary General, again, said that he would view a cyberattack on a NATO member &#8212; this time talking about NATO members &#8212; as something that would be under Article 5.&nbsp; Is that the view of the United States also, that a cyberattack on NATO &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I answered this yesterday, and I said that it would be up to NATO members to determine what that looks like and what any response would look like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President been in touch with &#8212; before or after the decision today &#8212; with Congressman Clyburn?&nbsp; He, of course, was a big boost &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, he called him this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve said &#8212; you&#8217;ve said that the U.S. &#8212; we don&#8217;t go to war against Russia (inaudible) Russia is heavily armed.&nbsp; The U.S. is heavily armed.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m just wondering if you&#8217;re not being pragmatic here with Russia.&nbsp; Are we not being pragmatic to recognize that it may not be in the interest of the U.S. for Ukraine to be a member of NATO, which is the key request from Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m understanding your question.&nbsp; Is it &#8212; are you asking me if &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it &#8212; is it in the interest of the U.S. for Ukraine to be a member of NATO?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is up to every country to determine what alliances they want to join or not join.&nbsp; And that is not a pressure point we issue from the United States.&nbsp; And we &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you &#8212; can you &#8212; can you confirm &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; think it&#8217;s important for that to remain open.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you confirm that you are looking for a job at CNN or MSNBC?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have more than enough on my plate here.&nbsp; So, you can&#8217;t get rid of quite yet.&nbsp; Sorry, Peter, for you on that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I will see you all on Monday.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, do you have more as &#8212; when you might brief us on the State of the Union?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we might have more on Sunday is my expectation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>4:28 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/25/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-and-section-614a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 04:03:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the following authorities, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 614(a)(3) and section 652 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), in order to provide immediate military assistance to Ukraine:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;the authority under section 614(a)(1) of the FAA to determine whether it is important to the security interests of the United States to furnish up to $250 million in assistance without regard to any provision of law within the purview of section 614(a)(1) of the FAA; and</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $350 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on his Nomination of Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson to Serve as Associate Justice of the U.S. Supreme&#160;Court</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/25/remarks-by-president-biden-on-his-nomination-of-judge-ketanji-brown-jackson-to-serve-as-associate-justice-of-the-u-s-supreme-court/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cross Hall 2:02 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Today, as we watch freedom and liberty under attack abroad, I’m here to fulfill my responsibilities under the Constitution to preserve freedom and liberty here in the United States of America.  And it’s my honor to introduce to the country a daughter of former public school teachers, a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cross Hall</p>



<p>2:02 P.M. EST<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Today, as we watch freedom and liberty under attack abroad, I’m here to fulfill my responsibilities under the Constitution to preserve freedom and liberty here in the United States of America. <br> <br>And it’s my honor to introduce to the country a daughter of former public school teachers, a proven consensus builder, an accomplished lawyer, a distinguished jurist &#8212; one of the nation’s most &#8212; on one of the nation’s most prestigious courts.  My nominee for the United States Supreme Court is Judge Ketanji Jackson.<br> <br>You know, four weeks ago, when a member of the Court &#8212; a friend of mine; we used to work together in the Senate &#8212; Justice Stephen Breyer, announced his retirement, I said then choosing someone to serve on the United States Supreme Court is one of the most serious constitutional responsibilities a President has.  And I mean it. <br> <br>I promised the process would be rigorous, that I would select a nominee worthy of Justice Breyer’s legacy of excellence and decency &#8212; someone extremely qualified, with a brilliant legal mind, with the utmost character and integrity, which are equally as important.<br> <br>And that I would bring this decision &#8212; to this decision my perspective as a lawyer; a former Constitutional law professor; chairman of the Judiciary Committee for many, many years; and &#8212; I’m almost reluctant to say it &#8212; someone who has presided over more Supreme Court nominations than almost anyone living today, which makes me 28 years old &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I started doing it when I was 32 &#8212; and who has devoted much of my career to thinking about the Constitution and the role of the Supreme Court.<br> <br>With that perspective, I carefully studierd [sic] the re- &#8212; studied the records of candidates.  I’ve invited senators of both parties to offer their ideas and points of view, and I’ve met with a number of them. <br> <br>As a result, because I truly respect not only the consent &#8212; I know they give consent, but it says &#8212; the Constitution says ”advice and consent,” and I sought the advice of Democrats and Republicans. <br> <br>I’ve consulted with leading legal scholars and lawyers.<br> <br>And I’ve been fortunate to have the advice of the &#8212; Vice President Harris &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; an exceptional lawyer, a former Attorney General of California, and a former member of the Senate Judiciary Committee.<br> <br>And during this process, I looked for someone who, like Justice Breyer, has a pragmatic understanding that the law must work for the American people.  Someone who has the historical perspective to understand that the Constitution is a resilient charter of liberty.  Someone with the wisdom to appreciate that the Constitution protects certain inalienable rights &#8212; rights that fall within the most fundamental personal freedoms that our society recognizes.<br> <br>And then, someone with extraordinary character, who will bring to the Supreme Court an independent mind, uncompromising integrity, and with a strong moral compass and the courage to stand up for what she thinks is right.<br> <br>For too long, our government, our courts haven’t looked like America.  And I believe it’s time that we have a Court that reflects the full talents and greatness of our nation with a nominee of extraordinary qualifications and that we inspire all young people to believe that they can one day serve their country at the highest level.<br> <br>I’ve admired these traits of pragmatism, historical perspective, wisdom, character in the jurists nominated by Republican presidents as well as Democratic presidents. <br> <br>And today, I’m pleased to introduce to the American people a candidate who continues in this great tradition.<br> <br>Judge Jackson grew up in Miami, Florida.  And by the way, the mayor of Miami &#8212; a Republican &#8212; endorsed you; I thought that was interesting.  Her parents grew up with segregation but never gave up hope that their children would enjoy the true promise of America.<br> <br>Her parents graduated from Historic Brac- &#8212; Black Colleges and become public school teachers &#8212; her mom, a principal; her Dad, a teacher, who later went back to school and became a lawyer representing that very school district &#8212; that school board.<br> <br>Judge Jackson describes finding her love for the law from an apartment complex at the University of Miami where her dad was attending law school.  She’d draw in her coloring book at the dining room table, next to her dad’s law books.<br> <br>She grew up to be a star student &#8212; elected mayor of her junior high school and president of her high school class, where she was a standout &#8212; she was a standout on the speech and debate team.<br> <br>And it was after a debate tournament that took place at Harvard when she was in high school that she believed she could one day be a student there.  There were those who told her she shouldn’t set her sights too high, but she refused to accept limits others set for her. <br> <br>She did go on to Harvard undergraduate school, where she graduated magna cum laude.  She went into &#8212; to attend Harvard Law School, where she was a top student and editor of the prestigious Law Review.<br> <br>Then she applied for a highly competitive and coveted clerkship on the United States Supreme Court, and she was selected.<br> <br>The justice who thought that she was worthy of this high honor was a young lawyer.  It was none other than Justice Stephen Breyer, who’s seat I am nominating her to fill. <br> <br>Not only did she learn about being a judge from Justice Breyer himself, she saw the great rigor through which Justice Breyer approached his work.  She learned from his willingness to work with colleagues with different viewpoints &#8212; critical qualities for &#8212; in my view, for any Supreme Court Justice.<br> <br>Now, years later, she steps up to fill Justice Breyer’s place on the Court with a uniquely accomplished and wide-ranging background.<br> <br>She has served both in public service as a federal public defender &#8212; a federal public defender and in private law practice as an accomplished lawyer in pr- &#8212; with a prestigious law firm.<br> <br>If confirmed, she will join Justice Sotomayor as the only other member of the United States Supreme Court who has experience as a trial court judge –- a critical qualification, in my view.<br> <br>And once again following in the footsteps of her mentor, Justice Breyer, she would become the only member of the Court who previously served as a member of the United States Sentencing Commission.<br> <br>And she brings an additional perspective to the Court as well.  She comes from a family of law enforcement, with her brother and uncles having served as police officers.<br> <br>That’s one reason, I expect, why the Fraternal Order of Police &#8212; the national organization &#8212; today said, and I quote, “There is little doubt [that] she has the temperament, the intellect, and the legal experience, and family background to have earned this appointment.”  And they went on to say they are confident she will, quote, “approach her future cases with an open mind and treat issues related to law enforcement fairly and justly.”<br> <br>Incredibly, Judge Jackson has already been confirmed by the United States Senate three times.<br> <br>First, to serve on the U.S. Sentencing Commission &#8212; a bipartisan, independent commission we help &#8212; I helped design to reduce the unwarranted disparities in sentencing and promote transparency and fairness in the criminal justice system. <br> <br>On the commission, Judge Jackson was known for working with Democrats and Republicans to find common ground on critical issues.<br> <br>Second, she was concerned by &#8212; confirmed by the United States Senate with bipartisan support on the federal district court to administer justice with the special rigors and fairness that come with presiding over trials. <br> <br>And third, she was confirmed with a bipartisan Senate vote to serve on U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia,  considered the second most powerful court behind the Supreme Court itself and the court she once argued cases before as a distinguished advocate. <br> <br>And when Judge Jackson was nominated to this Circuit Court, one of its distinguished retired members, Judge Thomas Griffith, a former general counsel of Brigham Young University and a George Bush appointee to that court said he backed her “enthusiastically,” hailing her &#8212; hailing her “exemplary legal career in both public and private practice” and, he went on to say, her “careful approach” as a trial court judge.<br> <br>Judge Jackson’s service on the District Circuit Court of &#8212; for the D.C. Circuit Court of Appeals is another superb qualification for service on the Supreme Court.<br> <br>Three of her &#8212; of the current Supreme Court Justices also served with the D.C. Circuit judges where Judge Jackson now serves.<br> <br>Her opinions are always carefully reasoned, tethered to precedent, and demonstrate refrect &#8212; respect for how the law impacts everyday people.  It doesn’t mean she puts her thumb on the scale of justice one way or the other, but she understands the broader impact of her decisions.<br> <br>Whether it’s cases addressing the rights of workers or government service, she cares about making sure that our democracy works for the American people.<br> <br>She listens.  She looks people in the eye &#8212; lawyers, defendants, victims, and families.<br> <br>And she strives to ensure that everyone understands why she made a decision, what the law is, and what it means to them.  She strives to be fair, to get it right, to do justice. <br> <br>That&#8217;s something all of us should remember, and it&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve thought about throughout this process.  And as a matter of fact, I thought about it walking over here with her.<br> <br>One floor below, we have several displays celebrating Black History Month.  One of them includes the judicial oath of office taken and signed by Justice Thurgood Marshall himself &#8212; an oath that will be once again administered to a distinguished American who will help write the next chapter in the history of the journey of America &#8212; a journey that Judge Jackson will take with her family. <br> <br>I hope I don&#8217;t embarrass him, but her husband, Patrick &#8212; a surgeon &#8212; Dr. Patrick, stand up.  Let them see who you are.  There you go.  They met when they were undergraduate students at Harvard, and he&#8217;s a distinguished cancer surgeon at Georgetown. <br> <br>And like so many women in this country, Judge Jackson is a working mom.  She had her eldest child, Talia, when she was a private lawyer in practice.  She had her second child, Leila, when she served as U- &#8212; on the U.S. Sentencing Commission.  Stand up, Leila.  I asked Leila, when I showed her through the office, whether she&#8217;d like to be president.  She looked, &#8220;No, I don&#8217;t know about that.&#8221;  (Laughter.)  There&#8217;s other things that &#8212; anyway, Leila, you&#8217;re welcome to be here.  Thank you so much. <br> <br>And welcome your sister, who&#8217;s up in school in Rhode Island now. <br> <br>I have children and grandchildren.  Let me tell you, Judge, you&#8217;re always a mom.  That&#8217;s not going to change no matter what you&#8217;re doing.  You&#8217;re on &#8212; whether you&#8217;re on the Supreme Court or not. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ve always had a deep respect for the Supreme Court and judiciary as a coequal branch of the government, and I mean it.  The Court is equally as important as the presidency or the Congress.  It&#8217;s coequal. <br> <br>So, today, I&#8217;m pleased to nominate Judge Jackson, who will bring extraordinary qualifications, deep experience and intellect, and a rigorous judicial record to the Court. <br> <br>Judge Jackson deserves to be confirmed as the next justice of the Supreme Court.  I&#8217;ve met with the chairman and ranking members of the Senate Judiciary Committee, Senator Dick Durbin, Senator Chuck Grassley, and my hope is that they will move promptly, and I know they&#8217;ll move fairly. <br> <br>Judge Jackson, congratulations.  And the podium is yours.  Let me pull this out for you.  How &#8212; where is &#8212; there you go.  (The President adjusts the podium.)  You got it?  The button &#8212; okay.  See?  Presidents can&#8217;t do much.  Thank you.<br> <br>JUDGE JACKSON:  Thank you, Mr. President.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Thank you very much, Mr. President.  I am truly humbled by the extraordinary honor of this nomination.  And I am especially grateful for the care that you have taken in discharging your constitutional duty in service of our democracy with all that is going on in the world today. <br> <br>I also offer my sincerest thanks to you as well, Madam Vice President, for your invaluable role in this nomination process. <br> <br>I must begin these very brief remarks by thanking God for delivering me to this point in my professional journey.  My life has been blessed beyond measure, and I do know that one can only come this far by faith.<br> <br>Among my many blessings &#8212; and indeed, the very first &#8212; is the fact that I was born in this great country.  The United States of America is the greatest beacon of hope and democracy the world has ever known. <br> <br>I was also blessed from my early days to have had a supportive and loving family.  My mother and father, who have been married for 54 years, are at their home in Florida right now, and I know that they could not be more proud. <br> <br>It was my father who started me on this path.  When I was a child, as the President mentioned, my father made the fateful decision to trans- &#8212; to transition from his job as a public high school history teacher and go to law school.  Some of my earliest memories are of him sitting at the kitchen table, reading his law books.  I watched him study and he became my first professional role model. <br> <br>My mother, who was also a public high school teacher, provided invaluable support in those early days, working full-time to enable my father&#8217;s career transition while also guiding and inspiring four-year-old me.<br> <br>My only sibling &#8212; my brother, Ketajh &#8212; came along half a decade later, and I am so proud of all that he&#8217;s accomplished. After graduating from Howard University, he became a police officer and a detective on some of the toughest streets in the inner city of Baltimore.  After that, he enlisted in the Army, serving two tours of duty in the Middle East.  I believe that he was following the example set by my uncles who are in law enforcement. <br> <br>You may have read that I have one uncle who got caught up in the drug trade and received a life sentence.  That is true, but law enforcement also runs in my family.  In addition to my brother, I had two uncles who served decades as police officers, one of whom became the police chief in my hometown of Miami, Florida. <br> <br>I am standing here today by the grace of God as testament to the love and support that I&#8217;ve received from my family. <br> <br>I have also been blessed with many dear friends, colleagues, mentors, law clerks.  I could not possibly name all of the people to whom I owe great thanks.  But I must mention specifically the three brilliant jurists for whom I had the privilege of serving as a law clerk at the outset of my legal career: U.S. District Judge Patti Saris in Massachusetts, U.S. Court of Appeals Bruce &#8212; Judge Bruce Selya in Rhode Island, and last but certainly not least, Associate Justice Stephen Breyer of the Supreme Court of the United States. <br> <br>Justice Breyer, in particular, not only gave me the greatest job that any young lawyer could ever hope to have, but he also exemplified every day in every way that a Supreme Court Justice can perform at the highest level of skill and integrity while also being guided by civility, grace, pragmatism, and generosity of spirit. <br> <br>Justice Breyer, the members of the Senate will decide if I fill your seat, but please know that I could never fill your shoes. <br> <br>To my dear family, those who are here with me now and those who are watching from home, I am forever indebted to you for your love and support. <br> <br>To my beloved husband, Patrick, thank you for being my rock today and every day for these past 26 years.  I love you.<br> <br>To my daughters, Talia and Leila, you are the light of my life.  Please know that whatever title I may hold or whatever job I might &#8212; may have, I will still be your mom.  That will never change. <br> <br>There are so many other people I would love to be able to address and to thank, but time is short.  So, let me end by sharing an interesting coincidence that has actually meant a great deal to me over the years. <br> <br>As it happens, I share a birthday with the first Black woman ever to be appointed as a federal judge: the Honorable Constance Baker Motley.  We were born exactly 49 years to the day apart. <br> <br>Today, I proudly stand on Judge Motley&#8217;s shoulders, sharing not only her birthday but also her steadfast and courageous commitment to equal justice under law. <br> <br>Judge Motley&#8217;s life and career has been a true inspiration to me as I have pursued this professional path.  And if I am fortunate enough to be confirmed as the next Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States, I can only hope that my life and career, my love of this country and the Constitution, and my commitment to upholding the rule of law and the sacred principles upon which this great nation was founded will inspire future generations of Americans. <br> <br>Thank you again, Mr. President, for this extraordinary honor.  (Applause.)<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I forgot to introduce the First Lady, Dr. Jill Biden, and the Second Gentleman.  I &#8212; that seems strange to say that, but the Second &#8212; Doug is &#8212; Emhoff.  They&#8217;re both here as well.  So, thank you.  <br> <br>Thank you all.  (Applause.)<br> <br>2:22 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of the President on the NATO Summit and Call with President&#160;Zelenskyy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/25/statement-of-the-president-on-the-nato-summit-and-call-with-president-zelenskyy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 20:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today I met with fellow leaders from our NATO Allies to discuss our shared commitment to collective defense and Transatlantic security. As President Putin threatens the very foundations of international peace and security, NATO is once again demonstrating that it stands for freedom and democracy. As I said yesterday, the United States will defend every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today I met with fellow leaders from our NATO Allies to discuss our shared commitment to collective defense and Transatlantic security. As President Putin threatens the very foundations of international peace and security, NATO is once again demonstrating that it stands for freedom and democracy.</p>



<p>As I said yesterday, the United States will defend every inch of NATO territory. Our commitment to Article 5 is ironclad. I have ordered the deployment of additional forces to augment our capabilities in Europe to support our NATO Allies. And I strongly welcome the decision to activate NATO’s defensive plans and elements of the NATO Response Force to strengthen our collective posture, as well as the commitments by our Allies to deploy additional land and air forces to the eastern flank and maritime forces from the High North to the Mediterranean.</p>



<p>We were joined today by our close partners Sweden, Finland, and the European Union. President Putin has failed in his goal of dividing the West. NATO is as united and resolute as it’s ever been, and NATO will maintain its Open Door to those European states who share our values and who one day may seek to join our Alliance. As we navigate this crisis, we pledged to work even more closely together in our defense of freedom and the democratic values that imbue our Alliance with purpose and power.</p>



<p>Immediately after the NATO Summit, I spoke with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine. I commended the brave actions of the Ukrainian people who were fighting to defend their country. I also conveyed ongoing economic, humanitarian, and security support being provided by the United States as well as our continued efforts to rally other countries to provide similar assistance.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
