<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 03:08:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: National Cyber Workforce and Education&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/fact-sheet-national-cyber-workforce-and-education-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 03:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 19, 2022, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis hosted the National Cyber Workforce and Education Summit at the White House. The event focused on building our Nation’s cyber workforce, improving skills-based pathways to cyber jobs, educating Americans so that they have the skills they need to thrive in our increasingly digital society, and improving&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 19, 2022, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis hosted the National Cyber Workforce and Education Summit at the White House. The event focused on building our Nation’s cyber workforce, improving skills-based pathways to cyber jobs, educating Americans so that they have the skills they need to thrive in our increasingly digital society, and improving Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility (DEIA) in the cyber field. Bringing together entities who employ, train, and educate cyber professionals and Americans at large, the event involved senior U.S. Government officials, senior executives from the private sector, and thought leaders from across the cyber community and the education sector.</p>



<p>Participants included Ambassador Susan E. Rice, White House Domestic Policy Advisor; Secretary of Commerce Gina M. Raimondo; Secretary of Labor Martin J. Walsh; Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas; and Under Secretary of Education James Kvaal.Other U.S. Government participants included Jen Easterly, Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency; Laurie Locascio, Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology; Anne Neuberger, Deputy Assistant to the President and Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology on the National Security Council; George Barnes, Deputy Director of the National Security Agency; and Principal Deputy National Cyber Director Kemba Walden. The Biden-Harris Administration and the various stakeholders in this area are committed to meeting the challenges and opportunities relating to cyber workforce and education, which will help improve the economy, secure Americans and our Nation’s infrastructure, advance our digital way of life, and enable our society to maximize cyber capabilities to achieve our highest aspirations.</p>



<p>The Summit included three roundtable discussions: the “All” roundtable focused on ways to help ensure that all Americans are equipped with the skills and knowledge to effectively and safely engage in our global digital ecosystem; the “Many” roundtable explored ways to improve practices in cyber-adjacent fields that are not focused solely on cyber but are still impacted by it, are related to it, or benefit from it; and the “Few” roundtable discussed the jobs and career pathways that are specifically focused on cyber.</p>



<p>In connection with the Summit, the Biden-Harris Administration announced the following actions:</p>



<ul><li><strong>National Cyber Director Chris Inglis</strong> committed to developing a National Cyber Workforce and Education Strategy in coordination with other elements of the Executive Office of the President (EOP) as well as Federal departments and agencies, with input from key public and private stakeholders. The National Cyber Workforce and Education Strategy will aim to address the challenges and opportunities in these critical areas, improve collaboration across government-wide efforts, help align resources to aspirations, and implement Biden-Harris Administration priorities on education and workforce development.</li><li><strong>Secretary of Commerce Gina M. Raimondo and Secretary of Labor Martin J. Walsh </strong><a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/osec/osec20220719">announced</a> a 120-day Cybersecurity Apprenticeship Sprint that they are leading with support from other Federal agencies, including the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Education, the Office of Personnel Management, and others. This initiative is aimed at providing individuals with the opportunity to receive the training and mentorship they need to begin a career in the cyber workforce by expanding and promoting cyber-related Registered Apprenticeship programs. More information on this program can be found at <a href="https://www.apprenticeship.gov/cybersecurity-apprenticeship-sprint">https://www.apprenticeship.gov/cybersecurity-apprenticeship-sprint</a>.</li><li><strong>Ambassador Susan E. Rice </strong>announced efforts to strengthen the K-12 system to more effectively prepare students for job opportunities in cybersecurity.Specifically, 1) the National Security Agency is supporting an initiative by the U.S. Department of Education’s Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education that will provide technical assistance to state and local educational agencies to accelerate the development, adoption, and implementation of middle grades CTE programs focused on emerging career pathways, such as space and cybersecurity; and 2) the U.S. Department of Commerce’s National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education will make its Cybersecurity Workforce Framework—which provides a range of cyber curricula and resources—easier to use for K-12 teachers and leaders by creating a K12 Educator FAQ resource.</li></ul>



<p>In addition, the following organizations have made substantial announcements, commitments, or pledges in connection with the Summit:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Accenture</strong> is committed to creating access to new roles in cybersecurity, cloud, and other technical areas through its apprenticeship and upskilling programs. This is part of Accenture’s broader goal in the U.S. to fill 20% of entry-level roles from its apprenticeship program. Additionally, Accenture is committed to training all 700,000+ of its own people through its award-winning interactive security awareness courses next year.</li><li><strong>The</strong> <strong>Alperovitch Institute for Cybersecurity Studies</strong>, aimed at developing a unique mix of geopolitical focus and technical rigor with cutting edge research at the intersection of cybersecurity and statecraft, has been established to train postgraduate students to become future policymakers and practitioners for leading firms and government agencies in the field of cybersecurity. The Alperovitch Institute will also offer an executive education program to provide critical understanding of cyber issues to industry executives, boards of directors, Congressional staffers, government officials, and military and intelligence officers, with classes to begin this fall.</li><li><strong>Auburn University’s</strong> Ginn College of Engineering commits to incorporate the U.S. Department of Energy’s National Cyber-Informed Engineering (CIE) Strategy throughout its engineering and computer science programs. As a land grant institution with roots in outreach and extension to its citizenry, Auburn also announced an initiative to partner with cooperative extension offices across the state to better reach underserved communities.</li><li><strong>Cisco </strong>is committing to training an additional 200,000 students in the U.S. over the next three years and will continue to increase the reach and impact of its efforts. For nearly 25 years, Cisco Networking Academy has trained more than two million U.S. students with leading networking and cybersecurity skills, and currently partners with 49% of the nation’s community and technical colleges and 48 of the nation’s 107 Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs).</li><li><strong>CompTIA</strong>, in partnership with ConnectWise,will run a nationwide pilot program to fill critical cybersecurity roles for managed services providers.CompTIA, as a National Program Sponsor for Apprenticeship, will use its training and certifications to provide jobseekers the skills needed for a career in IT and help employers realize the benefits of IT apprenticeship.</li><li><strong>The Council on Competitiveness</strong> National Commission on Innovation and Competitiveness Frontiers is launching two new working groups this fall: “The Future of Work: Developing, Supporting, and Expanding the Modern Innovation Workforce” and “The Future of Technology: Developing and Deploying Disruptive Technologies at Scale.” Both working groups will address how to advance and optimize cyber infrastructures of the future, including the robust cyber security and resiliency on which these digital platforms depend.</li><li><strong>The Cyber Readiness Institute (CRI) </strong>has released a new guide to raise awareness and implementation of multi-factor authentication (MFA) among small and medium-sized businesses (SMB). The new MFA guide provides clear and actionable information SMBs can implement today to enhance their cybersecurity. Developed with input from CRI’s Small Business Advisory Council and subject matter experts at the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), the guide employs an FAQ format to address concerns SMBs have expressed about using MFA.</li><li><strong>Dakota State University </strong>highlighted their $90 million investment for a cyber-research initiative supported by a multi-party, public-private partnership. These funds will be used to double the annual number of graduates of The Beacom College of Computer and Cyber Sciences over the next 5 years, launch a statewide Governor’s Cyber Academy accessible to all high school students, and build and operate an applied research laboratory facility in Sioux Falls, South Dakota.</li><li><strong>Fortinet </strong>is furthering its commitment to close the cyber skills gap by making its information security awareness and training service available for free for all K-12 school districts across the U.S. The expansion of its free training offerings provides the potential to help more than 8 million staff and faculty members in U.S. schools become more cyber aware and improve their skillsets to avoid breaches at educational institutions. This initiative will also advance Fortinet’s pledge to train 1 million people in cybersecurity by 2026.</li><li><strong>Girls Who Code </strong>will develop a coding challenge and activity sets focused on cybersecurity that will be geared toward middle and high school students, and implement workshops for Computer Science Education Week focused on cybersecurity and introductions to cryptography this fall.</li><li><strong>IBM</strong> is creating more pathways to cybersecurity careers through its new Cybersecurity Leadership Centers with Historically Black Colleges &amp; Universities (HBCUs) and Minority Serving Institutions (MSIs) and is partnering with the American Council on Education (ACE) to translate cybersecurity apprenticeships into college credits. This builds on IBM’s commitment last year to train more than 150,000 people in cybersecurity skills over three years through its signature programs – IBM SkillsBuild, IBM Security Academy, and its collaboration with Coursera.</li><li><strong>(ISC)²</strong>—the world’s largest nonprofit association of certified cybersecurity professionals—announced the (ISC)<sup>2</sup>&nbsp;One Million Certified in Cybersecurity<sup>SM</sup>&nbsp;program, pledging to put one million people through its Certified in Cybersecurity entry-level certification exam and education program for free. (ISC)² also has committed that half of this investment – 500,000 course enrollments and exams – will be directed toward students of HBCUs, minority-serving institutions (MSIs), tribal organizations and women’s organizations across the U.S. and the globe.</li><li><strong>The Linux Foundation (LF) </strong>is offering for free the Developing Secure Software training program, which is 15 hours of training across 3 modules (security principles; implementation considerations and software verification; and cloud security). The goal is to teach software developers how to develop more secure software from the beginning because that is much more efficient than finding and remediating vulnerabilities. Since launching it this spring, over 10,000 students have started the course and over 1,000 completed it and received their verifiable certification. Over the next few months, LF will launch new courses and certification exams on topics such as Sigstore, SBOMs and Air Gap Software Delivery.</li><li><strong>NightDragon</strong>, along with several industry partners, is creating the Cyber Talent Hub (CTH) because the Nation must leverage technology to better align the economic incentives of stakeholders involved in addressing the cyber talent shortage. The CTH will take the best attributes and practices from other technology driven marketplaces, helping employers find qualified candidates from diverse backgrounds and subsidize their cybersecurity education and training, which is tailored to the specific positions sought by these students.</li><li><strong>NPower </strong>will offer skill development opportunities and free IT training and credentials to military-connected individuals as well as young adults from underserved and underrepresented communities. NPower will increase the number of students in its Tech Fundamentals certification training by 50% within three years, thereby increasing its pipeline for advanced credentials in cloud computing and cybersecurity. NPower will also double the number of participants in its cybersecurity and cloud training over the next three years. These goals include expanding its SkillBridge cyber training program so that military service members transitioning to civilian employment are well positioned for careers in cybersecurity.</li><li><strong>Trellix </strong>has undertaken numerous initiatives, including hiring 50 interns, 40% of whom are from diverse backgrounds, and committing to hiring 100 more in the next year; partnering with the Hispanic Alliance for Career Enhancement (HACE) to launch a comprehensive mentorship and educational program; and partnering with Gotara, a global career growth platform for women in STEM+.<strong></strong></li></ul>



<p>A video recording of the Summit’s keynote session is available <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I7FvGMpuS8w">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris To Members of Omega Psi Phi&#160;Fraternity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-to-members-of-omega-psi-phi-fraternity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 01:56:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carole Hoefener CenterCharlotte, North Carolina  THE VICE PRESIDENT: &#160; Thank you.&#160; Good afternoon to the Brothers of the Omega Psi Phi.&#160; It’s good to be with you all. I just &#8212; I stopped by &#8212; I’m so happy that this worked out.&#160; I’m on my way to the airport.&#160; I came here to North Carolina to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Carole Hoefener Center<br>Charlotte, North Carolina </em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT: &nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good afternoon to the Brothers of the Omega Psi Phi.&nbsp; It’s good to be with you all.<br><br>I just &#8212; I stopped by &#8212; I’m so happy that this worked out.&nbsp; I’m on my way to the airport.&nbsp; I came here to North Carolina to talk about a few things, but I’m so happy to see you.&nbsp; The last time, Dr. Marion, we were all together was &#8212; what was it 2019, Atlantic City?<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Atlantic City.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Atlantic City.&nbsp; And we had a huge group there, and I know for the Conclave this is the first time probably in two years &#8212; right? &#8212; that you’ve been in person.<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Four years.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Four years in person.&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;<br><br>I just attended our sorority’s Boulé.&nbsp; We had that in Orlando just a couple &#8212; last week, wasn&#8217;t it?&nbsp; Last week.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>So, it&#8217;s so good to see everybody.<br><br>And listen, I just wanted to come by to say thank you.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been through a lot in our nation over the last couple of years.&nbsp; And the men of Omega Psi Phi, as always, as I have known you my entire life, I feel have been leaders &#8212; national leaders on so many important issues and including what you all did to elect Joe Biden and to elect me as Vice President of the United States.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And I think &#8212; I mean, when I was at the Boulé in Orlando, I was talking about how our sorority, with so many of our sister sororities &#8212; the Divine Nine as a whole &#8212; really organized folks around that important election.<br><br>And, you know, now we&#8217;re 110 days out from a midterm that is so critically important.<br><br>And if you don&#8217;t mind, I&#8217;ll talk just a little bit about that, because I&#8217;m here to also, yet again, come to you to ask for your leadership and to thank you in advance for what I know you&#8217;ve already planned to do.&nbsp;<br><br>A hundred and ten days out.&nbsp; And right now &#8212; I’ll just be very frank with you &#8212; we need to elect two more senators in the United States Senate who are willing to pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act and the Freedom to Vote Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who are willing to take seriously and pass the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Who will stand up for the Women&#8217;s Health <s>Initiative</s> [Protection] Act. &nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause). &nbsp;<br><br>Two votes, right here in North Carolina &#8212; Cheri Beasley &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who can win (inaudible).<br><br>I was just in Pennsylvania &#8212; John Fetterman &#8212; right? &#8212; who can win.&nbsp; And if we pick up some seats, then during the course of our administration, we can really see through what we got started.<br><br>But because of all that you did as leaders, who then inspire other leaders, we did win in 2020 because we convinced people based on our good word and standing in community that it would matter, and it did.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I was just over &#8212; I was with the governor of North Carolina, Roy Cooper, and we were talking about it.&nbsp; Our administration was able to extend the Child Tax Credit, which is why we were able in the first year to lift over 40 percent of Black children in America out of poverty.<br><br>We were able to pass &#8212; (applause) &#8212; a tax cut for working families of up to $8,000 a year, which means more money in their pocket to pay for school supplies and medication and food for their children.&nbsp; We put over $5 billion into our HBCUs because we know they are &#8212; (applause) &#8212; (inaudible).<br><br>We have, through our Delta sister, Marcia Fudge &#8212; Secretary Marcia Fudge at HUD &#8212; taken on one of the longstanding civil rights issues, which has been fair housing, and looking at a very specific issue beyond what we know has been the historic and current issues of things like redlining, but also one of the issues that has received more attention because we are handling it, which is racially biased home appraisals, knowing that our families, our greatest source of wealth and intergenerational wealth &#8212; meaning passing it from the grandparent to the children to grandchildren &#8212; is homeownership.&nbsp;<br><br>However, with home appraisals, we still have an issue &#8212; you all have heard the stories &#8212; those stories of a Black family trying to sell them home, and then the appraiser comes in and appraises the home for what they know is undervaluing the home.<br><br>So they have friends of the family who are a white family, so they invite that family to come in and put up their family pictures and take down the Black family’s pictures.<br><br>The appraiser comes in and, all of a sudden, the appraisal is much higher.&nbsp; Racial bias in home appraisals, which then directly impact the ability of a Black family and, by extension, the community to pass on intergenerational wealth.&nbsp; These are some of the things we&#8217;ve been taking on, but there&#8217;s so much more to do.<br><br>And so, I&#8217;m here to ask you to help us with this because there is so much at stake.<br><br>You look at states like Georgia, like Texas.&nbsp; You look at what some of these folks in North Carolina are doing and South Carolina are doing to do to attack the right of people to vote.&nbsp; And you know why they&#8217;re doing it?&nbsp; You can see a direct link between what Omega Psi Phi and so many others did to increase the voter turnout, which was record highs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and the backlash &#8212; the backlash &#8212; because they saw folks, who weren’t turning up before, turned out.&nbsp; And then all of a sudden, after the election, among those who were denying and lying, frankly &#8212; excuse my word &#8212; but lying about who won the election. &nbsp;By the way, we won.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But then they decided, well, maybe a way to do it is to pass laws that &#8212; for example, now in Georgia &#8212; make it illegal to give folks food and water if they&#8217;re standing in line to vote.&nbsp; Passing laws to make it more difficult to vote around trying to get rid of drop boxes.&nbsp; Why do we need drop boxes?&nbsp; Well, if you are a single father or a single mother and you got them three kids back &#8212; bad kids in the backseat &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and you know you want to go vote, you know you can’t get out and stand in line to vote and wait for four hours.&nbsp; But you can pack them kids in the backseat after &#8212; the night before &#8212; you filled out your ballot, and then drive over to the drop box, drop it off, and keep driving.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>And these are the kinds of things, the details that matter about what we are up against.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I&#8217;m here to thank you and to ask you that we continue to educate &#8212; as is the history of this so important fraternity &#8212; to always educate the people about what is at stake, and to inspire through the model of your success and leadership, to inspire people to see what is possible, and to also remember who we are, who we have been, and who we’re going to be.&nbsp; Because that is who this organization is.&nbsp;<br><br>And one last point that I&#8217;d like to raise is the issue of choice, because I need your help &#8212; and I&#8217;m just having a candid conversation here &#8212; about how we are going to talk with our young men.&nbsp; Because I think it is very important that we not leave our young men out of any conversation that is of national importance.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think it&#8217;s important to also recognize and agree that one does not have to abandon their faith or their beliefs to agree that a woman, and not her government, should make decisions about her own body.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So it may not be your choice, it may not be the choice for your family, but the government shouldn&#8217;t be in the business of making that decision for her.<br><br>And I &#8212; and I &#8212; I&#8217;m here to ask for your help, because it is about our sisters and our daughters and our mothers and our aunties.&nbsp; It is about seeing that, also on the issue of maternal health &#8212; it&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve been working on for years &#8212; the issue of Black maternal mortality is real, which is that Black women are still, in this country, three times more likely than other women to die from pregnancy-related issues.&nbsp; A lot of it which has to do with an ilabi- &#8212; inability to have access to the kind of care she needs.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, when we think about how Black women are experiencing the healthcare system in America, we know it&#8217;s an issue for all of us.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something that we should weigh in to address.<br><br>Not to mention &#8212; you know, my goddaughter is 17 right now, and she&#8217;s applying to college.&nbsp; And she knows she’s pledging AKA wherever she goes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; With all due respect to everybody else.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but she’s &#8212; she was &#8212; I was talking to her the other day, and she was like, “Auntie, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I got to now look at which states I’m looking at in terms of where I’m going to apply for college.”&nbsp; That’s real.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>So I would ask us to think &#8212; because I would like your help, in terms of &#8212; on my &#8212; at my stage and my platform.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s make sure that we&#8217;re not leaving anyone out of this important conversation, because it is front and center as a very real issue in our country.&nbsp;<br><br>And I can&#8217;t emphasize it more than sharing with you my experience as Vice President, which is: I&#8217;ve been traveling around the world.&nbsp; I just was just yesterday, or it was the day before, with the &#8212; President Zelenskyy’s wife, Madam Zelenska.&nbsp; I met him two days before the invasion of his nation when I was in Munich giving an important talk there about the integrity of what should be a global priority around sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp;<br><br>But what I can tell you is this: I&#8217;ve probably talked to &#8212; I&#8217;ve had at least 80 conversations in person or by phone with presidents, prime ministers, and kings, some of whom I’ve hosted at the official residence of the Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>We, as Americans, hold ourselves out to be a leader.&nbsp; We walk into these rooms, chin up, shoulders back, proud &#8212; openly proud of the fact that we hail from a democracy, one of the greatest in the world &#8212; flawed though it may be, imperfect though it may be.&nbsp;<br><br>And people around the world watch us because we are a role model.&nbsp; And each of us knows what that&#8217;s like in our personal lives to be a role model. &nbsp;It means people watch everything you do to see if what you do is consistent with what you say.<br><br>And they’re right now seeing that the United States Supreme Court &#8212; the court of Thurgood &#8212; took a constitutional right, that had been recognized, from the people of America, the women of America.<br><br>So when we&#8217;re looking at an issue like this, when we&#8217;re looking at an issue like voting rights and what is happening in our country, let&#8217;s also understand it’s not only about an attack on the rights that we have been leaders on, but it is an attack on our democracy.&nbsp; And in that way, it also extends to an attack on our standing around the world when we walk into these various rooms talking about the need for protecting human rights and standing up for democratic principles or rule of law.&nbsp;<br><br>So we got a lot of work to do.&nbsp; And this fraternity has always been front and center on all of these issues.&nbsp; And so, again, I&#8217;m here to say thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Enjoy the Conclave.&nbsp;<br><br>And thank you, Dr. Marion, for inviting me to come by and speak with you for a minute.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with North Carolina State Legislators on Reproductive Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-north-carolina-state-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 22:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened more than 20 North Carolina state legislators, local leaders, and advocates who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights.  The Vice President convened state legislators from across the country on July 8, 2022 at the White House; on July 14, 2022 in Orlando, Florida; on July 16,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened more than 20 North Carolina state legislators, local leaders, and advocates who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights.  The Vice President convened state legislators from across the country on July 8, 2022 at the White House; on July 14, 2022 in Orlando, Florida; on July 16, 2022 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; and on July 18, 2022 in Atlantic City, New Jersey.<br> <br>During the meeting, the legislators, advocates, and providers in attendance discussed the importance of building a broad coalition to protect reproductive rights. The state legislators described how Republican leaders in North Carolina are pushing for extreme laws that would take away the right of women to make decisions about their own bodies. The Vice President thanked North Carolina Governor Roy Cooper for using every tool to protect access to reproductive health care, including a recent state executive order issued to protect patients seeking care from harassment and intimidation, and his veto of extreme legislative attacks on reproductive rights.<br> <br>The Vice President shared actions the Administration is taking on a national level in response to the Supreme Court overturning <em>Roe w. Wade</em>, including protecting access to abortion medication, defending the Constitutional right to travel, and addressing patient privacy. The Vice President encouraged the state legislators to keep defending the rights of women in North Carolina and said she looks forward to continuing to fight alongside them to protect the people of our nation.<br> <br><strong>Speakers:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Governor Roy Cooper, North Carolina Governor</li><li>Rep. Julie von Haefen, NC State Representative</li><li>Sen. Natalie Murdock, NC State Senator</li><li>Jenny Black, President and CEO, Planned Parenthood South Atlantic</li><li>Calla Hales, Co-owner and Executive Director, A Preferred Women’s Health Center</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By Vice President Harris In Roundtable Discussion With NC Legislators On Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-roundtable-discussion-with-nc-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 22:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carole Hoefener CenterCharlotte, North Carolina THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Governor Cooper.  And back at you.  (Laughter.)  Because we have &#8212; Roy Cooper and I stood shoulder-to-shoulder fighting for working people of America.  And I&#8217;ve seen him in rooms when there are no cameras and in rooms when the cameras are on, and he&#8217;s always&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Carole Hoefener Center<br><em>Charlotte, North Carolina</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Governor Cooper.  And back at you.  (Laughter.)  Because we have &#8212; Roy Cooper and I stood shoulder-to-shoulder fighting for working people of America.  And I&#8217;ve seen him in rooms when there are no cameras and in rooms when the cameras are on, and he&#8217;s always fighting for the people.<br> <br>So it is my honor and joy to join you yet again as we stand up for the principles that I think we, as Americans, hold dear.<br> <br>I will also mention what I don&#8217;t need to tell all the leaders here, who are not only state leaders but national leaders on so many issues: We got to make sure that Governor Cooper &#8212; who is right now the only line of defense in the state house, in terms of his veto power &#8212; that we ensure that we give him the support he needs in terms of the legislature so that he can continue to hold the line, as you have been.  And thank you for that.<br> <br>There are certain principles that are at stake on this issue and in this discussion.  And one of them is that every woman in America should be free to make decisions about her own body without government interference. <br> <br>And let&#8217;s be frank about this issue: As has been said, to stand for a woman&#8217;s right to make one of the most intimate decisions that she can make about her own life without government interference, to agree with the importance of her right and ability to do that does not require you to abandon your faith or your beliefs.  It&#8217;s to agree that she should be able to make that right without the government telling her what to do.<br> <br>That really is, as much as anything, what&#8217;s at stake here.  Every woman should be free to make that decision for herself and, if she chooses, in consultation with her loved one, with her physician, with her pastor, her priest, her rabbi.  But the government should not be making this decision for her. <br> <br>Ultimately, that is what this is about.  It&#8217;s about one of the most important principles upon which our nation was founded: freedom, liberty &#8212; freedom from government interference in the most intimate decisions that are essentially about heart and home.  Because when we look at what&#8217;s going on right now, let&#8217;s understand it is the issue of choice. <br> <br>But it is an interpretation of the right to privacy that &#8212; you know, Clarence Thomas said the quiet part out loud &#8212; puts at risk the right to make decisions about contraception, the right to make decisions about who you love in terms of same-sex marriage.  All of this is at stake. <br> <br>So, the United States Supreme Court took a constitutional right, that had been guaranteed and recognized, from the people of America &#8212; the women of America.  That is also what is at stake. <br> <br>And as Vice President, I have traveled the world.  I have talked with at least 80 prime ministers, presidents, kings around the globe.  And when we look at our highest court taking a constitutional right from the people of our country, we must understand what this also means in term of &#8212; in terms of what we stand for as a democracy, which has stated certain principles about the rights of individuals to be free from interference by their government.  So all of this is at stake. <br> <br>And we are looking at &#8212; in particular, after the Dobbs decision, but even before &#8212; extremist so-called leaders around the country who are daring to also pass laws that will not provide an exception for violent criminal acts like rape and incest. <br> <br>I spent the majority of my career as a prosecutor.  And during the time that I was working in courtrooms, a great deal of my focus was on crimes against women and children, including child sexual assault. <br> <br>And we have so-called leaders who are saying there is no exception for those violent acts, for that woman, for that person to be able to have agency over their own body after they have been a victim of such a heinous act.<br> <br>These are the issues that are at stake right now in our country.  This is what&#8217;s happening right now in our country. <br> <br>And so, yes, the President has signed an executive order to say that we, in terms of the federal government, will do what we must and what we can through the executive branch to protect a woman&#8217;s legal right, in terms of interstate travel, to protect access to medication. <br> <br>But we have three coequal branches of government.  The Court has acted now.  Now it is time for Congress to act and to codify the protections of Roe, which means to put it into law at a national level. <br> <br>And this is also going to require us to look to the leaders in the states to do what the leaders here in North Carolina, at this table and elsewhere, have been doing: to have the courage to stand up for the rights of women and the rights of the American people to make certain decisions for themselves. <br> <br>And so, I&#8217;m here to thank you all.  You are fighting on the frontlines, including our courageous service providers.  And we are in this together. <br> <br>I will emphasize again &#8212; you know, I asked my team to do a Venn diagram for me of where we are seeing attacks and who are the attacks against and the similarity.  And if you look at attacks on a woman&#8217;s right to choose, attacks against the LGBTQ community, attacks on voting rights &#8212; it&#8217;s very interesting to see a lot of them are coming from the same source. <br> <br>And so that&#8217;s also to say that let&#8217;s bring folks together, understanding that on this issue, as well as so many others, we all have so much more in common than what separates us, in terms of the need to stand up for these rights against those who have decided to attack them, and to do so fighting for the best of who we are as a country. <br> <br>And with that, I look forward to our discussion. <br> <br>And, again, I thank you.  I&#8217;m here to listen as much as I am to share with you my thoughts because, truly, we have extraordinary leaders here in this beautiful state. <br> <br>So with that, thank you all.  And I think we should begin our discussion. <br> <br>Okay, thank you.  (Applause.)<br> </p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By Vice President Harris On The Affordable Connectivity&#160;Program</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-affordable-connectivity-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 20:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carole Hoefener CenterCharlotte, North Carolina 1:32 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  All right!  Can we hear it for Ms. Tiffany?  (Applause.)  Well, good afternoon, Charlotte.  It’s so good to be back.  Good afternoon.  You know, Ms. Tiffany and I were talking in the back, and I said, you know, “The President” &#8212; who I’m going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Carole Hoefener Center<br><em>Charlotte, North Carolina</em></em></p>



<p>1:32 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  All right!  Can we hear it for Ms. Tiffany?  (Applause.) <br> <br>Well, good afternoon, Charlotte.  It’s so good to be back.  Good afternoon.  You know, Ms. Tiffany and I were talking in the back, and I said, you know, “The President” &#8212; who I’m going to speak of in a moment &#8212; “The President &#8212; I talked to him this morning.  I told him I was on my way here.  And he said, ‘Tell everybody hello.’”  And he knew why I was here, which is to talk about what we are doing to connect folks to high-speed Internet. <br> <br>And the work that we’re going in Washington, D.C., the work that we are doing in terms of the policy work, it’s not real until it hits the streets.  It’s not real until real people have the ability to take advantage of what we hope will help them and uplift their lives.<br> <br>And the connectivity, if you will, between what we do in Washington, D.C., and it hitting the streets of Charlotte are people like Ms. Tiffany.  So she makes all the difference.  So, again, can we please applaud her?  (Applause.)  Please applaud her.<br> <br>And before I begin, I do &#8212; wanted to speak about our incredible President, Joe Biden.  This morning, he and I spoke by phone.  He is in good spirits.  He is feeling well.  He is doing well.  He is fully vaccinated and twice boosted.  And &#8212; of course, he is, and as everyone we &#8212; who would encourage, who was eligible, would do the same.  And he is working from the White House Residence.<br><br>And when we spoke, he was very pleased, as I said, that we were all here together today talking about the work our administration is doing on behalf of parents and working families and all who deserve to be seen and heard.<br> <br>So, with that, it is good to be with everyone today.  The great Governor Roy Cooper.  Where is Roy?  He was here earlier.  He’s been with me all at &#8212; he’s been with me all morning and met me on the tarmac. <br> <br>And I have to tell you, Roy Cooper is extraordinary, because there’s so much about we are doing that is about getting these resources to folks.  But we cannot do it if there’s not a governor in place who takes seriously the importance of the partnership to make sure that they don’t let anything get in the way of the services and resources getting to the people of the states.  So I really do thank Governor Roy Cooper for all that he has done.  And if we’d applaud him, please.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And Governor Cooper and I were most recently together at the White House highlighting the jobs that have been created under his leadership here in North Carolina through the American Rescue Plan.  So I thank him, of course, for all the action he has taken get folks online. <br> <br>I also want to recognize the leaders of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration for your work advancing our administration&#8217;s efforts to ensure Internet for all.  And thank you to all of the leaders who are here today, including, of course, the advocates and the organizers who have fought so long to connect our communities.<br> <br>So I will begin with a simple and obvious truth: In the 21st century, high-speed Internet is not a luxury, it is a necessity.  (Applause.)  It&#8217;s as basic as is what we have come to accept over generations: how electricity is a necessity.  Same point.<br> <br>Students use the Internet for so many reasons that are in pursuit of their education, including to attend virtual classes.  Workers use the Internet to find jobs and receive training.  Seniors use the Internet to see a doctor without leaving their home. <br> <br>For so many of us, the Internet is an essential part of our daily lives.  And yet, more than 30 million people in our country still do not have access to high-speed Internet.  Think about that.  It&#8217;s a lot of folks.  And millions more cannot afford the cost of a high-speed plan.<br> <br>Every person in our nation, no matter how much they earn, should be able to afford a high-speed Internet plan.<br> <br>So last year, our administration invested $65 billion through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to help connect every household in our country with affordable high-speed Internet and to lower monthly Internet bills for tens of Americans through an initiative that we&#8217;re here to talk about today called the Affordable Connectivity Program.<br> <br>So this program provides working families with up to $30 a month off of their Internet bill or $75 a month for those living on Tribal lands.  And it also gives families a one-time discount of up to $100 to purchase a laptop, a desktop computer, or a tablet &#8212; because an Internet connection is not much good if you don&#8217;t have a way to get online, if you don&#8217;t actually have the technology that allows you to take advantage of the service. <br> <br>So we have been working with Internet service providers to make sure they offer plans for $30 or less a month, which means the vast majority of households eligible for the Affordable Connectivity Program can receive high-speed Internet without paying a dime. <br> <br>So, if you are eligible, or even think you might be eligible &#8212; I’m going to give you a website; everybody get ready.  Write it on you smartphone or pull out a pen and paper.  Please visit &#8212; the website is GetInternet.gov.  GetInternet.gov.  And when you log on there, you can check to see if you qualify, you can find a plan, and you can sign up.<br> <br>The Affordable Connectivity Program has already done so much good.  Today, about 13 million people are enrolled.  And these are students who can now study at their kitchen table instead of in the parking lot of a local fast-food restaurant, which is what so many of our students did, especially during the height of the pandemic &#8212; because, you see, they would take advantage of the Internet accessibility from the fast-food restaurant by sitting in the parking lot.<br> <br>Think about it: The people who will benefit include parents who used to rely on their cell phone data plan to connect the whole family, which can be incredibly expensive.  And now, those families can stream and search and study on Wi-Fi for free.  This includes women who need access to healthcare. <br> <br>Because as many of you know, this is an issue that has been a priority of mine for a long time &#8212; the issue of maternal health.  And our nation is facing a maternal mortality crisis.<br> <br>In fact, Black women are three times as likely to die in our country from pregnancy-related causes.  Native American women are more than twice as likely to die.  Rural women &#8212; women who live in rural America &#8212; are one and a half times more likely to die.<br> <br>And think about it: For many of the women who live in rural communities, they also live in maternal care deserts, which means they lack access to health providers and facilities.<br> <br>But with high-speed Internet connection and through telehealth, these women can access lifesaving maternal care.<br> <br>Among the other 13 million people who have benefited from our program, there are also folks who are the entrepreneurs in our communities; folks who always wanted to start a business online and work from home but could never afford Internet access to do so until now.<br> <br>Here is what it comes down to: We created this program because we know when we connect folks with high-speed Internet, it is also a connection to opportunity &#8212; the opportunity to live a healthier, happier, and more prosperous life and, importantly, more affordable lives.<br> <br>Every month, the Affordable Connectivity Program saves working families over a quarter billion dollars, and it is important for so many reasons, incler- &#8212; including our larger fight to make sure that we do everything &#8212; and the President and I feel very strongly about this &#8212; to bring down the costs for lower &#8212; and lower the costs for working families.<br> <br>So, we expanded the Child Tax Credit, which lifted millions of children out of poverty last year.  And we passed a tax cut<br>to give parents up to $8,000 for childcare so they will have more room in their pockets to buy food and medication and school supplies for their children.  And we are fighting to pass legislation to lower the price of prescription drugs, and healthcare, and childcare, and so much more.<br> <br>Today we are in Charlotte because we need your help.  We know that when we hold events like this, more people sign up.  But it takes the support of leaders like you in this room to sustain that momentum.<br> <br>So, we need your help, and that’s why I’m here to ask you, like Ms. Tiffany &#8212; we’re going to look at her as a role model for this &#8212; to help us spread the word.  Think about it.  Talk to everybody who comes over for Sunday dinner, at Little League games, at work, at school, in your neighborhood.  Talk with folks about what is available to them that they may not otherwise know but can be a huge help for everything that is about their daily lives and obligations.<br> <br>And we need community and faith-based organizations to help people fill out their applications.  There is an application.  It’s not too detailed.  It’s not too complicated.  But folks might need an extra hand, so please offer to help them fill out the application as well.<br> <br>And we need state and local governments to drive enrollment every way they know how.  I know that Governor Cooper is already hard at work on this front.  The partnership between the leaders here today is essential.<br><br>So, again, I am here to ask you to help spread the word to let people know what is available to them.  And like Tiffany’s story, when we see people take advantage of it, we see so much good that is not only about that individual but truly is about their family and the community as a whole.<br> <br>So thank you, all of you, for all that you have done to help connect the people of our nation with a better future.  And I look forward to seeing you all again soon. <br>God bless you, and God bless the United States of America.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br> <br>END                 1:44 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-76/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 20:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=58026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Shailen P. Bhatt, of Michigan, to be Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, vice Nicole R. Nason. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Jeffrey Matthew Marootian, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy), vice Daniel Simmons. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Stephen A. Owens, of Arizona, to be Chairperson of the Chemical Safety&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Shailen P. Bhatt, of Michigan, to be Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, vice Nicole R. Nason.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jeffrey Matthew Marootian, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy), vice Daniel Simmons.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stephen A. Owens, of Arizona, to be Chairperson of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board for a term of five years, vice Katherine Andrea Lemos, resigning.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 19:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57996</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&#160; Shailen P. Bhatt, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation Jeff Marootian, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, U.S. Department of Energy Stephen A.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Shailen P. Bhatt, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation</li><li>Jeff Marootian, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, U.S. Department of Energy</li><li>Stephen A. Owens, Nominee for Chairman of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board</li></ul>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Shailen P. Bhatt, Nominee for Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, U.S. Department of Transportation</strong><br></span><br>Shailen Bhatt is Senior Vice President of Global Transportation Innovation and Alternative Delivery at AECOM, a multinational infrastructure consulting firm. Bhatt previously served as the Executive Director of the Colorado Department of Transportation, Cabinet Secretary of the Delaware Department of Transportation, and as a presidential appointee at the U.S. Department of Transportation. In these roles, Bhatt spearheaded innovative solutions, collaborations, and partnerships to support the delivery of safe, sustainable, and cost-effective transportation systems for the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century.&nbsp;He previously worked as the CEO of the Intelligent Transportation Society of America,&nbsp;Chair of the Board of Directors for the National Operations Center of Excellence (NOCoE), Chair of&nbsp;the Executive Committee of the I-95 Corridor Coalition, and was&nbsp;a member of the World Economic Forum’s Global Agenda Council on the Future of Automotive and Personal Transport.<br><br>Bhatt chairs an external advisory board for the United States Department&nbsp;of Energy, is a member of the Aurora Safety Advisory Board for autonomous driving,&nbsp;and is the Chair of the ITS World Congress Board of Directors.&nbsp;Bhatt is a proud husband and father to two daughters. He graduated summa cum laude from Western Kentucky University with a degree in Economics.&nbsp;<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Jeff Marootian, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, U.S. Department of Energy</strong><br></span><br>Jeff Marootian currently serves as a Special Assistant to the President in the White House Office of Presidential Personnel. Prior to his service in the Biden-Harris Administration, he was a member of the Biden-Harris Transition Team. Marootian previously served in Washington D.C government as the Director of the District Department of Transportation, where he piloted sustainable transportation technologies, oversaw the effort to electrify the city’s Circulator bus fleet, and led the city’s early adoption of the Transportation and Climate Initiative. Marootian oversaw the modernization of hundreds of miles of roads and sidewalks and advanced critical infrastructure projects, such as the reconstruction of the Frederick Douglass Memorial Bridge and expansion of dedicated bus and bike lanes.<br><br>Marootian previously served in the Obama-Biden Administration as the Assistant Secretary for Administration and Chief Sustainability Officer at the U.S. Department of Transportation. He is an alumnus of The George Washington University where he has also taught as an adjunct faculty member in the Trachtenberg School of Public Policy and Administration.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Stephen A. Owens, Nominee for Chairman of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board</strong><br></span><br>Steve Owens is a member of the U.S. Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board (CSB), appointed by President Biden and confirmed by the U.S. Senate in December 2021. Since being sworn in, Owens has worked to increase transparency and information-sharing by the CSB, identify ways to reduce the backlog in the CSB’s investigative reports, and increase collaboration and communications between agency leadership and CSB career professional staff and stakeholders.&nbsp;Prior to joining the CSB, he was an attorney in Phoenix, Arizona, focusing on environmental, safety, and health issues, and also advising clients on a range of matters relating to chemical safety and safe chemical practices.&nbsp;Owens previously served as the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency’s (EPA) Assistant Administrator for the Office of Chemical Safety and Pollution Prevention, where he was responsible for overseeing EPA’s chemical regulatory programs. He also previously served as Counsel to the Subcommittee on Investigations and Oversight of the U.S. House Committee on Science and Technology, and Chief Counsel and later State Director for then-U.S. Senator Al Gore (D-TN).<br><br>Before serving at EPA, Owens was Director of the Arizona Department of Environmental Quality (ADEQ).&nbsp;As ADEQ Director, Owens oversaw the department’s policies and regulations relating to chemical safety and hazardous substances, including responding to chemical hazards and other emergency situations.&nbsp;He graduated with honors from Brown University and received his law degree in from Vanderbilt Law School, where he was Editor-in-Chief of the Vanderbilt Law Review.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Launches Effort to Create More Affordable and Equitable Outdoor Recreation&#160;Opportunities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-effort-to-create-more-affordable-and-equitable-outdoor-recreation-opportunities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 15:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As part of the President’s America the Beautiful Initiative, the Biden-Harris Administration today launched an interagency effort, called the Federal Interagency Council on Outdoor Recreation (FICOR), that will work to create more safe, affordable, and equitable opportunities for Americans to get outdoors. The FICOR – which includes leaders from the Departments of the Interior, Agriculture,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As part of the President’s America the Beautiful Initiative, the Biden-Harris Administration today launched an interagency effort, called the Federal Interagency Council on Outdoor Recreation (FICOR), that will work to create more safe, affordable, and equitable opportunities for Americans to get outdoors.</p>



<p>The FICOR – which includes leaders from the Departments of the Interior, Agriculture, Commerce, and Defense – will focus on improving access to nature, expanding outdoor recreation opportunities, and providing the public with improved and more affordable experiences on America’s public lands and waters.</p>



<p>Increasing access to outdoor recreation is one of the six areas of focus outlined in President Biden’s America the Beautiful Initiative. The FICOR will help coordinate policies, facilitate partnerships, and improve implementation on issues such as: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Investing in resilient recreation infrastructure, such as electric vehicle charging stations, trails, campgrounds, visitor centers, docks, and boating access;</li><li>Bolstering education and career opportunities in conservation, outdoor recreation, habitat restoration, and resource management work, and &nbsp;providing comprehensive visitor information for the hunting, fishing, hiking, biking, birding, climbing, and boating communities;</li><li>Cooperating with State, Tribal, territorial, and local governments, including those in communities near Federal lands and waters; and</li><li>Improving equitable access to Federal lands and waters and creating a welcoming visitor experience in collaboration with private, public, Tribal, and nonprofit organizations.</li></ul>



<p>The launch of the FICOR renews and re-energizes a body that was originally created in 2011 but was suspended by the previous administration. Prior to being suspended, the FICOR successfully launched <a href="https://www.recreation.gov/">recreation.gov</a>, helped the <a href="https://www.bea.gov/news/2021/outdoor-recreation-satellite-account-us-and-states-2020">Bureau of Economic Analysis</a> begin tracking outdoor recreation as an economic sector, and worked to establish the <a href="https://www.everykidoutdoors.gov/pass.htm"><em>Every Kid </em><em>Outdoors</em><em> Pass</em></a>.</p>



<p>With outdoor recreation continuing to grow rapidly as an economic sector, including by contributing <a href="https://www.bea.gov/news/2021/outdoor-recreation-satellite-account-us-and-states-2020">1.8 percent of GDP and generating $374.3 billion</a> in economic output, and America&#8217;s parks and public lands experiencing record-level visitation, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking unprecedented steps to expand equitable access to the outdoors and to protect natural, cultural, and historic resources.</p>



<p>In addition to launching the FICOR, the Administration has:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Launched historic investments through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law in the restoration of Federal lands and waters, including by improving availability of and equitable access to outdoor recreation opportunities</strong>.<ul><li>Commerce Secretary Gina M. Raimondo announced funding opportunities from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration’s (NOAA) $2.96 billion in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds to address the climate crisis and strengthen coastal resilience and infrastructure. Over the next five years, NOAA’s targeted investments in the areas of habitat restoration, coastal resilience, and climate data and services will advance ongoing Federal efforts toward building climate resilience. Projects focused on building “Climate Ready Coasts” will invest in natural infrastructure projects that power outdoor recreation along our coasts by restoring coastal habitats, removing marine debris, storing carbon, and creating jobs.</li></ul><ul><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2022/04/11/biden-harris-administration-launches-1-billion-america-the-beautiful-challenge-to-support-and-accelerate-locally-led-conservation-and-restoration-projects/">Established the America the Beautiful Challenge</a>, a $1 billion public-private competitive grant program which funds locally led, voluntary conservation and restoration activities, including the development of outdoor recreation access and workforce development. The <a href="https://www.nfwf.org/programs/america-beautiful-challenge">first round of grants</a> – totaling $85 million – will be released in November 2022.</li></ul><ul><li>The Interior Department announced more than $61 million in grant funding to communities in 26 cities to create new parks and trails, or substantial renovations to existing parks, through the <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-announces-61-million-increase-outdoor-access-urban-spaces">Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership</a> program. The program, established in 2014 and supported by the Land and Water Conservation Fund, enables urban communities to create new outdoor recreation spaces, reinvigorate existing parks, and form connections between people and the outdoors in economically underserved communities.</li></ul><ul><li>As the largest Federal provider of water-based outdoor recreation in America, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE) is investing $120 million from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the Disaster Relief Supplemental Appropriations Act of 2022 to improve recreation facilities across the nation. These investments will promote equitable access to outdoor recreation opportunities and support local communities. USACE recreation areas had 268 million visits in the last fiscal year, resulting in spending that supports approximately 217,000 jobs and generates nearly $14.5 billion for local economies.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Expanded hunting and sport fishing opportunities on National Wildlife Refuge System lands and waters.</strong><ul><li>The U.S. Department of the Interior <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-largest-expansion-fishing-and-hunting-us-fish-and">expanded hunting and fishing access on 2.1 million acres of National Wildlife Refuge System</a> lands and waters in 2021, the largest expansion of outdoor recreation opportunities in recent history. The Department is continuing to explore opportunities to provide additional access to refuge system lands. Hunting, fishing, and other outdoor activities contributed more than $156 billion in economic activity in communities across the United States in 2016, according to the Service’s National Survey of Fishing, Hunting, and Wildlife-Associated Recreation, published every five years. More than 101 million Americans — 40 percent of the U.S. population age 16 and older — pursue wildlife-related recreation, including hunting and fishing.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Focused acquisitions and improvements of Federal lands and waters under the Great American Outdoors Act (GAOA) of 2020, which passed with overwhelming bipartisan support.</strong><ul><li>The U.S. Department of Agriculture <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/06/06/usda-announces-503-million-improve-outdoor-recreation-and">announced more than $503 million in funding</a> for National Forests and Grasslands. The funds will go to projects to address deferred maintenance and improve campgrounds, trails, and facilities on National Forests. Funds will also be spent on land acquisition to expand recreation opportunities for visitors and strengthen resource protection partnerships with State agencies and private organizations.</li></ul><ul><li>The Department of the Interior <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/department-interior-announces-279-million-support-public-parks-expand-outdoor">announced $279 million</a> to support Federal lands and waters and expand outdoor recreation access utilizing the Land and Water Conservation Fund (LWCF) to all 50 states, U.S. territories, and the District of Columbia for state-identified outdoor recreation and resource protection projects.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Expanded outdoor recreation opportunities by protecting areas for future generations.</strong><ul><li>In celebration of National Trails Day, Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-promotes-outdoor-recreation-designates-ten-new-national-recreation">announced the designation of nine new National Recreation Trails</a> in seven states, adding nearly 600 miles to the National Trails System.</li></ul><ul><li>Secretary Deb Haaland <a href="https://www.fws.gov/press-release/2022-07/secretary-haaland-announces-lost-trail-conservation-area-montana">announced the establishment of the Lost Trail Conservation Area</a> in Northwest Montana as the 568th and newest unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System, managed by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service. This expansion – the first new unit in the Refuge System for the Biden-Harris Administration – is the culmination of a 20-year, locally-led effort to conserve important big game corridors and recreational areas in the region. The Service worked in partnership with the Trust for Public Land and the Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes (CSKT) to purchase the 38,052-acre conservation easement from its continuing owner, Southern Pine Plantations.</li></ul><ul><li>The Bureau of Land Management, the U.S Department of Agriculture&#8217;s Forest Service, and the five Tribes of the Bears Ears Commission <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/blm-forest-service-and-five-tribes-bears-ears-commission-commit-historic-co-management">formalized their partnership</a> for co-management of the Bears Ears National Monument. The Hopi Tribe, Navajo Nation, Ute Mountain Ute Tribe, Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation, and the Pueblo of Zuni will be joint managers of the National Monument and will receive resources from Federal agencies to participate in and take leadership on the management of their ancestral lands.</li></ul><ul><li>The USDA Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/06/23/usda-forest-service-announces-plans-open-comments-rainy-river">are considering</a> a 20-year withdrawal of 225,000 acres of U.S. Forest System lands in Minnesota to protect the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness – the most visited wilderness area in the country. The Rainy River watershed flows north toward the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness and Voyageurs National Park, landscapes renowned for high-quality fishing, wildlife viewing, and recreational opportunities due to the large number of interconnected lakes and pristine water quality. The proposed mineral withdrawal aims to prevent further negative environmental impacts from future mining operations. It also evaluates the impacts of future mining on important social, cultural, and economic values.</li></ul><ul><li>On World Oceans Day, NOAA Administrator Rick Spinrad announced NOAA’s initiation of the designation process for a new national marine sanctuary <a href="https://sanctuaries.noaa.gov/hudson-canyon/">to conserve Hudson Canyon</a> in the Atlantic Ocean. A sanctuary designation would help conserve the area’s rich marine wildlife and habitats, and promote scientific research, ocean education, and recreation opportunities such as whale watching, recreational fishing, and boating.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Created workforce development opportunities with the establishment of an Indian Youth Service Corps Program.</strong><ul><li>The Biden-Harris Administration announced the launch of the <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-launches-new-indian-youth-service-corps-program">Indian Youth Service Corps Program</a>, which will provide meaningful education, employment, and training opportunities to Indigenous youth through conservation projects on Federal and Indian lands – thereby putting young people on a path to good-paying jobs while helping to address the climate crisis.</li></ul></li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Transnational Criminal&#160;Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/21/message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-transnational-criminal-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 15:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57991</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#160;emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&nbsp;emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date. &nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations that was declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13581 of July&nbsp;24, 2011, under which additional steps were&nbsp;taken in Executive Order 13863 of March 15, 2019, is&nbsp;to&nbsp;continue in effect beyond July 24, 2022.</p>



<p>The activities of significant transnational criminal organizations have&nbsp;reached such scope and gravity that they threaten the stability of international political and economic systems. &nbsp;Such&nbsp;organizations are becoming increasingly sophisticated and dangerous to the United States; they are increasingly entrenched in the operations of foreign governments and the international financial system, thereby weakening democratic institutions, degrading the rule of law, and undermining economic markets. &nbsp;These organizations facilitate and aggravate violent civil conflicts and increasingly facilitate the activities of other dangerous persons.</p>



<p>Significant transnational criminal organizations continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States. &nbsp;Therefore, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency with respect to&nbsp;significant transnational criminal organizations declared in&nbsp;Executive Order 13581.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">    July 21, 2022 </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Transnational Criminal&#160;Organizations.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/21/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-transnational-criminal-organizations-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 15:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 24, 2011, by Executive Order 13581, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by significant transnational criminal organizations. On March&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 24, 2011, by Executive Order 13581, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by significant transnational criminal organizations.</p>



<p>On March 15, 2019, by Executive Order 13863, the President took additional steps to deal with the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations in view of the evolution of these organizations as well as the increasing sophistication of their activities, which threaten international political and economic systems and pose a direct threat to the safety and welfare of the United States and its citizens, and given the ability of these organizations to derive revenue through widespread illegal conduct, including acts of violence and abuse that exhibit a wanton disregard for human life as well as many other crimes enriching and empowering these organizations.</p>



<p>Significant transnational criminal organizations continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.  For these reasons, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13581 on July 24, 2011, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13863 on March 15, 2019, must continue in effect beyond July 24, 2022.  Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations declared in Executive Order 13581.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal&nbsp;Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 21, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
