<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:20:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The American Jobs Plan Will Produce, Preserve, and Retrofit More Than 2 Million Affordable Housing Units and Create Good-Paying Jobs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/26/fact-sheet-the-american-jobs-plan-will-produce-preserve-and-retrofit-more-than-2-million-affordable-housing-units-and-create-good-paying-jobs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 13:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18443</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even after the COVID-19 pandemic, tens of millions of Americans will struggle to access affordable, safe, energy efficient, and resilient housing. Across the country, 11 million families pay more than half their income on rent, 3 million families with children under six reside in homes with lead paint, thousands of working families are displaced every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Even after the COVID-19 pandemic, tens of millions of Americans will struggle to access affordable, safe, energy efficient, and resilient housing. Across the country, 11 million families pay more than half their income on rent, 3 million families with children under six reside in homes with lead paint, thousands of working families are displaced every year as a result of extreme weather fueled by climate change, and millions of families cannot afford to purchase their own homes. These challenges are even more severe in low-income communities and communities of color, many of which have been segregated, excluded, and neglected for generations.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is proposing a bold investment in America’s housing infrastructure and make housing more affordable for working and middle-class families. The American Jobs Plan pairs $213 billion in direct funding with more than $100 billion in new and expanded tax credits with bipartisan support to build and modernize housing across the country. Together with new incentives for zoning reform, these investments will produce, preserve, and retrofit more than two million affordable and sustainable places to live in more – and higher opportunity – communities. This includes more than 500,000 new and rehabilitated homes for low- and moderate-income homebuyers and homeowners.<br><br>Along the way, these investments would create and sustain hundreds of thousands of good-paying jobs – the majority of which won’t require a college degree – with a free and fair choice to join a union and bargain collectively. As President Biden has said, we need a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild our economy and ensure that all Americans have the opportunity to share in its prosperity. These investments will ensure local community members, including workers of color, can fill these jobs, and they will provide employment and economic opportunities for residents of assisted housing. Stable, affordable housing serves as the foundation on which working families build their lives and invest in their children’s future. The American Jobs Plan would:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Create good, middle-class jobs for local community members. </strong>The housing investments in the American Jobs Plan will create tens of thousands of good jobs, with a free and fair choice to join a union, for workers around the country as they build, upgrade, and retrofit homes in their communities. Employers will be required to pay workers prevailing wages; enter into project labor, community workforce, and local hire agreements; and use workers from registered apprenticeships and other labor or labor-management training programs. Employers receiving funding would also be required to remain neutral when their employees seek to organize a union and bargain collectively and may not require their employees to agree to mandatory individual arbitration. And, the American Jobs Plan includes $10 billion to provide federal enforcement agencies with the tools they need to ensure employers are providing workers with good jobs – &nbsp;including jobs with fair and equal pay, safe and healthy workplaces, and workplaces free from racial, gender, and other forms of discrimination and harassment.<br></li><li><strong>Expand access to federal subsidies that will enable the construction or rehabilitation of more than 1 million </strong><strong>affordable rental&nbsp;housing units</strong>. In addition to expanding LIHTC, President Biden’s American Jobs Plan would bolster funding for successful housing subsidy programs that pair with LIHTC to produce and preserve housing that is affordable for very- and extremely-low income renters. This includes a $35 billion investment in the HOME Investment Partnerships program, $45 billion for the Housing Trust Fund, and $12 billion for the Capital Magnet Fund. The President is also proposing authorizing $2 billion in new project-based rental assistance agreements for the first time in more than 20 years to help even more working families access affordable housing. Together, these investments will produce, preserve, and retrofit more than a million affordable, rental&nbsp;housing units in big cities and small towns across the country.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Build and rehabilitate more than 500,000 homes for low- and middle-income homebuyers and homeowners</strong>. Across the country, millions of homes sit empty and in poor condition with values too low to support new construction or substantial renovation. To address this problem, the American Jobs Plan proposes creating a new federal tax credit, based on the innovative, bipartisan Neighborhood Homes Investment Act. The tax credit will make homeownership and wealth-building possible for low- and moderate-income families by encouraging the construction and rehabilitation of homes in and for underserved communities.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Expand and strengthen the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit. </strong>Financing the construction or rehabilitation of affordable rental housing for low-income households is challenging. The Low-Income Housing Tax Credit (LIHTC) reduces financing barriers by offering federal income tax credits to private investors in exchange for equity investments in affordable rental housing. &nbsp;As the federal government’s primary tool for financing affordable housing, LIHTC currently produces an estimated 100,000 units per year. President Biden’s plan will build on this success by proposing to invest an additional $55 billion in tax credits, enabling the creation of tens of thousands more units each year, including more units in high opportunity neighborhoods.<br></li><li><strong>Expand access to federal subsidies that will enable the construction or rehabilitation of more than 1 million </strong><strong>affordable rental&nbsp;housing units</strong>. In addition to expanding LIHTC, President Biden’s American Jobs Plan would bolster funding for successful housing subsidy programs that pair with LIHTC to produce and preserve housing that is affordable for very- and extremely-low income renters. This includes a $35 billion investment in the HOME Investment Partnerships program, $45 billion for the Housing Trust Fund, and $12 billion for the Capital Magnet Fund. The President is also proposing authorizing $2 billion in new project-based rental assistance agreements for the first time in more than 20 years to help even more working families access affordable housing. Together, these investments will produce, preserve, and retrofit more than a million affordable, rental&nbsp;housing units in big cities and small towns across the country.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Address longstanding public housing capital needs. </strong>Nearly two million people across the country live in public housing—families with children, older Americans, and people with disabilities. Like roads, schools, and power grids, public housing is critical infrastructure that directly impacts the health and viability of our communities. Yet nearly half of the nearly 1 million units of public housing are over 50 years old and many contain lead paint, mold, and other health hazards. The American Jobs Plan calls for a transformative investment of $40 billion to rehabilitate and preserve public housing, addressing residents’ critical health and safety concerns. This is not just a safety issue but a racial justice issue, as approximately three in four public housing residents are people of color.<br></li><li><strong>Remove lead-based paint from homes.</strong> Over three million homes with children under six years of age have lead-based paint hazards, including more than 1 million low-income households. The American Jobs Plan proposes a $3 billion investment to fund the inspection and removal of lead-based paint from 175,000 housing units.<br></li><li><strong>Incentivize the removal of exclusionary zoning and harmful land use policies. </strong>For decades, exclusionary zoning laws – like minimum lot sizes, mandatory parking requirements, and prohibitions on multifamily housing – have inflated housing and construction costs and locked families out of areas with more opportunities. President Biden’s plan seeks to help jurisdictions reduce barriers to producing affordable housing and expand housing choices for people with low or moderate incomes. The American Jobs Plan will create a $5 billion incentive program that awards flexible and attractive funding to jurisdictions that take concrete steps to reduce barriers to affordable housing production.<br></li><li><strong>Support and sustain homeownership and renting opportunities in rural America.</strong>&nbsp;Rural communities face unique housing needs that are not always fulfilled by traditional federal housing programs. The American Jobs Plan proposes investing $2 billion to build and rehabilitate housing across rural America. This includes additional Section 502 loans that would enable thousands of low-income individuals in federally declared disaster areas to use funds for new construction of single-family homes. The plan would also provide new resources through Section 504 to enable existing low-income rural homeowners to make energy efficiency improvements to their homes. And, this proposal would support the construction and rehabilitation of thousands of multifamily units, including units that would provide affordable, sustainable housing to farmworkers and their families.<br></li><li><strong>Develop and operate affordable housing for older Americans.</strong> More than half of renters over the age of 65 are cost-burdened, meaning they spend more than 30 percent of their income on housing expenses. The American Jobs Plan would invest $2 billion in HUD&#8217;s Section 202 program, increasing the supply of affordable housing with supportive services for very low-income older Americans.<br></li><li><strong>Meet tribal communities’ housing needs</strong>. Tribal communities face outsized housing shortages and a dire need for infrastructure. The American Jobs Plan will invest $2 billion to expand the development and rehabilitation of affordable housing, build supportive infrastructure, and spur green, climate resilient community development in Indian Country.<br></li><li><strong>Create more climate-resilient communities. </strong>Every year, thousands of American families are displaced in the wake of extreme weather events fueled by climate change. The Biden-Harris Administration has proposed a more than $2 billion investment for a new Community Development Block Grant Program for resilience activities in communities vulnerable to climate change. HUD would target funding to low- and moderate-income areas with increased risk from climate related disasters..<br></li><li><strong>Make housing more</strong> <strong>energy efficient and resilient for millions of families.</strong> Millions of single-family and multifamily housing were built decades ago and are less energy efficient and resilient than modern technologies and practices allow. The American Jobs Plan would seek to address this problem through a historic investment in building upgrades. This includes an $17.5 billion investment in the Department of Energy’s Weatherization Assistance program and $500 million in grants and low-interest loans to help renovate multifamily homes. The American Jobs Plan also proposes a new, $10 billion consumer electrification rebate program modeled on the bipartisan HOPE for HOMES Act. And, the American Jobs Plan would extend and expand existing home efficiency tax credits for working families. These investments will make housing more energy and water efficient and more resilient to extreme weather events, creating jobs, improving public health, and saving families money along the way.<br></li><li><strong>Build affordable housing and supportive infrastructure in small towns all across America. </strong>Many of America’s small towns face shortages of affordable housing for households experiencing poverty and for lower-wage workers. The American Jobs Plan would devote $250 million towards a new Main Street Revitalization Program that would provide grants to communities for renovating their downtown business districts and adding units of affordable housing while, retaining the area’s traditional and historic character.<br></li><li><strong>Revitalize the physical assets that build community connectedness and spark innovation. </strong>Across the country, too many low-income communities and communities of color have suffered from years of disinvestment. The American Jobs Plan proposes investing $10 billion to support community-led redevelopment projects that create innovative shared amenities, spark new economic activity, provide services, build community wealth, and strengthen social cohesion.&nbsp; The proposed Community Revitalization Fund would support a wide range of transformational places to work and gather, including but not limited to: upgrading access to natural areas, restoring vacant buildings to provide low-cost space for services and community entrepreneurs, and removing toxic waste and building new parks, greenways, and community gardens.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/05/25/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-39/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  1:34 P.M. EDT ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&#160; Good afternoon, and thank you for joining us.&#160; Today, one of my goals is to avoid embarrassment, and therefore, I will focus my remarks squarely on the serious business of the progress of vaccinating the country.&#160; So I begin by talking about VAX-a-Million.&#160; Ohio Governor Mike DeWine&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference </p>



<p>1:34 P.M. EDT<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, and thank you for joining us.&nbsp; Today, one of my goals is to avoid embarrassment, and therefore, I will focus my remarks squarely on the serious business of the progress of vaccinating the country.&nbsp;<br><br>So I begin by talking about VAX-a-Million.&nbsp; Ohio Governor Mike DeWine has unlocked a secret: People do care about getting vaccinated, but it turns out they also have other things they care about.&nbsp; Some of those things might encourage people to think about what might otherwise be a lower priority.&nbsp; So, every week for the next five weeks, one Ohioan will win $1 million.&nbsp; The only way to win is to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Vaccines &#8212; patriotic, free, good for your social life, and a chance to win.<br><br>In the days after Ohio announced the program, the state saw a 55 percent increase in its vaccination rate among younger adults 20 to 49 years of age.&nbsp; In several counties, the rate of vaccination doubled compared to before the announcement.&nbsp; In other words, the program is working.&nbsp; Since then, we&#8217;ve seen more states, including Maryland, New York, and Oregon announce similar programs.&nbsp; We are nothing if not responsive to good ideas.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, the Treasury Department issued new guidance on these programs, providing additional information on how federal funds in the American Rescue Plan can be used for vaccine incentive programs.&nbsp;<br><br>And the bottom line is: With this guidance, we encourage states to use their creativity to draw attention to vaccines and to get their states and the country back to normal as quickly as possible.&nbsp; This includes lottery programs for vaccinated individuals &#8212; cash or in-kind transfers or other monetary incentives &#8212; for individuals to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Dozens of businesses and organizations have also responded to the President&#8217;s call to action to volunteer their services and help the American people get vaccinated.&nbsp; For example, yesterday, United Airlines announced that every day in the month of June, they&#8217;re giving away two round-trip, first-class tickets to anywhere in the world if you are vaccinated, and they will give away five sets of round-trip tickets to travel anywhere in the world for an entire year.&nbsp; The only way to qualify is to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>So people may say all of this is frivolous.&nbsp; I say: Anything that ends the pandemic, it&#8217;s time for us to pull out now.&nbsp;<br><br>For those on the fence, find whatever reason you want to get vaccinated.&nbsp; For those not sure yet, do your homework.&nbsp; Talk to your doctor or your pharmacist.&nbsp; All concerns are reasonable, but do yourself a favor: Don&#8217;t let some guy on Facebook answer your question when good answers are available.<br><br>Today, the U.S. will hit 50 percent of adult Americans that are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; This is a major milestone in our country&#8217;s vaccination efforts.&nbsp; The number was 1 percent when we entered office January 20th.&nbsp;<br><br>Across the country, 25 states and the District of Columbia have fully vaccinated 50 percent or more of their adult population, and 9 states have recently crossed the threshold of 70 percent of adults with at least one shot.&nbsp; I really do want to applaud all of the good work and applaud all the people in those states.&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, the progress that we&#8217;ve made &#8212; we&#8217;ve reduced suffering across the country &#8212; is due to all of you who have gotten vaccinated; who&#8217;ve contributed not only to your health, but to mine and my family’s and my friends and yours, and the health of people who can&#8217;t get vaccinated because of their medical condition.&nbsp; You’ve contributed to our country.&nbsp;<br><br>You might be seeing all the positive news around you &#8212; cases down, deaths down, friends safely shedding their masks, businesses reopening &#8212; and think you&#8217;re in the clear.&nbsp;<br><br>But we have a couple of messages: We have more work to do to meet the President&#8217;s goal of 70 percent of adult Americans with one shot by July 4th, and, unless you&#8217;re vaccinated, you are at risk.&nbsp; When the virus looks for a place to spread and it doesn&#8217;t spread to a vaccinated person, it will look for you.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I hope you&#8217;ll go to Vaccines.gov or text your ZIP Code to 438829 or walk into one of the more than 20,000 locations where you don&#8217;t even need an appointment and get vaccinated today.&nbsp;<br><br>And with that, I will turn it over to Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Andy.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp;<br><br>We continue to see decreases in the COVID-19 cases nationwide.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is 22,877 cases per day.&nbsp; This represents yet another decrease of about 25 percent from the prior seven-day average and reflects seven contex- &#8212; consecutive days with our seven-day average below 30,000 cases a day.&nbsp; The seven-day average of hospital admissions is 3,080, a decrease of almost 17 percent from the prior seven-day period.&nbsp; And seven-day average daily deaths have also declined to two- &#8211;to 501 per day.&nbsp;<br><br>We are continuing to watch these data closely, and I remain cautious but hopeful they will continue to trend downward as vaccinations scales up.<br><br>This coming weekend is Memorial Day.&nbsp; I know that many of you are looking forward to spending time with your family and friends at picnics and bar (inaudible).&nbsp; Thanks to vaccines, tens of millions of Americans are able to get back to something closer to normal: visiting friends and family.&nbsp; These are the events we missed over the last year, and we are now safe (inaudible) when we are vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>This past weekend, I got to spent time outside with my family, and I was encouraged to see so many others outside and to see so many of their smiles, working to regain so much of what we have lost.&nbsp; All of this is possible because vaccinations are going up and cases and risk of community transmission across the country are going down.&nbsp;<br><br>Here are the important points to remember going into Memorial Day weekend: If you are vaccinated, you are protected and you can enjoy your Memorial Day.&nbsp; If you are not vaccinated, our guidance has not changed for you.&nbsp; You remain at risk of infection.&nbsp; You still need to mask and take other precautions.&nbsp; And if you are not vaccinated, I want to encourage you to take this holiday weekend to give yourself and your family the gift of protection by getting vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>We are on a good downward path, but we are not quite out of the woods yet.&nbsp; Cases, hospitalizations, and deaths are all declining because of the millions of people who have stepped forward and done their part to protect their health and the health of their communities to move us out of this pandemic.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s to the start of blue st- &#8212; skies and better days ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Please, everyone, enjoy a safe, happy, and vaccinated Memorial Day weekend.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; So let me just talk a little bit about the situation regarding how well we are doing in the care and the treatment of people with COVID-19.<br><br>As you can see from this chart, the case fatality rate of the ongoing pandemic has dramatically diminished over a period of about a year, such that we&#8217;re down to around 2 percent or so.&nbsp; This is due not only to being able to take care of people better in a non-pharmacological way, but also to be able to utilize some of the interventions that have been shown to be safe and effective.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>I spoke to this group previously about the NIH treatment guidelines panel, which is accessible on the website shown here:&nbsp; www.COVID19TreatmentGuidelines.NIH.gov.&nbsp; If you can&#8217;t remember that, just go NIH.gov and search for “treatment guidelines.”&nbsp;<br><br>The reason I show you this &#8212; and I know it&#8217;s very difficult to read the small print &#8212; is that we now have compartmentalized the disease severity and the most appropriate therapies from people not hospitalized to those hospitalized without severe disease; for those hospitalized requiring oxygenation; those hospitalized requiring delivery through high-flow devices; and those hospitalized requiring mechanical ventilation or “ECMO.”<br><br>I would like to have people realize that continuing going to this treatment guidelines panel website, literally on a daily basis, you can get a feel for what the latest data are in the treatment of individuals.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s an example.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Just about four days ago, it was posted, on this pre-print server, the results from a Regeneron trial using their combination cocktail monoclonal antibodies, which showed a rather substantial diminution in the risk of hospitalization or all-cause death compared to a placebo.&nbsp; This will immediately be on the treatment guidelines panel.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>I just want to also introduce you to something that we have been using at the NIH and with our collaborators.&nbsp; It’s called “ACTIV”, which is the Accelerating COVID-19 Therapeutic Interventions and Vaccines, which is a public-private partnership in which we&#8217;ve evaluated hundreds of potential therapeutic agents and prioritizing the most promising candidates to test in later clinical trials.<br><br>These protocols are coordinated and efficient evaluation of multiple investigational agents as they become available.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>And these are some of the ones that we have.&nbsp; There&#8217;s an ACTIV-1 trial on immunomodulators; ACTIV-2 on monoclonal antibodies; ACTIV-3 on monoclonal antibodies together with other therapies; ACTIV-4 with antithrombotics; and ACTIV-5, which we call the “BET,” or Big Effect Trial, aims to identify promising treatments for large trials; and, finally, repurposed drugs, which we’re always trying to see if we have a hit there.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>And, finally, just something I didn&#8217;t get a chance to mention to you when I spoke about vaccines and variants.&nbsp; A little bit off the current topic, but this is very important.&nbsp; Because Public Health England, just about three days ago, published that their clinical trial, looking at Pfizer-BioNTech and AstraZeneca, show that two weeks after the second dose, there was extremely good protection not only against the predominant variant B117, but also against 617.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the same thing I mentioned a couple of weeks ago: importance that when you look at vaccines, things get better and better.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll stop there and hand it over to Marcella.<br><br>DR. NUNEZ-SMITH:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Just great to be with you to provide a brief update on where we are with equity.&nbsp;<br><br>Last week when I joined, I shared the very encouraging equity trends that we&#8217;ve seen in the federal vaccination channels.&nbsp; The majority of those vaccine doses have been administered to people of color at the federally run mass vaccination centers, through the community health center partnership, and most recently, we see similar trends through the Federal Retail Pharmacy Program.<br><br>So, today, I want to speak briefly to the states, the Tribes, the territories, and to local jurisdictions: We all know equity is a team sport, and I just want to say thank you to all of you for centering equity in your vaccination campaigns and for the collaboration.&nbsp;<br><br>As we look at our national data now on race, ethnicity, it continues to suggest close to the majority of first-vaccine doses administered to adults in recent weeks are going to people of color.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve made substantial, significant progress in data collection and reporting: We&#8217;ve gone from 17 states reporting those variables in January to 48 states reporting them now.&nbsp;<br><br>And we also see that data completeness is improving: Race/ethnicity data in approximately 70 percent of administered doses in the country are now available, and that&#8217;s up from the low 50s previously.&nbsp; And so this is an important milestone.&nbsp; And as data quality continues to improve, we will have greater confidence as we use these data to guide and drive outreach, engagement, and resource investment.&nbsp;<br><br>We all have more work to do.&nbsp; We have to continue to ensure everyone who is at “yes” does not face barriers to vaccination &#8212; assisting with transportation; creating more walk-up opportunities; having flexible hours; making sure that vaccination menus are accessible; being clear that insurance is not required, vaccines are free &#8212; no one will have out-of- pocket costs; and being clear everyone is eligible regardless of documentation status; and partnering with employers so people have paid time off for vaccination; and, of course, always meeting people where they are.<br><br>So we must also recognize many groups have been hard hit by the pandemic.&nbsp; Equity metrics are not limited to race and ethnicity.&nbsp; We must be intentional about place, reaching rural frontier communities.&nbsp; We have to work to remedy data invisibility.&nbsp; The disability community, the LGBTQ-plus community &#8212; among others &#8212; are often hidden in our data.<br><br>Our role of race/ethnicity categories &#8212; such as Asian American; Native Ameri- &#8212; Native Hawaiian, Pacific Islander &#8212; mask subgroup differences and should be better desegregated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, at the White House, we&#8217;re continuing our stakeholder roundtables to make sure these voices are elevated and represented in order to better inform our work.&nbsp;<br><br>So across all of the partnerships &#8212; state, local, federal, clinical providers, community faith-based organizations, philanthropy &#8212; thank you for continuing to prioritize equity.&nbsp; We need everyone in this effort if we&#8217;re going to be successful.&nbsp; We will use every tool in our tool belt to position all of our communities for success so, together, we can ensure every community makes it to the other side of the pandemic and to our new normal.&nbsp; So, thank you.<br><br>With that, back to you, Andy.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Nunez-Smith.&nbsp; Kevin, let&#8217;s take a few questions.&nbsp; Here comes Kevin.&nbsp; One moment, please.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; I just was able to unmute.&nbsp; Thank you for taking the question.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re reporting that General Perna just told the governors, earlier today, that there are 53 million doses available to the states that have yet to be ordered in the federal supply.&nbsp; I want to ask if you have a response to that, and at what point you think you&#8217;ll be able to steal the &#8212; steer these doses elsewhere to other countries.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; This &#8212; the sound working?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right, all of our problems have been fixed now.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the question is to &#8212; how we were handling excess doses and global doses.&nbsp; The President announced, I believe it was two weeks ago, that we were going to be taking 20 million of the doses that were designated for distribution in the U.S. and adding them to the 60 million doses that we previously committed to distributing around the globe.&nbsp; So, by the end of June, we know that 80 million doses will be distributed across the globe.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also implemented an even tighter distribution system for vaccinations &#8212; for vaccines to states so to &#8212; to even more tightly manage the supply chain.&nbsp; So, we will be able to keep track of and be able to export additional vaccines to the extent that we have the capacity.<br><br>I will say that it is our first objective and prime hope that people in this country use the doses that we have all procured and that are &#8212; that are clearly our path to better health and to getting back to normal.&nbsp; And so we are going to work with states to use every single dose possible, as you heard Dr. Nunez-Smith talk about, making sure that we reach out to people as aggressively as possible where they are and get them vaccinated.<br><br>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith at NPR.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; I know that you expressed excitement about this coming Memorial Day weekend.&nbsp; Remembering a year ago &#8212; and there were so many concerns about whether it would be safe or whether it would lead to a bunch of super-spreader events &#8212; are you at all concerned that the, sort of, masks-off, life-is-back-to-normal reality is going to lead to unvaccinated people having super-spreader-type events?&nbsp; Are you worried cases could rise after Memorial Day?<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Thanks, Tamara.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?&nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; So we have seen &#8212; we have seen after holiday weekends in the past that cases have risen, but we&#8217;ve never been in a position where we&#8217;ve had almost ha- &#8212; half the adults of America vaccinated and protected from this virus.<br><br>Our guidance is very clear: If you are vaccinated, you are protected.&nbsp; And if you are unvaccinated, in the context of Memorial Day weekend, we are really encouraging you to adhere to our guidance for people who are unvaccinated, and, of course, to get vaccinated.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT: Next question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; We know that Moderna is going to be applying for an EUA for teens.&nbsp; What is the significance of this?&nbsp; And what does this mean for getting teens vaccinated by the school year?<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, would you like to take that?&nbsp; I don’t think he heard me.&nbsp;<br><br>So, let me &#8212; let me give an answer to that.&nbsp; It will be inferior to the answer Dr. Fauci would give me if he &#8212; if he heard me.&nbsp;<br><br>Yeah, they can’t hear.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp;&nbsp; You’ve &#8212; you’ve muted.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; They finally muted me.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Andy, you&#8217;re muted.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; I think we can hear you, Andy.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Can you hear me?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Now we can hear you.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, did you hear the question?&nbsp; The question was: the significance of the Moderna press release that they will have 12- to 18-year-old apply &#8212; that they&#8217;ll have an application in next month.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, certainly, that&#8217;s one of the things we would like to have, because if you put the Pfizer together &#8212; which already will be able to vaccinate and are vaccinating 12- to 15-year-olds &#8212; together with the recent data from Moderna, which likely would lead &#8212; as we enter into the beginning of the new fall term &#8212; that hopefully we&#8217;ll be able to get adolescent vaccine &#8212; I mean, high school students vaccinated actually before they enter the fall term, which is really very good news.<br><br>So, now we only &#8212; we have not only a single company, Pfizer, but it looks very much like we&#8217;ll have (inaudible) of another similar vaccine &#8212; an mRNA from Moderna.&nbsp; So, all good.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Shannon Pettypiece at NBC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; Hopefully neither two are going to take too much time.&nbsp; But, when will the first doses start being shipped overseas?&nbsp;<br><br>And also, on the booster: I know you don&#8217;t have an answer yet on whether or not we&#8217;ll need one, but could you give us a timeline on when you think we will know whether or not we will need one, and what the process looks like to coming to that decision about whether or not we&#8217;re going to need a booster?<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; So the President has committed that we will export 80 million doses before the end of June.&nbsp; We are currently awaiting FDA approval for the AstraZeneca doses.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s the only thing in our way.<br><br>Dr. Fauci, do you want to take the second question?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; (Inaudible), Andy.&nbsp; So, with regard to the boosters, as I&#8217;ve said many times, we do not know precisely when we will need to boost.&nbsp; There are two ways to determine that: One, is from a laboratory correlative-immunity way, and the other is from the clinical observation.&nbsp;<br><br>The correlative immunity is when you look at the level below which you lose a considerable amount of protection.&nbsp; You can follow cohorts of individuals &#8212; like we are doing with people who are involved in the original phase 1, 2-A, 2-B trials &#8212; and determine from them when they go below that level.&nbsp; That could be several months; that could be a year or more.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t know the answer to that.<br><br>But what we are doing &#8212; just to preemptively get to the point where we&#8217;ll be able to do it &#8212; is that there are a number of studies now looking at what the effect of the booster dose would be: namely, how high would you bring it up?&nbsp; At what level will you start?&nbsp; What is the differential between where you start and where the boost brings you?&nbsp;<br><br>So the bottom line: I&#8217;d like to give you a specific time and say, “X number of months,” but, quite frankly, we don&#8217;t know the answer to that right now.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re continuing to look so that we will be able to give you a definitive answer.&nbsp;<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; We have time for (inaudible) question before 2 &#8212; Ricardo at the AP.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, sorry about that &#8212; a little slow there with the mouse.&nbsp; Yeah, my question is for Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an issue that&#8217;s been coming back up again.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just curious to ask you, what is your latest thinking on the origins of the virus &#8212; whether it&#8217;s, as you like to say, “wild-type,” or if it&#8217;s something that could have escaped from a lab?&nbsp; I’m just curious what your latest thinking is on that.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve said many time: Many of us feel that it is more likely that this is a natural occurrence, as has happened with SARS-CoV-1, where it goes from an animal reservoir to a human.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t know 100 percent the answer to that.&nbsp;<br><br>And since this is a question that keeps being asked, we feel strongly &#8212; all of us &#8212; that we should continue with the investigation and go to the next phase of the investigation that the WHO has done.&nbsp;<br><br>So, because we don&#8217;t know 100 percent what the origin is, it&#8217;s imperative that we look and we do an investigation.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how we feel right now.&nbsp;<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Yeah, let me just close up by saying: It is our position that we need to get to the bottom of this, and we need a completely transparent process from China; we need the WHO to assist in that matter.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t feel like we have that now.&nbsp; We need to get to the bottom of this, whatever the answer may be, and that&#8217;s a critical priority for us.&nbsp;<br><br>So with that, I will thank you all for attending and hope you have a great rest of the day and rest of the week.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ll be doing this on Friday.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:00 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/COVID-Press-Briefing_25May2021_for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/COVID-Press-Briefing_25May2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, May 25, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/05/25/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-may-25-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:48 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Tuesday.&#160; So, I know the COVID briefing is at 1:30, so I&#8217;m going to try to get through as many people as possible between now and then.&#160; I just have one item at the top.&#160;&#160;After an update from our COVID-19 team&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:48 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Tuesday.&nbsp; So, I know the COVID briefing is at 1:30, so I&#8217;m going to try to get through as many people as possible between now and then.&nbsp; I just have one item at the top.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>After an update from our COVID-19 team yesterday &#8212; you may have seen out there this morning that today the United States will hit 50 percent of adult Americans fully vaccinated.&nbsp; That number was around 1 percent when the President took office, so that&#8217;s certainly a significant development.<br>&nbsp;<br>Alex, that&#8217;s all I have for the top.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Short.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not to disappoint, but go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let&#8217;s start with Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you share any further details on the meeting?&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s on the agenda?&nbsp; What does President Biden hope to get out of the meeting?&nbsp; And the choosing of Geneva &#8212; obviously, Geneva is an historic place, so was that part of the decision-making process in deciding to hold it in Geneva?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me start with &#8212; of course, you&#8217;ve seen the statement we put out this morning confirming that President Biden will be meeting with President Putin in Geneva, as you said, on June 16th.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The leaders will discuss the full range of pressing issues as we seek to restore predictability and stability to the U.S.-Russia relationship.&nbsp; And to &#8212; more specific to your question,&nbsp;&nbsp;we expect they will spend a fair amount of time on strategic stability, where the arms control agenda goes following the extension of New START.&nbsp;&nbsp;Obviously, we&#8217;re both members of the P5+1, as well, as those negotiations are ongoing.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President will also raise Ukraine, underscoring America’s support for Ukraine&#8217;s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he will also plan to raise Belarus and convey our grave concerns, as he has now done publicly &#8212; privately, as he’s done &#8212; has now done pri- &#8212; publicly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It also is three weeks away, so there could be a range of issues that could be discussed during the forum &#8212; during the meeting.&nbsp; And we will, of course, provide a preview for you as we get closer.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you respond to criticism from some Republicans that the administration is essentially rewarding Putin for bad behavior considering, you know, his sort of soft response to the Belarus situation, his treatment of Navalny, various other issues he&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s had recently?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we may have forgotten over the last couple of years, but this is how diplomacy works.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t work together &#8212; we don&#8217;t meet with people only when we agree.&nbsp; It&#8217;s actually important to meet with leaders when we have a range of disagreements, as we do with Russian leaders.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we don&#8217;t regard the meeting with the Russian President as a reward; we regard it as a vital part of defending America&#8217;s interests.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And President Biden is meeting with Vladimir Putin because of our country&#8217;s differences, not in spite of them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to raise concerns where we have them and, again, to move toward a more stable and predictable relationship with the Russian government.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the George Floyd Act: Negotiations on the Hill have been hung up on the issue of ending qualified immunity.&nbsp; Tim Scott has proposed a compromise that would allow individuals to essentially sue police departments and not individual police officers.&nbsp; Would the President sign a bill that included that compromise if it came to his desk?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President has had a principle from the beginning, which is that he wants to allow the negotiators the time and space to have those negotiations and those discussions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, in a &#8212; in a statement they released together yesterday, they conveyed that while they are &#8220;still working through differences on key issues, [they] continue to make progress toward a compromise and remain optimistic about the prospects of achieving that goal.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He has great trust in Senator Booker, who he spoke with just last Friday, as well as Congresswoman Bass, but we&#8217;ll see what the final agreement looks like between the parties.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President obviously was hoping for more progress to be made by today &#8212; he had set this as sort of that unofficial deadline.&nbsp; We are seeing some movement on the Hill, but can you explain to us a little bit more what the President himself has been doing &#8212; conversations he may have been having to try and deliver on that goal?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, we have been closely engaged with the negotiators and a range of parties on the Hill.&nbsp; We have also been respecting the space needed for the negotiators to have these discussions about where they can find common ground and where they can find agreement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;ve been closely engaged.&nbsp; The President himself called Senator Booker to get an update last Friday.&nbsp; I expect he&#8217;ll continue to get updates over the coming days.&nbsp; And we have also been &#8212; made it imper- &#8212; and made it a priority to leave space for the negotiators to have these discussions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve actually gone back and have been talking to some of the police reform advocates, some of the victims’ families who met with the President during the campaign to kind of get their perspective on &#8212; on action, or lack thereof, coming out of Washington.&nbsp; And some of them have expressed some real frustration that they feel that the President could be doing more here, that he could be putting more public pressure on Congress.&nbsp; Your response to that?&nbsp; And why aren’t we seeing him &#8212; today, for instance &#8212; come out and speak publicly and try and urge more action here?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we issued &#8212; or are issuing, if it hasn&#8217;t gone out yet &#8212; a public statement from the President, in his name, commemorating the anniversary of the death of George Floyd &#8212; a moment that impacted him deeply, personally, as it did millions of Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, he&#8217;s meeting with the family today.&nbsp; He wants that to be a private discussion.&nbsp; He has a close relationship with them &#8212; or they’ve really impacted him in their courage and grace over the last year.&nbsp; And he felt it was important for that to be private.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, I think we may just have a disagreement in terms of what the right strategic approach is to these negotiations moving forward and getting to the final outcome, which we all want to see, which is a bill that the President can sign into law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say that we are very engaged with a range of groups around the country &#8212; civil rights groups, police reform groups and advocates &#8212; about what they think is going to work, and we&#8217;ve kept them abreast of what our strategy is.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll also note though that the President has also &#8212; while we&#8217;ve been pushing for this legislation, he also, when he was running for office, pledged to appoint DOJ leadership that would prioritize pattern-or-practice investigations; emphasize the importance of the Justice Department, using the authority he spearheaded as senator, to investigate systemic police misconduct.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the Attorney General has already moved forward on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we, also, in our initial budget call, we &#8212; in our initial budget calls that we put out several weeks ago, we called for increasing funding for the Department of Justice&#8217;s Civil Rights Division by millions of dollars in order to advonce &#8212; advance accountability and reform.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I will say, we are continuing to press in the way we feel is most effective and most constructive in coordination with the negotiators, but we also are taking additional steps that we can take &#8212; and our administration can take &#8212; to move forward accountability and justice.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just to follow up on Mary’s questions: Why wouldn&#8217;t the President use his bully pulpit today to call for police reform?&nbsp; Is it a missed opportunity?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Kristen, he used the opportunity of his joint session address &#8212; which is the highest-profile moment any President of the United States has in their first year of office &#8212; to call for forward movement on police reform, to call &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But today is the one-year anniversary &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; let me finish &#8212; to call for the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act to pass.&nbsp; And we put out a statement today, and he&#8217;s meeting with the family.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, I think this is a matter of what we feel is most constructive to move these negotiations forward and to get to the final outcome that everybody who advocates for justice, who advocates for &#8212; for reform wants to see, which is signing this bill into law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when does he expect to see this bill on his desk?&nbsp; Is it this summer?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not here to put a new timeline on it, Kristen.&nbsp; He&#8217;s encouraged by the statement we saw the negotiators put out yesterday &#8212; that they feel there is an opportunity for progress, for forward momentum, for forward movement.&nbsp; That, certainly, is significant coming from Democratic and Republican negotiators.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you know, Congress works very well when they have a deadline.&nbsp; There doesn&#8217;t seem to be a deadline anywhere in sight.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As soon as possible, he&#8217;d like to sign the bill into law.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How does the President keep the pressure up?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As soon as possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How does he keep the pressure up, though?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He remains closely engaged and closely in touch with the negotiators about what is most constructive and what role he can play and we can play to leave the space for them to negotiate and to move toward a place where he can sign the bill into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And following up on Russia: What message does it send to the United States adversaries that the President would hold a summit with President Putin in the wake of all of these recent provocations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That the President of the United States is not afraid to stand up to our adversaries and use a moment of in-person diplomacy to convey areas where he has concern and look for any areas of opportunity to work together in areas where we have mutual agreement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But why not wait until they&#8217;ve shown some good faith on some of these issues before setting up a summit?&nbsp; Is he not, in some ways, offering him a victory here?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We proposed the summit because we feel that it is an opportunity to move forward our national interests and our agenda.&nbsp; And the most effective me- &#8212; approaches to diplomacy are those where you seek opportunities to have tough conversations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re not suggesting that at the end of this that it’s going to be easy breezy from here.&nbsp; In fact, we continue to expect that we&#8217;ll have difficult conversations.&nbsp; We will have confrontations at points about areas where we have disagreement, but this is an opportunity to move to &#8212; or toward a more stable and predictable relationship with Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Very quickly on Belarus &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you got a question on this yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s now been 24 hours.&nbsp; Has the White House &#8212; has the President determined whether Russia had any role in diverting that plane?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I did not give any indication that we had that view yesterday, and that has not changed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But have you &#8212; so, will the White House make a determinization before this summit?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a belief that that is the case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; First, on COVID: Does President Biden think these theories we hear more about now &#8212; that COVID-19 may have been manmade and escaped from a lab in China &#8212; are a wacky conspiracy theory?&nbsp; Or, based on what he has heard and been briefed on, does he think that&#8217;s possible?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we went through this journey together yesterday, so let&#8217;s do it again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the President believes there needs to be an independent investigation, one that&#8217;s run by the international community.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an international pandemic that&#8217;s killed hundreds of thousands of people around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He believes the Chinese need to do more to put forward data, to be more transparent.&nbsp; And in the second phase of this effort, he&#8217;s certainly hopeful that will be the case.&nbsp; And he believes that every theory should be explored through that process but that we shouldn&#8217;t jump to conclusions before that data and that information is made available.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And on the rise in violent crime: Compared to this time last year, homicide is up 113 percent in Minneapolis, up 38 percent in Philly, up 22 percent in Chicago.&nbsp; Just to clarify: The White House&#8217;s position on this is that that is mostly because of guns?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I&#8217;m not sure what data you&#8217;re looking at, but I think what we can &#8212; most data that is out there shows that there&#8217;s actually been a rise in crime over the course of the last year, since the start of the pandemic &#8212; which actually predates President Biden taking office, to be totally clear.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he is President right now &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re right.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; while there is a big &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re right.&nbsp; You&#8217;re right, Peter.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; increase in violent crime and homicides.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; we are focused as well.&nbsp; We&#8217;re focused on solutions here.&nbsp; And that’s why we proposed putting 5- &#8212; we put $5 billion in the American Jobs Plan to help address community violence-intervention programs &#8212; to help fund them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s also why we fought for funding for state and local governments in the Rescue Plan, something many opposed; there was a lot of Republican opposition to that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s helped keep cops on the beat and other public servants in vital role ro- &#8212; roles.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it&#8217;s why his budget proposal &#8212; his budget proposes to increase funding for the COPS program by $300 million to invigorate community policing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We believe there needs to be funding.&nbsp; We believe there needs to be &#8212; we need to help, from the federal government, ensure community policing and local police have the assistance they need.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Then the last one: The mayor of St. Louis says that she believes more police does not prevent crime.&nbsp; Does President Biden agree with that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President believes there&#8217;s a number of steps that need to be taken to rebuild trust in communities.&nbsp; Police reform is long outdated.&nbsp; He also believes that there needs to be funding for local programs and local initiatives, and there&#8217;s not going to be a shortage of funding under our watch.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to Belarus.&nbsp; Why does it seem like the U.S. is sort of lagging behind what other nations have done?&nbsp; The EU was very quick to impose sanctions.&nbsp; What is the U.S. considering and why is it taking until now or beyond to &#8212; for the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s only been a few days.&nbsp; It’s not &#8212; not been that long.&nbsp; I will say the President has asked his team to develop appropriate options in close coordination with the European Union, our allies, and other international organizations to help hold the Lukashenko regime to account, including sanctions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is there anything &#8212; does anything &#8212; can give us some readout of what&#8217;s being considered?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not before it&#8217;s presented to the President.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s asked that…<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not before it&#8217;s presented to the President.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s asked his team to put together some options for him.&nbsp; And we certainly remain in close touch and coordination with our European counterparts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as I read out yesterday, our National Security Advisor spoke with his Russian counterpart and, certainly, conveyed in strong terms our concerns here as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And secondly, on infrastructure: Republicans, today, are saying that in their Oval Office meeting with President Biden two weeks ago, the President indicated he was comfortable with $1 trillion over eight years.&nbsp; Is that accurate?<br>&nbsp;<br>And secondly, they&#8217;re also saying that White House staff has since ignored that sort of offer &#8212; if that&#8217;s the right word.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just peel the curtains back for you here a little bit.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s &#8220;peeling the curtains back,&#8221; but you know what I&#8217;m saying.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President &#8212; the proposal &#8212; the counterproposal that the President &#8212; that our team put forward on Friday was approved by the President, was signed off by the President, every single detail of that was directed by the President of the United States.&nbsp; He was in the Senate for 36 years; I can promise you he does not take a hands-off approach to legislating, negotiating, and determining what kind of counterproposals we should put forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, we put forward a counterproposal that reduced the &#8212; that cut the price tag by $550 billion.&nbsp; We felt that was a good-faith effort, and we look forward to getting a counterproposal back from the Republicans, which we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; they&#8217;ve conveyed &#8212; we expect to get later this week.&nbsp; And we certainly look forward to that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, I will say that we expect this week to be a week of progress.&nbsp; We know tomorrow, the energy &#8212; Environment and Public Works Committee, under the leadership of Chairman Carper and Ranking Member Capito, is marking up the Surface Transportation bill.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a $303 billion infrastructure bill.&nbsp; That is a great down payment; it&#8217;s very much aligned with the President&#8217;s proposal and initiatives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We expect the Senate to finalize an agreement on the Innovation and Competition Act this week.&nbsp; This is a proposal, led by Leader Schumer, that will make an important re- &#8212; investment in research and development.<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, we expect to get a counterproposal later this week.&nbsp; I&#8217;d say that&#8217;s progress.&nbsp; That&#8217;s legislating.&nbsp; That&#8217;s negotiating.&nbsp; That&#8217;s compromise certainly happening.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just so we&#8217;re real clear, they said the $1 trillion &#8212; that was not mentioned in the Oval Office?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to read any more specifics of a private conversation.&nbsp; But I will just reiterate that the proposal put forward last Friday, that we put out transparently to all of you, that brought the price tag down by $550 billion was directed, signed off on by the President of the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Question for you on the Olympics.&nbsp; On Monday, the U.S. urged against travel to Japan, and this is just two months before the Olympics.&nbsp; Has there been any change in the United States&#8217; support for Japan&#8217;s decision to hold the Olympics?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our position has not changed on the Olympics.&nbsp; We respected the decision to delay the games last summer.&nbsp; We understand the careful considerations that the Japanese government and the International Olympics Committee are weighing as they prepare for the Tokyo Olympics this summer.&nbsp; And the government has stressed that public health remains the central priority as they plan to host the Games.&nbsp; The President proudly supports U.S. athletes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that we&#8217;re talking about athletes, of course, traveling under the Olympic umbrella, which &#8212; within their strict COVID protocols.&nbsp; This is one of the very limited categories of U.S. travelers that are actually planning on going to Japan for the Olympics.&nbsp; There are very specific entry and movement rules and procedures which the organizers have laid out in order to ensure the protection of everyone involved.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then I just had a quick follow-up on Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned that the President is likely to bring up Ukraine and Belarus.&nbsp; What is going to be his message to President Putin, specifically on Ukraine?&nbsp; I mean, despite Russia&#8217;s announced withdrawal, a senior Ukrainian official told Reuters earlier that Russia still had about 100,000 troops near the border and in Crimea.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President will continue to convey what has been his consistent message, that is: Ukraine is a sovereign country.&nbsp; We respect, you know, their &#8212; that.&nbsp; And we are closely coordinated with them.&nbsp; We support them in their efforts to protect their people and protect their borders.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been consistent &#8212; a consistent message from him.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; it will be the basis of his message to the Russian President in a couple of weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And will he bring up, also, concerns about cyberattacks, specifically &#8212; specifically Colonial as well, considering he said that, you know, he did not believe the government was involved but the malware was based in Russia?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, again, there will be a range of topics.&nbsp; This meeting is about three weeks away.&nbsp; So, certainly, cyber has been a topic of discussion with &#8212; between the President and President Putin, but we&#8217;ll have a much more detailed preview as we get closer to the meeting in a couple of weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Weijia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On Russia, now that the summit has been formalized, were there any preconditions attached to the meeting?&nbsp; And are there any circumstances under which the President would pull out of it &#8212; as an example, if it turns out that Moscow was involved with this forced plane landing in Belarus?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to predict something we don&#8217;t &#8212; that&#8217;s disproving a negative here, that doesn&#8217;t exist, that we have not conveyed from here.&nbsp; But I would just reiterate that we don&#8217;t see this meeting as an opportunity to just talk about everything we agree on.&nbsp; We see this as a diplomatic opportunity for the United States, one that&#8217;s in our national interests, which is to convey areas where we disagree, to have a conversation about concerns we have and also look for a more stable and predictable path forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t expect everything to be solved at the end of this meeting, but we think that it is in our interest to &#8212; to have the meeting, which is why we proposed it to the President.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Were there any preconditions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, under the previous administration, there was little detailed record of the face-to-face meetings between former President Trump and Putin.&nbsp; In the Helsinki meeting, no one was in the room except the two leaders and their interpreters.&nbsp; Will there be other U.S. officials in their face-to-face meetings to serve as witnesses?&nbsp; And can you commit to providing readouts of the meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly will provide readouts.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything on the format of the meeting.&nbsp; But, as is standard, there typically is a representation from both sides.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one, I guess, housekeeping bit.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In Europe, the President will be in Brussels for the NATO summit on the 14th.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll be meeting with Putin on the 16th.&nbsp; What are his plans for that day in between?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s an EU summit, I believe, in that day in between; that&#8217;s been announced that he would be attending &#8212; I think is the day in between.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken announced today that the U.S. wants to reopen the consulate in Jerusalem.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering, why now &#8212; why not three months ago or four months ago, given the role that consulate has played historically, pre-the last four years?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; You&#8217;re right, and we didn&#8217;t &#8212; you&#8217;re right, in that he has announced that, I should say.&nbsp; And that it is an important step in our view, in terms of continuing to rebuild the relationship with the Palestinian leaders that was cut off for several years because of the closure of the consulate, because UNRWA funding was cut off in 2018, and there really wasn&#8217;t a method for engaging with Palestinian leaders and others.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, we&#8217;ve taken a number of steps over the last couple of months.&nbsp; Back in April, we announced the resumption of U.S. assistance to the Palestinians, including economic development, humanitarian, and security assistance.&nbsp; In our view, this is an eth- &#8212; naxtra- &#8212; a next natural step to announce plans to reopen the consulate.&nbsp; And again, also announce our commitment to contributing to the funds to rebuild Gaza.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So these are all part of our efforts to rebuild that relationship.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Following up on Alex&#8217;s question a little bit.&nbsp; A Republican senator said, explicitly, they believe their counteroffer will be in the trillion-dollar range.&nbsp; Would that meet the definition of &#8220;progress by Memorial Day&#8221; to keep these talks going beyond this week?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, as I said a few minutes ago, our view is that this can be a week of progress.&nbsp; And &#8212; including the counteroffer, which we expect to get later this week &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to prejudge what that looks like; we&#8217;ll have to look at the nitty-gritty details &#8212; certainly, them coming up in funding is progress.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll see what that looks like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, the markup, tomorrow, of the Surface Transportation bill, that&#8217;s bipartisan work trying to fund an infrastructure bill.&nbsp; That&#8217;s consistent with the principles of the American Jobs Plan.&nbsp; And these are all positive steps forward, in our view.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more quick one.&nbsp; If you have to go alone, do you feel like Democrats are ready to do &#8212; like, you were talking yesterday to Eugene that, you know &#8212; constant conversations with Dem committee chairs, rank and file.&nbsp; If you have to go along, do you feel like the caucuses are with you in that decision?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp; We&#8217;re still working with Republicans, Phil.&nbsp; Hang in.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got two questions.&nbsp; First, just continuing on the Wuhan journey: I wanted to ask a little bit about a report from House Republicans suggesting that dissenting views in the intelligence community were suppressed &#8212; sort of, for follow-up on the origins of this &#8212; of this virus.&nbsp; Can you comment on that, whether some of these dissenting views were suppressed in intelligence community and whether the Biden administration is doing anything to ensure that doesn&#8217;t happen?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; By &#8212; intelligence views suppressed by the prior administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This administration, the prior administration, whether, you know &#8212; this is now the Biden administration, so &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know, but I &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But this is our culture &#8212;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; I think this is an accusation about the prior &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, this is a culture &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; administration suppressing views.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But this is a culture that the &#8212; the Biden administration has inherited.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the intelligence community has not had any sort of major overhaul, that I&#8217;m aware of at least.&nbsp; And if there is a sense that this view was being suppressed in some &#8212; in some way, is there anything the Biden administration has done to make sure that&#8217;s not the case?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ve sent a clear message that we are going to rebuild our institutions, whether that&#8217;s the intelligence community, the Justice Department, other &#8212; the civil service that &#8212; who are the backbone of our government.&nbsp; So, there’s no question about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think, when it comes to the kind of reports we’ve seen over the last couple of days, you know, our view is that sound and technically credible theories should be thoroughly evaluated by international experts.&nbsp; And, yes, there have been a range of reports, but a factsheet issued by the previous administration on January 15th, which I think there&#8217;s been a lot of focus on, did not draw any conclusions regarding the origins of the coronavirus.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our view is that, yes, there are a range of views.&nbsp; We welcome the range of views throughout the administration.&nbsp; There still needs to be an international investigation.&nbsp; We need Chinese cooperation in order to provide data in order to be transparent about what happened on the ground.&nbsp; We all want to see that outcome.&nbsp; There are a lot of good questions we have the Chinese should answer, and that&#8217;s where our primary focus is on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have an intelligence apparatus that’s much greater, ideally, than the rest of the world.&nbsp; I mean, wouldn’t there naturally be quite a curiosity within the Biden administration that this could have come from a lab in Wuhan?&nbsp; I mean, it’s &#8212; you know, nearly 600,000 people here have died, and the President has shown an enormous amount of empathy for that.&nbsp; But should this be the cause, it would seem, that the United States would want to put some of its intelligence firepower onto that question?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, Annie, as you&#8217;re not a public health expert, I assume &#8212; neither am I &#8212; I think we need ac- &#8212; we need access to the underlying data.&nbsp; We need access to the information that the Chinese government has in order to make a determination through the international bodies that would do this investigation.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something we&#8217;ve called for many, many times.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve pressed, with our international partners for the WHO to support an expert-driven evaluation&nbsp;of the pandemic’s origins.&nbsp; We would certainly participate in that with all of our research &#8212; resources from the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>But given it was an international pandemic &#8212; yes, it&#8217;s killed, as you said, more than 500,000 people here in the United States; killed hundreds of thousands more around the world &#8212; we&#8217;re going to do that in coordination with our international partners, continue to press the Chinese to release that data and information and play a constructive role in the second phase of the investigation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just also wanted to ask you about &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; a phenomenon, known as &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The giggle gives away &#8212; I don&#8217;t know what this question is.&nbsp; We’ll see.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I can see I’ve already ruined it here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is quite a serious issue: There are these unrecognized objects in U.S. airspace that are also known as “unidentified aerial phenomenon,” I understand.&nbsp; And I wanted to see &#8212; there&#8217;s a DNI report, that I understand, that&#8217;s going to be released soon &#8212; can the Biden administration commit to releasing it in full?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that would be for &#8212; a decision by the Department of National Intelligence to make.&nbsp; As you noted, we&#8217;re aware of the report requirement, and our team at the Office of the Director of National Intelligence is, of course, actively working on that report.&nbsp; And we take reports of incursions into our airspace by any aircraft identified or unidentified very seriously and investigate each one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But ODNI would be working on that report.&nbsp; And in terms of disclosure, that would be up to them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess, in all seriousness though, can you characterize the President&#8217;s concerns about this phenomenon?&nbsp; I mean, it is this concept of objects in U.S. airspace that are either origin from other nations or other entities, but what is the concern of the President that this phenomenon seems to occur, and the national security apparatus?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, broadly speaking, the fact that we have a team that&#8217;s actively working on a report.&nbsp; Certainly, the safety of our personnel, security of our operations, our airspace are of paramount concern, whether that is identified or unidentified aircraft.&nbsp; And we don&#8217;t discuss that publicly for a range of reasons, but certainly the President supports the ODNI putting together a report and following through on that commitment.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On housing, today, we saw that sales of new homes declined in April by more than analysts had expected, in part because of rising prices because of the cost of &#8212; the increasing cost of materials like lumber.&nbsp; Does the administration have concerns about what it&#8217;s seeing in the housing market &#8212; in particular, both in the new homes and existing &#8212; and, sort of, the bidding war environment that&#8217;s existing for a lot of existing homes right now, and what it can mean for the broader economy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, let me say: For some middle-class families &#8212; some &#8212; I know not the ones you referenced &#8212; their home is their primary source of wealth.&nbsp; So, the financial effects that some are feeling are positive.<br>&nbsp;<br>That said, the increase in housing prices we&#8217;ve seen does raise concerns for us about housing affordability and access to the housing market, which is certainly, as you alluded to, Jen, impacting many, many Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>We recognize there is a need for new housing supply, particularly on the affordable end of the market.&nbsp; There are issues &#8212; supply-and-demand issues, as you are well aware of, with construction and supplies that are needed to build new houses, which we&#8217;re seeing an impact on the market.<br>&nbsp;<br>One of the reasons that we put &#8212; proposed a number of the initiatives we did &#8212; including the Neighborhood Homes Tax Credit &#8212; which would renovate 500,000 single family homes in low-income neighborhoods and help ease the nationwide shortage &#8212; is because we knew we could see this becoming an issue.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as our team looks at it, we recognize that &#8212; as we&#8217;ve talked about a little bit around other issues &#8212; restarting the economy is going to produce some bumps, and there are some barriers to increasing supply in the short-term supply and demand, et cetera.&nbsp; We&#8217;re carefully monitoring these issues.&nbsp; We are cognizant of and &#8212; and concerned about housing affordability and access in the housing market, and our team is watching it very closely.<br>&nbsp;<br>Oh, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up on some of the infrastructure questions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Both in some of the Republican senators’ comments on the Hill today, in the written statement last week, there were mentions of, sort of, this &#8212; the White House staff potentially getting in the way of negotiations.&nbsp; This is also a theme that we heard back in February.&nbsp; Is there any daylight between the staff and the President on &#8212; in these negotiations?&nbsp; Is &#8212; do you think that &#8212; and why do you think that the Republicans are using this kind of wedge in this conversation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I&#8217;m probably not the right source to answer the second part of that question.&nbsp; But I can tell you, on the first &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; on the first &#8212; many people you can ask that question.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the first: The President directs &#8212; oversees and directs his team, as it relates to what he wants to see on negotiations, what kind of proposals he wants to see.&nbsp; And he signed off on the proposal that was put forward on Friday, which he felt and we all felt was a reasonable counteroffer given it brought the price tag down by $550 billion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is an ongoing negotiation.&nbsp;We&#8217;re eager to see what the Republicans propose or what their counterproposal looks like, and it sounds like we&#8217;re going to see that in the next few days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If Congress has not passed legislation to create a January 6th commission, does the President want to create his own presidential commission to look into the events of that day?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not quite there.&nbsp; There have been Republicans who have come out over the past several days and conveyed their support or their openness to discussing the path forward on a January 6th commission.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a positive sign.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our view is this is not a political issue; that it is one &#8212; it is a commission that could help look into one of the darkest days in recent modern history, a dark day on our democracy.&nbsp; And the President is hopeful that members of Congress will do the right thing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I wanted to get some guidance on the Floyd meeting this afternoon.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us any guidance on what the President intends to convey to the family, what he hopes to tell them,<br>even in broad terms?<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think a lot of the meeting will be him listening to them and hearing from them on what they want the path forward to look like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;ll provide them, I&#8217;m sure, an update on his efforts on the legislation and the negotiators, which is important to everybody who will be in that meeting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But he really wants it to be &#8212; he wanted it to be a private meeting because he has personal &#8212; a personal relationship, and he wanted to hear how they&#8217;re doing, give them an update on his efforts to sign a bill into law, and ensure there&#8217;s long-overdue accountability.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, I expect we&#8217;ll have a readout after the meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more quick question, and that is: We were told that the administration moved to terminate members of the U.S. Commission of Fine Arts.&nbsp; And one of my colleagues reported a story with an interview with the chairperson of this commission, who said that in the history of this Commission on Fine Arts, this had never happened before, that the President or his administration had asked for the termination of all three members of the committee.&nbsp; Can you give us any clarification on &#8212; on why this move was made and why the President decided to remove these commissioners?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I, unfortunately, don&#8217;t have all the details on this.&nbsp; The little piece I recall is that a number of them were nominated just recently in January of 2021, so before President Trump left office.&nbsp; And certainly any President coming in has the right to nominate their own people to serve on a commission or serve in any positions in their own administration.&nbsp; But I can see if there&#8217;s more details to provide to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there is not a negotiation that has been able to be reached on &#8212; today on the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act, what is the President willing to do? What if this just cannot go through?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s not the &#8212; that&#8217;s not the indication we&#8217;ve been given by any of the negotiators who put out a joint statement yesterday indicating that there was progress, that there was an opportunity to move these negotiations forward.&nbsp; And the President thought that was encouraging.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Part of that was the issue of qualified immunity.&nbsp; How does the President feel &#8212; is deciding &#8212; is he more on the side of, like, Congressman Clyburn, who says, &#8220;Let&#8217;s take it out and come back to that issue&#8221;?&nbsp; Or more on the side of Representative Maxine Waters, who&#8217;s like, &#8220;I&#8217;m not just going to take just anything&#8221;?&nbsp; How does he feel with that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President was a supporter of the original bill proposed, but he also wants to leave space for the negotiators.&nbsp; He has a great deal of trust in Congresswoman Bass, and he&#8217;s looking forward to seeing what comes out of those discussions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more question: What percentage of the approximate 48 million rental units that are available in the U.S. &#8212; how many are actually covered under the eviction moratorium?<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a great &#8212; excellent question.&nbsp; I&#8217;d have to check with our Department of Housing and Human and &#8212; you know, HUD &#8212; the HUD.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll check with our friends at HUD.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m happy to get a number to you if that&#8217;s available.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And to build off her question on police reform &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; is there a plan B?&nbsp; Would President Biden use executive action on police reform?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s already, of course, taken many executive actions.&nbsp; He wants &#8212; at this point, he feels the be- &#8212; most constructive role he can play is to stay in close touch with the negotiators, to make sure he is continuing to advocate for moving this legislation forward, and leave space for them to negotiate.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not going to get ahead of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>He was encouraged by the public statement made by the negotiators &#8212; bipartisan; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; just yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lawmakers say they&#8217;re making progress.&nbsp; Is President Biden happy with the progress they&#8217;re making or would he like them to pick up the pace of it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President looks forward to signing the bill into law as soon as possible, but he is encouraged by the fact that they&#8217;re making progress, and he&#8217;ll stay in close touch with them as they continue to negotiate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A couple more on infrastructure:&nbsp; Senator Wicker, up on the Hill, just said, a little while ago, not only is it &#8212; the counteroffer going to be in the trillion-dollar range, but he also said, &#8220;We&#8217;re going to make an offer [which will] make it clear [that] we are not going to disturb the 2017 tax bill.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>If that is indeed the case, is there any way in which the White House would accept a counterproposal in which the 27 [sic] &#8212; 2017 tax bill is not touched?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That sounds like a question for Senator Wicker.&nbsp; What are they proposing instead to pay for it?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, what &#8212; I guess, you guys need to see some of the details.&nbsp; But in terms of a topline, if that just flat out isn&#8217;t touched, is that &#8212; does that mean you guys can&#8217;t come &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The proposal is about investing in infrastructure, creating millions of jobs, making sure we&#8217;re competing with China, and preparing our workforce.&nbsp; The President proposed a way to pay for it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re waiting hear that &#8212; hear back from Republicans on how they would propose to pay for it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, if they don&#8217;t want to touch the 2017 Tax Cuts &#8212; $2 trillion tax cuts that did not end up having a windfall back to the American public &#8212; I guess that&#8217;s their choice what they put in their proposal, but they have to propose an alternative.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I guess &#8212; I hope you ask Senator Wicker that question.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then to bounce off another question as well: Can you assure the American people that there is going to be an infrastructure package &#8212; whether it&#8217;s negotiated between the White House, congressional Democrats, and congressional Republicans, or if this ends up going down line of reconciliation in which Democrats come together and put forth their own plan?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One way or another, however this comes about, are you confident that there, at the end of the day, is going to be an infrastructure package?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the only &#8212; the President&#8217;s only line in the sand is inaction.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re in the midst of bipartisan negotiations.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking forward to getting a counterproposal.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing bills marked up over the next few days that are a down payment on the President&#8217;s ideas.&nbsp; Those are all positive signs.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re in the midst of progress here, so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re focused on at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; To follow up on some of the questions about investigations on the origins of the coronavirus &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;ve spoken a lot about the need for an independent investigation.&nbsp; What role does the Biden administration think U.S. scientists or CDC scientists should play in that investigation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the WHO would be the body that would be overseeing a transparent, indef- &#8212; independent, phase two investigation.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something we have strongly supported.<br>&nbsp;<br>That would require China finally stepping up and allowing access needed to determine the origins.&nbsp; Of course, the United States would be supportive of that second stage of the investigation, but it would be led by an international body.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the U.S. wouldn&#8217;t take a lead role, essentially, in this investigation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, the WHO, which we rejoined when the President took office, is the body that we have been pressing and is the appropriate body for moving this investigation forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just quickly: Given some of the concerns among some economists and some lawmakers about inflation, has the President considered loosening trade barriers like some of the tariffs that were put in place during the last administration to, sort of, combat those concerns?&nbsp; Or is he &#8212; I guess, essentially, is he weighing lifting some of those trade barriers like tariffs on &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re constantly reviewing the policies of the last administration, but I would reiterate that monitoring inflation is obviously the purview of the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; Our economists have conveyed that they feel that the impact of our proposals will be transitory.&nbsp; The economy is getting going again.&nbsp; But in terms of any actions that would be taken, we would defer to the Federal Reserve.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Oh, and I&#8217;ll come back to you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t mean to skip you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Anti-Defamation League has noticed an increase of over 63 percent in reported anti-Semitic incidents since May 10th.&nbsp; Both the President and the Vice President have condemned them, but can you discuss how the administration is working with various stakeholders and outside groups to try and curb them?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I will say that the President issued &#8212; we issued a tweet from the President &#8212; he issued a tweet yesterday conveying his concern about the anti-Semitic acts we&#8217;ve seen happen around the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is something that he has spoken passionately out against &#8212; anti-Semitism &#8212; throughout his career, from one of his first &#8212; first speeches &#8212; just to take you in the time &#8212; time machine &#8212; as senator.&nbsp; He condemned anti-Semitism from the Senate floor in May of 1973 in his &#8212; and, obviously, up to his vocal condemnation of the events at Charlottesville.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He recognizes this is a persistent evil that always deserves our attention and efforts.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been working in close and ongoing contact &#8212; we&#8217;ve been in close and ongoing contact, I should say, with the Jewish community to offer our support.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve taken steps to confront anti-Semitic violence and hate crimes of any type, including by signing into law stronger hate crimes legislation just last week.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we are also working to bolster safety and security of synagogues and other religiously affiliated facilities and organizations.&nbsp; DHS has briefed security directors across the Jewish community in the United States and preparing &#8212; and is preparing a public awareness bulletin that will include security messag- &#8212; measures individuals and facilities can take.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we have an across-government effort that the President is quite focused on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on that.&nbsp; Some Jewish groups are planning a day of action against anti-Semitism on May 27th, which is this Thursday.&nbsp; Do the President or the Vice President have plans to make any remarks there or make virtual appearances?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know that the President will be traveling on Thursday, and he&#8217;ll &#8212; in Ohio, and he&#8217;ll be delivering an economic speech.&nbsp; I can see if there&#8217;s anything more in scheduling plans to read out to all of you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the back.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just in terms of trans-Atlantic travel: The EU, last week, announced an easing of restrictions on Americans coming into Europe, and yet most of the rest of world is not permitted back into America at the moment.&nbsp; Does the President have any plans to ease restrictions on incoming travelers from the EU, maybe this summer &#8212; and particularly, maybe, the Summit you mentioned next month in Brussels?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, currently, we have no announcements in regards to lifting existing travel restrictions.&nbsp; Any decision to change or lift them would be based on the guidance of the &#8212; of our public health experts, of course, and an interagency process including all relevant agencies would be required to ensure a policy change is operationalized appropriately.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say: Of course we want to have travel resume between the United States and Europe and other countries around the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re very mindful of the pandemic, ensuring we&#8217;re doing &#8212; taking every step we can to keep the American people safe.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we rely on the guidance of public health officials.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a quick second question: We&#8217;re now more than four months into the presidency and very few ambassador positions have been announced.&nbsp; A, when should we expect something on that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, B, just a bit more specifically: More than two dozen members of Congress has written &#8212; have written to the President calling for the appointment of a Special Envoy for Northern Ireland in light of recent &#8212; an uptick in tensions there.&nbsp; Is there any plan to appoint a Special Envoy to Northern Ireland?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, on the latter, we certainly continue to closely monitor issues in Northern Ireland.&nbsp; We welcome the provisions in both the trade deal between the United Kingdom and European Union and Northern Ireland Protocol that will help &#8212; which will help protect the gains of the Belfacs [sic] &#8212; Belfast Good Friday Agreement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t have any personnel to announce for you.&nbsp; That would be the State Department that would make that recommendation, in terms of ambassadors.&nbsp; I know keep saying this, but: Coming soon.&nbsp; Soon.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any update for all of you today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, sorry, this has got to be the last one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some governors and mayors want to use their portion of the $350 billion in direct aid from the American Rescue Plan on infrastructure, such as road and bridges repairs, but this type of infrastructure spending is prohibited under the American Rescue Plan law.&nbsp; Is the Biden administration open to offering more flexibility to allow cities and states to use their money on roads, bridges, and other infa- &#8212; infrastructure improvements?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The state and local funding &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; from the American Rescue Plan?&nbsp; Just to make sure I understand what you&#8217;re asking about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, there were certain parameters that were quite broad that were put into this law, and put &#8212; in the implementation phase of this, as this money went out to communities.&nbsp; One of the areas was to ensure we keep cops on the beat; ensure we keep local &#8212; state and local officials in their jobs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there&#8217;s a range of ways that state and local authorities can use this funding, but we &#8212; there&#8217;s a bill that is being negotiated to ensure we get infrastructure funding out to communities across the country.&nbsp; And we believe we agree that it&#8217;s a priority, but I don&#8217;t have anything new on the parameters of it or intentions moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:31 P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 20:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Daryl W. Baldwin, of Ohio, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for a term expiring January 26, 2024, vice Camila Ann Alire, term expired. &#160; &#160; &#160;Genine Macks Fidler, of Florida, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Daryl W. Baldwin, of Ohio, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for a term expiring January 26, 2024, vice Camila Ann Alire, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Genine Macks Fidler, of Florida, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for a term expiring January 26, 2022, vice John Unsworth, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Beverly Gage, of Connecticut, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for a term expiring January 26, 2024, vice Daniel Iwao Okimoto, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Lynnette Young Overby, of Delaware, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for the remainder of the term expiring January 26, 2022, vice Adair Margo, resigned.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Daryl W. Baldwin, of Ohio, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for a term expiring January 26, 2026, vice David Armand DeKeyser, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on April 29, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Genine Macks Fidler, of Florida, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for a term expiring January 26, 2026, vice Joyce Malcolm, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on April 29, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Beverly Gage, of Connecticut, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for a term expiring January 26, 2026, vice Noel Valis, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on April 29, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Lynette Young Overby, of Delaware, to be a Member of the National Council on the Humanities for a term expiring January 26, 2026, vice Phyllis Kaminsky, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on April 29, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala Harris on Meeting with the Family of George Floyd</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-meeting-with-the-family-of-george-floyd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 19:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the President and I met with the family of Mr. George Floyd. Mr. Floyd should be alive today. He should be with his family who continue to show courage, grace, and resilience. One year ago, a cellphone video revealed to the country what Black Americans have known to be true for generations. The verdict&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the President and I met with the family of Mr. George Floyd. Mr. Floyd should be alive today. He should be with his family who continue to show courage, grace, and resilience.</p>



<p>One year ago, a cellphone video revealed to the country what Black Americans have known to be true for generations. The verdict finding Derek Chauvin guilty of murder provided some measure of justice. But one verdict does not address the persistent issue of police misconduct and use of excessive force. It does not take away the Floyd family’s pain, nor the pain of all those families who have grieved the untimely loss of a loved one.</p>



<p>We need to do more.</p>



<p>After Mr. Floyd was murdered, Senator Cory Booker, Representative Karen Bass, and I introduced the Justice in Policing Act to hold law enforcement accountable and build trust between law enforcement and the communities it serves. Congress must move swiftly and act with a sense of urgency. Passing legislation will not bring back those lives lost, but it will represent much needed progress.</p>



<p>We must address racial injustice wherever it exists. That is the work ahead.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the First Anniversary of George Floyd’s Murder</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-first-anniversary-of-george-floyds-murder/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, in the Oval Office, I met with George Floyd’s family. Although it has been one year since their beloved brother and father was murdered, for the family – for any family experiencing a profound loss – the first year can still feel like they got the news a few seconds ago. And they’ve had&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, in the Oval Office, I met with George Floyd’s family.</p>



<p>Although it has been one year since their beloved brother and father was murdered, for the family – for any family experiencing a profound loss – the first year can still feel like they got the news a few seconds ago. And they’ve had to relive that pain and grief each and every time those horrific 9 minutes and 29 seconds have been replayed.</p>



<p>Yet the Floyd family has shown extraordinary courage, especially his young daughter Gianna, who I met again today. The day before her father’s funeral a year ago, Jill and I met the family and she told me, “<em>Daddy changed the world</em>.”</p>



<p>He has.</p>



<p>His murder launched a summer of protest we hadn’t seen since the Civil Rights era in the ‘60s – protests that peacefully unified people of every race and generation to collectively say enough of the senseless killings.</p>



<p>Last month’s conviction of the police officer who murdered George was another important step forward toward justice. But our progress can’t stop there.</p>



<p>To deliver real change, we must have accountability when law enforcement officers violate their oaths, and we need to build lasting trust between the vast majority of the men and women who wear the badge honorably and the communities they are sworn to serve and protect. We can and must have both accountability and trust and in our justice system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The negotiations on the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act in Congress are ongoing. I have strongly supported the legislation that passed the House, and I appreciate the good-faith efforts from Democrats and Republicans to pass a meaningful bill out of the Senate. It’s my hope they will get a bill to my desk quickly.</p>



<p>We have to act. We face an inflection point. The battle for the soul of America has been a constant push and pull between the American ideal that we’re all created equal and the harsh reality that racism has long torn us apart.</p>



<p>At our best, the American ideal wins out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It must again.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces His Intent to Appoint Members to the Commission of Fine Arts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/president-biden-announces-his-intent-to-appoint-members-to-the-commission-on-fine-arts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to appoint four new members to the Commission on Fine Arts: Peter Cook, Principal, HGA ArchitectsPeter Cook is a Principal at HGA Architects. Among Cook’s high-profile projects are the Smithsonian Institution’s National Museum of African American History and Culture, Watha T. Daniel / Shaw Neighborhood Library, Embassy of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to appoint four new members to the Commission on Fine Arts:<br><br><strong><u>Peter Cook, Principal, HGA Architects</u></strong><br>Peter Cook is a Principal at HGA Architects. Among Cook’s high-profile projects are the Smithsonian Institution’s National Museum of African American History and Culture, Watha T. Daniel / Shaw Neighborhood Library, Embassy of South Africa, and Saint Elizabeth’s East Gateway Pavilion. Cook is a member of the American Institute of Architects, Washington, D.C. Chapter and the National Organization of Minority Architects. He holds a Master of Architecture from Columbia University’s Graduate School of Architecture, Planning &amp; Preservation, and a Bachelor of Arts in Visual &amp; Environmental Studies from Harvard University.<br><br><strong><u>Hazel Ruth Edwards, Professor and Chair, Howard University Department of Architecture in the College of Engineering and Architecture</u></strong><br>Dr. Hazel Ruth Edwards has been Professor and Chair of the Department of Architecture, College of Engineering and Architecture at Howard University since July 2016. Appointed in 2016, Edwards is the first female to chair the department since architecture education began at Howard in 1911. Her unique career has combined place-based research with planning and urban design practice and teaching. She is a certified planner with the American Institute of Certified Planners (AICP) and was elected to their College of Fellows (FAICP) in 2018.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><u>Justin Garrett Moore, Inaugural Program Officer, Humanities in Place, Andrew Mellon Foundation</u></strong><br>Justin Garrett Moore is a transdisciplinary designer and urbanist. He recently took a job at the Andrew Mellon Foundation as the Inaugural Program Officer of the Humanities in Place program. Moore previously served as Executive Director of the City of New York Public Design Commission. He is a member of the American Planning Association&#8217;s AICP Commission, the Urban Design Forum, and the Black urbanist collective BlackSpace. Justin is an adjunct faculty member at Columbia University&#8217;s Graduate School of Architecture, Planning and Preservation and the Yale School of Architecture.<br><br><strong><u>Billie Tsien, Partner, Todd Williams Billie Tsien Architects</u></strong><br>Billie Tsien is an architect and a founding partner with Tod Williams of the New York City-based studio Tod Williams Billie Tsien Architects | Partners.&nbsp;Their work is committed to reflecting the values of non-profit, cultural and academic institutions through an architecture that is serene and enduring.&nbsp;Currently serving as President of the American Academy of Arts and Letters, she is also a member of the National Academy of Design, American Academy in Rome, and the American Philosophical Society.&nbsp;Maintaining an active academic career as the Charles Gwathmey Professor in Practice at Yale University, she is steadfast in her mission to create a better world through architecture and to contribute to supporting a broader and more diverse cultural landscape.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Opens Pacific Coast to New Jobs and Clean Energy Production with Offshore Wind Development</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/fact-sheet-biden-administration-opens-pacific-coast-to-new-jobs-and-clean-energy-production-with-offshore-wind-development/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[White House Marshals Departments of the Interior, Defense, and Energy to Advance California Offshore Areas for Wind Energy Development and Good-Paying, Union Jobs Today, the White House convened National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy, California Governor Gavin Newsom, Interior Secretary Deb Haaland, and Under Secretary for Defense for Policy Dr. Colin Kahl to announce an effort&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>White House Marshals Departments of the Interior, Defense, and Energy to Advance California Offshore Areas for Wind Energy Development and Good-Paying, Union Jobs</em></p>



<p>Today, the White House convened National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy, California Governor Gavin Newsom, Interior Secretary Deb Haaland, and Under Secretary for Defense for Policy Dr. Colin Kahl to announce an effort to advance areas for offshore wind off the northern and central coasts of California – opening up the Pacific Coast to its first commercial scale offshore clean energy projects. This significant milestone is part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s goal to create thousands of good-paying, union jobs through the deployment of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/29/fact-sheet-biden-administration-jumpstarts-offshore-wind-energy-projects-to-create-jobs/">30 gigawatts (GW) of offshore wind by 2030</a>. These initial areas for offshore wind development in the Pacific Ocean could bring up to 4.6 GW of clean energy to the grid, enough to power 1.6 million American homes.</p>



<p>More specifically, the Department of the Interior, in coordination with the Department of Defense, has identified an area (“the Morro Bay 399 Area”) that will support three gigawatts of offshore wind on roughly 399 square miles off California’s central coast region, northwest of Morro Bay. The Department of the Interior is also advancing the Humboldt Call Area as a potential Wind Energy Area, located off northern California. These identified areas will enable the build out of a significant new domestic clean energy resource for years to come.</p>



<p>Because the Defense Department engages in significant testing, training, and operations off the coast of California that are essential to national security, the Defense Department played a critical role in identifying these new areas for offshore wind development. The Department of the Interior acknowledges the critical nature of current and future military testing, training, and operations and that the operational integrity thereof is a national security imperative. It will work closely with the Department of Defense to ensure long-term protection of military testing, training, and operations while pursuing new domestic clean energy resources.</p>



<p>Because the outer continental shelf falls away much more quickly into much deeper waters in the Pacific than it does in the Atlantic Ocean, new floating offshore wind technology will be deployed in offshore California waters. Notably, and as a further demonstration of the Biden administration’s whole-of-government approach to clean energy development, the. Department of Energy, through its Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy and ARPA-E, has invested more than $100 million in researching, developing, and demonstrating floating offshore wind technology. These investments have helped position the United States as a leader in the emerging global floating offshore wind market.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement comes after the Biden Administration announced a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/29/fact-sheet-biden-administration-jumpstarts-offshore-wind-energy-projects-to-create-jobs/">set of bold actions to catalyze offshore wind energy</a> as part of the President’s commitment to building new American infrastructure and a clean energy future that creates good-paying, union jobs. And, it follows the Administration’s <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-approves-first-major-offshore-wind-project-us-waters">approval of the first major offshore wind project</a> in U.S waters advancing the construction and operation of the Vineyard Wind project in Massachusetts.</p>



<p><em>Administration leaders shared their perspective on today’s announcement and collaboration:</em></p>



<p><strong>National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy: </strong>“Today’s announcement again demonstrates that by taking a whole-of-government approach, the U.S. can smartly develop our nation’s world-class offshore wind energy resources, deploy new technologies that our government has helped to advance, and create thousands of good-paying, union jobs – all in the service of combating the climate crisis. I salute the Departments of the Interior, Defense, and Energy, and our partners in California, for all they have done to make this possible.”</p>



<p><strong>California Governor Gavin Newsom:</strong> “Developing offshore wind to produce clean, renewable energy could be&nbsp;a game changer to achieving California’s clean energy goals and addressing climate change – all while bolstering the economy and creating new jobs. This historic announcement, which could provide clean power for up to 1.6 million homes over the next decade, represents the innovative approach we need for a clean energy economy that protects the coasts, fisheries, marine life, and Tribal, and cultural resources we value so much as Californians.”</p>



<p><strong>Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland: </strong>“I believe that a clean energy future is within our grasp in the United States, but it will take all of us and the best-available science to make it happen. Today’s announcement reflects months of active engagement and dedication between partners who are committed to advancing a clean energy future. The offshore wind industry has the potential to create tens of thousands of good-paying union jobs across the nation, while combating the negative effects of climate change. Interior is proud to be part of an all-of-government approach toward the Biden-Harris Administration&#8217;s ambitious renewable energy goals.”</p>



<p><strong>Under Secretary for Defense Policy Dr. Colin Kahl: </strong>“Tacking the climate crisis is a national security imperative and the Defense Department is proud to have played a role in this important effort. The Defense Department is committed to working across the U.S. government to find solutions that support renewable energy in a manner compatible with t essential military operations.&nbsp;Throughout this effort, the Defense Department has worked tirelessly with the White House, the Department of the Interior, and the State of California to find solutions that enable offshore wind development while ensuring long-term protection for testing, training, and operations critical to our military readiness.&nbsp;The Defense Department applauds this step and looks forward to continued coordination to address the climate crisis.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White House Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the Meeting Between President Joe Biden and President Vladimir Putin of Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-president-vladimir-putin-of-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden will meet with President Putin in Geneva, Switzerland on June 16, 2021. The leaders will discuss the full range of pressing issues, as we seek to restore predictability and stability to the U.S.-Russia relationship. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden will meet with President Putin in Geneva, Switzerland on June 16, 2021. The leaders will discuss the full range of pressing issues, as we seek to restore predictability and stability to the U.S.-Russia relationship.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Marine One Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/25/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 13:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[5:16 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I&#8217;m going up to a viewing of a woman who worked with me in a senior position from the time I ran for the county council who passed away.&#160; Her name was Norma Long.&#160; That’s why I&#8217;m heading home.&#160; I&#8217;m heading back &#8212; back tonight.&#160; And so I just wanted to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>5:16 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going up to a viewing of a woman who worked with me in a senior position from the time I ran for the county council who passed away.&nbsp; Her name was Norma Long.&nbsp; That’s why I&#8217;m heading home.&nbsp; I&#8217;m heading back &#8212; back tonight.&nbsp; And so I just wanted to let you know what I&#8217;m doing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, how was your meeting with the Floyd family?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The Floyd family meeting went incredibly well.&nbsp; We spent a long time together.&nbsp; I spent &#8212; I got a chance to spend a lot of time with Gianna and the family.&nbsp; And we just talked about &#8212; you know, it’s the one-year anniversary, and those of you who’ve been through personal loss know that although every anniversary is &#8212; you&#8217;re happy people remember, it also brings everything back immediately like it happened that day.&nbsp; It takes a lot of courage to go through it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And they&#8217;ve been wonderful.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve spoken with the negotiators.&nbsp; I&#8217;m hopeful that sometime after Memorial Day, we&#8217;ll have an agreement on the &#8212; on the George Floyd legislation.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m optimistic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think they spoke to you.&nbsp; Maybe they didn’t speak to you; they spoke to some of you.&nbsp; I think they were very pleased with the time we spent together.&nbsp; It was mostly personal.&nbsp; We spent a long time &#8212; I guess, almost a couple of hours.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how was the time with Gianna for you?&nbsp; What did you (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; First thing she did when she ran in was throw her arms around me &#8212; gave me a big hug and wanted to sit in my lap.&nbsp; And we spent &#8212; she also loved the idea that &#8212; she said, “I&#8217;m really hungry.”&nbsp; And so she &#8212; she said, “Do you have any snacks?”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did you give her?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, we gave her &#8212; my wife would kill me. We gave her some ice cream.&nbsp; She had some Cheetos.&nbsp; And I think she had a chocolate milk.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure what the third one was.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But they were in and out.&nbsp; I showed them all &#8212; and we spent time &#8212; I spent time showing them around not just the Oval, but around the White House.&nbsp; And they were interested and &#8212; I gave them all &#8212; I gave them all little mementos, especially her.&nbsp; I had a great picture of Gianna when I went down for the funeral &#8212; or for the eve of the funeral, and I gave her that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why have you decided to meet with President Putin?&nbsp; And why are you letting Germany and Russia to build &#8212; to continue building Nord Stream 2?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because it’s almost completely finished, number one.&nbsp; The idea that anything that &#8212; and it’s not like I can allow Germany to do something they&#8217;re not.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I have been opposed to Nord Stream 2 from the beginning, but it only has &#8212; it’s almost completed by the time I took office.&nbsp; And to go ahead and impose sanctions now, I think, would be counterproductive now in terms of our European relations.&nbsp; And they know how strongly I feel.&nbsp; And I hope we can work on how they handle it from this point on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you considered canceling the summit because of what happened in Belarus?&nbsp; Have you ever considered cancelling the summit with Mr. Putin because of what just happened &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no, no.&nbsp; I &#8212; Putin had indicated he wanted to meet with me well over a month ago.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken with him a number of times. &nbsp;We’re going to be having a meeting in Switzerland not too long from now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are you thinking about in terms of sanctions on Belarus?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s in play.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to speculate until we get it done.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, (inaudible) end qualified immunity?&nbsp; That’s one of the hang-ups in negotiations.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The negotiations are taking place now.&nbsp; In case you haven&#8217;t figured me out by now, I never negotiate in public like others do.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I&#8217;m relatively successful in getting things done.&nbsp; And so I will tell you when that happens.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you so much.<br>&nbsp;<br>5:20 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
