<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:17:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, And Intersex Pride Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-queer-and-intersex-pride-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; During Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex (LGBTQI+) Pride Month, we reflect on the progress we have made as a Nation in the fight for justice, inclusion, and equality while reaffirming our commitment to do more to support LGBTQI+ rights at home and abroad.&#160; I often say that America can be defined&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; During Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex (LGBTQI+) Pride Month, we reflect on the progress we have made as a Nation in the fight for justice, inclusion, and equality while reaffirming our commitment to do more to support LGBTQI+ rights at home and abroad.&nbsp; I often say that America can be defined by one word: &nbsp;possibilities.&nbsp; This month, we celebrate generations of LGBTQI+ people who have fought to make the possibilities of our Nation real for every American.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, the rights of LGBTQI+ Americans are under relentless attack.&nbsp; Members of the LGBTQI+ community &#8212; especially people of color and trans people &#8212; continue to face discrimination and cruel, persistent efforts to undermine their human rights.&nbsp; An&nbsp;onslaught of dangerous anti-LGBTQI+ legislation has been introduced and passed in States across the country, targeting transgender children and their parents and interfering with their access to health care. &nbsp;These unconscionable attacks have left countless LGBTQI+ families in fear and pain. &nbsp;All of this compounded has been especially difficult on LGBTQI+ youth, 45&nbsp;percent of whom seriously considered attempting suicide in the last year &#8212; a devastating reality that our Nation must work&nbsp;urgently to address.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This month, we remind the LGBTQI+ community that they are loved and cherished. &nbsp;My Administration sees you for who you are &#8212; deserving of dignity, respect, and support. &nbsp;As I said in my State of the Union Address &#8212; especially to our younger transgender Americans &#8212; I will always have your back as your President so that you can be yourself and reach your God-given potential. &nbsp;Today and every day, my Administration stands with&nbsp;every LGBTQI+ American in the ongoing struggle against intolerance, discrimination, and injustice.&nbsp; We condemn the dangerous State laws and bills that target LGBTQI+ youth.&nbsp; And&nbsp;we remain steadfast in our commitment to helping LGBTQI+ people in America and around the world live free from violence. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since my first day in office, I have taken historic action&nbsp;to ensure that everyone &#8212; no matter who they are or whom&nbsp;they love &#8212; has an equal place in our democracy.&nbsp; I signed a landmark Executive Order charging the Federal Government with&nbsp;preventing and combating discrimination on the basis of&nbsp;sexual&nbsp;orientation and gender identity. &nbsp;This includes non‑discrimination protections for LGBTQI+ Americans in housing, health care, education, employment, credit and lending services, and the criminal justice system.&nbsp; My Administration has expanded access to inclusive passports for transgender Americans and instituted reforms to the traveler screening process at United&nbsp;States airports. &nbsp;We&nbsp;are supporting the open service for&nbsp;patriotic transgender military members and providing better services for LGBTQI+ veterans. &nbsp;I am honored by the service of the first openly gay Cabinet Secretary and the first transgender person confirmed by the Senate and to have been able to establish the first White House Gender Policy Council.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there is more work to be done. &nbsp;That is why I continue to call on the Congress to pass the Equality Act, which will enshrine long overdue civil rights protections and build a better future for all LGBTQI+ Americans. &nbsp;We must also fight for LGBTQI+ seniors so that they can age with dignity. &nbsp;And we must confront the disproportionate levels of poverty, homelessness, and unemployment in the LGBTQI+ community.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This month, we honor the resilience of LGBTQI+ people, who are fighting to live authentically and freely. &nbsp;We reaffirm our belief that LGBTQI+ rights are human rights. &nbsp;And we recommit to delivering protections, safety, and equality to LGBTQI+ families so that everyone can realize the full promise of America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex Pride Month.&nbsp; I call upon the people of the United States to recognize the achievements of the LGBTQI+ community, to celebrate the great diversity of the American people, and to wave their flags of pride high.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br>                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Great Outdoors Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-great-outdoors-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; During Great Outdoors Month, we celebrate our Nation&#8217;s vast array of parks, wildlife refuges, forests, monuments, marine sanctuaries, waters, national conservation lands, and other natural treasures. &#160;Every day, Americans across the country draw inspiration and pride from the beauty of our magnificent outdoor spaces. &#160;From lush forests in Washington State and coral reefs in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During Great Outdoors Month, we celebrate our Nation&#8217;s vast array of parks, wildlife refuges, forests, monuments, marine sanctuaries, waters, national conservation lands, and other natural treasures. &nbsp;Every day, Americans across the country draw inspiration and pride from the beauty of our magnificent outdoor spaces. &nbsp;From lush forests in Washington State and coral reefs in the Virgin Islands to snow-capped mountains in Alaska and rolling hills in Vermont &#8212; the grandeur of the American landscape fills our souls and fuels our spirit of adventure. &nbsp;These iconic and stunning natural wonders have always been central to our heritage as a people and essential to our identity as a Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Boundless outdoor spaces across the country unite Americans of every age and background for hiking, fishing, canoeing, hunting, exploring, reflecting, and finding solace.&nbsp;&nbsp;As part of my Administration&#8217;s efforts to advance equity, diversity,&nbsp;and inclusion,&nbsp;we are committed to ensuring that everyone can access and enjoy America&#8217;s great outdoors.&nbsp;&nbsp;Outreach efforts &#8212; including the National Park Service&#8217;s Rivers, Trails, and Conservation Assistance program &#8212; expand trails, conserve rivers, and restore green space so that more people can benefit.&nbsp;&nbsp;We are also enhancing safe outdoor resources for communities so that more people can participate in healthy, active outdoor recreation and enjoy the physical and spiritual nourishment it provides. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, our lands and waters face unprecedented threats from climate change that require historic action to safeguard and preserve them. &nbsp;That is why my Administration is setting ambitious environmental standards and making bold climate commitments for the United States:&nbsp; reducing greenhouse gas emissions by up to 52 percent by 2030, reaching 100 percent carbon pollution-free electricity by 2035, and achieving net‑zero emissions economy-wide by 2050.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Together with our State, Tribal, and local partners,&nbsp;we also launched the America the Beautiful Initiative, our Nation&#8217;s first-ever voluntary conservation goal, to conserve and restore 30 percent of America&#8217;s lands and waters by 2030.&nbsp; We also spearheaded a $1 Billion America the Beautiful Challenge, combining Federal investments with private and philanthropic contributions to accelerate land, water, and wildlife conservation and restoration efforts across the country.&nbsp; And we&nbsp;are making critical investments through the Great American Outdoors Act for land acquisition and community-based conservation and recreation projects in national parks, national forests, public lands, and Tribal schools.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Land and ocean conservation is a crucial part of addressing the world&#8217;s climate challenges. &nbsp;Proper stewardship protects the&nbsp;outdoors while contributing to sustainability, climate mitigation, and climate resilience. &nbsp;It is estimated that as much as one-third of the global emissions reductions needed to&nbsp;stabilize the world&#8217;s climate can come from natural climate solutions. &nbsp;That&#8217;s why I issued an Executive Order on Earth Day to strengthen our Nation&#8217;s forests, communities, and local economies, and to take stock of nature and its benefits.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During Great Outdoors Month, I encourage Americans to take time to experience the natural wonders across our Nation.&nbsp; As we&nbsp;enjoy the great outdoor landscapes and seascapes, let us each recommit to doing our part in their stewardship, preservation, and sustainable use so they continue to be a source of inspiration for outdoor enthusiasts for generations to come.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as Great Outdoors Month.&nbsp; I urge all Americans to explore the great outdoors, to experience our Nation&#8217;s natural heritage, and to continue our Nation&#8217;s tradition conserving our lands and waters for future generations.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Black Music Appreciation Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-black-music-appreciation-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Music has the power to lift our spirits, comfort our souls, and inspire our hearts. &#160;It gives a voice to the human spirit, creating a common language that unites people and breaks down barriers. &#160;Perhaps no music has had as profound and powerful an&#160;impact in shaping America&#8217;s musical score as Black music. &#160;Intricately woven&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Music has the power to lift our spirits, comfort our souls, and inspire our hearts. &nbsp;It gives a voice to the human spirit, creating a common language that unites people and breaks down barriers. &nbsp;Perhaps no music has had as profound and powerful an&nbsp;impact in shaping America&#8217;s musical score as Black music. &nbsp;Intricately woven into the tapestry of our Nation, Black music enriches our lives and pushes the boundaries of creativity. &nbsp;Throughout the decades and across the country, Black music has fueled a myriad of genres &#8212; from rhythm and blues to jazz, gospel, country, rap and more. &nbsp;This month, we celebrate the extraordinary legacy of Black music on American culture and recognize the indelible impact it continues to have on the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For generations, Black music has conveyed the hopes and struggles of a resilient people &#8212; spirituals mourning the original sin of slavery and later heralding freedom from bondage, hard truths told through jazz and the sounds of Motown during the Civil Rights movement, and hip-hop and rhythm and blues that remind us of the work that still lies ahead. &nbsp;The music created by Black artists continues to influence musicians of all persuasions, entertain people of all backgrounds, and shape the story of our Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During Black Music Appreciation Month, we honor Black musicians, singers, and contributors to the music industry &#8212; past and present &#8212; whose innovative talents unite us in joy as&nbsp;much as in sorrow and healing.&nbsp; We pay homage to the musical legends whose artistic expressions help build community, generate empathy, and foster a sense of shared identity. &nbsp;And&nbsp;we&nbsp;celebrate Black artists who have used their songs to stand up to injustice, fight for equality, and reflect a mirror on society &#8212; reminding us all of our enduring obligation to deliver the promise of America for all Americans.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as Black Music Appreciation Month. &nbsp;I&nbsp;call upon public officials, educators, and all the people of the United States to observe this month by honoring Black Musicians and raising awareness and appreciation of Black music.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Readout of Meeting Between Prime Minister Ardern and Vice President&#160;Harris</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/31/joint-readout-of-meeting-between-prime-minister-ardern-and-vice-president-harris/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand and Vice President Kamala Harris met at the White House and jointly&#160;reaffirmed the strong and&#160;deep&#160;relationship&#160;between the United States and New Zealand, based on shared values, people-to-people ties, and cooperation across a wide range of bilateral, regional, and global challenges. The Prime Minister and the Vice President welcomed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand and Vice President Kamala Harris met at the White House and jointly&nbsp;reaffirmed the strong and&nbsp;deep&nbsp;relationship&nbsp;between the United States and New Zealand, based on shared values, people-to-people ties, and cooperation across a wide range of bilateral, regional, and global challenges.</p>



<p>The Prime Minister and the Vice President welcomed the completion of&nbsp;negotiations on&nbsp;the bilateral Space Framework Agreement, which will be the foundation of our already robust civil space cooperation in the years ahead. The Framework will underpin the two nations’ cooperation including in: space science, earth science, sustainability, education, and technology. The Prime Minister and the Vice President reviewed the growing&nbsp;space partnership between the United States and New Zealand,&nbsp;including in supporting space exploration and taking action on climate change. They looked forward to future exchanges between the two countries.</p>



<p>The Prime Minister and the Vice President agreed on the importance of establishing and upholding international rules and norms to promote the peaceful, sustainable, and responsible use of outer space. They agreed that our two nations will work together to uphold and strengthen a rules-based international order for space and that we will work constructively with commercial industry, allies, and partners, and through multilateral fora to support the safety, stability, security, and long-term sustainability of space activities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Prime Minister and the Vice President discussed mutual efforts to combat violent extremism and radicalisation. They condemned recent mass shootings in the United States, including in Buffalo, Laguna Woods, and Uvalde, and agreed that we all must stand up against hate and violence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Highlights Strategy to Address the National Mental Health&#160;Crisis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/31/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-highlights-strategy-to-address-the-national-mental-health-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we mark&#160;Mental Health Awareness Month, our country faces an unprecedented mental health crisis among people of all ages. Two in five American adults&#160;report&#160;symptoms of anxiety and depression, and more than half of parents express&#160;concern&#160;over their children’s mental well-being. Over forty percent of teenagers&#160;state&#160;they struggle with persistent feelings of sadness or hopelessness. These growing demands&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As we mark&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-mental-health-awareness-month-2022/">Mental Health Awareness Month</a>, our country faces an unprecedented mental health crisis among people of all ages. Two in five American adults&nbsp;<a href="https://www.kff.org/report-section/the-implications-of-covid-19-for-mental-health-and-substance-use-issue-brief/">report</a>&nbsp;symptoms of anxiety and depression, and more than half of parents express&nbsp;<a>concern</a>&nbsp;over their children’s mental well-being. Over forty percent of teenagers&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/71/su/pdfs/su7103a1-a5-H.pdf">state</a>&nbsp;they struggle with persistent feelings of sadness or hopelessness. These growing demands have exposed longstanding cracks in our care infrastructure while compounding many other domestic policy challenges, from criminal justice to homelessness to the labor shortage.&nbsp;<br><br>To address this crisis, as part of his Unity Agenda, President Biden has put forward a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-announce-strategy-to-address-our-national-mental-health-crisis-as-part-of-unity-agenda-in-his-first-state-of-the-union/">comprehensive national strategy</a>&nbsp;to tackle our mental health crisis, and used his State of the Union Address to call for a major transformation in how mental health is understood, accessed, treated, and integrated – in and out of health care settings. Across the federal government, the Administration has already invested nearly $4 billion in&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/the-american-rescue-plan-people-difference/">American Rescue Plan</a>&nbsp;(ARP) funding to expand access to mental health and substance use services. The President’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/budget_fy2023.pdf">FY23 budget</a>&nbsp;goes further, by proposing over $27 billion in discretionary funding and another $100 billion in mandatory funding over 10 years to implement his national strategy and transform behavioral health services for all Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>This month, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking additional, new actions to advance the President’s mental health strategy across its three objectives: strengthening system capacity, connecting more Americans to care, and creating a continuum of support.<br><br><strong><u>Strengthen System Capacity</u></strong><br><br>At the center of our behavioral health crisis is a severe workforce shortage. We do not have enough providers, and they are not located in the right places or providing the right services to meet Americans’ needs. Even where there are sufficient providers, the fragmentation and inconsistency of the current system can make it difficult for people to find the right level of care. To address these needs, this month, the Administration is taking&nbsp;new&nbsp;actions to:<br><br><strong>Promote the mental well-being of our frontline health workforce.&nbsp;</strong>Even before the COVID-19 pandemic, health worker burnout had reached&nbsp;<a href="https://nap.nationalacademies.org/catalog/25521/taking-action-against-clinician-burnout-a-systems-approach-to-professional">“crisis”</a>&nbsp;levels – affecting up to 60 percent of frontline providers. To respond, the U.S. Surgeon General is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/05/23/new-surgeon-general-advisory-sounds-alarm-on-health-worker-burnout-and-resignation.html">issuing</a>&nbsp;the first-ever Advisory on Health Worker Burnout, which lays out whole-of-society recommendations to advance health worker well-being.<br><br><strong>Pilot new approaches to training behavioral health paraprofessionals.&nbsp;</strong>To better support veterans with substance use disorders, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) is hiring 277 new Peer Specialists, employees in recovery themselves specifically trained and certified to help fellow veterans. The Department of Defense (DOD) is also hiring roughly 2,500 new personnel over the next 6 years to comprehensively address risk for conditions like mental illness and substance use.<br><br><strong>Strengthen our crisis care and suicide prevention infrastructure.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will expand access to mobile crisis services in high-need communities by launching a Mental Health Crisis Response Partnership Pilot Program. DOD will also strengthen suicide prevention services for service members, by establishing and training military health providers in new, standardized procedures to promote the identification, treatment, and tracking of patients at risk of suicide.<br><br><strong>Build the capacity of long-term care facilities to deliver behavioral health care.&nbsp;</strong>HHS is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/05/16/hhs-announces-new-funding-opportunity-strengthen-behavioral-health-services-nursing-homes-other-long-term-care-facilities.html">launching</a>&nbsp;a new, $15 million funding opportunity to establish a Center of Excellence for Building Capacity in Nursing Facilities to Care for Residents with Behavioral Health Conditions, which will work to strengthen behavioral health care in long-term care facilities by improving mental health literacy and combating stigmatization among staff.<br><br><strong>Address our caregiving crisis.&nbsp;</strong>In partnership with the&nbsp;<a href="https://acl.gov/programs/support-caregivers/raise-family-caregiving-advisory-council">RAISE Family Caregiving</a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href="https://acl.gov/programs/support-caregivers/supporting-grandparents-raising-grandchildren-0">Supporting Grandparents Raising Grandchildren</a>&nbsp;Advisory Councils, HHS’s Administration for Community Living will submit a National Caregiving Strategy to Congress outlining new recommendations for better supporting family caregivers, many of whom have been under great strain during the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>This builds on prior Administration actions, including:</p>



<ul><li>HHS invested nearly $400 million to help states prepare for the July launch of 988, the new three-digit code for the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline. And the Center for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/press-releases/biden-harris-administration-awards-15-million-20-states-mobile-crisis-intervention">established</a>&nbsp;a new state option for Medicaid coverage of qualifying community-based mobile crisis intervention services.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>HHS awarded&nbsp;<a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/newsroom/press-announcements/202107291030">$250 million</a>&nbsp;across 100 grants to increase access to Certified Community Behavioral Health Centers (CCBHCs), which provide 24/7, comprehensive primary and behavioral health care – including crisis care – to the most vulnerable Americans.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Bright Futures, a HRSA partnership with the American Academy of Pediatrics,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2022/01/12/2022-00461/updates-to-the-bright-futures-periodicity-schedule">added</a>&nbsp;universal screening for suicide risk to its national guidelines for individuals ages 12 to 21.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>AmeriCorps invested $8 million through its new&nbsp;<a href="https://americorps.gov/about/what-we-do/public-health-americorps">Public Health AmeriCorps</a>&nbsp;to fund the recruitment of new AmeriCorps members to support individuals with mental health and substance use challenges.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>HHS invested&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/11/22/hhs-announces-record-health-care-workforce-awards-in-rural-underserved-communities.html">$1 billion</a>&nbsp;in the National Health Service Corps, Nurse Corps, and Substance Use Disorder Treatment and Recovery Loan Repayment Program, which has enabled these provider pipeline programs to amass the largest field strength in history.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>HHS awarded&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/01/20/biden-harris-administration-awards-103-million-american-rescue-plan-funds-reduce-burnout-promote-mental-health-wellness-among-health-care-workforce.html">$103 million</a>&nbsp;to 45 health care organizations to address burnout and strengthen resiliency among health care workers.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The President signed the bipartisan Dr. Lorna Breen Health Care Provider Protection Act into law, which&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aha.org/news/news/2022-03-18-dr-lorna-breen-health-care-provider-protection-act-signed-law">authorized</a>&nbsp;$135 million over three years to train health care providers on suicide prevention and behavioral health.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Connect Americans to Care</u></strong><br><br>Even when services are available, barriers like cost, cultural bias, and inconvenience prevent people from consistently accessing the care they need. On average, it takes&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nami.org/mhstats">11 years</a>&nbsp;after the onset of mental health symptoms for someone to seek treatment. It is critical that we make care affordable across all types of health insurance coverage, and integrate mental health services in ways that reduce stigmatization and access barriers. This month, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking&nbsp;new&nbsp;actions to:<br><br><strong>Advance behavioral health care for the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AANHPI) community.&nbsp;</strong>To reduce behavioral health-related disparities, HHS is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/05/17/hhs-announces-funding-opportunity-for-new-asian-american-native-hawaiian-pacific-islander-behavioral-health-center-of-excellence.html">announcing</a>&nbsp;a nearly $3.5 million, five-year grant opportunity to launch a new AANHPI Center of Excellence, which will promote culturally and linguistically appropriate behavioral health practices while providing training and technical assistance on addressing the mental health impacts of hate and unconscious bias against the AANHPI community.<br><br><strong>Lower barriers to behavioral health care among service members.&nbsp;</strong>To reduce concerns about potential negative impacts on military career progression, DOD is revising its policy that outlines requirements for notifying military commanders when service members seek mental health or substance use care.<br><br><strong>Ensure access to mental health support in schools, colleges and universities.</strong>&nbsp;The Department of Education is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/building-president-bidens-unity-agenda-education-department-urges-colleges-use-american-rescue-plan-funds-provide-mental-health-supports-students">issuing</a>&nbsp;new guidance to colleges and universities on how to use ARP relief funds to provide mental health and substance use disorder services on campus, including by hiring mental health professionals, expanding virtual counseling support, offering stress-reduction activities, building peer support programs, and erecting student-staffed crisis hotlines.<br><br><strong>Strengthen the federal government’s role as a model employer for behavioral health.&nbsp;</strong>In addition to facilitating access to comprehensive telebehavioral health benefits through the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) is working to reinvigorate Employee Assistance Programs provided by all federal agencies to better meet employees’ behavioral health needs, while disseminating best practices and new ideas for improving federal workplace mental health.<br><br>This builds on prior Administration actions, including:</p>



<ul><li>In January, federal agencies&nbsp;<a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/EBSA/laws-and-regulations/laws/mental-health-parity/report-to-congress-2022-realizing-parity-reducing-stigma-and-raising-awareness.pdf">issued</a>&nbsp;a detailed report about how to improve insurance company compliance with requirements related to mental health services. HHS also developed&nbsp;<a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/newsroom/press-announcements/20220427/hhs-new-mental-health-substance-use-disorder-benefit-resources">new resources</a>&nbsp;to help patients and state regulators better understand how to enforce their rights.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>ARP provided&nbsp;<a href="https://oese.ed.gov/offices/american-rescue-plan/american-rescue-plan-elementary-and-secondary-school-emergency-relief/">$122 billion</a>&nbsp;in relief funds for schools to help them reopen safely and address the social and emotional needs of students. As of April, the number of social workers in public schools has increased by 67 percent, and the number of counselors has increased by 18 percent, since the years before the pandemic.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>In March, HHS and the Department of Education&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/03/24/hhs-secretary-xavier-becerra-education-secretary-miguel-a-cardona-announce-joint-effort-develop-share-resources-ensure-children-have-access-school-based-health-services.html">announced</a>&nbsp;a joint effort to develop and share&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/school-based-health-services-resources.pdf">resources</a>&nbsp;to ensure that children have access to school-based health services.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>HHS invested $80 million in ARP funding into the Pediatric Mental Health Care Access program, which promotes integrating care for behavioral health needs into pediatric primary care settings.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The final&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/fact-sheets/calendar-year-cy-2022-medicare-physician-fee-schedule-final-rule">CY 2022 Medicare Physician Fee Schedule rule</a>&nbsp;increased access to telebehavioral health services, including by allowing certain services to occur via audio-only calls when video is unavailable, and by allowing Rural Health Clinics and Federally Qualified Health Centers to report and receive payment for telebehavioral health services.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Support Americans by Creating Healthy Environments</u></strong></p>



<p>No health problem can be addressed solely through the health care system. We must also invest in programs that can prevent mental health challenges and build environments that promote wellness and recovery. Decades of research show that coordinated prevention across settings can pay long-term dividends, including reductions in community violence. Similarly, when settings provide services and restorative programs that support individuals with mental health problems or other at-risk behaviors, they can promote broader social and economic gains. This month, the Biden-Harris Administration is taking&nbsp;new&nbsp;actions to:<br><br><strong>Train social and human services professionals in basic mental health skills.</strong>&nbsp;The Department of Agriculture (USDA) is launching a series of initiatives to improve mental health literacy among its partners and employees. It will give all public-facing employees who work with agricultural producers and grant recipients access to Mental Health First Aid Training and integrate more robust mental health messaging into its programs. And, it will support efforts to train 4-H volunteers and participants in social and emotional skills, help-seeking, and self-care.<br><br><strong>Train tribal law enforcement personnel in mental health.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Interior’s Bureau of Indian Affairs Office of Justice Services is implementing a Mental Health Crisis Instructor Training Program and a Resiliency Initiative to train officers on coping with stress; managing anxiety; providing psychological first aid; and identifying substance use disorder, depression, and post-traumatic stress in themselves and in colleagues.<br><br><strong>Enhance school-based supports in Native communities.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Interior’s Bureau of Indian Education is launching a Social and Emotional Learning Initiative for educators and staff, which will work to improve access to culturally relevant social and emotional learning supports at schools serving Native communities. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Spur innovation in recovery support models.</strong>&nbsp;HHS is&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/05/18/hhs-announces-its-first-ever-behavioral-health-recovery-innovation-challenge.html">launching</a>&nbsp;its first-ever behavioral health Recovery Innovation Challenge, which will disburse up to 10 awards totaling $400,000 to peer-run and community-based groups implementing innovative programs that advance recovery from substance use disorders. &nbsp;<br><br><strong>Improve financial security among veterans.&nbsp;</strong>VA is launching a National Center for Veterans Financial Empowerment to provide veterans with education, tools, and resources to successfully navigate financial strain, which has been associated with increased risk of suicide.<br><br><strong>Enforce workplace rights of the mentally ill.</strong>&nbsp;The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) is increasing outreach to mental health providers to support protections under the Americans with Disabilities Act. It is also committing to increase the accessibility of its technical assistance and guidance documents on mental health.</p>



<p><strong>Establish a federal research action plan on mental health.&nbsp;</strong>The underlying causes of most mental health conditions remain largely unknown.&nbsp;To fill this knowledge gap, the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/">White House Office of Science &amp; Technology Policy</a>&nbsp;is leading an effort to establish several new cross-agency research priorities for mental health as part of a broader coordinating effort on brain health. &nbsp;<br>This builds on prior Administration actions, including:</p>



<ul><li>HHS opened the first-ever&nbsp;<a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/about-us/who-we-are/offices-centers/or">Office of Recovery</a>&nbsp;at the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, dedicated to evaluating and initiating programs, policies, and services that center the needs and experiences of those in recovery.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>HHS’s Centers for Disease Control and Prevention announced new&nbsp;<strong>Comprehensive Suicide Prevention Program</strong>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.grants.gov/web/grants/view-opportunity.html?oppId=337047">funding</a>&nbsp;to support a comprehensive public health approach to suicide prevention with attention to disproportionately affected populations, such as veterans, rural communities, tribal, LGBTQ, and youth.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>EEOC has actively used its enforcement authority to combat unlawful disability discrimination against individuals based on their&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/newsroom/ranews-management-company-pay-250000-settle-disability-discrimination-lawsuit">mental health conditions</a>, their use of legally prescribed&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/newsroom/lonza-america-pay-150000-settle-eeoc-disability-lawsuit">opioid medications</a>, and their participation in substance use recovery programs. It has also&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/wysk/what-you-should-know-about-covid-19-and-ada-rehabilitation-act-and-other-eeo-laws">conducted</a>&nbsp;outreach and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/laws/guidance/depression-ptsd-other-mental-health-conditions-workplace-your-legal-rights">education</a>&nbsp;programs for&nbsp;<a href="https://content.govdelivery.com/accounts/USEEOC/bulletins/2cc9aa1">employers</a>&nbsp;emphasizing their obligations to treat employees with mental health conditions the same as those with any other disabilities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>USDA invested nearly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=%2425+million+in+the+form+of+50+grants+to+the+Farm+and+Ranch+Stress+Assistance+Network+projects">$25 million</a>&nbsp;in the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nifa.usda.gov/grants/programs/farm-ranch-stress-assistance-network-frsan">Farm and Ranch Stress Assistance Network</a>&nbsp;projects which to strengthen programs that provide professional behavioral health counseling and other services to individuals in agricultural occupations.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The Department of Education released&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.ed.gov/documents/students/supporting-child-student-social-emotional-behavioral-mental-health.pdf">Supporting Child and Student Social, Emotional, Behavioral and Mental Health</a>&nbsp;to enhance the promotion of mental health and the social and emotional well-being among children and students.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>CDC invested $15 million in the Healthy Schools program, which&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/chronicdisease/resources/publications/factsheets/healthy-schools.htm">works</a>&nbsp;with states, school systems, and national partners to improve the well-being of K-12 students.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The Surgeon General issued a new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-youth-mental-health-advisory.pdf">Advisory</a>&nbsp;to highlight the urgent need to address the nation’s youth mental health crisis – with particular attention to online harms and the impact of social media on young people’s mental health. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>HHS&nbsp;<a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/grants/grant-announcements/sm-22-013">announced</a>&nbsp;$2 million in funding to establish the new Center of Excellence on Social Media and Mental Wellness, which will develop and disseminate information, guidance, and training on the impact of children and youth social media use, especially the potential risks social media platforms pose to mental health.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President&#160;of Turkey</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/30/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-ibrahim-kalin-spokesperson-and-chief-advisor-to-the-president-of-turkey/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 21:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Dr. Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey. They discussed their ongoing support for Ukraine in the face of Russia’s continued aggression, as well as their respective efforts to enable Ukrainian agricultural exports to reach global markets. Mr. Sullivan expressed support&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Dr. Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey. They discussed their ongoing support for Ukraine in the face of Russia’s continued aggression, as well as their respective efforts to enable Ukrainian agricultural exports to reach global markets. Mr. Sullivan expressed support for Turkey’s continued direct talks with Sweden and Finland to resolve concerns over their applications for NATO membership, which the U.S. strongly supports. He also reiterated the importance of refraining from escalation in Syria to preserve existing ceasefire lines and avoid any further destabilization. Finally, Mr. Sullivan urged continued dialogue and diplomacy to resolve any disagreements in the eastern Mediterranean region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the 154th National Memorial Day&#160;Observance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/30/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-154th-national-memorial-day-observance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 19:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arlington National CemeteryArlington, Virginia 12:54 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; They lie here in glory and honor &#8212; in quiet rows in Arlington, in cemeteries in Europe that I visited and many of you have, in graves across our country, in towns large and small &#8212; America’s beloved daughters and sons who dared all,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Arlington National Cemetery<br>Arlington, Virginia</p>



<p>12:54 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They lie here in glory and honor &#8212; in quiet rows in Arlington, in cemeteries in Europe that I visited and many of you have, in graves across our country, in towns large and small &#8212; America’s beloved daughters and sons who dared all, risked all, and gave all to preserve and defend an idea unlike any other in human history: the idea of the United States of America.</p>



<p>And today, as a nation, we undertake a sacred ritual: to reflect and to remember.&nbsp; Because if we forget the lives that each of those silent markers represent &#8212; mothers, fathers, siblings, spouses, children &#8212; if we forget what they sacrificed, what they made so that our nation might endure strong, free, and united, then we forget who we are &#8212; who we are.</p>



<p>Ladies and gentlemen, our First Lady and the love of my life, Jill; Vice President Harris and the Second Gentleman; Secretary Austin; General Milley; the Joint Chiefs of Staff, Cabinet members; Gold Star families, most importantly; and survivors: Today we renew our sacred vow &#8212; it’s a simple vow: to remember.&nbsp; To remember.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Memorial Day is always a day where pain and pride are mixed together.&nbsp; We all know it, sitting here.&nbsp; Jill and I know it.&nbsp; Today is the day our son died.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, for those who have lost a loved one in the service of our country, if your loved one is missing or unaccounted for, I know the ceremonies reopen that black hole in the center of your chest that just pulls you in, suffocates you.</p>



<p>As I said, seven years ago today, our son, Major Beau Biden, took his last breath at Walter Reed.&nbsp; A major in the Delaware Army National Guard, he insisted on deploying to Iraq</p>



<p>with his unit for a year when he was attorney general.&nbsp; He came home a decorated soldier, a Bronze Star, Legion of Merit, and Delaware’s Conspicuous Service Cross.</p>



<p>He didn’t die in the line of duty.&nbsp; He came home from Iraq with cancer.&nbsp; It was a horrific cancer that stole us from him, stole &#8212; and him from us.</p>



<p>But still, it always feels to me on Memorial Day &#8212; I see him, not as he was the last time I held his hand, but the day I pinned his bars on him as a second lieutenant.</p>



<p>I see him with me down at the Delaware Memorial Bridge hugging all the Gold Star families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Days like this bring back, before your eyes, their smile and their laugh.&nbsp; And the last conversation you had, each of you know it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The hurt can be overwhelming.  But for so many of you, as is with Jill and me, the hurt is wrapped around the knowledge that your loved one was part of something bigger &#8212; bigger than any of us.</p>



<p>They chose a life of purpose.&nbsp; It sounds corny, like a Memorial Day speech, but I mean it from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; They chose a life of purpose.</p>



<p>They had a mission.&nbsp; And above all, they believed in duty; they believed in honor; they believed in their country.</p>



<p>And still today, we are free because they were brave.&nbsp; We live by the light of the flame of liberty that they kept burning.&nbsp; And so a part of them is still with us no matter how long ago we lost them.</p>



<p>And as hard as it is for many to believe, especially those whose loss is still raw, I promise you the day will come when the memory of your loved one, your patriot, will bring a smile to your lip before it brings a tear to your eye.&nbsp; That’s when you know you’re going to make it.</p>



<p>Today, America’s ser- &#8212; American service members stand watch around the world, and, as many of you know, often at great personal risk.</p>



<p>And this Memorial Day, we know the memory is still painful of all the fallen who lost their lives during the last two decades in combat.  Each of them leaving behind a family, a community.  Hearts broken by their absence, and lives that will never be the same.</p>



<p>We see in the hundreds of graves here in Section 60, at Arlington, a reminder that there’s nothing low-risk or low-cost about war for the women and men who fight it.</p>



<p>7,054 American military members gave their lives over 20 years of our Iraq and Afghan conflicts.&nbsp; Untold others died of injuries and illness connected to their service and these wars.</p>



<p>And the enduring grief borne by the survivors is a cost of war that we’ll carry as a nation forever.</p>



<p>And so, to every Gold Star family, to every survivor and family member and caregiver: This grateful nation owes you as well as that person you lost.</p>



<p>And we can never repay the sacrifice, but we will never stop trying.&nbsp; We’ll never fail in our duty to remember: With their lives, they bought our freedom.</p>



<p>And so, with our lives, we must always live up to their example &#8212; putting service before self; caring for our neighbors as ourselves; working fervently to bring our union just that much closer to fulfilling the founding creed, as the Secretary said, that all men and women are created equal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve often said that, as a nation, we have many obligations.&nbsp; But the only one that is truly sacred &#8212; the only truly sacred obligation we have &#8212; is to prepare and equip those women and men we send into harm’s way, and care for them and their families when they return home and when they don’t.</p>



<p>This is an obligation that unites Americans and brings us together &#8212; to make sure the women and men who are willing to lay down their lives for us get the very best from us in return.</p>



<p>I want to acknowledge that we’re making progress in key areas like the comprehensive, bipartisan legislation that is advancing in Congress that will deliver healthcare services and benefits to veterans and their survivors impacted by toxic exposures.</p>



<p>We don’t know how many Americans and service members may have died because of what they were exposed to on the battlefield.&nbsp; The toxic smoke from burn pits near where they were based &#8212; burn pits that incinerated the wastes of war, medical and hazardous material, jet fuel, and so much more.</p>



<p>But we have a duty to do right by them.&nbsp; And I am determined to make sure that our brave service families and members that served alongside them do not wait decades for the care and benefits that they deserve.&nbsp; And that’s why &#8212; that’s why we’re working so hard to find out what the facts are.&nbsp; Where we can still save lives, we have to act.</p>



<p>All of us also have a duty to renew our commitment to the foundational values of our nation, in their honor &#8212; for those are the values that have inspired generation after generation to service.</p>



<p>On Friday, I spoke at the graduation and commissioning of &#8212; ceremony of the U.S. Naval Academy.&nbsp; I had an opportunity to do that before as well.&nbsp; It was a remarkable experience again, an honor, looking out at those young men and women &#8212; newly commissioned officers &#8212; embarking on a life of service.</p>



<p>They hold before them the example of the heroes who have gone before them &#8212; many of you are family members &#8212; heroes who have answered duty’s call at Lexington and Concord, Antietam and Gettysburg, Belleau Woods and thee Battle of the Bulge, in Korea and Vietnam and Afghanistan, Iraq, and so many other places around the world &#8212; so many of whom never returned home, including the legacy of all those held prisoners of war or who are still missing in action.</p>



<p>To be here today, soon after that joyful celebration at the Academy, is a bracing reminder of all that we ask of our service members and their families &#8212; for it’s on the strong shoulders and noble spirits of our service members that our freedom is built, our democracy sustained.</p>



<p>And in this moment, when a war of aggression is once more being waged by Russia to snuff out the freedom, the democracy, the very culture and identity of neighboring Ukraine, we so &#8212; we see so clearly all that’s at stake.</p>



<p>Freedom has never been free.&nbsp; Democracy has always required champions.</p>



<p>And, today, in the perennial struggle for democracy and freedom, Ukraine and its people are on the frontlines fighting to save their nation.</p>



<p>But their fight is part of a larger fight that unites all people.&nbsp; It is a fight that so many of the patriots, whose eternal rest is here in these hallowed grounds, were part of.</p>



<p>A battle between democracy and autocracy, between liberty and repression, between appetites and ambition of a few who forever seek to dominate the lives and liberties of many.</p>



<p>A battle for essential democratic principles &#8212; the rule of law, free and fair elections, freedom to speak and write and to assemble, freedom to worship as one chooses, freedom of the press &#8212; principles that are essential for a free society.</p>



<p>You’ve heard this a lot.&nbsp; You’ve heard this a lot over the years, but we’re now realizing how real it is around the world in so many countries as I speak.&nbsp; These are the foundations of our great experiment, but they are never guaranteed, even here in America.</p>



<p>Every generation has to defeat democracy’s mortal foes.&nbsp; And into every generation, heroes are born, willing to shed their blood for that which they and we hold dear.</p>



<p>Ladies and gentlemen, today we remember and we reaffirm: Freedom is worth the sacrifice.&nbsp; Democracy is not perfect; it’s never been good &#8212; perfect.&nbsp; But it’s worth fighting for; if necessary, worth dying for.</p>



<p>It’s more than just our form of government, it is part of the very soul of America.&nbsp; The soul of America.</p>



<p>Our democracy is our greatest gift as a nation, made holy by those we’ve lost along the way.&nbsp; Our democracy is how we undertake the constant work of perfecting the union &#8212; and we have not perfected it, but we’ve never stopped trying; of opening the doors wider of opportunity and prosperity and justice for people everywhere.</p>



<p>Our democracy is how we endure through every challenge, overcome every obstacle we faced through the last 246 years of self-government, and how we’ve come back stronger than before.</p>



<p>We must never walk away from that.&nbsp; We must never betray the lives laid down to make our nation a beacon to the world &#8212; a  citadel of liberty and justice for everybody.</p>



<p>This is the mission of our time.&nbsp; Our memorial to them must not be just a day when we pause and pray, it must be a daily commitment to act, to come together, to be worthy of the price that was paid.</p>



<p>May God bring comfort to all those who mourn.&nbsp; May God bless our Gold Star families and survivors.&nbsp; And please, God, protect our troops.&nbsp;</p>



<p>God bless America and all of you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>1:09 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Marine One&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/30/remarks-by-president-biden-after-marine-one-arrival-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 18:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 9:15 A.M. EDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good morning, Mr. President.&#160; Do you feel more motivated to get action on guns now? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, I’ve been pretty motivated all along.&#160; You know, the folks &#8212; the folks who were victimized there, and their families, they spent 3 hours and 40 minutes with me.&#160; And they&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>9:15 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning, Mr. President.&nbsp; Do you feel more motivated to get action on guns now?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I’ve been pretty motivated all along.&nbsp; You know, the folks &#8212; the folks who were victimized there, and their families, they spent 3 hours and 40 minutes with me.&nbsp; And they waited all that time, and some came two hours early.</p>



<p>And &#8212; but the pain is palpable.&nbsp; And I think a lot of it is unnecessary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I’m going to continue to push, and we’ll see how this works.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to send long-range rocket systems to Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We’re not going to send to Ukraine rocket systems that can strike into Russia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, do you think there is anything different in how Republicans will approach the gun reform question now, given the circumstances?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Since I haven’t spoken to them, I don’t know.&nbsp; But my guess is, if they have &#8212; if they &#8212; yes, I think they’re going to have to take a hard look.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there one element &#8212; is it aid, is it red flag, is it some component that you think could be most successful now?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, that’s hard to say because I have not been negotiating with any of the Republicans yet.&nbsp; And I deliberately did not engage in a debate about that with any Republican in &#8212; when we were down consoling the families in Texas.&nbsp; So I don’t &#8212; I don’t know what is the most &#8212; how far it goes.</p>



<p>I know that it makes no sense to be able to purchase something that can fire up to 300 rounds.&nbsp; I know it makes &#8212; and I know what happened when we had rational action before, back in &#8212; when the crime bill was &#8212; the law that got passed.&nbsp; It did significantly cut down mass murders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so there’s only one reason for something that can fire, you know, 100 shots.</p>



<p>I mean &#8212; and I’ll just conclude with this: Look, when I first started doing hearings on the issue of what rational gun laws should be, it was during a period when I was a senator and the death rate was going up.&nbsp; Not that many more people were being shot, but the death rate was up.&nbsp; And when I think of &#8212; I’m not sure, I think it was (inaudible) hospital in New York &#8212; whatever the largest trauma hospital is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I sat with a trauma doctor, and I asked him &#8212; I said, “What’s the difference?&nbsp; Why are so many people…” &#8212; and not that many more people were being shot.&nbsp; This is now 20 years ago, or 25 years.&nbsp; I said, “Why are they dying?”&nbsp; And they showed me x-rays.&nbsp; He said, “A .22-caliber bullet will lodge in the lung, and we can probably get it out, may be able to get it, and save the life.&nbsp; A 9mm bullet blows the lung out of the body.”</p>



<p>So the idea of these high-caliber weapons is of &#8212; there’s simply no rational basis for it in terms of thinking about self-protection, hunting.&nbsp; I mean, I just &#8212; and remember, the Constitution, the Second Amendment was never absolute.&nbsp; You couldn’t buy a cannon when the Second Amendment was passed.&nbsp; You couldn’t go out and purchase a lot of weapons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And those who &#8212; not many are saying it anymore, but there was a while there where people were saying that, you know, the Tree of Liberty is watered with the blood of patriots, and what we have to do is you have to be able to take on the government when they’re wrong.&nbsp; Well, to do that, you need an F-15, you know?&nbsp; Or you need an Abrams tank.</p>



<p>I mean &#8212; so, it’s just &#8212; as I say, I think thing &#8212; I think things have gotten so bad that everybody is getting more rational about it.&nbsp; At least that’s my hope and prayer.</p>



<p>I’ve got Gold Star moms in there, so I got to go in.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, I know you want Congress to act, but do you believe that as President you have a particular responsibility now?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, I know I have it, but I &#8212; but there’s a Constitution.&nbsp; I can’t dictate this stuff.&nbsp; I can do the things that I’ve done.&nbsp; And any executive action I can take, I’ll continue to take.&nbsp; But I can’t outlaw a weapon.&nbsp; I can’t, you know, change the background checks.&nbsp; I can’t do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, my whole career, I’ve been doing it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And persuasion?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Persuasion, yeah.&nbsp; But, you know, there’s been a few things happening.&nbsp; I know you’ve noticed it.&nbsp; You’ve had to travel with me.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; McConnell has ordered a directive to Senator Cornyn to search for a compromise.&nbsp; Do you really think there’s something there?&nbsp; Or are they just making noise?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, I don’t know, but I think there’s a realization on the part of rational Republicans &#8212; and I think Senator McConnell is a rational Republican; I think Cornyn is as well.&nbsp; I think there’s a recognition in their part that they &#8212; we can’t continue like this.&nbsp; We can’t do this.</p>



<p>I’ve got to go in.&nbsp; I’ve got the Gold Star parents.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>9:20 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New&#160;Zealand</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/28/statement-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-jacinda-ardern-of-new-zealand/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, May 31, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand to the White House, for the first visit of a leader from New Zealand since 2014. The President and Prime Minister will continue to advance the U.S.-New Zealand partnership and their shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, May 31, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand to the White House, for the first visit of a leader from New Zealand since 2014. The President and Prime Minister will continue to advance the U.S.-New Zealand partnership and their shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific. The two Leaders will discuss strengthening cooperation to support the Pacific Islands region, and our work together on a range of issues, including the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, addressing the climate crisis, and countering terrorism and radicalization to violence both off and online. Vice President Harris will also meet with Prime Minister Ardern at the White House.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at the University of Delaware Commencement&#160;Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/28/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-university-of-delaware-commencement-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 20:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[University of DelawareNewark, Delaware 10:24 A.M. EDT AUDIENCE:&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe! THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; Thank you all.&#160; Is this working?&#160; There you go. Before you all sit down completely, the reason why you’re here is because of all of those people up in the stands.&#160; Stand up&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">University of Delaware<br>Newark, Delaware</p>



<p>10:24 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Is this working?&nbsp; There you go.</p>



<p>Before you all sit down completely, the reason why you’re here is because of all of those people up in the stands.&nbsp; Stand up and give your parents and your grandparents, and those who got you, an applause.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You owe them!&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to all the parents up in the stands, this may be the best day of all.&nbsp; No more tuition!&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; But probably all of them are going to graduate school, so that probably won’t work.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Dr.&nbsp;Assanis, trustees, faculty, the staff; my good friend &#8212; and he is my really good friend for a long time &#8212; Tommy &#8212; I call him “Tommy” &#8212; but Tom Carper &#8212; Senator Carper.&nbsp; Lisa Blunt Rochester, our congresswoman who can preach &#8212; this woman can preach.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And is really good.&nbsp; She’s a great congresswoman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the Class of 2022: Congratulations!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I know they’ve been recognized already, but I can’t &#8212; yesterday, I did the commencement at the Naval Academy, and it reminds me today: I want a special cons- &#8212; special congratulations to the veterans who are graduating today, all those who are being commissioned in the United States military.&nbsp; Would you please stand &#8212; of the graduating class?&nbsp; Stand up if you’re &#8212; (applause) &#8212;</p>



<p>And those of you have served as well in this class, stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And for all those of you who are joining the service or about to join the finest group of warriors the world has ever seen &#8212; and that’s not hyperbole; that’s literally true.&nbsp; So thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jill &#8212; better known as Dr. Biden &#8212; I happen to be her husband &#8212; not only earned her undergraduate degree here,</p>



<p>she also got her doctorate degree here.&nbsp; She got a master’s in between, somewhere else.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And the First Lady has continued to work full-time as a professor while being the First Lady.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, Gerret, you and I have something in common, pal: We both married way above our station.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not only can she speak five different languages, whatever language she’s speaking, you better damn well listen, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, I’m telling you, thank you.</p>



<p>And I want to say this is a special day for my sister Valerie and I.&nbsp; She’s my best friend in the world.&nbsp; She graduated here with honors.&nbsp; I graduated.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Oh, that’s literally true.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And we took the same damn classes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>We used to be three years apart, and now Val is 22 years&nbsp;</p>



<p>younger than I am.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But it feels like coming home because it is &#8212; this is home.&nbsp; This is home.</p>



<p>I once walked this campus as you did.&nbsp; Took the classes in the same classrooms you’ve taken classes.&nbsp; Walked the graduation ceremony just as you’re walking today.<a>&nbsp; Some of the best and most important years of my life were spent here.</a></p>



<p>And I had the opportunity to be taught by some great professors.&nbsp; I’ll bet every one of you already can name one or two professors that’s changed your life, that’s had an impact on you in a fundamental way.&nbsp; I was lucky &#8212; I graduated with a dual degree in history and political science.&nbsp; If you add up both my GPAs in each of those, I was probably a 4.0.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside,&nbsp;Dr. Dolan, from the political science department &#8212; I think he could picture me here in the endzone, maybe catching a pass over my left shoulder, but I doubt whether ever the hell he thought I’d be standing here as President of the United States.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Although,&nbsp;Dr. Ingersoll is the one &#8212; you know, professors make a difference.&nbsp; I was asked to seek the nomination by a group of people I won’t bore you with, and I thought it was a little off the wall that I was &#8212; I wasn’t even old enough.&nbsp; And I turned &#8212; it was after a Democratic off-year convention.&nbsp; And I turned to the Chief Justice, who was retired &#8212; from a family that has more senators than any family in American history: former Justice Tunnell.</p>



<p>And I said, “Mr. Justice, I’m not old enough.”&nbsp; He said, “You obviously didn’t do well in constitutional law, Joe.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, the Constitution says you need to be 30 to be sworn in, but you can be elected at any age they want to elect you.&nbsp; So why the hell I did it, I wasn’t sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I got in a car in Dover, and I drove straight to the campus.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And I looked up Dr. Ingersoll, one of my professors that I admired most; taught political philosophy.</p>



<p>And I told him the dilemma, because I hadn’t thought about that at all at the time.&nbsp; I really hadn’t.&nbsp; And he looked at me and he said, “Joe, remember what Plato said.”&nbsp; I’m thinking, “What the hell did Plato say?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And he paraphrased it.&nbsp; And he said: The penalty good people pay for not being involved in politics is being governed by people worse than themselves.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, it’s what I want to talk to you all about today.&nbsp; Though I think even my professors would be surprised if there’s a Biden School of Public Policy and Administration at the University of Delaware.&nbsp; Thank you, Tatiana.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>But no one is more surprised than me.&nbsp; And while I had graduated before I &#8212; he started teaching, I wanted to acknowledge the respect and the &#8212; that I had for Dr. James Newton, a trailblazer in Black American studies and the civil rights across our nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>If there’s one message&nbsp;I hope you take from me today,</p>



<p>it’s: This is no time to be on the sidelines.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; I mean it from the bottom of my heart.</p>



<p>We need all of you to get engaged in public life and the life of this nation.</p>



<p>Because here’s the simple truth: You’re graduating and entering a world at a momentous and consequential and defining time.</p>



<p>The next 10 years of your life are going to determine what the next 50 years of this nation are going to look like.&nbsp; We’re at one of those inflection points in history where things are changing so fundamentally that we have to act.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like the Americans in the 1850s and ‘60s &#8212; we had to decide whether to preserve slavery or become a free nation &#8212; truly free.</p>



<p>Like Americans in the ‘30s and ‘40s &#8212; President Roosevelt had said they had a “rendezvous with destiny,” at home and abroad.</p>



<p>Like Americans in the ‘60s, in my generation &#8212; when I sat where you’re sitting in 1965&nbsp;&#8212;&nbsp;were bitterly divided over the war in Vietnam.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We watched our heroes &#8212; two Kennedys and a King &#8212; gunned down by assassins and, still, we chose to expand the possibilities of America by breaking down unjust barriers&nbsp;</p>



<p>of civil rights and voting rights.</p>



<p>Well, now, it’s your hour.&nbsp; The challenges are immense &#8212; foreign and domestic &#8212; but so are the possibilities.</p>



<p>I spent time &#8212; more time with Xi Jinping than any world leader has &#8212; over 76 hours.&nbsp; We traveled 17,000 miles in China and the United States together.&nbsp; We were on the Tibetan Plateau, and he turned to me and said, “Can you define America for me?”&nbsp; And I said, “Yes, I can, in one word: possibilities.”&nbsp; Everything is possible in America.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Everything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe that with every fiber of my being this is a decisive decade for America, at a time when we can choose the future we want, at a time when we must decide that darkness will not prevail over light.</p>



<p>In the last five years since many of you were in high school, America has faced some of its most difficult tests.</p>



<p>A global pandemic ended a million lives in America alone &#8212; a million &#8212; and upended, according to most studies, the lives of &#8212; personal lives of at least another 9 million children and family members, and many of your lives.</p>



<p>And a crisis of faith in the institutions that have &#8212; however flawed they may be &#8212; serve as the infrastructure for the American experiment in liberty and self-government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve defined to my foreign colleagues and heads of state America when I was at the G7.&nbsp; I said America is unique in the world.&nbsp; We’re the only nation in the world founded on an idea.&nbsp; Every other nation is founded on ethnicity, religion, geography.&nbsp; But only America is founded on an idea: We hold these truths to be self-evident that all women and men are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable rights &#8212; life, liberty, the pursuit of happiness.</p>



<p>We say it so often.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never met the goal, but we&#8217;ve never walked away from it &#8212; ever.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And each generation has brought us closer to the goal.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what you&#8217;ve been through the last four years &#8212; and I&#8217;m not being solicitous with you &#8212; what you’ve been through the last four years, you could not have imagined when you were graduating from high school: campus shutdowns, classes on Zoom, the world turned upside down.</p>



<p>But you got through it.&nbsp; And it took an extraordinary commitment, determination, and resolve to do it.&nbsp; You should be proud you overcame it all to see this day.&nbsp; Your generation, and this class, can do anything.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I decided to seek the presidency.&nbsp; When I had concluded &#8212; I was a professor at Penn &#8212; I was never going to run again.&nbsp; And I meant that from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; I had just lost my son Beau.&nbsp; And I had no interest whatsoever.&nbsp; And I was teaching at Penn.&nbsp; And then, Charlottesville.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the United States of America, in the 20th century &#8212; 21st century &#8212; people coming out of fields at night carrying torches.</p>



<p>Close your eyes.&nbsp; Remember what you saw.&nbsp; Their veins bulging, preaching the same hate &#8212; white supremacy; chanting the same Nazi phrases &#8212; not figuratively, literally &#8212; that were being chanted in the ‘30s in Europe.&nbsp; Torches lit again.</p>



<p>You know, when I was a young senator, I was proud to be the senator who actually got Strom Thurmond to vote for the Voting Rights Act.&nbsp; I got it extended 25 years, and I thought, “You can bury hate.&nbsp; You can wipe it out.”&nbsp; But I learned a lesson: You can&#8217;t eliminate hate.&nbsp; It only hides when it&#8217;s defeated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But when the prominent leaders are leader- &#8212; breathe oxygen under the rocks it&#8217;s hiding in, it takes on a new life.&nbsp; It comes roaring back out in ways, I must tell you, I never thought would happen.&nbsp; Because I got into politics sitting where you&#8217;re sitting because of civil rights in Delaware.</p>



<p>And then, nearly four years later, a mob of insurrectionists stormed the Capitol &#8212; the very citadel of democracy.</p>



<p>Imagine what you&#8217;d be thinking today if you had heard this morning, before you got here, that a group of a thousand people broke down the doors of the Parliament in Great Britain, killed two police officers, smashed and ransacked the office of members of the British Parliament, or any other.&nbsp; What would you think?&nbsp; What would you think?</p>



<p>And then, just this month, we thought that white supremacy</p>



<p>was finally being got hold of.</p>



<p>Buffalo, New York: A shopping center in a Black community.&nbsp; I went and met with every one of those parents, every one of those families.</p>



<p>And now, tomorrow, I&#8217;ll be heli- &#8212; I&#8217;ll be heading to Uvalde, Texas, to meet with each of those families.</p>



<p>And as I speak, those parents are literally preparing to bury their children in the United States of America &#8212; to bury their children.&nbsp; There’s too much violence, too much fear, too much grief.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s be clear: Evil came to that elementary school classroom in Texas, to that grocery store in New York, to far too many places where innocents have died.</p>



<p>In the face of such destructive forces, we have to stand stronger.&nbsp; We must stand stronger.&nbsp; We cannot outlaw tragedy, I know, but we can make America safer.</p>



<p>We can finally do what we have to do to protect the lives of the people and of our children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I call on all Americans this hour to join hands and make your voices heard and work together to make this nation what it can and should be.</p>



<p>I know we can do this.&nbsp; We have done it before.&nbsp; You and I acted as “We the People” seeking a more perfect union.</p>



<p>Always remember: Democracy is a human enterprise.&nbsp; We do many things well.&nbsp; Sometimes we fall short.&nbsp; That&#8217;s true in our own lives; it’s true in the life of the nation.&nbsp; And yet democracy makes progress possible.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And progress comes when we begin to see each other again, not as enemies but as neighbors.</p>



<p>When I spoke yesterday at Annapolis, I finished by talking about my friend &#8212; he was my close friend; on his deathbed, asked me to do his eulogy &#8212; who would scream at each other and holler like hell at one another: John McCain.&nbsp; Very different views.&nbsp; We still loved one another.</p>



<p>Not as mindless, competing factions, but as fellow citizens.&nbsp; Learned anew, in their own &#8212; on their own time that democracy is fragile, democracy is precious, but it&#8217;s also precarious.</p>



<p>Truth is truth.&nbsp; Lies are lies.&nbsp; And the truth is: We have a solemn duty to keep the flame of liberty burning.&nbsp; This is not about blue and red, rural and urban.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about America.&nbsp; The right to govern ourselves.&nbsp; The right to determine our own destinies, to overcome division and despair, and to meet the challenges of our time with grit and, maybe equally important, with some grace.&nbsp; To press ahead determined, resolved, and full of hope.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not easy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s never been.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s who we are &#8212; people united by a idea &#8212; by an idea, unbending in the face of adversity, and devoted to creating and sustaining the beloved nation of ours.</p>



<p>You don’t have to take my word for it.&nbsp; Frederick Douglass said it better.&nbsp; He said, “No soil is better adapted to growth of reform than [the] American soil.”</p>



<p>The women of Seneca Falls call for suffrage by writing, “We hold these truths to be self-evident that all&nbsp;<em>women</em>&nbsp;and men are created equal.”</p>



<p>Dr. King said his dream of liberty for all was deeply rooted in the American Dream &#8212; the right to life, liberty, the pursuit of happiness; the right to rise in the world as far as your talent can take you, unlimited by unfair barriers of privilege and power.</p>



<p>Such are the principles of democracy, and such are the principles of America.</p>



<p>And I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m exercising hyperbole.&nbsp; I’ve been around too long.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what is at stake today.</p>



<p>The question we face is nothing less than: “Who are we?”&nbsp; “What do we stand for?”&nbsp; “What do we believe?”&nbsp; And maybe more importantly, “Who are we going to be?”</p>



<p>And while this can feel like a very dark moment in America,</p>



<p>I&#8217;m optimistic.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve never been more optimistic in my entire life.&nbsp; And here&#8217;s why &#8212; and I mean this, my word as a Biden.</p>



<p>I mean it.&nbsp; Because of you &#8212; this generation, your generation &#8212; it makes me more optimistic.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve said it many times, as I look at my granddaughters who all graduated from universities and about to enter them &#8212; I&#8217;ll say it again today: Your generation is the most generous, the most tolerant, the least prejudiced, the best-educated generation this nation has ever known.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a simple fact.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And it’s your generation, more than anyone else, who will have to answer the question, “Who are we?”&nbsp; “What do we stand for?”&nbsp; “What do we believe?”&nbsp; “Who will we be?”</p>



<p>Progress in our country has always been met with ferocious pushback from the oldest and darkest forces in America.&nbsp; Always.</p>



<p>We should not be surprised that these same forces are fighting back again, preying on hopelessness and despair; demonizing people who don&#8217;t look like them; doing everything, no matter how desperate, to hold on to power.</p>



<p>This was never going to be an easy battle, and it never has been, because it&#8217;s occurred before in America.</p>



<p>The oldest and darkest forces in the past may believe they&#8217;ll determine America&#8217;s future.&nbsp; But I promise you &#8212; remember I said this, if you remember nothing that I said at this graduation: They are wrong.&nbsp; Wrong, wrong, wrong.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will, you will &#8212; in this moment, in this battle, we will not lose the right to vote, the right to self-determination, the right to choose, the right to be you, and marry the person you love.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We must and will stand together to save the planet and preserve democracy.</p>



<p>When America was literally facing war with itself when Lincoln was President &#8212; excuse me &#8212; when Lincoln was President, Lincoln reminded us.&nbsp; He said, “Let&#8217;s have faith that right makes might.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Right makes might.</p>



<p>This is an essential principle of the soul of America.&nbsp; I mean it sincerely &#8212; the soul of America.&nbsp; The principle must guide you and your lives regardless of your politics &#8211;conservative or liberal &#8212; but just human decency.&nbsp; The principle that guides me and my administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For we can and will and should disagree about the means of governance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what democracy is about as well.&nbsp; But we have to be unified in the purpose of America: to create possibility, prosperity; protect decency and dignity; to be free and fair.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just think about who we are.&nbsp; The bloodiest civil wars led the abolition of slavery.&nbsp; Generation after generation who stood against totalitarianism and terror.</p>



<p>And while we, the people, have undertaken great enterprises when building interstates, to finding vaccines, to going to the stars &#8212; in all these moments, we were driven, as we are today, by the most American of principles: that we the people have created the strongest, freest, most prosperous nation the world has ever known.&nbsp; And again, that is not hyperbole, it&#8217;s a fact.</p>



<p>Now, in this moment, we face our own test: to resolve &#8212; a test of resolve, a test of conscience, a test of history itself.</p>



<p>No generation gets to choose what world they graduate into.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; But a few &#8212; a few generations enter at a point in history where they have the power to change the trajectory of a nation.&nbsp; And you can.</p>



<p>When I sat where you are, in the mid-‘60s, I believed we could.&nbsp; And we did, through civil rights, change the trajectory of the nation.</p>



<p>And now I know that may feel like an added burden on top of all you&#8217;ve already been through.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not saying you have to shoulder the burden on your own.&nbsp; The task at hand and the task ahead is the work of all of us.&nbsp; What I am saying is you represent the best of us.&nbsp; You literally represent the best of us &#8212; a better America than we are today.</p>



<p>A generation &#8212; your generation will not be ignored, will not be shunned, and will not be silenced.&nbsp; You have an opportunity to not only reaffirm but to breathe new life into America&#8217;s most important values: equality, fairness, justice.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what I felt like all those years ago when I sat where you are sitting today.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t think I was going to be President of the United States.&nbsp; It wasn’t like “I’m going to be President” &#8212; although I loved reading the biographies.&nbsp; Everybody knew I was going to be President when I was in high school.&nbsp; I had no idea of it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But for all the uncertainty in the world, this university gave me confidence in myself to engage, to get involved, because I believed I could make a difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My sister Valerie and I come from very modest backgrounds.&nbsp; A three-bedroom, split-level home in a decent neighborhood; four kids and a grandpop living with us.&nbsp; We never felt we were poor, but we never had &#8212; we had trouble making the tuition, which was 300 bucks a year.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Or semester, I should say.</p>



<p>I hope you feel that way today, though, that you can change things.&nbsp; Because that&#8217;s what I see in all of you.&nbsp; You can make the difference.&nbsp; You can lift the country up.&nbsp; You can meet the challenges of our time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve always believed this nation can be defined by one word, as I said before: possibilities.&nbsp; It&#8217;s still true today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so to the University Class of 2022, there is no limit on what you can do.&nbsp; I promise you.</p>



<p>So get going, for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp; Godspeed on your journey.&nbsp; Keep the faith.&nbsp; And take it back &#8212; please.&nbsp; This is yours.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Take it back!&nbsp; We need you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; I really mean it &#8212; I believe in you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>10:51 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
