<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 12:43:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on&#160;Vesak</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/statement-by-president-biden-on-vesak-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 12:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I extend warm wishes to Buddhists in the United States and around the world as they celebrate Vesak. This sacred day is a time to reflect on the Buddha’s teachings, including the need to work for peace and justice, recognize our common humanity, respect and preserve the nature that surrounds us, and cultivate&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I extend warm wishes to Buddhists in the United States and around the world as they celebrate Vesak. This sacred day is a time to reflect on the Buddha’s teachings, including the need to work for peace and justice, recognize our common humanity, respect and preserve the nature that surrounds us, and cultivate humility and compassion. The Buddha taught that we are but guests visiting this world, and for over 2,500 years, those who adhere to these teachings have enriched and strengthened this world we share. As we mark Vesak, we honor the American Buddhists who contribute so much to our country and advance our common values.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council Establishes Economic and Technology Policies &#038;&#160;Initiatives</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/fact-sheet-u-s-eu-trade-and-technology-council-establishes-economic-and-technology-policies-initiatives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Policies Will Strengthen Our Economic Partnership, and Update Rules of Global Economy Read the U.S.-EU Joint Statement here. The U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council (TTC) held its second ministerial meeting in Saclay &#8211; Paris, France on May 15-16, 2022. U.S. co-chairs, Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, and United&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New Policies Will Strengthen Our Economic Partnership, and Update Rules of Global Economy</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Read the U.S.-EU Joint Statement <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/TTC-US-text-Final-May-14.pdf">here</a>.</em></p>



<p>The U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council (TTC) held its second ministerial meeting in Saclay &#8211; Paris, France on May 15-16, 2022. U.S. co-chairs, Secretary of State Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, and United States Trade Representative Katherine Tai were joined by EU Co-Chairs European Commission Executive Vice Presidents Margrethe Vestager and Valdis Dombrovskis to review progress, meet with a range of U.S. and EU stakeholders, and advance Transatlantic cooperation and democratic approaches to trade, technology, and security that deliver for people on both sides of the Atlantic. </p>



<p>Thanks to the close and enduring ties between the United States and the European Union, we have resolved long-standing bilateral issues, including disagreements on tariffs, and leveraged the strength of our partnership to counter non-market, trade distortive practices, and respond swiftly to Putin’s war with unprecedented sanctions and export control measures. Building on these successes, the United States and European Union, home to 780 million people who share democratic values and the largest economic relationship in the world, will advance the TTC agenda on a number of critical economic and technology policies and initiatives designed to strengthen our bilateral economies, meet current geopolitical challenges and update the rules of the global economy.</p>



<p>TTC working groups are deepening U.S.-EU cooperation by expanding access to digital tools for small- and medium-sized enterprises and securing critical supply chains such as semiconductors. They are collaborating closely on emerging technology standards, climate and clean tech objectives data governance and technology platforms, information and communications technology services’ (ICTS) security and competitiveness, and the misuse of technology threatening security and human rights. The TTC working groups are also coordinating on export controls, investment screening and security risks, and a range of global trade challenges, including countering the harmful impact of non-market, trade-distortive policies and practices on technological development and competitiveness in sectors of shared priority. To ensure that the government dialogues are informed by the broad perspectives of the U.S. and EU communities inform their work, the TTC working groups are continuing robust engagement with a diverse range of stakeholders, including those in industry, labor organizations, think tanks, non-profit organizations, environmental constituencies, academics, and other civil society members.</p>



<p>During their ministerial meeting, the U.S. and EU TTC co-chairs reviewed the outcomes generated by the joint working groups and announced key outcomes including:</p>



<ul><li>Deeper information exchange on exports of critical U.S. and EU technology, with an initial focus on Russia and other potential sanctions evaders, coordination of U.S. and EU licensing policies, and cooperation with partners beyond the United States and the European Union;</li><li>Development of a joint roadmap on evaluation and measurement tools for trustworthy Artificial Intelligence and risk management, as well as a common project on privacy-enhancing technologies;</li><li>Creation of a U.S.-EU Strategic Standardization Information (SSI) mechanism to enable information sharing on international standards development;</li><li>An early warning system to better predict and address potential semiconductor supply chain disruptions as well as a Transatlantic approach to semiconductor investment aimed at ensuring security of supply and avoiding subsidy races;</li><li>A dedicated taskforce to promote the use of trusted/non-high-risk ICTS suppliers through financing for deployments in third countries;</li><li>A new Cooperation Framework on issues related to information integrity in crises, particularly on digital platforms, with a focus on ongoing issues related to Russian aggression, including Russia’s actions to manipulate and censor information;</li><li>A stakeholder-focused Trade and Labor Dialogue to discuss policy options to promote internationally recognized labor rights and to help workers and firms make successful digital and green transitions, remain globally competitive, and enjoy broad and inclusive prosperity;</li><li>An early dialogue on shared trade concerns regarding third-countries measures or initiatives and an early stage consultation mechanism regarding bilateral barriers that may disadvantage the transatlantic economy;</li><li>A policy dialogue aimed at developing responses to global food security challenges caused by Russian aggression in Ukraine; and</li><li>A <a href="https://www.trade.gov/useuttc-cybersecurity">U.S.-EU guide</a> to cybersecurity best practices for small- and medium-sized companies, whose business is impacted disproportionally from cyber threats.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson Welcoming the Resumption of Flights from&#160;Sana’a</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-welcoming-the-resumption-of-flights-from-sanaa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 11:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States welcomes the resumption of direct flights between Sana’a, Yemen and Amman, Jordan.  These are the first commercial flights from Sana’a since 2016, and they demonstrate the ongoing benefits for the Yemeni people from the UN-brokered truce that went into effect nearly six weeks ago.  Yemen today is witnessing its calmest period since&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States welcomes the resumption of direct flights between Sana’a, Yemen and Amman, Jordan.  These are the first commercial flights from Sana’a since 2016, and they demonstrate the ongoing benefits for the Yemeni people from the UN-brokered truce that went into effect nearly six weeks ago.  Yemen today is witnessing its calmest period since the war began, and these flights are an important step in further improving the lives and opportunities for the Yemeni people.  The United States thanks Saudi Arabia for its leadership in helping to overcome obstacles to the resumption of these flights.  We also thank the Government of Jordan and the Republic of Yemen Government’s efforts in finalizing the arrangements for what should be the first of regular flights between these destinations.  The United States, led by the efforts of Special Envoy Tim Lenderking, supports continued diplomatic engagement between the parties and UN Special Envoy Hans Grundberg’s efforts to further improve freedom of movement inside Yemen, including by opening roads in Taiz and other areas.  The United States remains committed to supporting Yemen’s sovereignty, stability, security, and prosperity through an inclusive, UN-led political process to assist the Yemeni people in determining their country’s future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces New Actions to Ease the Burden of Housing&#160;Costs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/president-biden-announces-new-actions-to-ease-the-burden-of-housing-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Biden-Harris Administration Housing Supply Action Plan To Help Close the Housing Supply Gap in Five Years As President Biden said last week, tackling inflation is his top economic priority. Today, President Biden is releasing a Housing Supply Action Plan to ease the burden of housing costs over time, by boosting the supply of quality&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>New Biden-Harris Administration Housing Supply Action Plan To Help Close the Housing Supply Gap in Five Years</em></strong></p>



<p>As President Biden said last week, tackling inflation is his top economic priority. Today, President Biden is releasing a Housing Supply Action Plan to ease the burden of housing costs over time, by boosting the supply of quality housing in every community. His plan includes legislative and administrative actions that will help close America’s housing supply shortfall in 5 years, starting with the creation and preservation of hundreds of thousands of affordable housing units in the next three years. When aligned with other policies to reduce housing costs and ensure affordability, such as rental assistance and downpayment assistance, closing the gap will mean more affordable rents and more attainable homeownership for Americans in every community. This is the most comprehensive all of government effort to close the housing supply shortfall in history.</p>



<p>The Plan will help renters who are struggling with high rental costs, with a particular focus on building and preserving rental housing for low- and moderate-income families. The Plan’s policies to boost supply are an important element of bringing homeownership within reach for Americans who, today, cannot find an affordable home because there are too few homes for sale in their communities. And it will help reduce price pressures in the economy, as housing costs make up about one-third of of the market basket for inflation, as measured by the Consumer Price Index.</p>



<p>Under the Plan, the Administration will:</p>



<ul><li><strong><em>Reward jurisdictions that have reformed zoning and land-use policies</em></strong> with higher scores in certain federal grant processes, for the first time at scale.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><em>Deploy new financing mechanisms to build and preserve more housing where financing gaps currently</em></strong> <strong><em>exist</em></strong>: manufactured housing (including with chattel loans that the majority of manufactured housing purchasers rely on), accessory dwelling units (ADUs), 2-4 unit properties, and smaller multifamily buildings.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><em>Expand and improve existing forms of federal financing</em></strong>, including for affordable multifamily development and preservation. This includes making Construction to Permanent loans (where one loan finances the construction but is also a long-term mortgage) more widely available by exploring the feasibility of Fannie Mae purchase of these loans; promoting the use of state, local, and Tribal government COVID-19 recovery funds to expand affordable housing supply; and announcing reforms to the Low Income Housing Tax Credit (LIHTC), which provides credits to private investors developing affordable rental housing, and the HOME Investment Partnerships Program (HOME), which provides grants to states and localities that communities use to fund a wide range of housing activities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><em>Ensure that more government-owned supply of homes and other housing goes to owners who will live in them</em></strong> – or non-profits who will rehab them – not large institutional investors.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Work with the private sector to address supply chain challenges and improve building techniques to <strong><em>finish construction in 2022 on the most new homes in any year since 2006</em></strong>.</li></ul>



<p>Today’s rising housing costs are years in the making.&nbsp; Fewer new homes were built in the decade following the Great Recession than in any decade since the 1960s – constraining housing supply and failing to keep pace with demand and household formation. &nbsp;This mismatch between housing supply and housing demand grew during the pandemic. While estimates vary, <a href="https://www.moodysanalytics.com/-/media/article/2021/Overcoming-the-Nations-Housing-Supply-Shortage.pdf">Moody’s Analytics estimates</a> that the shortfall in the housing supply is more than 1.5 million homes nationwide. This shortfall burdens family budgets, drives up inflation, limits economic growth, maintains residential segregation, and exacerbates climate change. &nbsp;Rising housing costs have burdened families of all incomes, with a particular impact on low- and moderate-income families, and people and communities of color.</p>



<p>As his Action Plan reflects, President Biden believes the best thing we can do to ease the burden of housing costs is to boost the supply of quality housing. This means building more new homes and preserving existing federally-supported and market-rate affordable housing, ensuring that total new units do not merely replace converted or dilapidated units that get demolished.</p>



<p>The President continues to urge Congress to pass investments in housing production and preservation. One independent <a href="https://www.novoco.com/notes-from-novogradac/more-12-billion-lihtc-provisions-and-nearly-6-billion-neighborhood-homes-tax-credits-nov-3-draft">analysis</a> of proposals in the House of Representatives-passed reconciliation bill found that the housing-related proposals would finance close to 1 million affordable homes. Key provisions, like the expansion of LIHTC and the Neighborhood Homes Tax Credit, have received bipartisan support. The President’s 2023 Budget includes investments in housing supply that would lead to the production or rehabilitation of another 500,000 homes.</p>



<p>Building on the actions the Administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/01/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-immediate-steps-to-increase-affordable-housing-supply/">announced</a> last September to build and rehabilitate 100,000 homes over the next three years, these legislative proposals and the new administrative steps being launched – in partnership with state, local, for-profit, and non-profit partners – can put the economy on a path to closing the housing supply gap in the next five years.</p>



<p><strong><u>Providing Incentives for Land Use and Zoning Reform and Reducing Regulatory Barriers</u></strong></p>



<p>One of the most significant issues constraining housing supply and production is the lack of available and affordable land, which is in large part driven by state and local zoning and land use laws and regulations that limit housing density. Exclusionary land use and zoning policies constrain land use, artificially inflate prices, perpetuate historical patterns of segregation, keep workers in lower productivity regions, and limit economic growth. &nbsp;Reducing regulatory barriers to housing production has been a <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-02-20/utah-pro-housing-bill-is-zoning-reform-red-state-style">bipartisan</a> cause in a number of states throughout the country. It’s time for the same to be true in Congress, as well as in more states and local jurisdictions throughout the country.</p>



<p>To that end, the Administration is taking the following <strong><em>immediate steps</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Leveraging transportation funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law (BIL).</strong> Earlier this year, the Administration began using federal transportation programs to encourage state and local governments to boost housing supply, where consistent with current statutory requirements. For example, this year, the U.S. Department of Transportation (DOT) released three funding applications for competitive grant programs totaling nearly $6 billion in funding that reward jurisdictions that have put in place land-use policies to promote density and rural main street revitalization with higher scores in the grant process. Today, the Administration is announcing that DOT will continue to include language encouraging locally driven land use reform, density, rural main street revitalization, and transit-oriented development in BIL and other transportation discretionary grant programs.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Integrating affordable housing into DOT Programs. </strong>DOT will also issue updated program guidelines that increase financial support for Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act (TIFIA) program projects that include residential development.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Including land use within the U.S. Economic Development Administration’s (EDA) investment priorities</strong>.EDA evaluates all project applications for its competitive grants to determine the extent to which they align with EDA’s <a href="https://eda.gov/about/investment-priorities/">investment priorities</a>. EDA already includes transit-oriented and infill development within its “Environmentally-Sustainable Development” priority. Over the coming year and before its next round of grants, EDA will add language to its investment priorities to encourage economic development projects that enhance density in the vicinity of the development.</li></ul>



<p>These actions build on the strategies that the <strong><em>Administration has proposed and continues to call on Congress to pass</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Unlocking Possibilities Program</strong>. The Unlocking Possibilities Program, proposed by President Biden and included in the reconciliation bill passed by the House last year, would establish a new, $1.75 billion competitive grant program, administered by HUD, to help states and localities eliminate needless barriers to affordable housing production, including permitting for manufactured housing communities.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Housing Supply Fund grants to reduce affordable housing barriers.</strong> Building on the Unlocking Possibilities Program, the President’s 2023 Budget includes a mandatory spending proposal that would provide $10 billion in HUD Grants to Reduce Affordable Housing Barriers for states and localities that have already adopted Housing Forward policies and practices to address challenges to housing supply production constraints. While Unlocking Possibilities would help states and localities undertake reform, the Housing Supply Fund would reward those that have already made reforms by giving them additional funding to boost the affordability and maximize the benefits of their new policies. This funding would also support broader housing development activities, including environmental planning and mitigation, road infrastructure, and water or sewer infrastructure.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Piloting New Financing for Housing Production and Preservation</u></strong></p>



<p>A second, significant barrier to increasing housing supply is a lack of attractive and low-cost financing for new construction and rehabilitation – particularly for units that are affordable. While the federal government currently offers a range of financing options for large multifamily development, market gaps exist for the construction and rehabilitation of single-family homes, 2-4-unit properties, ADU construction, manufactured and modular housing delivery, and smaller multifamily properties. Financing for these housing types has the potential to boost supply in constrained markets, and create location-efficient, modest density that can improve labor market outcomes and reduce greenhouse gas emissions – particularly when paired with state and local policies that remove barriers to where these kinds of housing can be located. &nbsp;</p>



<p>To that end, the Administration is taking the following <strong><em>immediate steps</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting production and availability of manufactured housing.</strong> The majority of people buying new manufactured homes rely on personal property financing (chattel lending) rather than conventional mortgages. This type of financing typically costs more than traditional mortgage financing due to higher interest rates and shorter loan terms. Freddie Mac has announced that it will complete a feasibility assessment for the requirements and processes necessary to support loan purchases of personal property manufactured housing loans. If FHFA approval is obtained, Freddie Mac will purchase these kinds of loans to assist with product design and support future loan purchase capabilities. Beyond personal property financing, both Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac (the Enterprises), in their Duty to Serve Plans, also released revised purchase targets for manufactured housing loans, which will have the effect of fostering greater liquidity for manufactured housing and increasing delivery of manufactured homes. Finally, recognizing the cost and development time savings provided by manufactured housing, HUD is making it easier to finance new units and helping manufacturers update their designs to meet changing consumer demands. This includes working to increase the usability of FHA’s Title I loan program for Manufactured Housing, supporting greater securitization of Title I loans through Ginnie Mae’s platform, updating the HUD Code to allow manufacturers to modernize and expand their production lines, and helping manufacturers respond to supply chain issues.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Scaling Up ADUs and piloting ADU and home renovation financing tools. </strong>As the Biden-Harris Administration highlighted at a recent <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C-vzPIHUTts">event</a>, a number of states and local jurisdictions have made land-use changes to permit the construction and renovation of ADUs, which can offset the cost of homeownership while expanding the supply of affordable rental housing. According to a recent independent <a href="https://www.urban.org/sites/default/files/publication/105265/the-role-of-single-family-housing-production-and-preservation-in-addressing-the-affordable-housing-supply-shortage.pdf">analysis</a>, these kinds of state and local reforms – when combined with policies to improve financing options – could lead to the creation of more than 1 million ADUs in the next five years. In addition to zoning and land use changes, achieving that goal will require simpler and more affordable financing options for homeowners and builders. To that end, FHA and FHFA are exploring avenues to help lenders pilot and scale renovation and construction financing for ADUs—particularly for low- and moderate-income homeowners – in addition to new financing options for other single-family renovations and for 2-4-unit rehabilitation. FHA and FHFA will evaluate the credit performance of these loans to identify opportunities to add features and flexibilities to existing loan programs, expanding affordable financing options for homeowners and builders.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Boosting rural single-family construction. </strong>USDA’s Construction to Permanent program, allows approved lenders and homebuilders participating in the Single Family Housing Guaranteed Loan program to close both construction and permanent financing at the same time and receive a loan note guarantee before construction begins. This additional certainty has the effect of encouraging more single-family supply to be built more quickly in rural areas throughout the country. In the months ahead, USDA will educate lenders on the benefits of the program in order to improve program utilization, increase new construction in rural areas, and address obstacles that may be limiting use of the program.</li></ul>



<p>These actions build on the strategies that the <strong><em>Administration has proposed and continues to call on Congress to pass</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Provide tax credits to build and rehabilitate 125,000 homes for low- and middle-income homebuyers. </strong>The Neighborhood Homes Investment Act, proposed by the President and included in last year’s reconciliation bill, would provide tax credits to encourage investment in the millions of homes that are otherwise too costly or difficult to develop or rehabilitate. It also requires that these homes are sold to owner-occupants, rather than large investors. This investment would boost the supply of affordable homes for low- and moderate-income homebuyers who have struggled with historically low availability of affordable, starter homes – and has received bipartisan support in Congress.  </li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Provide Housing Supply Fund financing for affordable housing production to develop 500,000 units of housing for low- and moderate-income renters and homebuyers.</strong> The President’s 2023 Budget includes a proposal for $25 billion for Grants for Affordable Housing Production. These resources would be distributed to State and local housing finance agencies and their partners, territories, and Tribes, and would be focused on streamlining financing tools to reduce transaction costs and increase housing supply through multifamily and single-family housing units of modest density (up to 100 units per site). HUD will encourage grantees to develop housing that directly meet identified local needs, especially housing that is not sufficiently provided by the market. This includes intergenerational housing, investments that place vacant or underutilized properties back into productive use, ADUs, and novel and non-traditional development techniques, including modular, panelized, or manufactured housing. States and localities would have flexibility to design their programs to meet local needs, and the resources would be used to support renters and homebuyers with up to 150 percent of area median income in high-cost areas. These investments, combined with complementary proposals in the Budget, would support the development of around 500,000 units of housing over the next 10 years.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Improving and Expanding Existing Federal Financing</u></strong></p>



<p>Multiple forms of federal financing have played a critical role over the years in boosting affordable housing supply. But more production is needed to make up for more than a decade of underbuilding before the pandemic, and existing programs need to work more effectively and efficiently in order to boost housing production at a pace that will close the housing shortfall in 5 years.</p>



<p>To that end, the Administration is taking the following <strong><em>immediate steps</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Strengthening Enterprise financing for multifamily development and rehabilitation. </strong>Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac are working to determine how to expand and better market their forward commitment programs. These programs allow developers to secure financing to pay off a construction loan upon completion of construction and when the housing project has been approved for occupancy. In addition, FHFA will work with Fannie Mae to consider the feasibility, in addition to the safety and soundness, of purchasing Construction to Permanent multifamily loans. These single closing loans finance the construction of multifamily housing, in addition to serving as a permanent mortgage, which allows for the developers to only need one loan, thus reducing interest rate risk, loan resizing risk, and transaction costs – encouraging production and supply. These loans would not finance land purchases. Expansion of forward commitments and increasing liquidity for Construction to Permanent financing will provide a stable and low-cost source of capital for new construction of affordable multifamily units. These actions build on actions earlier this year to meet the demand for rental housing and growth in the multifamily originations market. For example, FHFA raised the maximum amount of multifamily loans Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac can purchase by 11 percent to a total of $78 billion in 2022. These purchases allow for more liquidity in the multifamily market, which in turn allows more deals to be financed. &nbsp;&nbsp;Last September, Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac also increased their equity investment in LIHTC deals, resulting in investments in over 7,000 units. The Enterprises anticipate further growing their LIHTC equity investments in the year ahead. And to ensure a strong focus on affordable housing and traditionally underserved markets, FHFA is requiring that at least 50 percent of the Enterprises’ 2022 financing for multifamily housing be targeted to mission-driven affordable housing.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Leveraging American Rescue Plan funds for investments in affordable housing. </strong>Treasury has urged state, local, and Tribal governments to dedicate more of their American Rescue Plan funds to build additional affordable housing at lower costs for families and individuals.A broad range of affordable housing production and preservation activities are eligible uses of the American Rescue Plan’s State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds, including development of multi-family or single-family affordable housing, preservation of existing affordable housing, permanent supportive housing, support for home repairs, homeownership assistance, rental subsidies, and other activities. To date, nearly 570 jurisdictions have committed over $11.7 billion to housing-related activities, with $3.2 billion committed to production and preservation. For example, Los Angeles County, California will invest $10 million into creating permanent supportive and interim housing for individuals and families with complex health or behavioral health conditions who are experiencing homelessness by constructing new modular, prefabricated, or container housing on County-owned or City-owned or leased property, and by the strategic renovation of existing County facilities. &nbsp;Denver, Colorado has allocated $28 million to the Affordable Housing Fund, which will support 400 newly constructed rental units, 200 preserved rental units, 50 newly constructed homeowner units, and work to acquire existing unsubsidized affordable or hotel buildings. And Erie, Pennsylvania will use $6.5 million to preserve and expand the supply of quality affordable housing, creating 100 units of new affordable housing, helping homeowners and small businesses bring their properties up to code, and providing low-interest loans for new homeowners.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Finalizing</strong><strong> the LIHTC “Income Averaging” proposed rule. </strong>To qualify for LIHTC, developers must make commitments to create housing that is affordable to households that meet specific income thresholds. &nbsp;Income averaging allows a developer to meet the same affordability goals by taking the average of the income for some households who are in the property as opposed to requiring all to meet the same threshold. This “average-income test” for LIHTC qualification will enable the creation of more financially-stable, mixed-income developments and make LIHTC-supported housing more feasible in sparsely populated rural areas. It will also facilitate the production of additional affordable and available units for extremely low-income tenants. By the end of September, Treasury will finalize regulations to provide needed guidance to developers using LIHTC equity to build multifamily housing that is rented to tenants across a wider income spectrum.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Advancing HOME as a key tool for the production and preservation of affordable rental and homeownership housing. </strong>HUD will update guidance to strengthen the HOME Investment Partnerships Program. Through the reauthorization of HOME, updated guidance, and robust technical assistance, HUD will advance and streamline this critical resource for the creation of affordable rental housing and promotion of homeownership. HOME provides grants to states and localities that communities use to fund a wide range of activities including building, buying, or rehabilitating affordable housing for rent or homeownership or providing direct rental assistance to low-income people</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Continuing to drive housing production through the Federal Financing Bank’s Risk Sharing Program</strong>. Last September, the Administration announced that Treasury and HUD had finalized an agreement to restart the Federal Financing Bank’s Risk Sharing program. The program provides loans at reduced interest rates to state and local housing finance agencies to create and preserve high-quality, affordable homes. Twenty-two state agencies have been approved to use FFB, and HUD has committed to guarantee more than $1.3 billion in loans representing more than 7,100 affordable units. HUD will work in the months ahead to accelerate this work by encouraging more state and local HFAs to participate and explore the development of a permanent financing mechanism for these loans through Ginnie Mae’s securitization platform.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Improving the alignment of federal funds to reduce transaction costs and duplications, and accelerate development. </strong>Affordable housing development projects often require more than one federal source of funding. The most common pairing is LIHTC and HUD funds, such as FHA Multifamily, the Housing Trust Fund, or HOME. But each funding source comes with its own set of requirements and procedures. To reduce transaction costs and duplication, and to speed development, the Administration will make changes to harmonize federal requirements across programs as much as possible – including through programs like HUD’s LIHTC Pilot Program, which streamlines FHA processing of mortgage insurance applications for projects with LIHTC equity. To encourage alignment of affordable housing subsidies, the White House, HUD, Treasury, and USDA will convene state housing agencies to discuss best practices on the alignment of applications, reviews, and funding.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting the construction of more than 8,000 rural multi-family housing units</strong>.&nbsp; In March 2022, the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) announced a new fee structure that would lower initial and annual guarantee fees for lenders under the Section 538 program. This new fee reduction will encourage lenders to utilize the program to develop multifamily housing. USDA anticipates these fee reductions will facilitate a 84.5 percent increase over the pre-fee reduction volume.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Disposing of federal properties to create affordable housing for people experiencing homelessness</strong>. Title V of the McKinney Vento Act allows for the disposition of federal property for re-use as housing for the homeless. While only a small percentage of disposed properties are suitable for this use, Title V is an important mechanism to create housing, especially in places with high rates of homelessness. GSA, HUD, and HHS are planning to &nbsp;issue new Title V regulations this summer. The goals of the proposed regulations are to make the disposition process easier to navigate for affordable housing developers and enable the creation of new affordable housing developments to serve people experiencing homelessness. In addition to the proposed regulations, HUD and GSA will strengthen the process to identify suitable properties, market them to potential developers, and enhance technical assistance.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting new and existing affordable housing in Indian Country.</strong> HUD will award Indian Housing Block Grant (IHBG) funding to Tribes and Tribally Designated Housing Entities to finance the construction of new affordable housing in Indian Country, and also make historic levels of annual IHBG formula funding available to them.</li></ul>



<p>These actions build on the proposals that the <strong><em>Administration has proposed and continues to call on Congress to pass</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Financing more than 800,000 affordable rental units by expanding and strengthening the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit. </strong>LIHTC offers federal income tax credits to private investors in exchange for investments in affordable rental housing. The House-passed reconciliation bill would increase tax credit allocations, provide additional capacity for private activity bonds to finance affordable housing, target tax credits for housing that serves extremely low-income Americans, and make it easier to use tax credits in Indian Country. The President’s 2023 Budget also includes a provision that would provide additional subsidy through LIHTC to developments that add net new supply and that would otherwise not be financially feasible. Given the longstanding bipartisan support for LIHTC, the Administration looks forward to working with Congress to pass these critical enhancements, as soon as possible.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding access to federal subsidies for the construction or rehabilitation of rental&nbsp;homes affordable to low and extremely low income households. </strong>Additional federal resources are needed to create housing affordable for people with the lowest incomes such as people experiencing homelessness. The House-passed reconciliation bill would bolster funding for successful housing subsidy programs that can pair with LIHTC to produce and preserve housing that is affordable for very- and extremely-low-income renters. These programs include the Housing Trust Fund, the HOME Program, Housing Choice Vouchers and the Project Based Rental Assistance program. Together, these investments would produce, preserve, and retrofit hundreds of thousands of deeply affordable, rental&nbsp;housing homes in big cities and small towns across the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing longstanding public housing capital needs. </strong>Nearly two million people across the country live in public housing. The House-passed reconciliation bill includes a transformative investment to rehabilitate and preserve public housing, addressing residents’ critical health, safety, and energy efficiency concerns.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Preserving more than 10,000 multifamily rental housing units in urban and rural America</strong>.&nbsp;The House-passed reconciliation bill provides funding to preserve over 10,000 HUD-assisted multifamily rental properties that are at risk of deterioration and do not have other sources of repair funds. It also invests specifically in rural preservation through USDA, as rural communities face unique housing needs that are not always fulfilled by other federal housing programs. The bill would support the construction, rehabilitation, and affordability of thousands of multifamily units, including units that provide affordable, sustainable housing to farmworkers and their families.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Preserving the Availability of Affordable Single-Family Homes for Owner-Occupants</u></strong></p>



<p>Beyond financing challenges, in recent years, the share of single family home purchases by investors has grown – comprising <a href="https://www.corelogic.com/intelligence/single-family-investor-activity-remained-high-in-the-third-quarter/">more than 25%</a> of all purchases nationally in some months of 2021, with an even higher share in certain markets, like Atlanta, San Jose, and Phoenix. Well over half of these purchases were made by investors with more than ten properties, and almost a quarter of these purchases were made by investors with over 100 properties. Large investor purchases of single-family homes drive up home prices for lower-cost starter homes, making it harder for aspiring first-time and first-generation home buyers, among others, to access wealth-building opportunities from homeownership. &nbsp;</p>



<p>To that end, and beyond the proposed investments discussed above, the Administration is taking the following <strong><em>immediate steps</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Directing supply to owner-occupants and mission-driven entities instead of large investors. </strong>After the Administration announced it would take steps to direct a greater percentage of the supply of FHA- and Enterprise-defaulted asset dispositions to owner-occupants and mission-driven entities instead of large investors, 50% of mortgage notes secured by vacant HUD-held properties were sold to non-profit organizations in a recent sale, rather than investors. This compares to just 10% in a typical sale. FHA and the Enterprises, at the direction of FHFA, have extended the period during which available real-estate owned (REO properties) are only made available to owner-occupants and non-profit organizations to 30 days. Large investors are only permitted to submit bids after that period. In addition, earlier this month, FHA announced it is expanding its Claims Without Conveyance of Title Process (CWCOT) to include the establishment of an initial exclusive Post-Foreclosure Sales Period for owner-occupant buyers, HUD approved non-profit, and governmental entities.&nbsp; FHA, FHFA, and agencies across government will accelerate efforts to direct available supply to targeted buyers by continuing to target the sale of at least 50 percent of mortgage notes to owner-occupants and mission-driven entities. Additionally, FHFA previously <a href="https://www.fhfa.gov/Media/PublicAffairs/Pages/Fannie-Mae-and-Freddie-Mac-to-Conclude-Single-Family-Rental-Pilot-Programs.aspx">announced</a> that it will prohibit the Enterprises from purchasing institutional investor mortgages for single family homes.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Encouraging use of CDBG for local acquisition and local sales to owner-occupants and mission-driven entities. </strong>HUD also will provide technical assistance and update guidance on the “Use of CDBG Program Funds in Support of Housing” to promote acquisition, homeownership assistance, conversion of existing structures into rental housing and “starter” homes, housing counseling, and rehabilitation and reconstruction.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Addressing Other Constraints to Supply: Materials Costs and Labor Supply</u></strong></p>



<p>During the pandemic, the price of goods used in residential construction has increased, squeezing already-tight project budgets and delaying completions. And even before, there has been limited adoption of potentially cost-saving, off-site building techniques used widely in other countries. Additionally, labor supply challenges in construction have made it harder for affordable housing developers to recruit and retain workers. In the months ahead, the Administration is committed to working with the private sector to address near-term constraints to supply and production – with the goal of achieving the most completed housing units in a single year in 15 years.</p>



<p>To that end, the Administration is taking the following <strong><em>immediate steps</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Partnering with the private sector to address supply chain disruptions for building materials. </strong>Secretary Fudge, Secretary Raimondo, and other Administration leaders will meet with representatives from the building industry to explore additional actions that the federal government and the private sector can take in partnership to help turn the record number of homes under construction into completed homes where Americans can live. The Administration already has taken a range of short-term and long-term actions that will have the effect of easing price pressures for building materials over time. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law included funding for wildfire resilience, forest management, and reforestation that will promote the health and resilience of our forests and timber supply. In addition, the Department of Commerce recently announced that it had reduced duties on softwood lumber shipments from Canada, as part of an independent and quasi-judicial process.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Promoting modular, panelized, and manufactured housing – and construction R&amp;D. </strong>Innovations in homebuilding, including manufactured, modular, panelized, precut, and additive construction, hold promise for increasing housing productivity and thus housing supply. HUD will highlight these and other technologies that can benefit affordable housing construction during the Innovative Housing Showcase on the National Mall in June 2022. HUD is also working to assess hurdles to modular and panelized housing posed by inconsistent state and local inspection requirements and standards, which limit economies of scale and potential cost savings. The Department of Energy also recently awarded $32 million in funding to support 30 next-generation building retrofit projects that will dramatically improve affordable housing technologies. These technologies include prefabricated, super-insulated wall retrofit panel blocks and 3D-printed modular overclad panels.</li></ul>



<p>These actions build on the strategy that the <strong><em>Administration has proposed and continues to call on Congress to pass</em></strong>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Recruiting more workers into good-paying construction jobs</strong>. The House-passed reconciliation bill included funding for increasing the number of Registered Apprenticeships for career technical education, as well as for pre-apprenticeship programs like JobCorps and YouthBuild, which would increase the pipeline of construction workers. The President’s Budget includes a 50% increase in funding for Youth Build, invests $303 million to expand Registered Apprenticeships and $100 million for a new Sectoral Employment through Career Training for Occupational Readiness program, which will support training programs focused on growing industries, like construction. Additionally, the $1.2 trillion for training in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is creating good paying union jobs, many of them in construction. In addition, the Administration continues to call on Congress to pass comprehensive immigration reform, while the Administration acts administratively to accelerate visa processing and other improvements to our immigration system.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-⁠Harris Administration Hits the Ground Running to Build a Better America Six Months into Infrastructure&#160;Implementation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-hits-the-ground-running-to-build-a-better-america-six-months-into-infrastructure-implementation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For decades, Washington policymakers have celebrated “infrastructure week” without delivering anything more than promises. In contrast, President Biden worked across the aisle, forged consensus, and secured the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law – a once-in-a-generation investment in our nation’s infrastructure and competitiveness.&#160; President Biden promised to deliver results, change people’s lives for the better, and build a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For decades, Washington policymakers have celebrated “infrastructure week” without delivering anything more than promises. In contrast, President Biden worked across the aisle, forged consensus, and secured the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law – a once-in-a-generation investment in our nation’s infrastructure and competitiveness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden promised to deliver results, change people’s lives for the better, and build a better America. Six months in to implementing the historic law, that’s exactly what he’s doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The law is already creating good-paying, union jobs, helping fight climate change, advancing environmental justice, boosting domestic manufacturing, strengthening critical links in our supply chains, and ultimately lowering costs for working families.</p>



<p>Since signing the law:</p>



<ul><li>The Biden-Harris Administration has announced&nbsp;<strong>over $110 billion</strong>&nbsp;to rebuild roads and bridges, modernize ports and airports, replace lead pipes to deliver clean water, and expand high-speed internet. This includes funding for&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build/six-month-anniversary/">over&nbsp;<strong>4,300 specific projects</strong>, touching over&nbsp;<strong>3,200 communities</strong>&nbsp;across all&nbsp;<strong>50 states</strong>, D.C., and Puerto Rico</a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>53 states and territories</strong>&nbsp;have appointed state infrastructure coordinators, responding to the call from Infrastructure Coordinator Landrieu to appoint an individual to coordinate efforts in a state along with serving as a single point of contact for the White House Infrastructure Implementation Team.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>The President, Vice President, and Cabinet have traveled on more than&nbsp;<strong>125 trips to over 40 states&nbsp;</strong>as well as D.C. and Puerto Rico to demonstrate how the President is delivering on this once-in-a-generation opportunity.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>DELIVERING RESULTS FOR THE AMERICAN PEOPLE</u></strong></p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has announced over $110 billion for the federal government, states, territories, Tribes, and local governments from formula and competitive programs that will change people’s lives for the better – improving roads and highways, rebuilding bridges, strengthening links in our supply chains like ports and airports, replacing lead pipes to deliver clean drinking water, building out high-speed internet, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This includes funding for over 4,300 specific projects, touching over 3,200 communities across all 50 states, D.C., and Puerto Rico.&nbsp;&nbsp;Another nearly $100 billion in requests for information and notices of funding availability have been released.&nbsp;The Administration has also unveiled new offices and action plans that will ensure these investments are implemented wisely and well.&nbsp;To showcase the state announced allocations and projects, please visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build/six-month-anniversary/">here</a>.</p>



<p>And, in line with the President&#8217;s Justice40 commitment, the Administration is ensuring that 40% of the benefits of the climate and energy related investments are delivered to disadvantaged communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Outlined at the bottom is a summary of funding announcements, opportunities, and more that demonstrate how President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is upgrading transportation and supply chains, improving water, conservation, and resilience, cleaning up legacy pollution, modernizing the grid and deploying clean energy, and expanding high-speed internet.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>ENSURING ACCOUNTABILITY&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<p>In April, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) released&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/29/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-prioritizes-effectiveness-accountability-and-transparency-in-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-implementation/">guidance</a>&nbsp;to federal agencies to set a strong foundation for effective, efficient, and equitable implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. As the President said in his State of the Union, “in my administration, the watchdogs are back.” President Biden has a long-standing commitment to collaboration with Inspectors General (IGs) and the broader oversight community, dating back to his leadership as Vice President when he was tasked with implementation of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act. He has made clear that results and accountability go hand-in-hand, and that to deliver results for all Americans, the federal government must act and support appropriate oversight of its activities in a manner deserving of public trust.</p>



<p>The initial guidance will combat fraud, waste, and abuse in the implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The initial guidance also ensures that projects are delivered on time and on budget with accountability, effectiveness, and transparency – collaborating with IGs and the oversight community and providing technical and financial assistance for communities.</p>



<p>As part of his commitment to accountability, President Biden and senior administration officials—including OMB Director Shalanda Young, Infrastructure Coordinator Landrieu, American Rescue Plan Implementation Coordinator Gene Sperling, and OMB Deputy Director for Management Jason Miller— met in April with agency IGs who have been providing oversight to the implementation of the American Rescue Plan and who will provide oversight of implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The President, his senior advisors, and IGs discussed steps they are taking to ensure robust oversight of federal programs.</p>



<p>To make the most of these historic investments and ensure infrastructure projects are delivered on time and on budget, the Biden-Harris Administration also released a new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-permitting-action-plan-to-accelerate-and-deliver-infrastructure-projects-on-time-on-task-and-on-budget/">Permitting Action Plan</a>&nbsp;to strengthen and accelerate federal permitting and environmental reviews by fully leveraging existing permitting authorities, as well as new provisions in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The Action Plan outlines the Administration’s strategy for ensuring that federal environmental reviews and permitting processes are effective, efficient, and transparent, guided by the best available science to promote positive environmental and community outcomes, and shaped by early and meaningful public engagement.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Action Plan is the latest example of the Administration acting to swiftly deliver the benefits of infrastructure investment to the American people through well-designed projects that support the President’s ambitious climate and clean energy goals. Putting the Action Plan into place will result in better permitting outcomes, enhanced predictability for project sponsors, and increased accountability across federal agencies to execute efficiently and effectively.</p>



<p><strong><u>BUILDING THE TEAM</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden’s s Infrastructure Implementation Task Force, led by White House Senior Advisor &amp; Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator Mitch Landrieu, has focused on building the team across the federal government and with state and local partners who will execute on this historic undertaking. In the first months, each agency appointed an Infrastructure Coordinator, senior leaders who are in constant communication, meet as a group multiple times each week to collaborate across the government to deliver results from the law. The federal government is hiring for over 8000 essential and mission-driven roles to implement the law including scientists to combat climate change, engineers to repair and rebuild our roads and bridges, and workers to help ensure that every community in America has clean water, among many others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Given that over 90 percent of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding will be implemented by non-federal partners, the White House also requested in January that&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ibtta.org/sites/default/files/documents/Advocacy/GA053-Mitch%20Landrieu%20Letter%20to%20Governors%202022-0104.pdf">Governors</a>&nbsp;and local leaders take a series of preparatory actions, including appointing infrastructure coordinators to manage the flow of funds to their states. Since then, 53 states and territories have made appointments to lead implementation within states, including Puerto Rico and the District of Columbia. Those coordinators have met regularly with the&nbsp;<a>White House Infrastructure Implementation Team.&nbsp;&nbsp;</a></p>



<p><strong><u>PROVIDING SUPPORT FOR STATES, TERRITORIES, TRIBES, AND LOCAL GOVERNMENTS</u></strong><strong>&nbsp;<br><br></strong>In January, the White House released the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.build.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first edition of its Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Guidebook</a>&nbsp;to help state, local, Tribal, territorial governments, community members and other key partners unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure. The guidebook is a central repository on the law and contains the most comprehensive information to date on 375 programs included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Along with its accompanying information online, the guidebook provides&nbsp;states, territories, Tribes, local governments community members and other key partners with information on funding opportunities, who to contact, and how to get ready to rebuild. In February, the White House launched an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build/briefing-room/2022/05/04/infrastructure-school-webinars/">“Infrastructure School” webinar series</a>&nbsp;to go more in depth into each of the guidebook’s 13 chapters&nbsp;and allow communities the opportunity to ask questions to the agency experts, overseeing implementation of key programs. The Administration has also released a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BIL-Factsheet-Local-Competitive-Funding.pdf">fact sheet</a>&nbsp;on some of the largest sources of competitive funding, particularly for local governments. Infrastructure Coordinator Landrieu has shared these resources during meetings with the National Governors Association, U.S. Conference of Mayors, National League of Cities, National Association of Counties, and hundreds of tribes through Tribal Consultations.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>While many funding streams in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law specifically set aside funds for underserved communities, the White House Infrastructure Implementation Team has also been engaging states, local governments, Tribal governments, territories, federal agencies, philanthropy, and others to leverage all available resources to quickly deliver the necessary technical assistance and capacity to underserved communities. In keeping with efforts like the President’s Justice40 Initiative, the Administration is committed to ensuring disadvantaged communities receive benefits from all available resources in relevant Bipartisan Infrastructure Law programs.</p>



<p>In April, the White House released a&nbsp;<a href="/Users/RFBerni/OneDrive/build.gov/rural">Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Rural Playbook</a>&nbsp;to help state, local, Tribal, territorial communities, community members and other key partners in rural areas unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure by providing rural communities with information on the “what, when, where, and how to apply” for funding under the law – so that no community needs to hire a lobbyist to access their government. The Playbook also identifies over 100 programs funded under the law with federal cost share flexibilities and matching requirement waivers for rural communities, making it easier for rural communities to access funds from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<strong></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>DELIVERING RESULTS FROM PRESIDENT BIDEN’S&nbsp;BIPARTISAN INFRASTRUCTURE LAW&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<p><em><u>Upgrading Transportation and Supply Chains</u></em></p>



<ul><li><strong>Roads:</strong>&nbsp;The U.S. Department of Transportation (USDOT) and Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) announced&nbsp;$52.5 billion in Federal Highway Apportionment&nbsp;for fiscal year 2022 the largest in decades for all 50 states and D.C. The law invests $350 billion in highway programs over the next 5 years.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Highway Safety:</strong>&nbsp;The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) at USDOT&nbsp;announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/nhtsa-announces-260-million-grants-highway-safety-programs-made-possible-bipartisan">$260 million in highway safety&nbsp;grants</a>&nbsp;to reduce traffic crashes. The law provides NHTSA with over 4 billion dollars over the next 4 years to improve the safety of our roadways.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Rural Highways:</strong>&nbsp;USDOT announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/president-biden-and-us-department-transportation-announce-12-billion-highways-rural">$1.2 billion for highways in rural Appalachia</a>&nbsp;for the Appalachian Development Highway System (ADHS) toward the timely completion of designated corridors in 11 states in the Appalachian region. The total amount that will be available to the states in Fiscal Year 2022 is $246 million.<br></li><li><strong>Bridges:</strong>&nbsp;USDOT and FHWA announced&nbsp;over&nbsp;$27 billion in funding to replace, repair, and rehabilitate bridges&nbsp;across the country to all 50 states, D.C., Puerto Rico, and Tribal governments over the next five years.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Major Local Infrastructure Projects:</strong>&nbsp;USDOT opened applications for&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/president-biden-us-dot-announce-29-billion-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-funding">$2.9 billion for major transportation projects</a>&nbsp;through a combined notice of funding opportunity (NOFO) for MEGA, INFRA, and Rural programs. Putting these three programs under a single NOFO makes it easier for communities to apply to one, two, or three major discretionary grant programs with a single application and common set of criteria.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Public Transit</strong>: USDOT announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transit.dot.gov/about/news/president-biden-usdot-announce-more-20-billion-communities-all-sizes-support-transit">$20.5 billion</a>&nbsp;in Fiscal Year 22 transit funding and a recommendation of $4.45 billion through the Capital Investment Grants program to advance public transit projects across the nation including in New York, Phoenix, Los Angeles, Indiana, Chicago, Minneapolis, St. Paul, Madison, Pittsburgh, Seattle, and Memphis. Notably, this includes first time funding commitments for the Gateway Program and Second Avenue Subway. USDOT announced nearly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/07/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-actions-to-accelerate-clean-transit-buses-school-buses-and-trucks/">$1.5 billion</a>&nbsp;in funding to help state and local governments purchase low and no emission transit buses and upgrade bus facilities.<br></li><li><strong>Airports:</strong>&nbsp;The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) at USDOT announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/faa-announces-first-year-airport-funding-amounts-bipartisan-infrastructure-law">$3 billion for 3,075 airports</a>across the country that can use investments to upgrade critical infrastructure. FAA also announced a&nbsp;$1 billion notice of funding opportunity to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/application-process-opens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-funds-build-safe-sustainable-and">modernize airport terminals</a>&nbsp;across the country. The law invests $25 billion dollars in three FAA programs over the next 5 years.<br></li><li><strong>Rebuilding American Infrastructure with Sustainability and Equity (RAISE) Grants:&nbsp;</strong>USDOT released a&nbsp;$1.5 billion&nbsp;notice of funding opportunity for its&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/us-secretary-transportation-buttigieg-announces-nearly-1-billion-grant-awards">Rebuilding American Infrastructure with Sustainability and Equity (RAISE) grant programs</a>, building off a $1 billion series of awards made to 90 major projects across 47 states in December 2021. Funding under the law allows USDOT to invest $7.5 billion dollars over the next 4 years in this program.<br></li><li><strong>Ports &amp; Waterways:</strong>&nbsp;The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE) announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/19/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-historic-investment-to-americas-port-and-waterway-infrastructure/">&nbsp;$17 billion</a>&nbsp;to strengthen supply chains, improve waterways, and bolster climate resilience in fiscal year 2022 for over 500 projects across 52 states and territories using Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds and other appropriations.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Maritime Administration (MARAD) at USDOT also announced a&nbsp;$450 million&nbsp;notice of funding opportunity for the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/us-transportation-secretary-pete-buttigieg-announces-over-241-million-grants-americas">Port Infrastructure Development Program grants</a>&nbsp;to improve ports and strengthen the nation’s supply chains, building off of&nbsp;$230 million&nbsp;of awards in December 2021. The Ports Infrastructure Development Program will invest $2.25 billion over the next 10 years in our nation’s critical port infrastructure.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Land Ports of Entry:</strong>&nbsp;GSA made&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gsa.gov/about-us/newsroom/news-releases/president-biden-and-us-general-services-administration-announce-major-land-port-projects-funded-by-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-02252022">$3.4 billion</a>&nbsp;in awards to build and modernize land ports of entry at the northern and southern border. The investments will improve commerce and trade; create good-paying construction jobs; and incorporate new and innovative sustainability features.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>EV Charging Infrastructure:</strong>&nbsp;Vice President Harris announced an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/">EV Charging Action Plan</a>&nbsp;to achieve the President’s goal of building a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle chargers. USDOT and DOE also formed a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/doe-and-dot-launch-joint-effort-build-out-nationwide-electric-vehicle-charging">Joint Office of Energy &amp; Transportation&nbsp;</a>focused on building out the national network of EV chargers. USDOT and the Department of Energy (DOE) also&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/president-biden-doe-and-dot-announce-5-billion-over-five-years-national-ev-charging">announced nearly $5 billion</a>&nbsp;that will be made available over the next 5 years under the new National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure (NEVI) Formula Program and released guidance to states, available on driveleectric.gov on how to strategically deploy EV charging infrastructure to create an interconnected national electric vehicle charging network.</li></ul>



<p><em><u>Improving Water, Conservation, and Resilience</u></em></p>



<ul><li><strong>Water Infrastructure:</strong>&nbsp;The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) announced&nbsp;$7.4 billion in funding in 2022 for states, tribes, and territories&nbsp;to upgrade America’s aging water infrastructure, sewerage systems, pipes and service lines, and more through their State Revolving Fund (SRF) programs. This is the first of five years of supplemental funding to the SRFs. EPA Administrator Michael S. Regan also issued a letter to Governors outlining the key priorities for water investments, including targeting resources to disadvantaged communities, making rapid progress on lead-free water for all, and tackling dangerous chemicals such as PFAS. The law provides nearly $44 billion over five years to EPA’s State Revolving Funds programs.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan:</strong>&nbsp;Vice President Harris announced a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-lead-pipe-and-paint-action-plan/">Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan&nbsp;</a>to&nbsp;&nbsp;accelerate Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments to replace all of the nation’s lead pipes in the next decade and expand access to clean drinking water.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Fulfilling Tribal Water Settlements:&nbsp;</strong>The Department of the Interior announced&nbsp;$1.7 billion&nbsp;to fulfill Indian Water Rights Settlements,&nbsp;which will break down barriers and help create conditions that improve water resources management by providing certainty as to the rights of all water users who are parties to the disputes.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Tribal Water Systems:</strong>&nbsp;The Department of the Interior announced&nbsp;$10 million&nbsp;for tribal water systems and another&nbsp;$10 million&nbsp;for irrigation and power in Indian Country.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Drought Resilience:</strong>&nbsp;The Department of the Interior announced awards of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-420-million-rural-water-funding-president-bidens">$420 million for rural water projects</a>&nbsp;for drought resilience, and $240 million for aging water infrastructure through the Bureau of Reclamation. This investment in rural water systems includes work related to pipeline connections, construction of water treatment plants and intakes, pump systems, reservoir construction and other efforts to provide potable water to rural and Tribal communities.&nbsp;The Bureau of Reclamation also announced application periods for hundreds of millions of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding opportunities for water infrastructure, some of which are still open. Funding for the maintenance of aging infrastructure, and water recycling and desalination projects have been advertised, with more on the way during the rest of 2022.<br></li><li><strong>Watershed Infrastructure Projects:</strong>&nbsp;The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) announced nearly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/04/21/president-biden-usda-announce-420-million-investment-watershed">$420 million</a>&nbsp;in funding for projects that improve or rehabilitate watersheds, rehabilitate dams, and improve flood prevention through its Natural Resource Conservation Service.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Wildlife and Habitat Conservation:</strong>&nbsp;The Department of the Interior announced $38 million for the National Fish Passage Program, to support fish habitat across 23 states and in Puerto Rico and a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-over-15-billion-support-state-wildlife-conservation-and">record $1.5 billion</a>&nbsp;in annual funding from excise taxes on guns, ammunition, and archery sales through the Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration (WSFR) Program to support state and local outdoor recreational opportunities, and wildlife and habitat conservation efforts. The WSFR Program contains two funding sources: the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund, which was reauthorized as part of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and the Wildlife Restoration Program.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Ecosystem Restoration</strong>: The Department of the Interior, USDA, and DOD jointly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2022/04/11/biden-harris-administration-launches-1-billion-america-the-beautiful-challenge-to-support-and-accelerate-locally-led-conservation-and-restoration-projects/">announced a $1 billion America the Beautiful Challenge</a>&nbsp;that will combine Federal funding with private and philanthropic contributions for conservation and restoration. The America the Beautiful Challenge is anchored by an initial commitment of $440 million of Federal resources over the next five years to a new public-private grant program, administered by the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation (NFWF), that will support locally led ecosystem restoration projects. DOI also announced&nbsp;$68 million for 125 projects for ecosystem restoration, habitat protection, invasive species eradication and post-fire recovery work.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Tribal Climate Resilience:&nbsp;</strong>The Department of the Interior announced $46 million in funding to Tribal communities to address the unique impacts of climate change in Indigenous communities.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Pacific Coastal Salmon Recovery Fund</strong>:&nbsp;&nbsp;NOAA announced&nbsp;<a href="/www.fisheries.noaa.gov/grant/pacific-coastal-salmon-recovery-fund">$100 million for the Pacific Coastal Salmon Recovery Fund</a>&nbsp;which supports&nbsp;conservation efforts in California, Oregon, Washington, Idaho, and Alaska and is essential to preventing the extinction of the 28 listed salmon and steelhead species on the West Coast. &nbsp;The jobs and economic benefits of salmon restoration activities are largely realized in local and rural communities.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Coastal Resilience Fund:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;NOAA and the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nfwf.org/programs/national-coastal-resilience-fund">announced $98 million for the National Coastal Resilience Fund</a>, which&nbsp;supports the implementation of nature-based solutions to enhance the resilience of coastal communities and ecosystems to these threats. These projects construct or restore coastal habitats that increase the capacity of communities and habitats to withstand and recover from disruptions and adapt to changing environmental conditions.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Wildfire Mitigation:</strong>&nbsp;USDA announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/04/11/biden-administration-announces-bipartisan-infrastructure-law">$131 million in wildfire mitigation</a>&nbsp;investments to begin work on the USDA Forest Services’ 10 year wildfire strategy&#8211;&nbsp;<a href="/www.fs.usda.gov/managing-land/wildfire-crisis%3c">Confronting the Wildfire Crisis: A Strategy for Protecting Communities and Improving Resilience in America’s Forests</a>. The&nbsp;<a href="/www.fs.usda.gov/sites/default/files/WCS-Initial-Landscape-Investments.pdf%3c">initial investment in 10 landscapes</a>&nbsp;in Washington, Oregon, California, Idaho, Montana, Colorado, New Mexico and Arizona will lead to about 208,000 acres of wildfire risk reduction treatments.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Flood Resilience:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;FEMA announced the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.fema.gov/press-release/20220321/president-biden-vice-president-harris-fema-announce-flood-mitigation#:~:text=The%20new%20Swift%20Current%20initiative,survivors%20with%20repetitively%20flooded%20homes.">$60 million Swift Current</a>&nbsp;federal grant initiative that will help four states affected by Hurricane Ida, one of the most intense storms to hit the United States in recent years, become more resilient to flooding. The program will more equitably expedite mitigation grants to disaster survivors with repetitively flooded homes.</li></ul>



<p><em><u>Cleaning Up Legacy Pollution&nbsp;</u></em></p>



<ul><li><strong>Orphaned Oil and Gas Wells:</strong>&nbsp;The Department of the Interior launched a new $4.7 billion program to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-releases-implementation-guidance-states-infrastructure-law-efforts">cap</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-releases-implementation-guidance-states-infrastructure-law-efforts">and plug orphaned oil and gas wells</a>&nbsp;in order to reduce methane emissions and create jobs over the next decade. The first&nbsp;$1.15 billion&nbsp;in funding is now available to 26 states to create jobs cleaning up orphaned oil and gas wells across the country.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Abandoned Mine Lands:&nbsp;</strong>The Department of the Interior announced the availability of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-administration-announces-nearly-725-million-create-good-paying-union-jobs">nearly $725 million</a>in Fiscal Year 22 funding for 22 states and the Navajo Nation to create good-paying union jobs and catalyze economic opportunity by reclaiming abandoned mine lands (AML). The program will help communities eliminate dangerous environmental conditions and pollution caused by past coal mining. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law reauthorized the existing fee and provided nearly $11.3 billion to be allocated evenly over the next 15 years.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Superfund Site Cleanup:</strong>&nbsp;EPA announced&nbsp;$1 billion&nbsp;this year&nbsp;to initiate cleanup&nbsp;and clear the backlog of 49 previously unfunded Superfund sites and accelerate cleanup at dozens of other sites across the country. Until this historic investment, many of these were part of a backlog of hazardous waste sites awaiting funding.&nbsp;These funds will help communities living near many of the most serious uncontrolled or abandoned releases of contamination finally get the protections they deserve. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides a total of $3.5 billion over the next five years for Superfund site cleanup.<br></li><li><strong>Brownfield Cleanup</strong>:&nbsp;EPA awarded&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/biden-administration-announces-254-million-tackle-polluted-brownfield-sites">$254.5 million in brownfield clean up grants</a>&nbsp;to 265 communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides a total of $1.5 billion over the next five years to advance environmental justice, spur economic revitalization and create jobs by cleaning up contaminated, polluted, or hazardous brownfield properties.<br></li><li><strong>Great Lakes Restoration:</strong>&nbsp;EPA announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/president-biden-epa-announce-1-billion-investment-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-will">$1 billion over five years for the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative</a>, including $200 million in FY2022,&nbsp;to accelerate progress in the clean-up and restoration of the Great Lakes’ most environmentally degraded sites, securing clean water and a better environment for millions of Americans in the Great Lakes region.<br></li><li><strong>Chesapeake Bay:&nbsp;</strong>EPA announced $238 million over five years to help restore the Chesapeake Bay, including $40 million this year. This funding will advance efforts to promote environmental justice and counter climate change by supporting projects that that protect public health, improve water quality, and help restore lands, rivers, and streams in the Chesapeake Bay region.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><em><u>Modernizing the Grid and Deploying Clean Energy</u></em></p>



<ul><li>&nbsp;<strong>Energy Efficient Homes:</strong> DOE released a grant&nbsp;&nbsp;application for&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-administration-announces-investments-make-homes-more-energy-efficient-and-lower">$3.16 billion in funding for residential energy retrofitting</a>&nbsp;and weatherization. This expanded funding will allow states to retrofit thousands of low-incomes homes to make them healthier and more energy efficient while lowering utility bills.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Home Energy Assistance</strong>:&nbsp;The Department of Health and Human Services announced the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/01/25/president-bidens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-directs-100-million-lower-heating-cooling-bills.html">release of $100 million</a>&nbsp;to help families pay their outstanding heating and cooling bills. This funding comes on top of investment in the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP) through the American Rescue Plan and the Continuing Resolution most recently passed by Congress, and is the first installment of the five-year, $500 million investment in the program provided from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;<br></li><li>&nbsp;<strong>Energy Efficient Schools:</strong> DOE released a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-harris-administration-announces-500-million-program-better-school-infrastructure">Request for Information (RFI) seeking public input on their $500 million grant program&nbsp;to make public schools more energy efficient</a>. The program will help deliver cleaner and healthier classrooms, libraries, cafeterias, playgrounds, and gyms where over millions of teachers teach and tens of millions of students learn, eat, and build friendships every day.</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp;<strong>Building a Better Grid:</strong> DOE launched a new&nbsp;Building a Better Grid&nbsp;initiative to modernize and upgrade the nation’s electric grid, increasing reliability, reducing outages and giving more communities access to cheaper and cleaner energy.. As part of this initiative, DOE has released a request for information and notice of intent seeking feedback on $2.3 billion in grid resilience funding for state and Tribal Nations and a&nbsp;request for information&nbsp;for the $2.5 billion Transmission Facilitation Program. DOE also released a&nbsp;request for information&nbsp;for a $505 million long-duration energy storage program to commercialize new technologies that increase grid reliability and enable great amounts of clean energy on the grid. In addition, the Department of Transportation released&nbsp;<a href="https://www.fhwa.dot.gov/real_estate/right-of-way/corridor_management/alternative_uses_guidance.cfm">guidance</a>&nbsp;to help facilitate the use of public highways and other transportation rights-of-way to speed the siting and permitting of transmission lines.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Clean Energy and Advanced Batteries</strong>: DOE issued two funding opportunities, inviting applications for more than&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-administration-doe-invest-3-billion-strengthen-us-supply-chain-advanced-batteries">&nbsp;$3 billion to boost production of the advanced batteries</a>, their components, and the critical materials needed for them. Advanced batteries&nbsp;are critical for rapidly growing clean energy industries of the future, including electric vehicles and grid energy storage, and the materials processing components will invest in critical mineral production that is a key component of the President’s strategy to increase the security and resilience of U.S. supply chains</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Nuclear Power</strong>: DOE released guidance to seek applications and sealed bid submissions on the implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s $6 billion Civil Nuclear Credit Program. The nuclear credit program supports the continued operation of U.S. nuclear reactors, the nation’s largest source of clean power.<br></li><li><strong>Clean Energy and Critical Minerals Demonstration:</strong> DOE released&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-launches-140-million-program-develop-americas-first-kind-critical-minerals-refinery">a Request for Information (RFI) on the design, construction, and operation</a>&nbsp;of a new $140 million facility to demonstrate the commercial feasibility of a full-scale rare earth element and critical minerals extraction and separation refinery using unconventional resources.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Critical Mineral Research</strong>:&nbsp;The Department of the Interior announced over&nbsp;$167 million&nbsp;that will go towards a new facility for the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-colorado-leaders-announce-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-funding">U.S. Geological Survey</a>, which is working on critical energy and mineral programs.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Clean Hydrogen Initiatives</strong>:&nbsp;DOE established&nbsp;$9.5 billion in&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-establishes-bipartisan-infrastructure-laws-95-billion-clean-hydrogen-initiatives">Clean Hydrogen Initiatives</a>&nbsp;to help decarbonize industry and the transportation sectors. The Department announced two Requests for Information (RFI) to collect feedback from stakeholders to inform the implementation and design of the Regional Hydrogen Hub and the Electrolysis and Clean Hydrogen Manufacturing and Recycling Programs.<br></li><li><strong>Clean Infrastructure Deployment</strong>:&nbsp;DOE announced an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-optimizes-structure-implement-62-billion-clean-energy-investments-bipartisan">organizational realignment</a>&nbsp;to ensure the Department has the structure needed to effectively implement the programs and investments in President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the Energy Act of 2020. A newly created Under Secretary for Infrastructure will focus on deploying new energy infrastructure—including upgrading the electric grid, building new battery and clean energy manufacturing capacity and building new commercial-scale demonstration projects for technologies like hydrogen and carbon storage. DOE will be hiring as many as 1,000 new people for its&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/CleanEnergyCorps">Clean Energy Corps</a>, the staff of the new Under Secretary’s infrastructure offices and other offices at DOE working to implement the BIL.<br></li><li><strong>Clean Energy Demonstrations:</strong> DOE established the new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-establishes-new-office-clean-energy-demonstrations-under-bipartisan-infrastructure-law">Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations,</a>&nbsp;a component of the new Office of the Under Secretary for Infrastructure, which will&nbsp;oversee $20 billion&nbsp;of infrastructure funding to scale up clean energy, create new, good-paying jobs for American families and workers, and reduce pollution while benefiting underserved communities.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><em><u>Expanding High-Speed Internet</u></em></p>



<ul><li>&nbsp;<strong>Affordable Connectivity Program:</strong> The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) launched the Affordable Connectivity Program providing broadband subsidies of up to $30/month for low-income households (up to $75 per month for households on Tribal Lands) and up to $100 towards the purchase of a desktop, laptop or tablet computer. To date, more than 11.5 million households in affordable, high speed internet plans.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp;<strong>Lowering Internet Costs</strong>: To lower costs for tens of millions of families, the President and Vice President also secured commitments from 20 leading internet providers—providing service to urban, suburban and rural areas where more than 80% of the U.S. population lives&nbsp;to either cut prices or increase speeds (or both), to offer to ACP-eligible households high-speed internet plans for no more than $30 per month.&nbsp;<br></li><li>&nbsp;<strong>Internet for All Initiative:</strong> The NTIA also launched its&nbsp;<a href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2022/05/biden-harris-administration-launches-45-billion-internet-all-initiative">$45 Billion “Internet for All” initiative</a>&nbsp;– releasing notices of funding opportunity for three of its major programs including the Broadband Equity, Access and Deployment (BEAD) Program, the Middle-Mile Broadband Infrastructure Program, and the Digital Equity Planning Grant Program. The programs will build internet infrastructure, support the development of digital skills, and provide necessary tools to ensure that everyone in America – including communities of color, rural communities, and older Americans – has the access and skills they need to fully participate in today’s society. Through the BEAD program alone, each state is eligible for a minimum of $100 million, with an initial $5 million in planning funds to help create a five-year action plan.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Rural Internet:</strong>&nbsp;The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) accepted applications for the $1.15 billion&nbsp;<a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2021/11/24/usda-begins-accepting-applications-115-billion-loans-and-grants">ReConnect rural broadband deployment program</a>&nbsp;for loans and grants to state, local or territory governments, corporations, Tribes and limited liability companies and cooperative organizations to help people in rural areas get access to high-speed internet.&nbsp; This funding will be boosted by a $2 billion investment from BIL.&nbsp;<br></li><li>&nbsp;<strong>Tribal Internet:</strong> NTIA has made&nbsp;<a href="https://broadbandusa.ntia.doc.gov/news/latest-news/biden-administration-awards-nearly-77-million-expand-internet-access-dozens-tribes">34 awards totaling approximately $83 million</a>&nbsp;in funding through the Tribal Broadband Connectivity Program. These awards are part of the Biden Administration’s whole-of-government effort to connect everyone in America with affordable, reliable, high-speed internet. &nbsp;The program, which is receiving an additional $2 billion in funding through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, is directed to Tribal governments to be used for broadband deployment on Tribal lands, as well as for telehealth, distance learning, broadband affordability, and digital inclusion.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council Meeting in&#160;Paris</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/15/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-u-s-eu-trade-and-technology-council-meeting-in-paris/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thanks everyone for joining us.&#160; We’re going to just do a quick call to preview the Monday meeting of the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council.&#160; We’re just going to walk through what we’re expecting in the meeting and just some of the outcomes that will come out of it.&#160; We’re going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks everyone for joining us.&nbsp; We’re going to just do a quick call to preview the Monday meeting of the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council.&nbsp; We’re just going to walk through what we’re expecting in the meeting and just some of the outcomes that will come out of it.&nbsp; We’re going to have more to say on the outcomes on Monday itself.</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;&nbsp; The contents of this call are embargoed until this Sunday, 11 p.m.&nbsp; Eastern.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, our speakers on the call are [senior administration officials].&nbsp; So again, that was just for your awareness and not for reporting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re going to do some remarks at the top and then try to take as many questions as we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I’m going to kick it over to [senior administration official] to get us started.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much, and thanks to all of you for joining us today.&nbsp; As you all might remember, last June at the U.S.-EU Summit, President Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen and European Council President Charles Michel established the U.S. and EU Trade and Technology Council.&nbsp; The U.S.-EU TTC, as we call it, will have its second ministerial meeting, as [senior administration official] mentioned, in Saclay, a technology hub near Paris on May 15th and 16th.&nbsp; The inaugural meeting, as many of you know, was held in Pittsburgh at the end of September last year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the co-chairs, just to remind everybody, are Secretary of State Anthony Blinken, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai, and EU co-chairs, European Commission Executive Vice Presidents Margrethe Vestage and Valdis Dombrovskis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we made a lot of progress, I think, at the Pittsburgh meeting, including working towards common principles to update the rules of the road for a 21st century economy and technology ecosystem, including addressing non-market trade practices, enhancing cooperation on semiconductors and supply chains, exchanging information on investment trends that impact our security, shared principles on export control cooperation and developing and implementing technologies like artificial intelligence in accordance with our shared democratic values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, in addition to all of that work that had been staked out at Pittsburgh, as you all are well aware, the TTC, I think, really laid the foundation for the really unprecedented cooperation on sanctions and export controls that you’ve seen in response to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, at this upcoming meeting on Monday, the U.S. and EU co-chairs will review the progress we’ve been making and really the deep cooperation over the last six months, both by the working groups and all of the additional cooperation that spawned and will work to advance action on our transatlantic cooperation agenda with respect to democratic approaches to trade, technology, and innovation.&nbsp; And in addition, the co-chairs will be meeting with a range of U.S. and EU stakeholders to hear out their views on the past and future work of the TTC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, I’ll hand it over to my colleague.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, and thanks everyone for joining us on this call today.&nbsp; We’re all tremendously excited about the second meeting of the TTC and really see it as a key opportunity to drive further cooperation across the Atlantic on a whole range of global trade and technology issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think over the last six months, as [senior administration official] says, we really have been able to drive close and enduring ties between the U.S. and the European Union.&nbsp; We’ve strengthened, deepened, and elevated our relationship.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to give just a couple of examples of the kinds of things we’ve accomplished just over the last six months.&nbsp; Between the last TTC and this one, we’ve been able to resolve our disagreement over tariffs on steel trade, reaching an agreement with the European Union on steel trade.&nbsp; We also just earlier this year reached an agreement in principle on a new transatlantic data privacy framework to create legal certainty for transatlantic data flows.&nbsp; And then of course, as [senior administration official] mentioned, I think there’s been an unprecedented level of cooperation on sanctions and export control measures as part of our coordinated overall response to President Putin’s war on Ukraine.</p>



<p>I think on Sunday evening and Monday at the second meeting of the TTC, you’re going to see us deepen this partnership and announce a number of key outcomes, including deeper information sharing on exports of critical U.S. and EU technology, commitment to develop a joint roadmap on evaluation and measurement tools for trustworthy artificial intelligence and risk management.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’ll see us announce joint approaches on technical discussions to the international standard-setting bodies, an early warning system to better predict and address potential semiconductor supply chain disruptions, a transatlantic approach to semiconductor investments aimed at ensuring security of supply through strengthened ecosystems and investments.&nbsp; As both Washington and Brussels look to encourage semiconductor investment in our respective countries, we do so in a coordinated fashion and don’t simply encourage a subsidy race.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’ll see us announce a dedicated task force to promote the use of trusted ICTS suppliers through financing for deployments in third countries, be announcing a new cooperation framework to explore issues to inform information integrity in crises, particularly on digital platforms with a focus on ongoing issues related to the misinformation, false information that Russia is spreading related to its war on Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’ll see us announce a stakeholder-focused trade and labor dialogue to promote internationally recognized labor rights.&nbsp; We’ll be developing joint and coordinated strategies to address the adverse impact on the U.S. and EU economies of non-market trade distortive policies and practices, be establishing a policy dialogue aimed at developing responses to global food security challenges caused by Russian aggression in Ukraine, be announcing an early alert mechanism to identify and address at an early stage non-market trade concerns which may disadvantage the transatlantic economy.</p>



<p>We’ll be announcing plans to have a U.S.-EU guide to cybersecurity best practices for small and medium-sized companies whose business is impacted disproportionately from cyber threats.&nbsp; And we’ll be launching a new climate and clean tech-focused dialogue on lifecycle greenhouse gas assessments, methodologies on green public procurement and on electric vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think you’ve really seen us do a lot over the last six months and I think you’re really seeing us going forward, driving forward work across a whole range of issues that we had hoped to be accomplishing through the TTC process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Back to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Let’s go to our next speaker.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, and good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Well, I won’t go into the deliverables.&nbsp; You’ve already heard about them in detail.&nbsp; But I would just say that the TTC is really a cornerstone of the U.S.-EU economic partnership, and promotes an affirmative agenda on key global technology, economic, and trade issues that is really based on our democratic values while working to reduce areas of friction in the U.S.-EU relationship.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so our task is multi-fold, to put forward and carry out a compelling vision for global trade and technology in a way that serves our people, protects our interests, and promotes innovation and our democratic values, including respect for human rights.&nbsp; And as others have said, these efforts really reflect the deep and abiding partnership between the United States and the EU and its member states, as well as our shared values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, the U.S. and the EU account for a quarter of global trade and almost half of global GDP and that represents a huge driver of economic prosperity for citizens on both sides of the Atlantic.&nbsp; And so, the goal here is really to find ways to ensure that our competition policies, our technology regulations are complementary and that our markets are ever more interconnected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in addition to addressing technical issues like supply chain bottlenecks and other things that have been described already, the TTC has really proven to be an agile framework that facilitates our cooperation on global issues.&nbsp; As has already been said, I think, our cooperation on sanctions and export controls is really a great example and the relationship and the shared, common operating picture developed via the TTC have really helped us to take groundbreaking steps in those areas, in response to Putin’s war of aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would also just as a final note say that those types of steps that we have taken together would not have been possible without the work that we have done in the TTC and pre-dating the TTC and leading up to the U.S.-EU summit last year to really remove obstacles to deeper cooperation, and to focus on our shared values in terms of articulating an affirmative vision for trade and technology that promotes democracy, human rights, and other shared values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we really see that this deeper cooperation not only will help to deepen our trade and economic ties, but it also will help us to articulate a vision of the kind of world we want to see, and to help preserve the rules-based international order that we have created over the last 70 years.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; Let’s go to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You’ve heard a lot already, so I’ll be brief.&nbsp; And I thought I might just try to ground some of what you’ve already heard in the technical work that’s happening in the working groups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, first, you’ve heard from all of us the priority we put on revitalizing transatlantic ties and advancing a common agenda that’s based on market-oriented democratic values.&nbsp; That certainly is animating our work at the Department of Commerce, the work that my colleague referenced in transatlantic data privacy framework, the work in relation to resolving disputes over 232 tariffs, and now in the TTC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Export controls have already been mentioned, but I think it’s a prime example of where deep technical collaboration that was happening in TTC prior to Russia’s invasion of Ukraine was able to be leveraged so we could move with remarkable speed to put in place these unprecedented collaboration on export controls.&nbsp; I guess the point that I would share, and again with a lot of ground already covered, is just that’s something that’s risen to geopolitical fore because of the crisis in Ukraine but similar types of technical work are being done on supply chains, on ITTS infrastructure, on standards, on AI that is really deepening our collaboration, helping us align the future of standards and policy in ways that I think will be exceptionally meaningful going forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So with a lot of ground covered, I’ll be brief and just stop there and look forward to questions.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And for our last speaker, let’s go to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you very much and good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks for joining.&nbsp; The USTR is very excited to join the second ministerial meeting of the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council with our colleagues from the State and the Commerce Departments next week.</p>



<p>Since 2021, Ambassador Tai has made it a significant priority to rebuild and revitalize our bilateral and multilateral relationships with our partners around the world.&nbsp; This work was part of President Biden’s vision to make America a leader on the world stage and partner with our allies on pressing global issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think over the past year perhaps no relationship has seen more progress or success than our engagement with the European Union.&nbsp; In June 2021, Ambassador Tai resolved the 17-year-old large civil aircraft dispute involving Boeing and Airbus.&nbsp; In October, she announced, along with Secretary Raimondo, an arrangement to address global steel and aluminum non-market excess capacity, which will preserve the long-term viability of critical domestic sectors, help fulfill the President’s climate agenda and protect American jobs.&nbsp; We also terminated investigations of unilateral digital services taxes in Europe in favor of an OECD pluri-lateral negotiation.</p>



<p>The foundation of trust and respect we’ve built with our EU partners has enabled us to make tremendous progress in our collaboration through the TTC.&nbsp; So next week in France, you will hear Ambassador Tai talk about our joint commitment to tackling urgent economic trade and technology issues impacting people on both sides of the Atlantic.&nbsp; As you have heard, this cooperation is grounded on our shared values, specifically our respect for internationally recognized labor rights, for transparency, a level playing field, and the rule of law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To give a few examples, through the TTC, we will establish a transatlantic labor dialogue aimed at giving labor a seat at the table along with business as we develop trade initiatives to ensure that they address the needs of workers.&nbsp; And this includes making sure that businesses and workers make successful digital and green transitions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second example, we will work closely together as we each take our own actions to defend ourselves against non-market economy policies and practices in third countries that unfairly undermine our competitiveness in new and emerging technologies, and that threaten U.S. jobs.&nbsp; And we will also work to avoid the negative impacts of those actions on each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And final example, we will undertake to consult with each other at an early stage on our regulatory and other initiatives that could impact bilateral trade to avoid as much as possible the emergence of unnecessary barriers to trade in new and emerging technologies, which would undermine a strong transatlantic market for those technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And of course, we will continue the close collaboration you have seen over the past three months to isolate Russia from multilateral trading institutions and the global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Ambassador Tai has said many times, strong and durable trade relationships require regular engagement and consultations to ensure that both sides are aligned on key priorities.&nbsp; The Trade and Technology Council was created to do exactly that.&nbsp; We’re looking forward to productive conversations in France next week, and in the months to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will now turn things back over to our moderator to begin the question-and-answer session.&nbsp; Moderator.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, guys, for doing this call.&nbsp; I guess I wanted to ask kind of more broadly if you think the focus of this meeting will be Russia or if it’s shifting back to China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And along the lines of the semiconductor supply chain issues you mentioned, if there was any stuff afoot shore up neon supplies, which is such a key ingredient for semiconductors, and a lot of it comes from Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also if there’ll be any discussion of, I guess, tightening up export controls on advanced semiconductor equipment to Chinese chipmakers like SMIC.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Hi, Alex.&nbsp; I’ll take the first part of that question and then open it up to others on the second.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I think you’re going to see Russia as a focus across a number of areas of the TTC’s work.&nbsp; I mean, if we look at supply chains, we have been worried about China-related supply chains.&nbsp; We’re going to continue to be worried about China-related supply chains.&nbsp; But as your question suggests, we’re going to see us talk about the supply chain impacts from Russia and look for ways collectively to address them, probably particularly in global food issues, where we are quite concerned about a looming food security crisis in the back part of this year because of Putin’s war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think you’ll see us look at Russia in the supply chain space; Russia, obviously, in the Russian disinformation kind of space.&nbsp; Obviously, Russia has implications for trade, but I don’t think we’re losing our focus.&nbsp; I think you just heard USTR talk about the ongoing work and the continuing ongoing work that we need to be doing together about China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think this is very much a case of being able to walk and chew gum at the same time and address the impacts we’re seeing, the very serious impacts we’re seeing because of Russia’s war on Ukraine while also continuing the work we started last fall collectively on China.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I can add a little bit on the on the last part of your question, which is, I think the TTC is certainly discussing all parts of the semiconductor supply chain through the working groups.&nbsp; And I think one of the reasons you’re hearing all of us talk about export controls, generally, is that I think there’s an agreement the foundation that we have built now with the Russia export controls is something that we can really build on.&nbsp; And it’s something as a basis for transatlantic cooperation more broadly.&nbsp; So I think you’ll see in the statement some reference to ways that we can consolidate that cooperation and that framework going forward.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thank you.&nbsp; Does anyone else have any thoughts before we move to the next question?</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Can we do our next question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this call.&nbsp; I wonder if there’s specifically any plans to discuss China’s industrial subsidies with your counterparts in the European Union next week.&nbsp; I know that’s been a concern for many of the agencies on the call today, but Europeans have not been as apt to call out those industrial subsidies as unfair trade practices.&nbsp; Is that something that you plan to bring up next week?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We do have a set of outcomes, which will be part of the discussion about our coordination together to push back against the injurious effects of these non-market economy policies and practices, including in key priority sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You mentioned subsidies but I think it’s fair to say that the non-market economy policies and practices go far beyond subsidies to include state-directed &#8212; government-directed state enterprises, force technology transfer, a broad range of industrial policies that really threatens some of the important emerging technologies that we are competitive in and should remain competitive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I think the importance of us working together to counter the bundle of non-market economy policies and practices &#8212; which includes subsidies, but not only &#8212; will, to my mind, clearly be a focus of the discussions and of the outcomes next week.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And if I can just add, I think, zooming out a bit, we really have seen incredible convergence in terms of just European understanding of the challenge that China poses from an economic perspective, but increasingly, as well, from a security perspective, given China’s support for Putin’s aggression in Ukraine, and the “no limits partnership” between Russia and the PRC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so this was a topic of conversation in the recent U.S.-EU high-level dialogue on China, which took place a few weeks ago in Brussels led by Deputy Secretary of State Sherman.&nbsp; And it’s an area of, I would say, continuing and increasing focus in our work with the EU, as we look to really ramp up cooperation in the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thank you.&nbsp; Any other thoughts before we move to the next question?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: This is [senior administration official], just to say I totally agree.&nbsp; And I think it’s fair to say that several years ago you would never have seen the kind of convergence and outcomes that we’ll be seeing in this TTC coming up.&nbsp; There’s been a very significant convergence over the last few years.&nbsp; So this is very different from what one would have seen several years ago.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thank you.&nbsp; Can we do our next question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; I was just wondering, you went over this a bit but if you could detail some of the efforts with relation to non-market economies.&nbsp; You talked about a trade dialogue on non-market challenges.&nbsp; Is that right?&nbsp; And an early alert mechanism for non-market challenges that disadvantage the U.S. economy.&nbsp; Can you give some more detail there?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, this is [senior administration official] again.&nbsp; Maybe I can give a few details.&nbsp; We each have and the European Union increasingly has their own measures of laws, regulations, actions to take to push back against various non-market economy policies and practices.&nbsp; So one of the things we’re doing in the TTC is a plan to work closely together so that we can leverage the instruments on both sides so that we can push back on those non-market economy policies and practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also intend to identify particular practices and particular sectors that present challenges from a non-market economy point of view and develop joint strategies to push back on the injurious effects of the non-market economy policies and practices in those sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think, very importantly, we’re also looking very much to make sure to avoid as much as possible, as we each take our own actions, which ideally will be advanced in cooperation with each other, that we don’t inadvertently hit each other and that we use those tools together and leverage them to push back against the particular non-market economy policies and practices that are undermining our competitiveness in key areas.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I want to be mindful of the time and just get a couple of more questions in.&nbsp; So can we please do our next question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; Can you guys just maybe talk about the timeline on the chip supply disruption and early warning system?&nbsp; And what we’re seeing now with the lockdowns in China, has that changed the conversation for that timeline?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; This is an issue we’ve been working with the Europeans on over the last couple of months.&nbsp; As you know, we &#8212; last year, Commerce Department did a process to solicit information from U.S. semiconductor companies and companies consuming semiconductors on supply chain vulnerabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we had, actually, via our embassies last year, gotten a number of our embassies out in the Southeast Asia to set up for the U.S. side an early warning system where we were tracking key semiconductor-oriented production sites across Southeast Asia to understand as early as possible when disruptions would emerge.&nbsp; I think that early warning system that we established on a U.S. basis late last year, last fall &#8212; September, October &#8212; has been very helpful in helping us get ahead of a couple of potential shutdowns that would have hit earlier this year with Delta.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is really a chance for us to expand that work and multilateralize it with our European partners.&nbsp; I would say we are very closely monitoring the situation in China, which is clearly impacting a number of different supply chains, not just semiconductors.&nbsp; We’ve seen a number of different products being hit from that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don’t know if you have anything you want to add to that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, I would just say it’s been all along one of the highest priority initiatives for the Commerce Department, within TTC and outside of it, and something that comes up in bilateral engagements with any of the semiconductor producing countries.&nbsp; And so there’s different variations of this conversation with a lot of countries.&nbsp; It was very much high priority before any more recent concerns about shutdowns in China and so a great deal of urgency already.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re excited about what we’re going to announce on Monday in this regard.&nbsp; I think there’s a lot more work we can build on with our European counterparts on this.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Great.&nbsp; Let’s do our last question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; I was hoping you could talk a little bit about the principals who will be attending and how they’ll break up their roles.&nbsp; I see that Secretary of State Blinken is going; U.S. Trade Representative is going.&nbsp; Secretary Raimondo is going.&nbsp; How will they kind of break up their roles and responsibilities?&nbsp; And who from the White House specifically or the top-ranked White House official, who will that be?&nbsp; Who will be attending from the White House?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, thanks.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; As you note, our principals are Ambassador Tai, Secretary Blinken, and Secretary Raimondo.&nbsp; They are co-leading this as they did in the fall.</p>



<p>I’m not going to get into exactly who’s going to say what at each of the different sessions, but the flow of the day &#8212; there’s a dinner Sunday evening, a working dinner Sunday evening for the principals.&nbsp; And then there are a set of sessions on Monday focused on different topics, including a session with stakeholders from both Europe and in the U.S.&nbsp; I think you’ll see very active participation by each of our principals across the different sessions, focusing, obviously, on the issues within each of their remits.&nbsp; Obviously, it’s also three principals who work very well together across a whole range of issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>The White House does not attend this at a principal level, but there are a couple of White House staff who will be attending.</a></p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Any other thoughts before we wrap up the call on this question?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, I would just add that I think this has been actually a really good exercise in terms of knitting together all of these equities and those of other departments and agencies that also participate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, within the State Department, we have half a dozen bureaus that are very active within the TTC’s 10 working groups.&nbsp; And beyond the three co-chairs, as I said, there are a number of different agencies that are also involved at the working group level.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, I think it really just demonstrates the breadth of the U.S.-EU partnership and how cross-cutting these issues are that we’re dealing with, and that the TTC is really designed not just to deal with the trade and economic aspects, and the regulatory aspects of the digital side of things, but also to really bring in our shared values and the democratic and human rights aspects of the challenges that we face related to both trade and technology.&nbsp; So it really is pretty close to a whole-of-government effort.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well, thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and the contents of this call are embargoed until Sunday 11:00 p.m. Eastern.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you have any more questions, please feel (inaudible) to myself or the State Department, Commerce, and USTR.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; Have a good day.</p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Air Force Two&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/15/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-air-force-two-departure-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 22:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53298</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George’s County, Maryland THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hi.&#160; So, we are &#8212; I&#8217;m leading a delegation on behalf of the President and our administration to express our condolences.&#160; The United States takes quite seriously the strength of our relationship and partnership with UAE.&#160; And we are going there, then, to express our condolences,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Joint Base Andrews<br><em>Prince George’s County, Maryland</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; So, we are &#8212; I&#8217;m leading a delegation on behalf of the President and our administration to express our condolences.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States takes quite seriously the strength of our relationship and partnership with UAE.&nbsp; And we are going there, then, to express our condolences, but also as an expression of our commitment to the strength of that relationship and continuing to strengthen that relationship.<br><br>I&#8217;ll speak also about what happened in Buffalo.&nbsp; It&#8217;s horrendous.&nbsp; It&#8217;s horrendous.&nbsp; In our country, we have to recognize that we may very well be experiencing an epidemic of hate towards so many Americans that is wrong.&nbsp; It is taking on a level of violence &#8212; in the case of what happened in Buffalo, and we&#8217;ve seen it in other places in our country.&nbsp; And we all must speak out against it.<br><br>Hate against any one of us, we should interpret as being hate against all of us, as a nation.&nbsp; We are a nation that prides ourselves on our diversity as an element of our strength.&nbsp; And to see what has happened yesterday &#8212;<br><br>An 86-year-old grandmother who had just been taking care of her husband in a nursing home, was just going to get some groceries.<br><br>A security guard who dedicated his life as a law enforcement officer and was known in the community to be one of the kindest, most gentle people, who showed extraordinary heroism.<br><br>I think we all have to know that this is something that we have to not only speak about, but we&#8217;ve got to do everything in our power as a nation to stop it &#8212; to stop it.&nbsp; There&#8217;s too much at stake that we should be working at and thinking about, not hating one another.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at the National Peace Officers’ Memorial&#160;Service</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-national-peace-officers-memorial-service/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 21:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. CapitolWashington, D.C. 12:28 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  President Yoes; Auxiliary President Hennie; Auxiliary President Lehmann; and Director and good friend Jimmy Pasco &#8212; we&#8217;ve worked together a long time: Thank you for inviting me to join you today and for the service you&#8217;ve extended to this nation.  I’d also like to thank the Attorney&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">U.S. Capitol<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>12:28 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  President Yoes; Auxiliary President Hennie; Auxiliary President Lehmann; and Director and good friend Jimmy Pasco &#8212; we&#8217;ve worked together a long time: Thank you for inviting me to join you today and for the service you&#8217;ve extended to this nation. <br><br>I’d also like to thank the Attorney General &#8212; General Garland; Attorney General Gupta; Homeland Security Secretary Mayorkas; and the Directors of the FBI and Secret Service;  Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms; the U.S.  Marshalls Service; U.S. Capitol Police &#8212; all for being here, but for your leadership. <br><br>We’re also joined by my long-time friends, Senator Patrick Leahy and House Majority Leader Steny Hoyer. <br><br>Before I begin, let me say a word about yesterday’s mass shooting in Buffalo, New York.  A lone gunman, armed with weapons of war and a hate-filled soul, shot and killed 10 innocent people in cold blood at a grocery story on Saturday afternoon. <br><br>Jill and I, like all of you, pray for the victims and their families and a devastated community.<br><br>I’ve been receiving updates from my team at the White House that’s in close contact with the Justice Department.  We&#8217;re still gathering the facts, but already the Justice Department has stated publicly that it is investigating the matter as a hate crime, a racially motivated act of white supremacy and violent extremism.  <br><br>As they do, we must all work together to address the hate that remains a stain on the soul of America.  Our hearts are heavy once again, but our resolve must never, ever waver.  <br><br>No one understands this more than the people sitting in front of me &#8212; moms, dads, children, family members &#8212; about how those folks in Buffalo feel today when they got the call.  They&#8217;re pulled into &#8212; it&#8217;s as if you get pulled into a black hole in your chest and there&#8217;s no way out.<br><br>Jill and I know &#8212; we know no memorial, no gestures can fill the void in the hearts they have now or that you &#8212; you who have lost someone feel as well.<br><br>Being here today and hearing the name of your husband, wife, father, mother, son, daughter, brother, sister brings it all back as if you just got that phone call 10 minutes ago.<br><br>The American people, we owe you.  You know, you (inaudible) down the street, you&#8217;re normal families, all neighbors.  And every day, you worry and you worry you&#8217;d get that phone call when they pinned on that shield.  And now you look at an empty chair.<br><br>Although I didn’t personally know your husbands, wives, sons, daughters, brothers, sisters, I knew them.  They were the first ones to run into help when everyone else ran away when we were kids, when we were young men and women.  Even in grade school, they&#8217;d jump in when someone else was threatened or being bullied, regardless of the odds.<br><br>Think about it.  It was part of their DNA.  They didn&#8217;t think about it in terms of serving and protecting and defending, but that&#8217;s what they did.  They served even before they put on that shield.  They protected.  And they were there.<br><br>Being a police officer is not just what they did.  It’s who they were.<br><br>I was telling the president of this organization, I grew up in a neighborhood where you became a cop, a firefighter, or a priest.  I wasn&#8217;t qualified for any of them, so here I am.  (Laughter.)  <br><br>But all kidding aside, we expect so much from our law enforcement officers today.  This is a different world we&#8217;re in.  Just in the last several years, it&#8217;s so much more complicated.  The job is complicated.   <br><br>Yet we expect so much more of all of you.  We expect you to be drug counselors for the 100,000 overdose deaths that took place this year &#8212; 100,000.  <br><br>We expect you to counsel those who speak to a couple in the midst of a violent confrontation of a husband and wife, man and woman.  So many of you are &#8212; literally and figuratively get caught in the crossfire.  You&#8217;re not trained psychologists; you&#8217;re law enforcement officers.<br><br>We expect you to be everything.  We expect everything of you.  Being a cop today is a heck of a lot harder than it’s ever been.  COVID-19 &#8212; one million deaths in America, leaving behind, the estimates indicate, nine significant family members or others who also look at that empty chair at the kitchen table.  So many kids left behind because of COVID and schools closing down.<br><br>You engage in longer shifts.  The strain and stress of it all is why I continue to be so committed to do more, do better to keep you safe, to keep our communities safe, and to build trust and respect that everyone deserves, particularly all of you.<br><br>We should focus on and fund the things we know that work, like crime prevention and community policing.  Not one cop in a car, but two walking the street.  Cops who walk the beat, who know the neighborhood, who can restore trust and safety. <br><br>Folks, the answer is not to abandon the streets.  It’s not to choose between safety and equal justice.  And we should agree: It’s not to defund the police.  It’s to fund the police.  Fund them with the resources, the training &#8212; (applause) &#8212; they need to protect our communities and themselves and restore trust among the police and the people. <br><br>My dad used to say &#8212; when someone would say, &#8220;Let me tell you what I value, Joe.&#8221;  He&#8217;d look at them and say, &#8220;Don’t tell me what you…&#8221;  My dad was a well-read, high-school-educated man who was a graceful man.  He&#8217;d say, &#8220;Don&#8217;t tell me what you value.  Show me your budget, and I will tell you what you value.&#8221;<br><br>Well, here’s what I value.  As soon as I came to office, we inherited a raging pandemic, with only 2 million people vaccinated.  We needed to rebuild our economy and restore public safety.  <br><br>We understood the risk that communities could face with rising violence during the pandemic and at a time when state and local budgets were shrinking because they didn&#8217;t have the tax base.  They were having to lay off cops, firefighters, teachers.  They were under tremendous strain.<br><br>So, we made sure we passed a thing called the American Rescue Plan, providing historic $350 billion directly to the cities and counties and states and Tribes so they didn&#8217;t have to lay off law enforcement.  They could keep the cops on the job and fight to keep communities safe. <br><br>And it’s working.  More than 300 communities, from big cities to small towns, are using more than $10 billion of American Rescue Plan funds for violence prevention and public safety this year &#8212; building new police training facilities; recruiting, which is getting harder; hiring; and giving policemen a raise; partnering with the federal, state, and local community groups to reduce gun violence; investing in community interventions that use trusted community members to work directly with people who are most likely to commit gun crimes or become the victims of gun crimes and intervene before it’s too late. <br><br>My mother used to say, &#8220;Out of everything bad, something good will come if you look hard enough for it.&#8221;  Well, we&#8217;re looking hard to determine why and what we can do to prevent that law enforcement officer being put in the middle.<br><br>I’m encouraging every mayor, governor to use the American resource money they have, and they have it now.  You spend it now &#8212; this summer, when crime historically spikes.<br><br>And this Rescue funding for police is part of a comprehensive strategy to combat violence in America.  I&#8217;ve laid out this plan to all the police agencies, and they&#8217;re taking a good look at it.<br><br>With my budget last year, we increased funding for state and local law enforcement by almost &#8212; well, not almost &#8212; 29 percent.  That included significant investment in Community Oriented Policing Services &#8212; the “COPS” program designed to build legitimacy and trust in communities, to address violent crime, to combat hate and extremism. </p>



<p>My budget for next year doubles the investment in community policing &#8212; $<s>573</s>&nbsp;[537] million, the most in over a decade.&nbsp;&nbsp;And on top of that, it includes $30 billion in new mandatory investments in law enforcement and crime prevention.&nbsp;<br><br>During my State of the Union Address, I announced what I called a Unity Agenda that brings the country together to address the big challenges we face.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And one of those included ending the opioid edemic [sic] &#8212; epidemic and addressing the mental health crisis.&nbsp; So many, young and old, because of this pandemic, need help.&nbsp; And having a problem &#8212; a mental problem &#8212; is no different that breaking your arm or your leg.&nbsp; You need invest in systems that provide adequate healthcare, counseling drug treatment, prevention, housing, education, and other social services to those that need it most.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, in most places, you serve your time in prison, you get a bus ticket and 25 bucks, and you end up under the same bridge you got arrested under the first time.&nbsp; They should have access to education and housing.&nbsp; Give them a chance to move beyond where they were.<br><br>And I’m committed to investing in mental health services so we have more school counselors, psychologists, and social workers working alongside you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, we have to do more to protect our officers’ mental health and emotional well-being.&nbsp; Suicide was the second-highest cause of death for law enforcement officers in 2021, surpassed only by COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Last November, I signed laws that extended critical peer counseling and mental health resources for officers, expanded elibilit- &#8212; eligibility for benefits for first responders who were disabled in the line of duty.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not unusual.&nbsp;<br><br>We wonder &#8212; we were talking briefly about the impact on the &#8212; post-traumatic stress.&nbsp; How many police officers have, multiple times, been put in line and had to do things that they didn&#8217;t have to &#8212; think they&#8217;d have to do?<br><br>We recognize it with our military.&nbsp; More people continue to die from post-traumatic stress at home than die in any wars that are going on now &#8212; 20 a week.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; We face up to it and help these folks &#8212; everyone.<br><br>There are other areas we need to continue to work on together.&nbsp; Forty percent of all the calls that result in an officer’s death are calls to intervene in a domestic violence dispute.&nbsp; Let me say it again: Forty percent.<br><br>You expect officers to have degrees in psychology?&nbsp; Do we expect them to have things that are beyond the capacity of any PhD or doc or anybody else?<br><br>That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important to get reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act, providing critical resources for law enforcement.<br><br>And I want to acknowledge law enforcement’s constructive role in trying to reach an agreement on meaningful policing legislation in Congress.&nbsp; We haven’t gotten there yet, but we must get there to strengthen public trust and public safety.&nbsp;<br><br>2021 was one of the strongest years on record when it comes to federal support delivered to state and local law enforcement.&nbsp; But while these are important steps, there&#8217;s much more work to be done.&nbsp; I’m committed to being your partner, as I always have.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me close with this.&nbsp; Jill and I know how it is when there&#8217;s a memorial service for our son, who won the Bronze Star and Conspicuous Service Medal in Iraq.&nbsp; We were proud, but we also &#8212; it&#8217;s bittersweet, because you remember everything.<br><br>I want to thank the families that are here.&nbsp; It really takes courage to show up, because everything comes back.&nbsp; Everything comes back.<br><br>A short walk from here at the National Law Enforcement Memorial, there is a quote engraved on the wall.&nbsp; And the quote goes, &#8220;It is not how these officers died that made them heroes, it is how they lived.&#8221;<br><br>To the families, Jill and I &#8212; we have some idea how hard it is.&nbsp; But I promise you: The day will come when the memory of your loved one &#8212; you open that closet door and you smell the scent, or you go by that park you used to walk in, or you hear that song.&nbsp; The day will come when it will bring a smile to your lips before it brings a tear to your eyes.&nbsp; And through your pain and your will to find a purpose worthy of how they lived, you&#8217;ll get through it.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s nothing easy about it.<br><br>Our hope and prayer is that we as a nation find that purpose as well.&nbsp; May the souls of those who you loved and those with whom you served rest in peace and rise in glory.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our police and our troops.&nbsp; God bless you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>12:46 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the United Arab Emirates to Pay Respects Upon the Death of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan, President of the United Arab&#160;Emirates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/15/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-united-arab-emirates-to-pay-respects-upon-the-death-of-his-highness-sheikh-khalifa-bin-zayed-al-nahyan-president/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential&#160;Delegation to&#160;Abu Dhabi,&#160;United Arab Emirates,&#160;to&#160;pay respects upon the death of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed&#160;Al&#160;Nahyan, President of the United Arab Emirates, on May&#160;16, 2022. &#160; The Honorable&#160;Kamala Harris,&#160;Vice President of the United States&#160;of America,&#160;will lead the delegation. Members of the Presidential Delegation: Mr.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential&nbsp;Delegation to&nbsp;Abu Dhabi,&nbsp;United Arab Emirates,&nbsp;to&nbsp;pay respects upon the death of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed&nbsp;Al&nbsp;Nahyan, President of the United Arab Emirates, on May&nbsp;16, 2022. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The Honorable&nbsp;Kamala Harris,&nbsp;Vice President of the United States&nbsp;of America,&nbsp;will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</strong></p>



<p>Mr. Sean Murphy,&nbsp;Chargé&nbsp;d’Affaires&nbsp;ad interim, U.S. Embassy Abu Dhabi</p>



<p>The Honorable&nbsp;Antony J. Blinken, Secretary of State of the United States</p>



<p>The Honorable Lloyd&nbsp;J.&nbsp;Austin&nbsp;III, Secretary of Defense of the United States</p>



<p>The Honorable John F. Kerry, Special Presidential Envoy for Climate</p>



<p>The Honorable Philip Gordon, Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor to the Vice President</p>



<p>The Honorable William Burns, Director of the Central Intelligence Agency</p>



<p>The Honorable Brett McGurk, Deputy Assistant to the President and&nbsp;Coordinator for the Middle East and North Africa, National Security Council</p>



<p>The Honorable Barbara Leaf, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for the Middle East and North Africa, National Security Council</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Harris on Mass Shooting in Buffalo, New York&#160;</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/15/statement-by-vice-president-harris-on-mass-shooting-in-buffalo-new-york/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 16:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today our hearts are broken and we grieve for the victims of the horrific act of gun violence in Buffalo and for their families and friends.  The Second Gentleman and I are praying for all those who knew and lost love ones.  Law enforcement is proceeding with its investigation, but what is clear is that we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today our hearts are broken and we grieve for the victims of the horrific act of gun violence in Buffalo and for their families and friends.  The Second Gentleman and I are praying for all those who knew and lost love ones. <br> <br>Law enforcement is proceeding with its investigation, but what is clear is that we are seeing an epidemic of hate across our country that has been evidenced by acts of violence and intolerance.  We must call it out and condemn it. Racially-motivated hate crimes or acts of violent extremism are harms against all of us, and we must do everything we can to ensure that our communities are safe from such acts. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
