<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 03:58:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout from Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Constitutional Law, Privacy, and Technology Experts on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/readout-from-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-constitutional-law-privacy-and-technology-experts-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 03:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris held a roundtable with constitutional law, privacy, and technology experts to discuss what is at stake if Roe v. Wade is overruled. The roundtable followed recent meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with faith leaders, and with health care providers, and is part of the Administration’s work&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris held a roundtable with constitutional law, privacy, and technology experts to discuss what is at stake if <em>Roe v. Wade</em> is overruled. The roundtable followed recent meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with faith leaders, and with health care providers, and is part of the Administration’s work to build coalitions and preparedness in response to the attack on reproductive rights.<br>&nbsp;<br>During the meeting, the Vice President said that the principles of liberty and self-determination are at stake in the Supreme Court’s leaked opinion in <em>Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization. </em>The conversation highlighted the real-world limitations to liberty that the American people will experience if <em>Roe v. Wade </em>is overruled. The participants discussed constitutional law and the history and meaning of the right to privacy. The participants expressed concerns that if <em>Roe v. Wade</em> is overturned, states with abortion bans could potentially restrict in vitro fertilization if their definition of life begins at the point of fertilization.&nbsp;They raised the impact that overturning<em> Roe</em> could have on access to contraception and same-sex marriage. They also discussed implications on data privacy – including concerns that states that make abortion illegal may subpoena women’s personal data.<br>&nbsp;<br>The participants also discussed the maternal health care crisis, which disproportionately impacts Black women, rural women, and Native women – and they described the detrimental impact that overturning <em>Roe v. Wade</em> will have on women’s health.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Vice President raised the connection between restrictions on reproductive rights and limitations on other rights, noting that many of the states that have trigger ban laws where abortion will be banned if the Supreme Court overrules <em>Roe v. Wade</em> are also the states that are passing laws to restrict voting rights and LGBTQ+ rights.<br>&nbsp;<br>Vice President Harris called on the legal experts to use their voices to inform the American people about the potential consequences of the Court’s decision. The Vice President affirmed that the Administration will continue to fight for the health, safety, and wellbeing of women.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Participants:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Professor Peggy Cooper Davis of NYU School of Law &nbsp;</li><li>Professor Melissa Murray of NYU School of Law</li><li>Professor Glenn Cohen of Harvard Law School</li><li>Professor Michele Bratcher Goodwin of UC Irvine School of Law</li><li>Jennifer Weiss-Wolf of Brennan Center for Justice and Ms. Magazine</li><li>Professor Leah Litman of University of Michigan Law School</li><li>Domestic Policy Advisor to the Vice President Rohini Kosoglu</li><li>White House Counsel Dana Remus</li><li>Executive Director and Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council Jennifer Klein</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-asian-american-native-hawaiian-and-pacific-islander-leaders-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 02:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, Erika Moritsugu, Deputy Assistant to the President and Senior Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA and NHPI) Liaison, the White House Office of Public Engagement, the White House Gender Policy Council, and the Office of the Vice President convened a meeting with AA and NHPI leaders on reproductive health and rights. Participants&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, Erika Moritsugu, Deputy Assistant to the President and Senior Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA and NHPI) Liaison, the White House Office of Public Engagement, the White House Gender Policy Council, and the Office of the Vice President convened a meeting with AA and NHPI leaders on reproductive health and rights. Participants discussed the devastating consequences that overturning&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>&nbsp;would have on AA and NHPI communities, who overwhelmingly support reproductive rights, which have been guaranteed under&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>&nbsp;for nearly 50 years and are integral to equality, opportunity, and self-determination.<br><br>Advocates highlighted the importance of using an intersectional approach&nbsp;anchored on ensuring accessibility, language access, and cultural competency; all crucial in reproductive freedom. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials highlighted the President and Vice President’s commitment to supporting reproductive health and rights and the Administration’s commitment to including the diverse AA and NHPI communities in conversations on this critical issue and other key priorities.<br><br>Participants included representatives from:<br><br>National Asian Pacific American Women’s Forum (NAPAWF)&nbsp;<br>Asian Americans Advancing Justice – AAJC&nbsp;<br>Empowering Pacific Islander Communities (EPIC)<br>RISE<br>Asian Pacific Institute for Gender Based Violence (API-GBV)<br>Asian &amp; Pacific Islander American Health Forum (APIAHF)<br>National Association of Asian Pacific Community Health Organizations (AAPCHO)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the 29th AFL-CIO Quadrennial Constitutional&#160;Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-29th-afl-cio-quadrennial-constitutional-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 21:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Philadelphia Convention CenterPhiladelphia, Pennsylvania 11:03 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, AFL-CIO!  (Applause.)  You ain’t labor, you’re union.  It makes a difference!  (Laughs.)  It’s good to be home.  (Applause.)  As they say in Claymont, you all brung me to the dance.  Thank you. Please.  Please, have a seat if there is one.  (Laughs.)  You’re a gigantic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Philadelphia Convention Center<br>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>11:03 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, AFL-CIO!  (Applause.)  You ain’t labor, you’re union.  It makes a difference!  (Laughs.)  It’s good to be home.  (Applause.)  As they say in Claymont, you all brung me to the dance.  Thank you.<br><br>Please.  Please, have a seat if there is one.  (Laughs.) <br><br>You’re a gigantic reason why I’m standing here &#8212; standing here today as your President.  I really mean it.  I owe you.  From the very beginning of my running for office, back when I was a kid, it was labor, the unions.  Made a difference.  At the time, we were a right-to-work state, and we changed that too.<br><br>You’ve &#8212; I’ve never forgotten not only what you’ve done for me but how importantly it meant to me and &#8212; and to the country, to our country &#8212; what you’ve done for our country.</p>



<p>And I want to thank Liz for being such a good friend for so long, the first woman to lead the AFL-CIO.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Born into a union household.&nbsp; Started out as an organizer, and she never stopped.&nbsp; Congratulations, Liz.&nbsp; Congratulations.</p>



<p>And congratulations to Fred Redmond, your Secretary-Treasurer as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I hope your daughter-in-law knows she’s marrying into a union family.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Anyway, look, I know this is bittersweet for all of us.&nbsp; This is the first convention without Rich Trumka.&nbsp; Rich was not only a legendary labor leader, he literally was a close friend to me and to so many of you.&nbsp; A true friend, particularly there when things weren’t going well.&nbsp; He was always there.</p>



<p>Above all, he was an American worker.&nbsp; No matter how high he rose through the ranks, he never forgot where he came from.&nbsp; We use that phrase all the time &#8212; “never forget where you came from.”&nbsp; He never forgot where he came from or what this work is all about.</p>



<p>You know, before Rich passed, he gave me &#8212; (applause) &#8212; he gave me the highest compliment that I’ve ever gotten in my life, and I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; He called me &#8212; which your president just did &#8212; the “most pro-union President in history.”&nbsp; I promised you I would be, and I commit to you: As long I have this job, I will remain that.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.<br><br>I’ve got to tell you, nothing made me prouder than that.&nbsp; That’s why I made sure we put a former union president in as Secretary of Labor.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; <em>Marty Walsh.&nbsp; Marty.</em>&nbsp; (Pronounced in Boston accent.)&nbsp; He’s going to learn how to speak English, but he’s real.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I kid him all the time.&nbsp; I’m joking.&nbsp; He <em>parks his car in a car barn</em> &#8212; (pronounced in Boston accent) &#8212; but he knows what he’s doing.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Marty was here yesterday, and he’s doing a hell of a job, but he fights like hell for us all.</p>



<p>And just yesterday &#8212; (applause) &#8212; just yesterday, I had a conversation &#8212; a Zoom conversation &#8212; with our next senator from this state, John Fetterman.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You know, if you’re in a foxhole, you want John with you, man.<br><br>I know he can’t wait to get back on the trail.&nbsp; He’s looking good.&nbsp; And there’s no bigger, stronger voice for working people in this state than John &#8212; certainly no bigger one, for that matter.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p><a>Look, we’re also joined here today by three great members of Congress who flew up with me on Air Force One: Brendan Boyle, who is labor, labor, labor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Donald Norcross, who is labor, labor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Mary <s>Kay</s> [Gay] Scanlon as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; All &#8212; by the way, they’ve all be there when the tough &#8212; when the votes were tough.&nbsp; When the votes were tough to stay with you, they were there.&nbsp; And they’re great champions of unions.<br><br></a>And Stacey Abrams is here as well.&nbsp; By the way, I’m going to ask you all a favor.&nbsp; Help her in Georgia.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Help Stacey Abrams in Georgia.</p>



<p>There’s three things I learned about her early on.&nbsp; One, she’s loyal.&nbsp; Two, she’s capable.&nbsp; And three, she’s smarter than you &#8212; me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She knows what she’s doing.&nbsp; So, folks, please, help her out.<br><br>And, folks, thanks to all of you, we’re coming along and &#8212; we’ve come a long way in a short time.</p>



<p>Do you remember when our economy was like &#8212; what it looked like before we took office?&nbsp; Three thousand Americans were dying every day from COVID.&nbsp; Twenty million Americans had lost their jobs under the last guy.</p>



<p>In fact, so many Americans lost their jobs that my predecessor became just the second President in history to leave office with fewer jobs in America than when he took office.&nbsp; But you stepped up.&nbsp; The other one, by the way, was Herbert Hoover.</p>



<p>And just remember &#8212; remember those long lines of cars stretching miles back, waiting for just a box of food to be put back in their trunk?&nbsp; It wasn’t just poor folk, it was working-class folk, it was middle-class folks.&nbsp; A lot of pretty nice cars in those lines.<br><br>And while it was going on, America created more than &#8212; more billionaires during that crisis in 2020 than any year in history.&nbsp; Talk about a contrast.<br><br>Ordinary people getting &#8212; waiting in line for an hour for a box of food.&nbsp; And the policies in the past created more billionaires than ever in American history.<br><br>Folks, it’s hard to believe, but it’s true.&nbsp; That’s what we inherited.</p>



<p>And then, with your help, we went to work with an economic vision that looks out from Scranton, Pennsylvania &#8212; hardworking towns like it all across America &#8212; not down from Wall Street.</p>



<p>Wall Street didn’t build this country, the middle class built this country.&nbsp; And unions built the middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I’m not joking.&nbsp; Without unions, there would be no middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That’s a fact.</p>



<p>And, by the way, there’s a reason.&nbsp; You’re the best-trained workers in the world, not a &#8212; that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; When you do well, everybody does well.</p>



<p>You know, if investment bankers in America &#8212; they’re not all bad guys. &nbsp;They’re not bad.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; If they went on strike, not a whole hell of a lot would happen.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; I tell this to my buddy &#8212; if the IB- &#8212; IBEW went on strike, everything shuts down.&nbsp; (Applause.) All of you.&nbsp; Go down the row.<br><br>No, I’m serio- &#8212; no, you guys don’t understand; you don’t ta- &#8212; you don’t &#8212; I don’t think you appreciate how critically important you are.&nbsp; I’m not trying to be nice to you; it’s just a fact.<br><br>Folks, we need an economy built from the middle out and the bottom up, not the top down.&nbsp; Because I know when the middle class does well, everybody does.&nbsp; The wealthy do very well.&nbsp; They’re never hurt.</p>



<p>But I also know too often we’ve had an economy where the wealthy do better and better while the middle class gets left behind.</p>



<p>So we went to work to change that.&nbsp; It started with the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; The law helped 41 mi- &#8212; people &#8212; 41 million people put food on their table.&nbsp; Remember, they were having trouble putting food on their table.&nbsp; It put money in the pockets of hardworking Americans who were in trouble, being thrown out on the street because they couldn’t pay their rent through no fault of their own.&nbsp; It gave them what my dad used to call “just a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The next step was the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; And now not only is it Infrastructure Week, we&#8217;ve arrived at Infrastructure Decade!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And people are going to see a lot of it.&nbsp; We got to remind them where it&#8217;s coming from.&nbsp; We announced nearly $3 billion this year to improve more than 3,000 airports across 50 states this year &#8212; this year.&nbsp; We announced $5 billion so union workers could get to work building a national network of electric vehicle charging stations.&nbsp; We announced the largest investment of public transit in American history &#8212; more than the entire Amtrak system when it started: $20.5 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the people we come from &#8212; like when the President &#8212; President Obama used to always give me the good assignments.&nbsp; Well, I remember one day, I walked in &#8212; not a joke &#8212; he said, “Joe, fix Detroit.”&nbsp; I said, “Okay, no problem.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, you think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.</p>



<p>What I didn&#8217;t realize is I already knew a lot about the cities.&nbsp; When I was in Detroit, the vast majority of the people living in these cities, their jobs are out of town because they&#8217;re not doing manufacturing in towns anymore.&nbsp; Out of town.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we got a rail system for them.&nbsp; We got a freight sys- &#8212; we got a bus system.&nbsp; It changed it.&nbsp; It’s growing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to create more good jobs using products that are made in America.&nbsp; And, folks, it&#8217;s also going to reduce pollution while it&#8217;s making it safer and safer for folks to go to work and get to work every day.</p>



<p>What all this means for all of you is a simple proposition.&nbsp; And I remember us having this discussion, old buddy.&nbsp; When I think global warming, I think jobs.&nbsp; Jobs, jobs, jobs.&nbsp; Good-paying union jobs.&nbsp; Jobs you can raise a family on.&nbsp; Jobs you can’t out- &#8212; be outsourced.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, the infrastructure law is about more than rebuilding our infrastructure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about rebuilding the middle class.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we made sure that the infrastructure law included significant labor protections.&nbsp; For example, I insisted that the overwhelming majority of the funds included in the law are subject to Davis-Bacon requirements.&nbsp; Union has to do it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And it’s not just because they want to help unions.&nbsp; It’s simple: You’re the best in the world.&nbsp; If we’re going to build infrastructure, we should have &#8212; you know, what I always find we don&#8217;t talk enough about, and I&#8217;m not going to take the time today &#8212; but you know what?&nbsp; You don&#8217;t just decide you want to be a pipe fitter or an electrician or whatever else you want to pick.&nbsp; It takes you four or five years’ hard work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s like going to college.&nbsp; Fortunately, you get these union paid &#8212; you get paid to do some of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my point is: People don&#8217;t realize &#8212; and I see every place I go &#8212; and you&#8217;ve heard me do it at Chambers of Commerce &#8212; the best-trained workers in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, folks rebuilding our country will earn a prevailing wage.&nbsp; They should.</p>



<p>Another thing the law does: It’s helped expand registered apprenticeships.&nbsp; Remember when the la- &#8212; when the business was saying, “We’ll take care of the apprenticeships?”&nbsp; Bless me Father, for I have sinned.&nbsp; Come on, man!&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; Come on.</p>



<p>Union partnerships that allow workers to earn while they learn.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; Because laying a strong foundation for the future of this country is about more than having strong roads and bridges.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about making sure that, here in America, folks who work hard can live their lives with dignity and respect.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why I continue to call on Congress to finally pass the PRO Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; which will make it easier for workers to organize.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, when Franklin Roosevelt passed the NLRB, it didn&#8217;t say you can&#8217;t have unions.&nbsp; It said we should encourage unions.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the NLRB says.&nbsp; It’s a big difference.</p>



<p>And, look, I&#8217;m not just saying that to be pro-union.&nbsp; I&#8217;m saying it because I&#8217;m pro-American.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, that&#8217;s the approach I&#8217;ve taken to build this economy.&nbsp; And what has to be done?&nbsp; Well, we brought down COVID deaths by 90 percent.&nbsp; We opened schools and businesses that were shuttered.&nbsp; All &#8212; it all created the greatest job recovery in American history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>People don&#8217;t want to talk about it these days, but it&#8217;s true: Since I&#8217;ve become President, we&#8217;ve created 8.7 million new jobs in 16 months.&nbsp; An all-time record.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And even last month, 390,000 jobs and 600,000 new manufacturing jobs.&nbsp; And they said manufacturing is dead in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, folks, our unemployment rate is near historic lows &#8212; and 3.7 percent.&nbsp; And millions of Americans are leaving &#8212; I love these guys talking about why these &#8212; “This guy left my employment and went to another job.”&nbsp; Because he got paid more.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t that awful?&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t that a shame that they got to compete for labor?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Better-paying jobs, for better jobs for them and their families.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a long time since that&#8217;s happened in this country, but it&#8217;s happening now.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s working.</p>



<p>Since I took office, with your help, families are carrying less debt nationwide.&nbsp; They have more savings nationwide.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; More Americans applied for new small businesses last year than ever before in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; 5.4 million new small-business applications.&nbsp; Jobs and companies are coming home again.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re making “Buy American” a reality, not just a slogan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I award no contracts from the federal government unless they can prove they bought it in America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, Republicans like to portray me as some kind of big spender.&nbsp; We have spent a lot of money, but let&#8217;s compare the facts.&nbsp; Under my predecessor, the deficit exploded, raising &#8212; rising every single year.&nbsp; And all of the benefit going to the top 1 percent, basically.</p>



<p>Under my plan, last year we cut the deficit by $350 billion, doing all this.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know, they talk about, “Biden wants to spend more on schools and all this.&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; He’s going to create a deficit.”</p>



<p>Ladies and gentlemen, this year, by the end of the fiscal year, we will have cut the federal deficit by another $1.6 trillion &#8212; in one year.&nbsp; One year.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So, when they come to you and talk about big spenders, let them know.&nbsp; Almost $2 trillion in deficit reduction.</p>



<p>I don’t want to hear any more of these lies about reckless spending.&nbsp; We’re changing people’s lives.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And because of the fact, this year, we’re delivering the biggest drop in the deficit in the history of the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, the point is this: Under my plan for the economy, we’ve made extraordinary progress.&nbsp; And we put America in a position to tackle the wor- &#8212; worldwide problem that’s worse everywhere but here: inflation.&nbsp; It’s sapping the strength of a lot of families.</p>



<p>I grew up in household not far from here, in Claymont and Wilmington, where if the price of a gallon of gasoline went up, it was a conversation at the dinner table.&nbsp; It mattered.&nbsp; It mattered in my working family.&nbsp; It mattered if the price of food went up.</p>



<p>The problem is Republicans in Congress are doing everything they can to stop my plans to bring down costs on ordinary families.</p>



<p>That’s why my plan is not finished and why the results aren’t finished either.&nbsp; Jobs are back, but prices are still too high.&nbsp; COVID is down, but gas prices are up.&nbsp; Our work isn’t done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here’s the deal.&nbsp; America still has a choice to make: a choice between a government by the few, for the few, or a government for all of us, democracy for all of us, an economy where all of us have a fair shot and a chance to earn our place in the economy.</p>



<p>My plan is simple.</p>



<p>First, I’m doing everything in my power to blunt Putin’s gas price hike.&nbsp; Just since he invaded Ukraine, it’s gone up $1.74 a gallon &#8212; because of nothing else but that.</p>



<p>So I have a plan to bring down the cost of gas and food.&nbsp; It’s going to take time, but let the world coordinate the largest release of what I have been able to do &#8212; the largest release of oil in &#8212; from the global fund in history.&nbsp; A million barrels a day.&nbsp; And 240 million barrels to boost global supply while I convinced other nations to join us to keep prices from ri- &#8212; keep prices from rising even more.</p>



<p>And I’m working closely with our European partners to get 20 million tons of grains locked in Ukraine out onto the market to help bring down food prices.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, look, what Putin’s war has done is not only tried to wipe out the culture of the Ukrainians, decimate people, and commit innumerable war crimes, but is also &#8212; he’s also prevented the grain &#8212; thousands of tons of grain that are locked up in those silos, ready to be exported, but they can’t get out through the Black Sea because they’ll get blown out of the water.&nbsp; So we’re working on a plan to get it out through other countries by rail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But guess what?&nbsp; Ukraine has a system like Russia has &#8212; a rail gauge that is different than the gauge of the rest of the tracks in Europe.&nbsp; So we’re going to build silos &#8212; temporary silos &#8212; in the borders of Ukraine, including in Poland, so we can transfer it from those cars into those silos, into cars in Europe, and get it out to the ocean, and get it across the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But it’s taking time.</p>



<p>Second, we’re going to work to bring down gas and food prices.&nbsp; We can save families money and other items.&nbsp; We can change the dynamic of the middle-class families.&nbsp; Look, give them a little breathing room, as my dad said.&nbsp; You heard me say that before.</p>



<p>But imagine you’re &#8212; what most middle-class and working-class families do is they look at that monthly bill they have on everything.&nbsp; Maybe the rent or the mortgage.&nbsp; The cost of maintaining the car.&nbsp; The food.&nbsp; The &#8212; everything.</p>



<p>So if portions of that go up, one of the ways to deal with inflation for families is to bring the other costs down.</p>



<p>For example, 200,000 people with Type 1 diabetes are paying up to $1,000 a month for insulin.&nbsp; We can make sure they pay no more than $35 a month.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>By that, I &#8212; and, by the way, drug companies will still do very well.&nbsp; It’ll cost them 10 bucks to develop that insulin.&nbsp; So they’re making three and half times their cost.</p>



<p>My plan gives Medicare the power to negotiate pharmaceu- &#8212; with the pharmaceutical companies, just like the Veterans Administration does.&nbsp; To bring down the average cost of prescription drugs is a gigantic way &#8212; (applause) &#8212; it really does &#8212; it affects the total amount of money you got to write out of that checkbook.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, gas is up and food is up, which we’re going to get down come hell or high water.&nbsp; But there’s other things we can do beyond getting the price of insulin down to $35 a month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Imagine the difference it could make.&nbsp; Imagine the difference it could make if, in fact, you had other things that I&#8217;ve been proposing.&nbsp; Imagine.&nbsp; Just imagine if you&#8217;re in a situation where you&#8217;re going to &#8212; able to be in a position where you pay for preschool for kids that are three and four years old, increasing exponentially their possibility of going, no matter what kind of family they come from, in terms of educational standing &#8212; to raise the standard for people.</p>



<p><a>Imagine what we could do if we &#8212; for childcare in a city like Philadelphia and New York &#8212; the big cities &#8212; Chicago.&nbsp; It costs you twelve to fourteen thousand dollars a <s>month</s> [year] for childcare.&nbsp; Well, they shouldn&#8217;t have to pay more than 7 percent of your income for that.&nbsp; We could easily afford to do it.</a></p>



<p>Look, we could do the same thing &#8212; (applause) &#8212; but I &#8212; but I really mean it.&nbsp; Think how that would change the families that you represent.&nbsp; Think how it would fam- &#8212; change the circumstances for working-class people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, it could do the same thing with utility bills.&nbsp; Congress could ease the cost of families today by passing the clean energy investments I proposed &#8212; things like a tax credit for business to produce cleaner energy, tax cuts for families that make their homes more energy efficient, which is the way &#8212; it would mean a lot more jobs, by the way, for some folks in this room.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I met with nearly a dozen large CEO &#8212; CEOs of the largest 12 utility companies in America.&nbsp; They said, “If you pass that tax cut &#8212; that tax credit for modernizing the homes, winterizing, et cetera, we will guarantee we’ll immediately lower the average cost of &#8212; energy cost $500 a year for the average family.”&nbsp; That’d help a lot.&nbsp; And in the long run, it would help finally make America truly energy independent.</p>



<p>So, in the future, American families no longer are subject to the whims of di- &#8212; whims of dictators halfway around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve laid out concrete plans for families to save money &#8212; (applause) &#8212; not only prescription drugs and utility bills, but on rent and mortgage costs, high-speed Internet.&nbsp; You guys out there are going to be putting in high speed, and we&#8217;ve already got the money for it &#8212; billions of dollars.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; When you get it done, it&#8217;s going to lower the cost of high-speed Internet for every family in America by 30 bucks a month.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a lot of money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a lot of jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, we can do all this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking &#8212; all I&#8217;m asking is for the largest corporations and the wealthiest Americans to begin to pay their fair share in taxes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m deadly earnest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anybody out there think the tax system is fair?&nbsp; Raise your hand.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, under my plan &#8212; I made this commitment in the beginning, and nothing has changed &#8212; no one making less than $400,000 a year will pay a single, solitary penny more in federal taxes.&nbsp; Nobody.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we’ll no longer have the situation where 55 of the largest Fortune 500 companies made $40 billion the last &#8212; each year of the last two years, and paid zero &#8212; zero &#8212; zero in federal income tax on that profit.&nbsp; $40 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, that&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; I know it sounds like I’m making &#8212; I give you my word it&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact is we&#8217;ve got about roughly 790 or so billionaires in America.&nbsp; You know what their average tax rate is for a billionaire?&nbsp; I&#8217;m serious now.&nbsp; This is dead earnest.&nbsp; You can check it out.&nbsp; Eight percent.&nbsp; The tax rate for all of you is significantly higher &#8212; two to three to four times higher.&nbsp; Tax rate.&nbsp; I say it again: 8 percent in federal taxes.&nbsp; Anybody in this room who thinks that &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s fair, but we got to do something about it.</p>



<p>And, by the way, it&#8217;s not just labor &#8212; organized labor, unions, and Democrats who think that.&nbsp; The average Republican knows it&#8217;s not fair.&nbsp; That suburbanite mom and dad out there, they look around and know it’s not fair.</p>



<p>I happen to believe that no billionaires should be paying a lower tax rate than a teacher, a firefighter, an electrician, or a cop.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Republicans have it all backwards.&nbsp; Their plan literally calls for increasing taxes on middle-class and working people and cutting taxes on corporations and wealthy Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m not talking about punishing anyone; just pay your fair share.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a matter of decency.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a matter of dignity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a matter of fiscal responsibility.</p>



<p>Look, I believe in bipartisanship, but I have no illusions about this Republican Party &#8212; the MAGA party.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been able to bring some Republicans along on parts of my plan.&nbsp; But the fact is Republicans in Congress are still in the grip of the ultra-MAGA agenda.&nbsp; They still refuse to consider changing any part of the Trump tax cuts, which delivered massive windfalls to billionaires and others, and they weren’t paid for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They still refuse to consider a minimum corporate tax of 15 per- &#8212; 15 percent minimum tax.&nbsp; They seem to think that the problem in America today is that working families aren’t paying enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congressional Republican Senator Rick Scott of Florida &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; as my mother would say, “God love him” &#8212; he laid out a plan.&nbsp; I think you have it on your desks.&nbsp; I just took one page of that plan.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; This is published.<br><br>It says, “All…” &#8212; this is one &#8212; just one of their ideas.&nbsp; “All federal legislation sunsets in five years.&nbsp; If the law is worth keeping, Congress <s>could</s> [can] pass it again.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, guess what that is?&nbsp; Social Security.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Social Security.&nbsp; Medicare.&nbsp; Medicaid.&nbsp; Every &#8212; that’s not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every five years, it would be put on the chopping block.&nbsp; Every five years.&nbsp; And if it’s not reinstated by a vote in the Senate of 60 or more, guess what?&nbsp; It automatically goes out of existence.&nbsp; That’s what they’re proposing.&nbsp; Unless a common &#8212; the Congress affirmatively votes back that &#8212; bring them back into existence.<br><br>Think about that.&nbsp; Social Security you paid for your whole life.&nbsp; Medicare.&nbsp; Medicaid.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Really, ask yourself: How well are you going to sleep at night knowing that every five years Ted Cruz and the other ultra-MAGA Republicans are going to vote on whether you’ll have Social Security, Medicare, or Medicaid?<br><br>It’s unlikely they’ll be able to wipe it out, but any one of you doubt for a second they’ll find ways to cut benefits and programs in order to keep anything going?<br><br>That’s what this is about.&nbsp; They’ve always wanted to cut Social Security.&nbsp; They’ve always wanted to cut Medicare.&nbsp; They’ve always wanted to cut Medicaid.&nbsp; But if you have to start from scratch?</p>



<p>The gentleman from Wisconsin, Senator Ron Johnson, is back at it again, trying to dismantle the Affordable Care Act, including its protections for pre-existing conditions.&nbsp;&nbsp; Hundred million people have pre-existing conditions.&nbsp; The only reason the insurance company has to cover it is because of that law &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and they’re never going to stop going after it.&nbsp;<br><br>So, now, with the plan of Senator Scott trying to walk back.&nbsp; But it’s clear: The last thing they want to see is workers with power in this country.<br><br>The bottom line is this: I truly believe we’ve made extraordinary progress by laying a new foundation for our economy, which becomes clear once global inflation beco- &#8212; begins to recede.</p>



<p>There’s so much at stake today.&nbsp; But the truth is: I’ve never been more optimistic about America than I am today.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I travel the world trying to put things back together.&nbsp; You know, Trump did not leave a very good situation.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You think I’m kidding.<br><br>No matter where I go in the world, whether it was the inter-American conference we just had for the &#8212; this si- &#8212; this hemisphere; or NATO; or dealing with the ASEAN countries; or the Far East, guess what?&nbsp; They look at me and I say &#8212; I say, “America is back.”&nbsp; And they look and me and they say, “For how long?”<br><br>This is America.&nbsp; We can do any damn thing we put our minds to.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; We’re not going back to the false promises of the trickle-down economics.&nbsp; We’re going forward.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re going forward.<br><br>I really mean this. &nbsp;I know I’m called a cockeyed optimist, but this is based on history.&nbsp; We’re the most unique country in the world.&nbsp; We’re organized on one notion.&nbsp; Every other country is organized based on ethnicity, religion, geography.&nbsp; But the United States is based on an idea.&nbsp; The only country in the world based on an idea.&nbsp; Think about it.<br><br>Look to your right.&nbsp; Look at your left.&nbsp; See if you’re &#8212; everybody all shares the same &#8212; the same backgrounds.&nbsp; We’re so diverse.<br><br>Why are we doing it?&nbsp; Because we said, “We hold these truths to be self-evident that all men and women are created equal” &#8212; (applause) &#8212; “endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights…life, liberty.”<br><br>We’ve never met the goal, but we’ve never &#8212; other than the Trump administration &#8212; tried to walk away from that goal.&nbsp; And it gets better every time we push.<br><br>And unions &#8212; unions are going to play a critical role in that future.&nbsp; America has always counted on union workers.&nbsp; Given just half a chance, you have never, ever, ever, ever let the country down.&nbsp; We’re counting on you again to build this country for all of us &#8212; (applause) &#8212; help build an economy that works for working people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I promise you, I’m going to keep fighting for you!&nbsp; Are you prepared to fight with me?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Well, let’s build it together!&nbsp; Let’s continue to give working families a fighting chance, face our challenges head on, and let’s keep building a better America.&nbsp; Because we can do it!&nbsp;</p>



<p>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We can do anything!&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:37 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with State Legislative Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-state-legislative-leaders-on-reproductive-rights-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, convened a meeting with state legislative leaders from Colorado, New Mexico, and Nevada on reproductive rights. Colorado, New Mexico, and Nevada have taken and will continue to take critical steps to improve reproductive health care and protect&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, convened a meeting with state legislative leaders from Colorado, New Mexico, and Nevada on reproductive rights.</p>



<p>Colorado, New Mexico, and Nevada have taken and will continue to take critical steps to improve reproductive health care and protect access to abortion. In the 2022 legislative session, Colorado passed the Reproductive Health Equity Act, which codifies the right to make reproductive health decisions free from government interference. In 2021, New Mexico repealed an abortion ban that had been in place since 1969, before the Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>Roe v Wade</em>.</p>



<p>This fall, Nevadans will also vote on an Equal Rights Amendment to the state constitution, which would prohibit the denial or abridgement of rights on account of an individual’s race, color, creed, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, age, disability, ancestry or national origin.</p>



<p>Legislators from all three states discussed specific policy measures that would advance women’s reproductive health, including expanding coverage of abortion care and protecting the safety and security of doctors and clinics. They also discussed the need to prepare for an anticipated surge in out-of-state patients seeking abortion care; after Texas’s six-week abortion ban went into effect last September, some clinics in the region experienced a <a href="https://www.krqe.com/health/new-mexico-abortion-clinics-seeing-increase-in-texas-patients/">500% increase</a> in patients.</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials thanked the state legislative leaders for their efforts to protect reproductive rights and expand access to reproductive health care, and committed to working together in the months ahead.</p>



<p>State legislative leaders from today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>Nevada Senate Majority Leader Nicole Cannizzaro</li><li>Colorado House Majority Caucus Co-Chair Meg Froelich</li><li>Colorado State Senator Julie Gonzales</li><li>New Mexico House Majority Floor Leader Javier Martinez</li><li>New Mexico State Senator Shannon Pinto</li><li>New Mexico State Representative Micaela Cadena</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Roundtable to Discuss Roe V.&#160;Wade</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-roundtable-to-discuss-roe-v-wade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 19:39:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial OfficeEisenhower Executive Office Building 2:32 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you for being here to be a part of this conversation.  And I look forward to &#8212; to consulting with you about the implications of what we believe might be the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision on Roe and what&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial Office<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></p>



<p>2:32 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  Thank you for being here to be a part of this conversation.  And I look forward to &#8212; to consulting with you about the implications of what we believe might be the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision on Roe and what the implications of that will be for the people of our country.<br> <br>I think we all believe and know that our nation was founded on certain principles that we hold dear: principles of freedom, liberty, and self-determination.  And I do believe that all of those principles are at stake when we look at the leaked draft opinion about what this decision may end up being.<br> <br>From these principles, most notably, come the constitutional right to privacy &#8212; the right of an individual to make decisions about their life, about their family, about their body without government interference.  And so, there&#8217;s a lot at stake in the outcome of this decision. <br> <br>And for that reason, I&#8217;ve asked these &#8212; these experts to be here to talk with me about how we might best prepare the American people for the consequences of what this decision will be &#8212; in terms of their life and the choices that they are able to make and have a right to make &#8212; so that, at the very least, folks can be prepared.<br> <br>But I do believe that we should prepare for the right to privacy to be attacked and under attack with this decision, and that will have a number of implications.  If Roe is overturned, I believe that states will then have the power to interfere in personal decisions.  I do believe that there are three specific areas that we should be prepared to address. <br> <br>One is the issue of data privacy and the potential that if Roe is overturned, that states that have criminalized abortion could subpoena a woman&#8217;s personal data.  And so, I’m &#8212; I want to talk to these experts about their concern and the level of their concern about that very issue, including, for example, the vulnerability of women who are using menstrual tracking apps; those who use a search engine to find certain locations or certain help, in terms of their reproductive health, and how vulnerable those searches will be to bad actors attempting to track their history, much less any government forces that may be interested in investigating that for whatever purpose.<br> <br>The issue of IVF &#8212; in vitro fertilization.  I have a concern that if Roe is overturned, states with abortion bans could potentially restrict IVF if their definition of life begins at the point of fertilization.  So I&#8217;d like to talk with these experts about their thoughts about that and whether the law is established or not &#8212; well established or not, in terms of the protection that individuals have if they are in the process of IVF.<br> <br> And then on the issue of contraception, if Roe is overturned, we believe that states with abortion bans from the moment of fertilization could potentially restrict specific types of contraception &#8212; in particular, IUDs and the so-called morning-after pill.  And so, I&#8217;d like to talk with these experts about their thoughts, in terms of the legal theories that would be at play if that were to take place.<br> <br>I do believe that overturning Roe could clear the way for challenges to other fundamental rights, including the right to use contraception and &#8212; and same-sex marriage.  And so, I&#8217;m going to talk with these folks about that.<br> <br>And I think it&#8217;s a very important point to make that many of the states that have passed trigger ban laws are also the states that are passing laws to restrict trans rights, gay rights, and the freedom to vote.<br> <br>And when you look at a diagram of the &#8212; just a Venn diagram, in that regard, it tells a real tale of the ideo- &#8212; ideological perspective that some of these state legislatures have, in terms of this various &#8212; these various rights that &#8212; that folks have been given as part of what we believe are inherent rights under the principles and the ideals and the values that we hold dear.<br> <br>So I look forward to this conversation.  In particular, again, it is focused on the right to privacy to which all Americans should be entitled and what we must do to be aware of what the Court might be doing to attack those rights to privacy and &#8212; and what we can do to educate and inform the American people of what is at stake with this decision coming down, probably sometime this month.<br> <br>So, with that, let&#8217;s get started with our conversation.  And I thank the press for being part of this part of it.<br> <br>Thank you.  See you later.<br> <br>END                 2:38 P.M. EDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on World Elder Abuse Awareness Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/a-proclamation-on-world-elder-abuse-awareness-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 16:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION It is more vital than ever that we ensure our older adults can age with the dignity, security, and appreciation that every person deserves.  Honoring and respecting older Americans is a matter of basic human dignity and justice &#8212; it is part of the character&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>It is more vital than ever that we ensure our older adults can age with the dignity, security, and appreciation that every person deserves.  Honoring and respecting older Americans is a matter of basic human dignity and justice &#8212; it is part of the character of our Nation.  Yet every year, many Americans aged 60 and older experience abuse and neglect.  On World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, we join the international community to raise awareness and help end elder abuse here at home and across the world. </p>



<p>Elder abuse takes many forms, such as&nbsp;financial, emotional, physical, and sexual harm, including intimate partner violence in later life.&nbsp;&nbsp;It often comes in the form of neglect, abandonment, or exploitation.&nbsp;&nbsp;It is estimated that approximately 1 in 10 elderly Americans are abused annually.&nbsp;&nbsp;However, many of those who are abused suffer in silence, and many cases&nbsp;are never reported or brought to light.&nbsp;&nbsp;In the past few years, while the pandemic isolated all of us to different extents, it especially exacerbated the isolation felt by too many older adults.&nbsp;&nbsp;All of us have a role to play in preventing elder abuse and ensuring that our Nation&#8217;s seniors are able to age with dignity.&nbsp;&nbsp;With a majority of elder abuse victims being women, my Administration is focused particularly on improving our support for all women and preventing and addressing gender-based violence that impacts older adults both domestically and abroad.</p>



<p>We must remain steadfast in our commitment to preventing elder abuse.&nbsp;&nbsp;My Administration allotted $178 million through the American Rescue Plan and the COVID-19 recovery bill to improve and strengthen the work of Adult Protective Services (APS).&nbsp;&nbsp;Additionally, my budget proposal for 2023 would provide ongoing support for APS and State Long-Term Care Ombudsman programs.&nbsp;&nbsp;Our comprehensive, collaborative efforts to respond to elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation include initiatives to reform guardianship, support adult decision-making, crack down on scammers and fraudsters, and empower victims of exploitation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Our commitment to supporting survivors of all ages is reflected in the reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act, which includes dedicated Federal funds to support survivor service providers, law enforcement, and prosecutors working to respond to domestic and sexual violence experienced by older adults.</p>



<p>As we continue to build a better America, we must ensure that we bring everyone along.&nbsp;&nbsp;That is why my Administration is&nbsp;committed to safeguarding the rights of those who live in retirement and shared residential settings.&nbsp;&nbsp;I have called on the Congress to deliver significant reforms to improve the safety and quality of care in our Nation&#8217;s nursing homes.&nbsp;&nbsp;Recognizing the critical work of caregivers,&nbsp;I have also proposed measures to create a strong and well-compensated caregiving workforce to advance the well-being of our Nation&#8217;s older adults.&nbsp;&nbsp;By ensuring a high quality of life and care for older Americans, we can support every community and honor the dignity of every person.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On this World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, let us recommit to delivering all older Americans the promise of a comfortable and peaceful life with dignity.&nbsp;&nbsp;Let us reaffirm our commitment to a&nbsp;world free from the scourge of abuse and neglect.&nbsp;&nbsp;Let us join the world in celebrating the essential role older adults play in our lives.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 15, 2022, as World Elder Abuse Awareness Day.&nbsp;&nbsp;I encourage all Americans to be diligent, work&nbsp;togetherto&nbsp;strengthen existing partnerships, and develop new opportunities to improve our Nation&#8217;s prevention and response to&nbsp;elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this&nbsp;fourteenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on the President’s Trip to The Middle&#160;East</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/14/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-the-presidents-trip-to-the-middle-east/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference&#160;(June 13, 2022) 8:01 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:  Good evening, everyone.  This call will be on background attributable to a senior administration official.  For your awareness, not for reporting, on the line is [senior administration official].  The contents of the call will be embargoed until 8:00 a.m. tomorrow, June 14th. And, [senior administration official], I&#8217;ll&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>&nbsp;<br>(June 13, 2022)</p>



<p>8:01 P.M. EDT<br><br>MODERATOR:  Good evening, everyone.  This call will be on background attributable to a senior administration official.  For your awareness, not for reporting, on the line is [senior administration official].  The contents of the call will be embargoed until 8:00 a.m. tomorrow, June 14th.<br><br>And, [senior administration official], I&#8217;ll hand it over to you to get started.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks.  And thank you for joining this call to a preview the President&#8217;s trip to the Middle East later next month.<br><br>My opening here is about 15 minutes or so, maybe a little longer.  There&#8217;s a lot of information, and so I wanted to get it all out there.  I point out at the top that this trip has been in the works for some time.  <br><br>We&#8217;ve long recognized the importance of the President visiting this vital region in a manner similar to the Summit of ASEAN leaders here at the White House, the President&#8217;s visit to South Korea and Japan and convening the Quad Summit, the Summit of the Americas last week, and the G7 and NATO summits next week.<br><br>So this visit to the Middle East region, where the President will engage with nearly a dozen of his counterparts in three stops &#8212; Israel, the West Bank, and Saudi Arabia &#8212; is part of this clear sequence of global engagements at an important moment and demonstrates, we believe, the return of American leadership to bring countries together to address common threats and challenges, something the United States can uniquely do, and with new frameworks that aim to harness unique American capabilities to enable partners to work more closely together, which is essential to a more secure, prosperous, and stable Middle East region over the long term.<br><br>This comparative advantage of ours &#8212; bringing countries together, building and strengthening coalitions and alliances &#8211;atrophied under the last administration.  We&#8217;ve worked to restore it.  And as I think we&#8217;ve seen since Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine, the United States and President Biden personally has begun to revitalize our unique strength in building alliances and coalitions through diplomacy and highest-level engagement.<br><br>In the Middle East region, the topic of this call, I’d point to the vote last week at the IAEA Board of Governors in Vienna, where 30 countries condemned Iran&#8217;s lack of compliance with safeguard obligations, a resounding vote clearly isolating Iran, whereas a year and a half ago, it was the United States that was isolated internationally on this important issue.<br><br>So while there&#8217;s a great deal of work to do, this historic visit to the Middle East comes against that larger backdrop, both globally and in the Middle East region itself. <br><br>So now some details on the trip.  The President will visit the Middle East region from July 13th to July 16th with stops in Israel, the West Bank, and Saudi Arabia, and engagements with nearly a dozen counterparts from across the region and beyond.  The first stop is Israel.  This will be President Biden&#8217;s first visit to the country as President, and it comes nearly 50 years after his first visit to Israel as a young senator. <br><br>As the President often says about Israel, he learned as a young boy from his father that if Israel did not exist, then we would need to invent it.  He has a lifelong connection to the country, and his charge to all of us is to make sure we&#8217;re doing all we can to strengthen Israel&#8217;s security, prosperity, and integration into the larger region, both now and over the longer term.<br><br>One of the first foreign crises of the presidency was the Israeli-Hamas war in May of last year.  The President&#8217;s personal relations with leaders in the region and his very hands-on diplomacy helped end that war, one that had all the ingredients to last for months, in 11 days.  He has since remained deeply engaged with Israeli and other regional leaders to help maintain the peace.<br><br>Our administration also worked with the Congress to secure $1 billion to replenish the Iron Dome Missile Defense System after the Gaza conflict.  And in March, earlier this year, the Congress passed an NDAA with the largest funding package for Israel in U.S. history, with a particular focus on missile defense and security assistance. <br><br>While in Israel, the President will likely visit an area where these defensive systems are utilized, as well as discuss new innovations between our countries that use laser technologies to defeat missiles and other airborne threats.<br><br>In meetings with Israeli leaders, the President will reaffirm the ironclad U.S. commitment to Israel’s security and new areas of deepening cooperation in technology, climate, commerce, trade, and other sectors. <br><br>The visit will also focus on Israel&#8217;s increasing integration into the region, both through the Abraham Accords with UAE, Morocco, and Bahrain; through deepening ties between Israel, Jordan and Egypt; and also an entirely new groupings of partners, including Israel, India, UAE, and the United States &#8212; what we call I2U2.<br><br>We consider these initiatives central to our strategy of empowering partners and encouraging them to work more closely together, which will lead to a more stable region and also to Israel&#8217;s security and prosperity over the longer term.  Secretary Blinken, just last month in the Negev, in southern Israel, met with counterparts from Abraham Accord partners UAE, Bahrain and Morocco, together with Jordan and Egypt, highlighting these deepening regional partnerships.<br><br>Importantly, some of these new partnerships reach beyond the Middle East, and in this regard, the President will hold a virtual summit with the I2U2 heads of state for discussions of the food security crisis and other areas of cooperation across hemispheres where UAE and Israel serve as important innovation hubs. <br><br>The President looks forward to this unique engagement with Prime Minister Bennett of Israel, with Prime Minister Modi of India, and President Mohammed bin Zayed of the UAE. <br><br>He will also, of course, hold side meetings and engagements, which we will preview in the run-up to the trip.<br><br>I note, finally, for the Israel portion that the President will be in Israel at the start of the Maccabiah Games, which brings Jewish athletes from around the world to Israel for an Olympics-like competition.  And he may have an opportunity to meet some of the athletes, and we&#8217;re pleased that this joyous event, the first since 2017, happens to overlap with the President&#8217;s historic visit to Israel.<br><br>The President will also visit the West Bank to meet with President Mahmoud Abbas and other Palestinian leaders.  The President, of course, has known Abbas for decades, and he looks forward to reaffirming his lifelong commitment to a two-state solution and to discuss the ways in which we might rekindle a new political horizon that can ensure equal measures of freedom, security, prosperity, and dignity to Israelis and Palestinians alike.  <br><br>Of course, when we entered office nearly a year and a half ago, ties between the U.S. government and the Palestinians had been nearly severed.  We&#8217;ve worked to restore those ties, and we now have regular engagements with the Palestinian leadership.<br><br>Jake Sullivan visited Ramallah shortly before the new year.  My State Department colleague Barbara Leaf was there just this past Saturday.<br><br>And we&#8217;ve provided over half a billion dollars in support, including humanitarian, economic, and security assistance for the Palestinians since April of last year. <br><br>The President&#8217;s visit is a culmination of these contacts but also the start of what we hope will be new and reinvigorated dialogue, both between the United States and the PA, but also between the PA regional capitals and, most importantly, Israelis. <br><br>Following the visits to Israel and the West Bank, the President will fly directly from Israel to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, where he will participate in a summit of the Gulf Cooperation &#8212; GCC+3 &#8212; the GCC+3 &#8212; so the leaders of Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Oman, UAE, Bahrain, and Qatar, plus Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt. <br><br>The President will also hold bilateral meetings with the Saudi hosts and other counterparts. <br><br>We are grateful that Saudi Arabia, which holds the rotating presidency of the GCC in 2022, will host this important summit bringing together nine heads of state from across the region to meet the President at the invitation of King Salman. <br><br>The President will discuss a range of bilateral regional and global issues in Jeddah.  These include support to the U.N.-mediated truce in Yemen, which has led to the most peaceful period there since the war began seven years ago.  <br><br>He will also discuss means for expanding regional, economic, and security cooperation, including new and promising infrastructure and climate initiatives, as well as deterring threats from Iran, advancing human rights, and ensuring global energy and food security. <br><br>The President also looks forward to outlining an affirmative agenda for America&#8217;s engagement in this vital region, making clear that the United States is fully committed to supporting the territorial defense of our partners against threats from Iran or elsewhere, and doing so in new integrated and innovative ways, while also combining these strong deterrent capabilities with proactive diplomacy to de-escalate tensions and wars wherever possible.  <br><br>One of those wars, of course, is Yemen.  And from the earliest days of our administration, we have sought to de-escalate and ultimately end this terrible conflict.  Intensive U.S. engagement and diplomacy in the region, including with Saudi Arabia in particular, helped facilitate the first durable truce in Yemen in nearly six years.  That truce, as I mentioned, is now in its ninth week, after having been extended just last week.  <br><br>For the first time since the war began more than seven years ago, civilian flights are flying from Sana&#8217;a to Cairo and Oman.  And Yemen itself has a new government under new leadership that seems determined to establish a durable peace.  <br><br>This will require a great deal of work going forward, and I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;ll be an important topic of discussion between the President and other leaders. <br><br>That brings me to Saudi Arabia.  From the earliest days of our administration, we made clear that U.S. policy demanded recalibration in relations with this important country but not a rupture.  And that is because we have important interests interwoven with Saudi Arabia, and engagement is essential to protecting and advancing those interests on behalf of the American people. <br><br>Saudi Arabia has been a strategic partner of the United States for nearly 80 years, and the President considers Riyadh an important partner on a host of regional and global priorities that we are working on.  <br><br>Since entering office, the President has had two constructive conversations with King Salman.  And senior officials from across our national security team have been engaged with the Saudis regularly on a host of issues from climate, to energy security, to new openings for regional cooperation, to human rights, to ending the war in Yemen, containing Iran, supporting our maritime defense, among many other topics. <br><br>And these engagements do deliver results.  Only 10 days ago, of course, we welcomed the announcement from OPEC Plus, where Saudi Arabia is the leading producer and exporter, to raise its plant supply increases this summer by 50 percent, as well as the important renewal of the Yemen truce.  These are welcomed moves, and we anticipate more of them over the coming months. <br><br>At bottom, the President believes strongly that at this particular moment in the world with interests at stake for the for the United States and the American people, visiting Saudi Arabia for a summit of leaders from across the Middle East region and to discuss face to face with those leaders, including the Saudis, how we move forward as partners is a smart thing to do at the right time, and offers opportunity for significant gains both for the United States, for Saudi Arabia, for the Middle East region, and for advancing our strategy towards a more stable, more peaceful, and more integrated region, which ultimately benefits the American people and the world. <br><br>I will not get ahead &#8212; on this call, I will not get ahead of some of the initiatives that are underway or that may be announced before or during the visit.  But I will say that this visit is the culmination of months of diplomacy, bilateral and multilateral, and also sets the stage for what we hope to get done through the rest of this year and through 2023 as well. <br><br>So with that, I&#8217;m happy to take a few questions.<br><br>Q    Thank you so much.  Thank you, [senior administration official], for doing this.  This is Nadia Bilbassy of Al Arabiya.  If you remember, during the Obama administration, there were mechanisms where they had a similar summit &#8212; as you just mentioned, this one will be analogous to the Asia and the Americas Summit &#8212; where President Obama met with the GCC countries and they discussed the U.S. and regional interest. <br><br>So will this new summit &#8212; will it establish to a mechanism similar to that, adding Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt permanently where it&#8217;s held every year, in an Arab capital?  And will be the main focus, in addition to very serious issues, of course, is countering Iran?<br><br>And one quick technical question: Will the President meet Mahmoud Abbas in Bethlehem or in Ramallah? <br><br>Thank you so much.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Well, thanks, Nadia, for great questions.  Look, I think it&#8217;s a much different time than six, seven years ago.  And I think this unique gathering of leaders in Jeddah and of the President flying directly from Israel to Jeddah, I think it offers some unique opportunities to discuss some important issues in the world, some of which I laid out, but obviously, containing Iran and energy security.<br><br>I think the President will discuss some pretty innovative initiatives we have ongoing in CENTCOM, in the Red Sea; some unique naval task forces, which we&#8217;ll discuss on the security side; but also the economic integration.  Again, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of anything, but there&#8217;s some really important infrastructure and climate projects that are being done across borders by capitals who are cooperating with each other in really new and promising ways.<br><br>So the Middle East is much different than it was six, seven years ago, and I think we&#8217;re looking &#8212; really looking forward in trying to build on some of the opportunities in ways that can benefit both the region but, most importantly, the United States and the American people. <br><br>And I don’t &#8212; it’s likely to be in Bethlehem, Nadia, but I don’t want to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to discuss the specific meetings, details, or anything like that.  We’ll have more details as the trip approaches. <br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q    Hey there.  Thanks for doing the call.  I &#8212; two quick questions.  One, you just said &#8212; you said it’s likely to be in Bethlehem.  I didn&#8217;t quite hear what you said.  <br><br>And, secondly, on the trip to Jeddah, is it to be assumed that the President will have a bilat, then, with MBS?  And then, can we assume &#8212; I mean, what do we say about if the Khashoggi issue comes up during that meeting?  Does he intend to bring it up during that meeting, or is it an attempt to leave it in the past at this point?<br><br>And then, anything else you tell us about who he’ll meet with?  Will he meet individually with each of these nine leaders there or only as a group?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah, so the President, I think, will have meetings with leaders.  I would just say he&#8217;ll see over a dozen leaders on this trip, and so that includes King Salman and the leadership from our Saudi hosts for the GCC+3 Summit.  So, yes, we can expect the President to see the Crown Prince.<br><br>And I would just note that our teams have been quite constructively engaged over the last five or six months on Yemen and a host of things that I laid out in the introduction.  So I think that answers your question, Peter.<br><br>But, you know, I&#8217;m not going to get into specific meetings or the tick-tock of the visit.  Obviously, one reason &#8212; I know there&#8217;s been a lot of speculation on when the visit will be announced.  One reason is simply we&#8217;re scheduling a lot with a lot of different leaders from all across the region, so to nail everything down takes time.  But we&#8217;re now in a place where we feel this has come together in a very constructive way for everyone involved, and the President is looking forward to it. And I think we have a lot of work to get done over these four days in the Middle East.<br><br>Q    Thanks.  Will there be any particular asks on human rights during the trip, as some lawmakers, including many Democratic allies, have made of the President as a condition of the trip? <br><br>And then secondly, have the Saudis made any commitments, as a condition of the trip, on energy? Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  So I think the first question follows up on something Peter asked; I don&#8217;t think I fully addressed.  Look, human rights is always a part of the conversation in our foreign engagements, and I think it&#8217;s what makes the United States unique.  I think it&#8217;s what makes our administration unique.  And I think if you look at our record, including in the human rights region, I think we&#8217;re the first administration that reprogrammed FMF funding from Egypt; we&#8217;ve taken a number of other measures.<br><br>I&#8217;ll also say, though, a lot of these conversations we do hold them behind closed doors, and we think engagement &#8212; and that is the best way to get results.  <br><br>But our administration is not overlooking any contact that took place before we entered office.  And, of course, early on, we issued an extensive report about the Khashoggi murder.  That, of course, was not new news.  That was a report from the U.S. government that was issued years earlier that had been bottled up.  And we promised to issue it, and we did.<br><br>At the same time, we instituted the so-called “Khashoggi ban” to make sure that any country that seeks to use tools of repression against people abroad who criticize their government will pay a price.  We&#8217;ve used it multiple times.  So we imposed sanctions or visa restrictions on over 70 Saudi individuals and entities, including the Saudi Royal Guard’s Rapid Intervention Force.  This, of course, was all done over a year ago. </p>



<p>&nbsp;I think it&#8217;s very important also, though, of course, to emphasize, as we did then, that while we recalibrate relations, we&#8217;re not seeking to rupture relations, because Saudi Arabia has been a strategic partner of the United States for eight decades.&nbsp; And we share a host of interests with Saudi Arabia, from containing Iran, to counterterrorism, to helping protect its territory where, importantly, 70,000 Americans live and work.&nbsp; And I just think that&#8217;s an important fact.&nbsp;<br><br>I mean, Saudi Arabia has faced hundreds of missiles and UAVs over the last 18 months, many of them targeting areas where Americans live and work.&nbsp; And so we have been engaged very deeply and very constructively with the Saudis to help defeat those threats, and that&#8217;s something, obviously, that is going to continue.<br><br>So, yes, human rights is always a part of our conversation; there’s no doubt it will be part of the meetings the President has in the region, both in the stop in Jeddah and also, of course, in the stop in Israel.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very important topic of our conversation with the Israelis as well, and the Palestinian Authority.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing the call.&nbsp; I just want to follow up on what you were just talking about regarding the Khashoggi ban.&nbsp; And I know you don&#8217;t want to go into any of the specific meetings, but can you just address the criticism that is already being made that engaging more directly with the Saudi leadership could inadvertently be interpreted as allowing them to sort of get off the hook for what happened and sort of reinforce some of the problematic tendencies around that event?&nbsp;<br><br>And how can the United States think about perhaps engaging with the Crown Prince while he&#8217;s still the Crown Prince &#8212; he’s not the leader of the country just yet &#8212; and without doing that?&nbsp; Anything just to sort of talk about that angle would be helpful.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so I think &#8212; look, the &#8212; as I think as we said before, the President is not going to change his views on human rights; he made that clear.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also made clear that as President of the United States, it&#8217;s his job to “bring peace, if I can.”&nbsp; I think that was his direct quote.&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to try to do.<br><br>And he focuses our entire national security team on getting things done for the American people.&nbsp; And if he determines it&#8217;s in his interest to engage with any particular leader, and if such an engagement can deliver results, then he&#8217;ll do so.<br><br>I just would point again to our engagement over &#8212; you&nbsp;know, a lot of it is not above the surface until something actually happens, such as the truce in Yemen.&nbsp; I mean, the truce in Yemen is a clear example of where our engagement with the Saudis delivered results.&nbsp; And, obviously, we have more to do. Our Special Envoy, Tim Lenderking, is (inaudible) this every single day, together with Hans Grundberg, the UN Envoy.<br><br>But ending the Yemeni war was a priority for the President from the earliest days of the administration.&nbsp; And we explained, at the time of the Khashoggi ban, we issued the report that one reason we&#8217;re going to remain engaged with Saudi Arabia is because it is our priority to try to end this war.&nbsp; And I have to say the Saudi Crown Prince played a critical role in securing the extension of the truce &#8212; that was in place since April &#8212; just last week; Khalid bin Salman, who was in town last week, similarly.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I cannot speak to what happened in the Yemen war years ago. We&#8217;re focused on what&#8217;s happened on our watch.&nbsp; And this truce has brought about one of the most peaceful periods since the terrible war began seven years ago, saving thousands of lives, and it&#8217;s the type of example of how our engagement is important.<br><br>And I mentioned the 70,000 Americans who live and work in Saudi Arabia under threat from missiles and drones, not to mention the energy security piece, which, of course, is a pressing issue and, of course, will be a topic of engagement during the summit.<br><br>So I think, Missy, it&#8217;s a fair question, and I think &#8212; but if you just look at the breadth and the totality of interests we have with the countries that the President will be engaging on this very important visit to the Middle East, I think it speaks for itself why he believes very strongly and has given the charge to all of us to do all we can to work with these countries, to encourage them to work together cooperatively using unique American attributes and enablers wherever we can, including diplomatic enablers, to try to forge a more stable region.<br><br>And that takes a lot of work, and it takes presidential engagement. And I think his engagement here over four days in July, with about a dozen leaders, we think there&#8217;s significant opportunity not only to deliver some immediate results, but to really set the foundation for a more integrated, more cooperative, more stable region down the line.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think the President&#8217;s engagement is essential to that &#8212; and I would just finish from where I began &#8212; as you saw in&nbsp;the ASEAN Summit, and his trip to Asia and the Quad Summit and Summit of the Americas, and now the trip to the Middle East for a very important summit with about a dozen leaders from across the region.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; To everyone, as a reminder, this call was on background attributable to a senior administration official.&nbsp; The embargo will be lifted at 8:00 a.m. tomorrow.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s it.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Have a good night.<br><br>8:25 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Philadelphia,&#160;PA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/14/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-philadelphia-pa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 14:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 9:00 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Hey, everybody.  Okay, so good morning.  Thanks for joining us to &#8212; sorry &#8212; thanks for joining us so bright and early.  I have one quick thing at the top. As you all know, today, at the &#8212; I’m going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>9:00 A.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  All right.  Hey, everybody.  Okay, so good morning.  Thanks for joining us to &#8212; sorry &#8212; thanks for joining us so bright and early.  I have one quick thing at the top.</p>



<p>As you all know, today, at the &#8212; I’m going to put this down so you guys can hear me.&nbsp; Today, at the 29th AFL-CIO Convention in Philadelphia, the President will contrast his economic vision that works &#8212; that works out from Scranton &#8212; that looks out from Scranton, with one that looks down from Wall Street.</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s economic vision builds the economy from the middle out and the bottom up, not top down.&nbsp; The President will outline the strength of the economy, including historically low &#8212; low unemployment rates as a result of his American Rescue Plan and bipartisan infrastructure law.&nbsp; And he will say there is more work to do, and tackle &#8212; and tackling inflation is his top priority.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;ll lay out the stark choice: Ask the wealthy to pay their fair share, as he is proposing, or put Medicare, Social Security, and Medicaid on the chopping block every five years, which is what congressional Republicans are proposing.</p>



<p>As you all know, traveling with us today are Representative Brendan Boyle, Mary Gay Scanlon, and Donald Norcross.&nbsp; And greeting the President on the ground will be Philadelphia Mayor Jim Kenney.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; With that, Darlene, you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, it doesn&#8217;t sound like there&#8217;s &#8212; from your topper, it doesn&#8217;t sound like there&#8217;s any news in the President&#8217;s speech today.&nbsp; Will there be any news in the remarks?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going &#8212; like I said, he&#8217;s going to make the stark contrast.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to talk about the work that he has been doing on behalf of the American people.</p>



<p>As we’ve said before, his priority as it relates to the economy is tackling inflation.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of him.&nbsp; I’ll let him &#8212; I’ll let him speak to what he&#8217;s going to be discussing today or in his remarks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In a statement earlier today announcing the trip to Saudi Arabia and Israel, the White House statement did not mention a meeting with MBS, whereas the Saudi statement did.&nbsp; Is there a reason the White House did not mention this?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, just for folks who are not aware, yes, a statement was put out &#8212; I put out a statement this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just for a little bit &#8212; to give you a little &#8212; folks a little bit of what the statement says.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to, clearly, read through the whole thing, but President Biden will visit the Middle East region from July 13th to 16th to reinforce the United States’ ironclad commitment to Israel&#8217;s security and prosperity and attend a Summit of the Gulf Cooperation Council plus Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan, known as the GCC+3.</p>



<p>He will also meet with counterparts from across the region to advance U.S. security, economic, and diplomatic interests.</p>



<p>The visit to the Middle East region culminates months of diplomacy and follows the President&#8217;s meeting with ASEAN leaders at the White House, his travel to the Republic of Korea and Japan, and the Quad Summit, his hosting of the Summit of the Americas last week in Los Angeles, and his visit next week to Europe for G7 and NATO.</p>



<p>But to your question, look, you know, the President is going to see over a dozen leaders on this trip, including King Salman and the leadership from our Saudi hosts for the GCC+3 Summit.&nbsp; Yes, we can expect the President to see the Crown Prince as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just a quick question on the S&amp;P yesterday slipping into bear market territory.&nbsp; I mean, there are growing fears of the economy heading into a recession.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering how concerned is the President about, sort of, growing fears of the U.S. economy slipping into a recession?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we are closely watching.&nbsp; We know that families are concerned about inflation in the stock market.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that we are aware of.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we know that this is &#8212; what we&#8217;re seeing right now is &#8212; what we&#8217;re facing are global challenges: Putin’s price hike, inflation, coming out of a once-in-a-generation global pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The American people are well positioned, we believe, to face these challenges because of the &#8212; because of &#8212; because of what the President has done this past year and a half on dealing with the economy &#8212; a historic, economic &#8212; economic place that we’re in with more than 8 million jobs since President Biden took office.&nbsp; Seventeen states have historical &#8212; historically low unemployment.</p>



<p>So, all of these things matter.&nbsp; But, yes, we are watching it closely, and we understand what this &#8212; how this feels for the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he having &#8212; is he having meetings, perhaps, you know, to discuss sort of this &#8212; this &#8212; the growing forecasts that are coming out of &#8212; you know, from economists about the economy?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any meetings to read out for you at this time.&nbsp; Clearly, this President has made inflation a priority &#8212; an economic priority.&nbsp; <a></a><a>You&#8217;ve heard from him for the past several months on it.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll hear from him about it today.&nbsp; So this is something that is at top of mind.</a></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The market drop has caused a tremendous loss of wealth.&nbsp; Is the President more concerned about the loss of wealth or the inflation?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we know that higher prices are having a real effect, again, on people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; And so that matters, and that is something that the President really is keen on.&nbsp; And we are incredibly focused on doing everything we can to making sure the economy is working for the American people.<br><br>You&#8217;ll hear him talk about that specifically today, as I read out in the topper.&nbsp; But, you know, the economic &#8212; again, his economic plan has led to the strongest job market in American history.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s &#8212; thanks to the American Rescue Plan, unemployment is at historic lows.<br><br>So, these are global challenges that we&#8217;re facing.&nbsp; We believe that we&#8217;re in a good place to fight inflation.&nbsp; We know what the American people are feeling.&nbsp; This is, again, an &#8212; a top economic priority for the President.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Saudi portion of the trips, I wanted to ask you about that, if I may.&nbsp; Is this a last-ditch effort, a Hail Mary attempt to lower oil and gas prices that we&#8217;re facing right now?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I mean, look, we&#8217;ve &#8212; I was asked this &#8212; a similar question yesterday &#8212;</p>



<p>(A nearby interior door opens.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Watch out behind you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.<br><br>So, look, while energy security is one important issue, it&#8217;s hardly the only one.&nbsp; Saudi Arabia is the chair of OPEC-Plus, as you all know, and it&#8217;s the largest exporter.&nbsp;<br><br>Of course, we discuss energy with Saudi &#8212; the Saudi government, and we welcome its &#8212; its leadership in achieving a consensus amongst the group of &#8212; to increase planned supply increases by 50 percent last week.<br><br>But, look, Saudi Arabia has been a strategic partner of the United States for nearly 80 years.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no question that important interests are interwoven with Saudi Arabia, notably the recent extension of truce in Yemen, which has saved countless of lives.<br><br>So, there is an array of agenda, a long list of things to talk &#8212; to &#8212; to have a conversation about that&#8217;s going to be on the agenda.<br><br>But as the President has said many times, he is &#8212; he looks forward to leader-leader conversation and &#8212; as it relates to having a strategic partnership.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, so when the President does see MBS on his trip, does he plan to address Khashoggi’s murder with him directly?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The President &#8212; as you know, human rights is always part of the conversation in our foreign &#8212; our foreign engagements.&nbsp; So that will always be the case.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t ma- &#8212; it does- &#8212; regardless of who he&#8217;s meeting with.<br><br>We are not &#8212; what we &#8212; I want to say: We&#8217;re not overlooking any conduct that happened before the President took office.&nbsp; We issued an extensive report on Khashoggi and issued a Kha- &#8212; the so-called Khashoggi Ban.<br><br>So it&#8217;s important to also emphasize that while we collab- &#8212; re-collaborate relationships, we are not looking to rupture relationships as well.<br><br>But human rights &#8212; you know, human rights issues, human rights conversation is something that the President brings up with many leaders and plans to do so.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, there was a report in Axios this morning that the President favors lifting tari- &#8212; Chinese &#8212; tariffs on China on consumer goods.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you can confirm if that&#8217;s true, but also talk about &#8212; I mean, he&#8217;s going to meet with unions today who have pretty steadfastly opposed lifting tariffs.&nbsp; Is he going to speak about tariffs and his decision-making process here with the members of the Union?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I’ll say this: We have said from the beginning some Trump tariffs were irresponsible and do not advance our economic or national security and instead raise costs for families and businesses.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve said many times that, you know, we&#8217;re discussing this and working to align these haphazard tariffs and our priorities to safeguard the interest of our workers and critical industries; boosting American workers, wages, and creating jobs; securing the resilience of our supply chains; sustaining our technology edge; and advancing our national security.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have anything to share about what &#8212; where the President &#8212; what the President&#8217;s decision has &#8212; is, at this time.&nbsp; As you know, this is something that we&#8217;re discussing internally.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick housekeeping note: We’ve had a couple incidences in gaggles, including under the wing today, where staff members have been touching camera equipment and microphones.&nbsp; So, I was just wondering if we can get a commitment for you to talk to people about how that can&#8217;t happen during that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean, absolutely.&nbsp; Look, we want to make sure that there&#8217;s transparency, that you are &#8212; you are &#8212; you all are able to hear the President, directly from the President.&nbsp; We know that&#8217;s important not just for you, but for us as well.<br><br>As the plane lands &#8212; I &#8212; I was not out &#8212; I was not outside when &#8212; to the &#8212; to what you&#8217;re discussing or bringing up right now.&nbsp; But we understand how important it is for all of you to hear directly from the President.&nbsp; So, thank you for letting us know.<br><br>All right, guys.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>9:10 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on President&#160;Biden’s Travel to Israel, the West Bank, and Saudi&#160;Arabia </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/14/statement-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-president-bidens-travel-to-israel-the-west-bank-and-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will visit&#160;the Middle East&#160;region from&#160;July 13-16&#160;to reinforce the United States’ iron-clad commitment to Israel’s security&#160;and prosperity and attend a Summit of the&#160;Gulf Cooperation Council plus Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan (known as the GCC+3). &#160;He will also meet with counterparts from across the region, to advance U.S. security, economic, and diplomatic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will visit&nbsp;the Middle East&nbsp;region from&nbsp;July 13-16&nbsp;to reinforce the United States’ iron-clad commitment to Israel’s security&nbsp;and prosperity and attend a Summit of the&nbsp;Gulf Cooperation Council plus Egypt, Iraq, and Jordan (known as the GCC+3). &nbsp;He will also meet with counterparts from across the region, to advance U.S. security, economic, and diplomatic interests.</p>



<p>The President will begin his travel in Israel, where he will meet with Israeli leaders to discuss Israel’s security, prosperity, and its increasing integration into the greater region. &nbsp;The President will also visit the West&nbsp;Bank to consult with the Palestinian Authority&nbsp;and to reiterate his strong support for a two-state solution,&nbsp;with&nbsp;equal measures of security, freedom, and opportunity for the Palestinian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President will then travel to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, which is the current chair of the GCC and the venue for this gathering of nine leaders from across the region, at the invitation of&nbsp;King Salman&nbsp;bin&nbsp;Abdulaziz&nbsp;al-Saud.&nbsp;The President appreciates King Salman’s leadership and his invitation.&nbsp; He looks forward to this important visit to Saudi Arabia, which has been a strategic partner of the United States for nearly eight decades. &nbsp;</p>



<p>While in Saudi Arabia, the President will&nbsp;discuss&nbsp;a range of bilateral, regional, and global issues.&nbsp; These include support to the&nbsp;UN-mediated truce&nbsp;in Yemen,&nbsp;which has led to the most peaceful period there since war began seven years ago.&nbsp; He will also discuss means for expanding regional economic and security cooperation, including new and promising infrastructure and climate initiatives, as well as deterring threats from Iran, advancing human rights,&nbsp;and&nbsp;ensuring global energy and food security.&nbsp;&nbsp;The President looks forward to outlining his affirmative vision for U.S. engagement in the region over the coming months and years. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This visit to the Middle East region culminates months of diplomacy and follows the President’s meeting with ASEAN leaders at the White House, his travel to the Republic of Korea and Japan, the Quad Summit, his hosting of the Summit of the Americas last week in Los Angeles, and his visit next week to Europe for the G7 and NATO Summits.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summit of the Americas Agriculture Producers&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/summit-of-americas-agriculture-producers-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 23:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Argentina, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and the United States affirm the important role that we as major agricultural and agricultural input exporters can play to strengthen global food security.&#160; At a time when nearly one in three people around the world does not have access to adequate, affordable, and nutritious food, supply disruptions further interrupt&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Argentina, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and the United States affirm the important role that we as major agricultural and agricultural input exporters can play to strengthen global food security.&nbsp; At a time when nearly one in three people around the world does not have access to adequate, affordable, and nutritious food, supply disruptions further interrupt trade in grain, corn, cooking oil, and key agricultural inputs such as seeds, fertilizer, and refined fuels.&nbsp; At the same time, climate change has intensified severe weather events and made them more frequent.&nbsp; The resulting change in precipitation patterns around the world threatens crop yields, making farming more challenging, especially as the world emerges from the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; High energy and fertilizer prices are an additional constraint, making agriculture more difficult to practice profitably and increasing world food prices for consumers, further exacerbating global food insecurity.</p>



<p>We, as major producers and exporters of food and other agricultural inputs affirm the need to take near-term actions with the goal of stabilizing food prices and sustainably maximizing agricultural yields. as well as building more resilient, safe, and sustainable global food systems for the future. We stand with the other over 80 countries that have endorsed the Roadmap for Global Food Security Call to Action released at the U.S.-chaired Global Food Security Ministerial Meeting held at the United Nations on May 18 and urge those countries that have not yet endorsed the Roadmap to do so.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>In order to meet these goals, the aforementioned countries affirm that they plan to:</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Promote best practices to boost crop yields, agricultural production, and trade:&nbsp; We intend to work with farmers around the world to take steps to improve sustainable crop yields and enhance sustainable agricultural production.&nbsp; All exporting countries benefit from the use of effective practices and approaches, including:&nbsp; the use of high-yield crops and resilient seeds; double-cropping; seasonal soil rotation; integrated management of pests and diseases; pesticide productivity; vertical farming; fertilizer innovations and efficiencies; better irrigation use and techniques to improve the water footprint; new and innovative practices and technologies to support sustainable agriculture; greater access to precision agriculture technology and innovative financial tools, such as agricultural credit and crop insurance to guaranteed affordable credit access; and innovative storage techniques to reduce post-harvest loss before crops are sold on the world markets. Over the long-term, we intend to increase efforts to support the transformation of unsustainable agriculture inputs and food systems to make them more sustainable, resilient to shocks, financially and socially inclusive, and accessible to large, medium and smallholder farmers without distinction, according to national capacities and priorities.&nbsp; Countries intend to strengthen both physical infrastructure and logistical supply chain supports, as well as build on existing innovations for food cultivation, storage, and distribution to increase access to affordable, nutritious, and healthy food.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Maximize food supplies and improve trade and transportation of food&nbsp;within world&nbsp;markets:&nbsp; A steady and predictable flow of diverse agricultural exports from major producing countries onto the global market can help maintain price stability, reduce shocks, and project calm over commodity markets.&nbsp; Conversely, panic about shortages and price spikes, hoarding and excessive stockpiling, and export bans can create a vicious cycle that contribute to global food insecurity.&nbsp; We intend to maintain or expand the fair and open trade of agricultural commodities, in line with existing domestic policies and international obligations and standards.&nbsp;&nbsp;We will work towards the objective of substantial progressive reductions in support, resulting in fundamental reform.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calibrate sanctions, where applicable, and work to avoid other restrictions, like export bans, to limit the impact on trade in agricultural commodities and avoid disrupting markets.&nbsp; We intend to ensure that our countries’ domestic sanctions regimes do not inappropriately target food and to take all appropriate actions to avoid export bans and other economic restrictions that could unduly interfere with the free flow of agricultural commodities around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Provide humanitarian assistance to the most vulnerable:&nbsp; Countries within available resources intend to make new, additive financial or in-kind donations to key humanitarian organizations providing immediate life-saving humanitarian assistance, including cash, food and nutrition supplies, health and nutrition programming, water and sanitation, and humanitarian protection to the most vulnerable populations &#8211; whether inside or outside of their borders &#8211; to prevent malnutrition or famine.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Support increased access to fertilizers and their inputs (synthetic and organic based), including through production inside countries, as a part of their efforts toward food security.&nbsp; Subject to available resources, we intend to increase fertilizer production including with a focus on the development of climate-smart and versatile alternatives, coupled with integrated soil management and fertilizer efficiency techniques, such as 4R fertilizer management, to prevent shortages.&nbsp; Use of these soil management techniques combined with alternative fertilizer choices is critical to optimize global supplies of fertilizer and reduce single-source fertilizer producer dependency, increasing competition among fertilizer producers will also help stabilize production costs in supply chains and increase crop yields to vulnerable food markets.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Optimize use of fertilizers, enhancing sustainability of water resources and biodiversity:&nbsp; We intend to promote innovative techniques, such as precision agriculture, that enable farmers to optimize the balance between fertilizer and water use per ton of food produced through crop, season, and alternative techniques.&nbsp; We also intend to promote the use of high-value and -yield crops and seeds to maximize renewable energy sources from non-food crops, feedstocks, formulations, uses, and crop data to better manage agricultural risks and shortages in advance of critical planting seasons, reduce soil erosion, and enhance sustainable biodiversity.</p>



<p>•&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Food insecurity is a rising global problem that does not respect international borders.&nbsp; It is also historically associated with poverty and social, economic, and political instability.&nbsp; As countries that serve as major food exporters and homes to farmers that feed the world, it is both in our interest and a core part of our values to take these steps to prevent hunger, malnutrition, and poverty around the world, as well as to make investments in more resilient and inclusive global agriculture and food systems, that support rural development and contribute to peace in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
