<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 01:25:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe Biden on Call with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/27/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-call-with-fema-administrator-deanne-criswell/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 01:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I spoke this afternoon with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell to hear firsthand about her visit today to Surfside, FL and the scene of the partial collapse of the Champlain Towers residential building. What I heard from Administrator Criswell was excruciating: she reiterated that words can’t describe the scene on the ground and she gave me an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I spoke this afternoon with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell to hear firsthand about her visit today to Surfside, FL and the scene of the partial collapse of the Champlain Towers residential building. What I heard from Administrator Criswell was excruciating: she reiterated that words can’t describe the scene on the ground and she gave me an update on meetings she had with state and local officials to ensure they have everything they need.<br><br>I am grateful for the heroic first responders, search and rescue teams, and all FEMA, state, county, local, and volunteer personnel who are working around the clock to try to save lives and for those who are dedicated to helping survivors with many needs, including temporary housing. We will continue to coordinate closely with officials on the ground throughout this terrible ordeal and my administration is ready to provide any support or assistance that is needed. <br><br>This is an unimaginably difficult time for the families enduring this tragedy. For those who are waiting in anguish for word of their loved ones as search and rescue efforts continue in the aftermath of this catastrophic incident, the pain of the uncertainty is an added, heartbreaking burden. My heart goes out to every single person suffering during this awful moment. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/26/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 20:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, I reached a historic agreement with a bipartisan group of Senators on a $1.2 trillion plan to transform our physical infrastructure. The plan would make the largest investment in infrastructure in history, the biggest investment in rail since the creation of Amtrak, and the largest investment in transit ever. It would fix roads and bridges,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, I reached a historic agreement with a bipartisan group of Senators on a $1.2 trillion plan to transform our physical infrastructure. The plan would make the largest investment in infrastructure in history, the biggest investment in rail since the creation of Amtrak, and the largest investment in transit ever. It would fix roads and bridges, make critical investments in our clean energy future, and help this country compete with China and other economic rivals. It would replace lead water pipes in our schools and houses, and connect every American to high-speed internet. It would create millions of high-paying jobs that could not be outsourced.<br><br>In the days since, the primary focus in Washington has not been about the Plan’s scope, scale or provisions—but rather, how it relates to other legislation before Congress: my American Families Plan. The American Families Plan—which would make historic investments in education, health care, child care, and tax cuts for families, coupled with other investments in care for our seniors, housing, and clean energy—has broad support with the American people, but not among Republicans in Congress.<br><br>I have been clear from the start that it was my hope that the infrastructure plan could be one that Democrats and Republicans would work on together, while I would seek to pass my Families Plan and other provisions through the process known as reconciliation. There has been no doubt or ambiguity about my intention to proceed this way.<br><br>At a press conference after announcing the bipartisan agreement, I indicated that I would refuse to sign the infrastructure bill if it was sent to me without my Families Plan and other priorities, including clean energy. That statement understandably upset some Republicans, who do not see the two plans as linked; they are hoping to defeat my Families Plan—and do not want their support for the infrastructure plan to be seen as aiding passage of the Families Plan. My comments also created the impression that I was issuing a veto threat on the very plan I had just agreed to, which was certainly not my intent.</p>



<p>So to be clear: our bipartisan agreement does not preclude Republicans from attempting to defeat my Families Plan; likewise, they should have no objections to my devoted efforts to pass that Families Plan and other proposals in tandem.&nbsp;We will let the American people—and the Congress—decide.</p>



<p>The bottom line is this:&nbsp;I gave my word to support the Infrastructure Plan, and that’s what I intend to do.&nbsp;I intend to pursue the passage of that plan, which Democrats and Republicans agreed to on Thursday, with vigor.&nbsp;It would be good for the economy, good for our country, good for our people.&nbsp;I fully stand behind it without reservation or hesitation.</p>



<p>Some other Democrats have said they might oppose the Infrastructure Plan because it omits items they think are important:&nbsp;that is a mistake, in my view.&nbsp;Some Republicans now say that they might oppose the infrastructure plan because I am also trying to pass the American Families Plan: that is also a mistake, in my view.&nbsp;I intend to work hard to get both of them passed, because our country needs both—and I ran a winning campaign for President that promised to deliver on both.&nbsp;No one should be surprised that that is precisely what I am doing.</p>



<p>I will ask Leader Schumer to schedule both the infrastructure plan and the reconciliation bill for action in the Senate. I expect both to go to the House, where I will work with Speaker Pelosi on the path forward after Senate action. Ultimately, I am confident that Congress will get both to my desk, so I can sign each bill promptly.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on International Day in Support of Victims of Torture </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/26/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-international-day-in-support-of-victims-of-torture/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, on the anniversary of the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment coming into effect, I reaffirm the United States’ unequivocal ban on torture and opposition to all forms of inhumane treatment. Torture goes against everything we stand for as a nation, and we must never again&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, on the anniversary of the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment coming into effect, I reaffirm the United States’ unequivocal ban on torture and opposition to all forms of inhumane treatment. Torture goes against everything we stand for as a nation, and we must never again resort to its use. The late-Senator John McCain, my friend and a torture survivor, put it best: “the use of torture compromises that which most distinguishes us from our enemies—our belief that all people, even captured enemies, possess basic human rights, which are protected by international conventions the U.S. not only joined, but for the most part authored.”<br> <br>Here are the facts. We know that torture is an ineffective method for gaining reliable intelligence. We know that it is prohibited universally, and violates U.S. and international law. We know that it spurs terrorist recruitment and violent extremism. And we know that it compromises our moral standing in the world.<br> <br>On this International Day in Support of Victims of Torture, we recognize the individuals and communities who endured the pain of torture, and I pledge the full efforts of the United States to eradicate torture in all its forms. As part of this effort, the United States has nominated a leading American legal expert to sit on the Committee Against Torture, which monitors implementation of the UN Convention, and I have requested the largest ever budget for the U.S. Survivors of Torture Program in HHS’s Office of Refugee Resettlement. The United States also remains the largest contributor to the UN Voluntary Fund for Victims of Torture to aid human rights defenders, refugees, migrants and other groups, and we urge other governments to join us in supporting this critical lifeline for torture survivors.<br> <br>Torture, wherever it occurs, is a stain on our moral conscience. We all must redouble our efforts to end such inhumane practice for good. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting with President Ghani and Chairman Abdullah of Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-with-president-ghani-and-chairman-abdullah-of-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 03:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met with President Ashraf Ghani and High Council for National Reconciliation Chairman Abdullah Abdullah of Afghanistan. President Biden emphasized enduring United States support for the Afghan people, including Afghan women, girls, and minorities, through civilian, development, and humanitarian aid, as well as the continued provision of security assistance to support Afghan National Defense and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met with President Ashraf Ghani and High Council for National Reconciliation Chairman Abdullah Abdullah of Afghanistan. President Biden emphasized enduring United States support for the Afghan people, including Afghan women, girls, and minorities, through civilian, development, and humanitarian aid, as well as the continued provision of security assistance to support Afghan National Defense and Security Forces. President Biden expressed his concern about the recent increase in COVID-19 cases in Afghanistan, and noted additional emergency U.S. assistance, including three million doses of vaccines, to help the Afghan government respond to the pandemic. President Biden, President Ghani, and Chairman Abdullah concurred on the need for unity among Afghan leaders in support of peace and stability, and President Biden reaffirmed the U.S. commitment to fully support intra-Afghan negotiations. The U.S. and Afghan leaders firmly agreed that although U.S. troops are leaving Afghanistan, the strong bilateral partnership will continue.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and President Mohammad Ashraf Ghani of the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan Before Bilateral Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/25/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-mohammad-ashraf-ghani-of-the-islamic-republic-of-afghanistan-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 4:15 P.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN: Well, it&#8217;s good to see two old friends. We met many, many times in Afghanistan for long hours. And they&#8217;re welcome here. They&#8217;ve had a chance to meet with the &#8212; all the major players of the administration &#8212; from the Secretary of Defense, to the CIA &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>4:15 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Well, it&#8217;s good to see two old friends. We met many, many times in Afghanistan for long hours. And they&#8217;re welcome here. They&#8217;ve had a chance to meet with the &#8212; all the major players of the administration &#8212; from the Secretary of Defense, to the CIA &#8212; across the board. And it&#8217;s good to have them here in the White House.</p>



<p>The partnership between Afghanistan and the United States is not ending. It&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be sustained. And, you know, our troops may be leaving, but support for Afghanistan is not ending, in terms of support and maintenance of their &#8212; helping maintain their military, as well as economic and political support.</p>



<p>And they’ve both got very difficult jobs. Every time I think I&#8217;ve got a tough job, I think, Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT GHANI: (Laughs.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: But, seriously, I &#8212; they’re doing important work of trying to bring about unity among Afghan leaders up &#8212; across the board.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and they have to &#8212; Afghans are going to have to decide their future of what they &#8212; what they want. What they want. But it won&#8217;t be for lack of us being a help. There’s going to be a &#8212; and the senseless violence that has to stop, but it&#8217;s going to be very difficult.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re going to stick with you. And we&#8217;re going to do our best to see to it you have the tools you need.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT GHANI: Well, thank you, Mr. President. First of all, let me pay tribute to the 2,448 Americans who paid the ultimate sacrifice, over a million American veterans who have served with honor and dignity for your security and our freedom.</p>



<p>The United States has not spared any effort in blood or treasure during these years. And as a grateful nation, I want to acknowledge that and ask you &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT GHANI: &#8212; to thank the Gold Star families.</p>



<p>Second, President Biden&#8217;s decision has been historic. It has made everybody recalculate and reconsider. We are here to respect it and support it.</p>



<p>Third, we are entering into a new chapter of our relationship where the partnership with the United States would not be military, but comprehensive, regarding our mutual interest. And we&#8217;re very encouraged and satisfied that this partnership is taking place. Thank you for ordering the priorities.</p>



<p>The Afghan nation is in 1861 moment, like President Lincoln, rallying to the defense of the republic, determined that the republic is defended. It&#8217;s a choice of values &#8212; the values of an exclusionary system or an inclusionary system.</p>



<p>We’re determined to have unity, coherence, national sense of sacrifice, and will not spare anything.</p>



<p>Just for your information: Today, the Afghan Defense and Security Forces have retaken six districts, both in the south and the north. It&#8217;s showing our determination. So I hope that nobody does the Bernard Shaw on us &#8212; exaggerating our death before something has happened.</p>



<p>Let us understand that in moments of great transition, things happen. But you will see that with determination, with unity, and with the partnership, we will overcome all odds. Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Thank you. Thank you all. Appreciate it. Thank you.</p>



<p>Q Mr. President, do you have any reaction to Derek Chauvin being sentenced to twenty-two and a half years in prison?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: I&#8217;ve not been able to hear anything about what’s happened. How long has he been sentenced?</p>



<p>Q Twenty-two and a half years.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Well, I &#8212; I don&#8217;t know all the circumstances that were considered, but it seems to me &#8212; under the guidelines &#8212; that seems to be appropriate.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>4:20 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Commemorating LGBTQ+ Pride Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/25/remarks-by-president-biden-commemorating-lgbtq-pride-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:39 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, my name is Joe Biden.&#160; I’m Jill Biden’s husband.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Ashton, thank you.&#160; You seemed awfully comfortable up here.&#160; (Laughter and applause.)&#160; You were awfully comfortable up here.&#160; I don’t know.&#160; I &#8212; I’m not sure I’ll be around, but, you know &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; if you’re&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>2:39 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, my name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; I’m Jill Biden’s husband.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Ashton, thank you.&nbsp; You seemed awfully comfortable up here.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; You were awfully comfortable up here.&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp; I &#8212; I’m not sure I’ll be around, but, you know &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; if you’re here, just don’t pretend you don’t know me.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Your story, your leadership, and your mom is an inspiration.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Your mom.&nbsp; If my mother were here, she’d look at you and say, “Honey, God love you, dear.”&nbsp; God love you &#8212; what you do, what you did, what you continue to do.</p>



<p>I want to thank Secretary &#8212; well, first of all, I want to say to Chasten: Belated happy birthday, Chasten. (Applause.) &nbsp;If you could hear us inside, we were singing happy birthday to him. &nbsp;We got a bunch of cupcakes, but not enough for everybody. &nbsp;(Laughter.) &nbsp;But &#8212; and, Mr. Secretary, thank you. &nbsp;You are &#8212; you&#8217;re the best, man.<br><br>Look, our presence here this afternoon makes a simple, strong statement: Pride is back at the White House.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>For this community and for our nation and for the world, Pride Month represents so much.&nbsp; It stands for courage &#8212; the courage of all those in previous generations and today who proudly live their truth.&nbsp;<br><br>It stands for justice: both the steps we’ve taken and the steps we need to take.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And above all, Pride Month stands for love &#8212; you know, being able to love yourself, love whomever you love, and love this country enough to make it more fair and more free and more just.</p>



<p>You know, during the campaign, Tim Gill and Scott Miller &#8212; and Tim &#8212; one of them is here today, I don’t want to embarrass him; he always gets mad when I do that &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; brought me and Jill to visit the Stonewall Inn. &nbsp;I wanted to go, and they wanted &#8212; they offered to take me. &nbsp;We wanted to pay tribute to that hallowed ground that represents the the fight to ensure that all people are treated with dignity and respect.<br><br>Just a few minutes ago, surrounded by the survivors of family members who were &#8212; we’ve lost, I signed a bill consecrating another piece of hallowed ground: the Pulse nightclub.&nbsp; And I want to thank all of the members of the United States House of Representatives and the United States Senate for standing up and making sure that will never be forgotten.&nbsp; Never be forgotten.&nbsp; The site of the deadliest attack affecting the LBT- &#8212; LGBTQ+ community in American history.&nbsp; It’s now a national memorial.&nbsp;<br><br>This month, on the way to the office, I walk through &#8212; from my &#8212; from the Residence to the Oval Office every morning &#8212; I walk through a hallway lit with rainbow colors of Pride, which you&#8217;ll have a chance to see in just a few minutes.&nbsp; You’ll see a candle carried during the AIDS vigil in the early &#8217;90s by a pair &#8212; and a pair of sandals belonging to Matthew Shepard.&nbsp;<br><br>They&#8217;re reminders of how much this community has suffered and lost.&nbsp; But they&#8217;re also reminders of this community’s incredible resiliency, the incredible contributions, the incred- &#8212; including, we just saw, the National Football League and the National Women’s Soccer League.&nbsp;<br><br>All of you here &#8212; Henry Muñoz and Kyle &#8212; good to see you, man &#8212; (laughter).&nbsp;&nbsp;I had the &#8212; I had the opportunity to officiate at their wedding.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughter and applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And Representative Malcolm Kenyatta &#8212; where are you, Malcolm?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;You&#8217;re around here some &#8212; (applause) &#8212; good to see you, man.&nbsp;&nbsp;And Dr. Matt Miller &#8212; they stole the show at the Democratic Convention.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>And my friend, Sarah McBride &#8212; where is Sarah?&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Sarah?&nbsp;&nbsp;Sarah worked closely with my son, Beau, when he was Attorney General of the State of Delaware; and is now serving Delaware, as well, as one of the first openly transgender state legislators in history.&nbsp;&nbsp;Senator.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>You just heard from our history-making Secretary of Transportation.&nbsp;<br><br>And we have today the first openly transgender person ever confirmed to the U.S. Senate &#8212; you just met her &#8212; Dr. Levine.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Representation matters.&nbsp; Recognition matters.&nbsp; But there’s something else that matters: Results.&nbsp; Results.<br><br>I am proud to lead the most pro-LGBTQ equality administration in U.S. history.&nbsp; And even on the very &#8212; my very first day in office, the first executive order I signed was to change the whole of the federal government to commit to work aggressively to root out discrimination against LBT- &#8212; LGBTQ+ people and their families.&nbsp; That was the first executive order.<br><br>I ordered our agencies &#8212; every agency &#8212; to rapidly implement the Supreme Court’s ruling in Bostock, which affirmed that civil rights protections on the basis of sex apply to sexual orientation and gender identity.&nbsp;<br><br>And as a result of that executive order, the Department of Housing and Urban <s>Affairs </s>[Development] announced that it would be &#8212; take steps to protect LGBTQ+ people from discrimination in housing, and ensured critical protections for transgender Americans experiencing homelessness.<br><br>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau announced it would work to combat discrimination against LGBTQ+ people in credit and lending.&nbsp; The Department of Health and Human Services announced it would protect against discrimination in healthcare services.&nbsp;<br><br>And just last week, the Department of Education made clear that Title IX protections apply to sexual orientation and gender identity &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and prohibit discrimination against LGBTQ students in our nation’s schools.<br><br>And a moment ago, I signed an executive order to advance diversity, equality, and inclusion, and accessibility across the entire federal workforce.&nbsp;&nbsp;The order directs the entire federal government to eliminate barriers so people from every background and walk of life have an equal opportunity to serve our nation, including LGBTQ+ folks and all employees in underserved communities.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, I also was proud to rescind the discriminatory and un-American ban on openly transgender servicemembers.&nbsp;&nbsp;Today, we’re joined by Lieutenant Colonel Bree Fram.&nbsp;&nbsp;Bree, Colonel &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;One of the highest-ranking openly transgender servicemembers in the United States Military.&nbsp;&nbsp;Lieutenant Colonel Fram, thank you for your service to our nation.&nbsp;&nbsp;We owe you.&nbsp;&nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)<br><br>And everyone who has served &#8212; everyone deserves the absolute high quality of healthcare.&nbsp; That’s why I was so pleased that, last week, Secretary McDonough announced the Department of Veterans Affairs is beginning the process to provide more comprehensive gender-affirming care to our nation’s transgen- &#8212; for our nation’s transgender veterans.<br><br>We’re also making equality the centerpiece of our diplomacy around the world.&nbsp; We believe LGBTQ+ rights are human rights.&nbsp;<br><br>In February, I signed a presidential memorandum establishing that it’s the policy of the United States to pursue an end to violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity.&nbsp;<br><br>This month, Pride flags are flying &#8212; as some of my friends in our last admin- &#8212; in the Obama-Biden administration who are openly gay &#8212; they are flying in more than &#8212; over 130 U.S. embassies around the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; A powerful &#8212; a powerful symbol of our commitment to safety, dignity, and opportunity for all.&nbsp;<br><br>And today, I&#8217;m proud to announce that Jessica Stern, who many of you know as an LGBT special &#8212; -Q+ special envoy at the State Department.&nbsp;<br><br>And yes, we&#8217;re also making progress, but I know we still have a long way to go, a lot of work to do. &nbsp;But we must protect the gains we&#8217;ve made and fend off the cruel and unconscionable attacks we&#8217;re seeing now to ensure that everyone enjoys the full promise of equality and dignity and protection. &nbsp;<br><br>When I was Vice President, I was proud &#8212; although, some &#8212; it won&#8217;t surprise some people in the administration at the moment &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and, by the way, I did tell the President that I would not go out and proselytize, but if I was asked, I would not remain quiet.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; The President &#8212; I was proud to have called for marriage equality, along with Barack Obama, because, at the time, I said, &#8220;Love is love, period.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>Six year ago, tomorrow, when the Supreme Court ruled in favor of marriage equality, we&#8217;re all reminded of the White House lit up in rainbow colors. &nbsp;Shortly thereafter, I went to New York to celebrate with my friend Evan Wolfson and a team from &#8212; at Freedom to Marry. &nbsp;The joy was palpable.<br><br>But we knew then, as we know now, that our work is unfinished.&nbsp;&nbsp; When a same-sex couple can be married in the morning but denied a lease in the afternoon for being gay, something is still wrong.&nbsp;<br><br>Over half of our states &#8212; in over half of our states, LGBTQ+ Americans still lack explicit state-level civil rights protections to shield them from discrimination.&nbsp;<br><br>As I said as a presidential candidate and in my first joint address to Congress, it’s time for the United States Senate to pass the Equality Act and put the legislation on my desk.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Put it on my desk.&nbsp;<br><br>Harvey Milk was right when he said, quote, “It takes no compromise to give people their rights.”&nbsp; It takes no compromise to give people their rights.&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, this bill doesn’t just protect LGBTQ+ people.&nbsp; It’s also going to strengthen existing civil rights protections for people of faith, people of color, people with disabilities, women &#8212; in public accommodations, like doctors’ offices, parks, and gyms.<br><br>I want to thank the leaders of the Congressional Equity [Equality] Caucus for their continued work to make it happen.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The Equality Act will also help protect against the disturbing proliferation of anti-LGBTQ bills we’re seeing in state legislatures.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So far this year, hundreds of anti-LGBTQ bills have been introduced in state legislatures.&nbsp; More than a dozen of them have already passed &#8212; more than a dozen of them.&nbsp; These are some of the ugliest, most un-American laws I’ve seen, and I&#8217;ve been here awhile.&nbsp; Many of them target transgender children, seeking to prevent them from receiving the appropriate medical care; for using the bathroom at high schools while they&#8217;re &#8212; the one where they&#8217;ll be most safe; even preventing them from joining sports teams with their classmates.<br><br>Let’s be clear: This is nothing more than bullying disguised as legislation.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As I’ve said before, many times, transgender kids are some of the bravest people in the world.&nbsp; I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; You just saw it with Ashton, and you&#8217;ll see it with several other young people here.&nbsp; It takes courage to be true to your authentic self and to face &#8212; in the face of the &#8212; these kinds of discrimination you know exist.&nbsp; It takes a toll.&nbsp;<br><br>We know more than half of transgender youth seriously considered suicide just in the past year.&nbsp; These young people aren’t hurting anyone, but these laws are hurting them.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve got to stop.&nbsp;<br><br>Our deceased son, Beau &#8212; when he was Delaware’s Attorney General &#8212; was one of the first AGs in the country to call for legislation to establish legal protections on the basis of gender identity to protect &#8212; to protect trans people &#8212; trans people.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>And now, the Department of Justice has filed statements of interest in cases challenging two of these &#8212; those bills that got passed &#8212; explaining why they&#8217;re so unconstitutional.<br><br>So, we have to work.&nbsp; We have to work to do so much in these areas to support seniors, aging in isolation without support; to confront disproportionate levels of homelessness and poverty and unemployment in the LGBTQ community; to address the &#8212; the epidemic level of violence against transgender people, especially transgender women &#8212; it&#8217;s been mentioned before &#8212; women of color &#8212; in the coming days, my administration is going to have more to say about that; and to finally eradicate the AIDS epidemic.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m allowed to talk about this &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but our son, Beau, who was a decorated war veteran and attorney general of the United &#8212; of the state of Delaware and should be standing here instead of me, came home from war after a year in Iraq and, before that, six months in Kosovo.&nbsp; And what he did &#8212; he decided he was going to set up a foundation for LGBTQ youth, but primarily focusing on transgender youth.&nbsp;<br><br>And he took all the money left from the campaign &#8212; he was going to run for governor &#8212; and put it in and a lot more.&nbsp; Because in his working with everyone from YMCAs to all the &#8212; all the &#8212; all the areas where young people can find some solace &#8212; his buddy Chris Coons and my buddy Senator Coons knows what he&#8217;s done.&nbsp;<br><br>The point is: A lot of transgender youth &#8212; those who commit suicide &#8212; based on the studies his foundation has done, do it because their mom doesn&#8217;t understand, because mom or dad says, &#8220;You can&#8217;t be here anymore&#8221; &#8212; are rejected.&nbsp;<br><br>So, folks, we got a lot of work to do.&nbsp; A lot of it&#8217;s basically public education.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me close with this: When you go downstairs, you&#8217;ll see some of the Smithsonian exhibit.&nbsp; You get a sense of the long, long journey &#8212; and how long it&#8217;s been, and how far we’ve come &#8212; have you come.&nbsp; But how much further we have to go.<br><br>So, this afternoon, we celebrate.&nbsp; But tomorrow, we go back to work.&nbsp; Progress won’t come easily; it never has.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to stand strong, stand together.&nbsp; And I promise you, we will succeed.&nbsp; I promise you.&nbsp;<br><br>I said to folks earlier, you know things are &#8212; why &#8212; why &#8212; I always get asked by the press, &#8220;Why are you so optimistic, Biden?&#8221;&nbsp; Well, as my neurosurgeon once said, I&#8217;m probably a congenital optimist.&nbsp; But beyond that &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; it&#8217;s a simple proposition.&nbsp;<br><br>Look at the young people: straight and gay, doesn&#8217;t matter.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the least prejudiced &#8212; this generation &#8212; the most open, the most giving, and the best educated generation in history.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; In all of history.&nbsp;<br><br>And look where they are.&nbsp; Look how it&#8217;s changing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s changing in ways that &#8212; in my generation, 270 years ago &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; you&#8217;d get beat up for defending somebody.&nbsp;<br><br>But really and truly, there&#8217;s a great reason for hope.&nbsp; And so much talent &#8212; so much talent can be unleashed by embracing the LGBT+ community &#8212; -Q+ community.&nbsp;<br><br>So I want to thank you and say: Happy Pride.&nbsp;<br><br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>2:58 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Six Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/president-biden-announces-six-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following six individuals to serve in key roles: Lisa Carty, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America on the Economic and Social Council of the United Nations with the rank of Ambassador and Alternate Representative to the United Nations General Assembly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following six individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Lisa Carty, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America on the Economic and Social Council of the United Nations with the rank of Ambassador and Alternate Representative to the United Nations General Assembly</li><li>Ernest DuBester, Nominee for Chair of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</li><li>Dennis DeConcini, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</li><li>Joseph Green, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</li><li>Barbara George Johnson, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</li><li>Mildred Otero, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Lisa Carty, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America on the Economic and Social Council of the United Nations with the rank of Ambassador and Alternate Representative to the United Nations General Assembly</span></strong><br>Lisa A. Carty is Director for Humanitarian Financing and Resource Mobilization with the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs.  She has worked for more than three decades in multilateral diplomacy, including on humanitarian, global health and development issues.  Carty has had leadership roles in both the public and non-profit sectors including twenty-five years as a diplomat with the U.S. Foreign Service with overseas assignments in Asia, the Middle East and Russia.  Her United Nations career has included work with the United Nations Relief Works Agency for Palestinian Refugees, as well as positions with the Joint United Nations Program on AIDS. <br><br>Earlier in her career, Ms. Carty helped lead the work of the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation’s Global Health Program and was a senior adviser at the Center for Strategic and International Studies in Washington, DC.   She holds a Master’s degree in Public Health from Johns Hopkins University and a Bachelor’s degree from Georgetown University’s School of Foreign Service.  She speaks French.  <br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Ernest DuBester, Nominee for Chair of the Federal Labor Relations Authority</span></strong><br>Mr. DuBester has served as a Member of the Federal Labor Relations Authority (FLRA) since August 2009. On January 21, 2021, he was designated Chairman by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr.  He was also FLRA Chairman from January to November 2013.  The FLRA administers the Labor-Management relations program for 2.1 million non-Postal federal employees worldwide.<br><br>With over 45 years of experience in Labor-Management relations, he began his career at the National Labor Relations Board as counsel to former Chairman and Member John Fanning.  He was also a Union attorney with the firm of Highsaw &amp; Mahoney, and legislative counsel to the AFL-CIO.  From 1993-2001, he was Chairman and Member at the National Mediation Board (NMB), which oversees labor relations in the airline and railroad industries. From 2001-2005, Mr. DuBester was the Professor and Director of the Dispute Resolution Program at the Antonin Scalia Law School.  Mr. DuBester received his A.B. from Boston College, his law degree from Catholic University, where he served as Recent Developments Editor of the Law Review, and his Masters of Law in Labor Law from Georgetown University Law Center.  He is married to Karen Marie Kremer.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Dennis DeConcini, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</span></strong><br>Dennis DeConcini is a native of Tucson, Arizona and served as a United States Senator from Arizona for 18 years, from 1977-1995, serving with both Senators Barry Goldwater and John McCain. During that time he was a member of the Committees on Appropriations, Judiciary, Veterans’ Aﬀairs, Rules, and served as Chairman of the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence.On the Intelligence Committee he was involved in the restructuring of the Post-War Intelligence community, reviewed security systems following the Aldrich Ames espionage case, and conducted general oversight of all technical and human intelligence gathering. DeConcini was also Co-Chair of the Commission on Cooperation and Security in Europe (Helsinki Commission) where he was involved in a vast number of Human Rights Matters and oversight of the Helsinki Accord.  This included the monitoring of human rights violations in Eastern Europe and the former USSR by meeting with heads of State and traveling extensively in those countries and observing elections in newly emerging democracies. Prior to his service in the United States Senate, he was elected Pima County Attorney (Tucson, Arizona) where he created one of the ﬁrst victim-witness programs in the country, which is still operational. <br><br>After retirement from the U.S. Senate, he continued to serve the public as a member of the Arizona Board of Regents, which governs the three main universities in Arizona, for eight years.  As a Regent, he was responsible for overseeing the operations of the universities to enhance the educational experience and opportunities for the student community.  He is a member of the Board of the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children and the International Center for Missing and Exploited Children where he continues to support the mission of ﬁnding and preventing the exploitation of children. DeConcini received his Bachelor of Arts Degree and Law Degree from the University of Arizona. DeConcini is currently retired and serves as a general partner of his family real estate business, 4-D Properties, in Tucson, Arizona.  He is the author of the book, From the Center of the Aisle, published by Arizona University Press, 2006. Dennis DeConcini is married to Patricia DeConcini, and has three grown children and seven grandchildren. He continues to be active in the public policy arena.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Joseph Green, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</span></strong><br>Joseph Michael “Joe” Green, Ph.D., currently works as the Dean of the University College at North Carolina Central University, where he works with other campus deans to ensure a quality undergraduate student experience. Dean Green’s primary role is to lead University College faculty and staff to develop, implement, assess and continuously improve the University College, courses, workshops, services, and projects.<br><br>Dr. Green previously worked as the Executive Director for Retention, Progression, and Completion, a Graduate Faculty Member, and head of the Student Success Center in the Division of Academic Affairs, at the University of North Carolina at Greensboro (UNCG) a major minority serving University. Dr. Green has been a leader and Conductor for UNCG’s Frontier Set Initiative, a partnership of 31 public and private colleges, Universities, community colleges and university systems created by the Bill &amp; Melina Gates Foundation to help colleges increase the number of graduates among under-represented, first-generation, low-income and non-traditional students.<br>Prior to arriving at UNCG, Joe served as the Executive Director for the nationally recognized Educational Opportunity Program (EOP) at Marquette University in Milwaukee, Wisconsin. Additionally, Dr. Green conceptualized, and executive produced the documentary film “Answering the Call for Justice”, a film which chronicles the early TRiO College Equity, Opportunity, and Access Movement in the United States. Over the past two and a half decades, Dr. Green was director of four federal TRiO programs and academic support centers.<br><br>Before his time at North Carolina, Dr. Green was Director of Undergraduate Research, the Ronald E. McNair Program and the Research and Mentoring Program (RAMP) Scholars Post-Baccalaureate Achievement Program in the University of Central Florida’s Division of Undergraduate Studies. He was elected to the Chapel Hill-Carrboro City Schools Board of Education and served as a member of the State of North Carolina’s Department of Public Instructions, Advanced Placement Advisory Council.<br><br>Dr. Green earned his undergraduate degree from Bowie State University, Bowie, Maryland and holds a doctoral degree in political science and public administration from Howard University in Washington. Joe is a member of Phi Beta Sigma Fraternity, and he and his wife, Kimberly and family now reside in Mebane, North Carolina.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Barbara George Johnson, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</span></strong><br>Barbara George Johnson brings more than 30 years of experience as a public policy professional in New Jersey and has been a leading voice in shaping economic, health and social policy in the region. Barbara is the Vice President of External Affairs and Urban Policy and Research at Kean University, where she brings her years of public policy analysis expertise to the newly launched John S. Watson Institute for Urban Policy and Research.<br><br>Previously, Barbara held the title of Executive Director for the John S. Watson Institute for Public Policy (JSWIPP) at Thomas Edison State University where she managed the activities of the New Jersey Urban Mayors Association, the only Association of its kind with over 30 urban mayors engaged in collective policymaking. Barbara also created the Newark Kids Initiative project for the Newark Health Department, a program that focused on healthcare and social services for children exposed to domestic violence. In addition, she has participated in many task forces on HIV/AIDS including the Newark Prevention Marketing Initiative which was a task force created by the Centers for Disease Control to address the increase of HIV/AIDS in Newark.  Barbara also served as principal of GOVCONNECTIONS, LLC,  a company she created to provide government relations, community relations and health care consulting services to urban communities. <br><br>Barbara has spent many years working in health care where she concentrated on Maternal and Child Health issues, as a Public Health Adviser for the Department of Health and New York City and later as the Director for the Family Life Institute of Planned Parenthood of Metropolitan New Jersey. She also served as Legislative Director for the American Civil Liberties Union of New Jersey.<br><br>Barbara earned a Bachelor of Arts in Biology and Technology from Cornell University and an MPH from Columbia University School of Public Health, as well as a Law degree from Rutgers-Newark Law School. A proud member of the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority Inc., she resides in Hillside, New Jersey with her husband and children.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Mildred Otero, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation</span></strong><br>Mildred Otero is the Senior Vice President for National Impact at Leadership for Educational Equity (LEE). In this role, she leads four national teams committed to developing the leadership skills of LEE members to pursue leadership opportunities in advocacy, elected, organizing and policy that empower them to end educational inequities in the United States. Prior to joining LEE, Mildred served as the Chief Education Counsel in the U.S. Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions, where she managed the Senate Majority’s education agenda and its policy development and strategies for children from cradle to career. Such efforts included, legislation addressing early childhood education, elementary and secondary and the workforce.  <br><br>Previously, Mildred served as a senior policy officer with the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation; senior advisor at the United States Department of State/United States Agency for International Development; senior policy advisor to then Senator Clinton (D-NY); Legislative Assistant to Sen. Reed (D-RI) in the US Senate and as Deputy Director for Early Childhood at the Children’s Defense Fund. Before her work in Washington, D.C., Mildred was a counselor for child victims of sexual and physical abuse at the Brooklyn District Attorney’s Office and began her career as a legislative aide to the New York State Assembly Speaker in Albany, NY.  <br><br>Mildred earned a Bachelor of Arts degree from the State University of New York- Albany and a Master’s degree from New York University, Silver School of Social Work. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility in the Federal Workforce</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/25/executive-order-on-diversity-equity-inclusion-and-accessibility-in-the-federal-workforce/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22147</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including sections 1104, 3301, and 3302 of title 5, United&#160;States Code, and in order to strengthen the Federal workforce by promoting diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, it is hereby ordered as follows: Section 1. &#160;Policy.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including sections 1104, 3301, and 3302 of title 5, United&nbsp;States Code, and in order to strengthen the Federal workforce by promoting diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Policy.&nbsp; On my first day in office, I signed Executive Order 13985 (Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government), which established that affirmatively advancing equity, civil rights, racial justice, and equal opportunity is the responsibility of the whole of our Government. &nbsp;To further advance equity within the Federal Government, this order establishes that it is the policy of my Administration to cultivate a workforce that draws from the full diversity of the Nation.</p>



<p>As the Nation&#8217;s largest employer, the Federal Government must be a model for diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, where all employees are treated with dignity and respect. &nbsp;Accordingly, the Federal Government must strengthen its ability to recruit, hire, develop, promote, and retain our Nation&#8217;s talent and remove barriers to equal opportunity. &nbsp;It must also provide resources and opportunities to strengthen and advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility across the Federal Government. &nbsp;The Federal Government should have a&nbsp;workforce that reflects the diversity of the American people. &nbsp;A growing body of evidence demonstrates that diverse, equitable, inclusive, and accessible workplaces yield higher-performing organizations.</p>



<p>Federal merit system principles include that the Federal Government&#8217;s recruitment policies should &#8220;endeavor to achieve a&nbsp;work force from all segments of society&#8221; and that &#8220;[a]ll employees and applicants for employment should receive fair and&nbsp;equitable treatment in all aspects of personnel management&#8221; (5 U.S.C. 2301(b)(1), (2)). &nbsp;As set forth in Executive Order&nbsp;13583 of August 18, 2011 (Establishing a Coordinated Government-Wide Initiative to Promote Diversity and Inclusion in&nbsp;the Federal Workforce), the Presidential Memorandum of October 5, 2016 (Promoting Diversity and Inclusion in the National Security Workforce), Executive Order 13988 of January&nbsp;20, 2021 (Preventing and Combating Discrimination on the&nbsp;Basis of Gender Identity or Sexual Orientation), the National Security Memorandum of February 4, 2021 (Revitalizing America&#8217;s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships), and Executive Order 14020 of March 8, 2021 (Establishment of the White House Gender Policy Council), the Federal Government is at its best when drawing upon all parts of society, our greatest accomplishments are achieved when diverse perspectives are brought to bear to overcome our greatest challenges, and all persons should receive equal treatment under the law.&nbsp; This order reaffirms support for, and builds upon, the procedures established by Executive Orders 13583, 13988, and 14020, the Presidential Memorandum on Promoting Diversity and Inclusion in the National Security Workforce, and the National Security Memorandum on Revitalizing America&#8217;s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships. &nbsp;This order establishes that diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility are priorities for my Administration and benefit the entire Federal Government and the Nation, and establishes additional procedures to advance these priorities across the Federal workforce.</p>



<p>Sec. 2. Definitions. For purposes of this order, in the context of the Federal workforce: &nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The term &#8220;underserved communities&#8221; refers to populations sharing a particular characteristic, as well as geographic communities, who have been systematically denied a full opportunity to participate in aspects of economic, social, and civic life. In the context of the Federal workforce, this term includes individuals who belong to communities of color, such as Black and African American, Hispanic and Latino, Native American, Alaska Native and Indigenous, Asian American, Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander, Middle Eastern, and North African persons. It also includes individuals who belong to communities that face discrimination based on sex, sexual orientation, and gender identity (including lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, gender non-conforming, and non-binary (LGBTQ+) persons); persons who face discrimination based on pregnancy or pregnancy-related conditions; parents; and caregivers. &nbsp;It also includes individuals who belong to communities that face discrimination based on their religion or disability; first-generation professionals or first-generation college students; individuals with limited English proficiency; immigrants; individuals who belong to communities that may face employment barriers based on older age or former incarceration; persons who live in rural areas; veterans and military spouses; and persons otherwise adversely affected by persistent poverty, discrimination, or inequality. Individuals may belong to more than one underserved community and face intersecting barriers.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The term &#8220;diversity&#8221; means the practice of including the many communities, identities, races, ethnicities, backgrounds, abilities, cultures, and beliefs of the American people, including underserved communities.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;The term &#8220;equity&#8221; means the consistent and systematic fair, just, and impartial treatment of all individuals, including individuals who belong to underserved communities that&nbsp;have been denied such treatment.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;The term &#8220;inclusion&#8221; means the recognition, appreciation, and use of the talents and skills of employees of&nbsp;all backgrounds.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;The term &#8220;accessibility&#8221; means the design, construction, development, and maintenance of facilities, information and communication technology, programs, and services so that all people, including people with disabilities, can fully and independently use them.&nbsp; Accessibility includes the provision of accommodations and modifications to ensure equal access to employment and participation in activities for people with disabilities, the reduction or elimination of physical and attitudinal barriers to equitable opportunities, a commitment to ensuring that people with disabilities can independently access every outward-facing and internal activity or electronic space, and the pursuit of best practices such as universal design.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;The term &#8220;agency&#8221; means any authority of the United&nbsp;States that is an &#8220;agency&#8221; under 44 U.S.C. 3502(1), other&nbsp;than one considered to be an independent regulatory agency, as defined in 44 U.S.C. 3502(5).</p>



<p>Sec. 3. &nbsp;Government-Wide Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and&nbsp;Accessibility Initiative and Strategic Plan. &nbsp;The Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) and the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) &#8212; in coordination with the Chair of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) and in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs, the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy (APDP), the Director of the National Economic Council, and the Co-Chairs of the Gender Policy Council &#8212; shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) reestablish a coordinated Government-wide initiative to promote diversity and inclusion in the Federal workforce, expand its scope to specifically include equity and accessibility, and coordinate its implementation with the provisions of Executive Order 13985 and the National Security Memorandum on Revitalizing America&#8217;s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;develop and issue a Government-wide Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility Strategic Plan (Government-wide DEIA Plan) within 150 days of the date of this order that updates the Government-wide plan required by section 2(b)(i) of Executive Order 13583. &nbsp;The Government-wide DEIA Plan shall be updated as appropriate and at a minimum every 4 years. &nbsp;The Government-wide DEIA Plan shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;define standards of success for diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility efforts based on&nbsp;leading policies and practices in the public and private sectors;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;consistent with merit system principles, identify strategies to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility, and eliminate, where applicable, barriers to equity, in Federal workforce functions, including: &nbsp;recruitment; hiring; background investigation; promotion; retention; performance evaluations and awards; professional development programs; mentoring programs or sponsorship initiatives; internship, fellowship, and apprenticeship programs; employee resource group and&nbsp;affinity group programs; temporary employee details and assignments; pay and compensation policies; benefits, including health benefits, retirement benefits, and employee services and work‑life programs; disciplinary or adverse actions; reasonable accommodations for employees and applicants with disabilities; workplace policies to prevent gender-based violence (including domestic violence, stalking, and sexual violence); reasonable accommodations for employees who are members of religious minorities; and training, learning, and onboarding programs;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;include a comprehensive framework to address workplace harassment, including sexual harassment, which clearly defines the term &#8220;harassment&#8221;; outlines policies and practices to prevent, report, respond to, and investigate harassment; promotes mechanisms for employees to report misconduct; encourages bystander intervention; and addresses training, education, and monitoring to create a culture that does not tolerate harassment or other forms of discrimination or retaliation; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;promote a data-driven approach to increase transparency and accountability, which would build upon, as appropriate, the EEOC&#8217;s Management Directive 715 reporting process;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;establish an updated system for agencies to report regularly on progress in implementing Agency DEIA Strategic Plans (as described in section 4(b) of this order) and in meeting the objectives of this order. &nbsp;New reporting requirements should be aligned with ongoing reporting established by Executive Order 13985 and the National Security Memorandum on Revitalizing America&#8217;s Foreign Policy and National Security Workforce, Institutions, and Partnerships. &nbsp;Agency reports on actions taken to meet the objectives of this order shall include measurement of improvements, analysis of the effectiveness of agency programs, and descriptions of lessons learned. &nbsp;The Director of OPM and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall support agencies in developing workforce policies and practices designed to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility throughout agencies by, for example, providing updated guidance and technical assistance to ensure that agencies consistently improve, evaluate, and learn from their workforce practices;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;pursue opportunities to consolidate implementation efforts and reporting requirements related to advancing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility established through related or overlapping statutory mandates, Presidential directives, and regulatory requirements; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;support, coordinate, and encourage agency efforts to&nbsp;conduct research, evaluation, and other evidence-building activities to identify leading practices, and other promising practices, for broadening participation and opportunities for advancement in Federal employment, and to assess and promote the benefits of diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility for Federal performance and operations and barriers to achieving these goals. &nbsp;Agencies should use the capabilities of their evaluation officers and chief statistical officers and requirements under the Foundations for Evidence-Based Policymaking Act of 2018, Public Law 115-435, to advance this&nbsp;goal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 4. &nbsp;Responsibilities of Executive Departments and Agencies. The head of each agency shall make advancing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility a priority component of the agency&#8217;s management agenda and agency strategic planning. &nbsp;The head of each agency shall implement the Government-wide DEIA Plan prepared pursuant to section 3 of this order and such other related guidance as issued from time to time by the Director of OPM or the Deputy Director for Management of OMB.&nbsp; In addition, the head of each agency shall:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;within 100 days of the date of this order, submit to&nbsp;the APDP, the Director of OPM, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB a preliminary assessment of the current state of diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in the agency&#8217;s human resources practices and workforce composition. &nbsp;In conducting such assessment, the head of each agency should:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;assess whether agency recruitment, hiring, promotion, retention, professional development, performance evaluations, pay and compensation policies, reasonable accommodations access, and training policies and practices are equitable;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;take an evidence-based and data-driven approach to determine whether and to what extent agency practices result in inequitable employment outcomes, and whether agency actions may help to overcome systemic societal and organizational barriers;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;assess the status and effects of existing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility initiatives or programs, and review the amount of institutional resources available to support human resources activities that advance the objectives outlined in section 1 of this order; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;identify areas where evidence is lacking and propose opportunities to build evidence to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility and address those gaps identified;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;within 120 days of the issuance of the Government-wide DEIA Plan, and annually thereafter, develop and submit to the&nbsp;APDP, the Director of OPM, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB an Agency Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility Strategic Plan (Agency DEIA Strategic Plan), as&nbsp;described by section 3(b) of Executive Order 13583 and as modified by this order. &nbsp;Agency DEIA Strategic Plans should identify actions to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and&nbsp;accessibility in the workforce and remove any potential barriers to diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in&nbsp;the workforce identified in the assessments described in subsection (a) of this section. &nbsp;Agency DEIA Strategic Plans should also include quarterly goals and actions to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility initiatives in the agency workforce and in the agency&#8217;s workplace culture;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;on an annual basis, report to the President on the status of the agency&#8217;s efforts to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility within the agency, and the agency&#8217;s success in implementing the Agency DEIA Strategic Plan. &nbsp;Consistent with guidance issued as part of the Government-wide DEIA Plan, the agency head shall also make available to the general public information on efforts to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in the agency&#8217;s workforce;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;oversee, and provide resources and staffing to support, the implementation of the Agency DEIA Strategic Plan;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;enhance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility within the agency, in collaboration with the agency&#8217;s senior officials and consistent with applicable law and&nbsp;merit system principles;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;seek opportunities to establish a position of chief diversity officer or diversity and inclusion officer (as distinct from an equal employment opportunity officer), with sufficient seniority to coordinate efforts to promote diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility within the agency;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(g) &nbsp;strongly consider for employment, to the extent permitted by applicable law, qualified applicants of any background who have advanced diversity, equity, inclusion, and&nbsp;accessibility in the workplace; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(h) &nbsp;in coordination with OMB, seek opportunities to ensure alignment across various organizational performance planning requirements and efforts by integrating the Agency DEIA Strategic Plan and diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility goals into broader agency strategic planning efforts described in 5 U.S.C. 306 and the agency performance planning described in 31 U.S.C. 1115.</p>



<p>Sec. 5. &nbsp;Data Collection.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall take a data-driven approach to advancing policies that promote diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility within the agency&#8217;s workforce, while protecting the privacy of employees and safeguarding all personally identifiable information and protected health information.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Using Federal standards governing the collection, use, and analysis of demographic data (such as OMB Directive No. 15 (Standards for Maintaining, Collecting, and Presenting Federal Data on Race and Ethnicity) and OMB Memorandum M-14-06 (Guidance for Providing and Using Administrative Data for Statistical Purposes)), the head of each agency shall measure demographic representation and trends related to diversity in the agency&#8217;s overall workforce composition, senior workforce composition, employment applications, hiring decisions, promotions, pay and compensation, professional development programs, and attrition rates.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;The Director of OPM,&nbsp; the Chair of the EEOC, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall review existing guidance, regulations, policies, and practices (for purposes of&nbsp;this section, &#8220;guidance&#8221;) that govern agency collection of demographic data about Federal employees, and consider issuing, modifying, or revoking such guidance in order to expand the collection of such voluntarily self-reported data and more effectively measure the representation of underserved communities in the Federal workforce. &nbsp;In revisiting or issuing any such guidance, the Director of OPM, the Chair of the EEOC, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall take steps to promote the protection of privacy and to safeguard personally identifiable information; facilitate intersectional analysis; and reduce duplicative reporting requirements. &nbsp;In considering whether to revisit or issue such guidance, the Director of OPM, the Chair of the EEOC, and the Deputy Director for Management of&nbsp;OMB shall consult with the Chief Statistician of the United&nbsp;States, the Chair of the Chief Data Officers Council, and&nbsp;the Co-Chairs of the Interagency Working Group on Equitable Data established in section 9 of Executive Order 13985.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall implement any such revised guidance issued pursuant to subsection (c) of this section to expand the collection of voluntarily self-reported demographic data. &nbsp;The head of each agency shall also take steps to ensure that data collection and analysis practices allow for the capture or presence of multiple attributes and identities to ensure an intersectional analysis.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall collect and analyze voluntarily self-reported demographic data regarding the membership of advisory committees, commissions, and boards in a&nbsp;manner consistent with applicable law, including privacy and confidentiality protections, and with statistical standards where applicable. &nbsp;For agencies that have external advisory committees, commissions, or boards to which agencies appoint members, agency heads shall pursue opportunities to increase diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility on such committees, commissions, and boards.</p>



<p>Sec<em>.</em> 6. &nbsp;Promoting Paid Internships.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; The Director of OPM and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall issue guidance to agencies and the Executive Office of the President with respect to internships and similar programs within the Federal Government, including guidance on how to:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;increase the availability of paid internships, fellowships, and apprenticeships, and reduce the practice of hiring interns, fellows, and apprentices who are unpaid;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;ensure that internships, fellowships, and apprenticeships serve as a supplement to, and not a&nbsp;substitute for, the competitive hiring process;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;ensure that internships, fellowships, and apprenticeships serve to develop individuals&#8217; talent, knowledge, and skills for careers in government service;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;improve outreach to and recruitment of individuals from underserved communities for internship, fellowship, and apprenticeship programs;&nbsp;and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ensure all interns, fellows, and apprentices with disabilities, including applicants and candidates, have a process for requesting and obtaining reasonable accommodations to support their work in the Federal Government, without regard to whether such individuals are covered by the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, Public Law 93-112.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall, as part of the annual reporting process described in section 4(c) of this order, measure and report on the agency&#8217;s progress with respect to the&nbsp;matters described in subsection (a) of this section.</p>



<p>Sec. 7. &nbsp;Partnerships and Recruitment. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), the Director of OPM, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB, in consultation with the Chair of the EEOC, shall coordinate a&nbsp;Government-wide initiative to strengthen partnerships (Partnerships Initiative) to facilitate recruitment for Federal employment opportunities of individuals who are members of underserved communities. &nbsp;To carry out the Partnerships Initiative, the Director of OSTP, the Director of OPM, and the&nbsp;Deputy Director for Management of OMB shall take steps to&nbsp;increase diversity in the Federal employment pipeline by supporting and guiding agencies in building or strengthening partnerships with Historically Black Colleges and Universities, including Historically Black Graduate Institutions; Hispanic-Serving Institutions; Tribal Colleges and Universities; Native American-serving, nontribal institutions; Asian American and Pacific Islander-serving institutions; Tribally controlled colleges and universities; Alaska Native-serving and Native Hawaiian-serving institutions; Predominantly Black Institutions; women&#8217;s colleges and universities; State vocational rehabilitation agencies that serve individuals with disabilities; disability services offices at institutions of higher education; organizations dedicated to serving veterans; public and non-profit private universities serving a high percentage of economically disadvantaged students or first-generation college or graduate students; community colleges and technical schools; and community-based organizations that are dedicated to serving and working with underserved communities, including return-to-work programs, programs that provide training and support for older adults seeking employment, programs serving formerly incarcerated individuals, centers for&nbsp;independent living, disability rights organizations, and organizations dedicated to serving LGBTQ+ individuals.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall work with the Director of OSTP, the Director of OPM, and the Deputy Director for Management of OMB to make employment, internship, fellowship, and apprenticeship opportunities available through the Partnerships Initiative, and shall take steps to enhance recruitment efforts through the Partnerships Initiative, as part of the agency&#8217;s overall recruitment efforts. &nbsp;The head of each agency shall, as part of the reporting processes described in sections 3(c) and 4(c) of this order, measure and report on the agency&#8217;s progress on carrying out this subsection.</p>



<p>Sec. 8. &nbsp;Professional Development and Advancement. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Director of OPM, in consultation with the Deputy Director for Management of OMB, shall issue detailed guidance to agencies for tracking demographic data relating to participation in leadership and professional development programs and development opportunities offered or sponsored by agencies and the rate of the placement of participating employees into senior positions in agencies, in a manner consistent with privacy and confidentiality protections and statistical limitations.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall implement the guidance issued pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, and shall use&nbsp;demographic data relating to participation in professional development programs to identify ways to improve outreach and recruitment for professional development programs offered or&nbsp;sponsored by the agency, consistent with merit system principles. &nbsp;The head of each agency shall also address any barriers to access to or participation in such programs faced by&nbsp;members of underserved communities.</p>



<p>Sec. 9. &nbsp;Training and Learning. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The head of each&nbsp;agency shall take steps to implement or increase the availability and use of diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility training programs for employees, managers, and leadership. &nbsp;Such training programs should enable Federal employees, managers, and leaders to have knowledge of systemic and institutional racism and bias against underserved communities, be supported in building skillsets to promote respectful and inclusive workplaces and eliminate workplace harassment, have knowledge of agency accessibility practices, and have increased understanding of implicit and unconscious bias.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The Director of OPM and the Chair of the EEOC shall issue guidance and serve as a resource and repository for best practices for agencies to develop or enhance existing diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility training programs.</p>



<p>Sec. 10. &nbsp;Advancing Equity for Employees with Disabilities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; As established in Executive Order 13548 of July 26, 2010 (Increasing Federal Employment of Individuals with Disabilities), the Federal Government must become a model for&nbsp;the employment of individuals with disabilities.&nbsp; Because a&nbsp;workforce that includes people with disabilities is a stronger and more effective workforce, agencies must provide an equitable, accessible, and inclusive environment for employees with disabilities.&nbsp; In order for Federal employees and applicants with disabilities to be assessed on their merits, accessible information technologies must be provided and, where needed, reasonable accommodations must be available that will allow qualified individuals with disabilities to perform the essential functions of their positions and access advancement opportunities. &nbsp;To that end, the relevant agencies shall take the actions set forth in this section.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The Secretary of Labor, the Director of OPM, the Chair of the EEOC, the Deputy Director for Management of OMB, and the Executive Director of the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board (Access Board), in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, as appropriate, shall coordinate with agencies to:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;support the Federal Government&#8217;s effort to provide people with disabilities equal employment opportunities and take affirmative actions within the&nbsp;Federal Government to ensure that agencies fully comply with applicable laws, including sections 501, 504, and 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended (29 U.S.C. 791, 794, 794d);<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;assess current practices in using Schedule A hiring authority to employ people with disabilities in&nbsp;the Federal Government, and evaluate opportunities to enhance equity in employment opportunities and financial security for employees with disabilities through different practices or guidance on the use of Schedule A hiring authority; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;ensure that:<br>(A) &nbsp;applicants and employees with disabilities have access to information about and understand their rights regarding disability self-identification;<br>(B) &nbsp;applicants and employees with disabilities have access to information about Schedule A hiring authority for individuals with disabilities;<br>(C) &nbsp;applicants and employees with disabilities have access to information about, understand their rights to, and may easily request reasonable accommodations, workplace personal assistance services, and accessible information and communication technology;<br>(D) &nbsp;the process of responding to reasonable accommodation requests is timely and efficient;<br>(E) &nbsp;the processes and procedures for appealing the denial of a reasonable accommodation request are timely and efficient; and<br>(F) &nbsp;all information and communication technology and products developed, procured, maintained, or used by Federal agencies are accessible and usable by employees with disabilities consistent with all standards and technical requirements of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;To ensure that all Federal office buildings and workplaces are accessible to employees with disabilities, the Administrator of General Services, the Director of OPM, the Deputy Director for Management of OMB, and the Executive Director of the Access Board shall work with Federal agencies to ensure that Federal buildings and leased facilities comply with the accessibility standards of the Architectural Barriers Act of 1968, Public Law 90-480, and related standards.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;Beyond existing duties to comply with the Architectural Barriers Act of 1968 and related standards, the head of each agency shall maximize the accessibility of the physical environment of the agency&#8217;s workplaces, consistent with applicable law and the availability of appropriations, so as to&nbsp;reduce the need for reasonable accommodations, and provide periodic notice to all employees that complaints concerning accessibility barriers in Federal buildings can be filed with the Access Board.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Labor shall review the use of the Workforce Recruitment Program (WRP) for college students and recent graduates with disabilities and take steps, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to expand the WRP.&nbsp; The Secretaries shall submit a report to the APDP describing any steps taken pursuant to this subsection and providing recommendations for any Presidential, administrative, or congressional actions to further expand and strengthen the program and expand job opportunities.</p>



<p>Sec. 11.&nbsp; Advancing Equity for LGBTQ+ Employees.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;As established in Executive Order 13988, it is the policy of my Administration to prevent and combat discrimination on the basis&nbsp;of gender identity or sexual orientation. &nbsp;Each Federal employee should be able to openly express their sexual orientation, gender identity, and gender expression, and have&nbsp;these identities affirmed and respected, without fear of&nbsp;discrimination, retribution, or disadvantage. &nbsp;To that end,&nbsp;the&nbsp;relevant agencies shall take the actions set forth in&nbsp;this section. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency shall, in coordination with the Director of OPM, ensure that existing employee support services equitably serve LGBTQ+ employees, including, as appropriate, through the provision of supportive services for transgender and&nbsp;gender non-conforming and non-binary employees who wish to&nbsp;legally, medically, or socially transition.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) To ensure that LGBTQ+ employees (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), as well as LGBTQ+ beneficiaries and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents of all Federal employees, have equitable access to healthcare and health insurance coverage:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the Director of OPM shall take actions to promote equitable healthcare coverage and services for&nbsp;enrolled LGBTQ+ employees (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), LGBTQ+&nbsp;beneficiaries, and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents, including coverage of comprehensive gender-affirming care, through the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;the Secretary of Defense shall take actions to promote equitable healthcare coverage and services for LGBTQ+ members of the uniformed services (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), LGBTQ+ beneficiaries, and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents, including coverage of comprehensive gender-affirming care, through the Military Health System.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;To ensure that LGBTQ+ employees (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), LGBTQ+ beneficiaries, and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents have equitable access to all other insurance coverage and employee benefits, the head of each agency shall, in coordination with the Director of OPM, ensure that the Federal Government equitably provides insurance coverage options and employee benefits for LGBTQ+ employees (including their beneficiaries and their eligible dependents), LGBTQ+ beneficiaries, and LGBTQ+ eligible dependents, including long-term care insurance, sick leave, and life insurance. &nbsp;This includes ensuring that Federal benefits, programs, and services recognize the diversity of family structures.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(e) &nbsp;To ensure that all Federal employees have their respective gender identities accurately reflected and identified in the workplace:&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the head of each agency shall, in coordination with the Director of OPM, take steps to foster an inclusive environment where all employees&#8217; gender identities are respected, such as by including, where applicable, non-binary gender marker and pronoun options in Federal hiring, employment, and benefits enrollment forms;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall update, as appropriate and in consultation with any other relevant agencies, any relevant Federal employee identification standards to&nbsp;ensure that Federal systems for issuing employee identity credentials account for the needs of transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees. &nbsp;The Secretary, in coordination with any other relevant agencies, shall take steps to reduce any unnecessary administrative burden for transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees to update their names, photographs, gender markers, and pronouns on federally issued employee identity credentials, where applicable; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii) &nbsp;the head of each agency shall, in consultation with the Director of OPM, update Federal employee identification standards to include non-binary gender markers where gender markers are required in employee systems and profiles, and shall take steps to reduce any unnecessary administrative burden for transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees to update their gender markers and pronouns in employee systems and profiles, where applicable.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(f) &nbsp;To support all Federal employees in accessing workplace facilities aligned with their gender identities, the head of each agency shall explore opportunities to expand the availability of gender non-binary facilities and restrooms in federally owned and leased workplaces.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(g) &nbsp;The Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Director of OPM and the heads of agencies, shall take steps to mitigate any barriers in security clearance and background investigation processes for LGBTQ+ employees and applicants, in particular transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees and applicants.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(h) The Director of OPM shall review and update, if necessary, OPM&#8217;s 2017 Guidance Regarding the Employment of Transgender Individuals in the Federal Workplace.</p>



<p>Sec. 12. &nbsp;Pay Equity. &nbsp;Many workers continue to face racial and gender pay gaps, and pay inequity disproportionately affects women of color.&nbsp; Accordingly:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Director of OPM shall review Government-wide regulations and guidance and, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, in order to address any pay inequities and advance equal pay, consider whether to:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;work with agencies to review, and revise if necessary, job classification and compensation practices; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;prohibit agencies from seeking or relying on an applicant&#8217;s salary history during the hiring process to set pay or when setting pay for a current employee, unless salary history is raised without prompting by the applicant or employee.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;The head of each agency that administers a pay system other than one established under title 5 of the United States Code shall review the agency&#8217;s regulations and guidance and, as&nbsp;appropriate and consistent with applicable law, revise compensation practices in order to address any pay inequities and advance equal pay. &nbsp;Agencies should report to OPM any revisions to compensation practices made to implement this direction.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;The Director of OPM shall submit a report to the President describing any changes to Government-wide and agency-specific compensation practices recommended and adopted pursuant to this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 13.&nbsp; Expanding Employment Opportunities for Formerly Incarcerated Individuals.&nbsp; To support equal opportunity for formerly incarcerated individuals who have served their terms of incarceration and to support their ability to fully reintegrate into society and make meaningful contributions to our Nation, the Director of OPM shall evaluate the existence of any barriers that formerly incarcerated individuals face in accessing Federal employment opportunities and any effect of those barriers on the&nbsp;civil service.&nbsp; As appropriate, the Director of OPM shall also evaluate possible actions to expand Federal employment opportunities for formerly incarcerated individuals, including the establishment of a new hiring authority, and shall submit a&nbsp;report to the President containing the results of OPM&#8217;s evaluation within 120 days of the date of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 14.&nbsp; Delegation of Authority.&nbsp; The Director of OPM is hereby delegated the authority of the President under sections 3301 and 3302 of title 5, United States Code, for purposes of carrying out the Director&#8217;s responsibilities under this order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 15. &nbsp;General Provisions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;Independent agencies are strongly encouraged to comply with the provisions of this order.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                             JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.  </p>



<p><br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>    June 25, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President Biden Signs Executive Order Advancing Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility in the Federal Government</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/25/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-advancing-diversity-equity-inclusion-and-accessibility-in-the-federal-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility (DEIA) in the Federal workforce. This Executive Order reaffirms that the United States is at its strongest when our Nation’s public servants reflect the full diversity of the American people. Even with decades of progress building a Federal workforce that looks&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility (DEIA) in the Federal workforce. This Executive Order reaffirms that the United States is at its strongest when our Nation’s public servants reflect the full diversity of the American people.</p>



<p>Even with decades of progress building a Federal workforce that looks like America, the enduring legacies of employment discrimination, systemic racism, and gender inequality are still felt today. Too many underserved communities remain under-represented in the Federal workforce, especially in positions of leadership. This Executive Order establishes an ambitious, whole-of-government initiative that will take a systematic approach to embedding DEIA in Federal hiring and employment practices.</p>



<p>When public servants reflect the communities they serve, the government is more effective and successful. That is why the Biden-Harris Administration has appointed <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/29/fact-sheet-100-days-in-biden-harris-administration-makes-history-with-presidential-appointees/">an historic number of&nbsp; diverse leaders</a>. Today’s Executive Order will help develop a Federal workforce that looks like America where qualified people from every background and walk of life have an equal opportunity to serve our Nation.</p>



<p>The Executive Order:</p>



<p><strong>Establishes a government-wide initiative to advance diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility in all parts of the Federal workforce. </strong>This initiative will be led by the Office of Personnel Management and the Office of Management and Budget, in close partnership with the White House and the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. The initiative will reinvigorate the whole-of-government approach to DEIA first established in the Obama-Biden Administration. The initiative will advance opportunity for communities that have historically faced employment discrimination and professional barriers, including: people of color; women; first-generation professionals and immigrants; individuals with disabilities; LGBTQ+ individuals; Americans who live in rural areas; older Americans who face age discrimination when seeking employment; parents and caregivers who face employment barriers; people of faith who require religious accommodations at work; individuals who were formerly incarcerated; and veterans and military spouses.</p>



<p><strong>Charges all agencies with assessing the current state of diversity, equity, inclusion and accessibility within their workforces, and developing strategic plans to eliminate any barriers to success faced by underserved employees. </strong>The Order charges all Federal agencies with reviewing within 100 days whether employees who are members of underserved communities face barriers to employment, promotion, or professional development within their workforce.</p>



<p><strong>Directs agencies to seek opportunities to establish or elevate Chief Diversity Officers within their organizations. </strong>To help ensure the coordination of DEIA initiatives across the Federal government, the Executive Order directs all agencies to look for opportunities to establish senior leaders to promote diversity and inclusion within the workforce.</p>



<p><strong>Expands diversity, equity, inclusion, and accessibility training throughout the Federal workforce. </strong>On his first day in office, President Biden rescinded a ban that prevented Federal employees from participating in diversity and sensitivity trainings. Today’s Executive Order builds on that by directing all Federal agencies to expand the availability of DEIA trainings for their workforce, so that Federal employees are supported in building skillsets to promote respectful and inclusive workplaces and have increased understanding of implicit and unconscious bias. These types of trainings equip public servants to best serve the American public, and the many diverse communities that make American strong.</p>



<p><strong>Addresses workplace harassment, including sexual harassment.</strong>&nbsp; Requires a government-wide, comprehensive plan to address workplace harassment, including sexual harassment.&nbsp; The plan will outline policies and practices to prevent report, respond to, and investigate harassment, and address training, education, and monitoring to create a culture that does not tolerate harassment or other forms of discrimination.</p>



<p><strong>Reduces the Federal government’s reliance on unpaid internships, which can create barriers for low-income students and first-generation professionals. </strong>The Federal government must be an engine of opportunity for Americans from every walk of life to serve our Nation through public service. But too often, unpaid Federal internships prevent hardworking and talented students and professionals from participating in Federal career advancement opportunities. The Executive Order directs key agencies to take steps to reduce the reliance on unpaid internships, fellowships, and apprenticeships to ensure that more Americans can take advantage of these opportunities.</p>



<p><strong>Advances pay equity to ensure that all public servants are fairly compensated for their work and their talents. </strong>Many workers continue to face racial and gender pay gaps, and pay inequity disproportionately affects women of color.&nbsp; The Order directs the Office of Personnel Management to review Government-wide regulations and guidance that set pay and wage standards for public servants. It also directs the Office of Personnel Management to consider taking steps to prohibit agencies from seeking or relying on an applicant&#8217;s salary history during the hiring process and compensation decisions, an important component of advancing pay equity.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Advances equity in the workplace for individuals with disabilities. </strong>The Federal government is stronger and more successful when individuals with disabilities have equal opportunities to lead at every level. In spite of decades of progress in removing barriers to employment for employees with disabilities, people with disabilities remain under-represented throughout the Federal government, and particularly in positions of leadership. The Executive Order directs the government to become a model employer for individuals with disabilities. It charges key agencies, including the Department of Labor and the U.S. Access Board, to coordinate across the Federal government to ensure that all Federal workplaces and technologies are fully accessible; improve the process for requesting reasonable accommodations; and ensure that all Federal employees understand their rights to request reasonable accommodations. The Executive Order also directs a review of Schedule A Hiring Authority for individuals with disabilities to assess opportunities to enhance employment opportunities and financial security for employees with disabilities. And the Executive Order directs the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Labor to take steps to expand the use of the Workforce Recruitment Program for college students and recent graduates with disabilities.</p>



<p><strong>Advances equity in the workplace for LGBTQ+ public servants. </strong>For too long, LGBTQ+ employees have faced discrimination and harassment in the workplace. To advance opportunity for LGBTQ+ employees in the Federal workforce, the Executive Order directs agencies to ensure that the Federal health benefits system equitably serves LGBTQ+ employees and their dependents by expanding access to comprehensive gender-affirming health care. Agencies are also directed to take steps to ensure that federal benefits like sick leave and life insurance equitably serve LGBTQ+ individuals and all families with diverse family structures.&nbsp; The Order charges all agencies to ensure that the usage of gender markers and pronouns in the Federal employment process respects transgender, gender non-conforming and non-binary employees, and directs all agencies to take steps to expand access to gender-neutral facilities inside federal workplaces. Finally, the Order charges all agencies with ensuring that their employee support services equitably serve LGBTQ+ employees, including, transgender and gender non-conforming and non-binary employees who wish to legally, medically, or socially transition.</p>



<p><strong>Builds a more diverse pipeline into public service through new recruitment partnerships. </strong>Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Hispanic Serving Institutions, Tribal Colleges and Universities, Minority Serving Institutions, and women’s colleges are engines of opportunity and innovation in our Nation. The Executive Order charges agencies with developing new recruitment partnerships to ensure that the Federal government can recruit our Nation’s best talent.</p>



<p><strong>Expands Federal employment opportunities for formerly incarcerated individuals. </strong>Individuals with prior convictions experience must be supported in accessing employment as they fully re-enter society. The Federal government has an important role to play in supporting formerly incarcerated individuals in fully reintegrating into society and making meaningful contributions to our country. The Executive Order directs the Office of Personnel Management to assess the barriers that formerly incarcerated individuals face when seeking Federal jobs.&nbsp; The Executive Order also tasks the Office of Personnel Management with considering creating new Hiring Authorities to expand job opportunities for individuals with past convictions.</p>



<p><strong>Advances equity in professional development. </strong>The Executive Order directs agencies to improve the collection of demographic data about which employees are able to access professional development and advancement opportunities to ensure that these programs equitably serve all Federal public servants.</p>



<p><strong>Improves the collection of demographic data about the Federal workforce. </strong>The Executive Order charges key agencies with reviewing and improving guidance on the collection of demographic data about Federal employees. With improved data on the Federal government’s workforce composition, agencies will be better able to take an evidence-informed approach to reducing inequitable barriers in hiring, promotion, professional development, and retention practices.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in Bill Signing of H.R. 49 to Designate the National Pulse Memorial into Law</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/25/remarks-by-president-biden-in-bill-signing-of-h-r-49-to-designate-the-national-pulse-memorial-into-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 22:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium  1:57 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m Joe Biden.  I&#8217;m Jill&#8217;s husband.  (Laughter.)  Before I sign, let me start with a few words about what&#8217;s going on now in &#8212; in Florida.  And, you know, the people who are here, who were part of what happened that night at the Pulse nightclub and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium </p>



<p><br>1:57 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m Joe Biden.  I&#8217;m Jill&#8217;s husband.  (Laughter.) <br><br>Before I sign, let me start with a few words about what&#8217;s going on now in &#8212; in Florida.  And, you know, the people who are here, who were part of what happened that night at the Pulse nightclub and the scores that I just spoke to a moment ago &#8212; they&#8217;re online looking at this &#8212; they understand that &#8212; what it&#8217;s like to have to wait and wonder what happened. <br><br>The families &#8212; I remember going down there to the Pulse nightclub afterwards and &#8212; and wondering: &#8220;Is it my son, my daughter, my husband, someone I love &#8212; is that who got lost?&#8221;  Because you didn&#8217;t know for certain initially. <br><br>And as &#8212; as Congressman Cicilline knows, there&#8217;s nothing worse than having to wait and wonder what happened.  And I know, Val, when you were a police chief, you had to go through waiting a lot as well. <br><br>And so, I just want to say, I&#8217;ve spoken to Governor DeSantis.  And we&#8217;ve provided all the help that they have &#8212; they need.  We sent the best people from FEMA down there.  We&#8217;re going to stay with them; with the disaster declaration we made, provide for everything from housing to, God forbid, whether there&#8217;s a need for moratoria- &#8212; if there are &#8212; to &#8212; for the bodies to be placed.  Everything in between. <br><br>And &#8212; but I just &#8212; I just want to say &#8212; and I&#8217;m sure I speak for all the members of the Congress here today and all the survivors here that &#8212; that it&#8217;s a tough, tough time.  There&#8217;s so many people waiting.  &#8220;Are they alive?  Will they be &#8212; what will happen?&#8221;  And so, our heart goes out to them. <br><br>And I &#8212; to the people of Florida, I want to &#8212; I&#8217;ve spoken to Debbie Wasserman Schultz.  I&#8217;ve spoken to most of the folks down there and member &#8212; in authority.  And I promise you, the administration, the Congress &#8212; we&#8217;re doing everything possible to be of assistance now and after this occurs &#8212; after they decide exactly what the state of play is.<br><br>But I&#8217;m glad to welcome everyone here to the adjunct to the White House here, and in person and virtually: survivors and family members, victims, and the path-breaking leaders like Senator Baldwin. <br><br>Just over five years ago, the Pulse nightclub, a place of acceptance and joy, became a place of unspeakable pain and loss.  And we&#8217;ll never fully recovery, but we&#8217;ll remember.  And we have to &#8212; what we&#8217;re going to do is what the members of Congress here did, and enshrine in law &#8212; as a consequence of that law, enshrine, in perpetuity, literally a monument to the loss that occurred there, and an absolute determination that we&#8217;re going to deal with this every single, solitary day and make sure that we&#8217;re not in a position to see this happen again. <br><br>Behind me, you see, on either board there, the 49 lives lost: family members, parents, friends, veterans, students, young, Black, Asian, Latino &#8212; all fellow Americans.  And in their memory and for the countless others forever scarred is why I sign this today. <br><br>And let me say how much I appreciate it &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; the &#8212; the commitment of the members of the House and Senate to make sure that we don&#8217;t forget &#8212; that this isn&#8217;t forgotten. <br><br>Now, there&#8217;s a tradition when a bill is signed that the President gives a signing pen to each of the people who had something to do with the law or the decision being made in the first place. <br><br>I promise you, I have all the pens, but they&#8217;re in the other room.  I couldn&#8217;t figure how to sign &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; sign them all.  But don&#8217;t leave without the pen.  Okay?  All right?  All right. <br><br>REPRESENTATIVE TAKANO:  Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>REPRESENTATIVE SOTO:  Thank you, Mr. President.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (The bill is signed.) <br><br>May we never have to sign another &#8212; no President ever have to sign another monument like this.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you. <br><br>And one last thing, as I said to &#8212; to the survivors and their &#8212; those who lost folks, a little earlier, in private: You know, what the Congress has done means a great deal, and it&#8217;s important.  But it&#8217;s really hard; it brings back everything as if it happened yesterday. <br><br>And every time there&#8217;s a memorial service for our son, Beau, you know, you&#8217;re flattered.  You feel good about it.  You think it&#8217;s wonderful &#8212; the recognition.  But it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s tough.  It&#8217;s as if it happened yesterday, it happened the day before, it happened the moment you&#8217;re signing it. <br><br>So, I want to thank the folks who are here and the folks who are survivors who are on Zoom with us.  I want to thank them for their courage &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; for their courage. <br><br>But, I promise you, none of the members of Congress that are here, nor I, nor Jill are going to let up until we deal with equity across the board. <br><br>Thank you so very much.  (Applause.)<br><br>PARTICIPANT:  Thank you, Mr. President.  It means so much to us. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And you&#8217;ve got to come back and get your pens.  (Laughter.) <br><br>2:03 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
