<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 21:58:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Bilateral Meeting with French National Security Advisor Emmanuel Bonne</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-bilateral-meeting-with-french-national-security-advisor-emmanuel-bonne/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 21:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met in Washington with Emmanuel Bonne, National Security Advisor to the President of France, to exchange views on a range of shared global policy issues. They talked about the upcoming G7 leaders meeting and NATO Summit. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Bonne agreed to continue coordinating on global access to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met in Washington with Emmanuel Bonne, National Security Advisor to the President of France, to exchange views on a range of shared global policy issues. They talked about the upcoming G7 leaders meeting and NATO Summit. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Bonne agreed to continue coordinating on global access to COVID-19 vaccines and supporting negotiations to address the tax challenges arising from globalization. They discussed our work to strengthen and modernize NATO, as well as counter challenges associated with malicious cyber activity such as ransomware, and terrorism. In addition, they discussed Russia, China, Iran, and the Sahel.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/president-biden-announces-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 20:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles: Paloma Adams-Allen, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources, United States Agency for International Development Isobel Coleman, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Policy and Programming, United States Agency for International Development Grant Harris, Nominee&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Paloma Adams-Allen, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Isobel Coleman, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Policy and Programming, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Grant Harris, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Industry and Analysis, Department of Commerce</li><li>Neil MacBride, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of the Treasury</li><li>Caral Spangler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Army (Financial Management and Comptroller), Department of Defense</li><li>Julieta Valls Noyes, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees, and Migration, Department of State</li><li>David Weil, Nominee for Wage and Hour Administrator, Department of Labor</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Paloma Adams-Allen, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Paloma Adams-Allen joined the Inter-American Foundation (IAF), a US agency supporting community-led development in Latin America and the Caribbean, in April 2017 as president and chief executive officer. Prior to joining the IAF, Adams-Allen was Sr. Director for global private sector partnerships initiatives at the international NGO, Winrock International. Before that, she served as deputy assistant administrator for the United States Agency for International Development&#8217;s (USAID) Latin America and Caribbean (LAC) Bureau. From 2010 to 2014, Adams-Allen served as Senior Adviser, during which she led the LAC Bureau&#8217;s public-private partnerships for development practice. She also spent a decade at the Organization of American States (OAS) in several hemispheric development policy, programming, and leadership roles. Early in her career she did short stints at the international law firm Coudert Brothers, and the advocacy organization Caribbean-Central American Action. Adams-Allen, who was born in Jamaica, spent her childhood between rural Jamaica and rural New England in the U.S. She holds a bachelor&#8217;s degree in development studies and African American studies from Brown University, a master’s in international affairs from Johns Hopkins University&#8217;s School of Advanced International Studies, and a Juris Doctorate from Georgetown University Law Center. An avid runner and gardener, Adams-Allen lives in Washington, D.C., with her husband, their puppy, and two awesome daughters.</p>



<p><strong><u>Isobel Coleman, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Policy and Programming, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Ambassador Isobel Coleman is a foreign policy and global development expert with more than 25 years of experience working in government, the private sector and non-profits.&nbsp; Most recently, she served on the Biden Transition Team, leading the review of the U.S. Mission to the United Nations. From 2014-2017, she was the U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations for Management, Reform and Special Political Affairs.&nbsp; During that time, she represented the United States in the UN General Assembly on budgetary matters and in the UN Security Council on Africa and peacekeeping issues. From 2018-2020, she was the Chief Operating Officer of GiveDirectly, an international non-profit tackling poverty by providing unconditional cash transfers to the extreme poor.</p>



<p>Previously, Dr. Coleman spent more than a decade as a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations where she directed CFR’s Women and Foreign Policy program and wrote extensively about global development and the advantages of women’s empowerment. Her writings have appeared in many publications, including The Atlantic, Foreign Policy, Foreign Affairs, The New York Times and The Washington Post. She is the author and co-author of numerous books including Pathways to Freedom: Political and Economic Lessons from Democratic Transitions (Council on Foreign Relations, 2013), and Paradise Beneath Her Feet: How Women are Transforming the Middle East (Random House, 2010). She graduated from Princeton University and earned MPhil and DPhil degrees in International Relations from Oxford University, which she attended on a Marshall Scholarship. She started her career at McKinsey &amp; Co. in New York, becoming a partner in the firm’s financial institutions group.</p>



<p><strong><u>Grant Harris, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Industry and Analysis, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Grant T. Harris is CEO of Connect Frontier LLC, a consulting firm that advises companies on doing business in emerging and frontier markets globally. Harris teaches on strategy and political risk in emerging markets as an Adjunct Professor of Global Management at Kellogg School of Management, Northwestern University, and a Lecturer at Haas School of Business, University of California, Berkeley. From 2011-2015, Harris served as Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for African Affairs at the White House. In this role, he conceived of the historic U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit, which generated $37 billion in commitments to support trade, investment, and development across Africa. Harris also initiated President Obama’s Doing Business in Africa Campaign and launched the President’s Young African Leaders Initiative. Harris was later appointed by President Obama to serve as a Member of the United States Holocaust Memorial Council.</p>



<p>Previously, Harris served as Deputy Chief of Staff and Counselor to U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Susan Rice. Earlier, Harris was an attorney at the global law firm of Cleary Gottlieb Steen &amp; Hamilton LLP, where he focused on cross-border transactions in Latin America. Harris also served in the African Affairs Directorate at the White House under President Bill Clinton and in the U.S. Mission to the United Nations under Ambassador Richard Holbrooke. Harris holds a law degree from Yale Law School, a Master’s in Public Affairs, with Distinction, from Princeton University, and a B.A., summa cum laude, from the University of California, Berkeley. Harris grew up in California.</p>



<p><strong><u>Neil MacBride, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Neil H. MacBride is a currently a litigation partner in the law firm of Davis Polk &amp; Wardwell, where he serves as head of its Washington, DC office and as co-head of the Firm’s Government Investigations Practice.&nbsp; Before entering private practice, Mr. MacBride spent extensive time as a government official on law enforcement, national security, and financial enforcement matters.&nbsp; He served in the Obama-Biden Administration, first as an Associate Deputy Attorney General for criminal enforcement in the U.S. Department of Justice and then as the United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Virginia overseeing all criminal enforcement and civil litigation on behalf of the United States.&nbsp; Mr. MacBride earlier served as Chief Counsel to then-Senator Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the Senate Judiciary Committee and as a federal prosecutor in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia.&nbsp; Mr. MacBride also served on the Biden-Harris and the Obama-Biden Transition Teams.&nbsp; Earlier in his career, Mr. MacBride served as General Counsel to the Business Software Alliance and practiced law at the Washington, DC law firm of Verner, Liipfert, Bernhard, McPherson &amp; Hand.&nbsp; He began his public service career clerking for the Honorable Henry C. Morgan, Jr. in the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A native of Oneonta, New York, MacBride graduated from the University of Virginia School of Law and Houghton College.&nbsp; He lives in Northern Virginia with his wife Christina Jackson MacBride and their three children.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Caral Spangler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Army, Financial Management and Comptroller, Department of Defense&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<p>Caral E. Spangler retired from government service in September 2020 after 39 years with the Department of Defense, serving as a career member of the Senior Executive Service in every Military Service and the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller). She began her career as a summer hire in the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Navy (Financial Management and Comptroller) and advanced during postings with the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) and as a Legislative Fellow in the office of Congressman Norman Y. Mineta (D-CA).&nbsp; Promoted to an SES in 1997, she served as the Director of the Investment Directorate within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller); the Director of the Budget Coordination Division in the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Navy (Financial Management and Comptroller (FM&amp;C); the Deputy for Budget, Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Air Force (FM&amp;C); the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Army (FM&amp;C); and retired as the Assistant Deputy Commandant, Programs and Resources (USMC).&nbsp; In these capacities, she has had oversight of every aspect of programming, budgeting, accounting, finance, financial systems, program and cost analysis in the Department of Defense. She has also served in acting capacities as the Auditor General, Department of the Navy, and as the Assistant Secretary of the Army (FM&amp;C). She was the recipient of a Presidential Meritorious Rank Award in 2015.</p>



<p>While Ms. Spangler was born in Minnesota, she spent her formative years in the Deep South, and graduated from Michigan State University with a Bachelor of Science in Economics.  She has a Master’s Degree in Public Administration from the Maxwell School at Syracuse University.  Ms. Spangler currently lives in Virginia with her husband.</p>



<p><strong><u>Julieta Valls Noyes, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Population, Refugees, and Migration, Department of State</u></strong></p>



<p>Julieta Valls Noyes, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister, is Deputy Director of the Department of State’s Foreign Service Institute, and a former U.S. ambassador to the Republic of Croatia.&nbsp; She previously served as a Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs in the Department of State, Deputy Executive Secretary of the Department, and as Deputy Chief of Mission and Charge d’Affaires a.i. at the U.S. Embassy to the Holy See.&nbsp; She also was Deputy Director of the Department’s Operations Center, and Director of the Office of Multilateral and Global Affairs in the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor.&nbsp; Earlier, Noyes served as Deputy Director, Office of Policy Planning and Coordination, Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs, as Political Section Chief, U.S. Embassy Panama City, and as Political Officer at U.S. Embassy Madrid.&nbsp; Noyes earned a B.A. from Wellesley College, and a Master’s from the Industrial College of the Armed Forces.&nbsp; She speaks Spanish, Italian, Portuguese and French.&nbsp; Noyes is a first-generation American whose parents entered the United States as refugees.</p>



<p><strong><u>David Weil, Nominee for Wage and Hour Administrator, Department of Labor</u></strong></p>



<p>David Weil is Dean and professor at The Heller School for Social Policy and Management at Brandeis University. Prior to joining the Heller School in August 2017, he served as Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division at the United States Department of Labor under President Obama from 2014 to 2017. Weil is an internationally recognized expert in employment and labor market policy along with regulation, transparency policy, and the impacts of industry restructuring on employment, work, and business performance.</p>



<p>Dean Weil has advised government agencies at the state and federal levels as well as international organizations on employment, labor, and workplace policies. He co-founded the Transparency Policy Project at the Harvard Kennedy School of Government that examines how information disclosure can be used to improve private and public decisions. He is the author of more than 125 articles and five books including The Fissured Workplace. He has received numerous awards including the Frances Perkins Intelligence and Courage Award (2019). He holds a Bachelor of Science degree from Cornell University and Masters and Ph.D. degrees in public policy from Harvard University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/03/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 19:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  11:10 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning and thank you for joining us.&#160; Today I will begin with an update both on our domestic and global efforts to defeat COVID-19.&#160; We have here with us National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who will join me in speaking about our next steps in our global&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference </p>



<p>11:10 A.M. EDT<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning and thank you for joining us.&nbsp; Today I will begin with an update both on our domestic and global efforts to defeat COVID-19.&nbsp; We have here with us National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan, who will join me in speaking about our next steps in our global COVID-19 response.&nbsp; Then, Dr. Walensky will give an update on the state of the pandemic, and Dr. Fauci will discuss the latest science.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll leave some time for Q&amp;A at the end.&nbsp;<br><br>On his first full day in office, President Biden released a comprehensive strategy to marshal a whole-of-government wartime effort to defeat the pandemic.&nbsp; We have spent each and every day of the last four and a half months executing against that strategy.&nbsp; And today I want to provide an update on the progress we are making: first, on our efforts to get Americans vaccinated as quickly, efficiently, and equitably as possible; and second, on our efforts to help combat the pandemic globally.&nbsp;<br><br>Here at home, we have built a best-in-class vaccination program.&nbsp; Already 63 percent of adult Americans have received at least one shot, and 52 percent of adult Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; Already 12 states have 70 percent of adults with at least one shot.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an important milestone.&nbsp; And 28 states and the District of Columbia have fully vaccinated 50 percent or more of their adult population.&nbsp; As a result, in communities and states across the country, the pandemic is in retreat.<br><br>Since the President took office on January 20th, cases are down over 90 percent and deaths are down over 85 percent.&nbsp; Our successful vaccination program isn&#8217;t just saving tens of thousands of lives.&nbsp; It&#8217;s letting tens of millions of Americans get back to living their lives.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s fair to say that we&#8217;re far ahead of where anyone thought we would be in our fight against the virus.&nbsp; And, importantly, we have secured enough vaccine supply for all Americans.&nbsp; This is a direct result to the President taking aggressive action, including through the use of the Defense Production Act, the DPA, to mobilize the full force of U.S. vaccine manufacturing and production.<br><br>Because of those actions and the success of U.S. vaccine manufacturers, we are confident in our supply of our authorized vaccines.&nbsp; As a result, we&#8217;re removing the DPA priority ratings for AstraZeneca, Novavax, and Sanofi.&nbsp; While the manufacturers will continue to make these three vaccines, this action will allow U.S.-based companies that supply these vaccine manufacturers to make their own decisions on which orders to fulfill first.&nbsp;<br><br>For all the progress we&#8217;ve made as a country, as the President reiterated yesterday afternoon, we have millions of Americans still in need of protection and communities at risk because of low vaccination rates.&nbsp;<br><br>Here&#8217;s the bottom line: The bottom line is that if you are unvaccinated, you are still at risk of getting seriously ill or spreading the disease to others.<br><br>To help get as many people vaccinated as we can by July 4th, we&#8217;re kicking off a month of action, mobilizing an all-of- America effort, including new commitments from childcare providers across the country to provide free drop-in childcare to allow parents to get vaccinated; extended hours of local pharmacies for vaccinations, including many pharmacies that will be open 24 hours every Friday starting next week; commitments from states in the private sector to incentivize vaccinations and celebrate our progress, including free beer for everyone over the age of 21, on July 4th, courtesy of Anheuser-Busch.<br><br>And the Vice President is leading a “We Can Do This” national vaccination tour.&nbsp; This national vaccination tour to key communities across the country will help reach millions of Americans who still need protection against the virus, highlight the ease of getting vaccinated, encourage vaccination, and energize and mobilize grassroots vaccine education and outreach efforts.<br>As the days get brighter and brighter at home, we&#8217;re focused on driving progress to help the pandemic &#8212; help end the pandemic around the globe.&nbsp; It&#8217;s both the right thing to do and an important step in protecting Americans by helping to stamp out the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has committed that the U.S. will be an arsenal for vaccines, and our work on vaccine supply is guided by a three-part approach:&nbsp;<br><br>First, having successfully secured enough supply of vaccine for Americans, we are donating surplus U.S. vaccine supply and encouraging other countries with surplus supplies to do the same.&nbsp; In March, the U.S. shared over 4 million doses of our AstraZeneca vaccine supply with Canada and Mexico.&nbsp; And the President has announced a U.S. commitment to sharing a total of 80 million doses by the end of June.&nbsp; This is five times the number of doses any other country has committed to sharing.&nbsp; And these 80 million doses represent 13 percent of the total vaccines produced by the United States by the end of this month.&nbsp;<br><br>We will continue to donate additional doses across the summer months as supply becomes available.&nbsp; But at the same time, we know that won&#8217;t be sufficient.&nbsp; So the second part of our approach is working with U.S. vaccine manufacturers to vastly increase vaccine supply for the rest of the world in a way that also creates jobs here at home.&nbsp; Driven by the aggressive actions that have been taken to accelerate manufacturing and production lines in the U.S., Pfizer and Moderna have already increased their capacity to produce vaccines for the world.&nbsp;<br><br>The third part of our approach will have us work with our partner nations and pharmaceutical companies and other manufacturers to facilitate the kind of global vaccine manufacturing and production capacity and capabilities that can not only help the world beat this pandemic, but also prepares the world to respond to potential future threats.&nbsp;<br><br>Today we&#8217;re outlining our framework for sharing with the world the first 25 million doses.&nbsp; To be clear, our approach is to ensure vaccines are delivered in a way that is equitable and follows the latest science and public health data.<br><br>Across the coming weeks, the administration will move as expeditiously as possible and work through regulatory requirements and logistical details to ensure safe and secure delivery of doses.<br><br>This is certainly a complex operational challenge but one that we take on and will get done.&nbsp; In fact, less than two weeks ago, the President committed to providing one million doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to the Republic of Korea.<br><br>After making a 2,000-mile journey to California, these one million doses are being loaded into a plane that will take off to the Republic of Korea this evening, carrying hope and bringing life-saving protection to the one million South Koreans who have already signed up to get a shot.&nbsp;<br><br>This is just the beginning.&nbsp; We expect a regular cadence of shipments around the world across the next several weeks.&nbsp; And in the weeks ahead, working with the world&#8217;s democracies, we will coordinate a multilateral effort, including through the G7, to combat and end the pandemic.<br><br>Now, let me turn it over to National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan.<br><br>Jake.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; As Jeff said, today we are announcing our plan for sharing the first 25 million U.S. vaccines with the world.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to briefly outline why we are sharing them, how we plan to share them, and where we will share them.<br><br>First, our goal in sharing our vaccines is in service of ending the pandemic globally.&nbsp; Our overarching aim is to get as many safe and effective vaccines to as many people as fast as possible.&nbsp; It&#8217;s as simple as that.&nbsp; We want to save lives and thwart variants that place all of us at risk.&nbsp; But perhaps most important: This is just the right thing to do.<br><br>Thanks to the ingenuity of American scientists and the resilience and commitment of the American people, we&#8217;re in a position to help others, so we will help others.&nbsp; And as the President has said, the United States will not use its vaccines to secure favors from other countries.<br><br>Next, I want to say a little bit about how we are sharing.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve received requests from all over the world, and a number of important factors went into our decision about how to allocate these first 25 million vaccines.&nbsp; These factors included achieving global coverage, responding to surges and other specific urgent situations and public health needs, and helping as many countries as possible who requested vaccines.<br><br>We&#8217;ve also decided to prioritize helping our neighbors.&nbsp; We made the decision to share at least 75 percent of these vaccines through COVAX.&nbsp; This will maximize the number of vaccines available equitably for all countries and will facilitate sharing with those most at risk.&nbsp; And we decided to share up to 25 percent of these vaccines for immediate needs and to help with surges around the world.&nbsp; We can share these 25 percent in a flexible way.<br><br>Finally, I want to talk a little bit about where we are sharing these first 25 million doses.&nbsp; We&#8217;re sharing them in a wide range of countries within Latin America and the Caribbean; South and Southeast Asia; and across Africa, in coordination with the African Union.&nbsp;<br><br>This includes prioritizing our neighbors here in our hemisphere, including countries like Guatemala and Colombia, Peru and Ecuador, and many others.&nbsp; It respects existing regional networks for vaccine sharing, like the platform of the African Union and African Centres for Disease Control and Prevention, and the regional public health agency in the Caribbean &#8212; CARPHA.&nbsp;<br><br>These networks will help decide where to allocate needed doses in regions with low vaccination rates and to those most at risk, including healthcare workers who haven&#8217;t yet gotten their shots.<br><br>Our approach also prioritizes South and Southeast Asia, including countries like India, Nepal, the Philippines, and others that are undergoing surges right now.&nbsp; It recognizes our closest neighbors, Canada and Mexico, which received our first shared vaccines; and friends like the Republic of Korea, where our military shares a command.&nbsp;&nbsp; And it prioritizes other partners around the world, including countries with low vaccination rates or dealing with urgent present crises, like the West Bank and Gaza, Ukraine, Kosovo, Iraq, Haiti, and others.<br><br>In the days ahead, we will coordinate closely with COVAX and with countries that will receive our vaccines.&nbsp; And as Jeff has said, this is only the beginning.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has committed to sharing doses on an ongoing basis, starting with 80 million by the end of June.&nbsp; We will continue to donate from our excess supply as that supply is delivered to us.&nbsp; We will work with our international partners to get ahead of the virus, to follow the science, and to help countries in crisis.&nbsp;<br><br>We also know that this won&#8217;t be enough to end or reduce the lifespan of the pandemic, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re working with allies and partners to expand the production of vaccines and raw materials, including here at home, as Jeff described, and by building capacity around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also working with our G7 partners on a larger effort to help end the pandemic so that the world&#8217;s democracies deliver for people everywhere.&nbsp; And we will have more to say about this next week when the G7 leaders meet in the UK.<br><br>We will continue to build on our existing health and health security efforts focused on stopping the spread of COVID-19: increasing vaccination, detecting outbreaks and variants, responding rapidly to flares, and critically recovering economically here at home and around the world.&nbsp; And we will do so in a way that strengthens our global public health institutions and our ability to come together as an international community to defeat not just this pandemic, but the next one and the one after that.<br><br>As President Biden said in May, this is a unique moment in history, and it requires American leadership, American science and ingenuity, American perseverance, and the world&#8217;s democracies to step up to the plate.&nbsp; Today, I&#8217;m proud to say that that effort is underway.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Now over to Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; It&#8217;s great to be back with you today.&nbsp; As always, let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.<br><br>Yesterday, CDC reported a little over 9,300 new cases of COVID-19. &nbsp;Our seven-day average is about 15,600 cases per day. &nbsp;This represents a decrease of more than 30 percent from our prior seven-day average. &nbsp;And, more importantly, it is a 94 percent decrease from the peak of COVID-19 cases we reported in January of this year. &nbsp;<br><br>This is the type of news I like to deliver and, certainly, these data are encouraging and uplifting as we battle this pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>In other good news, the seven-day average of new hospital admissions is about 2,750.&nbsp; That is a decrease of 83 percent in hospitalizations since January 9th of this year when we peaked at a seven-day average of almost 16,500 daily hospital admissions.<br><br>We can all agree these trends are going in the right direction.&nbsp;<br><br>And, finally, the seven-day average of daily deaths has also declined to a new low of 363 per day &#8212; a decrease of more than 16 percent from the last week.&nbsp;<br><br>As the administration kicks off its national month of action in the critical month of June, I want to highlight a specific population that we were hoping will join the tens of millions who have already been vaccinated, and that is adolescents.&nbsp;<br><br>In the month leading up to the recommendations of the Pfizer COVID-19 vaccines for teens and adolescents 12 and older, CDC observed troubling data regarding the hospitalizations of adolescents with COVID-19.&nbsp; More concerning were the number of adolescents admitted to the hospital who required treatment in the intensive care unit with mechanical ventilation.&nbsp;<br><br>Tomorrow, we will publish a report on this topic with more details in CDC’s Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report.&nbsp; And it is these findings within this publication &#8212; one that demonstrates the level of severe disease, even among youth, that are preventable, that force us to redouble our motivation to get our adolescents and young adults vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Last month, FDA authorized and CDC recommended a safe and effective vaccine for COVID-19 that can be used in adolescents to prevent disease and hospitalization.&nbsp; I strongly encourage parents to get their teens vaccinated, as I did mine.&nbsp;<br><br>If parents have questions or concerns, please talk with your child&#8217;s healthcare provider, your local department of public health, or your local pharmacist.&nbsp; And, of course, until teens are fully vaccinated, they should continue to wear masks and take precautions when around others who are not vaccinated, to protect themselves, their friends, family, and community.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, thank you, and I&#8217;ll turn things over to Dr.&nbsp; Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to spend just a minute or so just updating you in the arena of selected COVID-19 therapeutics.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you can see the slide, but the first slide that said “Selected Therapeutics” is broken up into three major components &#8212; just to remind you that the work that has been done over the last many months to a year has been three separate approaches: one, to target the virus itself &#8212; and, as you could see, the number of interventions listed there.&nbsp; The other is to moderate an aberrant inflammatory response, moderating the host.&nbsp; And the other adjunctive therapies, such as anticoagulants.&nbsp;<br><br>If we can move to the next slide, which has the red circle around the third bullet, that&#8217;s what I want to bring to the attention of the audience, and that is monoclonal antibodies, two of which &#8212; the Regeneron combination and Eli Lilly combination &#8212; have already been approved for EUA.<br><br>I&#8217;ve highlighted in blue another additional antibody made by GSK and Vir.&nbsp; And if you go to the next slide, six days ago, in a preprint server, some very interesting and exciting data has been published.&nbsp; And that is: A randomized placebo-controlled phase three trial of non-hospitalized patients with mild to moderate COVID-19 who are at high risk for the progression of their disease &#8212; close to 600 people &#8212; a single 500 milligram dose of the monoclonal antibody, sotrovimab &#8212; again, by GSK and Vir &#8212; reduced the risk of hospitalization or death by 85 percent, compared with the placebo.&nbsp;<br><br>It is well-tolerated and there are no safety signals identified.&nbsp; And, importantly, in the test tube, this antibody retains activity against multiple variants.&nbsp; So, what we really have now are three options within the arena of monoclonal antibodies &#8212; something that&#8217;s important for physicians to know that there is an important option for treating people early to prevent them from going to the hospital.&nbsp;<br><br>This has been granted an EUA, so it&#8217;s available for use, and we encourage physicians to at least consider this possibility as part of your therapeutic armamentarium.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll stop there, and back to you, Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Wonderful.&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we now open it up for a few questions?&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re running very short on time, so we&#8217;ll just take a couple of questions.&nbsp; Please keep to one question and on topic.&nbsp;<br><br>First, Josh Wingrove of Bloomberg.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Can you say &#8212;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; (Inaudible) take questions.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me?&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; I can hear you, Josh.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Jeff, can you speak a little bit to which specific vaccines will be sent in the 25 million?&nbsp; I assume it&#8217;s safe to say that the AstraZeneca doses remain under review.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, I think we&#8217;re working on some technical issues, and hopefully we are able to open it up for questions soon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jeff, let me know if you can hear me, please.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; I was just wondering if you can say which vaccines in particular will be sent among the 25 million?&nbsp; I assume that the AstraZeneca doses remain under review and are not available.&nbsp; Have you decided, or sorted, which will be the 25 million?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good question, and thank you for the question.&nbsp; That is correct.&nbsp; The AstraZeneca doses &#8212; the 60 million AstraZeneca doses &#8212; are awaiting FDA concurrence.&nbsp; So, the 25 million will be comprised of the three approved &#8212; EUA-approved authorized vaccines &#8212; some combination of Johnson &amp; Johnson, Pfizer, and Moderna.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Kaitlan Collins, CNN.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Jeff.&nbsp; (Inaudible) as part of this partnership with COVAX, my question is: Does the U.S. still have a final say where the doses (inaudible) COVAX go?&nbsp; Or is it COVAX making that decision?<br><br>And then, just to follow: When will these 25 million be distributed?&nbsp; And are you still confident the remaining 55 will be out by the end of June?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, Jake, why don’t I hand it to you on the first COVAX question?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, whether the U.S. still has final say on where the vaccines go, Jeff? &nbsp;Is that &#8212; was that the question?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; The question on COVAX &#8212; do you want to handle that?&nbsp; And then, I’ll handle the second piece.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We may be having some audio issues here.&nbsp; But as I understand it, the question was whether the United States still has the final say as to where the doses go that are being shared through COVAX.&nbsp; And the answer is that the U.S., working with COVAX, has taken &#8212;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; I’m not hearing Jake.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN &#8212; COVAX has a list of countries &#8212; the doses that are allocated to each of those countries, and we, the United States, have made selections against that list in coordination with them so that we will retain the say in terms of where they go.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, in the case of the African Union &#8212; we are sharing with the African Union, who will ultimately make &#8212; be making the determinations about how to allocate within Africa.&nbsp; And in the case of the Caribbean, we’ll be working closely with CARPHA, the public health authority in the Caribbean, who will be making some of the key determinations for where the doses are allocated.<br><br>But ultimately, the United States will have the authority to say, “The doses are going here, as opposed to there.” &nbsp;But that will be done in very close consultation and partnership with COVAX and, crucially, according to COVAX’s formula, and then using the COVAX logistics capacity and delivery capacity to ensure that these doses actually translate into shots in arms that helps save people&#8217;s lives.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, on the second part of the question.&nbsp; We are already sharing (inaudible) &#8212; (audio technical difficulties) &#8212; with Korea.&nbsp; As I mentioned earlier, those doses are in flight now.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve announced plans to share about 13 percent of the vaccines produced for the U.S. by the end of June.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the most of any nation, and that&#8217;s the 80 million.&nbsp; So, over the coming weeks, we&#8217;ll work to get those doses to countries and get shots in arms as soon as possible.<br><br>As we do so, we&#8217;ll work through logistics, like medical agencies, coordinating to ensure safety and regulatory information to share supply teams to ensure that we have the necessary needles, syringes, and alcohol pads; transportation teams to ensure proper temperature storage, prevent breakage, and ensure the vaccine immediately clears customs.&nbsp; So the process to export the first 25 million is underway in coordination with foreign governments.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President has committed, as we talked about earlier, to sharing 80 million doses by the end of June, and we will deliver on the President&#8217;s commitment of 80 million doses by the end of June.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; And sorry for the technical challenges.&nbsp; Sheryl at New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks for taking my call.&nbsp; I wonder if you could be a little bit more specific about the 25 percent of the doses that you are reserving for, you know, immediate use &#8212; the flexible doses.&nbsp; Where are those doses going?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Over to Jake.<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Technical difficulties persist.&nbsp; But the answer to the question of where the 25 percent of doses are going is: We will lay out, more specifically, the precise destination of those.&nbsp; The judgment we make about where those go is a combination of where there are specific urgent situations where partner countries are facing crises.&nbsp; And so, some examples of that include &#8212; a portion of those doses will go to India, which has, obviously, dealt with a surge, and we&#8217;ve seen the gripping images coming from that country.&nbsp; Some of them will go to the West Bank and Gaza, which has just, obviously, endured its own form of crisis over the course of the past month.&nbsp; And then there will be other destinations for the remaining doses, and we will lay that all out as those doses are prepared and then shipped.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; We’ll do one more question.&nbsp; To Zeke, at AP.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you all for (inaudible).&nbsp; Can you say where the doses are coming from?&nbsp; Are they coming from states’ inventory or the pool of federal supply right now (inaudible) manufacturers?&nbsp;<br><br>And then, for Jake: Can you explain how this is consistent with the President’s guidance that there would be “no strings attached” to these vaccines, that the U.S. is still maintaining ultimate say-so about where these doses go and reserving all of these (inaudible) bilateral, such as giving to allied troops rather than (inaudible).&nbsp; Why not just give it all to COVAX to be shared where it’s needed immediately?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, on the first question, the doses &#8212; the 25 million doses &#8212; are coming from the federal pool of supply.&nbsp; The doses that are at the states’ level, those states have ordered those doses and we&#8217;re working with those states to administer shots in arms so that the millions of Americans who are not getting vaccinated can get vaccinated as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>Jake, over to you.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, first and critically, the United States is not asking anything of any country to whom we&#8217;re giving doses.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not seeking to extract concessions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not extorting.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not imposing conditions, the way that other countries who are providing doses are doing.&nbsp; We are doing none of those things.&nbsp; These are doses that are being given &#8212; donated free and clear &#8212; to these countries for the sole purpose of improving the public health situation and helping end the pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>The Korea situation is unique.&nbsp; As the President said when President Moon visited, the animating purpose behind that is actually about the protection of American forces and the forces who serve alongside American forces: the Korean troops who are standing shoulder to shoulder with us in that country.&nbsp;<br><br>So it is a unique case and the kind of unique case for which we want to retain some flexibility, which is why we&#8217;re giving the majority &#8212; the 75 percent or more &#8212; of our doses through COVAX, but maintaining the capacity to allocate doses outside the COVAX formula as necessary.&nbsp; Korea is one case of that.&nbsp;<br><br>The West Bank and Gaza, as I mentioned, is another case where we&#8217;re not asking anything of the people of Gaza or the West Bank, but we feel that given what they are dealing with and the situation on the ground there, it is only right and proper and good for the United States to actually allocate some doses to that country.&nbsp; The same is true with some of the other allocations that we will make.&nbsp;<br><br>The President made a commitment to ensure that India received doses and giving them, not just an allocation under the regional portion of this, through COVAX, but an additional allocation from our discretionary portion was something that he wanted to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, the basic bottom line on this is that the United States is not doing this as some kind of back-and-forth deal, where we&#8217;re getting something for what we&#8217;re giving.&nbsp; We are giving these for a single purpose; it is the purpose of ending this pandemic.&nbsp; And we are doing so in a way consistent &#8212; we believe very strongly &#8212; with the public health requirements that will help hasten the end of the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we have time for one more question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, we&#8217;ll keep going.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s just go to Weijia from CBS.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; My question is actually for Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; As you watch this big push for vaccinations ahead of July 4th &#8212; and this morning on CBS you listed several reasons for why people may not be getting vaccinated yet &#8212; I&#8217;m wondering if you are making educated guesses or if you have any data and figures to show why some people are still holding out, especially in the South, where rates are relatively low.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Jeff, I think that Rochelle got kicked out by her computer.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, you know, I think the important thing is that all Americans have the opportunity to get vaccinated, and that means we need to make it even easier to get vaccinated; that we do answer people&#8217;s questions &#8212; people who have questions about the safety and effectiveness of the vaccine.&nbsp; And as we know, the vaccines &#8212; all three &#8212; are very effective and very safe, but we need to answer those questions.&nbsp;<br><br>The good news is confidence in the vaccines has grown across time, as people have neighbors and friends and faith leaders and doctors who have been vaccinated and advise them on their own decision.&nbsp; And the important thing here is that the most trusted messengers are local messengers, including doctors and faith leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>So we need to bring the vaccines to where people are and answer the questions that people have.&nbsp; And we are confident that more and more people will get vaccinated, leading up to the Fourth of July.&nbsp;<br><br>Should we try to do one more question, Kevin?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; I think we got to wrap up.&nbsp; But thank you, Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>11:43 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_3June2021_for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_3June2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Senior Advisor and Chief Spokesperson Symone Sanders on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Calls with Foreign Leaders on the Global Allocation Plan for the First 25 Million Doses of COVID-19 Vaccines</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-senior-advisor-and-chief-spokesperson-symone-sanders-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-calls-with-foreign-leaders-on-the-global-allocation-plan-for-the-first-25-million-doses-of-c/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala D. Harris spoke this morning to President Andres Manuel López Obrador of Mexico, President Alejandro Giammattei of Guatemala, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, and Prime Minister Keith Rowley, Chairman of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM). In four separate calls, the Vice President notified each of the leaders that the Biden-Harris Administration will begin&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala D. Harris spoke this morning to President Andres Manuel López Obrador of Mexico, President Alejandro Giammattei of Guatemala, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, and Prime Minister Keith Rowley, Chairman of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM). In four separate calls, the Vice President notified each of the leaders that the Biden-Harris Administration will begin sharing the first 25 million doses of COVID vaccines to their respective countries and others, as part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s framework for sharing at least 80 million vaccines globally by the end of June.<br><br>The Vice President reiterated that the Administration’s efforts are focused on achieving broad global coverage, responding to surges and other urgent situations and public health needs, and helping as many countries as possible who requested vaccines. The four leaders thanked the Vice President, and they agreed to continue working together to address COVID-19 and advance our mutual interests around the world.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-c/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC). I have determined that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order addressing the threat from securities investments that finance certain companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC).<br><br>I have determined that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 of November 12, 2020 (Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), including the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the PRC and its involvement in military, intelligence, and security research and development programs, and weapons and related equipment production under the PRC&#8217;s Military-Civil Fusion strategy.  In addition, I find that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC and the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse, constitute unusual and extraordinary threats, which have their source in whole or substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and I hereby expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 to address those threats. <br><br>I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.<br>    </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">     Sincerely,<br><br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People&#8217;s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/03/executive-order-on-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.) (NEA), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.) (NEA), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code,</p>



<p>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, find that additional steps are necessary to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 of November 12, 2020 (Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), including the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People&#8217;s Republic of China (PRC) and its involvement in military, intelligence, and security research and development programs, and weapons and related equipment production under the PRC&#8217;s Military-Civil Fusion strategy. &nbsp;In addition, I find that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC and the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse constitute unusual and extraordinary threats, which have their source in whole or substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States, and I hereby expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13959 to address those threats.</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby order as follows:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">1.</span>  Sections 1 through 5 of Executive Order 13959, as amended by Executive Order 13974 of January 13, 2021 (Amending Executive Order 13959 &#8212; Addressing the Threat From Securities Investments That Finance Communist Chinese Military Companies), are hereby replaced and superseded in their entirety to read as follows:</p>



<p>&#8220;<span style="text-decoration: underline">Section</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">1.</span> (a) The following activities by a United States person are prohibited: the purchase or sale of any publicly traded securities, or any publicly traded securities that are derivative of such securities or are designed to provide investment exposure to such securities, of any person listed in the Annex to this order or of any person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense:<br>          (i)   to operate or have operated in the defense and related materiel sector or the surveillance technology sector of the economy of the PRC; or<br>          (ii) to own or control, or to be owned or controlled by, directly or indirectly, a person who operates or has operated in any sector described in subsection (a)(i) of this section, or a person who is listed in the Annex to this order or who has otherwise been determined to be subject to the prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section.<br>     (b)  The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section shall take effect:<br>          (i)   beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 2, 2021, with respect to any person listed in the Annex to this order; <br>or<br>          (ii)  beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on the date that is 60 days after the date of the determination in subsection (a) of this section with respect to any person not listed in the Annex to this order.<br>     (c)  The purchase or sale of publicly traded securities described in subsection (a) of this section made solely to effect the divestment, in whole or in part, of such securities by a United States person is permitted prior to:<br>          (i)   12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 3, 2022, with respect to any person listed in the Annex to this order; or<br>          (ii)  12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on the date that is 365 days after the date of the determination in subsection (a) of this section with respect to any person not listed in the Annex to this order.<br>     (d)  The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or any license or permit granted before the date of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">2.</span>  (a)  Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>     (b)  Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">3.</span>  For the purposes of this order:<br>     (a)  the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;<br>     (b)  the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity;<br>     (c)  the term &#8220;publicly traded securities&#8221; includes any &#8220;security,&#8221; as defined in section 3(a)(10) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, Public Law 73–291 (as codified as amended at 15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(10)), denominated in any currency that trades on a securities exchange or through the method of trading that is commonly referred to as &#8220;over-the-counter,&#8221; in any jurisdiction; and<br>     (d)  the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">4.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.  The Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.  All executive departments and agencies (agencies) of the United States shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to carry out the provisions of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">5.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to submit recurring and final reports to the Congress on the national emergency declared in this order, consistent with section 401(c) of the NEA (50 U.S.C. 1641(c)) and section 204(c) of IEEPA (50 U.S.C. 1703(c)).</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">6.</span>  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense, is hereby authorized to determine that circumstances no longer warrant the application of the prohibitions in section 1(a) of this order with respect to a person listed in the Annex to this order, and to take necessary action to give effect to that determination.&#8221;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">2.</span>  The Annex to Executive Order 13959 is replaced and superseded in its entirety by the Annex to this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">3.</span>  Section 6 of Executive Order 13959 is amended to replace &#8220;Sec. 6.&#8221; with &#8220;Sec. 7.&#8221;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">4.</span>  Executive Order 13974 is hereby revoked in its entirety.  The Secretary of the Treasury and the heads of agencies shall take all necessary steps to rescind any orders or prohibitions issued prior to the date of this order implementing or enforcing Executive Order 13974 or the versions of sections 1 through 5 of Executive Order 13959 replaced and superseded by section 1 of this order.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec.</span> <span style="text-decoration: underline">5.</span>  (a)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>     (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>     (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>          (b)  This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>          (c)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">  <br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>   June 3, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><span style="text-decoration: underline">Annex</span><br>AERO ENGINE CORPORATION OF CHINA<br><br>AEROSPACE CH UAV CO., LTD<br><br>AEROSPACE COMMUNICATIONS HOLDINGS GROUP COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AEROSUN CORPORATION<br><br>ANHUI GREATWALL MILITARY INDUSTRY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIATION INDUSTRY CORPORATION OF CHINA, LTD.<br><br>AVIC AVIATION HIGH-TECHNOLOGY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC HEAVY MACHINERY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC JONHON OPTRONIC TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>AVIC SHENYANG AIRCRAFT COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>AVIC XI&#8217;AN AIRCRAFT INDUSTRY GROUP COMPANY LTD.<br><br>CHANGSHA JINGJIA MICROELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA ACADEMY OF LAUNCH VEHICLE TECHNOLOGY<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE SCIENCE AND INDUSTRY CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA AEROSPACE TIMES ELECTRONICS CO., LTD<br><br>CHINA AVIONICS SYSTEMS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA COMMUNICATIONS CONSTRUCTION COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA COMMUNICATIONS CONSTRUCTION GROUP (LIMITED)<br><br>CHINA ELECTRONICS CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA ELECTRONICS TECHNOLOGY GROUP CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA GENERAL NUCLEAR POWER CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA MARINE INFORMATION ELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA MOBILE COMMUNICATIONS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA MOBILE LIMITED<br><br>CHINA NATIONAL NUCLEAR CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA NATIONAL OFFSHORE OIL CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA NORTH INDUSTRIES GROUP CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA NUCLEAR ENGINEERING CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA RAILWAY CONSTRUCTION CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SATELLITE COMMUNICATIONS CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA SHIPBUILDING INDUSTRY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SHIPBUILDING INDUSTRY GROUP POWER COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>CHINA SOUTH INDUSTRIES GROUP CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA SPACESAT CO., LTD.<br><br>CHINA STATE SHIPBUILDING CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA TELECOM CORPORATION LIMITED<br><br>CHINA TELECOMMUNICATIONS CORPORATION<br><br>CHINA UNICOM (HONG KONG) LIMITED<br><br>CHINA UNITED NETWORK COMMUNICATIONS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CNOOC LIMITED<br><br>COSTAR GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>CSSC OFFSHORE &amp; MARINE ENGINEERING (GROUP) COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>FUJIAN TORCH ELECTRON TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>GUIZHOU SPACE APPLIANCE CO., LTD<br><br>HANGZHOU HIKVISION DIGITAL TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>HUAWEI INVESTMENT &amp; HOLDING CO., LTD.<br><br>HUAWEI TECHNOLOGIES CO., LTD.<br><br>INNER MONGOLIA FIRST MACHINERY GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>INSPUR GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>JIANGXI HONGDU AVIATION INDUSTRY CO., LTD.<br><br>NANJING PANDA ELECTRONICS COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>NORTH NAVIGATION CONTROL TECHNOLOGY CO., LTD.<br><br>PANDA ELECTRONICS GROUP CO., LTD.<br><br>PROVEN GLORY CAPITAL LIMITED<br><br>PROVEN HONOUR CAPITAL LIMITED<br><br>SEMICONDUCTOR MANUFACTURING INTERNATIONAL CORPORATION<br><br>SHAANXI ZHONGTIAN ROCKET TECHNOLOGY COMPANY LIMITED<br><br>ZHONGHANG ELECTRONIC MEASURING INSTRUMENTS COMPANY LIMITED</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments that Finance Certain Companies of the People’s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/fact-sheet-executive-order-addressing-the-threat-from-securities-investments-that-finance-certain-companies-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 17:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in E.O. 13959 of November 12, 2020 with respect to the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China (PRC). President Biden also expanded the scope of this national emergency by finding that the use&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in E.O. 13959 of November 12, 2020 with respect to the threat posed by the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China (PRC). President Biden also expanded the scope of this national emergency by finding that the use of Chinese surveillance technology outside the PRC, as well as the development or use of Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuses, constitute unusual and extraordinary threats. This E.O. allows the United States to prohibit – in a targeted and scoped manner – U.S. investments in Chinese companies that undermine the security or democratic values of the United States and our allies.<br><br>Specifically, the E.O. the President is signing today will:<br><br><strong>Solidify and strengthen a previous E.O to prohibit U.S. investments in the military-industrial complex of the People’s Republic of China:&nbsp;</strong>This E.O. will amend E.O. 13959 by creating a sustainable and strengthened framework for imposing prohibitions on investments in Chinese defense and surveillance technology firms. The E.O. prohibits United States persons from engaging in the purchase or sale of any publicly traded securities of any person listed in the Annex to the E.O. or determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, and, as the Secretary of the Treasury deems appropriate, the Secretary of Defense:</p>



<ul><li>To operate or have operated in the defense and related materiel sector or the surveillance technology sector of the economy of the PRC; or</li><li>To own or control, or to be owned or controlled by, directly or indirectly, a person who operates or has operated in any sector described above, or a person who is listed in the Annex to this E.O. or who has otherwise been determined to be subject to the prohibitions in this E.O.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensure that U.S. investments are not supporting Chinese companies that undermine the security or values of the United States and our allies</strong>: This E.O. prevents U.S. investment from supporting the Chinese defense sector, while also expanding the U.S. Government’s ability to address the threat of Chinese surveillance technology firms that contribute — both inside and outside China — to the surveillance of religious or ethnic minorities or otherwise facilitate repression and serious human rights abuses. It signals that the Administration will not hesitate to prevent U.S. capital from flowing into the PRC’s defense and related materiel sector, including companies that support the PRC’s military, intelligence, and other security research and development programs; or into Chinese companies that develop or use Chinese surveillance technology to facilitate repression or serious human rights abuse.&nbsp; Tackling these challenges head-on is consistent with the Biden Administration’s commitment to protecting core U.S. national security interests and democratic values, and the Administration will continue to update the list of PRC entities as appropriate.&nbsp; At the same time, the E.O.’s prohibitions are intentionally targeted and scoped.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>The President listed the following 59 entities as subject to the E.O.’s prohibitions. </strong>The prohibitions against the entities listed in the Annex to this E.O. shall take effect beginning at 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 2, 2021. The U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) will also list these 59 entities on its new Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List (NS-CMIC List).<br><br><strong><em><u>Defense and Related Materiel Sector of the Economy of the PRC</u></em></strong><strong><em>:</em></strong><br>Aero Engine Corporation of China; Aerospace CH UAV Co., Ltd; Aerospace Communications Holdings Group Company Limited; Aerosun Corporation; Anhui Greatwall Military Industry Company Limited; Aviation Industry Corporation of China, Ltd.; AVIC Aviation High-Technology Company Limited; AVIC Heavy Machinery Company Limited; AVIC Jonhon Optronic Technology Co., Ltd.; AVIC Shenyang Aircraft Company Limited; AVIC Xi’An Aircraft Industry Group Company Ltd.; Changsha Jingjia Microelectronics Company Limited China Academy of Launch Vehicle Technology; China Aerospace Science and Industry Corporation Limited; China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation; China Aerospace Times Electronics Co., Ltd; China Avionics Systems Company Limited; China Communications Construction Company Limited; China Electronics Technology Group Corporation; China General Nuclear Power Corporation; China Marine Information Electronics Company Limited; China Mobile Communications Group Co., Ltd.; China National Nuclear Corporation; China National Offshore Oil Corporation; China North Industries Group Corporation Limited; China Nuclear Engineering Corporation Limited; China Railway Construction Corporation Limited; China Satellite Communications Co., Ltd.; China Shipbuilding Industry Company Limited; China Shipbuilding Industry Group Power Company Limited; China South Industries Group Corporation; China Spacesat Co., Ltd.; China State Shipbuilding Corporation Limited; China Telecommunications Corporation; China United Network Communications Group Co., Ltd.; Costar Group Co., Ltd.; CSSC Offshore &amp; Marine Engineering (Group) Company Limited; Fujian Torch Electron Technology Co., Ltd.; Guizhou Space Appliance Co., Ltd; Hangzhou Hikvision Digital Technology Co., Ltd.; Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd.; Inner Mongolia First Machinery Group Co., Ltd.; Inspur Group Co., Ltd.; Jiangxi Hongdu Aviation Industry Co., Ltd.; Nanjing Panda Electronics Company Limited; North Navigation Control Technology Co., Ltd.; Panda Electronics Group Co., Ltd.; Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corporation; Shaanxi Zhongtian Rocket Technology Company Limited; and Zhonghang Electronic Measuring Instruments Company Limited.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><em><u>Surveillance Technology Sector of the Economy of the PRC</u></em></strong><strong><em>:</em></strong><br>Hangzhou Hikvision Digital Technology Co., Ltd. and Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd.<br><br><strong><em><u>Own or Control, or Owned or Controlled by, Directly or Indirectly, a Person Who Operates or Has Operated in at Least One of These Two Sectors of the PRC Economy, or a Person Who Is Listed in the Annex to the E.O.:</u></em></strong><br>China Communications Construction Group (Limited); China Electronics Corporation; China Mobile Limited; China Telecom Corporation Limited; China Unicom (Hong Kong) Limited; CNOOC Limited; Huawei Investment &amp; Holding Co., Ltd.; Panda Electronics Group Co., Ltd.; Proven Glory Capital Limited; and Proven Honour Capital Limited.<br><br>For information concerning the process for seeking removal from any OFAC list, including the NS-CMIC List, please refer to OFAC’s Frequently Asked Question 897 at <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/faqs/897">https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/faqs/897</a>.&nbsp; Additional information regarding sanctions programs administered by OFAC can be found at <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/sanctions-programs-and-country-information">https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/financial-sanctions/sanctions-programs-and-country-information</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin Gantz</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-israeli-minister-of-defense-benjamin-gantz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin “Benny” Gantz to discuss recent developments in the region and continue the consultations between the United States and Israel on regional security issues. Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s right to defend itself and commitment to strengthening all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Israeli Minister of Defense Benjamin “Benny” Gantz to discuss recent developments in the region and continue the consultations between the United States and Israel on regional security issues. Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s unwavering support for Israel’s right to defend itself and commitment to strengthening all aspects of the U.S.-Israel security partnership, including support for the Iron Dome System. They exchanged views on the current situation in Gaza and Mr. Sullivan highlighted the importance of ensuring that immediate humanitarian aid is able to reach the people of Gaza. They also discussed their common interest in steps to enhance stability, peace, and security not just for Israelis and Palestinians, but across the entire region. They shared their concerns about the threat posed by Iran’s aggressive behavior in the Middle East and expressed their determination to counter these threats. They agreed that the United States and Israel would remain closely engaged in the weeks ahead to advance their strategic priorities in the region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Fight Against Corruption</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/03/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-fight-against-corruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 8:47 A.M. EDT&#160;MODERATOR: Good morning, everyone, from the National Security Council at the White House. I would like to welcome our participants to an on-background conference call to discuss a forthcoming announcement by the White House related to the fight against corruption.&#160;Today we are joined by [senior administration official], as well as [senior&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:47 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR: Good morning, everyone, from the National Security Council at the White House. I would like to welcome our participants to an on-background conference call to discuss a forthcoming announcement by the White House related to the fight against corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today we are joined by [senior administration official], as well as [senior administration official]. We will begin with remarks from [senior administration official], and then we&#8217;ll open it up for a question-and-answer session.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a reminder, today&#8217;s briefing is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” And the call content and the factsheet that we have not circulated yet but we will circulate at the conclusion of the call will be embargoed until they&#8217;re released by the White House later today.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I will turn it over to our senior administration official for introductory remarks.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Great. Thanks. Hi, everybody. Good morning and thanks for joining the call today. I am really excited to be speaking to all of you about the President&#8217;s anti-corruption agenda in advance of our rollout later this morning of a national security study memorandum &#8212; that&#8217;s NSSM &#8212; on the fight against corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s worth noting that this is the first national security study memorandum of the administration, so it&#8217;ll come out as “NSM-1.” I don&#8217;t want to get hung up on the bureaucratic language of all of that, but the point is the memorandum is important because it&#8217;ll serve as formal and public direction from President Biden that he expects all relevant federal departments and agencies to up their anti-corruption game in very specific ways. And when you see the NSSM yourselves, you&#8217;ll see the specificity in the document itself.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with the memorandum, President Biden is formally establishing the fight against corruption as a core national security interest of the United States. That was a commitment that he made during the campaign. And his pledge was that he would prioritize anti-corruption efforts and bring additional transparency to the U.S. and international financial systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that&#8217;s what we are embarked on, and the memorandum also speaks to our focus on delivering a foreign policy that benefits the American people, and particularly the middle class.<br>&nbsp;<br>So what the NSSM does is it directs the U.S. government to review and send to President Biden a report and recommendations in 200 days on how the government and its partners can modernize, coordinate, and further resource efforts to better fight corruption, tackle illicit finance, hold corrupt actors accountable, and build international partnerships. So it&#8217;s really the broadest span of what each of our federal departments and agencies does on anti-corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re really confident that implementation of this directive is going to lead to new and bold and decisive actions to combat corruption around the world. It, of course, builds upon much that we&#8217;re already doing &#8212; and I&#8217;m happy to speak to some of that agenda right now &#8212; but this is very much going to accelerate and prioritize that agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with that, why don&#8217;t I leave it there and we&#8217;ll take a few questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Hi, guys. Thank you for doing this. I just &#8212; my first question is simply, you know, can you talk a little bit about some of the existing efforts under the Biden administration at the various agencies to make corruption a priority? Because I know this has sort of been in the works for a while, so it&#8217;s not like they&#8217;re starting from scratch.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, thanks for that. So, that’s exactly right. We are very much hitting the ground running on this agenda, so let me just kind of give a few wave tops in terms what different departments and agencies are already doing that we expect to elevate with the NSSM today.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, some on the line may be familiar with the Corporate Transparency Act &#8212; that’s the law that Congress passed in last year’s National Defense Authorization Act that directs the Treasury Department to establish what’s called a “beneficial ownership registry” that effectively bars illicit assets from hiding the proceedings of corruption behind anonymous shell companies. So, Treasury is moving out on making that registry a reality. It&#8217;s a massive undertaking.<br>&nbsp;<br>And among other things, in his budget request, the President asked Congress to increase funding for this work by roughly 50 percent &#8212; 60-odd million dollars above what was enacted last year. So that really gave an early preview of how we&#8217;re looking to transform what Treasury does in terms of making sure that law enforcement is able to view the proceeds of corruption such that illicit actors can&#8217;t hide behind anonymity.<br>&nbsp;<br>Likewise, Treasury is building off of what&#8217;s already been done to limit the ability of illicit actors to hide behind anonymity. In terms of residential real estate, we have seen several instances over past years in which the proceeds of corruption have been funneled through shell companies and wound up in major metropolitan areas in the United States to offshore those ill-gotten gains, and so we&#8217;re going to be taking additional steps to make sure that that doesn&#8217;t happen in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>And across the board, we&#8217;re looking at analyzing the need for additional reforms to close loopholes in the entire regulatory regime that deals with corruption and illicit finance.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the Department of Justice side, some may be familiar with their Kleptocracy Asset Recovery Initiative. This initiative has really helped to make the United States a global leader in terms of recovery and return of stolen assets. In the &#8212; in the past two years, since 2019 alone, these asset recovery efforts have led to the transfer of more than $1.5 billion to countries that have been harmed by corruption.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, on the State and USAID side, I think you&#8217;ve already seen significant statements by Secretary Blinken and Administrator Power on increasing their anti-corruption work. Stay tuned. I think there are going to be more announcements out of USAID soon, but we&#8217;re looking across the board to elevate our anti-corruption work in all of our bilateral context, as well as in multilateral fora, such as the G7 and United Nations.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that’s a little taste of, across departments, what we expect to be working on or accelerating ongoing work in the months to come.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you for taking the time. You know, the previous administration took something of a hands-off approach with corruption or with &#8212; would have them &#8212; you know, a transactional relationship, where they would essentially say, “We won’t worry about what&#8217;s going on in your country if you will work with us on these things that we need to work on.” And I&#8217;m wondering if, in any sense, this is meant to send a signal to the world that the U.S. does care about corruption again. Is there any, sort of, like, response to the past in this?<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, ahead of Vice President Harris&#8217;s trip to Latin America, are there any corruption measures associated with that, or any, sort of, additional push related to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: I&#8217;m not going to characterize the views of the prior administration, but I would say, to your point: The essence of the memorandum we&#8217;re going to release today is that the U.S. government is placing the anti-corruption plight at the center of its foreign policy, so we very much want to prioritize this work across the board.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the Vice President&#8217;s trip, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any announcements that are going to be made on the trip, but I can say that anti-corruption in the region is a major focus for the administration and will be a focus of all of her conversations while she&#8217;s traveling.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for doing this. As you know, anti-corruption activists periodically urge the U.S. government to use its various assets and capabilities, including the intelligence community, to expose specific cases of corruption overseas, to name and shame corrupt officials &#8212; and the arguments they make are familiar &#8212; but also include not only, you know, a deterrent to corruption, but also a possible contribution to the promotion of democracy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Does the does the memorandum &#8212; does the program include any component that connects with that?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;What I can say on that front is that the memorandum includes components of the intelligence community. So, the work on that front, in part, remains to be seen, but they are included &#8212; the Director of National Intelligence and Central Intelligence Agency.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so we&#8217;re just going to be looking at all of the tools in our disposal to make sure that we identify corruption where it&#8217;s happening and take appropriate policy responses.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;ll take the opportunity to mention that we&#8217;re also going to be using this effort to think about what more we can do to bolster other actors that are out in the world exposing corruption and bringing it to light.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, of course, the U.S. government has its own internal methods, but, largely, the way that corruption is exposed is through the work of investigative journalists and investigative NGOs.<br>&nbsp;<br>The U.S. government &#8212; to my point earlier, in terms of the support we&#8217;re already providing &#8212; in some instances provides support to these actors. And we&#8217;ll be looking at what more we can do on that front as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does the word “support” mean in that context?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Well, sometimes it boils down to foreign assistance. There are lines of assistance that have jumpstarted investigatory journalism organizations. What comes to my mind most immediately is OCCRP, as well as foreign assistance that goes to NGOs, ultimately, that do investigative work on anti-corruption, as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, good morning. Thank you for doing this. My question is to ask you: How are you going to engage with international allies to combat the impact of corruption coming from Latin American countries into the United States? For example, Venezuela or the Northern Triangle, as my colleague mentioned before. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;So, as I mentioned earlier, the anti-corruption agenda will be front and center in the Vice President&#8217;s upcoming trip. And, across the board, we are engaging through every relevant multilateral body on this agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>And much of that &#8212; again, we&#8217;re not we&#8217;re not necessarily creating any of that work from scratch, but we are hoping to accelerate and elevate it, and that includes in the Western Hemisphere. But maybe [senior administration official] wants to jump in and say a little bit more on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks. You know, I think the general &#8212; underscoring what [senior administration official] just said &#8212; you know, working closely with our allies and partners includes engaging with civil society and investigative journalists, but also through our multinational and multilateral partnerships in the G7 and G20.<br>&nbsp;<br>This has been a big focus as well for the UK during their G7 presidency, to focus on working together on combating corruption. And so we have started those processes already, and I think you will see a lot more, particularly in our own backyard in the Western Hemisphere.<br>&nbsp;<br>A big indication is the Vice President&#8217;s trip &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s her first international trip. She&#8217;ll be going out there and discussing these issues. And as [senior administration official] mentioned earlier, anticorruption will be a key part of her trip there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi. So, [senior administration official], in your intro and in a couple of answers, you’ve referred to “illicit finance” and the danger of people profiting from corruption and being able to hide those profits through anonymity. Are you talking here about cryptocurrency? And if so, is this part of a larger discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we&#8217;ve seen the use of cryptocurrency, the risk of cryptocurrency for illicit purposes in the ransomware attacks, for example. And there are certainly growing calls now for the administration to crack down on cryptocurrency and its use in illegal means. Is that what you meant to refer to, and is that where this is going?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, thanks. We&#8217;ll certainly be looking at the impact of cryptocurrency as a means of illicit finance, but by no means was &#8212; were my remarks limited to crypto. We&#8217;ve seen, over many years, how corruption oversea- &#8212; the proceeds of corruption overseas make their way into the U.S. and international financial systems through anonymity.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this isn&#8217;t in any way limited to new technologies like crypto, but certainly as we think about the regulatory regime &#8212; the Bank Secrecy Act that governs much of this agenda, in terms of illicit finance &#8212; we will be asking for ideas around how we might want to modernize that regime to deal with issues like crypto, certainly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning and thanks for doing this. I want –- I think, as you mentioned, this is the first memorandum that we saw before sanctions against corruption yesterday. And there were sanctions against Bulgarian individuals. But also, we know that bad actors were able to survive despite sanctions everywhere, whether they are U.S. sanctions or, let’s say, international sanctions. Now, what tools are you planning to use? And let’s say you are using sanctions again &#8212; how you would use the sanctions as a tool without affecting an entire (inaudible) population? Let&#8217;s say, I give you an example here: Lebanon, let’s say.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Sure, thanks for that. So, this effort is really going to be across the board. And so, thinking about how we can better use sanctions to address corruption is definitely going to be part of the toolkit that we seek to emphasize. But sanctions are not the only tool in our toolkit.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I&#8217;ve been speaking to, we&#8217;re looking to make significant systemic changes to the regulatory structure that governs illicit finance. We&#8217;re looking to increase the use of law enforcement tools to go after corrupt actors. We&#8217;re looking to improve upon U.S. foreign assistance as a tool and increase the role that anticorruption plays in our day-to-day diplomatic work in bilateral engagements, in multilateral fora.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thinking about how sanctions are going to impact our anti-corruption agenda will be part of this conversation, but in no way will it be limited to sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>9:07 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Global Vaccine Distribution</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/03/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-global-vaccine-distribution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 15:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the United States continues our efforts to get every eligible American vaccinated and fight COVID-19 here at home, we also recognize that ending this pandemic means ending it everywhere. As long as this pandemic is raging anywhere in the world, the American people will still be vulnerable. And the United States is committed to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As the United States continues our efforts to get every eligible American vaccinated and fight COVID-19 here at home, we also recognize that ending this pandemic means ending it everywhere. As long as this pandemic is raging anywhere in the world, the American people will still be vulnerable. And the United States is committed to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts that we have demonstrated at home.<br><br>Already the United States has committed $4 billion to support COVAX, and we have launched partnerships to boost global capacity to manufacture more vaccines. My administration supports efforts to temporarily waive intellectual property rights for COVID-19 vaccines because, over time, we need more companies producing life-saving doses of proven vaccines that are shared equitably. We have already shared more than 4 million doses of vaccine with Canada and Mexico, and last month, I announced that, by the end of June, the United States will share 80 million doses of our vaccine supply with the world.<br><br>Today, we’re providing more detail on how we will allocate the first 25 million of those vaccines to lay the ground for increased global coverage and to address real and potential surges, high burdens of disease, and the needs of the most vulnerable countries. At least 75 percent of these doses—nearly 19 million—will be shared through COVAX, including approximately 6 million doses for Latin America and the Caribbean, approximately 7 million for South and Southeast Asia, and approximately 5 million for Africa, working in coordination with the African Union and the Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention. The remaining doses, just over 6 million, will be shared directly with countries experiencing surges, those in crisis, and other partners and neighbors, including Canada, Mexico, India, and the Republic of Korea.<br><br>We are sharing these doses not to secure favors or extract concessions. We are sharing these vaccines to save lives and to lead the world in bringing an end to the pandemic, with the power of our example and with our values. And we will continue to follow the science and to work in close cooperation with our democratic partners to coordinate a multilateral effort, including through the G7.&nbsp;<br><br>Strong American leadership is essential to ending this pandemic now, and to strengthening global health security for tomorrow—to better prevent, detect, and respond to the next threat. The United States will be the world’s arsenal of vaccines in our shared fight against this virus. In the days to come, as we draw on the experience of distributing the vaccine doses announced today, we will have more details to provide about how future doses will be shared. And we will continue to do all we can to build a world that is safer and more secure against the threat of infectious disease.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
