<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:40:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>G7 Leaders’ Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/g7-leaders-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the Leaders of the G7, met today in Brussels at the invitation of the German G7 Presidency, to further strengthen our cooperation in light of Russia’s unjustifiable, unprovoked and illegal aggression and President Putin’s war of choice against independent and sovereign Ukraine. We will stand with the government and people of Ukraine. We are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<ol><li>We, the Leaders of the G7, met today in Brussels at the invitation of the German G7 Presidency, to further strengthen our cooperation in light of Russia’s unjustifiable, unprovoked and illegal aggression and President Putin’s war of choice against independent and sovereign Ukraine. We will stand with the government and people of Ukraine.<br></li><li>We are united in our resolve to restore peace and stability and uphold international law. Following the United Nations General Assembly resolution on<br>2 March 2022, we will continue to stand with the overwhelming majority of the international community, in condemning Russia’s military aggression and the suffering and loss of life it continues to cause.<br></li><li>We remain appalled by and condemn the devastating attacks on the Ukrainian population and civilian infrastructure, including hospitals and schools. We welcome the investigations of international mechanisms, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court. We will work together to support the gathering of evidence of war crimes. The siege of Mariupol and other Ukrainian cities, and the denial of humanitarian access by Russian military forces are unacceptable. Russian forces must immediately provide for safe pathways to other parts of Ukraine, as well as humanitarian aid to be delivered to Mariupol and other besieged cities.<br></li><li>The Russian leadership is obligated to immediately comply with the order of the International Court of Justice to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine, without any further delay. We also urge Russia to withdraw its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine.<br></li><li>We further call upon the Belarusian authorities to avoid further escalation and to refrain from using their military forces against Ukraine. Moreover, we urge all countries not to give military or other assistance to Russia to help continue its aggression in Ukraine. We will be vigilant regarding any such assistance.<br> </li><li>We will spare no efforts to hold President Putin and the architects and supporters of this aggression, including the Lukashenko regime in Belarus, accountable for their actions. To this end, we will continue to work together, along with our allies and partners around the world.<br></li><li>We underline our resolve to impose severe consequences on Russia, including by fully implementing the economic and financial measures we already imposed. We will continue to cooperate closely, including by engaging other governments on adopting similar restrictive measures to those already imposed by G7 members and on refraining from evasion, circumvention and backfilling that seek to undercut or mitigate the effects of our sanctions. We task the relevant Ministers in a focused initiative to monitor the full implementation of sanctions and to coordinate responses related to evasive measures, including regarding gold transactions by the Central Bank of Russia. We stand ready to apply additional measures as required, continuing to act in unity as we do so. We commend those partners who have aligned with us in these efforts.<br></li><li>Russia’s attack has already risked the safety and security of nuclear sites in Ukraine. Russian military activities are creating extreme risks for the population and the environment, with the potential for catastrophic result. Russia must comply with its international obligations and refrain from any activity that imperils nuclear sites, allowing unhindered control by the Ukrainian authorities, as well as full access by and cooperation with the International Atomic Energy Agency.<br></li><li>We warn against any threat of the use of chemical, biological and nuclear weapons or related materials. We recall Russia’s obligations under the international treaties to which it is a signatory, and which protect us all. In this regard, we categorically denounce Russia’s malicious and completely unfounded disinformation campaign against Ukraine, a state in full compliance with international non-proliferation agreements. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.<br> </li><li>We are resolved in our support to the Ukrainian people in their heroic resistance to Russia’s unjustifiable and illegal aggression. We will step up our support to Ukraine and neighbouring countries. We thank all those who are already providing humanitarian aid to Ukraine and ask others to join. We will furthermore collaborate in our efforts to bolster democratic resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighbouring countries.<br></li><li>We will continue efforts to support Ukraine in defending its networks against cyber incidents. In preparation for any Russian malicious cyber response to the actions we have taken, we are taking steps to increase the resilience of the infrastructure in our respective nations by strengthening our coordinated cyber defences and improving our shared awareness of cyber threats. We will also work to hold accountable those actors that engage in destructive, disruptive, or destabilising activities in cyberspace.<br></li><li>We further commend neighbouring states for their solidarity and humanity in welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals from Ukraine. We highlight the need to further increase international assistance to countries neighbouring Ukraine, and, as a concrete contribution to this end, underline our commitment to receiving, protecting, and supporting refugees and displaced persons as a consequence of the conflict. We thus all stand ready to welcome them on our territories. We will take further steps to broaden our support to Ukraine and neighbouring countries.<br></li><li>We are concerned by the escalating and reinforced repression against the Russian people and the increasingly hostile rhetoric of the Russian leadership, including against ordinary citizens. We deplore the Russian leadership’s attempt to deprive Russian citizens of access to unbiased information through censorship, and denounce its malicious disinformation campaigns, which we will not leave unaddressed. We express our support to those Russian and Belarusian citizens standing up against the unjustified war of aggression against their close neighbour Ukraine. The world sees them.<br></li><li>The people of Russia must know that we hold no grievances against them. It is President Putin, his government and supporters, including the Lukashenko regime in Belarus, who are imposing this war and its consequences on Russians and it is their decision that besmirches the history of the Russian people.<br></li><li>We are taking further steps to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end. At the same time, we will ensure secure alternative and sustainable supplies, and act in solidarity and close coordination in the case of possible supply disruptions. We commit to actively support countries willing to phase out their dependency on Russian gas, oil and coal imports. We call on oil and gas producing countries to act in a responsible manner and to increase deliveries to international markets, noting that OPEC has a key role to play. We will work with them and all partners to ensure stable and sustainable global energy supplies. This crisis reinforces our determination to meet the goals of the Paris agreement and of the Glasgow climate pact and limit the rise in global temperatures to 1.5°C, by accelerating reduction of our reliance on fossil fuels and our transition to clean energy. <br></li><li>We stand in solidarity with our partners who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. His decision is putting the global economic recovery at risk, undermines the resilience of global value chains and will have severe impacts on the most fragile countries. We call on the international community to take action by fully recognising Russia’s responsibility and protecting the most vulnerable countries, with the support of international and regional institutions.<br></li><li>More immediately, President Putin’s war places global food security under increased pressure. We recall that the implementation of our sanctions against Russia takes into account the need to avoid impact on global agricultural trade. We remain determined to monitor the situation closely and do what is necessary to prevent and respond to the evolving global food security crisis. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food security, and build resilience in the agriculture sector in line with climate and environment goals. We will address potential agricultural production and trade disruptions, in particular in vulnerable countries. We commit to provide a sustainable food supply in Ukraine and support continued Ukrainian production efforts.<br></li><li>We will work with and step up our collective contribution to relevant international institutions including the World Food Programme (WFP), in parallel with Multilateral Development Banks and International Financial Institutions, to provide support to countries with acute food insecurity. We call for an extraordinary session of the Council of the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) to address the consequences on world food security and agriculture arising from the Russian aggression against Ukraine. We call on all participants of the Agriculture Markets Information System (AMIS) to continue to share information and explore options to keep prices under control, including making stocks available, in particular to the WFP. We will avoid export bans and other trade-restrictive measures, maintain open and transparent markets, and call on others to do likewise, consistent with World Trade Organization (WTO) rules, including WTO notification requirements.<br></li><li>International organisations and multilateral fora should no longer conduct their activities with Russia in a business as usual manner. We will work closely with our partners to act as appropriate, based on shared interests, as well as rules and regulations of respective institutions.</li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The White&#160;House Announces 2022 Springtime&#160;Events</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/the-white-house-announces-2022-springtime-events/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 17:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today,&#160;the President and First Lady&#160;are pleased&#160;to announce plans for the following springtime events: Spring Garden Tours and the White House Easter Egg Roll.&#160; &#160; SPRING GARDEN TOURS&#160; The President and First Lady will continue the annual tradition of opening the White House gardens and South Grounds to members of the public for Spring Garden Tours.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today,&nbsp;the President and First Lady&nbsp;are pleased&nbsp;to announce plans for the following springtime events: Spring Garden Tours and the White House Easter Egg Roll.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>SPRING GARDEN TOURS&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The President and First Lady will continue the annual tradition of opening the White House gardens and South Grounds to members of the public for Spring Garden Tours. This season’s tour weekend is scheduled for 10:00 AM ET to 4:30 PM ET on Saturday, April 9 and Sunday, April 10.</p>



<p>These&nbsp;tours&nbsp;are free and open to members of the&nbsp;public; however, a ticket is required for all attendees, including small children. The National Park Service (NPS) will distribute free, timed tickets at a tent stationed near the Ellipse Visitors Pavilion each day beginning at 8:30 AM ET. The entry point for all guests will be located near the intersection of 15th Street NW and Constitution Avenue NW. Tickets will be distributed, one ticket per person, on a first-come, first-served basis.</p>



<p><strong>WHITE HOUSE EASTER EGG ROLL</strong></p>



<p>The White House Easter Egg Roll will take place on the South Lawn on Easter Monday, April 18, continuing one of the oldest traditions in White House history.</p>



<p><strong><em>Online Ticket Lottery</em><br></strong>White House Easter Egg Roll tickets are free to the public and may be requested through an online lottery starting on&nbsp;Friday, March 25&nbsp;at 10:00 AM ET, and closing on Thursday, March 31, at 10:00 AM ET.&nbsp;Entering the lottery is free of charge, and randomly selected lottery winners will be notified via email by Thursday, April 7. Tickets are not for sale or resale. Those interested in attending may enter the lottery&nbsp;<a href="https://www.recreation.gov/ticket/facility/250029">here</a>.</p>



<p><em>Additional information and press coverage opportunities to be released in the coming days.</em></p>



<p><strong><em>Volunteer Opportunities</em></strong><br>As in past years, the White House will welcome volunteers interested in supporting the White House Easter Egg Roll through an online application. Those interested in applying to volunteer may register <a href="https://events.whitehouse.gov/EventInterestHolidayVol?rid=PBBWVB69PK">here.</a> The deadline to submit a White House Easter Egg Roll Volunteer application is Thursday, March 31, 2022 at 10:00 AM ET.</p>



<p><em>The White House will continue to closely monitor the COVID-19 situation based on recommendations from the CDC and other public health officials and medical experts. The White House reserves the right to adjust availability of the public tours as necessary to adhere to the latest health guidance. Anyone who has tested positive for COVID-19, has had any COVID-19 symptoms, or been in close contact with someone confirmed or suspected to have COVID-19 within 10 days prior to their visit may not attend. Face masks will be available when entering the White House complex for those who choose to wear them.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meetings with the G7 and the European&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/24/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-meetings-with-the-g7-and-the-european-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49644</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Via Teleconference 12:08 P.M. CET MODERATOR:&#160; For the second section, which is embargoed until 2:15 p.m. Central European Time/9:15 a.m. Eastern time, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you [senior administration official] to get us started. SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thanks, [senior administration official].&#160; And let me follow up from [senior administration official] and just preview some&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"> Via Teleconference</p>



<p>12:08 P.M. CET</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; For the second section, which is embargoed until 2:15 p.m. Central European Time/9:15 a.m. Eastern time, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you [senior administration official] to get us started.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And let me follow up from [senior administration official] and just preview some of the G7 discussions, in particular the actions we have planned on sanctions.</p>



<p>So, today the U.S. will sanction Russian elites, the Duma, and over 300 Duma members, and over 40 Russian defense companies.&nbsp; All of this will align and strengthen our sanctions in close coordination and partnership with the EU and G7.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The G7 and EU will also announce a new sanctions evasion initiative that’s designed to prevent circumvention or backfilling of our unprecedented measures.&nbsp; And that will happen through closing down avenues, for example, for the Russian Central Bank to prop up the ruble.&nbsp; It could be through growing our coalition of countries to deny cutting-edge technology to Russia, or through preventing Russia from designating crony banks to do it business abroad.</p>



<p>In all cases, we’ll use this initiative to share information and coordinate our responses to prevent the emergence of any safe haven for Russia, whether it’s in China or any other country.</p>



<p>Third, the G7 and the EU will also continue to blunt the Central Bank of Russia’s ability to deploy international reserves by making clear that any transaction involving gold related to the Central Bank of Russia is prohibited.</p>



<p>And for context: As of June of last year &#8212; the last official snapshot of Russia’s Central Bank reserves &#8212; gold was 20 percent of the total.&nbsp; And our purpose now is to fully disarm its war chest by making sure its foreign reserves serve no purpose in propping up the Russian currency.</p>



<p>And finally, we and the G7 will join together in saying that international organizations and multilateral fora should no longer conduct their activities with Russia in a business-as-usual manner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our purpose here is to methodically remove the benefits and privileges Russia once enjoyed as a participant in the international economic order.&nbsp; And this follows our actions to remove Russia’s most-favored-nation trading status and to suspend its borrowing privileges from the IMF and the World Bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You all have the factsheet, so I won’t get into all the detail on the specifics, but let me just step back and put all these actions into context.</p>



<p>All of you will remember that well before Putin invaded Ukraine, we warned that he would face the most severe sanctions ever levied on Russia and ever imposed on a large market economy.&nbsp; We also warned that we would respond to an invasion with unprecedented speed and with a historic degree of coordination.</p>



<p>Over the past month, we’ve done exactly what we said we’d do.&nbsp; Judging from the words and actions of the Russian leadership, this caught the Kremlin by surprise.&nbsp; Putin himself said these sanctions are delivering a profound blow; they&#8217;re causing “unprecedented” pressure, in his own words.&nbsp; And yesterday, Minister Lavrov said no one could have predicted the actions we’d take.&nbsp; But the reality is these are precisely the consequences we&#8217;ve signaled.</p>



<p>And the consequence is that Russia is now looking at a contraction in its economy of 15 percent this year, according to private sector estimates.&nbsp; To put that into perspective, that would be three times as much as the GDP declined after Russia’s debt default in 1998.&nbsp; The Institute for International Finance estimates that the shock to Russia’s GDP this year will wipe out the past 15 years of economic gains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the OECD projects that inflation will spike to 15 percent this year in Russia.&nbsp; More than 400 private sector companies have already quit Russia.&nbsp; And independent observers estimate that over 200,000 people emigrated from Russia just in the past month alone, as the brain drain accelerates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Set against the backdrop of export controls that deny cutting-edge technology and its removal from international supply chains, Russia will soon face an acute shortage of ideas, talent, and technology to compete in the 21st century.&nbsp; And Putin will be left with a strategic failure of his own making.</p>



<p>Let me turn it now to [senior administration official].&nbsp; Sorry, I guess I&#8217;ll take Q&amp;A before turning it to [senior administration official] on refugees, if that’s all right, [moderator].</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; We’ll open it up for a couple of questions for [senior administration official].&nbsp; If you can please indicate you have a question by raising your hand on the Zoom.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ll start with James Politi from the Financial Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could talk a bit more about energy and the sort of joint strategy that we expect to be announced tomorrow, if possible.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, James.&nbsp; Yeah, you know, I actually would rather &#8212; or not &#8212; I’d rather not get ahead of that announcement.&nbsp; It&#8217;s premature to go into detail, but I guess I&#8217;ll just let you know it&#8217;s something we&#8217;ve been working on for some time, and I think it&#8217;s going to be a meaningful step forward in terms of accelerating Europe’s diversification away from Russian gas and our collective phasing out of gas, both in the U.S. and Europe.&nbsp; So, please stay tuned on that front.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And for our next question, we’ll go to Daniel Bush from Newsweek.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, sorry about that.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wonder if you could just step back a little bit.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing these sanctions having a huge impact on the economy, as you pointed out in all these different ways.&nbsp; What impact do you see it having on Putin’s ability in the short and medium term to continue carrying out the war on the ground in Ukraine, especially if Russia is continuing to get revenue from oil and gas exports?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, you know, first of all, in oil and gas exports, if you look at Russia&#8217;s oil receipts, they are down.&nbsp; Estimates from the private sector suggest that roughly two to two and a half million barrels of Russian oil are no longer making it to their intended destination.</p>



<p>But, you know, look, if you consider the aggregate impact of these sanctions, what we&#8217;re doing is really depleting President Putin of the resources that he needs to conduct this war.&nbsp; He&#8217;s looking, as I mentioned, at a contraction in his economy; you know, some people estimate 10 percent, others 15 percent, other people say more.&nbsp; That is three times larger than the contraction Russia faced after it defaulted in 1998.&nbsp; Russia used to be the 11th largest economy in the world before its invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you consider the depreciation of the ruble already and the projected shrinking of its economy, it&#8217;s now looking at an economy half of the size that it was before this invasion.&nbsp; So it would fall out of the top 20 economies by ranking.</p>



<p>At the same time, we&#8217;re cutting off all of the sources of potential growth in Russia, whether it&#8217;s cutting-edge technology, or whether it&#8217;s access to supply chains from the West, or human capital.&nbsp; You know, people are leaving Russia by the droves, especially the best and brightest.</p>



<p>All of this will inhibit his ability to continue to execute a military operation and to have sources of growth outside of oil and gas.</p>



<p>Now, we can&#8217;t predict exactly when or how this will change Putin’s calculus.&nbsp; But what we can ensure is that this is going to be a failure; he&#8217;s going to emerge weaker, and we&#8217;re going to emerge stronger.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And next we&#8217;ll turn to Tamara Keith from NPR.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Unmute.&nbsp; So sorry.&nbsp; I just wanted to clarify whether all of these sanctions are being done in conjunction with Allies or whether this is the U.S. moving on its own, and just the &#8212; just the sanctions evasion part is done &#8212; being done in coordination today.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Tamara.&nbsp; So, the sanctions on individuals &#8212; as I mentioned, we’re sanctioning 300-plus members of the Duma, a handful of financial elites and oligarchs.&nbsp; Many of those measures are aligning the U.S. sanctions with those of the EU or G7 partners.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re also taking steps to align with our measures.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s an effort at strengthening our coordinated action.</p>



<p>The other measures I mentioned are being taken by the G7-EU as a whole.&nbsp; So the sanctions evasion initiative is something that you&#8217;ll see in the G7 statement.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll also see language in the G7 statement about prohibiting any transactions with Russia&#8217;s Central Banking goal.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re also going to say together in the G7 statement that it&#8217;s not &#8212; it cannot be business as usual anymore for international organizations or multilateral fora.</p>



<p>So, the overall message here i<a></a><a>s: We have taken historic steps in imposing costs on Russia.&nbsp; Now let&#8217;s make sure we&#8217;re fully aligned and we&#8217;re getting the maximal impact from the measures that we&#8217;ve implemented.</a></p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And next we’ll go to Phil Mattingly from CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official], on the sanctions evasion piece of it that you’re working with on the G7 &#8212; I guess, to start, can you give some examples of, over the course of the last four weeks, places where you&#8217;ve seen gaps or seen areas that could be exploited that will be closed by what you&#8217;re doing right now?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I guess, more broadly, conceptually, how have you approached putting the sanctions evasion piece together?&nbsp; Is it purely through what you&#8217;ve seen in asset flows or what you&#8217;ve seen in gaps, or is there kind of a broader methodology to it?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Phil.&nbsp; Yeah, I’ll give you a couple of examples &#8212; and, actually, one of them is gold.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve heard market chatter that Russia is still using &#8212; trying to use its gold reserves to prop up the ruble &#8212; so, selling its gold in order to buy ruble.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It still has a considerable amount of gold; estimates are that it’s somewhere between $100 billion to $140 billion in market value.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t know for sure because the last snapshot of Russia&#8217;s Central Bank reserves was from last June.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s roughly 20 percent of the total reserves that Russia held prior to the invasion.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We want to shut down any ability for Russia to use its gold to support its currency.&nbsp; And we need to do that as a G7 for it to be effective.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s an example of working together to prevent any circumvention of our sanctions measures.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another is on export controls, Phil.&nbsp; So, as you know, we have collectively denied the inputs for foundational technologies to Russia, whether it&#8217;s semiconductors or artificial intelligence or quantum or hypersonic flight.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we, in the West and the EU, produce and design many of these inputs, but so do our partners in Asia.&nbsp; And we just need &#8212; we want to make sure that for any of these technologies, including technologies that may be produced in China or designed in China, that we&#8217;re shutting down avenues for Russia to benefit from continued transactions with those countries too.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And next we&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to do an overview of our refugees announcement, followed by [senior administration official] to do a preview of the European Council meeting, after which we&#8217;ll open it up for more Q&amp;A.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And good morning, everyone.&nbsp; We&#8217;re happy today to share that the United States is announcing that we will welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians and others fleeing Russia&#8217;s aggression.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To meet this commitment, we are considering the full range of legal pathways to the United States.&nbsp; So that includes the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program, parole, and immigrant and non-immigrant visas.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have more details to share on this program in the days and weeks to come.&nbsp; But I would note today that we&#8217;re working, in particular, to expand and develop new programs with a focus on welcoming Ukrainians who have family members in the United States.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;ve all heard from many in the diaspora that they are eager to welcome their Ukrainian family members into their homes in the United States as quickly as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re also committed to protecting the most vulnerable among the refugee populations that have already fled, and that includes LGBTQI+ individuals, those with medical needs, third-country nationals who have already sought refuge outside of the &#8212; in Ukraine &#8212; excuse me &#8212; journalists, dissidents, and others who have specific vulnerabilities.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we&#8217;re, of course, coordinating our effort closely with our European allies and partners who are on the frontlines of this refugee crisis.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We still expect most displaced Ukrainian citizens will want to stay in neighboring countries or elsewhere in the EU where they may have family and where there are already large diaspora communities in the hope that they can return home soon.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But at the same time, we recognize that some number of Ukrainians who have fled may wish to come to the United States temporarily, especially those with family in the U.S.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By opening our country to these individuals, we will help relieve some of the pressure on the European host countries that are currently shouldering so much of the responsibilities for what is the largest refugee crisis in Europe since the Second World War.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We commend our European allies and partners for keeping their borders open to those that are seeking international protection.&nbsp; And as [senior administration official] noted, we are particularly grateful to Ukraine&#8217;s neighboring countries, including Poland, Romania, Slovakia, Moldova, and Hungary, who have opened their doors and set up welcome centers for the nearly 3.5 million who have fled Ukraine to date.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United States is and will continue to be a global leader in international humanitarian &#8212; in international humanitarian response.&nbsp; And we are asserting humanitarian assistance to provide immediate support for those on the ground in Ukraine and for those who are fleeing Ukraine and dealing with the catastrophic humanitarian consequences that Moscow and Moscow alone is responsible for.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to preview this afternoon&#8217;s EC meetings and our announcements on new humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, thanks for that, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And, yes, just to round out the day, you know, I think this is a banner day of multilateral meetings, starting here at NATO, moving to the G7, and then we will be driving across town for meetings with the EU.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President, this afternoon, will be joining the European Council meeting.&nbsp; That is a fairly regular gathering that the 27 EU heads of state and government have.</p>



<p>You may remember that, almost a year ago to the day, the President joined a meeting of the European Council.&nbsp; This was very early in the administration.&nbsp; He joined it virtually.&nbsp; And this will be the first time in the administration that the President will have sat down with all 27 of the EU heads of state and government in person.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, some of those countries &#8212; many of those countries, in fact &#8212; are here at the NATO summit.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s also an opportunity for him to engage with a number of other countries who are in the EU but not at NATO.</p>



<p>The President will be greeted by Charles Michel, who is the President of the European Council.&nbsp; And then they will have a short bilateral meeting at the top.&nbsp; And then President Michel will escort President Biden into the meeting where he will be then meeting with the 27 EU leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They will then continue on after the President leaves for their own previously scheduled meeting later this afternoon and dinner and then probably much of the day tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we really felt that, in addition to the NATO meeting, it was important for the President to have the opportunity to engage directly with his EU counterparts as well.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of the main things I think they will discuss is sanctions.&nbsp; [Senior administration official] obviously did the broad laydown of sanctions, including new measures that we are looking at today.&nbsp; And so, in addition to the coordination that we&#8217;ve had with the G7, I think it&#8217;s important to underscore the very close cooperation that we have had with the European Union generally over the last year.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of our approach to sanctions, our aim has always been to work in lockstep with the EU to the extent possible.&nbsp; But I think, particularly over the last month, we have tried to be as closely coordinated with the EU as we could, both in the development and the rollout of our sanctions packages.&nbsp; So this will be a good opportunity for the President to talk directly with EU leaders about that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, I think the leaders will have a significant conversation about the refugee crisis as well as the humanitarian assistance that we are all providing.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, a very clear recognition by the President that a number of these eastern flank countries, including Poland, Romania, Slovakia, Hungary, as well as some non-EU members, including Moldova, are very much on the frontlines of this.&nbsp; And so I think the President will welcome the opportunity to hear from a number of these countries that are facing these immediate flows of refugees, as well as to hear from a range of EU countries that are taking in a number of refugees.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Those of you that were covering St. Patrick&#8217;s Day last week will have heard the President talk with the Irish Taoiseach about the 7,000 refugees, for example, that Ireland has taken in, which is an example of how various EU member states are stepping up to deal with the humanitarian assistance piece.</p>



<p><a>Third, and related more broadly to the Eastern Partnership, which is what the EU calls these countries on their eastern side &#8212; the Caucasus, Moldova, Belarus, Ukraine</a> &#8212; the leaders are expected to discuss democratic resilience: the need to continue to bolster the ability of these countries to stand strong in the face of some of these autocratic pressures; to underscore the democratic developments that are happening in a lot of their countries; and to ensure that we are working together with the EU to support their resilience, especially at this particular moment.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, I would expect that the leaders will have some discussion of energy security along the broad lines of the G7 talks that [senior administration official] outlined, as well as food security.&nbsp; Food security is an increasing concern for the EU, similar to what it is at the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, coming out of the President’s meeting with the European Council, we are anticipating the announcement of a number of deliverables and new announcements.&nbsp; So, let me run through what those are now, as they are related specifically to the conversation that the President is going to be having with his EU counterparts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, we’re prepared to provide&nbsp;more than $1 billion in new funding towards humanitarian assistance for those affected by Russia’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world.&nbsp; So, this funding will be additional to money that we have already provided, and will provide food, shelter, clean water, medical supplies, and other forms of assistance.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, a new commitment to defend global food security. &nbsp;Russia’s war of aggression threatens to disrupt the supply of critical agricultural commodities from the Black Sea region, which jeopardizes global food security, particularly for vulnerable populations in the Middle East and Africa.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ukraine, known globally for its wheat production, for being a “bread basket” for the world, obviously is very much hindered in its ability to do that during this harvest season given the fact that you have Russian tanks rolling across Ukrainian fields and you have Ukrainian farmers who have taken up arms to defend their country.</p>



<p>But the United States, through the Feed the Future initiative and our nutrition commitments, will be providing over $11 billion over the next five years to address food security threats and malnutrition across the globe.&nbsp; And this includes programming in many of the countries that are vulnerable to increases in food and fertilizer prices.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The third thing to highlight is that today we will be launching a European Democratic Resilience Initiative.&nbsp; This initiative will be launched with $320 million in funding.&nbsp; The aim of this initiative is to defend human rights, to strengthen democratic and anti-corruption institutions, to support media freedom, and to increase accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international law.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as I mentioned, there will be a particular focus of these efforts on these countries neighboring the European Union who are currently vulnerable in this space.</p>



<p>So, an important component of this will be support for efforts to document and preserve evidence of potential war crimes being committed in Ukraine.&nbsp; The United States is already supporting several such initiatives.&nbsp; And as I mentioned, this will be an opportunity for the President to talk with EU counterparts about ways in which we can collaborate with the EU on these efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some new lines of efforts, including the establishment of a conflict observatory, will gather information that can be shared with a range of accountability efforts at the national and international level to hold Russia accountable for its actions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, [moderator], let me stop there.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And now we’ll open it up for Q&amp;A for [senior administration official] or [senior administration official].&nbsp; If folks could please raise your hand using the Zoom function.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’ll get started with Michael Shear from the New York Times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Question, I guess, for [senior administration official] about the 100,000 refugees.&nbsp; As you know, obviously the President said, I think last September, that the cap for refugees &#8212; for the refugee program for the entire world would be 125,000.&nbsp; Very few of those have actually come in.&nbsp; Is the 100,000 going to be part of that 125?&nbsp; Is this an additional 100,000?&nbsp; And do you have to go to Congress to consult for that, or can those just simply come in through the IRAP program?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for the question.&nbsp; So, a couple of things on this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, not everyone that comes in under this program would come in as a refugee.&nbsp; Like I mentioned, people could come in as refugees under &#8212; or under humanitarian parole, or using immigrant or non-immigrant visas.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s multiple pathways there.&nbsp; And obviously, only those that came in as refugees would be counted against that ceiling of 125,000.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll also note that the ceiling of 125,000 is for fiscal year 2022.&nbsp; And this commitment of 100,000 is not necessarily timebound to that fiscal year; it&#8217;s a broader commitment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I will say that, you know, we have still a significant capacity within the 125,000, so we don&#8217;t currently envision the need to go beyond that in terms of the portion of the individuals that would come in as refugees during this fiscal year.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next we&#8217;ll go to Geoff Earle with the Daily Mail.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; This is a little bit circling back to earlier in the call, but I was wondering if with President Zelenskyy or some of the other leaders, if there&#8217;s been any discussion of prospects for a negotiated settlement.&nbsp; Because I know a lot of the military aid is &#8212; you know, one aim is to try to force the Russians back to the table.&nbsp; And so, is this, you know, realistic?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, Zelenskyy keeps talking about reparations.&nbsp; Is there going to be an effort to acquire, you know, this impounded money from Russia to go toward that?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much for that question.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have anything new on this beyond what we have talked about in the past, which obviously is continued support for the Ukrainians in their effort and, most importantly, to get the Russians to agree to a ceasefire, especially considering the very dire humanitarian situation that we&#8217;re seeing in a number of parts of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So far, we have not seen a serious readiness on the part of Russia, certainly, to engage in a ceasefire or even necessarily to engage in serious conversations.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Certainly, if we get to that point, we can look at a broad range of scenarios.&nbsp; But for right now, the focus very much remains on getting to a ceasefire so we can support the people that are suffering.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next we’ll go to David Sanger with the New York Times.</p>



<p>David, if you’re there, please unmute.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; Can you hear me now?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; My question is for [senior administration official], and the question has to do with the European Democratic Resilience plan.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Senior administration official], is this the kind of plan that the President had in mind when he was first talking about autocracy versus democracy?&nbsp; Or is this specifically tailored to the Russian invasion and so forth?&nbsp; I’m trying to figure out the degree to which you think you have new threats to democracy in the region because of this versus what you faced before?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, David, for that question.&nbsp; So this European Democratic Resilience Initiative is something new that we are standing up to try and provide additional support to countries in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think our approach to the Ukraine crisis more broadly, as I said at the top, has been multifaceted, both in terms of imposing economic costs on Russia, supporting the people of Ukraine, defending the security of the NATO Alliance.&nbsp; And I think you could add a fourth line of effort to that that&#8217;s been implicit in what we&#8217;ve done, as well as in what the EU has done, which is to take steps to bolster the resilience of countries in the neighboring region.&nbsp; This is something that I heard a number of leaders mention in passing in the NATO interventions earlier today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The EU and the United States, they’re obviously very concerned about the situation in Moldova, in terms of refugees.  And a strong desire to ensure that we are doing everything possible to bolster the resilience of those countries as well &#8212; the ones that are not in NATO or the EU but that are, in EU parlance, part of their Eastern Partnership Program and on the eastern part of the European flank. <br><br>     So we&#8217;ve already done a lot with Moldova in terms of Secretary Blinken and others making visits there, with a very strong focus on what we can do on the humanitarian assistance side. <br><br>     The United States has long worked on democratic programs in all of these countries, frankly.  The EU also has programs in all of these countries as part of the Eastern Partnership Program. <br><br>     But I think &#8212; and then, you know, to take your question more broadly: As you rightly said, the President has been, for his entire administration, very focused on these broader questions of democracy and autocracy as well.  And it&#8217;s very much played out in the President&#8217;s Democracy Summit where we had participation from countries like Moldova and Georgia, among others.  It very much ties into what we are trying to do in this democracy “year of action” coming out of the Democracy Summit.  <br><br>     But this specific program that we are launching today is targeted at the countries within this region, with a very specific desire to try and shore up their democratic institutions, their anti-corruption institutions; to support media freedom; as well as accountability for human rights abuses. <br><br>     And part of this is based on the theory that one of the best things we can do for all of these countries and to increase the resilience and security of these countries, as well as our own countries, quite frankly, as the President has talked about, is to ensure that we&#8217;re doing everything we can to shore up the democratic resilience, the good governance, and the rule of law measures there. <br><br>     And then, as I mentioned, there is also an increasing focus on the potential for war crimes in Ukraine and wanting to ensure that we are doing everything we can to be supporting the collection of information there so that that can be fed into broader accountability mechanisms. MODERATOR:  Great, thank you so much.  And with that, those are all the questions we have time for, so we have to wrap. <br><br>     As a reminder of the ground rules, this call was conducted on background, attributable to a senior &#8212; to three “senior administration officials.”  And as a reminder, the second portion of the call is embargoed until 2:15 p.m. local time or 9:15 a.m. Eastern time.  Thank you very much.<br><br>12:39 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on Unemployment Insurance&#160;Claims</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-unemployment-insurance-claims-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Americans are getting back to work at a historic pace, with fewer Americans on unemployment insurance today than at any time in the last half century. This morning, we received news that the number of Americans on unemployment insurance fell to its lowest level since 1970 and the number of Americans filing new claims fell&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Americans are getting back to work at a historic pace, with fewer Americans on unemployment insurance today than at any time in the last half century. This morning, we received news that the number of Americans on unemployment insurance fell to its lowest level since 1970 and the number of Americans filing new claims fell to its lowest one-week level since 1969. This historic progress is no accident: it’s the result of an economic strategy to grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out, starting with the American Rescue Plan. And, it’s the result of effective management of emergency pandemic resources that resulted in 75% of adult Americans vaccinated and 99% of schools re-opened.  We have more work to do to cut costs for families, but today’s data are a reminder that the U.S. economy is uniquely well positioned to deal with the global challenge of inflation. We will continue the fight to lower costs with every tool at our disposal, from making more here in America and rebuilding our supply chains, to lowering costs that have held back Americans for decades, to promoting competition to ensure markets can operate effectively and consumers are protected.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on the Extraordinary NATO&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/statement-from-president-biden-on-the-extraordinary-nato-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATO leaders met today on the one-month anniversary of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine to reiterate our strong support for the Ukrainian people, our determination to hold Russia accountable for its brutal war, and our commitment to strengthening the NATO Alliance. We had the privilege of hearing directly from President Zelenskyy, and we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NATO leaders met today on the one-month anniversary of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine to reiterate our strong support for the Ukrainian people, our determination to hold Russia accountable for its brutal war, and our commitment to strengthening the NATO Alliance. We had the privilege of hearing directly from President Zelenskyy, and we will continue to support him and his government with significant, and increasing, amounts of security assistance to fight Russian aggression and uphold their right to self-defense.</p>



<p>In the past few weeks, the United States has announced $1 billion in new security assistance to Ukraine — anti-aircraft systems, anti-armor weapons, drones, and millions of rounds of ammunition. I welcome the steps by many other Allies to provide defensive support to Ukraine and together, we are committed to identifying additional equipment, including air defense systems, to help Ukraine.</p>



<p>We also discussed our work to bolster NATO’s collective defense, particularly on the Eastern flank. Our joint statement today makes clear that NATO is as strong and united as it has ever been. Immediately after Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, we activated NATO’s defensive plans and the NATO Response Force. The United States has surged thousands of forces and additional capabilities to Europe, and we have welcomed the new deployments made by our Allies. Today’s establishment of four new battle groups in Slovakia, Romania, Bulgaria, and Hungary is a strong signal that we will collectively defend and protect every inch of NATO territory. Between now and the NATO summit in June, we will develop plans for additional forces and capabilities to strengthen NATO’s defenses. We will adopt an updated Strategic Concept to ensure NATO is ready to meet any challenge in the new and more dangerous security environment.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meetings at&#160;NATO</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/24/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-meetings-at-nato/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Via Teleconference 11:53 A.M. CET MODERATOR:&#160; Well, good morning, everyone.&#160; And thank you for joining the White House background call on the President&#8217;s trip to Europe.&#160; As a reminder of the ground rules, this call will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” For your awareness but not for your reporting, the three officials&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"> Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:53 A.M. CET</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Well, good morning, everyone.&nbsp; And thank you for joining the White House background call on the President&#8217;s trip to Europe.&nbsp; As a reminder of the ground rules, this call will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”</p>



<p>For your awareness but not for your reporting, the three officials joining us on our call today are [senior administration officials].&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will have two sections of the call today.&nbsp; The first will be a recap of the President&#8217;s time at NATO, which will be embargoed until the call concludes.&nbsp; The second section, which previews the G7 and EU meetings, will be embargoed until this afternoon at 2:15 p.m. Central European Time, or 9:15 a.m. Eastern Time.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to our first speaker, [senior administration official], for the first section of the call.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And good morning, almost good afternoon, to everyone.&nbsp; I just stepped out of the listening room where I have been for the last hour or so, and I&#8217;m happy to share a little bit of color from what&#8217;s been happening in the meeting.</p>



<p>So, Secretary General Stoltenberg opened the meeting.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure all of you saw his open remarks, which were open to press. Then the leaders went into a closed session.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I think everyone is tracking, President Zelenskyy was beamed in via video link from Ukraine to address the group.&nbsp; He spoke very eloquently, as he has to a number of national parliaments in recent weeks, with a message very much focused on the efforts of the Ukrainian military and people to defend their country, to defend their citizens, and also to defend our shared democratic values.</p>



<p>He repeated his requests for continued and increased Western security assistance.&nbsp; But notably, there was not a request for a no-fly zone.&nbsp; There was also not a request for NATO membership in his remarks.</p>



<p>Following his intervention, he departed on the video link, and the members moved into a closed session among the Alliance.</p>



<p>After him, the President was the first speaker.&nbsp; He set out the three-pronged approach that we have taken throughout this this crisis, noting that today marks the one-month anniversary of the launch of Russian military aggression against Ukraine.</p>



<p>First, he talked about everything that we have done to impose costs on Russia, including the very significant package of sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, he reiterated our strong support for Ukraine, both in terms of security assistance &#8212; increased and continued security assistance, as well as humanitarian assistance that we were continuing to provide to those both in Ukraine and to those fleeing the violence.</p>



<p>And third, a very strong message of support for NATO &#8212; reaffirming the U.S. commitment to Article 5 and the steps that the United States, in partnership with other Allies, had taken in recent weeks to reinforce the security of the eastern flank.<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of that, speaking more generally: In terms of the Alliance, he talked about force posture adjustments, as I mentioned.&nbsp; He welcomed the similar moves that we have seen from a number of countries to strengthen NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.&nbsp; He welcomed the increased defense spending pledges that we have seen from a number of countries, as well as the ongoing robust exercises that are continuing.</p>



<p>Finally, he looked ahead to the Madrid summit, which will be in about two and a half months in late June, and laid out a number of issues that the Alliance is going to have to grapple with in advance of that summit, given the changed security context that we see ourselves in and as the Alliance is finalizing the strategic concept that will be addressing a number of these changes in security architecture.</p>



<p>By the time I left the room, I think about six leaders had spoken.&nbsp; So, just to give you a sense of the mood: First, there was a very strong sense that we are facing a significant, historical moment, and very strong support from all of the leaders who spoke about the need to defend our democracy, the need to defend our shared values, and a strong sense that NATO was appropriately poised to be able to do that.</p>



<p>Second and relatedly, there was a very strong message of unity &#8212; notes of how united the NATO Alliance was, notes of unity across the transatlantic alliance; very strong support for NATO, for its Article 5 commitments; a number of leaders speaking about increases in their own defense spending; and also notes about changes that various countries have made in terms of force posture, particularly with what we&#8217;ve seen in the last couple of weeks with a significant movement of NATO forces to NATO&#8217;s eastern flank to defend the security of Allies there.</p>



<p>Third, very strong admiration for the Ukrainian military and the Ukrainian people in terms of everything they are doing to defend their country from Russian aggression.</p>



<p>There was also very strong pledges of support from across the Allies that I heard speak about their readiness to continue, as well as increase, their security assistance to Ukraine.</p>



<p>Related to that, many of the leaders also spoke about the importance of economic sanctions and the need for us to continue imposing robust economic costs on Russia in response to its aggression.</p>



<p>Related to that: On the Ukrainian people, very strong support for refugees; a lot of appreciation to the eastern flank Allies that have been bearing the brunt of the crisis; and continued pledges by Allies to continue contributing financially to the humanitarian assistance, as well as, of course, a number of these countries taking in refugees themselves.</p>



<p>And just a final note: There was also a reference by many of the speakers to China and a recognition that China needs to live up to its responsibilities within the international community as a U.N. Security Council member, that we need to continue to call on China not to support Russia in its aggression against Ukraine, and that we need China to call for a peaceful end to the conflict as a responsible member of the international community.</p>



<p>So the mood overall has been sober, it&#8217;s been resolute, and it&#8217;s been incredibly united.&nbsp;<br>So let me stop there with my opening comments.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; With that, we&#8217;ll open it up to a couple of questions on the NATO portion before we move on to the second portion of the call, which will be EU and G7 specific.</p>



<p>If I can ask everyone who has a question to please indicate you have one using the “raise hand” feature.</p>



<p>Josh Wingrove from Bloomberg.&nbsp; I saw your hand up first.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Hello from the travel pool.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Can you give me a sense of what President Zelenskyy did ask for if he didn’t mention NATO membership and didn’t mention the closure?&nbsp;<br>And also, NBC is reporting that 100,000 refugees &#8212; the U.S. will announce a pledge to take in 100,000 refugees.&nbsp; Is there anything you can tell us on that in particular that we could publish before any later embargo?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you for that.</p>



<p>So, on your question about refugees, I don’t want to steal any thunder from my colleague, so let me defer that to the later part of the call where [senior administration official] is going to have more information specifically on some of our refugees and humanitarian assistance.</p>



<p>In terms of President Zelenskyy’s comments, I will let the Ukrainian government speak for themselves in terms of what specifically Zelenskyy conveyed to leaders in what was a closed, private session to leaders.</p>



<p>What I can say is that President Biden was very clear in his remarks about the security assistance that the U.S. has continued to provide, underscoring the $2 billion that we have provided over the last year, underscoring the billion dollars in new security assistance to Ukraine that we have just announced; talked in some specifics, as he has done previously, about the additional types of assistance that we have been providing to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>And then, just more broadly, I would say that we have started consulting with Allies on providing anti-ship missiles to Ukraine.&nbsp; There may be some technical challenges with making that happen, but that is something that we are consulting with Allies and starting to work on.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next, we go to Kevin Liptak with CNN.</p>



<p>Q &nbsp;Hi. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;Yesterday, Jake said that discussion of Russia’s potential use of chemical or biological or nuclear weapons would come up in all these discussions. &nbsp;I wonder if you could say whether that came up at NATO today and what the leaders &#8212; what was &#8212; if there was a consensus among the leaders about whether NATO would be obliged to respond to the use of those kinds of weapons should that take place.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, there were some references to that.&nbsp; I think there is a recognition that NATO needs to continue a lot of the good, ongoing work to be prepared to respond to various contingencies.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something that NATO, as a military alliance, is already postured to do, and it&#8217;s something that they recognize that they need to continue to do given the various scenarios that could emerge as part of this conflict.<br>&nbsp;<br>The United States is already taking steps both nationally, as well as through NATO, to enhance the readiness and capability of our defense forces to respond to chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear incidents.&nbsp; Frankly, for NATO, this is an important part of strengthening our longer-term defense and deterrence postures.<br>&nbsp;<br>NATO has a Combined Joint CBRN Defence Task Force, which is an element of the NATO Response Force, which is prepared to deploy at SACEUR’s direction.&nbsp; This includes specially trained and equipped forces who are able to deal with these types of incidents if there are attacks against NATO populations, territory, or forces.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And NATO Allies are also continuing to consult, as well as to take national decisions, to be able to provide on a bilateral basis protective equipment and medical countermeasures to help Ukraine detect, identify, and respond to these types of threats.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in sum, yes, it was a subject that came up in discussion today and I assume is a continuing part of the ongoing discussion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, there are broader conversations within NATO about how to respond to these types of incidents.<br>&nbsp;<br>And third, some NATO Allies are already taking national decisions to be able to respond to, potentially, Ukrainian needs on these threats as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then we&#8217;ll do one more question from Chris Megerian with AP.&nbsp; After that, we&#8217;ll move on to the second portion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; I wanted to see if you could talk any more about force posture adjustments.&nbsp; What specifically are we speaking about?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then on China, when you said that China needs to do more, what specifically do you want to see them do more or see them stop doing?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for that.&nbsp; So, in terms of force posture, there was considerable discussion by leaders about the number of changes that have already been made across the Alliance.&nbsp; I think what we&#8217;ve seen within the last couple of weeks with NATO Allies acting with great unity and speed to deploy additional defensive forces and capabilities in response to renewed Russian aggression against Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>NATO activated its response plans.&nbsp; It deployed the NATO Response Force.&nbsp; It increased NATO&#8217;s readiness.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s now approximately 40,000 Allied forces under direct NATO command with particular emphasis on the eastern flank.<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of that, the United States has already deployed thousands of additional forces to Europe.&nbsp; There&#8217;s now approximately 100,000 U.S. forces on land, in the air, at sea, training, exercising, and ready to defer &#8212; or to deter and defend against any threat.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in the parts of the meeting that I was in, there was a lot of recognition about the steps that the U.S. has taken and, frankly, that a large number of other Allies have taken to move their forces to the eastern flank as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>And in terms of China, I would refer to what I had said earlier in terms of similar messages that Stoltenberg himself actually has given within the last couple of days as well: that there is a desire for China to live up to its responsibilities within the international community, clearly a strong desire for Russia [China] not to provide economic or military assistance to Russia in furtherance of its aggression against Ukraine, and for China to join with other responsible members of the international community in calling on Russia to end its violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And with that, that concludes the first portion of the call, which, as a reminder, is embargoed until this call concludes.<br>&nbsp;<br>12:08 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Announces New Humanitarian, Development, and Democracy Assistance to Ukraine and the Surrounding&#160;Region</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-announces-new-humanitarian-development-and-democracy-assistance-to-ukraine-and-the-surrounding-region/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is proud to be the largest single donor of humanitarian, democracy, and human rights assistance to Ukraine, working closely with our European partners. We remain committed to ensuring those affected by President Putin’s war of aggression, especially vulnerable populations such as women, children, lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and intersex (LGBTQI+) persons, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States is proud to be the largest single donor of humanitarian, democracy, and human rights assistance to Ukraine, working closely with our European partners. We remain committed to ensuring those affected by President Putin’s war of aggression, especially vulnerable populations such as women, children, lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and intersex (LGBTQI+) persons, and persons with disabilities, are able to access food, clean water, shelter, and medical care. In addition to assisting people in need within Ukraine, we are supporting the efforts of Ukraine’s neighbors and the European Union to welcome and host millions of refugees. And we will do our part to welcome Ukrainians to the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Today, the United States is announcing that we are prepared to provide&nbsp;more than $1 billion in new funding towards humanitarian assistance for those affected by Russia’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world, including a marked rise in food insecurity,&nbsp;over the coming months. This funding will provide food, shelter, clean water, medical supplies and other forms of assistance. We are also announcing an additional $320 million in democracy and human rights funding to Ukraine and its neighbors.</strong> Since 2021, the United States has provided over&nbsp;$1.1 billion in economic, health, democracy and human rights, and humanitarian assistance to the Europe and Eurasia region.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to our humanitarian assistance, the United States continues to support public health initiatives in Ukraine and the region to tamp down the spread of communicable diseases like polio, tuberculosis, and COVID, and to help ensure patients continue to have access to medical care. And we remain committed to defending and strengthening democratic governance, human rights, and the fight against corruption in Ukraine and its neighbors, as together we reject autocracy and aggression.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing refuge to Displaced Ukrainians.</strong> While we expect many Ukrainians will choose to remain in Europe close to family and their homes in Ukraine, today, the United States is announcing plans to welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians and others fleeing Russia’s aggression through the full range of legal pathways, including the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.&nbsp;In particular, we are working to expand and develop new programs with a focus on welcoming Ukrainians who have family members in the United States.&nbsp;The United States and the European Union are also coordinating closely to ensure that these efforts, and other forms of humanitarian admission or transfers, are complementary and provide much-needed support to Ukraine’s neighbors.<br></li><li><strong>Supporting humanitarian assistance in Ukraine.</strong> Today, the Biden Administration is announcing that we are prepared to provide more than $1 billion in new funding towards humanitarian assistance to support people within Ukraine and assist those affected by the global impacts of Russia’s war.&nbsp;This support builds on the 25-person humanitarian response team the United States has deployed to the region to assess needs, provide assistance, and coordinate closely with the United Nations, NGOs, and the Government of Ukraine, including the State Emergency Services of Ukraine.&nbsp;With the support of the United States and Allies and partners, the World Food Programme is working to reach 3.1 million people in Ukraine with ready-to-eat rations, canned goods, bread, wheat, flour, and oil.&nbsp;U.S.-funded humanitarian organizations in Ukraine are operating mobile medical teams and delivering emergency health supplies and medicine to public health care centers, enabling continued primary health services, trauma care, and vaccinations.&nbsp;In collective shelters in places like Mariupol or Lviv, humanitarian organizations are distributing blankets, water containers, and hygiene kits containing soap, toothpaste, diapers, and toilet paper to help thousands of internally displaced persons and mitigate the spread of disease.&nbsp;Mobile teams are also providing psychological support, ensuring especially vulnerable populations have access to services and are protected from risks, including gender-based violence, child-trafficking, and landmines.<br></li><li><strong>Helping those who have fled in the region.</strong>&nbsp;Since February 24, the United States has already provided more than $123 million to complement the work of neighboring countries and the European Union to receive and host millions of refugees, including $48 million in Poland, $30 million in Moldova, $10 million in Romania, $9 million in Hungary, and $4 million in the Slovak Republic.&nbsp;U.S.-funded humanitarian organizations are working in partnership with host governments to launch cash programs that provide refugees with temporary assistance for food, accommodations, and medical care until they can work or receive social support.&nbsp;In addition to counselling, legal aid, and mental health and psychological support, U.S. partners are providing health support for refugees including infection prevention and control, and sexual and reproductive health assistance, as well as providing safe drinking water, strengthening sanitation infrastructure, and providing refugees with basic household items and shelter materials.&nbsp;The U.S. has deployed refugee coordinators to the region to work with the governments of neighboring countries, the UN, and other humanitarian organizations, and donors. Additionally, the U.S. has allocated $5.5 million to facilitate the safe and orderly return of up to 20,000 third-country nationals to return home from Ukraine.<br></li><li><strong>Bolstering democracy and human rights in Ukraine and neighboring states. </strong>In line with President Biden’s commitment to support democracy and human rights globally, the United States is launching the European Democratic Resilience Initiative (EDRI), which is intended to provide at least $320 million in new funding to support societal resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighboring countries. The EDRI is expected to support media freedom and counter disinformation, increase the safety and security of activists and vulnerable groups including LGBTQI+ persons,&nbsp;build resilience to strategic corruption and kleptocracy, strengthen democratic and anti-corruption institutions and the region’s rule of law, and support accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international law.&nbsp;Implementation of the EDRI will be closely coordinated with the European Union and other partners.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing accountability for Russian war crimes in Ukraine. </strong>An important component of EDRI will be support for efforts to document and preserve evidence of potential war crimes being committed in Ukraine. The United States is already supporting several such initiatives. New lines of effort, including the establishment of a conflict observatory, will gather information that can be shared with a range of accountability efforts at the national and international level designed to hold Russia accountable for its actions.<br></li><li><strong>Protecting children and other vulnerable populations.</strong> Russia’s unprovoked further invasion of Ukraine poses an immediate and growing threat to the lives and well-being of the country’s 7.5 million children who face attacks on schools, injuries from mines and explosives, and child trafficking.&nbsp;In response, in both Ukraine and surrounding countries, the United States has been supporting Children and Family Protection Support Hubs where professional case workers, mental health professionals, and legal aid providers are available to assist children, female heads of household, those with disabilities, older persons and other vulnerable populations.&nbsp;These centers offer safe spaces for psychosocial support, hygiene, health and nutrition; provide family tracing for unaccompanied children; as well as protection from sexual exploitation and abuse.&nbsp;With support to nine different organizations, the United States is also supporting 55 mobile protection teams to prevent family separation, mitigate gender-based violence, communicate the risks of mines and war remnants, and address the psychological effects of war.<br></li><li><strong>Strengthening public health.</strong> Since February 24, the U.S. government has rapidly accelerated support to the Ukrainian health system and systems in the region, on top of previously funded programs.&nbsp;Inside Ukraine, U.S. government partners are providing critical medical commodities, expanded immunization support to areas experiencing an influx of internally displaced persons, and supporting continuity of tuberculosis and HIV/AIDS treatment services to ensure patients do not lose access to lifesaving treatments – including through procuring $6.1 million worth of antiretroviral drugs, re-purposing of mobile HIV testing vans, and expanded support to patients and home delivery of medicines. The U.S. government is also supporting the Ministry of Health and World Health Organization with technical assistance on issues such as immunization, outbreak response, blood safety, and overall emergency response coordination. The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention is also supporting the Ministry of Health to consolidate medicine needs from over 5,000 public, private, and academic institutions in order to guide and prioritize humanitarian assistance efforts, while helping the Ministry of Health to shift and expand warehousing and medicines delivery capacity.&nbsp;The U.S. government is also working with the Public Health Center of Ukraine to roster all CDC-trained graduates of the Field Epidemiology Training Program (FETP) in-country and support relocation of critical public health equipment and personnel within Ukraine, to mitigate the impacts of the Russian invasion on public health infrastructure.&nbsp;These teams are augmenting the humanitarian response by monitoring the health conditions of the Ukraine population, including refugees and internally displaced persons with focus on COVID-19, HIV, TB, measles, polio, mental health, non-communicable diseases, and maternal and child health.<br></li><li><strong>Defending global food security.</strong> Russia’s war of aggression threatens to disrupt the supply of critical agricultural commodities from the Black Sea region, jeopardizing global food security, particularly for vulnerable populations in the Middle East and Africa.&nbsp;The United States, through the Feed the Future initiative and our nutrition commitments, will be providing over $11 billion over the next five years to address food security threats and malnutrition across the globe &#8211; with programming in many of the countries vulnerable to increases in food and fertilizer prices. Ongoing activities within the initiative that help buffer food systems against macroeconomic shocks like the Russian invasion of Ukraine include: increasing the productivity of smallholder farmers, including women, through access to improved agricultural technologies and inputs, financing, and markets; strengthening agricultural market systems by building a vibrant local private sector; and improving people’s access to higher quality diets and safer food for improved nutrition. Additionally, the United States will remain one of the top providers of humanitarian food and nutrition assistance globally, having contributed approximately $4.6 billion in humanitarian food and nutrition assistance in 2021.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and Allies and Partners Impose Additional Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-united-states-and-allies-and-partners-impose-additional-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United States sanctions over 400 Russian elites, Duma members, and defense companies in coordination with the European Union and G7; U.S. has now sanctioned over 600 targets&#160;G7 and EU announce sanctions evasion initiative to prevent circumvention and backfilling of our unprecedented sanctions; continue to blunt Central Bank of the Russian Federation’s ability to deploy international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>United States sanctions over 400 Russian elites, Duma members, and defense companies in coordination with the European Union and G7; U.S. has now sanctioned over 600 targets</em></strong><br>&nbsp;<br><strong><em>G7 and EU announce sanctions evasion initiative to prevent circumvention and backfilling of our unprecedented sanctions; continue to blunt Central Bank of the Russian Federation’s ability to deploy international reserves including gold</em></strong></p>



<p>President Biden is in Europe to continue our historic coordination with allies and partners on all aspects of our response to Russia’s war against Ukraine, including imposing further severe costs on those enabling President Putin’s war of choice. Today, the United States is sanctioning over 400 individuals and entities comprised of Russian elites, the Duma and more than 300 of its members, and defense companies, aligning and strengthening our sanctions in close coordination and partnership with the EU and G7.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our sanctions on Russia are unprecedented — in no other circumstance have we moved so swiftly and in such a coordinated fashion to impose devastating costs on any other country. The ruble has depreciated substantially, and is expected by markets to weaken further. The Moscow Stock Exchange closed for weeks. The Central Bank of the Russian Federation has doubled interest rates to 20 percent and companies are being forced to turn over foreign exchange for rubles to provide the Russian Government hard currency. The economy is forecast to contract as much as 15 percent or more in 2022. This economic collapse of Russia’s GDP will wipe out the past 15 years of economic gains in Russia, according to the Institute for International Finance. Inflation in Russia is already spiking, with analysts projecting it to rise up to 15 percent on a year-over-year basis, and the Russian Government has been downgraded to “junk” status by major credit rating agencies. More than 400 multinational companies have left Russia in a mass exodus by the private sector.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As long as President Putin continues this war, the United States and allies and partners are committed to ensuring the Russian government feels the compounding effects of our current and future economic actions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today’s actions include:&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Full blocking sanctions on more than 400 individuals and entities, including the Duma and its members, additional Russian elites, and Russian defense companies that fuel Putin’s war machine.</strong>&nbsp;This includes:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>328 Duma members and sanctioning the Duma as an entity.</li><li>Herman Gref,&nbsp;the head of Russia’s largest financial institution Sberbank and a Putin advisor since the 1990s.&nbsp;</li><li>Russian elite Gennady Timchenko, his companies and his family members.</li><li>17 board members of Russian financial institution Sovcombank.</li><li>48 Large Russian defense state-owned enterprises that are part of Russia’s defense-industrial base and produce weapons that have been used in Russia’s assault against Ukraine’s people, infrastructure, and territory, including Russian Helicopters, Tactical Missiles Corporation, High Precision Systems, NPK Tekhmash OAO, Kronshtadt. We are targeting, and will continue to target, the suppliers of Russia’s war effort and, in turn, their supply chain.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Establishment of an initiative focused on sanctions evasions. </strong>G7 leaders and the European Union today announced an initiative to share information about and coordinate responses related to evasive measures intended to undercut the effectiveness and impact of our joint sanctions actions. Together, we will not allow sanctions evasion or backfilling. As part of this effort, we will also engage other governments on adopting sanctions similar to those already imposed by the G7 and other partners. <br> <br><strong>Continuing to blunt the Central Bank’s ability to deploy international reserves, including gold, to prop up the Russian economy and fund Putin’s brutal war. </strong>G7 leaders and the European Union will continue to work jointly to blunt Russia’s ability to deploy its international reserves to prop up Russia’s economy and fund Putin’s war, including by making clear that any transaction involving gold related to the Central Bank of the Russian Federation is covered by existing sanctions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General Jens&#160;Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 11:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) ahead of the extraordinary NATO Summit to address Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. They discussed the unity and strength of the alliance and NATO’s ongoing efforts to deter and defend against any aggression, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) ahead of the extraordinary NATO Summit to address Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. They discussed the unity and strength of the alliance and NATO’s ongoing efforts to deter and defend against any aggression, and they welcomed the support of Allies for the government and people of Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Releases Report on Native American Voting&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-report-on-native-american-voting-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris Announces Additional Steps in Response to the to the President’s Executive Order to Promote Access to Voting&#160; Since their first days in office, President Biden and Vice President Harris have prioritized strengthening our democracy and taken steps to protect voters from the current efforts to suppress the vote and subvert our electoral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris Announces Additional Steps in Response to the to the President’s Executive Order to Promote Access to Voting&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Since their first days in office, President Biden and Vice President Harris have prioritized strengthening our democracy and taken steps to protect voters from the current efforts to suppress the vote and subvert our electoral process.&nbsp;&nbsp;The unprecedented nature and scale of the present attacks on voting rights must be met with federal legislation, which is why the President and Vice President have repeatedly called for the Senate to pass the Freedom to Vote Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act. The President and Vice President have also forcefully called for changing Senate rules to prevent a minority of Senators from blocking action on this fundamental right from which all other rights flow.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congress still has the responsibility to act, but the President is committed to using every tool at his disposal to protect the sacred right to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;On March 7, 2021, the 56th anniversary of Bloody Sunday, he signed an Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting, directing an all-of-government effort to promote information about the voting process and to further the ability of all eligible Americans to participate in our democracy.&nbsp;&nbsp;That work is ongoing, and agencies will continue to develop ways to deliver non-partisan election information and enable eligible Americans to register and to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>A key provision of the Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting highlighted the unique trust responsibility that the Federal government has for Tribal Nations and Native communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;In light of this responsibility, President Biden directed the creation of an Interagency Steering Group on Native American Voting Rights, whose mission is to study the barriers Native voters face in casting their ballot and having those votes counted, and to recommend steps to mitigate or eliminate these barriers.&nbsp;&nbsp;For far too long, members of Tribal Nations and Native communities have faced unnecessary burdens when they attempt to exercise their sacred right to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;Native voters often have to overcome language barriers, a lack of accessibility for voters with disabilities, cultural disrespect and outright hostility, geographically remote residences, and persistent poverty — conditions that have only been exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;State laws and local practices also present too many Native voters with undue impediments to full and fair exercise of the franchise, including barriers in receiving information about the voting process, discriminatory redistricting, and burdens in voter registration, voter identification, voting in person, and voting by mail.</p>



<p>The Steering Group held consultations with Tribal leaders and Native Americans across the country, and engaged in listening sessions with Native Hawaiians, organizations advocating for improved Tribal voting rights, and state and local election officials in jurisdictions with sizable Native populations.  These sessions revealed recurring, unnecessary, and unacceptable impediments to the franchise. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Tribal-Voting-Report-FINAL.pdf">The report released today </a>chronicles the barriers Native voters face and recommends actions for policymakers at every level to help break these barriers down.  To live up to the recommendations of the report, the Department of the Interior is taking the unique step of translating it into six Native languages that reflect the regional consultation structure: Navajo, Yup&#8217;ik, Ojibwe, Cherokee, Lakota, and Native Hawaiian.  The translations will be available in writing and by audio.  </p>



<p>A few key recommendations from the report include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Congress should pass the Freedom to Vote Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act, which includes the Native American Voting Rights Act.&nbsp;&nbsp;States do not need to wait for Congress to take this action— they can and should pass legislation incorporating and building upon the protections in the Native American Voting Rights Act, as several states since 2017 have already done.</li><li>Federal, state, and local policymakers should institutionalize engagement of Tribal leaders and Native communities, including in ensuring that county and municipal election officials locate offices and polling places serving Native communities for convenience to Native voters, and staff those sites with well-trained, bilingual members of those communities.</li><li>The U.S. Postal Service should evaluate whether it can add routes, offices, and staff hours or personnel in areas serving Native communities, and should prioritize assigning postal addresses to homes on Tribal lands.</li><li>Government offices with significant presence serving Native communities should expeditiously offer their programs for state designation under the National Voter Registration Act, and state officials should accept those requests for designation.</li><li>Jurisdictions serving Native voters should ensure that they offer effective language assistance through adequate translation of materials in appropriate media, even when no statutory mandate compels them to do so.</li></ul>



<p>This important report is the product of an extensive effort across the Administration — and it is also just a beginning.&nbsp;&nbsp;There will be more to come in the weeks and months ahead, as agencies work with partners and allies to implement the report’s recommendations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Agencies have also been working to implement other provisions of the President’s Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting, offering nonpartisan information and opportunities to help eligible Americans participate.&nbsp;&nbsp;Those efforts will continue across the whole of government, with new actions rolling out as they are ready for release.&nbsp;&nbsp;A selection of recent developments from individual agencies follows:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The <strong>U.S.</strong> <strong>Small Business Administration</strong> formally requested designation by Michigan as a voter registration agency under the National Voter Registration Act, becoming the first federal agency to request designation in any state.  Designation would ensure that Americans seeking service from a designated District Office are offered convenient one-stop opportunities to register to vote at the same time.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Veterans Affairs </strong>launched a survey to over 12 million Veterans in a first-of-its-kind effort to better understand Veterans’ experience with the voter registration process, and to better assist Veterans in addressing and overcoming any challenges.  The Department also developed a website for Veterans with nonpartisan information about voter registration and elections at va.gov/vote: <a href="https://www.va.gov/initiatives/vote/?msclkid=4ee33ffaa97111ecaf6453e6663908f9">How Veterans Can Register To Vote | Veterans Affairs (va.gov)</a>.  And the Department announced that, by summer, it would launch a pilot program for VA Medical Centers and other offices in six states, with an eye to the geographic and demographic diversity of the Veteran population, seeking designation as a voter registration agency under the National Voter Registration Act.</li><li>The <strong>Department of the Interior</strong> announced that it is working with states to formally designate the Department-operated post-secondary Tribal institutions — Haskell Indian Nations University in Kansas and the Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute (SIPI) in New Mexico — as voter registration agencies under the National Voter Registration Act, facilitating voter registration opportunities for enrolled students and members of the community.  </li><li>With <strong>Treasury Department</strong> and IRS support, Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) sites throughout the country are assisting taxpayers with access to voting opportunities.  The VITA centers provide assistance to low-income taxpayers with their returns.  This year, over 450 VITA centers in 40 states have reported that they will provide information about voting opportunities.  The IRS has also placed voter registration information referring taxpayers to vote.gov in the Form 1040 Instructions both online and in print.</li><li>The <strong>National Institute of Standards and Technology</strong> at the Department of Commerce released a <a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.1273.pdf">report</a>examining barriers across the voting process for people with disabilities.  The report offers recommendations for state and local election officials, the federal government, and other non-governmental organizations to eliminate or mitigate those barriers.</li><li>The <strong>Office of Personnel Management</strong> issued <a href="https://chcoc.gov/content/executive-order-promoting-access-voting">guidance</a> to agencies to offer paid time off that will ensure that the thousands of federal employees in every state have time to vote and to serve in nonpartisan election-related capacities, including as volunteer poll workers.  The guidance amounts to a significant step in fulfilling the directive in the President’s Executive Order that the federal government should serve as a model employer in facilitating employees’ civic participation.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Justice</strong> is offering information and resources to individuals in federal custody to promote access to voting for those who remain eligible to vote while incarcerated or who will regain eligibility to vote upon their release. The Department also created an online resource for the public that connects them with state-specific information about registering and voting, details the Department’s enforcement of federal voting rights laws, and explains how to report potential violations.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Health and Human Services </strong>Health Resources and Services Administration issued <a href="https://bphc.hrsa.gov/programrequirements/scope/voter-requirements">guidance</a>for nearly 1,400 federally funded community health centers, with more than 14,000 service delivery sites providing primary care to nearly 29 million patients in underserved areas in every state across the country, clarifying the ways in which those health centers may support voter registration efforts.</li><li>At the <strong>Department of Housing and Urban Development</strong>, the Office of Public and Indian Housing <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PIH/documents/PIH_announcement020922.pdf">wrote</a> to more than 3,000 public housing authorities managing approximately 1.2 million public housing units, explaining the ways in which grantees may support voter registration and information about the electoral process. The Office of Multifamily Housing <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PIH/documents/AllVotingCommunications.pdf">reminded</a> multifamily owners and agents of HUD-assisted properties about residents’ voting rights and opportunities to support their exercise of the franchise. And the Office of Field Policy and Management connected with local election officers and placed voter registration materials in all 10 HUD Regional Offices across the country. </li><li>The <strong>U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness</strong> released best practices election checklists—in five different languages—to be distributed to <a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-voting-guide-for-people-experiencing-homelessness"><a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-voting-guide-for-people-experiencing-homelessness">voters experiencing homelessness</a> and to <a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-guide-for-homeless-service-providers-to-help-people-vote">service providers</a> who can help them register and vote. </a></li></ul>



<ul><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Labor</strong>&nbsp;is providing guidance to state and local workforce officials on how they can work with state elections officials to designate American Job Centers, which provide employment, training, and career services to workers in every state, as voter registration agencies under the National Voter Registration Act. The Department’s guidance also clarifies which programs receiving federal workforce development funds could support nonpartisan voter registration efforts.</li><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Agriculture</strong>&nbsp;Food and Nutrition Service issued letters to state agencies administering nutrition assistance programs to encourage the promotion of voter registration and non-partisan voting information.&nbsp;&nbsp;For state SNAP and WIC agencies, the letters remind states of their responsibilities under the National Voter Registration Act.</li><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Education</strong>&nbsp;will send a letter next week to institutions of higher education highlighting their responsibilities under the Higher Education Act to make a good faith effort to distribute voter registration forms to the more than 19 million students enrolled in these institutions.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Department last reminded institutions of this requirement in 2013.&nbsp;&nbsp;The letter will also explain the conditions under which work-study funds may be used to support nonpartisan community service activity related to the electoral process.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
