<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 15:58:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on the Administration&#8217;s Operational Plan for Vaccinating Children Under Five Against&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/09/background-press-call-on-the-administrations-operational-plan-for-vaccinating-children-under-five-against-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 15:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (June 8, 2022) 5:33 P.M. EDT MR. MUNOZ:&#160; All right.&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Thank you for joining us for a call to discuss the Biden administration’s plan &#8212; operational plan for vaccinating children with &#8212; against COVID-19.&#160; On today’s call we have [senior administration official].&#160; She is our [redacted].&#160; We also have [senior administration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(June 8, 2022)</p>



<p>5:33 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us for a call to discuss the Biden administration’s plan &#8212; operational plan for vaccinating children with &#8212; against COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On today’s call we have [senior administration official].&nbsp; She is our [redacted].&nbsp; We also have [senior administration official].&nbsp; And for questions, we also have [senior administration official].</p>



<p>With that, I will kick it to [senior administration official] for remarks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much, Kevin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks so much for joining the call.&nbsp; We’re very excited to talk to you about all the planning that we’ve been doing in anticipation of possible authorization and recommendation for pediatric doses for kids under five.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; So, let me start with the timeline we’re currently tracking.&nbsp; Right now, FDA is working through a rigorous and independent scientific process.</p>



<p>As part of that process, FDA’s advisory committee will meet next Tuesday, June 14th, and Wednesday, June 15th, to review the data submitted by both Pfizer and Moderna for their vaccines for kids under six and under five.</p>



<p>We expect &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you may have muted yourself.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry, I hit my &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I’m sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; so, I think I already went over.&nbsp; Next Tuesday, June 14th and June 15th, FDA’s VRBPAC will review the submissions by Pfizer and Moderna.&nbsp; We expect FDA’s decision shortly after these meetings.</p>



<p>And then, CDC has announced that ACIP, its advisory committee, will meet on Friday, June 17th, and Saturday, June 18th, after which the CDC director would issue her recommendation.</p>



<p>At that point, after all those actions are taken &#8212; if they are taken &#8212; vaccinations can begin.</p>



<p>As a reminder, Monday, June 20th, is an important federal holiday.&nbsp; So, those are the key dates that we’re tracking for this.</p>



<p>I do want to emphasize, you know, we think it’s important to do this right.&nbsp; That’s what this entire process is about.&nbsp; And we’re not going to prejudge the outcome of the decisions being considered by FDA and CDC.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; So, let’s talk about, you know, if FDA authorizes and CDC recommends one or both of the COVID-19 vaccines for this age group, it would be an historic milestone in the nation’s fight against the virus.&nbsp; It would mean that nearly every American is now eligible for the protection that vaccination provides.</p>



<p>We know that there are many parents who have been eagerly awaiting the opportunity to vaccinate their youngest kids, and we share their eagerness.&nbsp; Therefore, you know, every day, all day, right now, we are focusing on getting ready to have this as accessible as possible to as many families as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re going to immediately launch &#8212; you know, if, in fact, FDA authorizes and the CDC recommends, we’re going to immediately launch a comprehensive nationwide effort to ensure that parents can get their youngest kids vaccinated easily and do so at locations that they know and they trust.</p>



<p>We will also launch an effort to ensure that parents have answers to their questions and the facts that they need to make informed decisions for their kids.</p>



<p>Based on the timeline I outlined, we could see vaccines start to be delivered to sites over that long weekend.&nbsp; We do expect that many pediatricians’ offices will be closed to observe Juneteenth on that Monday.&nbsp; So, realistically, vaccines for our youngest kids could start in earnest as early as Tuesday, June 21st.</p>



<p>Importantly, we know that it will take some time to ramp up.&nbsp; As more doses are delivered and more appointments become available, within a few weeks, parents who want an appointment will be able to make one.</p>



<p>Vaccinations will be available at a variety of trusted locations, but we know that many families will actually turn to their pediatricians and primary care doctors.&nbsp; And we stand ready to support those frontline providers.</p>



<p>We encourage every provider who can take this on to sign up.&nbsp; And we encourage parents to reach out to their pediatricians or family doctors directly to learn more about their plans to offer appointments.</p>



<p>Vaccines.gov will also continue to be an important resource for the families who need it.</p>



<p>We are also ready to leverage federal programs that serve parents and families.</p>



<p>We’re going to be reaching out to millions of children and their parents and guardians nationwide through WIC and SNAP, through Head Start and childcare programs, through HUD-supported housing, and Medicaid, and CHIP.</p>



<p>The administration’s goal on COVID from day one has been to leave no stone unturned and to deploy every capability of the federal government.&nbsp; We will put that into practice and help to vaccinate America’s youngest kids.</p>



<p>Let me close by highlighting the work that we’re doing to reach every parent and child, including those who may have questions.</p>



<p>We’re going to work with trusted organizations like the American Academy of Pediatrics, the Association of Children’s Museums, the American Library Association, the National PTA, the National Diaper Bank Network, and the National Association of Community Health Centers, as well as a number of Black, Latino, AANHPI, and Native American community-based organizations.</p>



<p>These organizations will work on a national and local level to help raise awareness and answer questions through a variety of activities.</p>



<p>We’re also going to activate our 17,000-plus-member HHS COVID-19 Community Corps, which will help provide creative, kid-focused English and Spanish toolkits to trusted local messengers.</p>



<p>This type of work will not always make headlines, but it’s the kind of local, community-by-community, person-to-person approach that has worked to date in getting over twenty- &#8212; 220 million Americans fully vaccinated.</p>



<p>With that, I’m going to turn it over to my colleague, [senior administration official].&nbsp; [Senior administration official]?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], thanks so much.&nbsp; Wonderful to be here.</p>



<p>You know, over the past 16 months, together with our partners, we have managed one of the most complex logistical challenges in our nation’s history: delivering more than 700 million doses of COVID-19 vaccine to more than 90,000 locations nationwide.</p>



<p>Today, as [senior administration official] said, more than 220 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; But we know that our work is not done yet.</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] noted, having COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of five would be a significant milestone in our historic vaccination program, helping extend the protection that vaccines offer to our youngest Americans and some additional peace of mind to parents and guardians.</p>



<p>Our objective is clear: to be ready to swiftly and efficiently deliver vaccines for kids under the age of five to communities nationwide as soon as the FDA grants emergency use authorization.&nbsp; And we are ready.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To achieve our objective, we have engaged state, local, Tribal, and territorial health departments; pediatricians and primary care providers; children’s hospitals and health systems; and pharmacies on operational planning.</p>



<p>These are many of the same partners we have been engaged with on other vaccination and COVID-19 response efforts over the past few years.&nbsp; These partners are on the frontlines and critical to success, and we stand ready to help them in any way that we can.</p>



<p>Last week, we opened up pre-ordering for states, Tribes, territories, and other partners to order in advance.&nbsp; And this would help place initial doses of vaccines to be sent in the first ordering wave.&nbsp; We are making 10 million doses of vaccine available initially, with millions more available in the coming weeks.</p>



<p>This approach allows us to seed communities with enough vaccine so that it is readily accessible and equitably distributed across the county.</p>



<p>We estimate that 85 percent of children under the age of five live within five miles of a potential vaccination site.</p>



<p>We have asked states and other partners to leverage prior pediatric vaccination best practices and tap into existing pediatric vaccination locations as they continue to sign up additional pediatricians and providers.</p>



<p>We have also asked states and other partners to ensure equity, giving priority to sites that will vaccinate children at highest risk for severe COVID-19 disease and considering factors such as hours of operation.</p>



<p>At this point in the Biden administration’s vaccination program, our partners are accustomed to this process, and so are we.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our teams are standing by and will immediately begin shipping vaccines across the country after FDA authorizes a vaccine should FDA authorize a vaccine.</p>



<p>It will take some time to position these vaccines across the country, and vaccinations can’t begin until CDC has made its decision.&nbsp; But we also know many parents have been waiting for a long time, so we will be working 24/7 until every dose is shipped and delivered.</p>



<p>As we have said previously, we are not in the predicting business; we&#8217;re in the planning business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our teams are hard at work planning for the possibility that FDA and CDC will give the green light in the near future.&nbsp; And if and when they do, we will be ready to deliver.</p>



<p>Thanks so much.&nbsp; And back to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Kevin?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s do a few questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Spencer Kimball at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; So the ordering started last week, you said.&nbsp; How many doses of the initial 10 million have been ordered so far by pharmacies in the states?&nbsp; And how much more vaccine do you expect to come online in the coming weeks?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; So we did open ordering last week.&nbsp; We made 5 million initially available in wave one.&nbsp; Fifty-eight percent of the Pfizer total threshold was ordered.&nbsp; Thirty-four percent of the Moderna threshold was ordered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We had 53 of 62 jurisdictions ordering, and we&#8217;re currently talking to the other jurisdictions to remind them that it would be important to go ahead and get in line and place some orders.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to open a second wave today.&nbsp; So those that have additional space to order, there are another 5 million available of the first 10 million.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re continuing to manage that to make sure that we&#8217;ve got these waves well accounted for and the vaccines seeded appropriately across the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you just &#8212; what did you mean by “thresholds”? I didn&#8217;t quite understand that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve made &#8212; you know, of the 5 million, we&#8217;ve made &#8212; let me make sure I&#8217;ve got this &#8212; we&#8217;ve made half of that.&nbsp; So 2.5 Pfizer doses and 2.5 Moderna doses available.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; (Inaudible) at NPR.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could clarify where kids can get vaccinated.&nbsp; I know that you&#8217;re focusing on pediatricians and doctors’ offices, but, you know, will there also be, like, mass vaccination sites set up for kids?&nbsp; Will there be daycare and preschool campaigns?&nbsp; Like, where is the breadth of places that people can go?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s [senior administration official].&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll take a swing at this, and then [senior administration official] &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; [senior administration official] can fill in any details that I missed.</p>



<p>But, obviously, we believe that most people are going to go to their pediatrician or their primary care provider if they have one.&nbsp; However, we recognize that that&#8217;s not everyone, and so we really do want to reach anybody who wants to get a vaccine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re looking at working with our &#8212; well, we are definitely working with our federal pharmacy partners so that you can get them at pharmacies.&nbsp; We’re also working with state and local health departments in terms of setting up clinics.&nbsp; And then we’re looking at ways to set up other sort of non-traditional sites as well.</p>



<p>And, [senior administration official], do you want to talk a little bit about &#8212; more detail on that?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; So as [senior administration official] said and as you’ll see in the factsheet, I think that just landed in your inbox, a wide variety of sites available based on the preferences of parents and guardians and families.</p>



<p>The one I&#8217;d add to [senior administration official]’s (inaudible) is: Children&#8217;s hospitals and health systems, they will play a critical role in reaching the highest-risk kids in our country and in doing high volume, both through their care locations, both in the inpatient and outpatient setting, as well as through community-based clinics and trusted locations.</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] said &#8212; that we anticipate that as kids get younger, they are less likely to go to large clinics.&nbsp; You want to have that one-on-one time with a provider.</p>



<p>So &#8212; but we do know that these clinics will play some role.&nbsp; And for the sites that are ready, we&#8217;ll be working with childcare sites, we&#8217;ll be working with museums and libraries to set up these clinics in partnerships with &#8212; in partnerships with providers, in partnerships with hospitals, and make sure that communities are getting access in places that they know and trust.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you guys.&nbsp; So I wanted to just quickly go back to those numbers that [senior administration official] had mentioned.&nbsp; It seems like there are still 2.7 million unordered doses then from that first tranche.&nbsp; Is that expected?&nbsp; Do you have any explanation for why that would be lower?&nbsp; Have you had conversations with states about Biden not ordering more?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Our experience has been that people are slow to order, and this has been true across each of the times we&#8217;ve opened up ordering.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I wouldn&#8217;t focus on those early numbers.&nbsp; We &#8212; you know, we &#8212; our experience is that the longer the ordering stays open, the more likely the states come forward.&nbsp; So some of this is a matter of letting them know the ordering is available and that they can begin that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those are just the early numbers.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not too worried or focused on that, and we&#8217;ll continue to do these outreach.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not, you know, untypical to what we&#8217;ve seen in previous waves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And about the diff- &#8212; (inaudible) &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I would just quickly add too, from our perspective, it&#8217;s one of the reasons why the federal health centers and rural health clinics program out of HRSA and federal pharmacy program play such a critical role in making sure we&#8217;re able to get directly to these providers in the earliest days of the program launch.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let’s go to Alyssa Rosenberg at Washington Post.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Can you tell us a little bit more about what you&#8217;ve learned from the vaccination campaigns for older kids about the concerns that parents have?&nbsp; And are there ways that you&#8217;re tailoring information and messaging to both parents and providers about the vaccine that build on these previous campaigns and what you&#8217;ve seen about if either parents were enthusiastic or parents were hesitant?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, good question.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; And, again, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] in a second.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we have learned from our previous campaigns.&nbsp; And one of the most important lessons that we&#8217;ve learned is that, you know, we know who people listen to when making decisions, and there are trusted people in their lives.&nbsp; And some of them are doctors, some of them are community leaders.&nbsp; We are going to meet people where they are and answer their questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, what we are trying to do is we are trying to ensure that those people in communities, including pediatricians, have the information that they need to answer parents’ questions.</p>



<p>And so, you know, I think our goals are twofold: to make sure that the product is available and to make sure that parents have the information that they need about the vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official]?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, just a little additional detail on some of the exciting stuff we have underway.&nbsp; And, again, you&#8217;ll see this in the factsheet.&nbsp; We&#8217;re really excited about the role that the Community Corps is going to play in this.&nbsp; This is a network of providers and trusted messengers across the United States, and we&#8217;re going to make sure they have a whole host of resources to reach their communities with.&nbsp; You know, these are people communities know and trust.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, two, as [senior administration official] said, working in close partnership with major medical associations, we know that parents look to providers for that trusted medical advice and that they&#8217;ll be looking to providers to answer questions they may have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ll be working with AAP to launch a speakers bureau so that community organizations can request a trusted doc come and visit with communities and partake in community events to answer questions and encourage uptake.&nbsp; Really excited about that one.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see another &#8212; a bunch of other examples in that factsheet as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to follow up on that &#8212; you&#8217;ve talked a lot about the specific &#8212; about the people who are trusted, but are there specific messages that you&#8217;re trying to get out, specific concerns you&#8217;re trying to get ahead of?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think, you know, on the messages, we’ll wait for FDA and CDC to fully review and share their findings on the data.&nbsp; Then we&#8217;ll have more to share on what we can say about safety and efficacy and ways that we can keep kids and their families safe.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let’s go to Alex Tin at CBS News.&nbsp; Alex, you’re unmuted.</p>



<p>All right, we’ll go back to Alex.</p>



<p>Let’s go to Ahmed at Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; So, there are a lot of differences between the Moderna shot and the Pfizer shot for this age group, the biggest being that Moderna is two doses and Pfizer is three.&nbsp; So if both get authorized, do you plan to distribute them differently?&nbsp; Will parents be able to opt for one or the other easily?</p>



<p>And similarly, if the manufacturers decide to do a strain change in the vaccines for adults to an Omicron-specific shot like they&#8217;re talking about, would there be plans to change the pediatric vaccine as well?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if you want to start there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hello, sorry, I couldn&#8217;t get off mute.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.&nbsp; Okay, so, in terms of the question about strain change: I think for right now, you know, we’re just looking at what is under review.&nbsp; You know, it is what it is right now.&nbsp; And I think, you know, at some point down the road there will be discussions.&nbsp; FDA is having discussions about strain changes, but, you know, right now, these are the products that are under review.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of distribution, I don’t &#8212; [senior administration official], do you want to talk about distribution of the doses?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, thanks.&nbsp; Great question.&nbsp; We&#8217;re making the same number of doses available both of Pfizer and of Moderna.&nbsp; So we aren&#8217;t making &#8212; you know, we aren&#8217;t prejudging any decisions made by FDA or CDC on what they might authorize or recommend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in our pre-ordering phase &#8212; which just began Friday, I want to remind everybody &#8212; we&#8217;re making equal numbers available and plan to distribute whatever is ordered.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let’s try Alex again.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Let’s go to Lourdes Torres at Univision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One, two, three.&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Alex, hello.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Sorry for the tech issues.&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on something that was mentioned earlier.&nbsp; You said that ordering seemed to be higher for Pfizer than Moderna.&nbsp; What are you hearing from jurisdictions as to why that is?&nbsp; Have you had any conversations about whether that will affect availability of people who prefer, say, Moderna over Pfizer?&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not in a position to know exactly how this is going to look.&nbsp; Again, the ordering started on Friday.&nbsp; The numbers I shared are very, very early days numbers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we did see, which is interesting, is we saw some states and jurisdictions only order Moderna.&nbsp; We saw some states and jurisdictions only order Pfizer.&nbsp; And, of course, this is just in those first early days where the second wave of ordering is going to allow these states and jurisdictions to come back and balance out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we, at this point, I think, don&#8217;t have numbers that can tell us one way or the other.&nbsp; And our job is to make both available in equal numbers.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let&#8217;s try Lourdes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Given that the numbers are very early in terms of the pre-ordering, would you feel comfortable sharing a list of the ones that have ordered and the ones that have not &#8212; the states that have not, at this point?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re still so early in.&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t want to &#8212; you know, there &#8212; we have those folks that do things on the first day anything opens, and we have those folks that wait until the last minute just by virtue of &#8212; you know, of various differences among all of our states and jurisdictions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are currently working with those that have not placed orders yet, and anticipate each of them placing orders by the end of the ordering period.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re in a position at this point to share those &#8212; those names.&nbsp; If that changes, we&#8217;ll get back to you for sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Last question. &nbsp;Let&#8217;s go to Anita Powell at VOA.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Just quickly: During the Quad summit, two months ago now, the U.S. committed to donating a number of pediatric doses to foreign countries in need.&nbsp; And I was just wondering if that was part of the planning for this, where you are on this.&nbsp; And, yeah, if you could just update us on that pledge.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; [Senior administration official]?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; That plan is still underway.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce on that today, but in the near future, I expect that we will have an announcement on that.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; And, Anita, those are 5-to-11 doses that we&#8217;ve committed to, just to clarify.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, thank you everybody for joining tonight.&nbsp; You all should all have a factsheet embargoed until 5:00 a.m.&nbsp; This call is embargoed until 5:00 a.m., and a reminder that it’s attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; You know where to find me if you have any questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>5:57 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Tackling Climate Change and&#160;Creating </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-tackling-climate-change-and-creating/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our hemisphere is facing the devastating impacts and costs of climate change. We must tackle the climate crisis and harness the opportunity for countries in the region to create good-paying jobs, grow clean energy economies, and build resilient communities.&#160;&#160;At the Summit of the Americas, President Biden will affirm the U.S. commitment’s to building an enduring&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Our hemisphere is facing the devastating impacts and costs of climate change. We must tackle the climate crisis and harness the opportunity for countries in the region to create good-paying jobs, grow clean energy economies, and build resilient communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;At the Summit of the Americas, President Biden will affirm the U.S. commitment’s to building an enduring hemispheric partnership to address climate change, create jobs, and advance energy security.</p>



<p><strong>U.S.-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis 2030 (PACC 2030):&nbsp;</strong>Vice President Harris will launch PACC 2030,&nbsp;a new framework to elevate U.S. cooperation with Caribbean countries to support climate adaptation and strengthen energy security, while building the resilience of critical infrastructure and local economies to the climate crisis.&nbsp;&nbsp;To achieve these objectives, PACC 2030 will organize its activities and programs under four pillars: 1) Improving Access to Development Financing; 2) Facilitating Clean Energy Project Development and Investment; 3) Enhancing Local Capacity Building; and 4) Deepening Collaboration with our Caribbean Partners.&nbsp;&nbsp;PACC 2030 will work towards meeting the objectives of the Paris Climate Agreement and the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</p>



<p><strong>Strengthening the Clean Energy Economy: </strong>The United States announced it will promote greater trade and investment in clean energy, and increase support for regional cooperation through the Renewable Energy in Latin America and the Caribbean (RELAC) initiative.  Five new countries announced on June 9 their intention to join RELAC, joining 15 other countries that have already signed on to this one-of-a-kind collective effort to reach 70% installed capacity for renewable energy generation in the region’s electricity sector by 2030.  The Administration is also announcing its intent to provide funding support for technical cooperation on regulatory and policy frameworks under RELAC and to work with regional development banks, private financial institutions, and other partners to mobilize additional resources.</p>



<p><strong>100,000 Strong in the Americas Climate Initiative (100K CLIMA):</strong>&nbsp;100K CLIMA will build on region-wide alliances between industry, governments, and 2,500 higher education institutions to catalyze climate action and collaboration by equipping students with technical and linguistics skills to lead in a clean energy economy.&nbsp;&nbsp;This initiative is supported by the Department of State with leading private sector partners, as well as the CAF Development Bank of Latin America.&nbsp;&nbsp;A diverse array of U.S. colleges and universities will be included in 100K CLIMA, providing critical access to&nbsp;new models of inclusive education exchange programs for students and faculty from Minority Serving Institutions (MSIs), Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) and Hispanic Serving Institutions (HSIs). 100K CLIMA will increase innovative models of social inclusion in training, exchanges, and workforce development programs in the pursuit of a more sustainable future for our hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Mobilizing Climate Finance:&nbsp;</strong>In response to a collective commitment from four regional development banks to make as much as $50 billion available over the next five years to support ambitious climate action, the United States is enhancing coordination with these institutions to mobilize additional financing from the private sector and other sources.&nbsp;&nbsp;The four banks are the Inter-American Development Bank, where the United States is the largest shareholder, the Development Bank of Latin America (CAF), the Caribbean Development Bank (CDB), and the Central American Bank for Economic Integration (CABEI).&nbsp;&nbsp;Several U.S. Government agencies, including the U.S. Department of State, the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, the U.S. Agency for International Development, the U.S. Trade and Development Agency, and the Export-Import Bank of the United States will support this effort.</p>



<p><strong>Amazonia Connect: </strong>In recognition of the potential for forests and other ecosystems to provide as much as one-third of global climate mitigation by 2030, the United States announced its intent to provide $12 million to support Brazil, Colombia, and Peru through Amazonia Connect.  This initiative will contribute to the President’s Plan to Conserve Global Forests: Critical Carbon Sinks by reducing commodity-driven deforestation and associated greenhouse gas emissions from agricultural supply chains while conserving biodiversity, improving livelihoods, and enhancing climate resilience.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:Biden Administration Announces Operational Plan for COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccinations for Children Under&#160;5</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheetbiden-administration-announces-operational-plan-for-covid-19-vaccinations-for-children-under-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 strategy, including a historic vaccination program that has gotten 220 million Americans fully vaccinated, over 100 million people a booster shot, and made vaccines free, widely available and convenient—daily COVID-19 deaths are down 90 percent since he took office. COVID-19 vaccines remain the single-most important tool that we have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 strategy, including a historic vaccination program that has gotten 220 million Americans fully vaccinated, over 100 million people a booster shot, and made vaccines free, widely available and convenient—daily COVID-19 deaths are down 90 percent since he took office.<br><br>COVID-19 vaccines remain the single-most important tool that we have to protect people against COVID-19 and its most serious outcomes. Next week, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) will consider whether to authorize and recommend the first COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of 5. If FDA authorizes and CDC recommends one or both of the COVID-19 vaccines for this age group, it would be a historic milestone in the nation’s fight against the virus—and would mean nearly every American is eligible for the protection that vaccination provides.<br><br>Today, the Biden Administration is announcing an operational plan that will ensure that vaccines—if authorized by FDA and recommended by CDC—are readily available for our youngest kids and that we continue the critical work of ensuring that all families know the benefits of getting their children vaccinated against COVID-19.<br><br>The Administration’s vaccination program for America’s youngest children will focus on addressing the specific needs of this age group and their families—recognizing that many parents and guardians will choose to get their kids vaccinated through their pediatrician or primary care doctor. As always, state and local governments, health care providers, federal pharmacy partners, national and community-based organizations, and other entities will be critical to the success of this historic, nationwide effort. And, the Administration will continue to work with trusted messengers, including pediatricians, to make a concerted effort to ensure that all families have answers to their questions and know about the importance of getting their children vaccinated.<br><br>As the FDA and CDC conduct their independent review processes, the Biden Administration is planning for all scenarios, including for the first vaccinations to start as early as the week of June 20th—with the program ramping up over time as more doses are delivered and more appointments become available.<br><br>For months, the Administration has been working with a range of stakeholders to get ready. The Administration has made 10 million vaccine doses available for states, Tribes, territories, community health centers, federal pharmacy partners, and others to pre-order. If the FDA authorizes a vaccine, the Administration will immediately begin shipping doses across the country—and will launch an effort to ensure that parents can get their youngest children vaccinated easily. 85 percent of children under the age of five live within five miles of a potential vaccination site.<br><br><strong>The Biden Administration’s plan includes:</strong><br><br><strong><u>Securing vaccine supply for our nation’s children.</u></strong> The Administration has procured a significant supply of vaccines for this age group, with 10 million doses available initially and millions more available in the coming weeks. To ensure that we are able to reach a broad range of pediatric providers—including those in smaller practices and in rural settings—vaccines will be available in package sizes of 100 doses and will come with all of the supplies that health care providers need to serve younger kids, including small needles.<br><br><strong><u>Making vaccinations available in convenient places parents and families know and trust.</u></strong> Working with states, localities, Tribes and territories, the Administration will make vaccinations for our nation’s youngest children widely available at thousands of trusted, accessible sites across the country—with 85 percent of children under the age of five living within five miles of a potential vaccination site. Vaccinations will be available at pediatricians’ and other doctors’ offices, community health centers, rural health clinics, children’s hospitals, public health clinics, local pharmacies, and other community-based organizations. The Administration will also work with state and local public health departments and others to ensure that every child—including those who may not have a pediatrician or primary care provider—has access to the vaccine. And, the Administration will work with states and other entities to make vaccinations available at convenient hours for children, parents and their guardians—including after school and evenings, and on weekends.</p>



<ul><li>Pediatricians and primary care providers: The Administration will make vaccinations available at thousands of pediatric and primary care sites across the country. Pediatricians continue to be one of the most trusted sources of information about COVID-19 for parents and will play a critical role in the nationwide effort to get our youngest children vaccinated—as they are the most common, trusted location for routine childhood vaccines. More than three in four children under the age of five receive their flu vaccine in a doctor’s office. Well-patient visits are also an opportunity for pediatric providers to conduct recommended screenings and provide counseling. The Administration is working hand-in-hand with states, localities, Tribes, and territories to prioritize these providers and ensure that they have the supply, resources, and support they need. The Administration will also continue to make vaccines available directly to health centers and rural health clinics, who together serve more than 2.2 million children under five nationwide.<br></li><li>Children’s hospitals and health systems: The Administration will make vaccinations available at more than 100 children’s hospitals and health systems nationwide. Children’s hospitals play an essential role in our efforts to ensure access for our nation&#8217;s highest-risk kids, including those with obesity, diabetes, asthma or immunosuppression. &nbsp;Through the Administration&#8217;s partnership with the Children&#8217;s Hospital Association, more than 120 children&#8217;s hospitals across 47 states and D.C. will provide pediatric vaccinations across their health care systems and in trusted community sites.<br></li><li>State and local public health clinics and sites: The Administration will build on its longstanding work with state and local health departments across the country to ensure that we are reaching those hardest-to-reach, including families who may not have regular access to a pediatrician, through public health clinics. The Administration will make available federal funding to support states as they stand up and operate these clinics, and will work hand-in-hand with states to maximize vaccination coverage and availability, particularly in the hardest-hit, highest-risk communities.<br></li><li>Local pharmacies: The Administration will make vaccinations for children available at thousands of local pharmacies nationwide through the federal pharmacy program. Participating pharmacies will offer vaccinations for this age group in a more limited set of locations, in many cases at clinics staffed by health care providers with primary care experience. And pharmacies will offer convenient hours and advanced scheduling to best meet the needs of parents and communities.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Leveraging federal programs to reach parents and families with information and advance equity.</u></strong> As with prior vaccination efforts, the Administration will leverage existing federal programs and capabilities to ensure that we are reaching parents and families with the information they need. And, as always, the Administration will remain laser-focused on equity and making sure that we reach those hardest-hit and most at-risk communities.</p>



<ul><li>Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) Program: In addition to other U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs, the Administration will engage families through the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) program, which serves over 6 million people, including almost half of all infants born in the United States. A longstanding partner to immunization programs, WIC settings across the country will be provided with tailored resources for talking to families about the COVID-19 vaccine and will continue providing families with referrals to vaccination providers, including those co-located with WIC settings.<br></li><li>Head Start Program: Through the Administration for Children and Families at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the Administration will work with Head Start grantees to get critical vaccination information to the approximately 1 million families they serve. Head Start has always played a crucial role in improving health outcomes for families, and COVID-19 is no different. The Administration will support training and resources for grantees to learn about vaccines for kids under five and how grantees can talk to families about them, and it will ensure that any Head Start location is ready and able to provide vaccinations to its community gets the help it needs.<br></li><li>Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting (MIECHV) Program: The Administration will engage families through HHS’ Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting (MIECHV) Program, which each year reaches more than 140,000 parents and young children across the country that are at risk for poor maternal and child health outcomes. MIECHV home visitors will leverage these established relationships to help families learn more about COVID-19 and the safety, efficacy, and benefits of COVID-19 vaccines and, upon request, will refer families to local vaccination sites.<br></li><li>Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) programs: The Administration will launch an effort to reach more than 800,000 children age five and under supported by HUD programs, including children in households that receive housing-choice vouchers and children living in public housing and Section 8 housing. Building on successful campaigns with children in other age groups, these efforts will include education events and on-site vaccination clinics near HUD-supported housing where appropriate, in coordination with other vaccination locations in the community.<br></li><li>Medicaid and the Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP): The Center for Medicaid &amp; Medicare Services (CMS) will take steps to support and push the message about the importance of vaccinating the millions of children under 5 who are enrolled in Medicaid and CHIP. This outreach will involve engaging states, local jurisdictions, and stakeholders to get the latest information on vaccines for this age group to Medicaid beneficiaries and their families. This effort builds on the work that CMS has already done to require state Medicaid programs to pay health care providers for providing counseling visits to parents and guardians about the importance of kids’ vaccination—giving families the support they need to engage with trusted community providers.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Supporting education and engagement efforts to build trust among parents and families.</u></strong> While many parents are eager to vaccinate their youngest children, others have questions. To ensure that parents and families have answers to their questions and information from sources that they trust, HHS will work with a broad range of national organizations to launch a national public education campaign that reaches parents, guardians, and families with facts and information that they need to make informed choices for both their youngest and their older children.</p>



<ul><li>The HHS COVID-19 Community Corps will reach parents and families about vaccinations for kids under the age of five. Launched last April to empower people and organizations to build vaccine confidence in their communities, the Community Corps now has over 17,000 members, including health care, faith, rural, sports, and youth organizations. The ‘HHS We Can Do This’ campaign will provide a pediatric COVID-19 vaccination toolkit—in both English and Spanish—to trusted messengers, health care providers, and state and local organizations so they can reach people where they are in-person and online. HHS will also provide additional materials for stakeholders, including a superhero-themed toolkit with creative resources for hospitals and pediatricians. And, pending FDA authorization and CDC recommendation, the Administration also plans to release a new public service announcement (PSA) letting parents of children 6 months and older know that the new COVID-19 vaccines are available and offer one more way to keep their children safe. The PSA, filmed in both English and Spanish, will be distributed broadly to local television and radio networks, and would air in early July.<br></li><li>American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) and American Academy of Family Physicians (AAFP), two leading medical, will provide a “Speaker’s Bureau” of pediatricians and family doctors who will lend their trusted voices to raise awareness, answer common questions among parents, and encourage vaccine confidence through community events, vaccine and health fairs, and other key opportunities to reach parents. AAP and AAFP will also work with HHS to co-brand a toolkit of resources geared toward pediatricians and primary care doctors, providing these and other health care providers the information and materials they need to support vaccine confidence among their patients and parents.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Association of Children’s Museums (ACM), a champion for children’s museums with more than 460 members in 50 states and 19 countries, will work with local member museums to: host vaccine pop-up clinics; provide in-person and virtual events including information sessions, community forums, and other events featuring museum leaders and medical experts to answer parent questions; display a museum exhibit providing educational information about vaccination in English and Spanish; and amplify digital and social content to reach families.<br></li><li>The National Diaper Bank Network, a nationwide organization with more than 200 member diaper bank programs that distributed over 68 million diapers last year, will distribute educational material to parents and caregivers through member diaper banks, packing fact sheets, postcards, and other materials in diaper boxes, sharing resources with local agency partners, and hosting virtual and in-person events with pediatricians and other trusted messengers.<br></li><li>The American Library Association (ALA) will provide resources to assist the nation’s 17,000 public libraries in providing trusted vaccine information to parents and guardians.&nbsp;ALA will conduct a national webinar for librarians and staff featuring a pediatrician from AAP and other trusted messengers to provide information to public librarians and staff on how they can support vaccine education and outreach, share resources through children’s programming, and host in-person events and vaccine pop-up clinics to promote vaccines in their communities. Public libraries have played an important role in the pandemic by equipping their communities with trusted information, supplies like masks and COVID-19 tests, and hosting pop-up vaccine clinics.<br></li><li>The National Parent Teacher Association (PTA) has been hosting dozens of vaccine pop-up clinics to reach parents, teachers, and school staff. The National PTA will continue to engage parents of school-aged children, as well as parents of younger children, by hosting a national symposium for local PTA leaders and affiliates featuring a pediatrician from AAP and other trusted messengers; hosting vaccine pop-up clinics in key geographic markets to reach parents of both school-aged and younger children; and hosting virtual events to reach parents and empower community leaders to act as trusted messengers and amplify vaccine information.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The National Association of Community Health Centers (NACHC), the leading association for community health centers, will provide culturally appropriate and evidence-based training to empower community health centers to act as trusted messengers with parents of school-aged and younger children and other patients in their communities. NACHC will also host virtual events, including webinars, trainings, and podcasts to aid in the dissemination of campaign materials and messaging about the importance of vaccinations for young children, and how community health workers can play a key role in reaching parents with trusted messaging.<br></li><li>Latino community-focused organizations, including the League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC), the largest and oldest Hispanic serving organization in the US with over 1,000 LULAC Councils, will hold in-person and virtual educational events for parents and caregivers and will design and distribute bilingual, culturally relevant resources (printed and digital) to community members and partner organizations.<br></li><li>Black community-focused organizations, including the W. Montague Cobb Health Institute, a consortium of scholars working toward the elimination of racial and ethnic health disparities within the National Medical Association, will host “Stay Well Health Fairs and Vaccine Clinics,” an ongoing series of health fairs offering free vaccines, educational materials, health screenings, and pediatric roundtables featuring subject matter experts. The Women’s Missionary Society Foundation, with 800,000 members across the African Methodist Episcopal (AME) Church’s boundaries, will host “family fun day” vaccine events reaching Black families and will collaborate with AME Church daycares and pre-schools to share information and messaging about pediatric vaccines.<br></li><li>Asian American, Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander community-focused organizations, including the Asian Community Development Council, The Progressive Vietnamese American Organization, Ethnic Minorities of Burma Advocacy and Resource Center, Chinese Community Center, Filipino Family Health Initiative, and Thai Community Development Center will: engage with local communities in Chinese, Korean, Vietnamese, Tagalog and other languages where possible through in-person engagement, phone banking, social media and written resources; reach families through WIC Market Match, which serves parents with small children who are on WIC; and host weekly vaccine clinics and vaccine education classes and events.<br></li><li>Native American community organizations, including Native Roots Radio, a leading radio station for Native Americans to discuss local, regional, and national Native American news and events will conduct virtual conversations including&nbsp;physicians, community advocates, and Tribal leadership speaking on the COVID-19 pandemic including vaccinations for children, boosters, mental health and long COVID; and the USDA Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations in partnership with the Great Plains Tribal Leaders Health Board will distribute educational materials to food distribution centers to be packaged in food boxes promoting vaccinations that are regionally and culturally tailored to Native American audiences.</li></ul>



<p>What to Expect, a platform of over 20 million moms, will author a blog series featuring doctors and other trusted experts answering questions about pediatric COVID-19 vaccines, and how moms, expecting moms, and all parents can get the information they need to get themselves and their children vaccinated; author new articles dispelling myths about the COVID-19 vaccine and children; and create and amplify new What to Expect social media content, reaching moms where they are and fighting vaccine misinformation across all platforms.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Proposes New Standards for National Electric Vehicle Charging&#160;Network</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-proposes-new-standards-for-national-electric-vehicle-charging-network/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Investments to Enable Families to Plug-In, Charge Up, and Drive Across America Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new steps to meet President Biden’s goal to build out the first-ever national network of 500,000 electric vehicle chargers along America’s highways and in communities, a key piece of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Investments to Enable Families to Plug-In, Charge Up, and Drive Across America</em></p>



<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new steps to meet President Biden’s goal to build out the first-ever national network of 500,000 electric vehicle chargers along America’s highways and in communities, a key piece of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</p>



<p>The Department of Transportation, in partnership with the Department of Energy, is <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/biden-harris-administration-takes-key-step-forward-building-national-network-user">proposing new standards</a> to make charging electric vehicles (EVs) a convenient, reliable, and affordable for all Americans, including when driving long distances. Without strong standards, chargers would be less reliable, may not work for all cars, or lack common payment methods. The new standards will ensure everyone can use the network –no matter what car you drive or which state you charge in.</p>



<p>The proposed standards, along with new coordinated federal actions on EVs, support President’s Biden’s priorities &nbsp;to lower costs for families, create good-paying jobs, and combat climate change. He is pressing Congress on his plan to provide tax credits that make EVs more affordable, so families’ budgets aren’t hurt by volatile gas prices. The actions will spur good-paying jobs with strong workforce requirements for America’s steelworkers, electrical workers, and laborers to build, install, and maintain the network. And, making chargers and EVs more accessible will help tackle the climate crisis – reducing emissions, increasing cleaner air, and advancing the President’s Justice40 Initiative.</p>



<p>Thanks to President Biden’s bold vision, leadership, and actions EV sales have doubled since he took office, and there are now more than two million EVs and 100,000 chargers on the road. The Biden Administration has positioned the United States to lead the electric future and make it in America:</p>



<ul><li>Secured historic investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law – $7.5 billion for EV charging infrastructure and more than $7 billion for the critical minerals supply chains necessary for batteries, components, materials, and recycling.</li><li>United automakers and autoworkers around an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">ambitious target</a> for 50% of new vehicles sold in 2030 to be electric.</li><li>Triggered a string of investment commitments of over $100 billion from private companies to make more EVs and their parts in America, create jobs for our autoworkers, and strengthen our domestic supply chains.</li><li>Activated the purchasing power of the federal government to procure 100% zero-emission light-duty vehicles by 2027 and all vehicles by 2035.</li><li>Finalized the strongest passenger vehicle emissions and fuel economy standards in history.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Historic Infrastructure Investments in Charging</u></strong></p>



<p>The $7.5 billion for EV charging infrastructure in President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will build a convenient and equitable charging network through two programs. The National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure (NEVI) program will provide $5 billion in formula funding to States to build out charging infrastructure along highway corridors – filling gaps in rural, disadvantaged, and hard-to-reach locations while instilling public confidence in charging. Today’s minimum standards and requirements will guide States on how to spend federal funds in a way that makes chargers function the same from state-to-state, easy to find, use, and pay for, no matter who operates chargers. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law also provides $2.5 billion in competitive grants to support community and corridor charging, improve local air quality, and increase EV charging access in underserved and overburdened communities. &nbsp;DOT will open applications for this program later this year.</p>



<p>These federal charging programs were designed to catalyze additional private sector investments that complement the build-out of a user-friendly, cost-saving, and financially sustainable national EV charging network. Together, President Biden’s leadership is mobilizing public and private charging investment to accelerate the adoption of EVs and create good-paying jobs across manufacturing, installation, and operation. These chargers will also make sure the new renewable electricity sources like solar and wind can power the cars we drive and reduce energy costs for families.</p>



<p><strong><u>Setting the Standard</u></strong></p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law also established a <a href="https://driveelectric.gov/">Joint Office of Energy and Transportation</a> to work hand-in-hand with States, industry leaders, manufacturers, and other stakeholders to meet the President&#8217;s goals. And to ensure that this electric transformation is both timely and equitable, Vice President Harris launched an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/">EV Charging Action Plan</a> that fast tracks federal investments and targets equity benefits for disadvantaged communities – and the Department of Transportation released a <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/rural/ev/toolkit">Rural EV toolkit</a> to help ensure all Americans, regardless of where they live, have the opportunity to benefit from the lower operating costs, reduced maintenance needs, and improved performance that EVs provide. These investments, steered by the standards proposed today, will create a public charging system that meets our goals of being reliable, affordable, equitable and seamless between states and networks. They will also use workforce standards such as the Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP) to increase the safety and reliability of charging station’s functionality and usability – creating and supporting good-paying, highly-skilled union jobs in communities across the country.</p>



<p><strong><u>Additional Steps to Drive Progress</u></strong></p>



<p>Today, as part of an Administration-wide strategy, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a fleet of actions from nine federal agencies across the charging ecosystem to complement the NEVI program – creating good-paying jobs in the U.S., reducing emissions, and putting us on a path to net-zero emissions by 2050.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The</strong> <strong>Joint Office of Energy and Transportation</strong> <a href="https://driveelectric.gov/work-with-us/">announced the formation</a> of a new Federal Advisory Committee called the EV Working Group that will be a key advisory body to “make recommendations regarding the development, adoption, and integration of light-, medium-, and heavy-duty electric vehicles into the transportation and energy systems of the United States,” including on infrastructure topics. The 25 members will be selected in the coming months. The joint office also announced a partnership to support EV charging with the American Public Power Association, Edison Electric Institute, and National Rural Electric Cooperative Association to inform electric system investments and support state planning.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Energy </strong><a href="https://www.arpa-e.energy.gov/news-and-media/press-releases/us-department-energy-announces-45-million-develop-more-efficient">announced $45 million</a> through its &#8220;EVs4ALL&#8221; program to develop very fast charging batteries to complement the rollout of the public charging network. They are also <a href="https://eere-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaIdd401a407-9f96-49cc-a6d8-7af4814e78e5">preparing multiple funding topics</a> for projects that offer EV charging solutions for drivers who lack access to home charging or who live in underserved communities. DOE’s Vehicle Technologies Office anticipates up to $30M in funding opportunities to support clean energy mobility pilots and demonstration in underserved and rural areas. The opportunity will seek projects to deploy EV charging solutions for drivers with no home charging and projects that will engage underserved communities to develop community-driven EV charging plans and install EV chargers in locations that maximize benefits to underserved communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Agriculture</strong> developed an <a href="https://www.rd.usda.gov/sites/default/files/508_RD_FS_71EVChargingStations.pdf">EV charging resource guide</a> and funding eligibility infographic for rural property owners, states and territories, Tribes, municipalities, cooperatives, and non- and for-profit entities to assist those looking to make the transition to electric. They also developed a <a href="https://www.rd.usda.gov/sites/default/files/508_RD_FS_LeadingTheChargeSchools.pdf">climate smart schools guide</a> that includes information on funding for charging for rural school districts. In addition, USDA signed a Memorandum of Understanding with the Department of Energy to address EV supply equipment and related charging infrastructure.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The General Services Administration</strong> created <a href="https://www.gsa.gov/about-us/newsroom/news-releases/gsa-awards-new-blanket-purchase-agreements-for-electric-vehicle-supply-equipment-procurement-05032022">Blanket Purchase Agreements</a> for federal agencies and other eligible users to seamlessly acquire an array of EV chargers and services at federally owned, managed, and occupied facilities. They also published a &#8216;Guide to Building Owners&#8217; that details the relationship between EV charging and building electricity loads – ensuring that buildings are equipped to handle new charging infrastructure, and optimize existing chargers. Through their Green Proving Ground program, GSA is working closely with the Department of Energy to install and pilot EV charging innovations, including managed and bidirectional charging, at selected GSA facilities and to accelerate market acceptance. In addition, GSA&#8217;s Public Buildings Service established an Interagency Agreement with the Department of Veterans Affairs to install EV charging stations at approximately 60 Veterans Affairs locations at a value greater than $40 million.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The National Park Service </strong>established an interdisciplinary EV Working Group that is developing a national strategy for electrifying their government fleets, public-serving transit fleets, and public-use charging infrastructure. They are in the process of transitioning Zion National Park&#8217;s transit fleet to battery-electric buses with <a href="https://www.nps.gov/zion/learn/news/zion-national-park-receives-33-million-federal-transit-grant.htm">$33 million in funding</a> from the Department of Transportation&#8217;s Nationally Significant Federal Lands and Tribal Projects program – with plans to pursue the same program to electrify transit at Grand Canyon National Park next year. In addition, NPS is working with State DOTs to fill charging gaps in corridors and routes that serve as gateways to national parks.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development</strong> has continued to support the inclusion of EV charging infrastructure as part of its green building standards through several of its housing financing programs. In addition, they are exploring the installation of EV chargers in multi-family rental housing as part of their Green Mortgage Insurance Premium incentive – lowering annual premiums for participants.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Environmental Protection Agency</strong> created a Clean School Bus Program through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to replace the nation&#8217;s fleet of dirty diesel buses, with clean, American-made, zero-emission buses. EPA <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/biden-harris-administration-makes-500-million-available-clean-school-buses-through-epa">released $500 million</a> in the first round of funding for this $5 billion program, and schools can use portions of this funding to build-out needed EV charging infrastructure for these new, clean school buses. In addition, there are now 300 different Level 2 EV charger products available under the EPA&#8217;s ENERGY STAR program.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Defense </strong>launched a pilot project to install 20 Level 2 EV chargers for government fleet vehicles at the Pentagon along with a planning study for future additional installations. The Senior Pentagon Climate Working Group also created a sub-working group focused solely on removing barriers to installing EV charging infrastructure that supports the Department’s zero-emission vehicle acquisition goals.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Commerce</strong> is supporting the build-out of the domestic EV charging supply chain and promoting foreign direct investment in American EV charging and supply equipment manufacturing. At the end of June, they will host the <a href="https://www.selectusasummit.us/">2022 SelectUSA Investment Summit</a> – the highest-profile event promoting foreign direct investment in the U.S. – where they will highlight investment opportunities in EV charging catalyzed by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. In addition, DOC’s Hollings <a href="https://www.nist.gov/mep">Manufacturing Extension Partnership</a> provides hands on assistance to manufactures across 51 centers, in every state and Puerto Rico, to address unmet needs in the EV charging supply chain and help traditional automotive suppliers diversify their customer base and enter into the EV charging market.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Inaugural Ceremony of the Ninth Summit of the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/08/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-inaugural-ceremony-of-the-ninth-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 03:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft TheaterLos Angeles, California 6:00 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Please be seated.  Welcome to Los Angeles.  (Applause.)  And I probably should stop right here because I’ve followed some difficult acts in the past. AUDIENCE MEMBER:  No fossil fuels!  No!  No fossil fuels! THE PRESIDENT:  (Laughs.)  (Applause.)  I followed some difficult acts, but never&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Microsoft Theater<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>6:00 P.M. PDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Please be seated.  Welcome to Los Angeles.  (Applause.)  And I probably should stop right here because I’ve followed some difficult acts in the past.<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  No fossil fuels!  No!  No fossil fuels!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (Laughs.)  (Applause.) <br><br>I followed some difficult acts, but never before have I followed such a difficult act as I’ve seen the last 45 minutes up here. <br><br>It’s an honor to host my fellow leaders from throughout the &#8212; our hemisphere for the ninth Summit of the Americas at a moment when we need more cooperation, common purpose, and transformative ideas that have never been a greater need than today.<br><br>I also want to welcome all the representatives from civil society, the private sector, international institutions, and especially young people from across the Americas who are participating in this summit.  (Applause.)<br><br>Democracy is a hallmark of our region.  Our Inter-American Democratic Charter, which grew out of the third Summit of the Americas, captures our unique commitment to democracy as a region.  It affirms the right of people throughout the Americas to democracy and our obligation as governments to promote and defend democracy.<br><br>As we meet again today, in a moment when democracy is under assault around the world, let us unite again and renew our conviction that democracy is not only the defining feature of American histories, but the essential ingredient to Americas’ futures. <br><br>Folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to state the obvious, our region is large and diverse.  We don’t always agree on everything, but because we’re democracies, we work through our disagreements with mutual respect and dialogue. <br><br>At this summit, we have an opportunity for us to come together around some bold ideas, ambitious actions, and to demonstrate to our people the incredible power of democracies to deliver concrete benefits and make life better for everyone.  Everyone.<br><br>And no longer is this a question of what will we do &#8212; what will the United States do for the Americas.  The question is what we accomplish by working together as true partners with diverse capabilities but equal and mutual respect, recognizing both our individual sovereignty and our shared responsibilities. <br><br>The COVID-19 pandemic hit our region particularly hard.  While we account for just 12 percent of the global population, we experienced more than 40 percent of reported global pandemic-related deaths.  It’s an enormous tragedy that has left too many families grief-stricken. <br><br>And the ensuing economic crisis, triggered by the pandemic, ravaged economies throughout the hemisphere, wiping out much of the hard-earned progress we had made. <br><br>Twenty-two million more people fell into poverty in just the first year of the pandemic.<br><br>Inequity continues to rise. <br><br>Global <s>inflammatory</s> [inflationary] pressures &#8212; were made worse by Putin’s brutal and unprovoked war against Ukraine &#8212; are making it harder for families to make ends meet. <br><br>And all of these factors are contributing to vastly increased migration flows throughout our hemisphere with too many people feeling there is no option available to them to provide for themselves and their families.<br><br>These challenges affect all of us.  All of our nations have a responsibility to step up and ease the pressure people are feeling today.<br><br>In the months leading up to this summit, countries have made meaningful and concrete commitments to address these challenges.  And the United States is attempting to do our part as well.<br><br>Yesterday, we launched our Cities Forward initiative, recognizing the key roles of mayors and local governments &#8212; the role they play in delivering for the people where they live.  And we’ll host the inaugural Cities Summit of the Americas in Denver in 2023. <br><br>Earlier today, we announced a new America[s] Health Corps with <s>50,000</s> [500,000] public health and medical professionals being trained in the region over the next five years to help strengthen our health systems throughout the hemisphere. <br><br>In the next few days, we’ll be rolling out another new initiative created in cooperation with many of your countries.  It includes the U.S.-Caribbean partnership to address the climate crisis, which the Vice President Harris will lead for our country, and a collaboration among the United States &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the United States, Argentina, Brazil, Canada, Chile, and Mexico &#8212; the hemisphere’s largest exporters of food &#8212; to increase food production for export, as well as increase fertilizer production for transportation &#8212; and transportation.<br><br>Our leaders, all of us, as we discuss ways to better target more than a half a billion dollars of &#8212; the United States is devoting to increasing security for our citizens, working with partners to disrupt transnational criminal organizations, go after drug traffickers and illicit firearms, advancing anticorruption efforts, and strengthening the rule of law.<br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing a new economic partnership that builds on all the work we have done with the region and will guide our engagement going forward.  We’re calling it “Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity,” and it’s grounded on the same core values that my administration is bringing to our own strong economic recovery and to bolster long-term economic competitiveness in the United States.<br><br>First, the <s>American</s> [Americas] Partnership will help economies grow from the bottom up and the middle out, not the top down.  What’s true &#8212; (applause) &#8212; what&#8217;s true in the United States is true in every country: Trickle-down economics does not work.  (Applause.)<br><br>But when we invest in strengthening workers and the middle class, the poor have a ladder up, and those at the top do just fine.  That’s how we can increase opportunity and decrease persistent inequity. <br><br>We need to break the cycle where marginalized communities are hit the hardest by disasters and have the fewest resources to recover from crises and prepare for the next one.<br><br>Together, we have to invest in making sure our trade is sustainable and responsible and creating supply chains that are more resilient, more secure, and more sustainable.<br><br>By working with close friends who share our values, we can make sure that we are not left vulnerable to unexpected shocks while generating economic opportunity for the people in our region. <br><br>Second, the Americas Partnership will foster innovation and help governments to deliver for their own people.  People everywhere expect their government to help give them just a little bit of breathing room, provide opportunities for work that pays a decent wage, educate children so they can rise as high as their talents can take them, make communities more secure so families feel safe in their homes and individuals know their rights will be respected. <br><br>That means directing investment to help governments deliver on those responsibilities, including modernize &#8212; modernizing multilateral development banks to better address the challenges of today and of the future. <br><br>For example, many countries in our region have prospered &#8212; have profited over &#8212; prospered overall, making it harder for them to secure development lending.  But they struggle with deep inequity.  I’m proposing a fundamental reforms to the Inter- &#8211;Inter-American Development Bank Group.  And the United States is ready to put our new capital in the bank’s private sector lending arm &#8212; the IDB investment &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to help <s>capitalize</s> [catalyze] in the critical flow of private capital into the region, especially to those startup, digital connectivity, renewable energy, and health.<br><br>Third, the <s>American</s> [Americas] Partnership will tackle the climate crisis head on, with the same mentality we’re bringing to the work in the United States. <br><br>When I hear “climate,” I think jobs &#8212; good-paying, high-quality jobs that will help speed our transition &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to a green economy of the future and unleash sustainable growth; jobs in developing and deploying clean energy; jobs in decarbonizing the economy; jobs in protecting biodiversity of our hemisphere; jobs that will provide dignity of being able to feed your family, give your children a better life, and envision a future of possibilities.<br><br>That’s what this is all about: responding to basic human desires that we share for dignity, for safety, and for security.  And when those basics are absent in one place, that’s when people make the desperate decision to seek them elsewhere.<br><br>So, on Friday, we’ll also come together to la- &#8212; to launch the Los Angeles Declaration, a ground-breaking, integrated new approach to managing migration and sharing responsibility across the hemisphere.<br><br>The declaration represents a mutual commitment to invest in regional solutions that enhance stability, increase opportunities for safe and orderly migration through the region, and crack down on criminal and human trafficking who prey on desperate people.  (Applause.)<br><br>Safe and orderly migration is good for all of our economies, including the United States.  It can be a catalyst for sustainable growth. <br><br>But unlawful migration is not acceptable.  And we will enforce our borders, including through innovative, coordinated action with our regional partners.<br><br>We’ve come a long way together since the United States hosted the first Summit of the Americas 28 years ago.  But the “Spirit of Miami,” as it was known &#8212; the sense of hope and new possibilities that defined that first summit &#8212; remains key to facing the challenges of today and unlocking the incredible potential that exists in this hemisphere &#8212; in the Americas.<br><br>There is no reason why the Western Hemisphere shouldn’t be secure, prosperous, and democratic, from Canada’s northernmost reaches to the southern tips of Chile. <br><br>We have all the tools we need right here in our own hemisphere.  Our people are dynamic and innovative.  Our nations are committed to working in partnership.  And our region is forever knit together by the close bonds of family and enduring friendship.<br><br>We see it here in Los Angeles, as you heard earlier, a city that has been shaped from its earliest days and strengthened over the decades by the rich and diverse con- &#8212; contributions from people of all our nations. <br><br>It’s written in the murals, the markets, the thoroughfares that crisscross the city, bearing witness to the history, struggle, and the indomitable spirit of the people of the Americas.<br><br>This city is testament to the connections that bind us and our capacity to achieve great things together.<br><br>So tonight, let’s enjoy a wonderful celebration.  Let us leave here renewed with purpose and a renewed partnership.  And tomorrow, let’s get to work building the future this region deserves. <br><br>Thank you all.  And again, welcome, welcome, welcome. (Applause.)<br><br>6:13 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Inaugural Ceremony of the Ninth Summit of the&#160;Americas </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-inaugural-ceremony-of-the-ninth-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 01:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft TheaterLos Angeles, California 5:36 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Good evening.  Good evening.  (Applause.)  Well, I know our future is bright when I look at these young leaders. Governor Gavin Newsom, thank you for that introduction.  It is, of course, so good to be back in my home state of California.  (Applause.) And to everyone here,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Microsoft Theater<br><em>Los Angeles, California</em></em></p>



<p>5:36 P.M. PDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Good evening.  Good evening.  (Applause.)  Well, I know our future is bright when I look at these young leaders.<br> <br>Governor Gavin Newsom, thank you for that introduction. <br> <br>It is, of course, so good to be back in my home state of California.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And to everyone here, on behalf of our administration, it is my honor to officially welcome you to the ninth Summit of the Americas.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And, of course, we are here together with world leaders; local elected officials, including our host city Mayor Garcetti; business and civil society leaders; and, of course, the President of the United States, Joe Biden.  (Applause.)<br>    <br>As many of you may know, I am a proud daughter of California.  I represented this state as Attorney General and as a United States Senator.  And I am proud to call Los Angeles my home. <br> <br>As Vice President, I am pleased to acknowledge, as the Governor mentioned, California is a place where ambitions and dreams become reality.<br>  <br>And so, we all gather in Los Angeles this week for the Summit of the Americas with big ambitions &#8212; ambitions that began 28 years ago in Miami at the first-ever Summit of the Americas, when our nations, together, set the Western Hemisphere on a new path &#8212; a path to grow our economies and improve the lives of our people.  <br> <br>And together, we have made progress on this path &#8212; a path that I believe is critically important for so many of us and, I will speak, important for the American people, because the Western Hemisphere directly affects the security and prosperity of the United States.<br> <br>And so, this week, we gather once more to build a more prosperous and inclusive future.   <br> <br>I look out at this room, and I see representatives of so many different countries and communities. <br> <br>We are joined, of course, by heads of state, and we are joined by youth leaders.  We are joined by CEOs, and we are joined labor organizers, women entrepreneurs, activists, and advocates.<br> <br>So here’s how I see it: To realize a more prosperous future for our hemisphere, partnerships between those assembled here are essential.<br> <br>It is in this spirit that I have focused on bringing companies and organizations together to collaborate and coordinate and share lessons learned, and to galvanize billions of dollars in new investments.<br> <br>The challenges facing our hemisphere in the months and years ahead are significant: the climate crisis, food insecurity, economic inequality, corruption, and gender-based violence. <br> <br>When I think about these challenges, I know and I am certain they will require new and innovative coalitions to solve, which is why President Joe Biden and I see this week as an opportunity for all of us &#8212; an opportunity to launch new initiatives, to begin new conversations, and to build new partnerships.<br> <br>So let us enjoy this evening and to also commit ourselves to taking advantage of this time that we spend together under the same roof.  At this convening, let us build a more prosperous and inclusive future for the entire Western Hemisphere.<br> <br>Thank you and welcome.  (Applause.)  <br> <br>END                 5:40 P.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After Tour of Dream Big Children&#8217;s&#160;Center </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-tour-of-dream-big-childrens-center/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 23:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dream Big Children’s CenterMonrovia, California Q    All right.  Madam Vice President, welcome home. THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Hi, Alex.  Good to be home.  Q    Good to have you back in California. THE VICE PRESIDENT:  It’s really great to be home. Q    What does it mean for you to be at a summit like this in your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Dream Big Children’s Center<br><em>Monrovia, California</em></em></p>



<p>Q    All right.  Madam Vice President, welcome home.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Hi, Alex.  Good to be home. <br><br>Q    Good to have you back in California.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  It’s really great to be home.<br><br>Q    What does it mean for you to be at a summit like this in your home state, as one of the leaders of it?  And what are you most excited about in terms of the summit?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So I&#8217;ll talk about the summit.  But let&#8217;s just first talk about this business, because Dream Big &#8212; I&#8217;ve been hearing about this business and this business owner.  It’s a small business right here in the heart of California. She now has five.  And it&#8217;s a business that serves the parents and the children of the community, in particular special needs children.<br><br>And the reason that I&#8217;ve been hearing about her work is not only because of what she does in such a loving way to help parents parent, but she did it through the pandemic when she, for just a short while, was, you know, under the threat that so many small businesses were of closing. <br><br>And the parents that she serves were desperate to know that she would be able to stay open.  And she did.  And parents bring their children here five days a week for four hours a day.  The parents of this community rely on the support that she gives their children throughout these early stages of their development.  And if she had to close down, it would have had a profound if not lifelong impact on those children, much less their families.<br><br>So I&#8217;m here to highlight the importance of our small businesses, because they do this out of love, out of concern, and being a member of the community, and with a sense of responsibility to the community.<br><br>And I&#8217;m also here to highlight then that it is small businesses like this that have been supported through our Small Business Administration, the administrators here, because we give loans that are able to help these businesses grow and then expand the service they provide to the community.<br><br>So I&#8217;m here to talk about that and also the importance of the PPP program, which allowed her to stay open through the height of the crisis of the pandemic.<br><br>On the summit: So one of the important components of the summit, from my perspective, is the work that we&#8217;ve been doing with the Call to Action, which is bringing CEOs together at historic numbers to invest in the northern part of Central America. <br>And we announced yesterday that as a result of the work that we only started a year ago, we&#8217;ve already raised $3.2 billion, which is about investing in these countries that are our neighbors, as the United States &#8212; because we are also a member of the Western Hemisphere.<br><br>And one of the things that is without question: When we are able to improve the prosperity and stability of our neighbors, we as a nation benefit.  So the work that we have been doing in the summit has been to bring CEOs together, heads of state of a number of the organiz- &#8212; of the countries in the Western Hemisphere are going to be here, to talk about how we can continue to collaborate.<br>But specifically on the issue of the economic investment that our CEOs are making, specifically on this subject of the beauty and strength of public-private partnerships, I&#8217;m very excited about the work that is being done and that will continue to be done.<br><br>Q    And especially great to be here (inaudible).<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  And it&#8217;s &#8212; in particular, yeah, it&#8217;s kind of nice that it just happens to be in Los Angeles, where I live.  So it&#8217;s been nice to be home for a change.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Young Leaders on Reproductive Justice and Civil&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-young-leaders-on-reproductive-justice-and-civil-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 23:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, the White House Office of Public Engagement, the White House Gender Policy Council, and the Office of the Vice President convened a meeting with young leaders on reproductive health and rights. Participants discussed the devastating consequences that overturning&#160;Roe v Wade&#160;would have on young people, who overwhelmingly support reproductive rights, which have been guaranteed under&#160;Roe&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, the White House Office of Public Engagement, the White House Gender Policy Council, and the Office of the Vice President convened a meeting with young leaders on reproductive health and rights. Participants discussed the devastating consequences that overturning&nbsp;<em>Roe v Wade</em>&nbsp;would have on young people, who overwhelmingly support reproductive rights, which have been guaranteed under&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade&nbsp;</em>for nearly 50 years and are integral to equality and full opportunity.&nbsp;&nbsp; Advocates highlighted the importance of mobilizing and organizing young people in support of reproductive freedom, including on college campuses.</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials highlighted the President’s commitment to supporting reproductive health and rights and the Administration’s commitment to including young people in conversations on this critical issue and other key priorities.</p>



<p>Participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Advocates for Youth</li><li>Generation Progress</li><li>Generation Ratify</li><li>Gen Z For Change</li><li>Planned Parenthood</li><li>Unite for Reproductive &amp; Gender Equity (URGE)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Los Angeles,&#160;CA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/08/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-los-angeles-ca/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 22:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Los Angeles, California 1:51 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Okay.  Hey, everybody.  I have a topper for you, and then I’ll hand it over to Jake.  Okay.&#160; Whoa.&#160; Thanks for joining us for our trip to Los Angeles where the President looks forward to &#8212; (eye glasses fall off) &#8212; that&#8217;s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>1:51 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Okay.  Hey, everybody.  I have a topper for you, and then I’ll hand it over to Jake. </p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us for our trip to Los Angeles where the President looks forward to &#8212; (eye glasses fall off) &#8212; that&#8217;s not good &#8212; looks forward to hosting fellow leaders from throughout our hemisphere.</p>



<p>The United States actually hosted the first Summit of Americas in Miami in 1994.&nbsp; Now 28 years later, we are meeting to talk about some of the most pressing challenges of our time.&nbsp;&nbsp; The summit will focus on building a sustainable, resilient, and equitable future for our hemisphere.&nbsp; The summit is a place to discuss and advance solutions that help &#8212; that will help the people of the region.</p>



<p>On that note, we&#8217;ve worked hard over the last several months to negotiate hemispheric consensus on several topics.&nbsp; As you &#8212; as you may have seen, this morning we announced investments the United States is making to strengthen the region&#8217;s health systems and health security.</p>



<p>The pandemic revealed the many cracks in our global health systems and underscored the importance of strong, resilient, and accessible health systems for the entire population, health security, and pandemic preparedness and response.</p>



<p>Tonight, the President will announce the APEP, the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity &#8212; APEP.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have a preview tonight at 7:30 p.m. Pacific Time of deliverables to expect tomorrow.</p>



<p>And right now, I will hand it over to Jake Sullivan, the President’s National Security Advisor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And hold on, guys &#8212; it’s bumpy.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sorry we&#8217;re doing this in the middle of a slightly bumpy ride.&nbsp; So, as Karine said, the U.S. hosted the first Summit of the Americas back in 1994.&nbsp; And this is our second opportunity to host it some 28 years later.</p>



<p>It comes at a moment when the United States and many of our partners in the region are looking to pursue an affirmative vision for the hemisphere that will lead to an Americas that is secure, middle class, and democratic &#8212; from Canada to Chile and everywhere in between &#8212; but also at a moment of profound challenge, as we emerge from the COVID-19 pandemic, as we deal with the climate crisis, as we deal with the pressures of food prices, energy, and so much else.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, much of the substance of this summit is designed to tackle the challenges this region is facing head on.&nbsp; And in five areas, we will have significant, substantive deliverables in food, health, in climate, in economic growth, and on migration.</p>



<p>On food, the United States will be announcing $300 million &#8212; and the President will talk about this tonight, and then it will be rolled out in the days ahead &#8212; $300 million in food security financing, both for the acute challenges the region is facing right now and also to help build more resilient food systems to be able to withstand future shocks.</p>



<p>In addition, we&#8217;ll have a number of countries signing up to the Roadmap for Food Security that Secretary Blinken launched at the United Nations a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp; And this region is home to some of the largest food-producing countries in the world, and we&#8217;ll be working with our partners to come together around a shared declaration for how we can leverage the agricultural capacity of the Americas to help address the global food security issue.</p>



<p>On climate, the President will announce, and then the Vice President will lead, a Caribbean climate partnership that&#8217;s focused on two things: first, greater energy security, as we go through the transition, by getting Caribbean countries access to low-carbon energy sources; and second, climate adaptation and resilience.&nbsp; And the specifics of that will be laid out in a launch event that the Vice President hosts, I believe tomorrow, Thursday.</p>



<p>On health, the President will announce an initiative to help train 500,000 health workers in the Americas over the next five years so that they are equipped and empowered to be able to deal with a range of health challenges, including the remaining challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic, but also much more than that.&nbsp; That will be in partnership with the Pan American Health Organization.</p>



<p>On migration, the President will host a number of other countries, a number of other leaders for the announcement of the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection, which will lay out in four pillars an approach to a migration management that is rooted in shared responsibility and involves source countries, transit countries, and destination countries for the first time ever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We regard this as an unprecedented set of statements and actions by the countries of the region to deal with a hemispheric crisis that is affecting all of the countries of the hemisphere, not just the United States, and for which all of the countries in the hemisphere need to step up and help solve the problem.&nbsp; And the Los Angeles Declaration will be a very strong step in the direction of doing that.</p>



<p>Accompanying the declaration, the U.S. will have a variety of specific announcements on labor pathways, on cracking down on smuggling networks, and other steps that we will take.&nbsp; And other countries also will be making announcements to show that they&#8217;re putting skin in the game to help address this challenge.</p>



<p>And then, finally, as Karine mentioned on economic growth, we&#8217;ll be launching the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity tonight.&nbsp; And we will have a number of countries putting out supportive statements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This builds on the chain of free trade agreements we already have in the hemisphere.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s really designed to deal with 21st century challenges like supply chains and decarbonization, but also a vision of economic growth that is rooted in President Biden&#8217;s principles about economic growth having to come from the bottom up and the middle out rather than the top down.&nbsp; And we think that that will be highly welcomed in the hemisphere.</p>



<p>One of the elements of the Americas Partnership that we think is very significant and will have lasting effects is institutional reform of the Inter-American Development Bank &#8212; adjusting the way in which concessional financing is done, increasing the United States’ commitment to the private sector arm of the IDB, and also bringing other international financial institutions more into the work of the hemisphere, including the IMF.</p>



<p>So there will be some meaty elements to this economic partnership, in addition to setting forth a plan to end up discussing and then negotiating arrangements with other countries on issues like supply chain resilience and decarbonization of the economy.</p>



<p>So, again, on these five areas &#8212; food, health, climate, migration, economic growth &#8212; we think we will have a potent story to tell.&nbsp; And that story won&#8217;t be words, it will be actions both taken and pledged at this summit.&nbsp; And at the end of it, we’ll be better positioned to deal with the major challenges facing the &#8212; facing the hemisphere than we were going in.</p>



<p>So let me stop there, and I’m happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, a question on Venezuela.&nbsp; So why was Guaidó not invited?&nbsp; Did the Mexican President ask for him not to be invited?</p>



<p>And separately, what is the status of negotiations between the opposition and the Maduro regime at this point?&nbsp; Is there some indication that things might be stalled?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, we’re not responding to anything from President López Obrador when it comes to the invitation of Guaidó.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that he made any specific ask on that one way or the other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what I will say is the following: First, we continue to recognize Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela.&nbsp; Second, we support a Venezuelan-led dialogue that leads to free and fair elections and a better future for the Venezuelan people.</p>



<p>And third, we thought the best way to lift up our desire to see that Venezuelan-led dialogue and, ultimately, a better future for the Venezuelan people was to focus on the invitations to Venezuelan civil society activists who will participate in various aspects of the summit.</p>



<p>I also anticipate that President Biden will speak with Guaidó at some point here, and we&#8217;ll keep you posted on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, then on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know when it’s going to happen?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I can’t tell you right now.</p>



<p>In terms of the actual negotiations, I&#8217;ll leave it to the two sides to lay out where they are.&nbsp; The United States has made clear that we support the return to those talks, and we&#8217;re prepared to take steps if those talks move forward.</p>



<p>We still believe that there is scope for that to happen.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s ultimately going to be up to the two sides to make it happen and &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of those talks, it makes it sound like they&#8217;re not happening right now, that there is a (inaudible).</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry, by “those talks,” I mean Mexico City.&nbsp; Obviously, the two sides are in communication about getting back to Mexico City and getting a more formal political process underway that can ultimately lead to the outcome that we&#8217;re seeking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And let me just follow up on Venezuela very quickly.&nbsp; So &#8212; and what&#8217;s the status of our negotiations with Venezuela as far as getting them involved in getting oil and gas supply to the region and the energy crisis that we&#8217;re in right now?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, our position on this is quite clear. We&#8217;ve made it clear to them privately &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said it personally, publicly &#8212; which is that we&#8217;re prepared to take steps if they take steps, but it has to be action for action.&nbsp; And the first critical step would be to come to some set of agreements with the opposition that showed good faith, that showed progress, and then then gets meaningful traction going in a political dialogue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Where do Venezuelan hostages &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Brazil, real quickly: How does the President plan to handle, you know, President Bolsonaro’s climate record when he meets with him at the summit, and also the comments that he&#8217;s made about not only perhaps casting a question on his own reelection, but also on President Biden&#8217;s reelection?&nbsp; I think President Bolsonaro has actually said that President Biden shouldn&#8217;t bring up the topic.&nbsp; Does he plan to bring it up?&nbsp; And, again, how does he plan to handle those issues on Amazon and climate that they have disagreements on?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN: &nbsp;There are no topics off limits in any bilateral the President does, including with President Bolsonaro &#8212; first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, I do anticipate that the President will discuss open, free, fair, and transparent democratic elections.</p>



<p>Third, climate will be an important topic of conversation, and we believe that it can be an area of progress in the U.S.- Brazil relationship, particularly around concrete and tangible action to protect the Amazon.&nbsp; And the U.S. has already shown, going back to Glasgow, that we&#8217;re prepared to put a lot on the table when it comes to helping countries like Brazil protect the Amazon from further deforestation.</p>



<p>The President announced a major initiative on forests at Copenhagen.&nbsp; He pledged billions of dollars between now and 2030 to mobilize &#8212; that&#8217;s public dollars &#8212; to mobilize more private sector financing for the purpose of protecting the Amazon and other forests from further decarbonization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He supports the LEAF Coalition, which is all about a public-private effort to compensate landowners for not cutting down forests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And at this summit here, the Summit of the Americas, we&#8217;ll have a modest but meaningful slug of money particularly devoted to the Amazon for technical assistance and other purposes to help with protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of that, I think, should pave the way for a good-faith effort on the part of every country, every stakeholder in the Americas &#8212; Brazil included &#8212; to take the necessary action and the necessary responsibility.&nbsp; We’ll see what President Bolsonaro comes to the table with on his side.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, what kind of money &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say how much money is allocated for the Amazon?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, on &#8212; in terms of the commitment the President made at Glasgow, I believe the number is $9 billion globally.&nbsp; But a huge chunk of that would end up getting devoted to the Amazon, including &#8212; in terms of the announcement at the Summit of the Americas, I&#8217;ll come back to you with the precise dollar figure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on money, regarding the economic measures &#8212; I mean, the call today &#8212; there wasn&#8217;t much money discussed.&nbsp; I mean, does the plan really meet the moment of the day?&nbsp; I mean, you have China making more and more inroads there, basically with an open checkbook.&nbsp; I mean, what is &#8212; how does the administration, how does the United States compete with that?&nbsp; And what is Biden&#8217;s real vision in that area?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The United States has never seen its comparative advantage in the world as just leveraging huge numbers of state dollars, but rather leveraging all of the tools available to us &#8212; yes, some public financing, but really unlocking substantial amounts of private sector financing to be able to drive inclusive economic growth across the Americas.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what these countries most want.</p>



<p>So just as an example, at the summit, the President will make a financial commitment to IDB Invest, to the private sector financing arm of the Inter-American Development Bank.&nbsp; That will unlock significant amounts of private sector financing for infrastructure, for clean energy, for digital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on top of that, we will be putting specific dollars into producing tangible results that matter to people &#8212; training 500,000 workers, mobilizing hundreds of billions of dollars on food security.</p>



<p>When you tally all that up and look at the practical impact of what the summit deliverables from the United States will mean for the hemisphere, it is significantly more impactful on the actual lives and livelihoods of the people of this region than the kinds of extractive projects that China has been invested in.</p>



<p>So, we think we are mobilizing and coming to the table with a lot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will also add that one of the things he will talk to the leaders of the region about is a global infrastructure partnership that he first raised at the G7 last year and that he will formally launch at the G7 this year in just a few weeks’ time.&nbsp; That will include signature projects from major geographies around the world, including the Americas.</p>



<p>So, we believe that whether you&#8217;re talking about infrastructure, talking about food security, the clean energy transition, investments in health, and the use of the major multilateral investment tools &#8212; both the IDB and the World Bank and IMF &#8212; that, collectively, that is going to add up to a major investment by the United States and outcomes for the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on the immigration &#8212; on the migration declaration, how much support is the U.S. going to be providing to the countries that are willing to participate in this declaration and house migrants at various stages like you described?&nbsp; And what incentives are there for these countries to participate in this declaration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we have &#8212; and not to get ahead of the announcement with too much detail &#8212; but we are &#8212; have developed an innovative concessional financing facility that will be for countries that typically can&#8217;t get access to that kind of financing because they&#8217;re middle-income countries, but providing support on migration will unlock that.&nbsp; So, we think that provides one form of incentive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second form of incentive is that we&#8217;re putting on the table something that a lot of these countries are asking from us, which is labor pathways to the United States for both migrants transiting their countries and for the source countries, from citizens of their home country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’ll have announcements related to labor pathways as part of the Los Angeles Declaration and, actually, an interesting and very innovative new program between our Department of Agriculture and the United Farmworkers that is designed to ensure that those labor pathways meet the highest labor standards and are not used for abuse or for a race to the bottom.</p>



<p>So we think when you look at the set of things we&#8217;re putting on the table in conjunction with this declaration, and then the commitments other countries are signing up to along with the principles they will be signing on to with respect to the declaration itself, it amounts to a really significant paradigm shift in how the region is tackling this migration crisis.&nbsp; And I think people will look back at the Los Angeles Declaration as a new platform upon which we build a migration strategy collectively as a hemisphere for the years going forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we question how seriously Central America, though, is taking it if the three leaders of the Northern Triangle are not coming?&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s where most of the source &#8212; at least most of U.S. source of migration is coming.&nbsp; But those leaders are not coming.&nbsp; I mean, does that &#8212; is that a sign that they are not as committed to this as the United States?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a sign at all.&nbsp; They&#8217;re all coming.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll all be represented.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not the leaders.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The leaders are not coming for each individual idiosyncratic reason, none of which has to do with the migration issue.&nbsp; And in each case, those countries have committed to working with the United States in a collaborative way on the migration issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Mexico, whose leader also is not coming and will be represented at the foreign minister level, who will similarly be signing on to the Los Angeles Declaration, is making its own commitments with respect to what it&#8217;s doing on the migration front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I think there&#8217;s no way you can look the substantive outcomes of the summit and find that there is a link between the lack of leader-level representation from those countries and what those countries’ commitments are on the migration question.</p>



<p>And then finally, just on López Obrador: He&#8217;ll be coming to D.C. in July &#8212; actually, specifically to build on summit outcomes like this one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the substantive work of the summit has in no way, shape, or form been touched or adjusted or reduced by the participation question.&nbsp; These two things are operating in entirely distinct lanes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we&#8217;re happy to have senior-level participation from each of these countries, even though the leaders, each for their own reason, has chosen not to come to Los Angeles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up on migration very quickly?&nbsp; You mentioned the labor pathways initiatives that you have.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; any of that going to require congressional approval?</p>



<p>And, two, will it deal with the severe labor shortage that the United States has had for some time?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to pretend like what we announced today is going to solve the whole of the systematic challenge that we have, but it will make a &#8212; it will help us make progress on it.&nbsp; It will.</p>



<p>And then, the specific announcements we&#8217;re making don&#8217;t require new congressional legislation. &nbsp;But more broadly, we are looking to Congress to step up and be a partner on a bipartisan basis on the migration question in a way that they &#8212; that we haven&#8217;t seen over the course of the last year.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, does the absence of some of those Central American leaders undermine the role of the Vice President in building ties with them and in helping to combat some of the root cause issues of migration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think you really have to look to see what those countries are signing up to, what they are committing to on the major priorities of the United States and the major priorities to the Americas.&nbsp; And if you look at the substantive agenda, substantive outcomes, and where they&#8217;re putting their name on the bottom line, it shows that they&#8217;re invested in the agenda we&#8217;ve set forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact that their leaders aren&#8217;t coming is, in each case, its own reflection of, again, these idiosyncratic decisions each of them are making, and I honestly wouldn&#8217;t read too much into it one way or the other.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on (inaudible) actions, right now it doesn&#8217;t look like the President has a press conference on his schedule at the end of this summit, which we&#8217;re hosting.&nbsp; What message does that lead to &#8212; give to our neighbors about democracy, freedom of the press, especially to those neighbors that we&#8217;re trying to encourage to change their ways?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I mean, the President &#8212; I have now accompanied him on multiple foreign trips.&nbsp; This one is not foreign, although it involves foreign policy.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;d be hard to argue that he hasn&#8217;t taken many, many questions from the press.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;ll be, over the course of the next three days, obviously in front of and addressing the press in various ways.&nbsp; And I think by the end of this, you can be pretty confident that he will be displaying &#8212; putting on full display America&#8217;s raucous democracy in all of its wonderful and attractive forms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t see the kind of formal press conference issue as a particular litmus test.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question on democracy.&nbsp; I mean, given that a number of leaders are not coming because of concerns about authoritarian governments not being invited, does the administration see a fracturing of the consensus around democracy, given that previous summits have had a sort of a consensus that non-democratic governments were not going to be invited?&nbsp; Is there a concern about backsliding in the hemisphere &#8212; a concern that, you know, you&#8217;re not really getting that same push for democracy that you used to have?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think this doesn&#8217;t have to do with the fundamental question of democracy.&nbsp; I think it has to do with a difference of opinion &#8212; a diversity of opinion, frankly &#8212; across the hemisphere &#8212; frankly, across our Congress, across the American public sphere &#8212; as to what the right way to approach the invitation of a dictator or a non-invitation of a dictator is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s really, kind of, more of a question about the role and purpose of participation in a summit like this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a question about whether democracy is a good form of government or a bad form of government.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You don’t see that eroding?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You don’t see that eroding in the hemisphere &#8212; the support for democracy?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I definitely see challenges to democracy in the hemisphere; there&#8217;s no doubt.&nbsp; We see challenges to democracy all over the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And part of what the President wants to send a strong message of at this summit is that the United States is put &#8212; is putting its shoulder to the wheel in terms of supporting democratic principles and, very critically, that as the host of the summit, we are going to lift up a vision for the hemisphere that is fundamentally democratic.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On a different topic from a colleague: Can you respond to the react- &#8212; get a reaction on Tehran moving two of the IAEA monitoring cameras from its nuclear site?&nbsp; How will this &#8212; will this impact the resumption of Vienna talks?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We see the issue of the IAEA compliance by Iran with its Safeguards agreement, with its obligations at the NPT, and its negotiations with Grossi &#8212; particularly on the files that Grossi has expressed concerns about and that the board is speaking to today &#8212; as operating on one track.&nbsp; On another track is a negotiated resolution to Iran’s nuclear program through a compliance-for-compliance return to the JCPOA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From our perspective, we have to view these on separate tracks, and that’s how we’re going to proceed.&nbsp; What actually happens in those negotiations is something we will see.&nbsp; But there is, in our view, a deal on the table that would effectuate a compliance-for-compliance return to the JCPOA without dealing with extraneous issues.&nbsp; That deal is available to Iran.&nbsp; They should take it.&nbsp; If they don&#8217;t, that&#8217;s on them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Yellen said today that the administration is working to recalibrate tariffs on China.&nbsp; And she also said there&#8217;s consideration of an oil price cap on Russia.&nbsp; On both those items, can you give us a timeline of when there might be a decision?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on the oil cap in particular, is that something you&#8217;re aiming to finalize at the G7 later this month?&nbsp; And how much buy-in do you have from European partn- &#8212; or, I guess, partners outside of Europe?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I won&#8217;t go beyond what Secretary Yellen said generally because we want to be able to protect space for intensive consultations with our European partners.&nbsp; Those are taking place in multiple channels, but one of the channels is in the G7 Sherpa channel.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;ll see what kind of progress we make generally on the question of energy at multiple different options for reducing revenue to Russia that could be available to us as the G7 over the course of the next three weeks.</p>



<p>On the question of China tariffs, all I will say is there have been &#8212; I think the last time I was on this plane with some of you, I said we &#8212; the President has been presented with a variety of views on this.&nbsp; He’s sought more information.&nbsp; He&#8217;s actively considering options.&nbsp; He said that himself when we were in Tokyo.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you, but I don&#8217;t expect that it will &#8212; this will go on indefinitely.&nbsp; He will make a decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on Ukraine &#8212; Jake, are you &#8212; is the U.S. concerned about the advance of Russian troops in the Luhansk region in the eastern part of the country?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you also just announced the NATO meeting &#8212; the trip the President will be taking later in the month.&nbsp; How difficult is it for the U.S. to maintain the Alliance, given the length of this war, the fact that fuel prices are going up in Europe, you know, the fact that we&#8217;ve seen some concern among France and Germany about providing Ukraine with longer-range weapons?&nbsp; Can you talk about just the strength of the unity right now?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s interesting &#8212; there is this natural instinct, I think, in the commentariat and in the press to presume the inevitable decline in Western unity, resolve, staying power.&nbsp; But all facts are to the contrary, as we stand here today.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve got European nations making new announcements of security assistance day by day.&nbsp; You have the European Union coming together not a month ago, but a week ago, to announce a far-reaching new package of sanctions, including on energy.</p>



<p>So, the notion that there is somehow, you know, signs of cracking or division or disunity, I think, is belied by what we&#8217;re actually seeing.&nbsp; And I think that both the G7 and NATO will be very impressive signs of strength and resolve.</p>



<p>And let&#8217;s remember also that the United States has allocated $40 billion to this effort.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not for a week or a month or three months; that is a commitment that we&#8217;re &#8212; will endure for many months to come and put us in a position to continue to very strongly support the Ukrainians.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re concerned by every act of aggression the Russians have undertaken, every inch of Ukrainian territory they sit upon, they wreck, they bomb, they destroy, both in the areas they&#8217;re moving on the ground and in the areas they’re raining missiles down on from afar.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so committed to providing the necessary equipment and tools to the Ukrainians to be able to resist Russian advances in where they can push them back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are we in a fundamentally different place when it comes to the willingness of OPEC-Plus to finally support the global economic recovery, as you&#8217;ve been asking them to do?&nbsp; And do you take credit for that, in terms of your outreach to Saudi?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a question for OPEC-Plus.&nbsp; I will simply note that at the last OPEC-Plus meeting, there was a recognition that the supply issue needs to be addressed.&nbsp; And we expect that it will continue to be addressed as we go forward.</p>



<p>And how&#8217;s that for a super clear and specific answer?</p>



<p>But, you know, that&#8217;s &#8212; we thought this last meeting was important, positive.&nbsp; And we look forward to continue our consultations to see OPEC-Plus playing a constructive role as we go forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What factors are complicating a presidential visit to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I said: What factors are complicating a possible presidential visit to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don’t have any &#8212; anything for you on an &#8212; on a trip to Saudi Arabia today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll only say the President is going to travel to places and meet with people with whom he wants to work to help solve problems for the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President had any conversations with Putin?&nbsp; Any updates on that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President plan to go to Latin America?&nbsp; Obviously, he&#8217;s been occupied with things happening in Asia, with Europe.&nbsp; The Vice President has only been to Latin America twice so far.&nbsp; Any more trips to Latin America?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We’re literally on our way to the Summit of the Americas &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, but (inaudible) to Latin America.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; and your question is whether he&#8217;s paying attention to Latin America?&nbsp; I mean, a little unfair.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we can fairly say that spending the next two and a half days engaging with the leaders of the hemisphere and, even more importantly, engaging with the challenges and opportunities in the hemisphere will be a display of the President&#8217;s commitment on these issues.&nbsp; And there will be an enormous amount of follow-up that comes out of that, including, by the way, already-scheduled plans to see additional leaders like the President of Mexico and the President of Argentina.&nbsp; And I think you can expect further announcements of him welcoming Latin American leaders to Washington coming out of the next three days.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jamal Khashoggi’s widow is asking to meet with the President as a sign that he hasn’t given up on the legacy of the journalist.&nbsp; Is that something that the President would consider doing before he goes anywhere in the Middle East?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I don’t want to speculate on a trip, so I don’t want to speculate on anything he would do in preparation for a trip.&nbsp; But, of course, he takes not just the principle of human rights seriously, he takes the personal impact of human rights very seriously.&nbsp; And that will always be true of Joe Biden.</p>



<p>So, if and when we have anything to announce, I’ll let you know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any plans to bring up, when he has a meeting with the Brazilians, the searching for Dom Phillips?&nbsp; He was a BBC &#8212; or a British journalist who disappeared a few days ago in the Amazon.&nbsp; Is there any movement or intention to bring that up or encourage the government to help find him?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we have, at various levels of the U.S. government, reached out to say we&#8217;re prepared to do what we can to try to be helpful on this.</p>



<p>And I don&#8217;t know if the President will end up raising it, but we&#8217;ll ask our team.&nbsp; If that would be helpful, then of course he would do it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has there been any update on North Korea?&nbsp; Has the U.S. heard &#8212; received any response from the North Korean government?&nbsp; And as these tests have continued over the last few months, is that a sign that maybe this approach is not working and there needs to be some sort of change in a way to engage North Korea on this issue?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIAN:&nbsp; We have not heard from North Korea.&nbsp; We continue to obviously monitor and respond to the tests that they have been conducting.</p>



<p>One thing that it has done is only further cemented the strength of our alliances with both the ROK and Japan, and we&#8217;ve been able to conduct joint exercises with both of them in response to some of these launches.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also watching very closely the continuing possibility of a nuclear test, to which we would also have a robust response.</p>



<p>And otherwise, we cannot do anything other than take the course of action that we think is strong, steadfast, and clear.&nbsp; And that is an openness and willingness to engage in diplomacy if North Korea is prepared to come to the table, and an absolute and resolute commitment to defending our allies in the ROK and Japan.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the position we&#8217;ve taken.&nbsp; We think it&#8217;s the right position, and it&#8217;s a position we will sustain as we go forward.</p>



<p>And maybe I’ll take one more question.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, I know you&#8217;ve laid everything out &#8212; all of what you&#8217;re hoping to get out of &#8212; out of this summit.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the kind of boilerplate success, you know, you walk away at the end of a couple of days?&nbsp; What do you want the American people to know or take away from this summit?</p>



<p>Well, what I want people to know &#8212; it might sound a little nerdy, but I think it&#8217;s super important in this moment &#8212; and that is that for all of the people of the Americas, the same set of interconnected challenges are pressing them &#8212; are pressing on their families, on their livelihoods, and in some cases, on their lives.</p>



<p>And this summit needs to produce tangible action against each of those challenges.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where I started, and that&#8217;s where I&#8217;ll finish.&nbsp; It’s food, it’s energy and climate, it’s health, it’s migration, and it&#8217;s inclusive economic growth.</p>



<p>And I think you guys should measure us against whether or not we are producing tangible results on those five things.&nbsp; And I would challenge you to go back and look at the last five Summit of the Americas and look at the results of those, and ask whether, in fact, what we&#8217;ve done here will end up exceeding that in terms of the substance, the ambition, and the roadmap we set going forward.&nbsp; And I think the answer to that question is going to end up being “yes.”</p>



<p>So, thanks, guys.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; I already had a topper, so &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I&#8217;ve done that part.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any response to the arrest of a man outside &#8212; near Brett Kavanaugh’s house?&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve been standing here, we&#8217;ve seen that he&#8217;s been charged with attempted murder as well.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President condemns the actions of this individual in the strongest terms and is grateful to law enforcement for quickly taking him into custody.</p>



<p>As the President has consistently made clear, public officials, including judges, must be able to do their jobs without concern for their personal safety or that of their families.&nbsp; And any violence threats &#8212; threats of violence or attempts to intimidate justices have no place in our society.&nbsp; He has said that himself, and we have been forceful from the podium many times.</p>



<p>Attorney General Garland has also blasted any threats to the justices, saying, “The rise of violence and unlawful threats of violence directed at those who serve the public is unacceptable and dangerous to our democracy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Department of Justice has U.S. Marshals providing support to the Supreme Court Marshal, and the President supports legislation to fund increased scrutiny for the Court and judges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Department of Homeland Security has said they are working with their partners across every level of government and the private sector to share timely information and intelligence to prevent all forms of violence and to support law enforcement efforts to keep our communities safe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just a quick question about the President&#8217;s statement to us as we boarded Air Force One this morning.&nbsp; By validating the voter recall of San Francisco&#8217;s district attorney, is the President giving into a right-wing narrative about rampant crime that needs to be met with severe punishment?&nbsp; And what does it say about the prospects for criminal justice reform that an advocate of progressive prosecutions was tossed out?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, first of all &#8212; and I&#8217;m just going to reiterate a little bit of what he said.&nbsp; The voters last night delivered a clear message: It&#8217;s time for both parties to get more serious about fighting crime and gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is something that the President has said throughout his first 16 months &#8212; that that&#8217;s why he has never supported “defund the police” &#8212; he&#8217;s been clear about that &#8212; and why he sent state and local government billions of dollars last year through the American Rescue Plan to hire more police.&nbsp; He said that right before coming on board, speaking to all of you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s past time that they put that money to use hiring accountable, well-trained police officers.</p>



<p>And the president &#8212; you know, the President has asked Congress in March for more funds to beef up policing coast to coast.&nbsp; We continue to call on Congress to pass the President&#8217;s budget.</p>



<p>And finally, it&#8217;s important for the Senate to move on gun measures.&nbsp; He thinks those things go hand in hand, like the ones President Biden discussed yesterday while he met with Senator Murphy to get guns out of the hands of dangerous people.</p>



<p>We don’t &#8212; we don’t need a bunch of speeches today on crime; we need state officials to &#8212; and Congress to move.&nbsp; So, he sees those things hand in hand as we talk about gun reform as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, but none of the things you talked about, the &#8212; when the President ran, he talked about criminal justice reform, he talked about cash bail, but none of those things are part of the conversation anymore.&nbsp; Has the President given up on criminal justice reform because of &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, absolutely not.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the GOP narrative on crime?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What &#8212; he ac- &#8212; he signed &#8212; he signed an executive order to deal with police reform.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; I mean, he poli- &#8212; criminal justice reform is something that he has supported from the moment that that &#8212; the moment that legislators on the Hill started talking about coming together, trying to have something to move forward with in Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, he signed an executive action on police &#8212; police reform, on measures that we can do from the executive &#8212; from the federal &#8212; from the federal side of things, from the White House, from the administration.</p>



<p>So, clearly, he hasn&#8217;t given up on that.</p>



<p>On bail reform, as you were just asking me: You know, on the campaign trail &#8212; to your point, Trevor &#8212; the President said that cash bail has become the modern-day debtor’s prison. No one should be held just because they are poor. &nbsp;And a person who is dangerous but has the money to pay bail shouldn&#8217;t have a get-out-of-jail card free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I mean, he still stands by that, from what he said at the campaign trail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll take another question.&nbsp; Who else has a question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President looked pretty friendly at yesterday&#8217;s bill signing with Senator Manchin.&nbsp; They were joking around a little bit.&nbsp; He was standing right behind the President when it was signed.&nbsp; How would you characterize their relationship at this point?&nbsp; And can you give us a temperature check on reconciliation talks?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as &#8212; as we say, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here, not from Air Force One heading to LA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have to tell you, I missed &#8212; I missed that interaction because I was preparing to come back out for my second briefing in front of you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, look, we&#8217;ve said this many, many times: Senator Manchin and the President have a good relationship.&nbsp; They are friends.&nbsp; They are long &#8212; longtime friends, and that continues, and you saw it for your very own eyes yesterday at the &#8212; you know, at the White House.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything else to share on any of the negotiations that are happening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) between the President or Senator Manchin that you can read out or plan &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don’t to have anything to read out or to announce.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, there&#8217;s going to be new consumer price index data coming on Friday while the President is in Los Angeles.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the overall assessment of whether inflation is beginning to moderate?&nbsp; And are we going to see the President talking about this at the end of the week, after the numbers come out?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on the CPI data, which is what you&#8217;re asking about, Ken: Given the impact of Putin’s price hike at the pump on gas prices in May, we expect the headline inflation number to be elevated.&nbsp; And we expect the war in Ukraine to have some effects on core inflation too, particularly when you look at things like airfares and the effect of higher jet fuel costs.</p>



<p>But despite these disruptions and the fact that the numbers can be volatile from month to month, as we say &#8212; we say pretty regularly, we continue to believe that the economy can transition from what has been a historic recovery from &#8212; of the economy &#8212; to stable, steady growth and inflationary pressures moderating, which is what experts have been saying for some time now.</p>



<p>And we are already &#8212; we already begin to see this happen in a range of measures.&nbsp; For example, core PCE, which is the inflation measure the Fed watches most closely, was around 4 percent at an &#8212; at an annualized rate in the last three months and is down from 6 percent annualized in the last months before that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are we going to hear him talk about it, though, on Friday?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything, you know, to lay out.&nbsp; I know last Friday he talked about the jobs numbers and &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out or to lay out for you about that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on inflation, retailers have actually started to warn that now they might have an opposite problem of having too much supply on their shelves.&nbsp; I mean, do you view that as a sign of success, or is that another kind of concern for you for the economy?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; that goes back to what we&#8217;ve been saying.&nbsp; Like, this has been an economic re- &#8212; historic recovery, and that is because of what this President has been able to do.</p>



<p>When you think about the American Rescue Plan more than a year ago that the President laid out and only Democrats signed &#8212; voted for the American Rescue Plan at a time when the President walked into the administration, the economy was in crisis, schools were closed, businesses were shutting down, there was no comprehensive plan to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; And he put all &#8212; he put that plan forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now we are in a place &#8212; just last Friday, as I was saying to Ken, he talked about the jobs numbers in May &#8212; 390,000 jobs that we saw in the last report for May.&nbsp; And that is part of the trajectory that we’re &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen with this economic, historical, you know, turnaround of the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, that is all important, and I think that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s one way to look at that now.&nbsp; Now, we&#8217;re &#8212; we’re going to be transitioning to a more stable &#8212; stable growth, which is going to help us tackle inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; and we&#8217;re &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re going to do our best.&nbsp; The President is going to continue to work very hard to make sure that we lower those costs when we think about food and we think about gas prices.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President plan to watch any of the January 6th hearing tomorrow?&nbsp; And, if not, how does he plan to monitor it?&nbsp; Is he going to comment on the first hearing?&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I mean, we&#8217;ve been very clear that it is an independent &#8212; we support the January 1st Committee hearings &#8212; Committee, I should say, to be more clear &#8212; on January 6th.</a></p>



<p>What we saw that day over a year ago was one of the darkest times in our democracy.&nbsp; But it is an independent committee.&nbsp; And clearly, he&#8217;ll be very busy, as you heard Jake lay out and myself lay out what the next couple of days are going to be.</p>



<p>You know, he might catch it here and there, but he&#8217;s going to be very focused on his trip, talking to Western Hemisphere leaders and making sure that he continues to deliver for the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the President&#8217;s approval rating in a new Morning Consult poll is his worst yet, with disapproving voters saying they&#8217;re more likely to vote GOP.&nbsp; Is he concerned about what this bodes for his party, for the Democrats in the upcoming elections?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, I can&#8217;t get into politics from my position, so I&#8217;m not going to, you know, give any political ana- &#8212; analysis as I&#8217;ve done in my past career.</p>



<p>But, you know, the President is going to continue to do what he&#8217;s doing right now, what he&#8217;s about to do, which is focus on the American people, make that &#8212; continue to make that his number-one goal as we talk about the economy; as we talk about, you know, the work that we have done to see, you know, jobs come back into &#8212; come back into the market; as we, you know, try to deal with costs, whether it&#8217;s gas prices as he&#8217;s doing all that he can to bring those down, the food prices as we&#8217;re really understanding what the American people are feeling.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s going to be his &#8212; his purpose.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be what he&#8217;s going to be focusing on and what his administration is going to be &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he seen the poll?&nbsp; Is he reading polls?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I &#8212; that &#8212; honestly, that is not the &#8212; that is not what is on &#8212; on the President’s &#8212; number one on the President’s mind.&nbsp; It’s the American people and how &#8212; what he can do to continue to deliver.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And back on negotiations again &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; Is he continuing to get updates &#8212; either daily, hourly &#8212; on the negotiations?&nbsp; Like &#8212; and do you have a sense &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Are you talking about the gun reform, the &#8212; yeah, specifically?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, specifically.&nbsp; And is he &#8212; is he optimistic &#8212; has he got a sense of optimism or pessimism about how things are going?&nbsp; And I know you&#8217;re not &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He’s &#8212; he said he’s encouraged.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We have that the President is encouraged at what he is seeing in Congress, in particular with the Senate negotiations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I&#8217;ve said this yesterday, and he has said this as well: The House has &#8212; has taken some actions.&nbsp; They took some actions last week.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to take some actions this week, if they haven&#8217;t already.&nbsp; I already forgot what day it is of the week.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been going so fast this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, Senator &#8212; Senator Murphy came, as you all know, to the White House to give the President an update.&nbsp; We&#8217;re very appreciative of his leadership.&nbsp; We’re appreciative of what Senator Schumer and others &#8212; and their leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, there&#8217;s no deal to talk about right now.&nbsp; They are still working &#8212; working out the details.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what the President truly believes &#8212; and he has said this himself; you heard him say this last Thursday &#8212; is we have to “do something.”&nbsp; And that is the two words that he heard from the families in Uvalde, who &#8212; parents who lost their children in a horrific, horrific mass shooting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s calling on Congress to do &#8212; is to do something, to take a step forward so that we can deal with one of our public health epidemics, which is gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Venezuelan Interim President Juan&#160;Guaidó</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-venezuelan-interim-president-juan-guaido/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Venezuelan Interim President Juan Guaidó to underscore the United States’ recognition of and support for the 2015 democratically-elected National Assembly and Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela. President Biden expressed his support for Venezuelan-led negotiations as the best path toward a peaceful restoration of democratic institutions,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Venezuelan Interim President Juan Guaidó to underscore the United States’ recognition of and support for the 2015 democratically-elected National Assembly and Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela. President Biden expressed his support for Venezuelan-led negotiations as the best path toward a peaceful restoration of democratic institutions, free and fair elections, and respect for the human rights and fundamental freedoms of all Venezuelans. They discussed the role the United States and other international partners can play to support a negotiated solution to Venezuela’s crisis. President Biden reaffirmed the United States is willing to calibrate sanctions policy as informed by the outcomes of negotiations that empower the Venezuelan people to determine the future of their country.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
