<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 13:35:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Bilateral Virtual Meeting Between President Joe&#160;Biden and President Andrés Manuel López&#160;Obrador</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-bilateral-virtual-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-president-andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 13:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, April 29, President Joe Biden will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador virtually. In this virtual event, the two leaders will discuss their vision for the Ninth Summit of the Americas and how North America can lead on priority initiatives for the region. They also plan to discuss cooperation on migration, joint&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, April 29, President Joe Biden will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador virtually. In this virtual event, the two leaders will discuss their vision for the Ninth Summit of the Americas and how North America can lead on priority initiatives for the region. They also plan to discuss cooperation on migration, joint development efforts in Central America, competitiveness and economic growth, security, energy, and economic cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Expands Second Chance Opportunities for Formerly Incarcerated&#160;Persons</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-expands-second-chance-opportunities-for-formerly-incarcerated-persons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America must offer meaningful opportunities for redemption and rehabilitation to empower those who have been incarcerated to become productive, law-abiding, members of society, and reduce crime and make our communities safer. Leaders on both sides of the aisle recognize that second chance opportunities offer people who have made mistakes and served their time a path&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America must offer meaningful opportunities for redemption and rehabilitation to empower those who have been incarcerated to become productive, law-abiding, members of society, and reduce crime and make our communities safer. Leaders on both sides of the aisle recognize that second chance opportunities offer people who have made mistakes and served their time a path to make meaningful contributions to their communities and reduce recidivism. In doing so, we can break the cycle of crime, and allow law enforcement to focus their time and resources on the most pressing threats to public safety.<br><br>Embodying the President’s belief that America is a nation of second chances, today the President granted pardons to three people and <a>commuted</a> the sentences of 75 people, all of whom have made efforts to rehabilitate themselves, including through educational and vocational training or drug treatment in prison.<br><br>Advancing successful reentry outcomes makes our communities safer, disrupts cycles of economic hardship, and strengthens our economy. Improving reentry is also key part of the comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">strategy</a><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> </a>President Biden announced last June to tackle gun crime and violence. And, since President Biden took office, our economy has added a record 7.9 million jobs and the unemployment rate has fallen to 3.6 percent. At the same time, many industries are facing workforce shortages to meet growing demand as their businesses flourish. America is in a prime position to offer opportunities for meaningful employment to the more than 600,000 people that leave prison every year—for whom securing stable employment is among the most significant challenges.<br><br>Today, during Second Chance Month, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing a comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Incarceration-to-Employment-Strategy.pdf">strategy </a>that expands Incarceration to Employment opportunities, as well as the following concrete policy actions as part of a whole-of-government effort to advance employment, bolster reentry, empower formerly incarcerated persons, and strengthen our communities and our economy:<br><br><strong>Investing in Job Training and Intensive Reentry in Federal Prisons</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Launching Historic DOJ-DOL Partnership.</strong> Today, the Department of Justice and the Department of Labor are announcing a first-of-its-kind collaboration to invest $145 million over FY22-FY23 to provide job skills training and individualized employment and reentry plans for people incarcerated in Bureau of Prisons (BOP) facilities, and to provide pathways for a seamless transition to employment and reentry support upon release. This landmark initiative is part of the Department of Justice’s implementation of the First Step Act, and it will be the first time the Department of Labor will bring its job training and reentry support and expertise to federal prisoners.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanding Federal Job Opportunities and Loan Programs</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing New Workforce Grant Funding.</strong> The Department of Labor has announced solicitations for grants totaling $140 million to advance job opportunities:<br><ul><li><a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/ETA/grants/pdfs/FOA-ETA-22-03_.pdf"><strong>Growth Opportunities</strong></a> is a new $85 million program that will provide education and training, paid work experience, mentorship, and leadership development to justice-involved youth and young adults.<br></li><li><a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/ETA/grants/pdfs/FOA-ETA-22-04%20.pdf"><strong>Pathway Home</strong></a> will fund $55 million for job training, pre-apprenticeship programs, digital literacy training, and pre-release and post-release career counseling for justice-involved adults.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Access to Business Capital.</strong> This week, the Small Business Administration (SBA) will publish <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2020/12/14/2020-26446/regulatory-reform-initiative-streamlining-and-modernizing-the-7a-microloan-and-504-loan-programs-to?msclkid=08f00f42c0ee11ecae5d0207f5e651a9">changes</a> to remove barriers to eligibility based on irrelevant criminal history records for its 7(a), Microloan, and 504 loan programs. SBA is also developing other ways to reduce restrictions in its programs. The SBA recently <a href="https://www.sba.gov/article/2022/mar/30/biden-harris-administration-expands-sba-pilot-program-targeting-access-capital-underserved">announced</a> the elimination of criminal record restrictions to access its Community Advantage loans, a critical program that provides loans to low-income borrowers and those from underserved communities. These actions build on SBA’s February 2021 expansion of eligibility for the Paycheck Protection Program by removing restrictions for entrepreneurs with certain prior criminal convictions or other involvement in the justice system.</li><li><strong>Expanding Access to Federal Employment. </strong>This week, the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) will publish <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/public-inspection/2022-08975/fair-chance-to-compete-for-jobs">proposed regulations</a> that remove barriers to federal employment for formerly incarcerated individuals under the bipartisan Fair Chance to Compete for Jobs Act. Once enacted, these regulations will expand the positions covered by the federal government’s “ban the box” policy, which delays inquiries into an applicant’s criminal history a conditional offer has been made. The regulations also create new procedures that outline due process and accountability steps for hiring officials who are alleged to have violated the “ban the box” procedures. </li><li><strong>Leveraging Historic Investments in Infrastructure to Promote Hiring of Formerly Incarcerated Persons. </strong>The Department of Transportation is expanding access to jobs for formerly incarcerated persons and historically marginalized populations in bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act grant programs, including the <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/RAISEgrants">RAISE Grants</a>, <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/grants/infra-grants-program">INFRA Grants</a>, and the <a href="https://www.maritime.dot.gov/PIDPgrants">Port Infrastructure Development Program</a>.</li><li><strong>Promoting Best Practices with Federal Construction Industry Contractors. </strong>Given the landmark level of funding available under the bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to the construction industry and provisions in those grant programs aimed at expanding access to project jobs for formerly incarcerated persons, it is critical that federal contractors and subcontractors comply with the law. This is why the Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contracting and Compliance Programs (OFCCP) issued <a href="https://content.govdelivery.com/accounts/USDOLOFCCP/bulletins/3136722">new guidance</a> to federal contractors and subcontractors that underscores its earlier <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/directives/2013-02">directive</a> that criminal background check policies, which may have a disparate impact on protected classes, may violate existing nondiscrimination obligations.  OFCCP also developed compliance assistance materials for contractors including a <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/compliance-assistance/outreach/webinars">webinar</a>, <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/faqs/construction-compliance">Construction Compliance FAQs</a>, and a <a href="https://ofccptraining.dol.gov/catalog/construction-compliance-review-contractors">training</a>. OFCCP has also <a href="https://content.govdelivery.com/accounts/USDOLOFCCP/bulletins/2ef6204">released</a> a new memorandum identifying 400 federal contractors and subcontractors who have been neutrally selected to undergo a full compliance review of their hiring practices to ensure people with arrest and conviction records are not being discriminated against.</li><li><strong>Expanding Second Chance Visiting Fellowship Program. </strong>The Department of Justice’s Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA) <a href="https://www.ojp.gov/blog/second-chance-fellows-john-bae-and-angel-sanchez">brought on two new Second Chance Fellows </a>who were formerly incarcerated to help develop reentry policy. For the first time, one of those Fellows will work with the Department of Education (ED) on educational policy for carceral settings and upon reentry.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Promoting Best Practices for Hiring Across the Federal Government</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing Interactive Training and Technical Assistance for Job Seekers.</strong> The Office of Personnel Management has published <a href="https://chcoc.gov/content/second-chance-month">detailed guidance</a> for applicants with arrest and conviction records who are interested in federal employment. To further support them, OPM is hosting interactive sessions between federal agencies’ Human Resources practitioners and applicants with arrest and conviction records.</li><li><strong>Leveraging Existing Hiring Authorities for Agencies.</strong> OPM will host a <a href="https://secondchance.eventbrite.com">training webinar</a> on April 28 to assist federal hiring officials, human resource and DEIA practitioners, and supervisors with leveraging existing federal hiring authorities to recruit and hire formerly incarcerated persons into the federal government.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Veterans</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expediting the Restoration of Benefits</strong>. In partnership with the Social Security Administration and the Bureau of Prisons, the Department of Veterans Affairs’ Veterans Benefits Administration <a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5780">announced</a> a new effort to automate information-sharing among these agencies to accelerate benefit restoration and reduce the administrative burden for veterans.</li><li><strong>Conducting Outreach to Incarcerated Veterans. </strong> The VA <a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5780">announced</a> new efforts to increase the number of state prisons and jails that use its Veterans Reentry Search Service, which helps identify veterans in their custody and connect them with reentry services.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanding Access to Health Care and Housing</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Access to Health Care. </strong>The Department of Health and Human Services is <a href="https://www.cms.gov/files/document/cms-4199-p.pdf">proposing</a> to establish a Special Enrollment Period (SEP) of six months post-release for Medicare for people who missed an enrollment period while incarcerated, which would reduce potential gaps in coverage and late enrollment penalties.</li><li><strong>Expanding Access to Housing.</strong> The Department of Housing and Urban Development announced that it has <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/Main/documents/Memo_on_Criminal_Records.pdf">initiated a 6-month comprehensive review</a> of its existing regulations and guidance to identify how HUD programs can increase their inclusivity of people with arrest and conviction records.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Developing and Amplifying Educational Opportunities</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Second Chance Pell.</strong> ED will select 73 additional schools to <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-expansion-second-chance-pell-program-and-actions-help-incarcerated-individuals-resume-educational-journeys-and-reduce-recidivism">expand</a> its Second Chance Pell Initiative. The expansion of the program into these schools will ultimately provide access to thousands of additional students. First established in 2015 by the Obama-Biden Administration, the Second Chance Pell Initiative provides Pell Grants to incarcerated individuals to participate in postsecondary education programs. This expansion of sites will help the Department to prepare for full expansion of Pell Grant eligibility to incarcerated students in July 2023.</li><li><strong>Providing a Pathway Out of Loan Default. </strong>ED will also announce <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-expansion-second-chance-pell-program-and-actions-help-incarcerated-individuals-resume-educational-journeys-and-reduce-recidivism">changes</a> to policies to help incarcerated individuals get out of loan default to access Pell Grants. In the short term, incarcerated persons who have defaulted will get a “fresh start.” Like other defaulted borrowers, incarcerated borrowers with defaulted loans will reenter repayment in good standing when the student loan payment pause ends. ED is also announcing a longer-term fix that will take place after “fresh start” is implemented: it will allow incarcerated persons to consolidate their loans to get out of default. Incarcerated persons interested in enrolling in Second Chance Pell were twice as likely as the broader population to be turned away because of defaulted loans. This change will now allow incarcerated persons the same opportunity to get out of default as non-incarcerated persons.</li><li><strong>Investing in Digital Literacy.</strong> The Department of Commerce’s <a href="https://broadbandusa.ntia.doc.gov/resources/grant-programs/digital-equity-programs">Digital Equity Planning Grant</a>, funded by the bipartisan Infrastructure and Investment Jobs Act, will provide $60 million to states and Puerto Rico to invest in digital literacy and equity programs for underserved communities,  including incarcerated and formerly incarcerated persons.</li><li><strong>Publishing New Guidance on Correctional and Reentry Education Resources.</strong> ED published <a href="https://cte.ed.gov/yadiversion/">guidance</a> to states and localities on how to divert young adults from the juvenile and criminal justice system. ED also published new <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ovae/pi/AdultEd/take-charge-your-future.pdf">guidance</a> for incarcerated persons seeking educational opportunities, summarizing the resources available to support them.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Job Seekers and Establishing Best Practices for Employers</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Tax Credits and Free Bonding Programs for Employers. </strong>DOL developed <a href="https://reo.workforcegps.org/resources/2022/04/06/17/28/Reentry-Employment-Opportunities-Recognizes-April-as-Second-Chance-Month">new resources</a> for justice-involved job seekers, reentry service providers, and employers to learn about existing federal reentry employment incentives including the <a href="https://bonds4jobs.com/">Federal Bonding Program</a> and the <a href="https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-self-employed/work-opportunity-tax-credit">Work Opportunity Tax Credit</a>.</li><li><strong>Resources for Employers, Job Seekers, and Employees.</strong> The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission’s new <a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/arrestandconviction">landing page</a> centralizes existing resources on the use of arrest and conviction records in employment decisions, and other technical assistance documents for employers and job seekers.</li><li><strong>Supporting Reentry 2030.</strong> DOJ’s Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA  partnered with the Council of State Governments (CSG) to launch the <a href="https://bja.ojp.gov/events/advancing-successful-reintegration-every-person-reentry-2030-national-launch#:~:text=Reentry%202030%20is%20a%20partnership,towards%20their%20Reentry%202030%20goals.">national Reentry 2030 campaign</a>, which will work with state leaders to set public reentry goals to achieve better economic mobility and outcomes for persons exiting prison, parole or probation by 2030.</li><li><strong>Promoting Resources for Second Chance Month. </strong>The National Reentry Resource Center (NRRC) is <a href="https://nationalreentryresourcecenter.org/second-chance-month-april-2022-calendar">hosting a series</a> of live training and technical assistance events for Second Chance Act grantees as well as the public in honor of Second Chance Month.</li><li><strong>Reentry Toolkit. </strong>The <a href="https://nationalreentryresourcecenter.org">National Reentry Resource Center</a> launched the Bureau of Justice Assistance’s <a href="http://www.reentrytoolkit.org/">Reentry Toolkit</a> for local reentry coalition leaders and community leaders to allow assessment of existing reentry efforts and opportunities to strengthen outcomes for incarcerated persons in their communities. The NRRC will also continue to host its searchable database of reentry resources.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clemency Recipient List</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/clemency-recipient-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is granting clemency to 78 individuals, consisting of three pardons and 75 commutations. President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is pardoning the following three individuals: Abraham W. Bolden, Sr. – Chicago, IllinoisAbraham Bolden is an 86-year-old former U.S. Secret Service agent and was the first African American to serve on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is granting clemency to 78 individuals, consisting of three pardons and 75 commutations.<br><br>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is pardoning the following three individuals:<br><br><strong>Abraham W. Bolden, Sr.</strong> – Chicago, Illinois<br>Abraham Bolden is an 86-year-old former U.S. Secret Service agent and was the first African American to serve on a presidential detail.  In 1964, Mr. Bolden was charged with offenses related to attempting to sell a copy of a Secret Service file.  His first trial resulted in a hung jury, and following his conviction at a second trial, even though key witnesses against him admitted to lying at the prosecutor’s request, Mr. Bolden was denied a new trial and ultimately served several years in federal custody.  He has steadfastly maintained his innocence, arguing that he was targeted for prosecution in retaliation for exposing unprofessional and racist behavior within the U.S. Secret Service.  Mr. Bolden has received numerous honors and awards for his ongoing work to speak out against the racism he faced in the Secret Service in the 1960s, and his courage in challenging injustice.  Mr. Bolden has also been recognized for his many contributions to his community following his release from prison.<br><br><strong>Betty Jo Bogans</strong> – Houston, Texas<br>Betty Jo Bogans is a 51-year-old woman who was convicted in 1998 of possession with intent to distribute crack cocaine in the Southern District of Texas after attempting to transport drugs for her boyfriend and his accomplice, neither of whom were detained or arrested.  At the time of her conviction, Ms. Bogans was a single mother with no prior record, who accepted responsibility for her limited role in the offense.  Because of the harsh penalties in place at the time she was convicted, Ms. Bogan received a seven-year sentence.  In the nearly two decades since her release from custody, Ms. Bogans has held consistent employment, even while undergoing treatment for cancer, and has focused on raising her son.   <br><br><strong>Dexter Eugene Jackson</strong> – Athens, Georgia<br>Dexter Jackson is a 52-year-old man who was convicted in 2002 for using his business to facilitate the distribution of marijuana in the Northern District of Georgia.  Mr. Jackson was not personally involved in trafficking marijuana, but allowed marijuana distributors to use his pool hall to facilitate drug transactions.  He accepted full responsibility for his actions at the time he was charged, and pled guilty.  Since his release from custody, Mr. Jackson has converted his business into a cell-phone repair service and hired local high school students through a program that seeks to provide young adults with work experience.  Mr. Jackson has also worked to build and renovate homes in a community that lacks quality affordable housing.<br><br>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is commuting the sentences of the following 75 individuals:<br><br><strong>Sergio Acosta</strong> – Montgomery, Alabama<br><strong>Offense:</strong> Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Kentucky). <br><strong>Sentence:</strong> 97 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 23, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kathy Marie Albrecht</strong> – Jamestown, North Dakota<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a controlled substance (District of North Dakota).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 150 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (November 6, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Maria Isabel Arreola</strong> – San Bernardino, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>:<br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine (Eastern District of Texas).<br>2. Conspiracy to distribute cocaine hydrochloride (Middle District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 121 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 24, 2016).<br>2. 130 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (November 17, 2016).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run concurrently.<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year terms of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Roberto Barrio </strong>– South Gate, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute cocaine base and cocaine powder; interstate travel in aid of racketeering enterprise (four counts); use of a telephone to facilitate the distribution of cocaine base and cocaine powder (two counts) (Western District of Oklahoma).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (October 23, 2000).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kelvin Beaufort</strong> – Charlotte, North Carolina<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute cocaine and cocaine base (Western District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 324 months of imprisonment, 20-year term of supervised release (December 10, 2007); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, 20-year term of supervised release (January 20, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 20-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brandon Todd Berry </strong>– Sikeston, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of a substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (October 19, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Sharon Louise Boatright</strong> – Richardson, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 190 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (December 16, 2013); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (July 15, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Terry Booty</strong> – Morgan City, Louisiana  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine (Eastern District of Louisiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $10,000 fine (November 13, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $10,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Ramola Kaye Brown</strong> – Huntsville, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute five kilograms or more of cocaine and less than 50 kilograms of marijuana (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 145 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (September 15, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Julian Burford </strong>– Bedford, Ohio<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute cocaine (Northern District of Ohio).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (September 17, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mark Richard Burton</strong> – Odessa, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and/or 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence: </strong>121 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $15,000 fine (March 16, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Nickolas Cano</strong> – Amarillo, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine and aiding and abetting (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (September 5, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Ruben Lopez Cazares</strong> – Chula Vista, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute controlled substance (District of Nebraska).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 300 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 7, 2007); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (January 12, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Jose Luis Colunga </strong>– Juniata, Nebraska<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possession with intent to distribute 1,000 kilograms or more of marijuana (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (July 13, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on October 26, 2023, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Paul Hernandez Contreras</strong> – Perris, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possession with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine and a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of cocaine (District of Colorado).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 108 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 8, 2019).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Karen Cox</strong> – Salt Lake City, Utah  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 121 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $900 community restitution (June 16, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 60-month term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $900 community restitution.<br><br><strong>Lori Jean Cross</strong> – North Richland Hills, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (September 12, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mario Cruz</strong> – Grand Rapids, Michigan<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute an unspecified quantity of cocaine and heroin (Western District of Michigan).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 121 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 23, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Christopher Dancy </strong>– Prince George, Virginia<br><strong>Offense: </strong>Conspiracy to distribute cocaine hydrochloride (Eastern District of Virginia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 336 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 27, 2009); amended to 288 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 19, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Catalina Davis</strong> – San Antonio, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute methamphetamine; aiding and abetting the possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 6, 2014); amended to 151 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 31, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stacie Demers</strong> – Constable, New York<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute marijuana; aiding and abetting the possession with intent to distribute marijuana (Northern District of New York).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (October 26, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Deborah Ann Dodd</strong> – Forney, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectible amount of methamphetamine or 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Eastern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 19, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Manuel Ruben Duran-Pimentel</strong> – Miami, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to import controlled substances; laundering of monetary instruments (District of Puerto Rico).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 151 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (April 20, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Nova Neal Finau</strong> – Fort Worth, Texas<br><strong>Offense: </strong>Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (March 31, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tina Marie Finazzo</strong> – Las Vegas, Nevada<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine (District of Hawaii).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 172 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 16, 2012); amended to 168 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 19, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David C. Frazier</strong> – St. Louis, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute cocaine; possession with intent to distribute a mixture containing cocaine; maintaining a drug involved premises (Eastern District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 144 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 21, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Julio Garza </strong>– Edinberg, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>:  Possession with intent to distribute 10 kilograms of cocaine (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (May 13, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Odell Givens</strong> – Certe, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute a controlled substance; possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (three counts) (Northern District of Illinois).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 186 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 14, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Dianna Gonzalez-Agosto</strong> – Altura de Rio G, Puerto Rico<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute at least 3.5 kilograms but less than 5 kilograms of cocaine within a protected location (District of Puerto Rico).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 87 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (July 14, 2020).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Virgil Goodman, Jr. </strong>– Lexington, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession of methamphetamine with intent to distribute (Western District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 262 months of imprisonment, six-year term of supervised release (June 30, 2005).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the six-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Christopher Gunter</strong> – Columbia, South Carolina  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute 50 grams or more of cocaine base, 5 kilograms or more of cocaine, and 100 kilograms or more of marijuana; possession with intent to distribute a quantity of marijuana and a quantity of MDMA (District of South Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (September 25, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rachel Lynn Hanson </strong>– Richton Park, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession of an unspecified quantity of cocaine with intent to distribute (Western District of Michigan).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 151 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 4, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stephanie Hernandez</strong> – Dallas, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (April 21, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brandon Jermaine Huguley</strong> – Chattanooga, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 280 grams or more of cocaine base (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 235 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 20, 2012); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 22, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David Charles Jenkins</strong> – Beaumont, Texas<br><strong>Offense:</strong><br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine base; possession with intent to distribute cocaine base (Western District of Louisiana).<br>2. Violation of supervised release (Eastern District of Texas).<br>3. Production of counterfeit access devices (Eastern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 151 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (November 28, 2011); amended to 121 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (February 9, 2018).<br>2. 24 months of imprisonment (January 5, 2012).<br>3. 24 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $2,516 restitution (April 29, 2015).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight and three-year terms of supervised release, and the unpaid remainders, if any, of the $5,000 fine and $2,516 restitution.<br><br><strong>Douglas Dean Johnson</strong> – Dickens, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to manufacture and distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and possess and distribute pseudoephedrine following a felony drug conviction; travel in interstate commerce and aid and abet travel in interstate commerce with the intent to promote and facilitate a business enterprise involving the manufacture and distribution of controlled substances (Northern District of Iowa).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (December 8, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Gregory Jones </strong>– Philadelphia, Pennsylvania  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute five kilograms or more of cocaine; attempted possession with the intent to distribute five or more kilograms of cocaine and aiding and abetting (East District of Pennsylvania).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 216 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,500 fine (March 30, 2012).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,500 fine.<br><br><strong>Stephan George Jones</strong> – Rosebud, South Dakota<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute a controlled substance (District of South Dakota).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $1,000 fine (April 11, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $1,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Terri Kelly </strong>– Rialto, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams of methamphetamine (Eastern District of Kentucky).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (November 30, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tellas Levallas Kennedy </strong>– Glennville, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a quantity of cocaine hydrochloride (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $4,800 fine (September 30, 2013); amended to 168 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $4,800 fine (October 22, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and $4,800 fine.<br><br><strong>Vincent Edward Kennedy </strong>– Surfside Beach, South Carolina<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine; money laundering (District of South Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 180 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 26, 2014); amended to 145 months of imprisonment 10-year term of supervised release (June 29, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brittany Krambeck </strong>– Fort Worth, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Maintaining drug involved premises; structuring transactions to evade reporting requirements (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 220 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (October 29, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2024, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Carry Le </strong>– Duluth, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 1,000 or more marijuana plants (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 4, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David Lee </strong>– Philadelphia, Pennsylvania<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute more than one kilogram of heroin and to distribute or manufacture in or near a school zone; distribution and possession of heroin with intent to distribute (seven counts); use of communication facility (Eastern District of Pennsylvania).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 300 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $1,500 fine (October 1, 2007); amended to 243 months of imprisonment,10-year term of supervised release, $1,500 fine (June 24, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and $1,500 fine.<br><br><strong>Rosamaria Lucero </strong>– New Braunfels, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance, aiding and abetting (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 13, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Paul A. Lupercio </strong>– Blue Springs, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 1,000 kilograms or more of marijuana and five kilograms or more of cocaine (Western District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (May 8, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Angelica Marquez </strong>– Apple Valley, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute more than 50 grams of methamphetamine (District of Kansas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 117 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (April 23, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Eddie Mateus </strong>– New York, New York<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute heroin and cocaine (Southern District of New York).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stephanie McMurphy </strong>– Adel, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of methamphetamine within 1,000 feet of a school (Middle District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 102 months of imprisonment, six-year term of supervised release (October 22, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the six-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Byron James Miller</strong> – St. Louis, Missouri<br><strong>Offense:</strong><br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute crack cocaine; possession with intent to distribute in excess of 500 grams of cocaine (Eastern District of Missouri).<br>2. Possession with intent to distribute heroin; possession of heroin in a federal prison (District of Central Illinois).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: <br>1. 292 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 6, 1997); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (December 17, 2019).<br>2. 210 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 5, 1999).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the consecutive eight and three-year terms of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Bethel Cheyenne Mooneyham </strong>– Spencer, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to manufacture and distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 13, 2011).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Colleen Mossberger </strong>– Crest Hill, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of methamphetamine (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 5, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Quang Nguyen </strong>– Houston, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 1,000 or more marijuana plants (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 30, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rickey Wayne Norton </strong>– Augusta, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $40,000 fine (October 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $40,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Shannon Ann Norton </strong>– Augusta, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $40,000 fine (October 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $40,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Thomas Perkins </strong>– Louisville, Kentucky<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute in excess of 5 kilograms or more of cocaine hydrochloride (mixture) and 50 grams or more of cocaine base (mixture) (Southern District of Indiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (December 22, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Aaron Ponce </strong>– Odessa, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a controlled substance, 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (July 11, 2013).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rose Trujillo Rangel </strong>– Waco, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute cocaine, a schedule II-narcotic-drug-controlled substance (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (April 14, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $5,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Alejandro Reyna</strong> – Brownsville, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Importation of more than 50 grams of methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (January 16, 2014); amended to 180 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (February 26, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Fermin Serna</strong> – Rio Grande City, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute in excess of 1,000 kilograms of marijuana, a schedule I controlled substance (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (November 9, 2007).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mackie Shivers</strong> – Ft. Lauderdale, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 5 kilograms or more of cocaine; possession with intent to distribute 5 kilograms or more of cocaine (Southern District of Florida).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (April 10, 2001).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kirstie Marie Smith Israel</strong> – Albertville, Alabama<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine (Northern District of Alabama).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 97 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (August 23, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tony Lee Stanfield</strong> – Villa Rica, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Western District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (November 2, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Cleola Sullivan</strong> – Tallahassee, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute cocaine base and 5 kilograms or more of cocaine; possess with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of cocaine (Northern District of Florida).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 13, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Charles Arnold Thomas </strong>– Inglewood, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>:<br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 100 grams or more of phencyclidine, or one kilogram or more of a mixture containing a detectable amount of phencyclidine (Southern District of Texas).<br>2. Possession of a prohibited item by a prison inmate (Eastern District of Arkansas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 4, 2011).<br>2. Seven months of imprisonment (April 25, 2018).<br>Prison sentences in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Edwin G. Tierney </strong>– Council Bluffs, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute methamphetamine (District of Nebraska).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (November 8, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Jesse Alan Trimue</strong> – Burton, Michigan<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute 5 grams of actual methamphetamine and 50 grams or more of methamphetamine mixture, a schedule II-controlled substance (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (June 6, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Daniel Valencia</strong> – Maylene, Alabama<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Importation of a quantity of 50 grams or more of methamphetamine and 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 135 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (April 24, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Martin R. Vandemerwe</strong> – Price, Utah<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (District of Utah).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 20 years of imprisonment; five-year term of supervised release (September 23, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>James Darrell Walker</strong> – Lubbock, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of and possession with intent to distribute cocaine base (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 327 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 21, 2006); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 9, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Cindy Noella Williams</strong> – Casper, Wyoming<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $800 restitution (October 10, 2018); amended to 102 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release; $800 restitution (November 4, 2019).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $800 restitution.<br><br><strong>Cynthia Lynn Yeley-Davis</strong> – Mills, Wyoming<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $1,000 fine (December 17, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $1,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Andrea Zavala</strong> – Waterloo, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute at least 50 grams of a mixture or substance containing methamphetamine and 5 grams of actual methamphetamine (Northern District of Iowa).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 108 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 7, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Courtney Donnell Zeno </strong>– Warner Robins, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of cocaine base (five counts); possession with intent to distribute cocaine base; forfeiture (Western District of Louisiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (August 31, 2010); amended to 240 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (February 7, 2013).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David L. Zouck </strong>– Buffalo, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of methamphetamine; distribution of five grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Western District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 132 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 30, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Clemency and Second Chance&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-clemency-and-second-chance-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America is a nation of laws and second chances, redemption, and rehabilitation. Elected officials on both sides of the aisle, faith leaders, civil rights advocates, and law enforcement leaders agree that our criminal justice system can and should reflect these core values that enable safer and stronger communities. During Second Chance Month, I am using&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America is a nation of laws and second chances, redemption, and rehabilitation. Elected officials on both sides of the aisle, faith leaders, civil rights advocates, and law enforcement leaders agree that our criminal justice system can and should reflect these core values that enable safer and stronger communities. During Second Chance Month, I am using my authority under the Constitution to uphold those values by <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/clemency-recipient-list/">pardoning and commuting</a> the sentences of fellow Americans.</p>



<p>Today, I am pardoning three people who have demonstrated their commitment to rehabilitation and are striving every day to give back and contribute to their communities. I am also commuting the sentences of 75 people who are serving long sentences for non-violent drug offenses, many of whom have been serving on home confinement during the COVID-pandemic—and many of whom would have received a lower sentence if they were charged with the same offense today, thanks to the bipartisan First Step Act. &nbsp;</p>



<p>My Administration is also announcing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-expands-second-chance-opportunities-for-formerly-incarcerated-persons/">new steps</a> today to support those re-entering society after incarceration. These actions include: a new collaboration between the U.S. Department of Justice and the U.S. Department of Labor to provide job training; new grants for workforce development programs; greater opportunities to serve in federal government; expanded access to capital for people with convictions trying to start a small business; improved reentry services for veterans; and more support for health care, housing, and educational opportunities.  </p>



<p>As I laid out in my comprehensive strategy to reduce gun crime, helping those who served their time return to their families and become contributing members of their communities is one of the most effective ways to reduce recidivism and decrease crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While today’s announcement marks important progress, my Administration will continue to review clemency petitions and deliver reforms that advance equity and justice, provide second chances, and enhance the wellbeing and safety of all Americans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Increases Access to COVID-&#8288;19 Treatments and Boosts Patient and Provider&#160;Awareness</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-administration-increases-access-to-covid-19-treatments-and-boosts-patient-and-provider-awareness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 response, there are now more tools than ever before to protect people from the virus, including highly-effective treatments. Over the past 15 months, the Administration has pulled levers across the federal government and deployed resources Congress provided to expedite the development, production, and procurement of COVID-19 treatments. As a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 response, there are now more tools than ever before to protect people from the virus, including highly-effective treatments. Over the past 15 months, the Administration has pulled levers across the federal government and deployed resources Congress provided to expedite the development, production, and procurement of COVID-19 treatments. As a result, the U.S. now has several treatments available that can help keep people out of the hospital and save lives.<br><br>One of the most effective available treatments is Pfizer’s oral antiviral pill, Paxlovid, which has been shown to reduce the risk of hospitalization or death by about 90 percent. The U.S. has committed to purchase 20 million treatment courses—more than any other country in the world. Although Paxlovid was initially in short supply after Food and Drug Administration (FDA) authorization, the Administration has worked with Pfizer to accelerate the delivery of these pills, and they are now in ample supply. The President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/covidplan/">National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan</a> lays out a roadmap for ensuring that these pills, along with other treatments, are available for any American who needs one.<br><br>Since December 2021, the Administration has distributed COVID-19 oral antivirals directly to states, Tribes, territories, and community health centers for free. States and territories play an important role in distributing these treatments to health care providers, pharmacies, and other locations, and any doctor can prescribe treatments. In March, as supply began to ramp up, the President announced the Test-to-Treat initiative to help make it easier for people at high risk of severe disease to quickly access oral antiviral treatments. The Test-to-Treat initiative creates additional locations where people can get a COVID-19 test, a visit with a medical provider, and, if needed, free oral antiviral pills—all in one visit.<br><br>To date, the Administration has worked with pharmacies, long-term care facilities, community health centers, and other health care settings to establish more than 2,200 Test-to-Treat sites around the country, including sites specifically for military families and veterans. As a result, usage of oral antivirals has more than doubled over the last several weeks.<br><br>Today, the Administration is announcing new actions to make these treatments even easier to access and to make sure health care providers and patients know about their safety, efficacy, and availability. These actions will help strengthen and further build the infrastructure to ensure that lifesaving treatments for COVID-19 are quickly distributed around the country, widely available, and easy to access. At the same time, ensuring that this remains the case—and securing more and even better treatments—will require additional funding from Congress.<br><br>Today’s actions include:<br><br><strong>Nearly doubling the number of places oral antivirals are available in the coming weeks. </strong>Right now, oral antivirals are available in about 20,000 locations across the country—including pharmacies, community health centers, hospitals, urgent care centers, and Veterans Affairs clinics, and Department of Defense Medical Treatment Facilities. Now that the United States has ample supply of these treatments, the Administration is making it easier for pharmacies to order antivirals from the federal government. Starting this week, the Administration will allow all pharmacy partners in the federal antiviral pharmacy program—tens of thousands of pharmacy locations nationwide—to order free oral antiviral treatments directly from the federal government. Pharmacies will also continue to be able to receive treatments from state and territorial health departments and through the Test-to-Treat initiative. For many Americans, pharmacies are the most common and convenient place to pick up their prescriptions and receive other forms of health care. Opening ordering to all of these pharmacies will dramatically expand the number of local pharmacies with oral antivirals in stock for patients in their community. The Administration expects that oral antivirals will soon be available in more than 30,000 locations. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will work with pharmacy partners to increase availability even further to up to 40,000 sites over the coming weeks—bringing these treatments closer to more Americans.<br><br><strong>Launching a new effort to stand up federally-supported Test-to-Treat sites. </strong>Building on the current 2,200 Test-to-Treat sites in pharmacies and other clinical settings, the federal government will work with states and jurisdictions to establish additional Test-to-Treat locations with federal support. These sites will co-locate testing, an assessment from a medical provider, and oral antiviral treatments in one convenient stop—launching in partnership with state, Tribal, and territorial governments, and with support and coordination from HHS and the Federal Emergency Management Agency. These sites will launch in select communities in the coming weeks and, as more data comes in, the Administration will determine how federally-supported sites can best be expanded and scaled if needed during any potential future surge in cases. These sites will be targeted to meet demand and increase equitable access to lifesaving COVID-19 treatments and will function in direct collaboration with state and local health agencies. The Administration will also continue working with existing Test-to-Treat pharmacy partners to improve the patient experience, including through telehealth options.<br><br><strong>Supporting medical providers with more guidance and tools to understand and prescribe treatments. </strong>It is critical that health care providers stay informed about the latest information on effective COVID-19 treatments—including their benefits, contraindications, drug-to-drug interactions, and other side effects—so that they are in a position to quickly prescribe one of these treatments where appropriate. The Administration has been working for months with health care providers around the country to inform them about new treatments, with weekly webinars with state and territorial health officials, health care and medical organizations, as well as biweekly clinical webinars with health care providers, including those who specialize in treating high-risk patients. The Administration will continue to engage the clinical community to broaden awareness and understanding of these treatments and to make sure that health care providers are counseling their patients about these effective treatments, prescribing them when appropriate, and helping patients identify where their prescription can be filled. This includes providing toolkits and resources to help doctors assess whether treatments are appropriate for their patients and additional guidance and outreach to every state, pharmacy chain, and major medical association to increase awareness around eligibility, accessibility, contraindications and prescribing considerations for COVID-19 treatments. To that end, just yesterday, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) issued a <a href="https://emergency.cdc.gov/han/2022/pdf/CDC_HAN_463.pdf">Health Alert Network health advisory</a> to its extensive network of public health officials to provide additional information about the efficacy and availability of these treatments. Building on its ongoing work with electronic health record companies to develop and disseminate information about COVID-19 treatments to providers, the Administration is also calling on these companies to incorporate information about oral antivirals directly into their health records interface. This would make it easier to prompt doctors with information about treatments and locations when interacting with a patient—helping to better integrate the prescription of oral antivirals to patients that need them into doctors’ everyday practice.<br><br><strong>Communicating to the American people that safe, effective treatments are widely available. </strong>Now that the Administration has made treatments widely available and there are tens of thousands of sites around the country where they can be dispensed, the Administration will ramp up its public awareness and education efforts on COVID-19 treatments. The Administration’s efforts will focus on making sure that people know that COVID-19 oral antiviral treatments must be taken within the first five days of symptom onset and understand their role in reducing the risk of severe disease and death from COVID-19. These efforts build on steps that the Administration has taken in recent weeks to help people access treatments, including the launch of COVID.gov, creating shareable infographics with clear test-and-treat messages, promoting test-and-treat messages on social media, launching the <a href="https://covid-19-test-to-treat-locator-dhhs.hub.arcgis.com/">Test-to-Treat locator</a>, and standing up a call center (800-232-0233) to provide help in English, Spanish, and more than 150 other languages.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan call with South African National Security Advisor Sydney&#160;Mufamadi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-call-with-south-african-national-security-advisor-sydney-mufamadi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with South African National Security Advisor Sydney Mufamadi. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Mufamadi reaffirmed President Biden and President Ramaphosa’s commitment to strengthen the U.S-South Africa bilateral relationship. Mr. Sullivan pledged support to the people and government of South Africa in response to the deadly floods in Kwa Zulu&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with South African National Security Advisor Sydney Mufamadi. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Mufamadi reaffirmed President Biden and President Ramaphosa’s commitment to strengthen the U.S-South Africa bilateral relationship. Mr. Sullivan pledged support to the people and government of South Africa in response to the deadly floods in Kwa Zulu Natal. He also emphasized the United States’ continued readiness to work closely with South Africa to address the crisis in Ukraine; enhance our partnership on trade and investment, health systems and health security, and climate change; and support counterterrorism and regional security efforts. They highlighted the need for an immediate end to Russia’s aggression in Ukraine, and shared views on addressing the impact on supply chains, commodity prices, and food security in Africa.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-national-security-advisor-dr-eyal-hulata-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following President Biden’s fruitful conversation with Israeli Prime Minister Bennett on April 24, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with his Israeli counterpart, National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata, to discuss a range of regional and global security issues.  Mr. Sullivan emphasized that the United States is attuned to Israel’s concerns about threats to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Following President Biden’s fruitful conversation with Israeli Prime Minister Bennett on April 24, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with his Israeli counterpart, National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata, to discuss a range of regional and global security issues.  Mr. Sullivan emphasized that the United States is attuned to Israel’s concerns about threats to its security, including first-and-foremost from Iran and Iranian-backed proxies.  They agreed to further enhance the ongoing coordination through the U.S.-Israel Strategic Consultative Group and strengthen security and diplomatic cooperation wherever possible with other regional partners.  They also discussed Israel’s relationships with key Indo-Pacific countries.  Sullivan and Hulata continued their discussions regarding Russia’s war on Ukraine and the need to continue supporting our Ukrainian partners.  They committed to continue their close coordination on the range of security issues of importance to both the United States and Israel, and they look forward to President Biden’s visit to Israel in the coming months.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 25,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/25/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-25-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 22:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51760</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:20 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; There’s nothing happening in the world today, I hear &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; so this should be a quick one. I have a couple of items for you at the top, as usual. Over the past year, businesses have been dealing with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:20 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; There’s nothing happening in the world today, I hear &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; so this should be a quick one.</p>



<p>I have a couple of items for you at the top, as usual.</p>



<p>Over the past year, businesses have been dealing with frequent freight delay &#8212; rail delays and poor service, which has stranded shipments of grain, fertilizer, ethanol, and other critical commodities across the country.&nbsp; This breakdown in service has also forced grain shippers to pay thousands of extra dollars to guarantee service.</p>



<p>So, on Friday, our administration took emergency action to get goods moving faster and lower shipping costs.&nbsp; The Surface Transportation Board, which regulates railroads, acted on a bipartisan basis to help bring relief to American businesses that ship their goods by freight rail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Basically, what they did is: This emergency rule would allow it to address situations where a monopolu- &#8212; monopoly railroad isn&#8217;t providing adequate service and show an alternative railroad to step in.&nbsp; So if a business wants to move their goods and the railroad that they are contracted with isn&#8217;t allowing them to move them quickly, this will allow them to have some flexibility, hopefully allowing the movement of more goods, getting them on shelves, lowering costs.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note that while the President is doing everything in his power to lower prices for American families, the Federal Reserve plays an important role, as you all know, in fighting inflation, which is why it&#8217;s so important that we have all of the seats filled on the Federal Reserve&#8217;s Board of Governors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today and this week, as Congress returns, we&#8217;re taking a big step forward toward filling these seats with the nominations of Lael Brainard and Lisa Cook making their way to the Senate floor.</p>



<p>We call on the Senate to confirm Dr. Brainard and Dr. Cook. And we also call on the Senate to swiftly take up Jerome Powell and Philip Jefferson&#8217;s nominations this week as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These nominees are eminently qualified, ready to get to work, and deserve bipartisan support.&nbsp; They also will make history.&nbsp; Lisa Cook would become the first Black woman to ever serve on the Board of Governors, and Philip Jefferson will be only the fourth Black man to serve on the Board of Governors.</p>



<p>Finally, the VA announced today new actions to expand disability and health bene- &#8212; benefits to veterans suffering from nine rare respiratory cancers.&nbsp; Supporting our veterans is a critical part of the President&#8217;s Unity Agenda.&nbsp; And with this step, the President is continuing to deliver on the sacred obligation we have to our nation&#8217;s veterans.</p>



<p>The President urges congress to pass bipartisan legislation to comprehensively address toxic exposures and further <s>delay</s> [deliver] the vital benefits our veterans have earned.</p>



<p>Andrea, welcome back.&nbsp; Peter, welcome from book leave.&nbsp; Now they&#8217;re going to ask me especially hard questions.</p>



<p>Zeke, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Secretary Austin, I believe, said earlier this morning that the U.S. wants to, quote, “see Russia weakened to the degree that it can’t do the kinds things that it has done in invading Ukraine.”&nbsp; He said that in regards to Russian military losses, quote, “We want to see them not have the capability to very quickly reproduce that capability.”&nbsp; Is it U.S. policy now to permanently degrade the Russian military?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what Secretary Austin in his press conference was referring to is the fact that if you go back about two months ago, remember President Putin gave a speech where he talked about the aspirations &#8212; his aspirations, the aspirations he had for the Russian military &#8212; which were to degrade Ukraine, of course; to subsume Ukraine, to take over their sovereignty, their territorial integrity.&nbsp; Of course, they haven&#8217;t succeeded at that, but to go beyond that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what Secretary Austin was talking about is our objective to prevent that from happening.&nbsp; Obviously, right now, the war is in Ukraine.&nbsp; They are &#8212; we&#8217;re proud of the Ukrainians’ success; their efforts to fight back, to push back on the Russian military, thanks to their bravery but also to our support.</p>



<p>But, yes, we are &#8212; we are also &#8212; we are also looking to prevent them from expanding their efforts and President Putin&#8217;s objectives beyond that, too.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any concern in the White House that that sort of rhetoric plays into their domestic message to their audience about “the West is out trying to get us and contain us,” that &#8212; by saying you’re trying to weaken the Russian military and weaken &#8212; it’s essentially strengthening Putin’s hand at home?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; I would say it&#8217;s consistent with our view and the President&#8217;s view and Secretary Austin&#8217;s view that we are going to do everything we can to push back on President Putin&#8217;s aspirations to subsume Ukraine, to take over their territorial integrity and their sovereignty, and aspirations he had as of two months ago to go beyond that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And Congress is back in town today.&nbsp; The President last week said he’s going to go back to Congress looking for additional &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; supplemental Ukraine funding.&nbsp; Do you have a dollar figure for how much the President need &#8212; is going to go ask for and how long that money would last?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Not quite yet.&nbsp; He is &#8212; expect he’ll have consultations and conversations with military leadership and, of course, leadership from the State Department over the course of the coming days.&nbsp; I expect it&#8217;ll be something later in the week, and expect it&#8217;ll be a longer-term package or proposal.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a quick one on the breaking news: Twitter agreeing to let Elon Musk purchase &#8212; make his &#8212; go through with this purchase.&nbsp; Do you have a response to that?&nbsp; And does the White House have any concern that this new agreement might have President Trump back on the platform?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to comment on a specific transaction.&nbsp; What I can tell you as a general matter: No matter who owns or runs Twitter, the President has long been concerned about the power of large social media platforms, what they ha- &#8212; the power they have over our everyday lives; has long argued that tech platforms must be held accountable for the harms they cause.&nbsp; He has been a strong supporter of fundamental reforms to achieve that goal, including reforms to Section 230, enacting antitrust reforms, requiring more transparency, and more.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s encouraged that there&#8217;s bipartisan interest in Congress.</p>



<p>In terms of what hypothetical policies might happen, I&#8217;m just not going to speak to that at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On the situation at the border and Title 42, Congressman McCaul said this weekend that Secretary Mayorkas has expressed some frustration directly to him about how the administration is ending Title 42.&nbsp; He says the Secretary is saying that the Border Patrol, Catholic Charities are already overwhelmed.&nbsp; So, has the Secretary raised these concerns with President Biden?&nbsp; And are these concerns that the White House shares?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to remember that Title 42 is not an immigration policy or an immigration authority.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a health authority.&nbsp; So, yes, it was coordinated with the Secretary of Homeland Security and through an interagency process, and there&#8217;s been planning in the works for months for this possibility that the CDC &#8212; to take this action.</p>



<p>Secretary Mayorkas is going to be testifying later this week, multiple times.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure he will answer that question and multiple other questions, and I will let him speak for himself.</p>



<p>But I would just note that we&#8217;re continuing to prepare for March &#8212; May 23rd and the im- &#8212; May 23rd and the implementation, and there is a multipart strategy that Secretary Mayorkas has been leading and overseeing for the past several months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But has he raised these concerns with the President?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into private conversations.&nbsp; But I think, again, it&#8217;s important to note this is a CDC decision and authority about when we were &#8212; had the health conditions to lift Title 42.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t an indication of an immigration policy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you not believe that there will not be a surge as a result of Title 42 being lifted come May 23rd?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the Department of Homeland Security has projected that there could be an increase in people coming to the border, and that&#8217;s why they&#8217;ve had a six-part, multipart plan and proposal and policy they&#8217;ve been implementing for months now to prepare for that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Title 42 &#8212; the potential end to it &#8212; the reason that the Congressional Hispanic Caucus is meeting with the President today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Actually, if you may remember, the President has been meeting with a number of the caucuses from Congress &#8212; from the Congressional Black Caucus; he met with CAPAC.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been meeting with all of the caucuses, as he did last year.&nbsp; So, this has been a meeting that&#8217;s been in the works for some time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Immigration, certainly we expect to be a part of it, but we expect it to be an expansive meeting.&nbsp; And I would note the CHC has a stated view and policy on Title 42.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of the members of the CHC is Senator Catherine Cortez Masto.&nbsp; And she said of the Title 42 decision that “This is the wrong way to do this and it will leave the administration unprepared for a surge at the border.”&nbsp; Obviously, this is a subject that&#8217;s likely to come up in this meeting today.&nbsp; What is the President&#8217;s message, primarily especially to these western and border-state Democrats who are concerned about both the impact on immigration as a policy matter but also the political fallout as well?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think his &#8212; our view and the President&#8217;s view is that we have a broken immigration system that&#8217;s been long overdue to be fixed.&nbsp; He agrees with that, and he&#8217;s certainly happy to discuss that during this meeting or any other meeting has with members of Congress.</p>



<p>But this is not an immigration policy.&nbsp; This &#8212; Title 42 is a health authority that&#8217;s determined by the CDC.&nbsp; And we &#8212; we need to have a conversation about immigration reform, and that&#8217;s vital.&nbsp; And maybe this is a reminder of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whenever the administration has been asked about immigration reform, the answer seems to be the President introduced the bill in the first week in office, but there&#8217;s not much more than that more.&nbsp; Is this an opportunity for the administration to try to move something forward this year?&nbsp; Or do you believe that campaign politics will just preclude the likelihood of getting it through?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we welcome that opportunity.&nbsp; But I&#8217;d also remind you that we were supportive of efforts to include some components of immigration reform in the reconciliation packages, and we&#8217;ve been looking for avenues to move it forward and have been supportive of efforts by Democratic senators to do exactly that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a specific ask of Congress related to Title 42?&nbsp; That was the position that was articulated last week &#8212; that this is not a decision for the President to make but for Congress to make.&nbsp; What is the decision that Congress should be making?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is a discussion we&#8217;ll have with members of Congress.&nbsp; We are continuing to prepare to implement the lifting of Title 42, a decision that was made by the CDC.</p>



<p>I would note that there are a range of views on Title 42.&nbsp; There are some, you noted, who are very vocal about how they would like to see it extended.&nbsp; There are some who are very vocal about how they would not like to see that happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s an important discussion that will be happening over the coming days and weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jacqui.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe the White House so far has commented on the death of Bishop Evans, the 22-year-old National Guard Specialist who drowned trying to save two migrants.&nbsp; I wanted to give you the opportunity to say some words on that.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thank you for that, Jacqui.&nbsp; And the news of the confirmation that his body had been found was confirmed just a couple of hours ago.&nbsp; I would note that, of course, our heart goes out to his family and to his loved ones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To confirm all the specific details, he went missing on Friday, following his selfless efforts to rescue two migrants who appeared to be drowning who were trying to cross a river in Mexico that went to the United States &#8212; went into the U.S., of course.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know that National Guard personnel, including &#8212; including him, risk their lives every day to serve and protect others.&nbsp; And again, our hearts go out to his family.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; in case you may ask, I don&#8217;t have any updates at this moment in terms of the President&#8217;s outreach, but if &#8212; if that is something I can update you on this afternoon, I will let you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House feel any responsibility for his death, given that there&#8217;s reporting that he lost his life allegedly trying to save two migrants who were smuggling drugs?&nbsp; This is a problem that, you know, the administration has been facing for some time and is obviously, as we&#8217;ve been discussing, getting some criticism on.&nbsp; Is &#8212; does the White House feel at all responsible?&nbsp; And what &#8212; what more can you offer to people who, you know, are on the border, in border communities, who are experiencing loss and trials like this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, of course, we are mourning the loss of his life and we are grateful for the work of every National Guardsman.&nbsp; I would note that the National Guard worked for the states, and so he is an employee of the Tex- &#8212; Texas National Guard, and his efforts and his operation were directed by there, not by the federal government, in this &#8212; in this effort, in this apparatus.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve long stated that our immigration system is broken.&nbsp; There needs to be more done to invest in smarter security, to have a more effective asylum processing system.&nbsp; And we would welcome any efforts to &#8212; for any elected officials to work with us on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A lot of the border communities often, you know, say that they have requested more from &#8212; from the federal government &#8212; more manpower to help manage these kinds of &#8212; these kinds of issues.&nbsp; Is that being looked at?&nbsp; Is that being &#8212; is that being &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Can you give me a more specific request or a specific person or &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you mentioned that, you know, this &#8212; this Specialist was a National Guard.&nbsp; Obviously, you know, the state is in charge of that.&nbsp; States are in charge of that.&nbsp; But there have been requests from the Texas governor, from &#8212; you know, to send more &#8212; you know, to help people who are in this position at the border, who are now trying to deal with an influx of migrants that they know is going to only increase, as you just mentioned, after Title 42 is lifted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You talked about having a humanitarian, you know, sort of, system in place to deal with people coming across and increase vaccinations and that kind of thing.&nbsp; But in terms of, you know, law enforcement presence at the border.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just say &#8212; if we just dial it back a few years to, kind of, what we inherited here &#8212; the former President invested billions of dollars in a border wall that was never going to work or be effective, instead of working towards comprehensive immigration reform.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As part of the President&#8217;s proposal he put forward on his first day in office, he proposed investing in smarter security at the border &#8212; something he&#8217;d be happy to work with governors on.&nbsp; And &#8212; and certainly we&#8217;re open to having that conversation whenever they&#8217;re ready to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Weijia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just more broadly on the Ukrainian aid.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since the Russian invasion started, the U.S. has provided more than $5 billion total when you factor in military, economic, humanitarian aid.&nbsp; Is there a figure that is a cap for what the U.S. is willing and able to provide Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the range of military assistance that we&#8217;ve provided to date was meant to be frontloaded because of our expectation or anticipation, led by our Department of Defense and military leaders, about the nature of the fight and how it has evolved, right?&nbsp; That because they&#8217;re on a terrain now that &#8212; where they&#8217;re in need of long-range military capacity, we&#8217;ve tried to expedite the assistance over the past couple of weeks that they&#8217;re receiving.</p>



<p>So it might not be, over the next couple of weeks, the same size of assistance week by week.&nbsp; But in terms of what the next package will look like and what will be passed, I mean, those are discussions and recommendations that the President will get from his military leaders.&nbsp; We’ll have those discussions with Congress.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not in a position to put a cap on it at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, got it.&nbsp; And then just switching over to COVID.&nbsp; The administration is planning to take new actions to expand Paxlovid.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything you can share about how you plan to do that and who might be eligible, since right now it&#8217;s only for people who are at higher risk?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, part of it is even people who are eligible are not taking advantage of the fact that they&#8217;re eligible.&nbsp; So, part of our effort is to share more information publicly about who can get access, who can call their doctor and get access to it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will tell you, Dr. Jha is going to make his debut in the briefing room tomorrow.&nbsp; So, he will lay out for you and others more specifically all the steps we&#8217;re taking to increase knowledge of Paxlovid, who can benefit from it.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re intending to &#8212; and I&#8217;ll let him speak to this &#8212; say there&#8217;s going to be an expansion of who&#8217;s eligible, as much as we’re &#8212; and I will, obviously, leave that to the health experts to determine &#8212; but more we need to focus on making sure that everybody who is eligible knows they&#8217;re eligible and they can get access to it, because it is very effective in treating COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Just a couple on Twitter.&nbsp; I wanted to go back and try again.&nbsp; Are you concerned about the kind of purveyors of election misinformation, disinformation, health falsehoods, sort of, having more of an opportunity to speak there on Twitter?</p>



<p>Is there, you know, any message that you would convey to Elon Musk as the new owner?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, you know, I would maybe just add to it that, you know, public &#8212; publicly traded companies have different levels of &#8212; there&#8217;s different levels of scrutiny that are possible of publicly traded companies.&nbsp; So, are you concerned about, you know, a billionaire taking control of a company that &#8212; where there&#8217;s already a lot of concentration of power?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that our concerns are not new.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve long talked about and the President has long talked about his concerns about the power of social media platforms, including Twitter and others, to spread misinformation, disinformation; the need for these platforms to be held accountable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While I know you tried again &#8212; I appreciate that &#8212; I still don&#8217;t have a specific comment on this specific transaction.&nbsp; And at this point, we don&#8217;t have any sense of what the policies will look like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, last week, Daleep Singh made some very strong comments and also Treasury Secretary Yellen made some comments about the positive impact on inflation of lowering tariffs on certain Chinese goods &#8212; bicycles, underwear, apparel.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s quite a list.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, it was quite a list.&nbsp; Is there something cooking?&nbsp; Can you tell us something?&nbsp; And do you notice the White House embracing that?&nbsp; Is that something we could see happen soon?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, from the beginning of the administration, we talked about how some of the tariffs implemented by the previous administration were not strategic and instead raised costs on Americans.&nbsp; And our effort &#8212; which has been ongoing, of course &#8212; has been to ensure current Section 301 tariffs align appropriately with our economic and trade priorities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you mentioned, you know, different goods that are sold.&nbsp; But, of course, on wages and job opportunities; critical supply chains, where we see critic- &#8212; impacts on critical supply chains; our ability to sustain our technological edge &#8212; this is an ongoing process.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re certainly looking at where we see costs being raised at a time where we&#8217;re seeing heightened inflation; certainly, that&#8217;s on our minds.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also about addressing the core issues we have with how China has approached, you know, their engagement around economic issues as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s both.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, can we look for some tariff reductions in some relatively short period of time?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to review it.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything at this moment to preview for you, but our focus is on those same categories and areas: where we can impact &#8212; where we think they&#8217;re impacting wages and job opportunities, our technological edge.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the prism through which our economic team &#8212; Ambassador Tai is, of course, leading this effort, is &#8212; is reviewing these sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just a real quick one on Putin.&nbsp; So, the sanctions that have been imposed &#8212; and I realize they&#8217;re quite sweeping and large, but on &#8212; especially on oligarchs and other people close to Putin &#8212; have thus far excluded his girlfriend, whose name I can&#8217;t quite pronounce &#8212; <em>Kayova</em>?&nbsp; <em>Kayeva</em>?&nbsp; Do you have any comment on why you would refrain from sanctioning someone arguably close to Putin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would remind you we&#8217;re continuing to review sanctions.&nbsp; No one is safe from our sanctions.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already, of course, sanctioned President Putin, but also his daughter, his closest cronies, and we&#8217;ll continue to review more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have an analysis at this point because we&#8217;re still reviewing.&nbsp; There&#8217;s more we will likely do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on just the broader strategy of helping Ukraine, there&#8217;s obviously hurting Russia economically, hurting Russia militarily.&nbsp; Given that the U.S. has rolled out so many sanc- &#8212; economic sanctions already against Russia, and the heavy fighting that we’re seeing now, should we expect that the help that the U.S. offers Ukraine, going forward, would be more heavily, like, militarily focused as opposed to economic?&nbsp; Or is that the wrong way of looking at it, as it’s sort of all of the above?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, I understand your question.&nbsp; I think these are all discussions that we&#8217;re having through the interagency, and there&#8217;ll be a recommendation made to the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, there&#8217;s no question they need additional military assistance.&nbsp; As part of Secretary Austin&#8217;s follow-up to his trip to Ukraine, he was in Germany today meeting to discuss kind of the next steps and what their needs are as the &#8212; as the &#8212; as the battle and the war continues to evolve.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But they are also going to have significant humanitarian and economic needs as well.&nbsp; So I would expect that all of them will continue to be touched on.&nbsp; But these are the discussions that are happening in the interagency process now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any new, updated U.S. assessment on any discontent or disagreement within Putin’s top advisors or inner circle about the direction of the war?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any assessment I can read out from here &#8212; or any new assessment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more on a different topic &#8212; just on inflation, given that it continues to be such a big concern for so many people.&nbsp; The President obviously doesn&#8217;t have the luxury of wandering outside the White House.&nbsp; He can&#8217;t, you know, go fill up this car or go to the grocery store.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of how he sort of is updated every day, or how he gets a sense of how much does milk cost more today than a week ago?&nbsp; Just how does he sort of keep up to date on how much more expensive things are for the average American?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can assure you that the President sees himself as the kid from Scranton, more than many people who work in his administration, and he is often the person who reminds people and members of his policy team in meetings what the impacts of rising food costs or gasoline costs or other issues are.&nbsp; He does request and receive regular updates from his economic team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And often, when he returns from weekends at home in Delaware, he comes back with conversations he had with people as he came out of church or, you know, as he &#8212; people he&#8217;s known for a long time in his community, and they often tell him about how these &#8212; how the rising costs impact his life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I would say that he stays abreast of these changes and of these increases in costs and the impacts through economic data and briefings, but also through his own conversations whenever he can have them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen?&nbsp; Jen?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have &#8212; I have a question here about &#8212; following the recent Palestinian terror attacks from the Temple Mount and previous week of attacks that have killed many Israelis and wounded more, is the Biden administration reconsidering its support of the Palestinian Authority’s two-state solution dividing Israel or stopping the welfare payments sent to the Palestinian Authority, who use the money for their pay-to-slay reward system?&nbsp; And I have a follow-up question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, I would just note that I spoke to this last week, on Wednesday, where I noted that the United States is deeply concerned by the recent violence in Jerusalem and the Temple Mount and across the We- &#8212; West Bank.&nbsp; And we also strongly condemn the recent rocket attack on Israel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You may or may not have seen also that the President conducted a call with Prime Minister Bennett on Sunday morning.&nbsp; He accepted an invitation by Prime Minister Bennett &#8212; Bennett to visit Israel in the coming months.&nbsp; No specific date yet.&nbsp; He took note of the ongoing efforts between Israeli and Palestinian officials to lower tensions and ensure a peaceful conclusion to the holy season of Ramadan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he also affirmed our unwavering support for Israel and its defense needs and welcomed the historic $1 billion allocation to replenish Israel&#8217;s Iron Dome system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; The follow-up is: In view of continued Palestinian violence against innocent civilians, is the Biden administration willing to stop payments to the anti-semitic U.N. agency, UNRWA, and support restoring the Jewish cemetery in Vilnius, Lithuania, to its former glory?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I think &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any changes to announce to our policy.&nbsp; I spoke to our condemnation of the violence just now as last &#8212; and last week as well, and noted also our call to the Prime Minister.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a point of clarification on the aid that the U.S. has already allocated to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said last week that he had “almost exhausted” his drawdown ability.&nbsp; So how much, after that announcement of the $800 million on Thursday, does the U.S. have left to provide Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure I can get you this specific, exact number.&nbsp; It was almost about $3.5 billion total of drawdown authority, I believe.&nbsp; I will double-check that number for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what he was referring to is: Because of how quickly we&#8217;ve been moving the military assistance to the Ukrainians on the ground, we anticipated being almost at a near end of that drawdown authority.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s why he&#8217;s going to put forward a new package this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on student debt cancellation: Yesterday, Senator Elizabeth Warren said that the White House has essentially already canceled some student debt by waiving interest on that student debt, and it could use that same exact authority to cancel student debt permanently.&nbsp; Does the White House agree with that view?&nbsp; This is about the authority, not whether you will but that you can derive the authority in the same exact way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of any authority and how &#8212; or how it would work.&nbsp; What I would tell you is that not a single person in this country has paid a dime on student &#8212; federal student loans since the President took office.&nbsp; And what we have said is that he would make a decision about any cancellation of student debt before the conclusion of that pause on student loans, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick follow-up on that.&nbsp; She said that it was “an issue of racial equity.”&nbsp; Does the White House view this as a racial equity issue?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think the President views student loan relief, debt relief as something that impacts &#8212; yes, it is a racial equity issue, but it is also an issue that impacts many individuals &#8212; young people, middle-aged people &#8212; of all races.&nbsp; It is something that he has &#8212; he has played &#8212; it has been a vital priority to the President, which again is why not a single person has played &#8212; paid a penny, a dime &#8212; a dime or a penny in student loans since he took office.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go &#8212; go &#8212; go ahead, JJ.&nbsp; I don’t want to forget you.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thanks.&nbsp; Two questions on the supplemental funding &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and then one Cedric Richmond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the supplemental, has the administration decided to definitely combine the COVID funding with the aid for Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have the mechanism yet.&nbsp; There&#8217;s &#8212; these are conversations that we&#8217;ll have with Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, prior to the recess, there was the proposal that did combine, but &#8212; but not &#8212; don&#8217;t have a &#8212; don&#8217;t have a sense yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not quite yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, is the White House considering extending the Title 42 immigration restrictions as part of a deal with Congress?&nbsp; Are you considering it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, this would be Congress having the discussion.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to prepare for a May 23rd implementation.&nbsp; There&#8217;ll be a range of conversations about this over the coming days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, the New York Times is reporting that Cedric Richmond is leaving.&nbsp; Is he?&nbsp; And just last week, he said publicly that he wouldn&#8217;t leave unless the President asked him to.&nbsp; So, has something changed there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, let me first say that Cedric Richmond has been, continues to be a vital, essential advisor to the President &#8212; was on the campaign, continues to be in the White House.&nbsp; I have been in many meetings with Cedric Richmond, where the President goes to him and looks to him for his political sense, his assessment of Congress.&nbsp; He trusts him implicitly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have nothing to announce at this point, but I can assure you when we have something to announce, it will involve a new important role to &#8212; for Cedric Richmond and something the President is excited about and has asked him to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, we saw the readout &#8212; we saw the readout from the call with the French President.&nbsp; Did the President see any larger meaning in the French elections in terms of the support of the Allied effort against Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any assessment of that.&nbsp; Can I &#8212; I&#8217;ll leave that to others to do analysis.&nbsp; The President was pleased with the &#8212; with the outcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, he spoke with President Macron this morning, and he&#8217;s looking forward to continuing to work with him in standing up against Russian aggression and standing with the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Ron &#8212; just along those lines, Ron Klain tweeted, “An interesting observation…[that] President Macron…secured a double-digit victory…at a time when his approval rating is 36%.”&nbsp; Was there anything he was suggesting with that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more analysis to provide on that front, though I appreciate the question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On NATO, reports in Finland and Sweden say that the country &#8212; the two countries are preparing to apply to join NATO as early as next month.&nbsp; Is the White House supportive of that effort?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, those are decisions for these countries to make and for the NATO Alliance to make.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;ll leave it to those entities.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just on gun violence.&nbsp; We learned more about Friday’s shooter today from D.C. police, who say he had hundreds of rounds of unspent ammo inside his Connecticut Avenue apartment.&nbsp; And then, today, the D.C. mayor announced a new police initiative to target violent crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Does the President believe he&#8217;s done all he can do to fight violent crime, gun issues around this country without the intervention of Congress?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he will continue to look for every authority he has to take steps to address gun violence &#8212; violent crimes across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last time we had data was in 2020, I believe.&nbsp; And at that time, about 77 percent of homicides were done with a firearm.&nbsp; And you saw him talk two weeks ago now &#8212; it&#8217;s all running together &#8212; but two weeks ago now, I believe, about ghost guns and the steps that he is going to continue to take to address ghost guns, which we have seen have a rising role in &#8212; in gun &#8212; in gun deaths and gun targeting over the past several months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would also note that then, when he was doing that event, he highlighted that two LA sheriff&#8217;s deputies who have been wounded by a shooter using a ghost gun.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s just even an example of how even they&#8217;re using &#8212; these ghost guns are being used to target police as well, which is also a problem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I would say, of course, there are significant steps that Congress can take that would make these laws permanent &#8212; that is the President&#8217;s first preference &#8212; whether it&#8217;s background checks, banning assault weapons.  These are laws that he has led the effort to pass throughout his career, many decades. <br><br>But he will continue to look for any steps he can take using his own authorities, as he has done several times since taking office.  I think he&#8217;s done more than any other president using executive authority. <br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Two questions for you.  President Biden made his first endorsement of the midterm election cycle on Saturday, endorsing Congressman Kurt Schrader.  Why did he decide to weigh in on this race first?  And what would he say to some progressives who are frustrated that he endorsed Schrader over his opponent?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand your question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t make the rules, but the rules are I can&#8217;t speak a lot about politics from here.&nbsp; So I would point you to the DNC, and I would point you to Congressman Schrader&#8217;s office.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second question for you: There&#8217;s been a fair bit of speculation about Vladimir Putin&#8217;s health based on recent videos of him.&nbsp; Has the White House made an assessment on this matter?&nbsp;&nbsp; And have concerns been raised internally at all about this topic?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any assessment for &#8212; to offer from here or any particular comment on the mental health of President Putin.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, back to Title 42 quickly.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to make sure I’m understanding what you&#8217;re saying today.&nbsp; I hear you talking about discussions going forward, the debate that&#8217;s happening, all of that.&nbsp; Are you saying that Title 42 &#8212; I know you&#8217;re prepared to lift the current policy on May 23rd.&nbsp; Are you saying that will happen unless Congress acts?&nbsp; Or are you saying the White House might do something else?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Congress would have to take action in order for the date not to be May 23rd.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On Hunter Biden: The New York Post is reporting &#8212; looking at White House visitor logs, there were 19 visits to the White House while the President was Vice President by Hunter Biden&#8217;s business partner, including one with the Vice President.&nbsp; Could you help us understand why that business partner had access and what those meetings were about?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any information on that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check and see if we have any more comment.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, former Senator David Perdue, last night, hoping to be a senator again, opened his debate by saying that the election &#8212; 2020 election was rigged and stolen.&nbsp; We know that every court &#8212; most courts &#8212; courts have ruled that it was fair, there&#8217;s no evidence of fraud.&nbsp; But I wonder what you make of those comments.&nbsp; And has the White House done enough to push back and to make it clear that the election was not stolen?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think that speaks to the former President&#8217;s hold over factions of the Republican Party, not facts.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions on Brazil.&nbsp; First, last Friday, President Biden said the United States and rich countries should be paying Brazil to protect the Amazon.&nbsp; And he said he&#8217;s trying to get this done.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what exactly is he trying to do?&nbsp; Is he trying to work with other rich countries, negotiating with Brazil?&nbsp; Is he ready to provide financial support to Brazil?&nbsp; And how much would that be?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  So the science &#8212; in the President&#8217;s view, and the reason he made these comments, is that the science has only become more clear that the world needs to both strengthen and accelerate emissions reductions.  And part of that goal is conser- &#8212; includes conserving global forest ecosystems that remove carbon from the atmosphere and store more carbon than they emit in a year, serving as carbon sinks. <br><br>So President Biden recognized the necessity of mobilizing funding from the whole go- &#8212; from world governments and the private sector.  And the Plan to Conserve Global Forest: the Critical Carbon Sinks launched at COP26 aims to mobilize finance from the public and private sector, with a strong focus on <s>levering</s> [leveraging] private-sector finance through market mechanisms.  So that&#8217;s what he was speaking to and certainly an effort he continues to support.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there is a delegation today from the State Department in Brazil.&nbsp; I wonder if this trip has anything to do with the war in Ukraine and perhaps the United States seeking or interested in working with Brazil food and energy security?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point you to the State Department.&nbsp; We are working with a range of countries, obviously, on addressing where we see any food shortages around the world.&nbsp; And, obviously, Ukraine is front and center on the minds of most global leaders.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a quick one: Why President Biden has declined to talk with President Bolsonaro?&nbsp; We know that the Brazilian government its trying &#8212; been trying &#8212; try more than once.&nbsp; So why is he declining to &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update.&nbsp; The President obviously has a busy schedule.&nbsp; He has spoken with a range of global leaders but not every single one, and you just noted the State Department is in Brazil for a visit.&nbsp; So I would note we have an ongoing dialogue at a high level.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Jen &#8212; oh.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Either one.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; You’re kind of matching today, I’ll note.&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, there you go.&nbsp; In your suits &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We got the memo.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; in blue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, so, more people are starting to talk about recession.&nbsp; Goldman Sachs and Bank of America alluded to it.&nbsp; You &#8212; because of inflation.&nbsp; The steps that have been taken so far haven&#8217;t seemed to work to get inflation to come back down.&nbsp; What additional steps are you guys looking at to curb inflation as well as the feeling that the economy is headed in the wrong direction?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, there are a number of strong economic indicators that we would point to.&nbsp; We created more jobs last year than any year in American history.&nbsp; The unemployment rate is at 3.6 percent.<br><br>We know that costs are too high.&nbsp; Inflation, which the Federal Reserve has purview over, still projects that it will moderate by the end of the year.&nbsp; There are a number of steps they have and they have indicated they have in &#8212; the plans to recalibrate.&nbsp; We support that effort.&nbsp; They have a lot of power here, in terms of taking steps to address inflation.&nbsp;<br><br>We are not &#8212; the President is not waiting for that to happen, and he is taking steps to address where we see costs increasing in different areas that impact the American people&#8217;s pocketbooks.&nbsp; Whether it&#8217;s gas prices &#8212; obviously, he made an announcement to tap the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; led the global release &#8212; led an effort to release from the &#8212; globally to bring down gas prices.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also taken steps to fix issues with our supply chain to make sure goods are moving as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a lot of interest &#8212; continues to be in Congress &#8212; to take steps to lower costs on prescription drugs, healthcare, eldercare, childcare.&nbsp; Those are all steps that are based on the President&#8217;s proposals.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) the President has pushed those spending proposals.&nbsp; The San Francisco Federal Reserve released a report &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They’d be fully paid for, so they&#8217;re not actually spending proposals; they’re proposals to lower costs that are fully paid for.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The San Francisco Federal Reserve released a report saying that government spending accounted for 3 percent of the inflation that we&#8217;re seeing now.&nbsp; So is spending more really the way to go?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think if you look back at where we were a year and a half ago, we were at the point where there was a significant economic downturn; where people were really suffering, struggling to put food on the table; strug- &#8212; people were out of work.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;ve done &#8212; what we did at that time is take steps to help stem that economic downturn.&nbsp; And that was a decision made that the President continues to believe was in the interest of the American people.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last quick one on China &#8212; the &#8212; looking at more lockdowns.&nbsp; Now Beijing may be involved in that.&nbsp; Is there anything that the administration is looking at doing to help the supply chains if this clogs up again?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re following this very closely.&nbsp; And as you know, there are a couple of different issues at play here.&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously Shenzhen, which has kind of reopened, and they had moved around where their goods were being produced and moved around which ports they were going through.&nbsp; Shanghai, obviously.&nbsp; And there were a couple of industries that were being impacted.&nbsp;<br><br>We haven&#8217;t seen, at this point, a decrease in ships coming to our ports in California from Asia.&nbsp; We obviously are continuing to monitor that.&nbsp; And Beijing is &#8212; has increased their testing, which could be a precursor to a lockdown, but we don&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t know at this point.&nbsp;<br><br>So what we&#8217;re doing right now is we&#8217;re closely monitoring &#8212; the State Department is, our economic team is.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we haven&#8217;t seen a slowdown in ships coming to our ports in California.<br><br>If there is an increase as lockdowns decrease in some parts of China, we&#8217;ll also be prepared for that, because we&#8217;ve been able to take steps to reduce the number of cargo ships there.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one question, Jen.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been &#8212; there&#8217;s been a lot of explosions and strange fires at quite significant places in Russia over the last couple of weeks, just most recently in the city of Bryansk.&nbsp; Its oil containers blew up.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of speculation over what&#8217;s causing it.&nbsp; And, obviously, one of the theories would be that Ukraine somehow doing it.&nbsp;<br><br>What is the U.S. position on Ukraine attacking inside Russian territory?&nbsp; Is this something that U.S. is encour- &#8212; would encourage them to do and try and help them do it &#8212; you know, in terms of weapons?&nbsp; Or is it something maybe where you’d advise the Ukrainians not to go there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; we don&#8217;t have any confirmation of that.&nbsp; Ukraine is defending their own country, so I&#8217;m just not going to speak to a hypothetical.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, no, I’m not asking for confirmation on things that have happened.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just there&#8217;s obviously a lot of speculation.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s kind of an obvious point, right?&nbsp; Like, they&#8217;re fighting the Russians tooth and nail inside their own country, quite often near the borders, and the Russians are inside their country.&nbsp; So, is there a U.S. position on &#8212; on whether the Ukrainians should have the right or maybe even be encouraged to take their fight beyond their border?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, that is a hypothetical, so I&#8217;m not going to speak to it.&nbsp; Ukraine&#8217;s country is being invaded.&nbsp; Russia is invading their country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re supporting them for.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s been no confirmation of what you&#8217;re detailing.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m just not going to speak to it.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I may, just &#8212; we know that Congressional Hispanic Caucus members are here meeting with the President.&nbsp; I wonder if immigration and also Title 42 is being discussed.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know how much you can reveal about that meeting that is taking place this afternoon.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have a readout of the meeting at this point in time.&nbsp; I would note that this is part of the series of meetings, as I noted earlier, that the President is doing with a range of the caucuses in Congress.&nbsp; He did the Congressional Black Caucus, he did CAPAC, and he did these last year as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So we certainly expect immigration to be a topic of discussion, but I would note that the CHC also has a stated position on Title 42 as a caucus, which is that they oppose any change to the decisions that been &#8212; that has been made.&nbsp; So anything could be discussed, but I wouldn&#8217;t anticipate that being a topic &#8212; a major topic.<br><br><a></a><a></a><a></a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I may on Transdniestria &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sorry, Matt.&nbsp; I’ll come to you next.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I may, on Transdniestria &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; there appears to have been some kind of attack on the ministry of state security.&nbsp; We know that Moscow has been talking about this area possibly entering the conflict.&nbsp; It seemed &#8212; it happened on a holiday when there wouldn&#8217;t have been people in the building.&nbsp; Does this bear the hallmarks of a false-flag operation of the sort that you&#8217;ve been warning us about?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;ve seen the reports.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; obviously we have, of course &#8212; but I have &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any confirmation of the specifics or the details at this point in time from here.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Matt.&nbsp; Matt, did you have a question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah. I just have two.&nbsp; The first is: With the CHC coming &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; some have wanted Biden &#8212; the administration to do more on executive actions related to immigration.&nbsp; And, I guess, just philosophically, does the President believe that he&#8217;s exhausted most of the things that he can do through executive power?&nbsp; You had alluded earlier about the legislative push &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but are there things that he feels like he could still do it through executive actions related to immigration?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, I think his view is that taking steps and working with Congress to pass comprehensive immigration reform that has smarter security, that does put in place an asylum processing system that works is the best step that will have a lasting impact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, we&#8217;re continuing to assess any executive actions we can take, but he’ll, I think, continue to discuss legislative actions as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, you had mentioned this at the top &#8212; about the toxic exposures and that the President wants comprehensive &#8212; for the comprehensive legislation to be passed.&nbsp; The House has passed a version related to this; the Senate has passed a version.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Senate version is sometimes criticized by advocates as not going far enough.&nbsp; So, does the President have a stance on which piece of legislation he views as addressing this issue comprehensively?&nbsp; Is he getting involved in that? There&#8217;s other legislation that&#8217;s &#8212; that hasn&#8217;t been passed in the Senate that also grapples with this issue.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I mean, obviously, as you know, now the next step is for both bodies of Congress to work together and figure out the path forward.&nbsp; We did issue a SAP on the PACT Act.&nbsp; So beyond that, I don&#8217;t think I have anything more to update you on, on the position.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I had a question on Title 42.&nbsp; At the risk of this being a dumb question: So if the CDC is able to extend Title 42, why is it up to Congress? &nbsp;Can you just help people understand why it&#8217;s on Congress to extend it and how (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Congress gave the CDC authority to determine when the conditions would be met to lift Title 42, which again, has never been an immigration authority or an immigration policy; it&#8217;s always been a health authority.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So when they determined we no longer had the conditions where we had to take action to quickly deport people who came to the country, they made that health decision based on data and science and the CDC decision-making.&nbsp; Congress would need to make any decision about a change to the authority they gave the CDC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the CDC doesn&#8217;t have the authority to just say, “Things have changed &#8211;”?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; If the health and data conditions change, they could certainly make a different decision, I supp- &#8212; sure.&nbsp; But they make decisions based on health and data, not based on politics or where members of Congress sit.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another coronavirus &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, actually, a follow-up on that question and something that was asked earlier.&nbsp; Does the &#8212; is the President willing to sign something if it comes to his desk as part of a legislative package that would change the rules for how Title 42 is administered?&nbsp; Because if it is, in fact &#8212; it is up to Congress ultimately, that would get to the President&#8217;s desk and he would ultimately have to either sign it or veto it.&nbsp; Is &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of steps between now and then.&nbsp; So, at this point, that&#8217;s very premature.&nbsp; There are many members who strongly would like to see Title 42 extended.&nbsp; There are many who strongly have the other point of view.&nbsp; So, we are not anywhere near that point in time.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the Surgeon General has said that misinformation about COVID amounts to a public health crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: Regardless of ownership, would the White House be interested in working with Twitter like it has in the past to continue to combat this kind of misinformation?&nbsp; Or are we in a different part of the pandemic where that kind of partnership is no longer necessary?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we engage regularly with all social media platforms about steps that can be taken that has continued, and I&#8217;m sure it will continue.&nbsp; But there are also reforms that we think Congress could take and we would support taking, including reforming Section 230, enacting antitrust reforms, requiring more transparency.&nbsp; And the President is encouraged by the bipartisan support for &#8212; or engagement in those efforts.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the U.S. and its allies in the Pacific: They&#8217;re clearly being blindsided by China&#8217;s security pact with the Solomon Islands, a very strategic location in the Pacific.&nbsp; Kurt Campbell was down there only last week, and he announced some initiatives on, you know, speeding up the embassy there &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and they&#8217;re sending a hospital boat, that sort of thing.&nbsp; The question is: Why wouldn&#8217;t you &#8212; why wouldn’t the U.S. commit to far more significant security/military initiatives in such a strategic place like that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, I wonder what would the Biden administration want from other countries.&nbsp; Australia hasn&#8217;t exactly been very well prepared for this Chinese-Solomon agreement either.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s a great group of questions. &nbsp;I have not talked to Kurt Campbell about this since he returned.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure if the President has.&nbsp; I can &#8212; I can see if there&#8217;s anything more we can update you on, on our policies.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has issued a statement on malaria.&nbsp; Do you &#8212; the President just issued a statement on malaria today.&nbsp; Since the time you started speaking, almost a hundred children have died of malaria.&nbsp; It said two &#8212; children &#8212; a child dies every two minutes of malaria.&nbsp; Is the President prepared to increase funding, maybe fight malaria the same way the U.S. has been fighting COVID?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s obviously something the President cares deeply about, as we do as an administration.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything for you in terms of predictions of additional funding.&nbsp; I can see if there&#8217;s anything more from USAID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the coronavirus &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the TPS, I know the administration has just granted TPS to Cameroonian living in the U.S.&nbsp; Why not extend it Ethiopia and Nigeria, other African countries that are also in crisis?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I know you&#8217;ve asked me a similar question before.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an effort or a process led by the Department of Homeland Security to make a determination about conditions on the ground and an interagency process.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict at this point.&nbsp; Obviously, they&#8217;re continuing to assess.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask about your announcement from last week on refugees from Ukraine.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re supposed to open the portal for applications today from DHS.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about how you&#8217;re preparing the resources to be able to accept what I&#8217;m sure is going to be a big influx of applications as soon as that portal opens?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So the Department of Homeland Security is going to do a briefing this afternoon for more &#8212; with more details to provide to you.&nbsp; And, obviously, they will oversee the process.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re right, we certainly anticipate lots of interest on both sides.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will there be someone in the White House &#8212; I know when you were working on Operation Afghans [sic] Welcome &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; there was someone in charge of it from this end.&nbsp; Is there going to be someone over here that&#8217;s working on it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Obviously, Russia and Ukraine, and implementing all of our programs, is a top priority for the national security team.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see if there is one individual who will be responsible.</p>



<p>Thanks so much.</p>



<p>4:08 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Welcoming the 2020 and 2021 Stanley Cup Champions Tampa Bay&#160;Lightning</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/25/remarks-by-president-biden-welcoming-the-2020-and-2021-stanley-cup-champions-tampa-bay-lightning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 20:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51756</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 2:16 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Clapping for you guys.&#160; (Removes sunglasses.)&#160; I’m going to put them back on.&#160; (Puts sunglasses back on.)&#160; (Laughs.)&#160;&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Welcome.&#160; Welcome to the White House.&#160; I see a couple of future All-Americans right there in the front row.&#160;&#160; You know, if there’s a little extra excitement&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>2:16 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Clapping for you guys.&nbsp; (Removes sunglasses.)&nbsp; I’m going to put them back on.&nbsp; (Puts sunglasses back on.)&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Welcome.&nbsp; Welcome to the White House.&nbsp; I see a couple of future All-Americans right there in the front row.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, if there’s a little extra excitement around the White House today, it’s probably because the Cup is in the building.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’re here today to congratulate and welcome to the White House the Stanley Cup Champion, Tampa Bay Lightning.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>To the players and coaches; and to the owner, Jeff; everyone involved in this team: It’s an honor to have you all here.&nbsp; And it’s great to see Congresswoman Castor.&nbsp; There she is.&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; She’s holding &#8212; you think I didn’t see you holding up that sign?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You know, and Mayor Jane Castor.&nbsp; And they’re not related.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I tell you.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyway, I want to thank Commissioner Gary Bettman and &#8212; for being here as well.</p>



<p>And at the risk of stating the obvious here, it’s a pretty good time to be a sports fan in Tampa.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know what the hell you have in the water down there &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but, over the last &#8212; please, have a seat.&nbsp; Don’t stand because of me.&nbsp; I am so sorry.&nbsp; See, the congresswoman knew to sit down immediately.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, the Buccaneers won the Super Bowl, the Rays won the pennant, and these guys behind me became back-to-back Stanley Cup Champions.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And they may be here next year.&nbsp; Who knows?</p>



<p>Well, I don’t know &#8212; I don&#8217;t know why they keep moving everything so quickly here, but with your &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; you all saw that, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; We can’t keep up either.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; They’re seeing if I’m on my toes (inaudible).&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But I really did worry about whether you got something in the water down there.&nbsp; It’s &#8212; with your victory last season, this team joined rare company.&nbsp; One of only eight teams over the last century to win two Stanley Cups in a row.&nbsp; In the last century.&nbsp; And I know that those two championships were very different.</p>



<p>In 2020, your fans watched you win from thousands of miles away as you competed in “The Bubble” in Edmonton due to the pandemic.</p>



<p>But this past season, you got to deliver something truly special: hosting the Cup in your &#8212; on your home ice in front of the Tampa faithful.</p>



<p>And don’t underestimate what that feeling meant to so many fans, especially kids, and lifelong memories you created for countless families.</p>



<p>Folks, the victory capped off an incredible run by one of the most well-rounded teams in recent memory, with outstanding players at every level, led by your captain, the Lightning stalwart of 14 seasons.&nbsp; Steve, 14 seasons?<br><br>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Yep.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You’re getting old, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I &#8212; I got to get some advice from Steve about this.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Of course &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; you accomplished this victory not as an individual, but as a team &#8212; pulling together when it mattered most.&nbsp; And now the names of every single one of you will be engraved on the Stanley Cup for all time.&nbsp; And that is a big deal where I come from.</p>



<p>And this team didn’t just step up on the ice, you stepped up in the community as well.</p>



<p>You know, through your Lightning Community Hero program, you’ve delivered more than $25 million in critical causes to the reg- &#8212; for critical causes in the region.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Provided food and clothing for the families in need.&nbsp; Supported early education for youth mentorship programs.&nbsp; Lifting up local non-profits.&nbsp; Donating to veterans’ hospitals, community colleges, and other vital institutions all across Western Florida, along with hundreds of other initiatives you engaged in.</p>



<p>And last year, your home arena also became a lifeline for families in Tampa.<br><br><a>The First Lady &#8212; and I am Jill’s husband &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; came down with Dr. Fauci during the Stanley Cup semifinals to encourage hockey fans to get vaccinated at your arena through a program called &#8212; called “Shots on Ice,” helping save lives, helping bring us back to our lives and loved ones, and helping the country and our &#8212; and our economy go from being on the mend to on the move.</a></p>



<p>Look, I’m not saying that the First Lady being there at your arena during the playoffs is why you won &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but just saying that she was there during the election season as well.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She seems to show up when people win.&nbsp; And just something to think about.</p>



<p>So thank you all for the great work you&#8217;re doing in the community.&nbsp; And congratulations again for all the great work you&#8217;ve done on the ice.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to wish you good luck in the upcoming playoffs.&nbsp; Who knows, as I said, you may be here next year if you&#8217;re willing to come back.&nbsp; But &#8212; but for now, let&#8217;s bring up Jeff to say a few words.</p>



<p>Jeff, the podium is yours.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>There you are.&nbsp; I got to find my blue dot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. VINIK:&nbsp; Yeah, you do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s right over here.&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MR. VINIK:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. &#8212; thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Now, we don&#8217;t get to hear &#8212; to be here very often, so you can stand up for me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I told you I’d use one joke.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So, Mr. President, on behalf of myself, the Tampa Bay Lightning players, coaches, staff, and all at Bolts Natsi- &#8212; Nation watching across &#8212; in Tampa, across North America, and around the world, we would like to thank you for hosting us today.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a tremendous honor to be here &#8212; tremendous &#8212; at the White House celebrating our back-to-back Stanley Cups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s been a long time coming for the lighthouse &#8212; the “lighthouse” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; the Lightning after three championships.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s how I felt.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. VINIK:&nbsp; And, by the way, our playoffs start in a week.&nbsp; The First Lady is welcome back.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve already told us she’s good luck.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know about you, yet, but we’re happy to have her come back.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So after the three championships, the first one of which was about 18 years ago, we&#8217;re extremely excited to finally make our first appearance here on Pennsylvania Avenue after missing out in previous years due to a bunch of different circumstances.</p>



<p>The Lightning&#8217;s 2020 Stanley Cup championship was one defined by the extraordinary time of sacrifice &#8212; on and off the ice &#8212; with many of these gentlemen behind me spending 65 days isolated in a bubble, away from their family and friends, in order to capture the ultimate prize.&nbsp; It was a true test of both physical and mental endurance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This last season, we&#8217;re proud to say we returned to home ice.&nbsp; And after starting the season with no fans, we capped it off with our second consecutive Stanley Cup championship in front of a roaring capacity crowd at AMALIE Arena.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>As we head back in the playoffs &#8212; exactly one week from now, we expect to start &#8212; we know exactly why the Stanley Cup is the hardest trophy to win in sports.&nbsp; Hopefully, we&#8217;ll get &#8212; hopefully, we&#8217;ll be back here again.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already been invited.&nbsp; So, hopefully, we&#8217;ll be back here next season.&nbsp; Maybe we can get &#8212; well, I did write down here we could get you down to Tampa.&nbsp; Oh, so the First Lady is invited for the games. You&#8217;re invited, though.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MR. VINIK:&nbsp; You&#8217;re invited, Mr. President, for one of &#8212; for one of our one-of-a-kind championship boat parades, and they are fun.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp; They&#8217;re fun to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can come for the games, too.&nbsp; You&#8217;re welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know what?&nbsp; We have a no talking rule in our suite. &nbsp;When the puck is in play, nobody is allowed to talk.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll make an exception for you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>In closing, thank you for your hospitality and the honor of coming here to be part of this storied tradition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s now my pleasure to introduce our defenseman &#8212; our defenseman and two-time Stanley Cup champion, a native of St. Paul, Minnesota, Alternate Captain Ryan McDonagh.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MCDONAGH:&nbsp; Thanks, Mr. Vinik.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, on behalf of all the players, coaches, and staff from the Tampa Bay Lightning, we&#8217;d like to extend a huge thank you for the invitation and hospitality here today.</p>



<p>This is a huge honor to come here to the White House.&nbsp; Like it&#8217;s been talked about, it&#8217;s been an incredible two years for everybody down there in Tampa Bay.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so proud to be standing up here beside all these guys and everything we&#8217;ve accomplished, and also to the guys that couldn&#8217;t make it here today, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s been a historic run.&nbsp; Like it&#8217;s been said, it&#8217;s only been done twice in this century: back-to-back Stanley Cup champions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Both came in very different fashions.&nbsp; The first one coming in a bubble in Canada for 65 days, isolated away from our family, playing in arenas with no fans, and having to deal with strict restrictions and daily COVID testing.&nbsp; But our group embraced it.&nbsp; We embraced the challenge and, boy, did it pay off.</p>



<p>For almost all of us, it was the first time we got to hoist the Stanley Cup &#8212; an unbelievable feeling that no one can take away from us.</p>



<p>The second championship run also had its challenges.&nbsp; We still had to abide by some restrictions while traveling from city to city playing and also started the year with no fans in the buildings.</p>



<p><a></a><a></a><a></a>But at the very end, we found ourselves at Amalie Arena with a chance to win the Stanley Cup not only in front of family friends, but in front of a packed arena filled with Bolts Nation fans &#8212; an unbelievable memory that&#8217;s something you can only dream about as a young kid learning and playing the sport of hockey.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like Mr. Vinik said, in a week from now, we’ll get to start another journey and, hopefully, chase down a third consecutive Stanley Cup.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although we know the difficulties ahead of us, we feel we have a great group intact that&#8217;s going to battle hard for one another and leave it all on the ice.&nbsp; The quest for a third cup is not out of reach.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll do whatever we can, Bolts Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like I said, Mr. President, it&#8217;s an honor to be here.&nbsp; As an American and someone who hails from St. Paul, Minnesota, I never thought I&#8217;d be standing here at the White House next to you.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s been a surreal experience and something I think all of us will remember for a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you for having us.&nbsp; And appreciate it again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thanks, pal.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MCDONAGH:&nbsp; I think Victor and Steven have some gifts for you now.&nbsp; We all like gifts, right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; I got to report every one.&nbsp; But &#8212; (laughter).</p>



<p>(The President is presented with a jersey and hockey stick.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>MR. HEDMAN:&nbsp; Now you’ve got this nice stick.</p>



<p>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Walk over to the Cup a little bit so you can &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Walk over to the Cup a little bit.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Yeah, so you can &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Yeah, let&#8217;s to do that.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. HEDMAN:&nbsp; Here you go.&nbsp; The stick.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Want to hold the stick?&nbsp; It’s heavy.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No wonder you guys win. (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, thank you very, very much.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:29 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-64/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 20:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: John Z. Lee, of Illinois, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Seventh Circuit, vice Diane P. Wood, retiring. Salvador Mendoza, Jr., of Washington, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Ninth Circuit, vice M. Margaret McKeown, retiring. Stephen Henley Locher, of Iowa, to be United States District&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>John Z. Lee, of Illinois, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Seventh Circuit, vice Diane P. Wood, retiring.</p>



<p>Salvador Mendoza, Jr., of Washington, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Ninth Circuit, vice M. Margaret McKeown, retiring.</p>



<p>Stephen Henley Locher, of Iowa, to be United States District Judge for the Southern District of Iowa, vice John Alfred Jarvey, retired.</p>



<p>Nancy L. Maldonado, of Illinois, to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Illinois, vice Matthew F. Kennelly, retired.</p>



<p>Gregory Brian Williams, of Delaware, to be United States District Judge for the District of Delaware, vice Leonard Philip Stark, elevated.</p>



<p>Rachelle L. Crowe, of Illinois, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of Illinois for the term of four years, vice Stephen R. Wigginton, resigned.</p>



<p>Joshua D. Hurwit, of Idaho, to be United States Attorney for the District of Idaho for the term of four years, vice Bart M. Davis, resigned.</p>



<p>Gerard M. Karam, of Pennsylvania, to be United States Attorney for the Middle District of Pennsylvania for the term of four years, vice David J. Freed, resigned.</p>



<p>Jacqueline C. Romero, of Pennsylvania, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania for the term of four years, vice William M. McSwain, resigned.</p>



<p>Phillip A. Talbert, of California, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of California for the term of four years, vice McGregor W. Scott, resigned.</p>



<p>Jaime Areizaga-Soto, of Virginia, to be Chairman of the Board of Veterans&#8217; Appeals for a term of six years, vice Cheryl L. Mason, resigning.</p>



<p>Carol Spahn, of Maryland, to be Director of the Peace Corps, vice Josephine Olsen.</p>



<p>Steven M. Dettelbach, of Ohio, to be Director, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, vice B. Todd Jones, resigned.</p>



<p>Cynthia Dyer, of Virginia, to be Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, with the rank of Ambassador at Large, vice John Cotton Richmond.</p>



<p>Rachna Sachdeva Korhonen, of New Jersey, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Mali.</p>



<p>Richard Lee Buangan, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Mongolia.</p>



<p>Michael Alan Ratney, of Massachusetts, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>Michael C. Gonzales, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Zambia.</p>



<p>Geoffrey R. Pyatt, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Energy Resources), vice Francis R. Fannon.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>Susan Harthill, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission for a term expiring April 27, 2027, vice James J. Sullivan, Jr., term expired, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>



<p>Amanda Howe, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, vice Craig Hooks, resigned, which was sent to the Senate on June 15, 2021.</p>



<p>James Arthur Jemison II, of Michigan, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, vice Robert Hunter Kurtz, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
