<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 14:52:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on  National Atomic Veterans Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/a-proclamation-on-national-atomic-veterans-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 14:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On National Atomic Veterans Day, we recognize the brave service of America&#8217;s Atomic Veterans.  We renew our commitment to supporting Atomic Veterans and to preserving their stories, so that Americans will always remember both their crucial role in our history and our aspiration for a world without nuclear weapons.  &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; The military personnel who participated&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On National Atomic Veterans Day, we recognize the brave service of America&#8217;s Atomic Veterans.  We renew our commitment to supporting Atomic Veterans and to preserving their stories, so that Americans will always remember both their crucial role in our history and our aspiration for a world without nuclear weapons. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The military personnel who participated in nuclear testing between 1945 and 1962, served in the Armed Forces in or around Hiroshima and Nagasaki through mid-1946, or were held as prisoners of war in or near Hiroshima or Nagasaki stand among our bravest heroes. &nbsp;Many&nbsp;of&nbsp;these veterans stepped forward to defend our democratic values and helped to end the deadliest conflict in history.&nbsp; Yet, despite their service in uniform, Atomic Veterans were prevented from discussing the nature of their service &#8212; including with their families.&nbsp; Although many Atomic Veterans developed serious health conditions due to radiation exposure, they were unable to seek medical care or disability compensation from the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for injuries and diseases associated with their exposure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Decades later, when the United States Congress repealed the Nuclear Radiation and Secrecy Agreements Act, veterans exposed to radiation through their service-related activities were finally able to break their silence and qualify for select VA benefits and services.&nbsp; Tragically, many Atomic Veterans passed away without ever receiving the health care they deserved and without their families knowing the true extent of their service.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our Nation has many obligations, but only one sacred obligation: &nbsp;to prepare and equip the troops that we send into harm&#8217;s way and to care for them when they return home, as well as their families, caregivers, and survivors.&nbsp; For far too long, our Nation failed in our sacred obligation to our Atomic Veterans.&nbsp; It is a mistake our country must never repeat.&nbsp; I am committed to ensuring that all of our Nation&#8217;s veterans and their families, caregivers, and survivors have timely access to the services, medical care, and benefits that they deserve &#8212; including addressing the health effects of exposures to environmental toxins and harmful substances, such as the toxic fumes from burn pits. &nbsp;Since taking office, we have made several improvements to how we identify and address potential service-connected conditions, and the First Lady and I are personally committed to ensuring that all our veterans and their families, caregivers, and survivors receive the benefits and services they have earned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On National Atomic Veterans Day, we honor the Atomic Veterans who sacrificed on behalf our Nation.&nbsp; Our Atomic Veterans are patriots, and their bravery and service will always&nbsp;be remembered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim July 16, 2022, as National Atomic Veterans Day.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this day with appropriate ceremonies and activities that honor our Nation&#8217;s Atomic Veterans whose brave service and sacrifice played an important role in the defense of our Nation.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fifteenth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-seventh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Captive Nations Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/15/a-proclamation-on-captive-nations-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America has firmly set its sights on the ideals of freedom, democracy, equality, liberty, and justice for all.  We have never fully lived up to that founding promise, but we have never walked away from it either.  These core values have also moved us to support people around the world &#8212; especially those who live&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America has firmly set its sights on the ideals of freedom, democracy, equality, liberty, and justice for all.  We have never fully lived up to that founding promise, but we have never walked away from it either.  These core values have also moved us to support people around the world &#8212; especially those who live under oppressive regimes &#8212; so that they can freely exercise their rights.  As a long-standing democracy, the United States carries a responsibility to show the world how representative governance delivers benefits for all people.  During Captive Nations Week, we reaffirm our commitment to supporting and amplifying the voices of the courageous individuals around the world who are striving to advance the universal principles of freedom, democracy, justice, and the rule of law while living under oppression.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, defending democracy is more vital and more urgent than ever.&nbsp; Around the world, we bear witness to alarming trends &#8212; autocratic nations brutally invading the territory of their neighbors, backsliding of democratic values, intrusive digital surveillance, widespread human rights abuses, and increasing acts of transnational repression.&nbsp; These practices and policies imperil the essential work of activists, journalists, and defenders of human rights, and they oppress average citizens.&nbsp; Increasingly, repressive regimes in Russia, Iran, Belarus, Syria, Cuba, Venezuela, Nicaragua, the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea, the People&#8217;s Republic of China, and elsewhere are seeking to subjugate not only those within their own borders but also those in other countries. &nbsp;They reach across borders to surveil, harass, threaten, and even kill human rights defenders, media workers, and civilians in other sovereign nations.&nbsp; It is an outrage and an affront to the rules-based order that underwrites international peace and security. &nbsp;The world&#8217;s democracies must stand together and show the strength of our resolve to put an end to these injustices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the first Summit for Democracy in December 2021 and the ongoing Year of Action, the United States launched an effort to bring together governments around the world to counter authoritarianism, defend democracy, and safeguard the human rights and fundamental freedoms that foster peace, security, and prosperity.&nbsp; Collectively, we are working to bolster sustainable and independent media, protect and support civil society, and insist on the rule of law and accountability for those who commit abuses.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As Russia relentlessly wages its brutal and unprovoked war against the people of Ukraine, our Nation has led a global response to hold Russia accountable and denounce its inhumanity and its contempt for international law.&nbsp; We honor the valor and sacrifice of the people of Ukraine, who have reminded the world through their courage of the universal yearning for freedom. &nbsp;We will continue to stand with them as they defend their country, their liberty, and their democracy.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During Captive Nations Week, we stand in solidarity with the brave human rights and pro‑democracy advocates around the world &#8212; many of whom risk their lives each day to protect the rights of others.&nbsp; We remain committed to ensuring that all those who are oppressed around the globe are heard, supported, and protected.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May Captive Nations Week reinvigorate our efforts to live up to our ideals by championing justice, dignity, and freedom for all.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Congress, by joint resolution approved July 17, 1959 (73 Stat. 212), has authorized and requested the President to issue a proclamation designating the third week of July of each year as &#8220;Captive Nations Week.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim July 17 through July 23, 2022, as Captive Nations Week.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to reaffirm our commitment to championing those around the world who are working, often at great personal risk, to secure liberty and justice for all.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fifteenth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-seventh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at East Jerusalem Hospital Network&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-east-jerusalem-hospital-network-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57590</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Augusta Victoria HospitalJerusalem, Israel 10:57 A.M. EEST&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; My name is Joe Biden.&#160; I am Jill Biden&#8217;s husband.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; She has been here twice before me.&#160; And before I begin, I&#8217;d like to say that &#8212; there&#8217;s an old expression: &#8220;Hope springs eternal.&#8221; I &#8212; my background and the background of my family is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Augusta Victoria Hospital<br>Jerusalem, Israel</p>



<p>10:57 A.M. EEST&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; I am Jill Biden&#8217;s husband.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She has been here twice before me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And before I begin, I&#8217;d like to say that &#8212; there&#8217;s an old expression: &#8220;Hope springs eternal.&#8221;</p>



<p>I &#8212; my background and the background of my family is Irish American, and we have a long history of &#8212; not fundamentally unlike the Palestinian people with Great Britain and their attitude toward Irish-Catholics over the years, for 400 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my colleagues, when I was a U.S. senator, used to always joke with me that I was always quoting Irish poets when I was on the floor of the Senate.&nbsp; And they thought I did it because I&#8217;m Irish.&nbsp; That’s not the reason I did it; I did it because they&#8217;re the best poets in the world.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a great poem from &#8220;The Cure at Troy” &#8212; a paragraph.&nbsp; It goes like this &#8212; and it&#8217;s classically Irish, but it also could fit Palestinians.&nbsp; It says:</p>



<p><em>“History [teaches us not to] hope</em></p>



<p><em>On this side of the grave.</em></p>



<p><em>But then, once in a lifetime</em></p>



<p><em>[That] longed-for tidal wave</em></p>



<p><em>Of justice [rises] up,</em></p>



<p><em>And hope and history rhyme.”</em></p>



<p>&#8220;Hope and history rhyme.&#8221;&nbsp; It is my prayer that we&#8217;re reaching one of those moments where hope and history rhyme.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; are there any nurses in the room?&nbsp; Because if there are not, I&#8217;m going home. (Laughter.)</p>



<p>If there are any angels in Heaven &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; no, no, no, I mean this sincerely from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; My wife and daughter were killed and my boys were trapped in a vehicle for three hours when a tractor trailer hit them.&nbsp; And doctors saved their lives, but the nurses made them want to live, and cared for them every day, and knew &#8212; knew when they were ready and when they weren&#8217;t ready.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I was making a speech and I had a terrible headac- &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; a terrible headache.&nbsp; And &#8212; sorry &#8212; (takes a sip of water) &#8212; (coughs) &#8212; I swallowed wrong.&nbsp; I had a terrible headache.&nbsp; This was years ago.&nbsp; And I did a very stupid thing: I got on an aircraft and I flew home.&nbsp; It turned out I had two cranial aneurysms, and I got rushed to a hospital in the middle of a snowstorm for a nine-and-a-half-hour operation that saved my life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then I had the second operation; they found an aneurysm on the other side of my brain.&nbsp; I joke: The reason they went in twice to take the top of my head off is because they couldn’t find a brain the first time.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And in between, I had a major embolism that almost killed me.&nbsp; Nothing unusual that other people haven’t gone through.&nbsp; But I look back on it, and I don’t think you nurses are nearly appreciated enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I found was: You lie in the ICU &#8212; and I have not said this publicly before &#8212; and you look at the monitors, and you know if the line goes flat, you&#8217;re dead.&nbsp; You don’t know what each monitor is, but you know.&nbsp; And I really mean it &#8212; it&#8217;s true.&nbsp; But you just get tired.&nbsp; Even when you&#8217;re not in pain, you just want to quit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the nurses at Walter Reed Hospital would come up, they&#8217;d rub my face, they&#8217;d whisper in my ear.&nbsp; They&#8217;d get close and tell me, &#8220;It&#8217;s going to be okay.&#8221;</p>



<p>They made a difference in my life.</p>



<p>My son spent a year in Iraq.&nbsp; He was the attorney general of the state of Delaware.&nbsp; He should be the man standing here and talking to you as President, not me.&nbsp; He came home because he &#8212; his &#8212; where he slept for a year in Iraq was about 150 yards from a burn pit where they burned everything from fuel to garbage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He went &#8212; the fittest guy in his regiment, in his outfit, and came home with stage four glioblastoma.&nbsp; I watched for 14 months the nurses take care of him &#8212; the doctors as well &#8212; but every day &#8212; every single day.</p>



<p>And so I really mean it from the bottom of my heart: Nurses &#8212; doctors are critical; I&#8217;m not in any way diminishing the role of a doctor.&nbsp; But nurses &#8212; nurses give you as much hope &#8212; male and female &#8212; as anybody else does.</p>



<p>I want to thank the CEO and everyone at East Jerusalem Hospital Network for welcoming me this morning.&nbsp; This is the first time I had the opportunity to see for myself the outstanding work that you do here, that I’ve heard about for such a long time.</p>



<p>My wife, Jill, visited in both 2010 and 2016, and I&#8217;m honored to be able to see firsthand the service and the quality of care you provide the Palestinian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These hospitals are the backbone of the Palestinian healthcare system.&nbsp; People turn to you in their moment of need, as you well know, with their children who are sick, with a loved one who’s injured.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When they get that cancer diagnosis &#8212; the most feared word, I think, in all languages is when the doctor looks at you and says, “It&#8217;s cancer.”&nbsp; They don&#8217;t know what to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You not only care for them, you guide them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the same [for] people all over the world.&nbsp; In that moment, all that matters is that you’ve got someone that you can turn to and radiates hope and help.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why the United States, through the Agency for International Development, has been so proud &#8212; has been proud to support this network of hospitals with $85 million since 2014.&nbsp; It’s part of our commitment to support health and dignity to the Palestinian people.&nbsp; Maybe the most overused phrase &#8212; word in the English language for the Irish is “dignity.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>My dad used to say, “Everyone, no matter what their circumstance, is entitled to be treated with dignity.”&nbsp; Dignity.</p>



<p>And dealing with the COVID-19 pandemic took a hard toll here, as it did in so many communities around the world.&nbsp; So, today, I&#8217;m pleased to announce the United States is committing an additional $100 million to support these hospitals, your staffs, and &#8212; that work for the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>This is a multiyear commitment in both resources and expertise.&nbsp; When I was Vice President, I asked the President, then Barack Obama &#8212; I asked him whether or not I could start what we called a Cancer Moonshot.&nbsp; I visited every major cancer hospital in the world, with one exception &#8212; and I mean it literally.&nbsp; Because there&#8217;s so much &#8212; so much we’re just on the edge of being able to discern.&nbsp; We&#8217;re so close, dealing with so many cancers.</p>



<p>When I got elected President, I announced that one of my goals was to change cancer as we know it so it was no longer viewed by many people, as it is, as a death sentence but as a disease that can either be cured or lived with.</p>



<p>**3</p>



<p>**12:30-end</p>



<p>And we started this Cancer Moonshot with billions of dollars at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Within our National Institute of Health, I set up a provision where, like within the Defense Department &#8212; there&#8217;s a special office in the Defense Department that’s nothing but looking at breaking technologies, whether it&#8217;s &#8212; just across the board.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where the Internet came from.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, we’re doing the same thing at the National Institute of Health, just focusing on cancer.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; This one provision.</p>



<p>It represents our investment in the future.&nbsp; As your &#8212; this &#8212; hopefully, this $100 million will generate other large contributions from other countries, focusing on the health of the Palestinian people so they&#8217;ll continue to have access to the best available care, so they know they have somewhere to turn for help.&nbsp; They have navigators that can help them through the process.<br><br>Those of you who have been on the other side of a diagnosis know the most frightening thing is: When you get the word, whatever it is, you can hardly listen.&nbsp; You need a navigator.&nbsp; You need someone to help you walk through the pieces, help you figure out how to deal with the treatment you&#8217;re going to have once you&#8217;re out of the hospital and need treatment.<br><br>Working together, it is my prayer the United States will both help relieve the hospital&#8217;s burden of debt and support for targeted infrastructure upgrades and key reforms in patient care to ensure long-term financial stability.<br><br>We also welcome the $25 million contribution from the UAE, and I encourage other nations around the region and around the world to step up as well with their own contributions to support the vital work that&#8217;s being done here.<br><br>Palestinians and Israelis deserve equal measure of freedom, security, prosperity, and dignity.&nbsp; And access to healthcare when you need it is essential to living a life of dignity for all of us.<br><br>The United States will continue to work with the Palestinian leadership, with the government of Israel, and with all our international partners to ensure that East Jer- &#8212; East Jerusalem’s Hospital Network retains sustainable, remains available, and is able to provide high-quality care that the Palestinian people deserve.<br><br>I could say much more, but if my mother were here, she’d look at me and say, “Joey, hush up.&nbsp; You’ve spoken too long.”<br><br>But I want to thank you again for welcoming me &#8212; welcoming me today.&nbsp; Most importantly, thank you for taking care of all the patients &#8212; all the patients whose lives you make better.<br><br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m finished.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If you have a question about hospitals &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; I’ll answer it; if you don’t, I&#8217;ll do it privately.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I am American Palestinian from New Jersey, Bergen County, and I vote for you.&nbsp; I am a head nurse of pediatric intensive care unit at Makassed Hospital.&nbsp; Thank you for your support, but we need more justice, more dignity.&nbsp; And thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, folks.&nbsp; Appreciate it very, very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:11 A.M. EEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Abbas of the Palestinian National Authority in Joint Press Statement &#124; Bethlehem, West&#160;Bank</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/15/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-abbas-of-the-palestinian-national-authority-in-joint-press-statement-bethlehem-west-bank/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 13:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Muqata’a Presidential CompoundBethlehem, West Bank 1:24 P.M. EEST PRESIDENT ABBAS:  (As interpreted.)  Formidable President Biden, we welcome you as a dear guest of Palestine, in the city of Bethlehem, the cradle of our Lord Jesus Christ, on your official visit, which expresses your interest in achieving peace in the land of peace. And today&#8217;s meeting,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Muqata’a Presidential Compound<br>Bethlehem, West Bank</p>



<p>1:24 P.M. EEST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT ABBAS:  (As interpreted.)  Formidable President Biden, we welcome you as a dear guest of Palestine, in the city of Bethlehem, the cradle of our Lord Jesus Christ, on your official visit, which expresses your interest in achieving peace in the land of peace.</p>



<p>And today&#8217;s meeting, our meeting, was an opportunity to discuss consolidating our military relations between the countries and peoples, and to review what the U.S. can contribute to prepare the atmosphere for a political horizon for a just, comprehensive, durable peace.</p>



<p>We have stressed to Mr. President Biden on the importance of reestablishing the foundations upon which the peace process was based &#8212; that is based on the international legitimacy resolutions and on the basis of the two-state solution along the 1967 borders.</p>



<p>Mr. President, after 74 years of the Nakba displacement and occupation, isn&#8217;t it not the time for this occupation to end and for our steadfast people, again, to gain their freedom and independence, and for the hopes of our young men and women, whom we cherish and trust their creativity, to achieve a promising future without occupation?</p>



<p>In this regard, we say that the key to peace and security in our region begins with recognizing state of Palestine and enabling the Palestinian people to obtain their legitimate rights in accordance with international legitimacy resolutions, and ending all the permanent status issues, including the Palestinian refugees issue.</p>



<p>And the way to that begins with ending the Israeli occupation of our land, the land of state of Palestine, with East Jerusalem as its capital, on the 1967 borders.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we have respected the resolutions of international legitimacy and signed agreements, and we have committed ourselves to renouncing violence and fighting terrorism in our region and the world.</p>



<p>We look forward to steps from the U.S. administration to strengthen bilateral relations by reopening the U.S. consulate in East Jerusalem, removing the PLO from the U.S. terrorist list. We are not terrorists. And also, we look forward to reopening PLO office in Washington. And we are ready to work within the framework of partnership and cooperation in order to remove any obstacles to achieving that.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we look forward to the efforts of your administration to turn the page on the Israeli occupation of our land and the acts of racial discrimination, apartheid against our people; and to stop unilateral actions that undermine the two-state solution.</p>



<p>We look forward to these efforts to stop settlement and settler violence; and respect of the historical situation in the Islamic and Christian holy sites and the Hashemite custodianship; and stopping the expulsion of Palestinians, demolishing houses, homes, and storming the cities, villages, and camps; and stopping the daily killing and arrests on daily basis; and holding the killers of the martyr journalist, Shireen Abu Akleh &#8212; they need to be held accountable.</p>



<p>Because the continuation of all of that will lead to escalation on the one hand and loss of hope for a better tomorrow on the other.</p>



<p>Mr. President, if Israel wants to be a compliant state, it cannot continue to act as a state above law. And this calls for Israel to end its occupation of the land of state of Palestine with East Jerusalem as its capital on the 1967 borders.</p>



<p>Only then, Israel will be accepted to live in peace, security, and good neighborhood with the countries and peoples of the region based on the Arab Peace Initiative. The opportunity for the two-state solution on the 1967 borders may be available today only, but we don’t know what will happen later.</p>



<p>Therefore, I take this opportunity on the occasion of the visit of Your Excellency to the region to say that I extend my hand to the leaders of Israel to make peace for the (inaudible). And this has happened much before. Before Oslo Accords, we have been extending our hands for peace with all the Israeli leaders for a better future for the future generations and for all the peoples of the region.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we welcome you again. And our confidence in you and your administration is very great. And we assure you of our readiness to work with you, hand in hand, in order to achieve comprehensive and just peace based on international legitimacy and the Arab Peace Initiative and the signed agreements between us and Israel.</p>



<p>There are agreements that we need to respect in a way &#8212; in a manner that guarantees security, peace, stability, and lasting prosperity for all the countries in the region.</p>



<p>Mr. President, peace begins with Palestine and Jerusalem. From here, peace starts. We extend our hands for peace and to work with you, Mr. President, to achieve it.</p>



<p>Peace be upon you. (In Arabic.) Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Mr. President, President Abbas, thank you very much and to your colleagues with whom I had the opportunity to meet as well.</p>



<p>And it’s good to see you again, my friend. We’ve known each other for a long time. And I’m very proud to be with you today as President of the United States. And I can &#8212; we can count ourselves among the earliest supporters of a two-state solution.</p>



<p>As I stand with you today, now as President of the United States, my commitment to that goal of a two-state solution has not changed in all these years.</p>



<p>Two states along the 1967 lines, where mutually agreed-to swaps, remain the best way to achieve equal measure of security, prosperity, freedom, and democracy for the Palestinians as well as Israelis.</p>



<p>The Palestinian people deserve a state of their own that’s independent, sovereign, viable, and contiguous. Two states for two peoples, both of whom have deep and ancient roots in this land, living side by side in peace and security. Both states fully respecting the equal rights of the other citizens. Both peoples enjoying equal measure of freedom and dignity. That’s what this is fundamentally all about.</p>



<p>Every person has a right to be treated with dignity. It’s simply basic. I know that the goal of the two states seems so far away while indignities like restrictions on movement and travel or the daily worry of your children’s safety are real and they are immediate.</p>



<p>The Pales- &#8212; the Palestinian people are hurting now. You feel &#8212; you can just feel it, your grief and frustration. In the United States, we can feel it.</p>



<p>But we’ve never give up on the work of peace. You know, there must be a political horizon that the Palestinian people can actually see or at least feel. We can’t allow the hopelessness to steal away the future that so many have worked toward for so long.</p>



<p>So even if the ground is not ripe at this moment to restart negotiations, the United States and my administration will not give up on trying to bring the Palestinians and Israelis and both sides closer together.</p>



<p>I do believe that in this moment when Israel is improving relations with its neighbors throughout the region, we can harness that same momentum to reinvigorate the peace process between the Palestinian people and the Israelis.</p>



<p>I recognize how hard all these challenges must be and will be to work through. Above all, there must be an end to the violence that has devastated too many families.</p>



<p>It’s heart-wrenching that so many Palestinians and Israelis have lost their life just this year. And the United States has suffered loss as well, including the killing of Shireen Abu Alkeh &#8212; Alkehli [Akleh].</p>



<p>And she was an American &#8212; an American citizen and a proud Palestinian. And she was performing very vital work on an independent media and vital work of democracy.</p>



<p>Her death is an enormous loss to the essential work of sharing with the world the story of the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>I hope that her legacy &#8212; her legacy will inspire more young people to carry on her work of reporting the truth and telling stories that are too often overlooked.</p>



<p>The United States will continue to insist on a full and transparent accounting of her death, and we will continue to stand up for media freedom everywhere in the world.</p>



<p>President Abbas, in the past, we met in Ramallah, but today, in the Palestinian city of Bethlehem, a place of enormous<br>significance in my faith as well &#8212; the birthplace of Jesus Christ.</p>



<p>This is the city that lives in the hearts of millions of Christians and is a reminder of God’s great gift to the world and our renewed and redemption in Christ.</p>



<p>Muslim and Jews also have an intense and deep connection to this land, particularly in Jerusalem.</p>



<p>Jerusalem is central to the national visions of both Palestinians and Israelis &#8212; to your histories, to your faiths, to your futures.</p>



<p>Jerusalem must be a city for all its people &#8212; its holy sites preserving the status quo, with the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan continuing to serve as custodian.</p>



<p>And throughout this Holy Land, which is filled with so many places of meaning and significance to Muslims, Christians, and Jews, we must all be free to practice our faiths in peace, in safety, and in dignity.</p>



<p>We cannot wait for a peace agreement to be reached or for every issue to be resolved to deliver on the needs of the Palestinian people that exist today, as I speak.</p>



<p>The best way to feed the flame of hope is to demonstrate that things can be better. And, President Abbas, the United States is a partner in this work to improve the day-to-day lives of the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>That’s why, when I came to office, I reserved the policy &#8212; I reversed the policies of my predecessor and resumed aid to the Palestinians &#8212; more than a half a billion dollars in [since] 2021.</p>



<p>That’s support for the economic development of the Palestinian people, to strengthen Palestinian security, to provide food for people to eat, to respond to the pandemic, including donating more than one million doses of COVID-19 [vaccine] to the West Bank and Gaza.</p>



<p>It also includes more than $400 million in humanitarian assistance to Palestinian refugees through the United [Nations] Relief and Works Agency &#8212; the UNRWA.</p>



<p>And today, I’m announcing the United States is going to provide an additional $200 million to the UNRWA so it can continue its vital work of helping the most vulnerable Palestinians, especially Palestinian children.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, and I &#8212; we decided &#8212; and this morning, I announced an additional $100 million in support of healthcare services for Palestinians throughout East Jerusalem Hospital Network.</p>



<p>We were &#8212; we were engaging with Israel around ways<br>to spur greater Palestinian economic growth, including by implementing 4G mobile networks, increasing the supply of renewable energy, improving freedom of movement for Palestinians, both people and goods.</p>



<p>These are the kinds of issues that progress can make life better for people right away, and we should be about it right away.</p>



<p>And the Palestinian Authority has important work to do as well, if you don’t mind my saying.</p>



<p>Now is the time to strengthen Palestinian institutions, to improve governance, transparency, and accountability.</p>



<p>All of this work is critical. And it will help build a society that can support a successful, democratic future, and a future Palestinian state. And the United States will work with you, President Abbas, at every step.</p>



<p>So thank you again for welcoming me and my delegation &#8212; the Secretary of State, National Security Advisor, and others &#8212; to visit with you.</p>



<p>I hope our visit is the start of a new and reinvigorated dialogue between the Palestinian Authority, the United States &#8212; and between the Palestinian &#8212; countries and counties throughout &#8212; and countries throughout the region, including Israel.</p>



<p>So let’s work together to show the people of the region, especially young people &#8212; young people &#8212; that the future can be better than it is today.</p>



<p>I thank you all very much. And may God protect us all. Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>END 1:40 P.M. EEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Abbas of the Palestinian&#160;Authority</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-abbas-of-the-palestinian-authority/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 11:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden Jr. met with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas. President Biden reaffirmed the enduring ties between the Palestinian and American peoples and underscored his commitment to a two-state solution on the 1967 lines with land swaps mutually agreed by the Israelis and Palestinians. He also highlighted the importance of direct negotiations&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden Jr. met with Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas. President Biden reaffirmed the enduring ties between the Palestinian and American peoples and underscored his commitment to a two-state solution on the 1967 lines with land swaps mutually agreed by the Israelis and Palestinians. He also highlighted the importance of direct negotiations leading to an independent, sovereign, viable, and contiguous Palestinian state alongside the State of Israel, both enjoying secure and recognized borders, allowing the two peoples to live side-by-side in peace and security.</p>



<p>In the meeting, President Biden highlighted a number of initiatives the United States is undertaking to support the Palestinian people. President Biden also discussed encouraging regional governments and the international community to assist the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>The leaders reaffirmed that both Palestinians and Israelis deserve to enjoy equal measures of freedom, security, prosperity, and democracy. President Biden emphasized his belief that the Palestinian people deserve to live lives of dignity and opportunity; to move and travel freely; to feel secure in their communities; and to give hope to their children that they will one day enjoy the same freedom and self-determination of their neighbors.</p>



<p>President Biden reiterated the importance of fostering a political horizon, and noted the United States stands ready to work with Israelis, Palestinians, and regional stakeholders toward that goal. As he had relayed to Israeli leaders, President Biden conveyed to President Abbas that in order to create the conditions for negotiations, it was important for both parties to avoid unilateral measures.</p>



<p>President Biden reiterated the U.S. position that Jerusalem is the capital of Israel, and that it continues to be the policy of the United States that the specific boundaries of sovereignty in Jerusalem must be resolved through final status negotiations between Israelis and Palestinians. He further reaffirmed the need to preserve the historic status quo at the holy sites in Jerusalem, recognizing the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan’s crucial role as custodian.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden Welcoming the Opening of Saudi Airspace to&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/15/statement-by-president-biden-welcoming-the-opening-of-saudi-airspace-to-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 06:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Saudi Arabia’s historic decision to open its airspace for all civilian planes, including those flying to and from Israel, is an important step towards building a more integrated and stable Middle East region.  While this opening has long been discussed, now, thanks to months of steady diplomacy between my Administration and Saudi Arabia, it is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Saudi Arabia’s historic decision to open its airspace for all civilian planes, including those flying to and from Israel, is an important step towards building a more integrated and stable Middle East region.  While this opening has long been discussed, now, thanks to months of steady diplomacy between my Administration and Saudi Arabia, it is finally a reality. Today, I will be the first president of the United States to fly from Israel to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia. As we mark this important moment, Saudi Arabia’s decision can help build momentum toward Israel’s further integration into the region, including with Saudi Arabia. I will do all that I can, through direct diplomacy and leader-to-leader engagement, to keep advancing this groundbreaking process.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The United&#160;States-Palestinian&#160;Relationship</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/fact-sheet-the-united-states-palestinian-relationship/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57460</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tomorrow, President Biden will announce a number of initiatives to support the Palestinian people by: Improving access to health care and technology; Rolling out long overdue 4G digital connectivity to both Gaza and the West Bank; Bolstering economic growth; Providing critical services for Palestinian refugees; Reducing food insecurity; Fostering people-to-people dialogue to support peace.&#160; President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tomorrow, President Biden will announce a number of initiatives to support the Palestinian people by:</p>



<ul><li>Improving access to health care and technology;</li><li>Rolling out long overdue 4G digital connectivity to both Gaza and the West Bank;</li><li>Bolstering economic growth;</li><li>Providing critical services for Palestinian refugees;</li><li>Reducing food insecurity;</li><li>Fostering people-to-people dialogue to support peace.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>President Biden will also announce new contributions totaling $316 million to support the Palestinian people.&nbsp;This is on top of the more than half a billion dollars the United States has provided to the Palestinian people since the Biden Administration restored much needed funding to the Palestinians.</p>



<p><strong>Improve Healthcare Access for Palestinians</strong></p>



<ul><li>During his visit to the Augusta Victoria Hospital in East Jerusalem, the President will announce the United States intends to provide a new multi-year U.S. contribution of up to $100 million for the East Jerusalem Hospital Network (EJHN), subject to congressional approval.&nbsp; The EJHN is a grouping of six hospitals in East Jerusalem providing specialized services including oncology, dialysis, neo-natal intensive care, and specialized maternity, ophthalmology, and emergency services to 50,000 patients from East Jerusalem, the West Bank, and Gaza annually.&nbsp; The funding is provided by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and paired with health system and hospital reforms.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Bolstering the Digital Economy to Improve Palestinian Economic Growth</strong></p>



<ul><li>To boost Palestinian businesses and improve connectivity for Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza, Israel has committed to speeding up the long overdue transformation of 3G to 4G in the West Bank and afterwards 2G to 4G in Gaza.&nbsp; Israeli and Palestinian teams will work together immediately to start the technological surveys, with an aim to roll out an advanced infrastructure for 4G by the end of 2023.&nbsp; This commitment will accelerate digital transformation and foster a more well-connected Palestinian economy.&nbsp; It will also generate jobs, increase productivity, and increase online operations in the health and education sectors.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Improve the Travel Experience from the West Bank to Jordan</strong></p>



<ul><li>President Biden supports creating a more autonomous, efficient, and reliable Palestinian experience of traveling abroad.&nbsp; He will announce that Israel is prepared to take measures to increase efficiency and accessibility to the Allenby Bridge for the benefit of Palestinians.&nbsp; In order to upgrade facilities, Israel has agreed to enable access 24 hours per day, 7 days per week, by September 30, 2022.&nbsp; A working group will assess several measures including the use of biometric passports and will complete its assessments within the next month and discuss conclusions with U.S. partners.&nbsp; In addition, the working group will consider steps to establish Palestinian Authority presence on Allenby Bridge while maintaining Israel&#8217;s security considerations.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Support Critical Services for Palestinian Refugees</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States believes that Palestinian refugees deserve to live in dignity, to see their basic needs addressed, and to have hope for the future.&nbsp; President Biden will announce an additional $201 million for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (UNRWA) to continue delivering critical services to Palestinian refugees in the West Bank, Gaza, Jordan, Lebanon, and Syria.&nbsp; UNRWA’s comprehensive services remain a lifeline to millions of vulnerable Palestinians – consistent with its mandate to provide assistance and protection to Palestinian refugees pending a just and lasting solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.&nbsp; These services directly contribute to maintaining regional stability, which is beneficial to the interests of the United States, our allies, and our partners.&nbsp; This contribution cements the United States’ status as UNRWA’s largest donor. &nbsp;These new funds bring the total United States assistance to UNRWA during the Biden Administration to more than $618 million. &nbsp;The United States is committed to supporting UNRWA to provide the most effective and efficient assistance possible and to continue to improve its operations and delivery. &nbsp;UNRWA’s work must be done while fully respecting the UN principles of neutrality, tolerance, human rights, equity, and non-discrimination. &nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Re-Launching Israeli-Palestinian Economic Discussions and Promoting Steps to Improve Lives</strong></p>



<ul><li>President Biden will share with President Abbas that Israel intends to convene the Joint Economic Committee with the Palestinians.&nbsp; Restarting discussions through the Joint Economic Committee has been a longstanding request of the Palestinian Authority. &nbsp;The committee last met in 2009 and is the mandated entity under the Oslo Accords for the Israeli government and Palestinian Authority to meet to discuss joint economic issues, including wastewater, clean energy, and other measures that impact Palestinian lives in the West Bank.&nbsp; President Biden also announced that Israel agreed to increase the number of permits for Palestinians in Gaza to work and do business in Israel to 15,500.&nbsp; The Biden Administration strongly supports increased access and movement for Palestinians, and this is a positive step toward that goal.&nbsp; Additionally, Israel agreed to approve the registration of 5,500 previously unregistered Palestinians on the Palestinian Population Register.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensure Food Security for Palestinians</strong></p>



<ul><li>In response to rising food insecurity for Palestinians in the wake of the Russian invasion of Ukraine, President Biden will announce that the United States is providing $15 million in additional humanitarian assistance for vulnerable Palestinians.&nbsp; Via funding to the UN World Food Program and two non-governmental organizations, the United States is providing electronic food vouchers, multipurpose cash assistance, and emergency livelihoods support, helping more than 210,000 food-insecure people meet their household food needs in coming months.&nbsp; This funding is part of the pledge of additional U.S. government resources that President Biden made at the G7 Leaders’ Summit in Germany in late June to protect the world’s most vulnerable populations from the escalating global food security crisis.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Fostering People-to-People Ties</strong></p>



<ul><li>To build grassroots support for peace through an eventual negotiated two-state solution, President Biden will announce two new grants under the Nita M. Lowey Middle East Partnership for Peace Act (MEPPA).&nbsp; MEPPA authorizes up to $250 million dollars over five years to implement projects led by both Israelis and Palestinians establishing the environment necessary to achieve long term peace.&nbsp; The first new grant, for $2.21 million to the Peres Center for Peace, will support collaboration and professional exchanges between the Palestinian and Israeli health sectors as they work to build mutual trust, confidence, and understanding between the two societies.&nbsp; The second new grant, for $5 million to AppleSeeds, will provide young Palestinian and Israeli professionals the opportunity to work together and learn critical technology and leadership. For more information on these and other activities under MEPPA please visit <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/west-bank-and-gaza/meppa">https://www.usaid.gov/west-bank-and-gaza/meppa</a>.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Mayors on Reproductive Rights&#160; </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-mayors-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, met with women and allied mayors from across the country to discuss reproductive rights.&#160; From safeguarding public health to overseeing critical infrastructure, mayors lead and implement policies closest to home. As abortion bans go into effect in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, met with women and allied mayors from across the country to discuss reproductive rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From safeguarding public health to overseeing critical infrastructure, mayors lead and implement policies closest to home. As abortion bans go into effect in states across the country, compromising women’s access to critical reproductive health care services,&nbsp;mayors can play an important role in their communities, including by supporting public education and outreach on reproductive health care, supporting the funding of services,&nbsp;sharing accurate information, and taking additional actions to protect abortion access and promote safety.</p>



<p>On June 30, the Women Mayors Network released a&nbsp;<a href="https://nam12.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Furldefense.com%2Fv3%2F__https%3A%2Fwww.womenmayorsnetwork.org%2Fabortionaccessletter2%2F__%3B!!AQdq3sQhfUj4q8uUguY!iz9lbb4k2qPMql2vQSzaIkbXehLFnIQSVFuYJ2uZbuErKQuqz-Pff91Bk8qG5HwgiLZ7mKsWjHcBjY1K2BwAE2_hnuJ7A_G_IKfr%24&amp;data=05%7C01%7CZMiller%40ap.org%7C928d3918aa964d68d4d908da65a61411%7Ce442e1abfd6b4ba3abf3b020eb50df37%7C1%7C0%7C637934061221694690%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=CJ8Y7dIJBu23JiIBcCBL3skploii%2BYuIOtLNmO2Vm7g%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">letter</a>&nbsp;from more than 65 women mayors and additional male allies in response to the Supreme Court’s decision in&nbsp;<em>Dobbs v. Jackson</em>&nbsp;<em>Women’s Health Organization.&nbsp;</em>In the letter, the mayors commit to “actions that safeguard our clinics and our residents who are seeking abortion services or helping others do so and funding services and logistical support whenever possible, and to organize with residents and activists to support actions that expand access to abortion care.”</p>



<p>In the meeting, which was co-hosted by the Women Mayors Network, mayors shared what they are seeing and hearing on the ground as patients from states that ban abortion travel to seek care. The mayors also discussed actions they have taken to support reproductive rights, as well as key messaging and outreach strategies. White House Senior Officials thanked the mayors for their leadership and reinforced the Administration’s commitment&nbsp;to working together to protect access to abortion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on the Opening of Saudi&#160;Airspace</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-the-opening-of-saudi-airspace/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden welcomes and commends the historic decision by the leadership of Saudi Arabia to open Saudi airspace to all civilian carriers without discrimination, a decision that includes flights to and from Israel. This decision is the result of the President’s persistent and principled diplomacy with Saudi Arabia over many months, culminating in his visit&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden welcomes and commends the historic decision by the leadership of Saudi Arabia to open Saudi airspace to all civilian carriers without discrimination, a decision that includes flights to and from Israel. This decision is the result of the President’s persistent and principled diplomacy with Saudi Arabia over many months, culminating in his visit today. This decision paves the way for a more integrated, stable, and secure Middle East region, which is vital for the security and prosperity of the United States and the American people, and for the security and prosperity of Israel. The President will have more to say on this breakthrough later today, as we embark on his historic flight directly from Israel to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris before Briefing from CENTCOM and SOCOM&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-briefing-from-centcom-and-socom-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MacDill Air Force BaseTampa, Florida THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I am very much looking forward to our discussion.&#160; And I&#8217;m very pleased to be here on the ground with you, who have been doing extraordinary work on so many levels.&#160;&#160;I was &#8212; all that I &#8212; that I admire about the service,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>MacDill Air Force Base<br><em>Tampa, Florida</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I am very much looking forward to our discussion.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m very pleased to be here on the ground with you, who have been doing extraordinary work on so many levels.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I was &#8212; all that I &#8212; that I admire about the service, the dedication, the discipline, and the skill that our men and women apply to this work was reinforced with the quick visit that I just had out in the hangar.&nbsp; And so, I want to thank everyone here for what you do every day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are here to highlight and to &#8212; to uplift with praise the work of CENTCOM and SOCOM.&nbsp; This work is critical to our national security.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As we know, the President is overseas right now in the Middle East.&nbsp; And there is so much about what happens through the leadership here on the ground that allows us to reinforce and strengthen our partnerships around the globe and reinforces our commitment to international rules and norms and America’s willingness and preparedness to uphold and defend those international rules and norms.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m here to speak with these leaders &#8212; in particular, General Kurilla and General Clarke.&nbsp; And I want to thank you both for hosting us today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The United States Military, without any question certainly in my mind or the President&#8217;s mind and in the mind of the American people, is the strongest and the best fighting force in the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>When you look at the work that happens just right here, you will see extraordinary work that is about dedication, discipline, the building and strengthening of skills, and just sheer commitment to defending our country and the principles upon which we were founded.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I&#8217;m here to talk with the leaders here to discuss the missions that are currently active around the globe and to talk with them about what might be necessary in terms of the additional support and resources that they need to do their job and complete their mission.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;I also am here to express gratitude not only to the service members but to their families.&nbsp; In particular, the folks who work out of CENTCOM and SOCOM are supported by wonderful families who dedicate so much of their lives to allow their family member to serve as they do for our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I am here to praise, again, the work that is being done by all of these folks.&nbsp; I also want to mention that partic- &#8212; in particular, regarding the work of CENTCOM, President Biden, being in the Middle East, is there to also make sure that we are clear about the role and the responsibility the United States plays in that region of the world, with an emphasis on many points, including our enduring relationship in support of our allies and friends and partners in Israel.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>His visit is also about emphasizing the work that is happening through CENTCOM that strengthens the relationships that we have in that region of the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>CENTCOM’s work also directly benefits the American people, in addition to ensuring that all of the values we care about in terms of our security are upheld.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>CENTCOM’s work includes protecting commercial shipping lanes and energy resources that Americans rely on and &#8212; in this moment when we know that commerce and the &#8212; the active ability of us to engage in commerce is something that directly affects the American people where they live and how they live.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Regarding SOCOM, this year we celebrate the 30th &#8212; 35th, excuse me, anniversary of its founding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And we call the Special Operations Forces our “quiet professionals” for a reason.&nbsp; They do big work.&nbsp; They never look for praise or acknowledgement.&nbsp; But the work they do we take for granted.&nbsp; Sometimes we don&#8217;t see, but we surely benefit from it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I&#8217;m here to also talk about the work that is happening in the frontlines on our continued fight against terrorism around the world and the work that SOCOM does to ensure that America&#8217;s interests are well served, including at this moment during Russia&#8217;s unprovoked aggression and the war in Ukraine, where the men and women of this division have been doing the work that they do around the globe, including training the forces that are the forces of our allies and, in particular, the Ukrainians in their fight to preserve their sovereignty and territorial integrity.<br>&nbsp;<br>So together, CENTCOM and SOCOM advance our national security interests and defend and strengthen our international rules-based order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I will conclude by saying to all here how much we appreciate you every day.&nbsp; I mentioned to the folks that I was with in the hangar: We talk about you guys all the time when we&#8217;re sitting in the Situation Room or in the Oval Office, talking about America&#8217;s responsibility not only to the citizens of our country but to our friends and allies around the world.&nbsp; We talk about you, because we could not follow through on anything that we do in the context of those relationships and priorities were it not for what you all are doing here on the ground.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you.&nbsp; And your mission remains critically important to the President, to me, and to our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I thank the press.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see you all later.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END<br>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
