<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 13:55:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meetings with Landlords and Tenant&#160;Advocates</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/06/readout-of-white-house-meetings-with-landlords-and-tenant-advocates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26429</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling and Special Assistant to the President for Housing and Urban Policy Erika Poethig, along with other Biden-Harris Administration officials, held virtual listening sessions with groups representing landlords and tenant advocates to discuss state and local disbursement of emergency rental assistance funds and ways to protect&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling and Special Assistant to the President for Housing and Urban Policy Erika Poethig, along with other Biden-Harris Administration officials, held virtual listening sessions with groups representing landlords and tenant advocates to discuss state and local disbursement of emergency rental assistance funds and ways to protect renters from eviction.</p>



<p>Administration officials communicated the need for landlords to accept rental assistance before pursuing evictions. They also received feedback on strengths and weaknesses of state and local rental assistance programs as well as ways the Administration can work with governors and mayors to expedite the release of rental assistance funds. Landlords also offered their feedback on how grantees might speed delivery and increase access to rental assistance.&nbsp; In their discussions with tenant advocates, Administration officials also heard about the challenges renters are facing in accessing emergency rental assistance funds. They also shared examples of where evictions are proceeding and ways to promote eviction diversion strategies.</p>



<p>In both meetings, Administration officials reiterated the commitment made by President Biden that his Administration will not rest—nor should state and local governments—until emergency rental assistance dollars reach Americans in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The meetings with these groups are part of continued engagement by the Administration to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-companies-non-profits-government-agencies-answer-biden-harris-call-make-combined-commitment-to-alert-tens-of-millions-of-americans-to-emergency-rental-assistance/">raise awareness among tenants and landlords</a> on available resources and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/">increase the pace of distribution</a> of the billions in emergency rental assistance that is available to state and local governments to prevent evictions and make landlords whole.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Health Center Week,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/08/06/a-proclamation-on-national-health-center-week-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 13:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26413</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; In 1965, our Nation launched its first community health centers to improve the lives and well-being of Americans regardless of their ability to pay.&#160; These health centers were a&#160;key component of President Lyndon B. Johnson&#8217;s &#8220;Great Society&#8221; series of policy initiatives to eliminate poverty and racial injustice, and today serve as the bedrock on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In 1965, our Nation launched its first community health centers to improve the lives and well-being of Americans regardless of their ability to pay.&nbsp; These health centers were a&nbsp;key component of President Lyndon B. Johnson&#8217;s &#8220;Great Society&#8221; series of policy initiatives to eliminate poverty and racial injustice, and today serve as the bedrock on which our public health system was built.&nbsp; Today, health centers are one of the largest health care providers in the country and provide high-quality affordable, accessible, and value-based primary health care services to 29 million Americans each year &#8212; approximately 1 in 11 people across the country.&nbsp; They have also been a vital part of our Nation&#8217;s response to the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; Over&nbsp;the course of National Health Center Week, we recognize the&nbsp;importance of federally-supported health centers and the role they play as a beacon of strength, service, and care in our&nbsp;communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Health centers integrate medical, dental, and behavioral health care services into a single &#8220;health home&#8221; and consistently yield strong patient outcomes.&nbsp; Health centers also&nbsp;play a critical role in reducing racial and ethnic, geographic, socioeconomic, and other health disparities in the&nbsp;United&nbsp;States.&nbsp; They are invaluable to ensuring that our&nbsp;Nation&#8217;s underserved populations, especially individuals and&nbsp;families living in poverty, rural communities, and communities of color are able to receive the care they need&nbsp;and&nbsp;deserve. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our Nation&#8217;s recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic is stronger because of our health centers, and the tireless, dedicated health center employees who continue to deliver critical services such as COVID-19 testing, treatment, and prevention services on the front lines. &nbsp;As we ramped up the distribution of COVID-19 vaccines over the past several months, health centers, through the Health Center COVID-19 Vaccine Program, have vaccinated and built vaccine confidence in millions of Americans from hard-hit and high-risk communities. &nbsp;Two-thirds of individuals vaccinated at health centers so far identify as racial and ethnic minorities. &nbsp;Health centers have also offered greater flexibility during the pandemic by expanding telehealth services to those in need.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I believe that health care in America should be a right, not a privilege. &nbsp;No one should have to lay awake at night staring at the ceiling wondering what they are going to do to&nbsp;get the care they need or to pay the bills if a family member gets sick.&nbsp; That is why I&nbsp;will&nbsp;do everything in my power to&nbsp;ensure&nbsp;that&nbsp;all Americans&nbsp;have access to&nbsp;the&nbsp;quality, affordable health care&nbsp;they deserve &#8212; and the peace of mind it&nbsp;brings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In support of that goal, my Administration is committed to&nbsp;expanding health centers and increasing access to their life-saving services. &nbsp;That is why we invested more than $7.6 billion to help health centers prevent and respond to COVID-19 and improve health care services &#8212; including over $1 billion for major infrastructure and renovation projects at health centers across the country through the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; I&nbsp;am also committed to doubling the Federal investment in community health centers to further expand access to care and&nbsp;make strides in our pursuit of health equity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During National Health Center Week, we recognize the importance of health centers and their staff who heal and strengthen our local communities. &nbsp;We salute their dedication and service.&nbsp; As our Nation builds back better, we commit to working together to bring about a stronger, healthier Nation for&nbsp;all.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim the week of August 8 through August 14, 2021, as&nbsp;National Health Center Week.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this sixth day of August, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/05/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-48/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:13 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning.&#160; And thanks for joining us.&#160; Dr. Walensky, Dr. Fauci, Dr. Murthy, and I will keep our comments brief this morning, so we can get to your questions. I’ll start with an update on the progress we&#8217;re making in our fight against the pandemic.&#160; Driven by the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:13 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; And thanks for joining us.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, Dr. Fauci, Dr. Murthy, and I will keep our comments brief this morning, so we can get to your questions.</p>



<p>I’ll start with an update on the progress we&#8217;re making in our fight against the pandemic.&nbsp; Driven by the more transmissible Delta variant, cases are continuing to rise.&nbsp; These cases are concentrated in communities with low vaccination rates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, over the past seven days, Florida and Texas have accounted for about one third of new cases and more than one third of new hospitalizations nationwide.</p>



<p>In seven states alone &#8212; Florida, Texas, Missouri, Arkansas, Louisiana, Alabama, Mississippi &#8212; states with some of the lowest vaccination rates account for about half of new cases and hospitalizations in the past week, despite making up less than a quarter of the U.S. population.</p>



<p>Vaccinations are the very best line of defense against COVID and the Delta variant, and we’re doing everything we can to keep getting shots in arms.&nbsp; And we are seeing results.</p>



<p>Over the past 24 hours, we’ve recorded 864,000 vaccinations &#8212; the highest in a day since July 3rd &#8212; and, importantly, 585,000 first shots &#8212; that&#8217;s the highest since July 1st.</p>



<p>For the fourth week in a row, we have increased the daily average number of Americans newly vaccinated, and importantly, we’re seeing the most significant increases in states with the highest case rates.</p>



<p>We have more than doubled the average number of people newly vaccinated each day over the past three weeks in the states with the highest case rates.&nbsp; In fact, Louisiana, Arkansas, Missouri, Alabama, Oklahoma, and Mississippi are now vaccinating people at a pace not seen since April.</p>



<p>And other states that have been lagging in vaccinations are also picking up their pace.&nbsp; Tennessee has seen a 90 percent increase in first shots over the past two weeks.&nbsp; Oklahoma, an 82 percent increase.&nbsp; And Georgia, a 66 percent increase in first shots over the past two weeks.</p>



<p>Clearly, Americans are seeing the impact of being unvaccinated and unprotected.&nbsp; And they respond by doing their part, rolling up their sleeve, and getting vaccinated.</p>



<p>In addition to getting more shots in arms, we are spurring action on vaccination requirements.&nbsp; Last week, the President announced new vaccination requirements for all federal workers and federal contractors.&nbsp; And he called for strong vaccination requirements from the private and public sectors to help protect lives and keep our economy strong.</p>



<p>Already, we&#8217;re seeing momentum in vaccination requirements across the country.&nbsp; Businesses know vaccinations are a way to keep their workers and customers safe, and to keep their doors open.</p>



<p>And today, Yelp is announcing a new feature that allows consumers to search for businesses with fully vaccinated workers or businesses that require proof of vaccination to enter the business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Small businesses across the country are stepping up.&nbsp; A recent study shows that half of America’s small businesses are likely to require their employees to be vaccinated.</p>



<p>Just this week, Saffron, a family-owned business in New Orleans, announced their staff is 100 percent vaccinated and they are requiring vaccinations or a negative test for all their customers.&nbsp; Tuesday was Saffron’s first night of service under their new rules, and the owner said the community response has been overwhelmingly positive.</p>



<p>At the same time, nearly 650 colleges and universities are already requiring on-campus employees and students to be vaccinated.&nbsp; And yesterday, leaders of America’s historically Black medical schools decided to mandate COVID-19 vaccines for all of their medical students.</p>



<p>Nationwide, over 100 hospital and healthcare systems, including the Department of Veterans Affairs, are requiring vaccinations for their healthcare workers.&nbsp; In fact, just this week, more than 30 healthcare employers, including Kaiser Permanente &#8212; one of the country’s largest &#8212; announced vaccination requirements for their healthcare workers.</p>



<p>So, America’s businesses, large and small; universities and medical schools; and many other institutions are stepping up on vaccination requirements.</p>



<p>And our message is quite simple: We support these vaccination requirements to protect workers, communities, and the country.</p>



<p>As we double down on getting more Americans vaccinated, we&#8217;re also stepping up our work to help states experiencing rising cases due to the Delta variant.&nbsp; Our COVID-19 Surge Response Teams are now working with 16 states to address their specific needs.</p>



<p>We have deployed hundreds of federal personnel to provide in-person support to address a range of needs, from increased testing, to getting shots in arms through mobile vaccination clinics, to encouraging more physicians to use antibody treatments, to helping states address hospital capacity issues.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: From the beginning, we have known that the virus is unpredictable.&nbsp; And we have been relentless &#8212; relentless &#8212; in our efforts to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; Our whole-of-government response will continue its relentless efforts to end this pandemic and deliver progress each and every day.</p>



<p>With that, let me turn it to Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; And thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; To keep things brief, I will simply give you an overview of the data and the state of where we are as a country.</p>



<p>Yesterday, CDC reported 103,444 &#8212; -45 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is about 89,463 cases per day.&nbsp; This represents an increase of 43 percent from the prior seven-day average.</p>



<p>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 7,348 per day, an increase of about 41 percent from the prior seven-day period.</p>



<p>And seven-day average daily deaths have also increased to 381 per day, an increase of more than 39 percent from the previous seven-day period.&nbsp; We saw 614 new deaths reported to CDC on Tuesday.</p>



<p>Eighty-three percent of our counties in the United States are experiencing moderate or high transmission with Delta variant continuing to be the predominant circulating virus.&nbsp;<br><br>Across the board, we are seeing increases in cases and hospitalizations in all age groups.&nbsp; Those at highest risk remain people who have not yet been vaccinated.&nbsp; Now is the time to get vaccinated.&nbsp; We know these vaccines are working and we know they save lives.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; I’d just like to spend a minute or two addressing a concern that I continue to hear regarding the speed with which the vaccines were developed.&nbsp; And this is usually among people who have a degree of vaccine hesitancy or reluctance to get vaccinated.<br><br>It really relates to two things that have gone on that people need to appreciate.&nbsp; One is the logistics and the investment in resources that was made, and others is the decades of basic and clinical research that antedated the development of the vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>What about the logistics and the resources?&nbsp; Generally, when you develop a vaccine &#8212; the thing that usually takes years to do &#8212; you do it in a sequential fashion.&nbsp; In other words, in order not to waste money, as it were, you do something preclinical, phase one, phase two, phase three, and then you start manufacturing the product.&nbsp; You do that sequentially because if the first one doesn&#8217;t succeed, you don&#8217;t want to go to the second, third, and fourth step.<br><br>Because of the wise investment in Operation Warp Speed &#8212; and we give credit to the Trump administration for doing this, particularly Secretary Alex Azar, who was an important component of that &#8212; what you did was make an investment to prepare for phase two and phase three, even before you knew that phase one worked or not, and to start manufacturing.&nbsp;<br><br>So when you do that, you make a major investment in resources.&nbsp; If the vaccine doesn&#8217;t work, you&#8217;ve lost a lot of money; if the vaccine does work, you save a lot of time.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what happened.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition, we had the clinical trial sites that we had built decades earlier for HIV and influenza, which were used to do the clinical trials.&nbsp;<br><br>And third, unfortunately for us, but fortunately for the vaccine trials, we were in the middle of the summer surge when the phase three trials were initiated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, next comes the decades of basic and clinical research, both in platform technology and immunogen.&nbsp; It didn&#8217;t start in January of 2020 when the sequence was put on a public database.&nbsp;<br><br>The data &#8212; the experiments on mRNA approach, which was funded predominantly by the NIH and also industry was involved, started decades earlier to develop an mRNA molecule that could be used as an immunogen for a vaccine.&nbsp; In addition, the vector-based approach, such as the one that J&amp;J did, was again done 10 or 20 years earlier with HIV.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the now very, very elegant work of the development of an immunogen that would be highly immunogenic to get the kind of high efficacy and effectiveness that we got was work done at the NIH Vaccine Research Center and by many of our grantees over the previous, literally, one to two decades.&nbsp;<br><br>So when people say, “I&#8217;m concerned that this went too fast,” it did not go too fast.&nbsp; It was a major investment, both in the logistics, the resources, and the clinical and basic research.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;ll hand it now back to you, Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Let me hand it over to Dr. Murthy.&nbsp; Dr. Murthy.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, thanks so much, Jeff.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s great to be with all of you again this morning.&nbsp;<br><br>I think we all know as cases have risen across the country due to the Delta variant, there are Americans who are wondering what this really means for them and their families.&nbsp; And today I want to emphasize one fact that remains true, and that is that the vaccines are working against the Delta variant.&nbsp; They are highly effective at preventing severe disease, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re also effective at reducing the overall risk of infection.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, a recent study in the New England Journal of Medicine found that two doses of the mRNA vaccines are 88 percent effective against symptomatic COVID-19 infection with the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>So, breakthrough infections in fully vaccinated people are the exception, not the rule.&nbsp; And when they do happen, the vast majority are mild and asymptomatic &#8212; mild or asymptomatic.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, this reflects the reality that we have the most effective tool we need to keep us safe and end this pandemic, and that is a vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>And recognizing the importance of continuing to push our efforts to vaccinate the nation, yesterday, we brought together the six living former surgeons general of the United States &#8212; from the Clinton, Bush, Obama, and Trump administrations &#8212; to discuss our public health COVID-19 response, with equity being at the forefront of our conversation.&nbsp;<br><br>It was a historic meeting for a historic moment.&nbsp; And these former surgeons general are public health leaders who have been friends, mentors, and partners to me in my years as Surgeon General.&nbsp; And we spoke about their concerns about health misinformation, about the importance of ensuring that communities of color and rural areas aren&#8217;t left behind in the vaccination effort, and the power also of engaging trusted community-based organizations in vaccinations.&nbsp;<br><br>We will continue to work together in the months ahead to ensure we continue to increase vaccination rates across the country with equity as our guide.&nbsp;<br><br>And finally, this gathering of surgeons general reflected the diversity of our nation, and it was emblematic of what we have to do together to defeat the virus.&nbsp; As SGs, we came together from different backgrounds, serving under different political administrations to work together on a path toward ending this pandemic.&nbsp; And we all share the belief that science and public health are what will help us protect our nation from this pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>So thanks for your time today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll turn it back over to Jeff for Q&amp;A.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Doctors.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go ahead and open it up for questions.&nbsp; First question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; First question, let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; We know that boosters are still under consideration, but there&#8217;s more openness to acting on them for immunocompromised people faster, so can you tell us when can immunocompromised people expect those boosters will be available? &nbsp;And are there any updates?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yes, thank you for that question.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve said, and continue to say, immunocompromised individuals are vulnerable.&nbsp; The reason is that it is clear now from the observational data that was made that they do not make, in general, with some exceptions, but in general, do not make an adequate response that we felt &#8212; feel would be adequately protected.&nbsp; So, in this regard, it is extremely important for us to move to get those individuals their boosters.</p>



<p>And we are now working on that, and we&#8217;ll make that be implemented as quickly as possible because, for us and for the individuals involved, it is a very high priority.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Weijia at CBS.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for taking my question.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky have both warned that the virus may mutate and perhaps into a strain that is powerful enough to evade the vaccine.&nbsp; Is there any way to gauge how long before the virus overtakes the vaccine?&nbsp; And so we understand what that means for the vaccine, is there a way to tweak it in that situation in order to give us protection?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Why don’t we start with you, Dr. Fauci, and then Dr. Walensky if you have anything to add?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yes, there is a very, very longstanding tenet in virology that viruses cannot mutate unless they replicate.&nbsp; And so, the easiest way to prevent the scenario that you&#8217;re proposing could happen would be to get as many people vaccinated as quickly as we possibly can to not allow the virus to continue to circulate in the community, giving it ample time to mutate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, not every mutation is going to result in a functional change, but every once in a while, you do get a series or a constellation of mutations that do that, and you get a functional change the way we have seen with the Delta variant, which functionally changed because it became significantly more able to transmit.</p>



<p>We have within our power to prevent that.&nbsp; And you prevent it by not allowing the virus to freely circulate, finding vulnerable targets.&nbsp; You protect the vulnerable targets, who are unvaccinated people, by vaccinating them.&nbsp; And when you do so, you do a very, very strong blocking of the evolution of variants that could be problematic.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Sharon LaFraniere at New York Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Many experts say that the falling antibody levels that Pfizer and, today, Moderna cite as evidence that booster shots are needed is not convincing because people may still be protected even with those.&nbsp; If that&#8217;s so, what is the right signal?&nbsp; Is it vaccinated people ending up sick enough to be in hospitals, and can the government wait for that kind of evidence before making a decision?</p>



<p>And then, secondly, I wanted to ask: What are the chances that the Delta variant will burn out, so to speak, here in a month or so, like in India and the UK?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, first.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, you know, we’re going to make the decision about booster shots based on a compilation of evidence, one of which will most definitely be the immune responses, as you know.&nbsp; But that is not necessarily known to be a perfect correlate &#8212; the antibody responses.&nbsp; Our immune system also has T cell responses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is going to be a combination of evidence, both of neutralizing antibody data, as well as clinical trial data, as well as our cohort data that monitor the safety and &#8212; or the effectiveness of our vaccines in many different populations across the country &#8212; tens of thousands of people, essential workers, healthcare providers, long-term care facilities, people who&#8217;ve been vaccinated early in the process. &nbsp;And it will be a combination of all of that evidence that helps inform our booster strategy.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, the question of the case count and quote &#8212;</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Go ahead, please.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Right, so, what you&#8217;re asking is, when are we going to turn around this acceleration that we&#8217;re currently experiencing with Delta.</p>



<p>There are two ways you do that.&nbsp; You do it in the immediate sense, right now, by mitigation.&nbsp; And mitigation are the kinds of things you&#8217;ve heard from the recommendations of the CDC regarding masking, by regarding avoiding situations &#8212; crowded situations where you can have the increased capability of the virus to spread.</p>



<p>The ultimate endgame of all this is vaccination.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we continue to harp on that in a very, very proactive way; that if we continue to vaccinate and we get that 93 million people who are eligible for vaccinations, who have not been vaccinated &#8212; if we do that, in the immediate, intermediate, and long term, and do the mitigation right now, we will turn the Delta surge around.&nbsp; I will guarantee you that that will happen, if we do what I just outlined.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Kaitlan Collins, CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Several of you and the President have repeatedly cited figures saying that 99 percent of those who die from COVID-19 are unvaccinated and 95 percent, around that, are hospital- &#8212; who are hospitalized are unvaccinated.&nbsp; With the Delta variant, do you still stand by these numbers, and do you have government data to back them up?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yes, thank you for that question, Kaitlan.&nbsp;&nbsp;So those data were data that were from analyses in several states from January through June and didn&#8217;t reflect the data that we have now from the Delta variant.&nbsp; We are actively working to update those in the context of the Delta variant.</p>



<p>I do want to reiterate, though, that based on the data we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; and we don&#8217;t have fully updated numbers &#8212; universally, as we look at our hospitalizations and as we look at our deaths, they are overwhelmingly unvaccinated people.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith at NPR.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s some reporting out there that the working groups that are looking at reopening some international travel are making plans to require vaccination for international visitors.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering how that would work &#8212; whether it would be simply an attestation with federal workers, or whether there would be a more rigorous form of vaccine verification.</p>



<p>And on vaccine verification: You talk about that restaurant and other businesses that are requiring their customers be vaccinated.&nbsp; How are these businesses supposed to do vaccine verification?&nbsp; Is it Wild West out there, or is &#8212; are there guidelines?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t I take the first question on travel, and, Dr. Murthy, vaccine verifications.</p>



<p>In terms of travel &#8212; and I&#8217;m glad you ask that question &#8212; the administration certainly understands the importance of international travel.&nbsp; And given where we&#8217;re &#8212; where we are today, as Dr. Walensky showed us earlier, on the prevalence of the Delta variant, the United States will maintain the existing travel restrictions at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, we do have, as you alluded to, agency working groups that are developing plans for when we do open travel, how do we do it in a consistent and safe way.&nbsp; And part of that planning is a phased approach that foreign nationals traveling to the United States may &#8212; there&#8217;s still policy work being done here &#8212; may need to have some type of a vaccine requirement, but that&#8217;s not a decision at this point.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the paths that&#8217;s being looked at and considered, but there are &#8212; there are alternative paths being looked at, at the same time.</p>



<p>So, the interagency working groups are currently developing a policy process, and we will be ready when it is the right time to consider reopening travel.&nbsp; And that&#8217;ll be guided, as always, by the science and the public health.</p>



<p>Dr. Murthy.</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And let me just ask: Can you repeat this specific question you had on the verification?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; I have &#8212; I had to &#8212; I had trouble unmuting myself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; It’s okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The question is: You guys have talked about restaurants or other private businesses having only vaccinated customers.&nbsp; How is a mom-and-pop shop supposed to know how to do vaccine verification?</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s good question.&nbsp; Well, the good news is that we have seen a significant movement in the private sector to develop, essentially, vaccine verification efforts.</p>



<p>We know this is not something that the federal government is leading, but we are happy to see the private sector leading and taking initiative on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, I think as more &#8212; this is going to be increasingly important because we know that more institutions are considering vaccine requirements.&nbsp; We certainly have seen that in the healthcare system.&nbsp; The vaccine requirements for healthcare workers is being adopted by more and more institutions, and we expect that that will continue.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR: &nbsp;Maureen Groppe at USA Today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the federal assistance being offered to states that are hit hard by COVID.&nbsp; At the &#8212; one of the White House briefings this week, Jen was asked if the offers had been accepted in Florida and Texas, and she called that a, quote, “discussion.”</p>



<p>Is there any update on that &#8212; on whether Florida and Texas want any of the help that the administration is offering?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; We are working with 16 states, and I believe there are conversations with Florida.&nbsp; I know there are conversations with the state of Florida, and I believe there are some conversations with Texas too.&nbsp; But that &#8212; let me &#8212; let me come back and verify that.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re working with 16 states at this point on testing, on increased vaccination through mobile clinics, the increased use of therapeutics, also assessing and helping out on hospital capacity.&nbsp; So, 16 states across a whole range of areas.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, we have time for one more question.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll go to Meg Tirrell at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; This is a question for Dr. Walensky, I think.&nbsp; Last week, in the slides, we saw from the CDC &#8212; the CDC noted that Delta may cause more severe disease than older strains and cited some evidence from other countries.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: Does CDC think the data show it does cause more severe disease?&nbsp; And also, how are you looking at the risk it poses to children?&nbsp; Do you see more severe disease from Delta for them?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for that question, Meg.&nbsp; Certainly, in that slide deck, there were some early preliminary studies that suggest that Delta may potentially cause severe disease.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We continue to monitor this not just in adults, but also in children.&nbsp; But I do want to highlight a couple of things that continue to confound some of the data, and that is we have enormous burden now of disease, so exposures are much higher.</p>



<p>And the mitigation strategies that were used last summer, even in the winter, have not been employed in many of these areas that we are having surges right now.</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s &#8212; we&#8217;re working to understand the differences between exposures and as well as the severity of disease, and working to confirm those preliminary data that might suggest so.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good.&nbsp; Well, thank you, and look forward to briefing early next week.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:40 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COVID-Press-Briefing_5August2021_for-transcript-1.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COVID-Press-Briefing_5August2021_for-transcript-1.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the President and Vice President’s Meeting with Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/readout-of-the-president-and-vice-presidents-meeting-with-asian-american-native-hawaiian-and-pacific-islander-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:57:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President and Vice President met with 13 Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA &#38; NHPI) leaders representing the rich diversity of the AA &#38; NHPI communities to discuss a wide range of issues, including the Administration’s Build Back Better Agenda. The conversation focused on the importance of combating the rise in anti-Asian hate crimes, economic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President and Vice President met with 13 Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA &amp; NHPI) leaders representing the rich diversity of the AA &amp; NHPI communities to discuss a wide range of issues, including the Administration’s Build Back Better Agenda. The conversation focused on the importance of combating the rise in anti-Asian hate crimes, economic opportunity, commitment to equity, protecting the sacred right to vote, and immigration reform. During the meeting, the President and Vice President reiterated their promise to work together to ensure the needs of the diaspora of the AA &amp; NHPI communities are heard, uplifted and met. The meeting also commemorated nine years since the horrific 2019 Sikh Temple mass shooting in Oak Creek, Wisconsin. The President and Vice President restated their support for a pathway to citizenship for Dreamers, farm workers, TPS holders, and essential workers through reconciliation, pledging to work with the AA &amp; NHPI community on immigration reform. The President and Vice President acknowledged the AA &amp; NHPI community record turnout in civic engagement and vowed to continue working to strengthen our democracy and the protection of voting rights.</p>



<p><em>AA &amp; NHPI Leaders:</em></p>



<ul><li>Seema Agnani, Executive Director, National Coalition for Asian Pacific American Community Development (National CAPACD)</li><li>Christine Chen, Executive Director, Asian and Pacific Islander American Vote (APIAVote)</li><li>Quyen Dinh, Executive Director, Southeast Asia Resource Action Center (SEARAC)</li><li>Satjeet Kaur, Executive Director, Sikh Coalition</li><li>Kiran Kaur Gill, Executive Director, Sikh American Legal Defense and Education Fund (SALDEF)</li><li>Kūhiō Lewis, President &amp; CEO, Council for Native Hawaiian Advancement (CNHA)</li><li>Neil Makhija, Executive Director, Indian American Impact</li><li>Gregg Orton, National Director, National Council of Asian Pacific Americans (NCAPA)</li><li>Tavae Samuelu, Executive Director, Empowering Pacific Islander Communities (EPIC)</li><li>Chiling Tong, President &amp; CEO, Asian/Pacific Islander American Chamber of Commerce and Entrepreneurship (National ACE)</li></ul>



<ul><li>Alvina Yeh, Executive Director, Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance (APALA)</li><li>Sung Yeon Choimorrow, Executive Director, National Asian Pacific American Women’s Forum (NAPAWF)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Signing of H.R. 3325, Awarding Congressional Gold Medals to Those Who Protected the U.S. Capitol on January&#160;6</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/05/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-h-r-3325-awarding-congressional-gold-medals-to-those-who-protected-the-u-s-capitol-on-january-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26345</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 5:18 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Thank you, Vice President Harris.&#160;&#160;Folks, not even during the Civil War did insurrectionists breach the Capitol of the United States of America, the citadel of our democracy &#8212; not even then.&#160; But on January the 6th, 2021, they did.&#160; They did.&#160;&#160;A mob of extremists and terrorists launched&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>5:18 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Thank you, Vice President Harris.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, not even during the Civil War did insurrectionists breach the Capitol of the United States of America, the citadel of our democracy &#8212; not even then.&nbsp; But on January the 6th, 2021, they did.&nbsp; They did.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>A mob of extremists and terrorists launched a violent and deadly assault on the People’s House and the sacred ritual to certify a free and fair election.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It wasn’t dissent.&nbsp; It wasn’t debate.&nbsp; It wasn’t democracy.<br>&nbsp;<br>It was insurrection.&nbsp; It was riot and mayhem.&nbsp; It was radical and chaotic.&nbsp; And it was unconstitutional.&nbsp; And maybe most important, it was fundamentally un-American &#8212; an existential threat and a test of whether our democracy could survive, whether it could overcome lies and overcome the fury of a few who were seeking to thwart the will of the many.<br>&nbsp;<br>But while the attack on our values and our votes shocked and saddened the nation, our democracy did survive.&nbsp; It did.&nbsp; Truth defeated lies.&nbsp; We did overcome.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s because of the women and men of the U.S. Capitol Police, the Washington D.C. Metropolitan Police Department, and other law enforcement officials who we honor today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Speaker Pelosi, who led the effort in the House; Senators Klobuchar and Blunt, the co-sponsors of the legislation in the Senate; and to all my colleagues &#8212; Pat Leahy and House members as well that are here: Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, I&#8217;m signing into law the bill you sent me that awards the Congressional Gold Medal to the United States Capitol Police, the Washington D.C. Metropolitan Police Department, and other law enforcement for their service in defense of our democracy on January the 6th.<br>&nbsp;<br>To all of them, on behalf of a grateful nation, thank you, thank you, thank you for protecting our Capitol.&nbsp; Maybe even more importantly, for protecting our Constitution and saving the lives of duly elected members of the Senate and the House and their staffs.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In these moments when we&#8217;re still debating &#8212; these were tragic hours back then &#8212; you stood in the breach.&nbsp; You did your duty &#8212; a duty to defend the Constitution of the United States against all enemies, foreign and domestic.&nbsp; The events that transpired were surprising but not your character or your courage, Chief, and all your men and women.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I didn’t grow up with any of you, but I know you.&nbsp; You’re just like all the women and men I grew up with &#8212; particularly, at that time, it was men &#8212; in Scranton and Claymont, places where &#8212; the neighborhood I lived in &#8212; you became a cop, a firefighter, or a priest.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I wasn’t qualified for any of them &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; so here I am.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, all kidding aside, I got to know you.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the same ones, after a ballgame in a visiting field, that come walking out of the gym if you won, and you may get jumped by the other team or their supporters.&nbsp; You may be all by yourself &#8212; the only one standing there when you watch six people jump one of our teammates.&nbsp; What the hell would you do?&nbsp; You&#8217;d jump in.&nbsp; You&#8217;d jump in, knowing you&#8217;re going to get the hell beat of you too.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Police officers are not what you do; it&#8217;s who you are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I got to know you after 36 years in the Senate, 8 years as Vice President.&nbsp; You&#8217;re always there.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s not a joke.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not some hyperbole to suggest “duty, honor, service.”&nbsp; That&#8217;s who you are.&nbsp; That&#8217;s who your dad was.&nbsp; It&#8217;s who your dad was.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And America owes you a debt we can never fully repay.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I know receiving this award is bittersweet.&nbsp; On that day, more than 140 law enforcement officers suffered physical injuries, an untold number suffering emotional toll.&nbsp; Fifteen of you were hospitalized and others were lost forever.&nbsp; May their souls rest in peace and rise in glory.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know each time you put on that shield in the morning or whenever you show for work, your families wonder whether they’re going to get a call that day &#8212; a call they don&#8217;t want to receive &#8212; hoping you come home safely.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it breaks my heart.&nbsp; It breaks the heart of the nation to remember that you were assaulted by thousands of violent insurrectionists at the Capitol of the United States of America.<br>&nbsp;<br>Jill and I would never have thought we&#8217;d have to join you in the Capitol Rotunda not once, but twice.&nbsp; Once to hiron [sic] &#8212; to honor Officer Brian Sicknick, who lost his life.&nbsp; And a second time to honor Officer Billy Evans, who lost his defending the Capitol as well.&nbsp; Both gave the full measure of their devotion to the country at the United States Capitol.<br>&nbsp;<br>Their families are here today.&nbsp; I know from similar &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes, we should clap for the families.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I know, like others may know, from personal experience, getting that phone call.&nbsp; It&#8217;s nice to be honored and have those who you lost remembered, but it&#8217;s tough to be here because it brings back everything like it happened 10 minutes ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I offer you not only our condolences, but recognize your courage, the courage of your children.&nbsp; And you have our most profound gratitude.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, the fallen, in my view, are casualties of a struggle, literally, for the soul of America &#8212; a struggle that they didn&#8217;t start, a struggle we didn&#8217;t seek, and a struggle that, by the grace of God, we&#8217;ll win.<br>&nbsp;<br>As I said, I know this is a bittersweet moment.&nbsp; As proud of Brian and Billy as you are, it still brings back pain &#8212; the moment it happened.<br>&nbsp;<br>And also, we also offer our prayers to the families of the Capitol Police Officer, Howard Liebengood.&nbsp; Those who have been around a while, we knew his dad.&nbsp; We knew his dad well.&nbsp; He was Secretary of the United States &#8212; Sergeant of Arms of the United States Senate.<br>We also pray for the families of the Metro Police Officer, Jeffrey Smith.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For anyone out there facing trauma, for anyone still struggling, please know there is help available.<br>&nbsp;<br>My fellow Americans, the tragedy of that day deserves the truth above all else.&nbsp; We cannot allow history to be rewritten.&nbsp; We cannot allow the heroism of these officers to be forgotten.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have to understand what happened &#8212; the honest and unvarnished truth.&nbsp; We have to face it.&nbsp; That’s what great nations do, and we are a great nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the past weeks and months, we’ve heard the officers themselves &#8212; some of whom are here today &#8212; describe what happened: the threats, the violence, the savageness.<br>&nbsp;<br>When asked what he was fighting for, Officer Hodges, who is here today, stated it eloquently &#8212; one word: &#8220;Democracy.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>My fellow Americans, let’s remember what this was all about.&nbsp; It was a violent attempt to overturn the will of the American people; to seek power at all costs; to replace the ballot with brute force; to destroy, not to build.<br>&nbsp;<br>Without democracy, nothing is possible.&nbsp; With it, everything is.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my fellow Americans, we must all do our part to perfect &#8212; perfect and to preserve our democracy.&nbsp; It requires people of goodwill and courage to stand up to the hate, the lies, the extremism that led to this vicious attack.<br>&nbsp;<br>It requires all of us working together &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, independents &#8212; on behalf of the common good to restore decency, honor, and respect for our system of government.<br>&nbsp;<br>And above all, it requires all of us to remember who we are at our best as a nation, as we see in the law enforcement officers who are here today &#8212; the best of our nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Congressional Gold Medal awards today will be housed in four locations.&nbsp; Two medals will be displayed at the U.S. Capitol Police Department in Washing- &#8212; and the Washington D.C. Metropolitan Police Department so that every morning, as you officers walk by, seeing those medals, they&#8217;ll remember the heroism of their colleagues and the importance of their work.<br>&nbsp;<br>The third medal will be displayed at the Smithsonian Museum with a plaque honoring all law enforcement that protected the Capitol on January 6th, so all visitors can understand what happened that day.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the fourth one will be displayed at the Capitol itself, to remind all who served and currently serve there and all who visit the honor and the service of those who protect and preserve all of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will now ask Speaker Pelosi, if she&#8217;s able &#8212; not able, willing &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and Senator Klobuchar and Senator Blunt, Chief Contee and Chief Manger, and the other officers here today to join me as I sign this bill into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops and all those who serve watch over our democracy.<br>&nbsp;<br>(The bill is signed.)<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>5:40 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Strengthening American Leadership on Clean Cars and&#160;Trucks</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/05/remarks-by-president-biden-on-strengthening-american-leadership-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 3:26 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Please, everybody, sit down &#8212; please, please, please.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; AUDIENCE MEMBERS:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I &#8212; before I begin, let me start with something &#8212; I apologize &#8212; more somber.&#160; I &#8212; I learned a couple of hours ago, when my staff came in,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>3:26 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Please, everybody, sit down &#8212; please, please, please.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBERS:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I &#8212; before I begin, let me start with something &#8212; I apologize &#8212; more somber.&nbsp; I &#8212; I learned a couple of hours ago, when my staff came in, that a close friend of mine &#8212; and I think of many of you as well &#8212; Rich Trumka died today from a heart attack.</p>



<p>The reason I was a few minutes late coming out &#8212; and I apologize for that &#8212; I was talking to his wife and to his son, who called.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He wasn&#8217;t just a great labor leader, he was a friend.&nbsp; And he was a friend of yours too, Debbie, I think.&nbsp; And he was someone I could confide in.&nbsp; And you knew whatever he said he&#8217;d do, he would do.&nbsp; It was simple, Tommy; you knew him well as well.&nbsp; He was always there.</p>



<p>He was an American worker.&nbsp; Always fighting for working people, protecting their wages, their safety, their pensions, and their ability to build a middle-class life.</p>



<p>I’ve also believed that the middle class built America, but I know who built the middle class: unions.&nbsp; Unions built the middle class.&nbsp; There is no doubt that Rich Trumka helped build unions all across this country.</p>



<p>My heart goes out to Barbara and Rich Jr. and the grandkids.&nbsp; And I might point out that, you know, I used to always kid him &#8212; he was from soft coal country; I was from hard coal country.&nbsp; We used to have this thing about &#8212; you know, he used to be president of the United Mine Workers and that&#8217;s how he got started.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, let&#8217;s &#8212; let me now turn to today’s events &#8212; event.</p>



<p>I want to thank Bernie for the introduction and for being part of the best autoworkers in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, Ray Curry, President of the UAW.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re here, Ray, I was in with you &#8212; it&#8217;s good to see you, pal.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I also want to thank the leaders of the “Big Three” companies for being here today.&nbsp; Mary Barra &#8212; she&#8217;s with General Motors.&nbsp; She &#8212; I want to tell you &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I think she&#8217;s one of the reasons we&#8217;re here today.&nbsp; We had a long discussion on a Zoom call with a bunch of labor leaders and other &#8212; other major business leaders, and she made a commitment and she&#8217;s keeping it.&nbsp; Thank you very much, Madam Chair.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jim Farley of Ford.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, my dad was in the automobile business.&nbsp; He sold Fords for a while, but mostly General Motors projects for &#8212; products.&nbsp; But you see that sucker over there?&nbsp; Zero to sixty in 4.1 seconds.&nbsp; It&#8217;s all electric.&nbsp; I tell you what.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to say publicly, I have a commitment from Mary when they make the first electric Corvette, I get to drive it.&nbsp; Right, Mary?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not kidding.&nbsp; And my entire Secret Service detail went, &#8220;Oh my God.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go.&#8221; &nbsp;</p>



<p>And Mark Stewart of Stellantis.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, I &#8212; Mark, we used to have one of your big plants in my state.&nbsp; And as &#8212; as the man I&#8217;m about to recognize &#8212; you know, a special thanks to all the member of Congress here, but I want to pay particular recognition to my chairman, my buddy &#8212; we served together for years &#8212; Tommy Carper.&nbsp; Tom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know that &#8212; I kid my Michigan friends, but, you know, I &#8212; I just want you to know &#8212; say to Senators Heinrich and Markey and Whitehouse and Padilla and, you know, Duckworth &#8212; and I&#8217;m leaving some folks out, I&#8217;m sure.&nbsp; Representative Kathy Castor.&nbsp; You know, and the Michigan delegation that&#8217;s here today: Debbie Stabenow; Senator Gary Peters; Congresswoman Debbie Dingell, who is automobiles; and Dan Kildee.</p>



<p>But I want you all to know &#8212; I remind the Michigan delegation of this: It used to be, when I was first got elected, Deb &#8212; and I used to tell your husband this well &#8212; we had a higher percentage of autoworkers in Delaware than any state in the Union, including &#8212; including Michigan.&nbsp; Now, the fact we that we had a very small population and we &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and we had almost 100,000 autoworkers in our states, counting the Autolite and others had something to do with it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I &#8212; I just want to be very straightforward.&nbsp; You know, UAW “brung me to the dance,” as they say.</p>



<p>And I also know we’re missing someone truly special and a dear friend of all of us &#8212; Senator Carl Levin, who passed away last week.&nbsp; Carl and I served together for 30 years in the United States Senate together.&nbsp; He was one of the most &#8212; and I think all my colleagues who knew him will attest to this &#8212; one of the most honorable people, most decent people I’ve not only served with but I’ve ever known.<br><br>He was a tireless champion of the American worker and the iconic American automobile industry.&nbsp; And so he embodied everything that his beloved Michigan and our country represents: respect, dignity, pride –- pride in the nation and pride in what we built.</p>



<p>And so, today, labor and industry, state and local leaders are all working together to write the next chapter of the American story.</p>



<p>As I’ve said before, we’re in competition with China and many other nations for the 21st century.&nbsp; To win, we’re going to have to make sure the future will be made in America.</p>



<p>You know, back in May, I toured the Ford plant, as I mentioned &#8212; a state-of-the-art facility in Dearborn &#8212; where the UAW workers like Bernie are building the first-ever all-electric Ford 150 [F-150].&nbsp; And as I said, the best part is, I got to drive it.&nbsp; It’s incredible, just like the other vehicles that are behind me today.&nbsp; They’re a vision of the future that is now beginning to happen, a future of the automobile industry that is electric &#8212; battery electric, plug-in hybrid electric, fuel cell electric.&nbsp; It’s electric, and there’s no turning back.</p>



<p>The question is whether we’ll lead or fall behind in the race for the future.&nbsp; It’s whether we’ll build these vehicles and the batteries that got them to where they are in the United States &#8212; here in the United States, or we’re going to have to rely on other countries for those batteries.&nbsp; Whether or not the jobs to build these vehicles and batteries are good-paying union jobs &#8212; jobs with benefits, jobs that’s going to sustain continued growth of the middle class.&nbsp; They have to be.&nbsp; They have to be made here in America.</p>



<p>Right now, China is leading the race, and is one of the largest and fastest-growing electric vehicle markets in the world.</p>



<p>And a key part of the electric vehicle &#8212; to state the obvious &#8212; is the battery.&nbsp; And right now, 80 percent of the manufacturing capacity for these batteries is done in China.</p>



<p>And here’s the deal: It’s not that China batter- &#8212; it’s not China’s battery technology that’s much more innovative than anyone else’s.&nbsp; Remember, our national labs in America, our universities, our automakers led in the development of this technology.&nbsp; We led in the development of this technology.&nbsp; And there’s no reason why we can’t reclaim that leadership and lead again.&nbsp; But we just have to move, and we have to move fast.</p>



<p>You know, when Barack and I were in office &#8212; President Obama and I were in office &#8212; that’s what we were doing.&nbsp;<br><br>In 2009, the automobile industry was flat on its back.&nbsp; We were told that we’d never be able to sell American-made cars at the same rate as we did before.&nbsp; But we didn’t listen to the naysayers.&nbsp; We even had some &#8212; in all &#8212; in both parties who didn’t think we should, quote, “bail out” the industry, if you remember.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, we bet on the American worker.&nbsp; And we extended a lifeline.&nbsp; And they stepped up and made sacrifices to do it, and they saved more than &#8212; we saved more than a million jobs in the process.</p>



<p>Working with the auto industry, we set fuel efficiency standards and provided incentives for folks to buy fuel-efficient vehicles.</p>



<p>Through the Recovery Act, we made the largest investment in clean energy and battery technology ever made.&nbsp; And then the previous administration came along into office, and they rolled back the standards we set.</p>



<p>Despite bipartisan support for consumer incentives, they also let the federal tax credit expire, penalizing autoworkers who were, at the time, selling the most electric vehicles in the world &#8212; in the United States.</p>



<p>They announced infrastru- &#8212; when we &#8212; they announced infrastructure week, they did it for every week for four years, and not once got anything done.&nbsp; Not once.</p>



<p>Folks, the rest of the world is moving ahead, and we’ve just got to step up: government, labor, and industry working together &#8212; what you&#8217;re seeing here today.&nbsp; We have a playbook, and it’s going to work.</p>



<p>Today, I’m announcing steps we’re taking to set a new pace for electric vehicles.</p>



<p>First, I&#8217;m following through on the campaign commitment to reverse the previous administration’s short-sighted rollback of vehicle emissions and efficiency standards.&nbsp; I’m doing so and &#8212; with the support of the auto industry &#8212; the automobile industry.</p>



<p>Today, the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Transportation are unveiling proposals to do just that.</p>



<p>These agencies are beginning to work on the next round of standards for a broad class of vehicles &#8212; for cars, SUVs,&nbsp;pick-up trucks, medium- and heavy-duty vehicles.</p>



<p>Importantly, we have announcements today from automakers representing nearly the entire auto industry market who have pos- &#8212; who have positioned around the ambition that of 40 to 50 percent of all vehicles sold by 2030 in America being electric.</p>



<p>This is a big deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But to unlock the full potential, we have to keep investing in our workers and our manufacturing capacity.&nbsp; And that’s what our Build Back Better plan is all about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s about leveraging once-in-a-generation investments and a whole-of-government effort to lift up American autoworkers</p>



<p>and strengthen &#8212; and strengthen the American leadership</p>



<p>in the world in the clean car technology &#8212; trucks &#8212; not just cars, but trucks as well, and buses.</p>



<p>You know, that’s why, today, I’m signing an executive order setting out a target of 50 percent of all passenger vehicles sold by 2030 will be electric and set into motion an all-out effort.</p>



<p>That’s why, along with the members of Congress here today,</p>



<p>we’re working around the clock on the Build Back Better plan, which does three critical things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, it transforms our infrastructure.&nbsp; We’re going to put Americans to work modernizing our roads, our highways, our ports, our airports, rail, and transit systems.</p>



<p>You know, that included putting IBEW members and other union workers to work installing a national network of</p>



<p>500,000 charging stations along our roads and highways and at our homes and our apartments.</p>



<p>Two, we’re going to boost our manufacturing capacity.&nbsp; The Build Back Better plan invests in new rooted [sic] facilities &#8212; excuse me, new and retooled facilities; and employs workers</p>



<p>with good-paying wages, good jobs.; and grants &#8212; the grants that kickstart new battery and parts production; loans and tax credits to boost manufacturing of these clean vehicles.</p>



<p>And our Build Back pletter [sic] &#8212; Build Back Better plan</p>



<p>makes the largest investment in research and development in generations.</p>



<p>This will help innovate, manufacture, and build the supply chains for batteries, semi-conductors, and those small computer chips that electric trucks and cars that are going to be even more reliant upon as we move forward.</p>



<p>Never again should we be in the situation we face today with a semiconductor shortage.&nbsp; And we know these kinds of federal investments &#8212; we know that they work.</p>



<p>It was the Defense Department and NASA that got the modern semi-conductor industry on its feet decades ago.&nbsp; Our own Department of Energy pioneered and transformed the battery industry where Barack and I &#8212; when we went into off- &#8212; when we were in office.</p>



<p>And with the help of the Recovery Act grants and loans, battery prices dropped 85 percent because we were forward-looking.</p>



<p>We need that same mindset today.</p>



<p>Thirdly, support of consumers and fleets.&nbsp; That means purchasing incentives for consumers to buy clean vehicles,</p>



<p>union-made right here in America, like the ones championed by Debbie Stabenow and Ron Wyden in the Senate, which provides</p>



<p>$7,500 basic credit, $2,500 credit for vehicles made in America, and an additional $2,500 credit for union-made vehicles.</p>



<p>That means spurring demand by converting the federal government’s enormous fleet of vehicles &#8212; we have over 600,000 vehi- &#8212; a lot of vehicles &#8212; 600,000, I should say &#8212; into an all American-made clean vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that’s what we’re going to do.&nbsp; As we &#8212; as we roll out and get rid of the existing fleet, we’re going to support the electric transit system as well and the electric school buses.</p>



<p>Look, and there’s one other thing we have in our playbook that will help us outcompete other nations: The American worker.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;The American worker.&nbsp; I really believe this, and I know you guys do too.&nbsp; American workers are our ace in the deck.</p>



<p>Now, I know many of you watching at home are like the folks I grew up with in Scranton and Claymont, Delaware.&nbsp; They feel left out, left behind in an economy and in an industry that’s rapidly changing.&nbsp; I get it.&nbsp; I understand it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we’re going to leave no one behind.&nbsp; Nearly 90 percent of the jobs created in our infrastructure plan do not require a bachelor’s degree.&nbsp; And when we invest in our infrastructure, we’re going to buy American products, American materials, and services from American businesses made in America, by American workers.</p>



<p>And we’re going to do everything in our power to encourage and protect the right of workers to unionize and collectively bargain.&nbsp; The bottom line is, we are proposing a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America.</p>



<p>That’s what it’s going to be.&nbsp; And we need automakers and other companies to keep investing in America.&nbsp; We need them not to take the benefits of our public investments and expand electric vehicles and battery manufacturing production abroad.&nbsp; We need you to deepen your partnership with the UAW, continue to pay good wages, support local communities across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why I’m so proud the UAW is standing here today as well.&nbsp; It’s why I am proud that the three largest employers are sitting here and their sights are set not only on electric vehicles, but on expansion &#8212; expanding union jobs, expanding the middle class.&nbsp; It matters.</p>



<p>You know, in the spring, I kept my commitment to convene leaders of all the major economies in the world on &#8212; it was not in person, but we did it &#8212; we did it on a Zoom call with a whole bunch of folks &#8212;&nbsp; including the heads of state of China, India, Japan, the European Union &#8212; for a meeting hosted in the White House on the most consequential issues facing the world, and the agreement was, it’s the climate crisis.</p>



<p>And I made clear &#8212; I made clear what I’ve long believed when I think of &#8212; when I think of the climate crisis: Beyond the devastation to the lives and livelihoods and the health of our very planet, when I hear “climate,” I think “jobs” &#8212; good-paying union jobs.</p>



<p>I wanted the world to see there was a consensus that all &#8212; that we’re at an inflection point in world history.&nbsp; If we act to save the planet, we can also come out of it better.&nbsp; We can create millions of good-paying jobs that generate significant economic growth and opportunity, to raise the standard of living for people not only here, but around the world.</p>



<p>But I also wanted to put the world on notice: America is back.&nbsp; America is back.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re in the competition for the 21st century &#8212; the future that will be built right here in America.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: Our economy is recovering.&nbsp; In six months, we’re seeing the fastest job growth on record at this point in any administration in history, the fastest economic growth in nearly 40 years.&nbsp; And we’ve shown each other and the world that there’s no quit in America.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; And that it’s never, ever, ever been a good bet to bet against America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are the United States of America.&nbsp; There is not a single, solitary thing &#8212; nothing &#8212; beyond our capacity to get done, if we and when we do it together.&nbsp; But we have to act.&nbsp; And that’s what we are doing today.</p>



<p>And again, I want to thank the CEOs of the automobile companies, and I also want to thank all the autoworkers.&nbsp; Thank you all for being here today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now I am going to sign the executive order, but I’d like to invite my congressional colleagues to come up &#8212; if they’re willing to stand behind me here when we do this &#8212; and others who know they’re supposed to come on up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>Now, when I sign &#8212; it’s so bright &#8212; when I sign this executive order, usually I am able to give a pen to all the folks who are a part of it.&nbsp; I’ve got one pen, but I’m going to make sure you each &#8212;</p>



<p>SENATOR STABENOW:&nbsp; Uh-oh.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>REPRESENTATIVE KILDEE:&nbsp; We’re going to fight for it.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You each are going to get a pen &#8212; I promise you.</p>



<p>This is an executive order strengthening America’s leadership in clean cars and trucks.&nbsp; And again, let me start off by thanking the CEOs, as well as the UAW.&nbsp; You all &#8212; all you elected are the reason why it’s happening, man.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>(The executive order is signed.)</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>(The President rides in an electric vehicle.)</p>



<p>(The President returns and answers questions from the press.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When was the last time you drove?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How did it feel, Mr. President?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you like it better than the Lightning, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It feels great, because, you know, you sit there &#8212; first of all, you don’t hear a thing.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Number one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I try?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s not mine yet.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you think about these breathalyzers that are going in the cars nowadays?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Pardon me?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The bill that’s coming up, making breathalyzers for vehicles in a couple of years mandatory?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s a good idea, by the way.&nbsp; I think.&nbsp; I think that’s a good idea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tell me why.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because in large part it just helps the driver, because lots of times people have a couple of drinks and don’t realize (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s thousands of cars in lots around the country lacking chips, Mr. President.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know they are.&nbsp; That’s why we’re &#8212; we’re going to invest billions of dollars in bringing chip manufacturing to the United States &#8212; a bipartisan effort that we’ve gotten done.&nbsp; It’s going to work.&nbsp; Because we can’t afford &#8212;&nbsp;we &#8212; for example, we got the chairman of the board of Ford here somewhere &#8212; they had to slow down production because of the lack of chips.&nbsp; It’s a gigantic, gigantic issue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a response to Governor DeSantis who was using your words about “don’t be in the way,” and he’s saying, “I am in the way” to block too much interference from the federal government?&nbsp; Your response, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Governor who?&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; DeSantis.</p>



<p>(Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s my response.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How did California’s 2019 framework influence the executive order that you signed today?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I think the framework was really helpful.&nbsp; And the reason I say that is that, you know, initially, the industry was opposed to it.&nbsp; And we literally sat over in the EEOB and I had five of the largest corporations in America, with Mary Barra representing General Motors down the street.&nbsp; And you’ve been there with me when I’ve done this.&nbsp; And five major labor unions.</p>



<p>And when it was all over, Mary Barra called and said, “I’m going to withdraw the suit against California.”&nbsp; They were suing California.&nbsp; To say, “You can’t have a higher standard than the rest of the nation,” which was what, you know, the last President did.&nbsp; He lowered the (inaudible) standard.</p>



<p>And she said, “I’m going to get &#8212; I’m going to drop the suit, and I’m going to go electric.”&nbsp; And we got the IBEW involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the biggest thing that’s happening here is there’s a realization, on the part of both labor and business now, that this is the future.&nbsp; We can’t sit by.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Think about the battery technology.&nbsp; Most of that research and development occurred with United States taxpayers’ dollars from the Department of Energy, the DOD, here in the United States.&nbsp; And we didn’t take advantage of it.&nbsp; We didn’t move on it.&nbsp; China moved, and China now owns the market.&nbsp; So we just got to get back in the game.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How is the eviction moratorium constitutional, sir?&nbsp; How is it constitutional?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How is the eviction moratorium constitutional, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think it is.&nbsp; But there’s a call &#8212; there are a number of constitutional scholars &#8212; I spoke to a lot of constitutional scholars.&nbsp; Let me explain the last &#8212; the last time why I did what I did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My greatest concern is &#8212; I have three concerns.&nbsp; One, we have $45 billion sitting in the state treasuries right now that were designed specifically to help landlords be able to not have to go bankrupt so that they &#8212; and keep those renters who couldn’t afford to pay their rent because of the pandemic, because of unemployment being as bad as it was since the Great Depression.</p>



<p>We gave it to the states and localities to be able to keep renters in their homes, as well as &#8212; as well as being able to continue to keep their business going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Court ruled by &#8212; and made it very clear &#8212; the Supreme Court said, “You can&#8217;t do that.&nbsp; You don’t have the authority to do that.”&nbsp; And &#8212; although it was a 5-to-4 decision.&nbsp; I got on the phone and contacted a number of constitutional scholars I&#8217;ve relied on for years, beyond my own team, and there was a split.&nbsp; And the consensus of the folks that I have used the most said, “We think it is &#8212; you have the authority to do it, but, in this court, who knows.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last point I’ll make: So, what I decided to do, I did not tell the CDC.&nbsp; I made a commitment to you all I would not tell the CDC what they should do, and I would not tell the Justice Department who they should prosecute.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve kept that commitment.</p>



<p>So I asked the CDC to go back and take another look at was there anything possible and check with the legal scholars as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Now, wait a minute.&nbsp; They went back and they concluded that if we had a completely different (inaudible) &#8212; we did not try to continue the existing moratorium; it was a different moratorium with another rationale.&nbsp; The rationale was that because of the COVID spread of the virus so rapidly, that &#8212; and the Delta COVID &#8212; what happened was they said: All those &#8212; all those counties that, in fact, are in a situation where they are in that red zone, that they &#8212; we should hold for another month &#8212; or I think they said two months &#8212; the ability to evict people from those facilities.&nbsp; And I said, “Okay, thank you.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I went ahead and did it, but here&#8217;s the deal: I can&#8217;t guarantee you the Court won&#8217;t rule if we don&#8217;t have that authority, but at least we&#8217;ll have the ability, if we have to appeal, to keep this going for a month at least &#8212; I hope longer than that.&nbsp; And in the process, by that time, we&#8217;ll get a lot of (inaudible).</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>4:00 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Senior White&#160;House Meeting with State Attorneys General on Efforts to Hold Gun Manufacturers&#160;Accountable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/readout-of-senior-white-house-meeting-with-state-attorneys-general-on-efforts-to-hold-gun-manufacturers-accountable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 23:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, White House Counsel Dana Remus, and Director of the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs Julie Rodriguez hosted a virtual convening with attorneys general from seven states and the District of Columbia to discuss policies and strategies for holding gun manufacturers and dealers accountable for wrongful conduct that contributes to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, White House Counsel Dana Remus, and Director of the Office of Intergovernmental Affairs Julie Rodriguez hosted a virtual convening with attorneys general from seven states and the District of Columbia to discuss policies and strategies for holding gun manufacturers and dealers accountable for wrongful conduct that contributes to the supply of firearms used to commit gun crimes. This convening is the first of two meetings with state and local officials that were announced in President Biden’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">comprehensive plan</a> to reduce gun crimes, including by supporting local law enforcement, investing in proven community violence interruption efforts, and stemming the flow of guns used to commit crimes.</p>



<p>President Biden has repeatedly and forcefully called for Congress to repeal the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act (PLCAA). This law gives gun dealers and manufacturers special immunity from certain liability for their products, hindering the public’s ability to address the epidemic of gun violence through the use of civil litigation in the same way they have been able to with the tobacco and opioid industries. As the President said in the Rose Garden this past April, “Imagine how different it would be had the same exemption been available to tobacco companies who knew and lied about the danger they were causing.” During today’s discussion, attorneys general shared how PLCAA has served as a significant barrier to holding gun manufacturers and dealers accountable for unlawful conduct that led to shootings, homicides, and other gun crimes, and how repeal of PLCAA would enhance their ability to advance the public safety of Americans.</p>



<p>As directed in the President’s gun crime reduction strategy, participants in the convening also discussed how we can hold gun manufacturers and dealers accountable for unlawful conduct while PLCAA is still the law of the land. Attorneys general discussed the opportunity and barriers to using generally applicable state consumer protection and nuisance laws to take action against gun manufacturers and gun dealers under PLCAA’s predicate exception. They also discussed how state legislators could enact firearm-specific liability laws, like New York State’s new law, to potentially create new predicates allowing litigation to proceed under PLCAA.</p>



<p><em>Attorneys General:</em></p>



<ul><li>District of Columbia Attorney General Karl Racine</li><li>New York Attorney General Letitia James</li><li>New Jersey Acting Attorney General Andrew Bruck</li><li>California Attorney General Rob Bonta</li><li>Pennsylvania Attorney General Josh Shapiro</li><li>Washington Attorney General Bob Ferguson</li><li>Massachusetts Attorney General Maura Healey</li><li>Connecticut Attorney General William Tong</li></ul>



<p><em>White House participants:</em></p>



<ul><li>Susan Rice, Assistant to the President and Domestic Policy Advisor</li><li>Dana Remus, Assistant to the President and White House Counsel</li><li>Julie Rodriguez, Deputy Assistant to the President and Director of Intergovernmental Affairs</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki and Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona, August 5,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/05/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-secretary-of-education-miguel-cardona-august-5-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:04 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hello.&#160; Okay.&#160; Today we have another great guest joining us in the briefing room, Secretary Cardona.&#160; As a mother of two little children myself, including one going to elementary school, I know you all have lots of questions about schools and school reopening and COVID.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:04 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Today we have another great guest joining us in the briefing room, Secretary Cardona.&nbsp; As a mother of two little children myself, including one going to elementary school, I know you all have lots of questions about schools and school reopening and COVID.&nbsp; So he is here to provide an update, take a few questions.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s great to be here with you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Fellow Nutmeggers.<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Do a little Connecticut plug.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; And thank you, Jen, for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m &#8212; you know, across the country there&#8217;s an excitement for the first day of school.&nbsp; And those of you that have children, you know what I&#8217;m talking about.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a vibe about going back to school.&nbsp; And this year, there&#8217;s no exception.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re committed to doing everything we can to ensure we get kids back into the classroom safely.&nbsp; We know students are provided the best opportunity to learn and thrive when they&#8217;re learning in person, in their classroom, with their peers, with their teacher.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We made significant progress last spring, bringing the students back in person.&nbsp; About 90 percent of the educators across the country are vaccinated.&nbsp; A hundred eighty million Americans have been vaccinated, including millions of students.&nbsp; We provided $130 billion in American Rescue Plan funds to support safe school reopening.&nbsp; It&#8217;s being used now to provide summer learning opportunities for students and help them &#8212; and help our buildings be prepared for the return of students in the fall.<br>&nbsp;<br>And this week, I&#8217;m very proud to announce the Department of Education launched the Return to School Roadmap.&nbsp; It provides parents, educators, students, and communities the resources they need to feel confident and be ready for a safe upcoming school year, to make sure we safety &#8212; safely open all schools for in-person learning this fall, which is the expectation; it has been, and it continues to be.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Roadmap includes three priorities that are critical to a safe reopening.&nbsp; The first one is protecting the health and safety of our students, our educators, and our staff.&nbsp; We need to make sure that we&#8217;re leading with health and safety first.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The second priority is supporting the social, emotional, and mental health needs of our students and our staff.&nbsp; We know that in order for students to learn at their potential, they need a strong social and emotional foundation, and we&#8217;re prepared to provide that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The third: accelerating academic achievement.&nbsp; We must do everything in our power to help students not only catch up, but to excel during this upcoming school year.&nbsp; As a part of the Roadmap, we&#8217;ll be releasing resources, tools, and holding events to help more schools and more communities and parents and students prepare for the fall and make sure that every student is set up for success.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re also highlighting how the American Rescue Plan funds can be used to support these areas.&nbsp; These include helping get our young people vaccinated.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doubling down to get more students vaccinated as they return to school.&nbsp; We know vaccines are working, and they&#8217;re the safest and most effective way to fight back the COVID-19, to prevent outbreaks, and to ensure a safe school year.<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s why I&#8217;m echoing the President&#8217;s call to action to post pop-up vaccine clinics in every school across the country, to enlist trusted leaders in our community, to build vaccine confidence &#8212; it&#8217;s all hands on deck here &#8212; and to get creative with incentives.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I know I&#8217;ve heard from states where they&#8217;re doing great work incentivizing it and getting student voice in the conversation to make sure that students hear from other students as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m also excited that, next week, the administration is holding Back to School Week of Action to mobilize school districts, students, teachers, organizations, and leaders to get more young people vaccinated, working with parent leaders and influencers to have conversations with students and families about the importance of getting vaccinated and why it&#8217;s our strongest tool to combat the virus and get students back into the classrooms, on sports fields, in school plays, and among their peers this fall.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Next week, I&#8217;ll be traveling with the Second Gentleman to Kansas to promote vaccination efforts in that area.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m additionally excited to lift up some additional efforts were engaged in with partners across the country, including incorporating COVID vaccination into sports physicals for student athletes this summer and fall.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The National PTA &#8212; we&#8217;re working with them and the Academy &#8212; American Academy of Pediatrics &#8212; to send pediatricians to back-to-school nights and PTA meetings so parents could hear from doctors directly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I said before, it&#8217;s all hands on deck.&nbsp; We all want our students in classrooms where they learn best.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The resources are there, and the urgency is there.&nbsp; Now is the time to get our students back into the classroom, not to be complacent or let politics get in front of what is best for our students across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m excited about the efforts we have underway at the department and across the administration to support a safe return to school this fall and make this school year the best one yet for all of our students.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we know it&#8217;s not enough to get to school &#8212; to get back to school safely.&nbsp; We owe it to our students to build back better.&nbsp; We owe it to our students not to go back to what school was like in March 2020.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we must pass the Build Back Better agenda.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have the opportunity right now to transform students’ educational experiences.&nbsp; We can build truly equitable schools that finally close gaps that have long existed in our education system across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We can set up all of our children for success by investing in our strongest asset, our people, and ensure America wins the future.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll give every family access to free pre-kindergarten for three- and four-year-olds.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll give students access to two years of community college.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll increase Pell Grants, rebuild and modernize our crumbling schools by investing in our school infrastructure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And these resources will allow us to build an education system more equitable and excellent than any system we&#8217;ve ever had in the past.&nbsp; These resources will allow us to build back better and give our students opportunities to have success not only now, but for generations to come.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you, and I&#8217;ll be happy to answer a few questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nancy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Secretary Cardona, for coming.&nbsp; Are you engaged in discussions with teachers&#8217; unions that might be reluctant about returning to the classroom this fall because of the Delta variant?&nbsp; And how significant do you expect that challenge to be?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; You know, I really don&#8217;t expect it to be a challenge to work with our teachers to get our schools reopened.&nbsp; In fact, I think they&#8217;ve shown a lot of proactive communication about wanting to reopen schools.&nbsp; All teachers want schools reopened, and we just want to make sure that they&#8217;re safe for students and for staff.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I look at it as another partner in the process of making sure that we&#8217;re doing what&#8217;s right to reopen our schools.&nbsp; And while the Delta variant is providing new challenges, we have the tools, we have the resources, and we have the experience of what worked last year to get it done safely.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what about states that are, say, prohibiting school districts from imposing mask mandates?&nbsp; Are you worried that there will be teachers&#8217; unions that say, &#8220;If we can&#8217;t keep the schools safe the way that we feel we should, we don&#8217;t want to come back&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; I&#8217;m worried that decisions that are being made &#8212; that are not putting students at the center, and student health and safety at the center &#8212; is going to be why schools may be disrupted.&nbsp; So, we know what to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, don&#8217;t be the reason why schools are disrupted because of the politicization of this effort to reopen schools.&nbsp; We know what works.&nbsp; We have to keep our students safe.&nbsp; We have to keep our educators safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tam.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, reopening school is one thing &#8212; I think you just alluded to this &#8212; keeping school open would seem to be another thing entirely.<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are you most worried about in terms of the ability to keep classrooms open, to keep kids, you know, running up that hill to the school every day?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; We know what works.&nbsp; This is not our first time doing this.&nbsp; We have the benefit of the experience of last year.&nbsp; We have strong CDC guidance.&nbsp; The Department of Education has several handbooks.&nbsp; The Back to School Roadmap with tools, checklists.&nbsp; The tools are there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just, are we following the mitigation strategies?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know what I&#8217;m worried about?&nbsp; The adult actions getting in the way of schools safely reopening.&nbsp; Let our educators educate, let our leaders &#8212; school leaders lead, and we can get our schools reopened safely.<br>&nbsp;<br>And another thing that I&#8217;m worried about that I want to share is complacency.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s not go back to the school system of March 2020.&nbsp; Our students deserve more.&nbsp; The funds are there.&nbsp; The urgency is there.&nbsp; This is our time to build back better.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just throw out &#8212; what do you mean by &#8220;adult actions&#8221;?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Well, when we make policies that go against what CDC recommendations are, you know, at the end of the day, we want to make sure that students are safe, we want to make sure the staff is safe.&nbsp; We know how to do that, so let&#8217;s not get in the way of school systems doing policies that they know work for students and staff.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Francesca &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will there be repercussions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Francesca, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; We know that vaccination rates among younger Americans, 18 to 24, are lower.&nbsp; We also know that vaccination rates among African Americans are also lower as a percentage of population.&nbsp; So what kind of guidance is the Department of Education giving historically Black colleges and universities this fall to help keep their students safe?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Thank you for that question.&nbsp; I visited Howard University about a month ago, and I was so impressed with how they stood up vaccination clinics in their facilities.&nbsp; And we had students from Howard University administering vaccine.&nbsp; They&#8217;re using their name in the community to build confidence in the community &#8212; the Black community &#8212; so that they felt comfortable coming in.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re also setting up pop-up clinics in schools.&nbsp; You know, the President put a charge there: Let&#8217;s get pop-up vaccination clinics in gymnasiums.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I visited a gymnasium at a high school in Washington, D.C., where, you know, parents felt comfortable with that school.&nbsp; They know the principal.&nbsp; They know the teachers.&nbsp; They feel more like &#8212; they&#8217;re more likely to go get vaccinated in a school that they know the folks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And another thing that we&#8217;re going to do is we&#8217;re going to take advantage of our &#8212; of our youth.&nbsp; You know, student voice is critically important.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get our youth, our high school students talking about it, because when students talk to one another about how they&#8217;re safe when they got the vaccine, it&#8217;s more likely to lead to an increase.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m excited about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about testing?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Well, the American Rescue Plan provides $10 billion in testing.&nbsp; So, the tools are there.&nbsp; Access to testing is much better.&nbsp; We were reopening schools last year &#8212; I remember reopening schools last year without testing availability, without vaccines, and we were able to do it safely because we followed the mitigation strategies.&nbsp; A year later, we have resources, we have testing, and we have vaccinations.&nbsp; We need to get it done.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go all the way in the back.&nbsp; Yahoo.&nbsp; Yeah, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Secretary, what are you going to do if and when teachers&#8217; unions protest and, you know, with placards that say, &#8220;we can&#8217;t teach from the grave,&#8221; &#8220;online until cases decline&#8221;?&nbsp; As the federal Secretary, with limited powers to affect local decisions, what are you going to do?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, as a parent, as a journalist, I know &#8212; I know about the $130 billion.&nbsp; I know that online has a lot of risks for kids.&nbsp; Everybody knows that, but what are we going to do in those situations?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; I think &#8212; what are we doing?&nbsp; We have the Roadmap, which &#8212; very clear guidance.&nbsp; We&#8217;re promoting pop-up clinics.&nbsp; We&#8217;re sharing best practices where it&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; We&#8217;re monitoring data.&nbsp; We stood up a system in the Department of Education.&nbsp; I&#8217;m having calls with governors daily.&nbsp; I&#8217;m having calls with superintendents, school chiefs to problem solve with them to make sure that we can get them in there.</p>



<p>And, you know, the way the question was framed, I&#8217;d like to look at it this way: How are we working with our teachers’ unions to ensure a safe reopening of schools?&nbsp; They&#8217;re doing a lot of work, and they&#8217;re investing their own money to make sure that our schools can safely reopen and getting the message out to their teachers.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working hand-in-hand to make sure that our students have teachers in front of the classroom, but that they both feel safe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kelly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Secretary, one of the big differences this time is that children are becoming infected more easily because Delta is more transmissible &#8212;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; so we might have, unlike March 2020, where there would be children in the classroom who themselves become ill.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Are you formulating policy for how schools should deal with the impact on other students &#8212; if there&#8217;s quarantining requirements;&nbsp;if it&#8217;s classrooms with only vaccinated children, mixed vaccination status?&nbsp; How are you going to deal with those dimensions?</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working very closely with CDC to have a unified message.&nbsp; And we lean very heavily on our health experts to make sure that we&#8217;re communicating which mitigation strategies should be employed based on what we&#8217;re seeing with the strains of COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I&#8217;ll tell you what worked: When you wear masks, when you provide distancing, when you are testing regularly, and when you&#8217;re quarantining, you can function in a school.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re expecting our education leaders and our educators to follow those practices that worked last year, and we expect our students to be in classroom every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Stephanie.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Cardona &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Stephanie.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; when kids have masks on in the classroom &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Stephanie.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Cardona, thank you so much &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; how seriously does that hurt their learning?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sir &#8212; sir, Stephanie is asking a question.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kids at this point have gotten used to wearing masks, my children included.</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is your message to governors like Governor DeSantis in Florida and Governor Abbott of Texas who have banned mask mandates?</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; You know, don&#8217;t be the reason why schools are interrupted.&nbsp; Our kids have suffered enough.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s do what we know works.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s do what we know works across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We shouldn&#8217;t get pol- &#8212; politics should &#8212; doesn&#8217;t have a role in this.&nbsp; Educators know what to do.&nbsp; We did it last year.</p>



<p>So, I have calls out to those states.&nbsp; But at the end of the day, I want to work with Texas; I want to work with Florida.&nbsp; I want to make sure those students have access to in-person learning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, at the end of the day, we&#8217;re all in this together.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s critically important that we have conversations with governors directly, with state chiefs directly.&nbsp; We want to be an ally and make sure that we&#8217;re supporting our students.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the end of the day, we&#8217;re talking about students being in classrooms.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve suffered enough.&nbsp; It&#8217;s time for them to be in the classroom without disruption to their learning.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Justin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Cardona &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Justin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; when kids have &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; masks on in the classroom, how seriously does that hurt their learning?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Cardona &#8212;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Less than if they’re at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m sorry, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Student loan payment &#8212; the student loan payment freeze ends next month.&nbsp; Democratic lawmakers and advocates have said that the lack of guidance so far from the administration has left a lot of borrowers confused and lenders reluctant to put out guidance &#8212; maybe alarming them that their student loan repayments will start.&nbsp; So do you guys have any additional guidance for that?&nbsp; And if not &#8212;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; when can we expect it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Sure, I’m not ex- &#8212; announcing anything today, but I will tell you this has been the highest priority for us: getting school safely reopened and taking care of our borrowers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re &#8212; you know, when we have information to share, we want to make sure that they have enough of an on-ramp to prepare and they have communication early so they can prepare for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is a priority for us, and we’re having conversations daily and we hope to have information soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Steve.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just as a follow-up to that: There was a study earlier this summer that said 60 percent of borrowers are not yet ready to make their payments.&nbsp; They have about &#8212; they have less than two months.&nbsp; When are they going to hear from you?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Very soon.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything today.&nbsp; But as I said, this is a priority for us.&nbsp; The borrowers are in need of information and they&#8217;re also in need of relief.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Phil.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Secretary, I understand what the federal position is, but given how fluid things have been over the course of the last couple weeks with the resurgence of Delta, is there anything &#8212; metrics wise or numbers wise, threshold wise &#8212; that you would look at and say, “All right, maybe in person is not the best answer right now,” even if the year gets started?&nbsp; Or is it: “In person no matter; we have the mitigation tools”?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; You know, we know what works.&nbsp; And yes, we&#8217;re looking at the metrics, and obviously in close consultation with CDC and local health directors because there are many local factors that contribute to whether or not a school should be open.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to continue to monitor and we&#8217;re going to continue to work with states.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m also looking at the policies that adults are putting in place that are putting students at risk.&nbsp; And I think, while we have a reopening team that&#8217;s focusing on the metrics &#8212; COVID spread, you know, school reopening &#8212; we&#8217;re also monitoring the decisions that adults are making where politics are getting in the way and it&#8217;s putting students at risk.&nbsp; So our efforts are going to go there as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Aamer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You made the point, just again, that, “Politicians, don’t be the reason why schools close.”&nbsp; On the flip side, if you’re a parent in one of these states, should families feel safe sending their children to schools where there aren&#8217;t mask mandates?</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; You know, as a parent myself, I would make sure that when I&#8217;m &#8212; my wife and I are making decisions about sending our children to school, I want to make sure that they&#8217;re going into a safe learning environment.&nbsp; I know that I can send my children into school with masks, although both of my children were vaccinated.&nbsp; If that&#8217;s the rule in the &#8212; in a school, that&#8217;s what we’ll follow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do ask parents to communicate with schools now and make sure that they feel comfortable sending their children to school.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m also going to be monitoring where places have rules that are limiting mask use, whether or not students that need to be in school are not going because of a lack of confidence.&nbsp; To me, those are adult actions preventing students to their right of public education.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any &#8212; if you find that that&#8217;s an issue, is there anything that, from the federal level, you can do?&nbsp; Any leverage that you guys have?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; If we find that because of poor policy students are not accessing the right to public education, we will have conversations with those states and &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yamiche.</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; &#8212; take that very seriously.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yamiche and Jeff.&nbsp; And then we got to wrap it up.&nbsp; The Secretary has got to go.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary.&nbsp; I&#8217;m over here.</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Sure, hi.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; for taking my question.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen &#8212;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for letting me ask it.</p>



<p>My question is: You&#8217;ve talked a bunch about, kind of, science not being in the way, not &#8212; politics not being able &#8212;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to get in the way of science.&nbsp; I wonder what mechanisms, what sticks, what sort of consequences might the Education Department have in its toolbox to ensure that in districts where we see school leaders fighting with, frankly, politicians when it comes to CDC guidance that the Education Department might be able to back some of those school districts up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing places where school districts want to mandate masks, but obviously state leaders are saying they can&#8217;t do that.&nbsp; What could the Education Department do to ensure that those leaders (inaudible)?</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to constantly work with those states, with those leaders.&nbsp; At the end of the day, we&#8217;re on the same team for the kids, right?&nbsp; And, you know, I applaud Governor Hutchinson for what he&#8217;s doing.&nbsp; And I recognize that we have to be malleable to address the increase in spread.&nbsp; And that requires partnership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, withholding money is not &#8212; that&#8217;s going to hurt kids.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to hurt kids more.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re going to continue to work with those states and do what we can to help them understand how important it is to make sure students are getting into school.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And my hope is that students go into schools in those communities as well.&nbsp; But if we&#8217;re starting to notice that students are not going in because they don&#8217;t feel confident, then we&#8217;re going to have to have conversations about that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) you said you don&#8217;t want to withhold money.&nbsp; Is there anything else that the Department can do if it&#8217;s not &#8212; that won&#8217;t hurt kids but that can send a message that science and politics can&#8217;t mix?</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; We&#8217;re in this to stay, and we want to make sure those kids get into school, and we’re going to do everything we can to make that happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Mr. Secretary, can you give us an update on the proposal to teach more Black history in schools?&nbsp; Did the&nbsp;Republican backlash over that have an impact over your plans?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; You know, I always say I trust my educators across the country to make sure that our curriculum promotes the beautiful diversity of this country.&nbsp; And we could do so, as educators, in a way to unify our students and our country and show respect to others.</p>



<p>That’s another example of something that’s become politized.&nbsp; And I have confidence in my educators.&nbsp; And I have confidence in their ability to teach students about our history.&nbsp; And in the process, we can learn about one another and become a stronger nation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s still on track, that proposal?</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Which &#8212; you’re talking about the priorities?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Yeah, the priorities are still what they are.&nbsp; I think, for us, the way we put it forward allows districts to and states to put in their proposals in how they want to teach it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think, again, it became a politicized issue that didn’t need to, and it took us away from what I think is most important: our Build Back Better agenda and getting students safely back into school.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary Cardona.</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would you like to teach more science?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re always welcome to join us.</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Let me get my mask on here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would you like to teach more science in school, Mr. Secretary?</p>



<p>SECRETARY CARDONA:&nbsp; We want to get in schools safely.&nbsp; We can talk about the discussions there, and I’ll be back for that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re pro-science, just in case there was confusion.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No confusion.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A couple of items for all of you at the top.</p>



<p>Today, the President will announce a new set of actions aimed at advancing the goal of increasing the impact of his Build Back Better investments to address our climate crisis, positioning America to drive the electric vehicle future forward, outcompete China.</p>



<p>He will sign an executive order &#8212; I know this was out there reported this morning &#8212; that sets an ambitious new target to make half of all new vehicles sold in 20- &#8212; in 2030 zero-emissions vehicles, including battery electric, plug-in hybrid electric, or fuel cell electric vehicles.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, later today, the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Transportation will announce how they are addressing the previous administration&#8217;s harmful rollbacks of near-term fuel efficiency and emissions standard.&nbsp; A good question a lot of you have been asking is: What is the implementation about this?&nbsp; They will announce the rulemaking &#8212; next steps in rulemaking process later today as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These new actions, paired with the investments in the President&#8217;s Build Back Better agenda will strengthen American leadership in clean cars and trucks by accelerating innovation and manufacturing in the auto sector, bolstering the auto sector domestic supply chain, and growing auto jobs and good pay and benefits.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are also announcing today the Biden administration commitment to &#8212; we are committing more than $3.46 billion in new funding to help states and partners increase resilience and reduce the impacts of climate change nationwide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At a time when communities across the country are facing the impacts of the climate change crisis and grappling with extreme heat; wildflou- [sic] &#8212; -fires; prolonged droughts; the onset of peak hurricane season, this historic edition of the Hazard Mitigation Grant Program will help states, localities, Tribal and territorial governments finance projects to safeguard our communities for the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>FEMA Administrator Criswell is currently briefing the National Governors Association, Homeland Security Advisors Council on these investments, and we will have a fact sheet after the briefing detailing how much funding each state and locality will be receiving.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also wanted to note that, today, senior White House officials, including Ambassador Susan Rice, Dana Remus, and&nbsp;Julie Rodriguez, will host a virtual convening with eight state attorneys general as part of the President&#8217;s ongoing strategy to combat the surge in gun crime we&#8217;ve seen over the last 18 months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>During the meeting, the group will discuss policies and strategies to hold gun manufacturers and dealers accountable for wrongful conduct that contributes to guns making their way into the hands of criminals and be used in shootings around the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are committed to using every tool at our disposal to crack down on gun crime.&nbsp; That includes money to put more cops on the beat and support community anti-violence programs.&nbsp; It also means aggressive steps to stem the flow of guns used in crimes.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to today&#8217;s convening, we also announced today tough, new regulations on untraceable ghost guns, as well as &#8212; and we also launched five regional gun trafficking strike forces, as you all know, and announced a national zero tolerance policy for gun dealers.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last item for all of you: As you all know, the President has been committed to the federal judiciary for decades.&nbsp; Having served as the Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, he&#8217;s has made it a chief priority to nominate deeply qualified nominees who are devoted to the rule of law and who represent the diversity of the country.&nbsp; He&#8217;s done that at a historic pace.&nbsp; And his nominees are also being confirmed with unprecedented speed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, he nominated three additional candidates for the federal judiciary, among them Justice Beth Robinson, Vermont&#8217;s first openly LGBTQ Supreme Court Justice, who would also be the first openly LGBTQ woman to serve on any federal circuit court.<br>&nbsp;<br>Under the President&#8217;s leadership, we&#8217;ve also confirmed the most African American women as federal circuit judge &#8212; judges of any single presidential term in American history, and the first Muslim &#8212; Muslim Article III judge in American history.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s also chosen nominees from a wide variety of backgrounds: prosecutors and also public defenders, law firm lawyers, and civil rights attorneys.&nbsp; That will continue to drive his decisions moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Aamer, why don’t you kick us off.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Two questions about &#8212; first, I wanted to ask about &#8212; related to yesterday &#8212; the importance of continuing to work with New York as the situation with Governor Cuomo is playing out. &nbsp;With that said, it&#8217;s a critical time for the state and the country with the surge of the Delta variant.&nbsp; Will the President pick up the phone and personally insist to the governor that, for the good of the state, it&#8217;s time to step down?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has addressed this, and I have no planned calls to preview or predict for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also have a question, EV related.&nbsp; The infrastructure bill, if I understand right, includes about half of what the President wanted in order to build a national network of charging stations.&nbsp; So how do you take EVs from that &#8212; from the niche &#8212; or merging from the niche to the mainstream without that necessary investment in charging stations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first I would say it&#8217;s a historic investment in EV charging stations.&nbsp; And we also know that &#8212; also as part of the investment is efforts to reduce the cost of purchasing electric vehicles.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I would say the President&#8217;s commitment to making electric vehicles the vehicle of the future; further incentivizing the direction of the industry &#8212; which is already where it&#8217;s headed; making us more competitive as it relates to China, is reflected both in the bill and the bill that&#8217;s working its way through the Senate.&nbsp; Also in announcements like the one that was made today about &#8212; that show clear initiative and commitment from this administration to make electric vehicles central to our &#8212; central to our focus moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I apologize, on the Governor Cuomo, you don&#8217;t have calls to read out, but has there been a call?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions for you.&nbsp; Has the President received a formal recommendation yet from the Secretary of Defense to mandate vaccines for the military?&nbsp; And if so, does the President intend to accept that recommendation and sign a waiver authorizing that mandate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, the President announced last week that he was asking the Secretary of Defense and the Defense Department to look into how and when they will add COVID to the list of mandatory vaccinations for our armed forces.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We expect a determination soon.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of that.&nbsp; And certainly he&#8217;s going to rely on the recommendation of his Secretary of Defense.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Also, on the COVID front, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis is now fundraising off of President Biden’s comments for him to, quote, “get out of the way” of people trying to help out on the COVID surge in that state.&nbsp; DeSantis has said, “I’m standing in your way,” “I’m not going anywhere.”&nbsp; And referred to the President as a “power-hungry tyrant.”&nbsp; What is your response to the governor and the administration&#8217;s response to the governor?&nbsp; And is the President considering reaching out to the DeSantis to talk this over?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, from day one, we&#8217;ve approached this not as a political issue, but a public health issue.&nbsp; We remain in touch with officials in Florida, just like we&#8217;re in touch with officials from around the country about how we can provide assistance from the federal level to help address this public health crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>What we &#8212; what I have cited and what the President has cited is publicly available data about public health and the impact in Florida.&nbsp; It is factual, and it is a fact, and data that you all are aware of, that 25 percent of hospitalizations in the country are in Florida.&nbsp; It is also a fact that the governor has taken steps that are conter [sic] &#8212; counter to public health recommendations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;re here to state the facts.&nbsp; Frankly, our view is that this is too serious &#8212; deadly serious &#8212; to be doing partisan name-calling.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re not doing here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re focused on providing public health data, information to the people of Florida to make sure they understand what steps they should be taking, even if those are not steps taken at the top of the leadership in that state.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Republicans have made it pretty clear over the last couple of days that they&#8217;re drawing a red line on the debt ceiling in terms of their willingness to negotiate &#8212; or to consider a clean debt ceiling increase.&nbsp; Does the President want Democrats to move that through reconciliation, or is he ready to have that fight at some point in September or October with Republicans, trying to get Republican support?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President believes that Democrats and Republicans should move forward, as they did three times during the last administration, to raise the debt ceiling &#8212; something that they did even in the wake of the former President putting in place a $2 trillion tax cut that certainly did not do anything to reduce the deficit.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, that&#8217;s his view.&nbsp; He believes they should move forward and do that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s responsible &#8212; responsible step for our country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on a very different subject.&nbsp; Does the President have a deadline, in his mind, in terms of, like, when his patience would run out on the Iran negotiations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think the President&#8217;s view is that it is our &#8212; in our interest to continue to pursue a diplomatic path forward, because even though we certainly don&#8217;t approve &#8212; in fact, we have great concern about a number of Iran&#8217;s problematic activities in the global community &#8212; having visibility into their nuclear capabilities and capacities is in our national interest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The timeline is not endless, and I know the Secretary of State has conveyed that clearly.&nbsp; But right now we are open to returning to a seventh round of negotiations.&nbsp; The inauguration is today, so we will see what happens from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jeff.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the President today offered safe haven to Hong Kong residents who are living in the United States for 18 months.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering why 18 months.&nbsp; Is that something he&#8217;d be willing to extend?&nbsp; And is citizenship on the table for those people as well?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the decision &#8212; the announcement that we made today &#8212; I know you&#8217;re closely following this, but for others who have not followed this closely &#8212; is in reaction to the steps that have been taken by the PRC to crack down on human rights and, frankly, make it a place where Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy and the freedoms of people in Hong Kong are undermined.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of what could happen 18 months from now, I&#8217;m certainly not going to get ahead of that.&nbsp; Obviously, our hope and our objective and our work on the international forum is to change the behavior that is happening and the oppression that we&#8217;re seeing of the people in Hong Kong.&nbsp; But certainly, this step is one that is meant to ensure we are practicing what we preach in terms of human rights values and ensuring that people who are in this country don&#8217;t face the ongoing repression that we&#8217;re seeing in Hong Kong.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more related to China.&nbsp; China says it has supplied over 770 million vaccine doses to other countries.&nbsp; President Biden often says that the amount of vaccines that the U.S. has shared is more than the rest of the world combined.&nbsp; President Xi today also said they&#8217;re planning to donate 2 billion this year.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering if you question China&#8217;s math and/or whether the U.S. is planning to give more than the President has already said.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly &#8212; this is just the beginning, and we certainly plan to give more.&nbsp; We want to be the arsenal for vaccines in the global community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note &#8212; and then I&#8217;ll come back to the numbers &#8212; that we provide vaccines to the world without &#8212; without strings attached.&nbsp; We want to provide them from a humanitarian standpoint because we think it is morally right, because we want to be a leader in the world on issues from &#8212; ranging from human rights to ensuring we&#8217;re addressing the global pandemic.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure that&#8217;s exactly the same approach that China is taking; in fact, it is not.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would say that, in terms of their numbers &#8212; it is not just us citing this &#8212; I believe the numbers we&#8217;ve cited or the numbers he cited the other day were from international experts who&#8217;ve looked at donations.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I don&#8217;t have data to confirm in terms of the numbers that China has contributed to the global community.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank, Jen.&nbsp; The automakers that are appearing with the President today at this big announcement also lobbied the Trump administration to roll back emission standards that were set by the Obama administration.&nbsp; So what gives this White House confidence that they are actually going to reach for this ambitious new goal, especially given the fact that the executive order is not binding?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say they&#8217;re standing with the President today while he&#8217;s making this announcement.&nbsp; That is certainly significant.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve also seen a lot of these industries move in the direction of electric vehicles.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s not just the President saying that; that is the direction where a lot of these industries are moving.<br>&nbsp;<br>One of the things the President is going to talk about this afternoon is the fact that we need to address also, you know, supplies, like batteries &#8212; which, right now, China is producing about 80 percent of batteries that are required for that industry to succeed.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I also would note that in addition to the announcement today &#8212; and I noted this a little bit at the top &#8212; there will be rulemaking steps that are announced by the appropriate agencies later this afternoon to ensure that we can move forward and make these pronouncements a reality.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the founder of Tesla, Elon Musk, expressed surprise that he was not invited to this ceremony because his company is obviously such a large manufacturer of electric vehicles.&nbsp; Can you give us any insight into why Tesla wasn&#8217;t included in this event?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we, of course, welcome the efforts of all automakers who recognize the potential of an electric vehicle future and support efforts that will help reach the President&#8217;s goal, and certainly Tesla is one of those companies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, it&#8217;s the three largest employers of the United Auto Workers and the UAW president who will stand with President Biden as he announces his ambitious new target.&nbsp; But I would not expect this is the last time we talk about clean cars, the move toward electric vehicles, and we look forward to having a range of partners in that effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not because Tesla is a non-union shop?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, these are the three largest employers of the United Auto Workers, so I’ll let you draw your own conclusion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Democratic Congresswoman Cori Bush is saying that she favors spending tens of thousands on private security to keep her safe, and that people should, quote, “Suck it up…defunding the police has to happen.”&nbsp; Didn’t President Biden say a few weeks ago that anybody who accuses the party of being anti-police is lying?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we shouldn&#8217;t lose the forest through the trees here, which is that a member of Congress, an elected official, is concerned that her life is threatened.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s disturbing that any elected official would have to suffer death threats and fear for their life.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to comment, of course, on their security arrangements.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more details on that, but I think we should start with that point first.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say that the President has been crystal clear that he opposes defunding the police.&nbsp; He has said that throughout the campaign &#8212; his campaign for office.&nbsp; His record over the last several decades has made that clear.&nbsp; He has proposed increased funding for law enforcement and the COPS program, increased funding from his predecessor &#8212; who was, as you might note or be aware of, a Republican.&nbsp; So I&#8217;d note that his record is pretty clear on this.<br>&nbsp;<br>There may be some in the Democratic Party, including Congresswoman Bush, who disagree with him.&nbsp; That&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; But I would say the majority of Democrats &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen this in polling &#8212; and the majority of members also agree that we should not defund the police.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a greater concern, though &#8212; I understand that’s not the President&#8217;s position, but is there a concern that defunding the police or “suck it up…defunding the police has to happen” might become a big Democratic message ahead of the midterms?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It does not appear to become &#8212; be becoming a Democratic message, even though there might be a desire for that on the other side of the aisle.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, there are reports the administration wants to require all foreign visitors to be vaccinated.&nbsp; Would that include migrants arriving in Texas and Arizona and who are released into border towns?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know there were a range of reports about this, so let me just give you a little bit of an update on this.&nbsp; One moment.&nbsp; And I know you asked, kind of, two questions there, and I promise I&#8217;ll address them both.<br>&nbsp;<br>We &#8212; one, let me reiterate &#8212; and I know Francesca asked a question about this the other day &#8212; the importance of international travel.&nbsp; Given where we are today with the Delta variant, we will plan to maintain existing travel restrictions at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>However, what our interagency working groups are focused on &#8212; and this is, I think, what was reported &#8212; is working to develop a plan for a consistent and safe international travel policy, and that will be done through the prism of providing consistent guidance, equitable guidance, digestible guidance. &nbsp;And there&#8217;s a lot of confusion about what the restrictions are now, and you all have asked a lot of good questions about it because it feels inconsistent, and it is.<br>&nbsp;<br>But that&#8217;s what our focus is.&nbsp; So that is certainly under strong consideration, but it is under a policy process review right now that I won&#8217;t get ahead of myself.<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to &#8212; I know there was also reporting about the vaccination of migrants.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not what the CBP is doing.&nbsp; There are NGOs and other international organizations who are vaccinating migrants as they come across the border, and as they work in partnership with us.&nbsp; Certainly, that helps keep a range of people safe in the &#8212; in the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But do you think that it’s keeping people safe in McAllen, Texas, where 7,000 COVID-positive migrants have been released into the city since February; 1,500 in the last seven days?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to note what&#8217;s actually happening in McAllen.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s actually been a &#8212; they signed a disaster declaration, approved setting up a temporary emergency shelter to provide a space &#8212; to create an isolated space to mitigate this issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And what happens is DHS &#8212; this is the process of what happens &#8212; the agency &#8212; one, we&#8217;re continuing to enforce Title 42, resulting first in the expulsion of the vast majority of those encountered at the border.&nbsp; We also &#8212; CBP also provides migrants who can&#8217;t be expelled under Title 42 with PPE.&nbsp; They&#8217;re required to wear the PPE.&nbsp; If any exhibit signs of illness in CB- &#8212; CBP custody, they&#8217;re referred to local health systems for appropriate testing, diagnosis, isolation, and treatment.&nbsp; And obviously there are steps taken as needed, as this is certainly evidence of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we’ve got to keep chugging here just because I don&#8217;t want to run out of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Kelly, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the eviction moratorium, landlord groups are already bringing legal action and the courts are requiring some steps of respondents by tomorrow and so forth.&nbsp; Given that, is the President still confident that the CDC’s action is within the law?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, and he would not have moved forward if not.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t &#8212; we can&#8217;t control, of course, what the courts do.&nbsp; We certainly understand that.&nbsp; Separate branches of government, but also they&#8217;ll make their own decisions.<br>&nbsp;<br>But what we can control and what we are very focused on is what we can do in states, and what we can do to push this funding and money out.&nbsp; And, you know, as we&#8217;ve been talking about quite a bit in here, there was an incredible amount of activism, of calls for an extension of the eviction moratorium by a range of members of Congress.&nbsp; We talked about Congresswoman Bush in a different capacity.&nbsp; She&#8217;s certainly one of them, and many other others joined her in this effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>And what we are hopeful now is that we can all take that activism &#8212; those calls for an extension, those calls for providing relief to renters &#8212; and take them to states and pressure states and leaders to get this money out easier.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note &#8212; it was interesting, I saw this morning &#8212; is that Senator McConnell and Senator Schumer both, in a moment of bipartisan agreement, agreed states needs to do a better job.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, that&#8217;s what we can control.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where our focus is.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t control the courts, and obviously we&#8217;re not going to speak to ongoing litigation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As you support the private-sector businesses around the country and other kinds of institutions that are setting requirements for vaccines and so forth, what guidance are you offering for how small businesses police that?&nbsp; If you&#8217;re in a restaurant situation where you have waitstaff or proprietors who would be challenging their own customers, what guidance does the federal government have for how this should be measured and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean vaccine verification and how its approached?&nbsp; You know, one, we, you know, do support efforts to incentivize workforces, of course, to protect their workforces and get more people vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>We want to ensure that it&#8217;s done in a transparent way, that it&#8217;s done in an equitable way, that if there are verification requirements, it can be done digitally.&nbsp; There are a range of ways to provide the information.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are basic guidelines, along those lines, that we have conveyed, and we will continue to convey as people have questions.&nbsp; And we understand different localities and communities will apply any verification measures in different ways.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Steve.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just to follow up on the international travel question.&nbsp; I understand that there&#8217;s an interagency process, but is it the goal of that process to end in a vaccine mandate for people who are flying to the U.S.?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s one of the considerations, but there hasn&#8217;t &#8212; the process has not been concluded yet.&nbsp; And what I was trying to note at the beginning is that, right now, I think &#8212; which is why a lot of you have very good questions about this &#8212; there is inconsistency, right?&nbsp; And there are good questions about why, when this country has larger rates of vaccination, et cetera.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we want to create or determine through this process is a way to provide clear, digestible guidance that also has our public health front and center.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a consideration, but it has not concluded yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know that it&#8217;s early, and the President, earlier today, expressed his sadness on the passing of Richard Trumka.&nbsp; Are you aware of any plans or intention on the President&#8217;s part to attend any kind of memorial service or funeral?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;It&#8217;s a good question, and I think as you all saw and noted, he &#8212; Richard Trumka was someone who the President considered a friend. &nbsp;He considered an ally in the fight for workers’ rights, for collective bargaining. &nbsp;And I think, as you all have seen &#8212; who have covered the President or followed him, long before he became President &#8212; this is probably a passion of his that he shared quite deeply. &nbsp;This is a passion of his he shared quite deeply with Richard Trumka.<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t know that there have been any plans announced yet.&nbsp; Certainly, the President will be interested in those once they become available.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask, first, about the talks that have been going on with Senator Cornyn &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the Hill, related to the infrastructure bill.&nbsp; He&#8217;s offering an amendment that would allow using some of the Rescue Plan money for infrastructure.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m wondering if you have, kind of, an update on &#8212; I know the White House started to engage in those talks last night &#8212; so if there&#8217;s been an agreement or where things stand.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And if you could speak more broadly to the concern that some in the White House and Democrats have expressed, that if you move money out of the Rescue Plan, you won&#8217;t have it to deal with Delta or some other COVID things.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; The talks are ongoing.&nbsp; We believe they&#8217;re happening in good faith.&nbsp; We are engaged in them.&nbsp; Our view is that there can be, and we think we are headed toward an agreement on this front.&nbsp; But we certainly are cognizant of and focused on the reality of funds being needed in communities across the country, as we are still in the midst of fighting a pandemic.&nbsp; And we are hopeful that any agreement on this front will take that into account front and center.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And after what we saw with the eviction moratorium and the concerns that the President and you have expressed about Delta, particularly (inaudible), I&#8217;m wondering &#8212; we&#8217;ve heard from the White House about unemployment &#8212; expanded unemployment benefits; those are set to expire in September.&nbsp; Has there been any sort of thought or revision about the White House asking Congress to extend those unemployment benefits beyond September?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There has not been a change at this point in time.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re quite focused and we designed the American Rescue Plan with the goal of being able to plan for contingencies, including rises in moments of the virus, economic needs, different communities recovering at different rates.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s one of the reasons why we pushed for state and local funding, why the child Tax Credit will benefit people through the course of next year, why there are also additional funding that people can have access to in their communities through small-business loans as well.&nbsp; But there hasn&#8217;t been any change to that at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one last quick one to follow on Phil&#8217;s question about the debt ceiling.&nbsp; Senate Democrats have been talking about attaching it to the CR.&nbsp; Mitch McConnell, earlier today, indicated that Republicans didn&#8217;t want to support this.&nbsp; But the result of this is: If Democrats throw it on to the CR, there could be a government shutdown in a couple of months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I&#8217;m wondering if that is a concern of the White House &#8212; if the White House has any sort of preference for how they want Congress &#8212; obviously, I know you want Congress to raise the debt ceiling, but any preference on how they do it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And are you at all concerned or preparing for the possibility of a government shutdown, if that&#8217;s the path that Democrats pursue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly that&#8217;s not our preference, I think it&#8217;s safe to say.&nbsp; We are, of course, in close touch with leaders in Congress about the path forward.&nbsp; But our preference is for Congress to move forward, as they have three times during the last administration, to raise the debt ceiling, which is the responsible step to take.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Francesca.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I have another question, but because international travel has come up multiple times today &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During the health briefing, it was talked about how vaccination requirements for foreign travelers are under consideration, but there were also other alternative pathways that were mentioned.&nbsp; Could you tell us a little bit more about those alternative pathways that are under discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>And relatedly, does the U.S. have concerns that if it doesn&#8217;t take action on this issue in the next few weeks, that other countries could ban American travelers from going there if the U.S. doesn&#8217;t reciprocate?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean, both really good questions, Francesca.&nbsp; I think what&#8217;s important here to note is that while there hasn&#8217;t been a final decision made, how the interagency working groups are looking at this is with the objective of taking steps that will return international travel at a moment when it&#8217;s appropriate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And right now, we&#8217;re not at that point because of the rise of the Delta variant.&nbsp; But we want to have a process in place that&#8217;s prepared for when we hit that moment.&nbsp; And whenever the decision is made about what that will look like, we want it to be clear; we don&#8217;t want it to be conflicting or confusing.&nbsp; And we want it to be equitable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, yes, there are a range of options.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to outline those from here.&nbsp; And certainly the one that has been reported on is strongly under consideration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And on the topic of immigration, is the White House looking at action to help so-called “documented DREAMers”? These are largely kids whose parents are here on H-1 visas.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They&#8217;ve waited for so long for green cards that the children are about to age out of the system and might have to return to their home country.&nbsp; So, is the White House looking at any action on that issue?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I think Lalit asked something similar the other day.&nbsp; And, yes, this is a part of what the President has proposed addressing in a comprehensive immigration bill.&nbsp; It is certainly something he&#8217;d want to address and supports taking action on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But not something necessarily that would show up in the reconciliation or upcoming budget bill?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not in the current &#8212; I think it&#8217;s not in the current discussions, but it is something the President would like to address, yes.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Jen. &nbsp;For those &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll go to you next, sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Go ahead, go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, for those foreign visitors who are anticipating vaccination proof to come into the United States: If they’ve had the Chinese or Russian vaccines, should they be confident that those would be accepted?&nbsp; Or should they go get another vaccine if it&#8217;s available?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a really great question.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just not at the point where the process has concluded.&nbsp; When it concludes, we will provide more details to everyone about what they would need to expect and what they would require and what they would need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will also note that you&#8217;ve asked me repeatedly a very good question about American citizens who were overseas.&nbsp; You may have received an answer from the State Department, but just in case, to confirm for you: We don&#8217;t provide direct medical care to private U.S. citizens abroad from the Department of State, as I think most of you who have covered the State Department are well aware.&nbsp; But we do work with countries that have a robust vaccination program to ensure that all residents, including U.S. citizens, can receive vaccinations.&nbsp; And we also work to ensure that U.S. citizens overseas who travel back to the United States can be trav- &#8212; can &#8212; vaccinated easily and effectively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, of course, we provide all consular assistance to U.S. citizens in need overseas, and this includes providing U.S. citizens with clear information regarding eligibility to receive a vaccination in a foreign country, if they&#8217;re &#8212; if it&#8217;s confusing or they&#8217;re not sure where to go or what their eligibility is; providing repatriation loans to assist destitute U.S. citizens with travel back to the United States; and helping them review country-specific data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why don’t you go ahead?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Cardona talked a lot about vaccinating students.&nbsp; What about vaccinations for teachers?&nbsp; Has the administration thought about this, especially for teachers who teach students who are too young to be vaccinated?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we know that 90 percent &#8212; it&#8217;s probably higher now &#8212; of student &#8212; of teachers, I should say, across the country are vaccinated.&nbsp; So it certainly has moved in the right direction.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something school districts may make decisions about as it relates to mitigation measures.</p>



<p>But that wouldn&#8217;t be something I would expect from the federal government.&nbsp; It would be something that school districts would determine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, 90 percent of stu- &#8212; of teachers, as of a week or so ago, were vaccinated, which we think is in part because they were prioritized from the beginning and because it has been emphasized by the administration, in part.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Katie.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Governor Abbott of Texas is convening another special session in an effort to pass that much-debated election legislation there.&nbsp; He has also said that the White House’s past objections to this legislation amounts to disinformation, so what is the administration&#8217;s response to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, our fundamental view is that if you are pushing for legislation that makes it harder and not easier to vote, that makes it less accessible, that limits the ability of people to get to the polls, to take time off to do that, then our question is: What are you afraid of here?&nbsp; Are you afraid of more people getting out to vote?&nbsp; Or what&#8217;s the concern?<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, our view is that we need federal legislation, of course, passed to protect people&#8217;s voting rights across the country.&nbsp; There&#8217;s ongoing discussions about that.&nbsp; The President would love to sign federal legislation into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the President think Texas Democrats should stay in town this time?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly the President believes that, one, they&#8217;ve been outspoken advocates and champions of voting rights.&nbsp; And w- &#8212; I can&#8217;t say I&#8217;m exactly following too closely the legislative calendar there, but certainly if it required them to be there, we would support that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, on COVID and vaccines: Working to reach out to Republicans, Senator Lindsey Graham, obviously, tested positive for COVID and spoke out about the importance of the vaccine.&nbsp; Does the President have any plans to try to elevate the voices of Republicans like Senator Graham?&nbsp; Or there&#8217;s a representative from South Carolina today who announced he tested positive &#8212; also Republican &#8212; said he was vaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp;You know, there’s obviously a large swath of the country that is not vaccinated.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a problem in Rep- &#8212; in conservative areas.&nbsp; Does the President or the administration have any more efforts to try to elevate those voices?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first I would say the majority of Republican governors also are doing exactly the right thing in their states.&nbsp; I mean, we talked about Asa Hutchinson earlier.&nbsp; There are a number of governors across the country who are either working with the federal government on resources we can provide, encouraging vaccination, encouraging masking.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not political to us, nor should it be political.&nbsp; And certainly, Senator Graham has a constituency, and we think it&#8217;s great that he&#8217;s out there talking about the impact of the vaccine, even while we wish him a speedy recovery.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note that what we&#8217;ve seen in poll after poll is that the most trusted voices are people in communities, not necessarily elected officials.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s a net positive for elected officials to be out there talking about the efficacy of the vaccine, the fact that they&#8217;re vaccinated, how it&#8217;s &#8212; I know Senator Graham talked about how it protected him from more severe symptoms from COVID.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re still going to focus our emphasis and our efforts on local voices and local trusted leaders in communities because that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve seen is most effective.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just today, Dr. Fauci gave &#8212; you know, talked about Operation Warp Speed, giving credit specifically to Alex Azar and his work.&nbsp; Any more effort to try to get the former President to speak out on this issue?&nbsp; People have said &#8212; you know, Trump officials said that he deserves some more credit, and if Biden did give him that, that could potentially help get more people vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just first say that the President not only talked about the role of the last administration in getting the vaccine approved during the transition, but he talked about it just last week.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t say we&#8217;re shying away from talking about the fact that it was a vaccine that was approved during &#8212; “some of the vaccines,” I should &#8212; approved during a Republican administration and the implementation and effort to get it in the arms of people during a Democratic administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>The former President has said he got the vaccine.&nbsp; He said it was &#8212; people should get it.&nbsp; And if he wants to do that more, then good for him.&nbsp; That&#8217;s good.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the requirement that federal employees be vaccinated or get tested, is there an estimate of the cost of this testing to the federal agencies?&nbsp; And will the administration commit to, once the testing starts, making public how much that is costing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s agency by agency, and obviously it&#8217;s &#8212; we&#8217;re less than a full work week in here, so they&#8217;re going to be &#8212; different agencies are going to be accounting for it different ways, but I certainly think it&#8217;s going to be covered by existing funds and existing budgets of each agency, but it&#8217;s not one federal pot.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we get an accounting of how that is costing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can certainly check and see.&nbsp; But it’s existing funding, so, you know, as people put out their budgets or spending, I&#8217;m sure it would be accounted for in terms of how we&#8217;re planning for and protecting people from COVID.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, funding to cover your testing is included in some of this as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead, Tam.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, I can’t see.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On the international travel working groups, do you have any sort of a timeframe on when their work would be completed, regardless of whether &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Like when the policy would be concluded?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, of when the policy would be concluded.&nbsp; I know you can’t tell us when Delta is going to go away.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean, our goal is to have the policy ready when we&#8217;re safe to reopen to travel, so it&#8217;s hard to determine what that looks like.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have a better estimate as we see what&#8217;s happening in our country and around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are active ongoing interagency discussions, but I don&#8217;t have an estimate on when it will be formally concluded.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Delta variant and breakthrough infections, there have been more and more, sort of, anecdotal cases of breakthrough infections &#8212; famous people, like Lindsey Graham, getting breakthrough infections.&nbsp; Has the administration thought about or reconsidered the way it talks about the incidence of breakthrough infections, how rare they are, what they look like? Is there any consideration of acknowledging in a more fulsome way that, yes, these are kind of happening on a semi-regular basis?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have said that.&nbsp; They are &#8212; they are happening.&nbsp; I think the most important thing, though, is that vaccines are doing exactly what they should be doing, which is protecting people &#8212; the vast majority of people &#8212; from severe illness, from hospitalization.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, there&#8217;s data that&#8217;s come out in a number of the states that has been &#8212; have been hardest hit, even in the last couple of weeks.&nbsp; Almost 100 percent of the new hospitalizations in Alabama are with unvaccinated folks.&nbsp; In Florida, officials have said that more than 95 percent of those hospitalized were not vaccinated.&nbsp; In Ohio, 99 percent of Ohio COVID-19 deaths, hospitalizations in 2021 were unvaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our objective is to project to people very clearly how vaccines can save your life.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean that every person who has a vaccine will not test positive for COVID.&nbsp; We know there are breakthrough cases around the country.&nbsp; As more people get vaccinated, there will be more just as a percentage, just by numbers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We certainly acknowledge that, but I think it&#8217;s also important for people to understand the benefit of vaccination, which is that it can save your life, it can prevent you from going to the hospital, and that&#8217;s where we&#8217;re trying to alleviate confusion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I’m told you have an out.&nbsp; Do you have time for one more?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Why don’t we go to you in the back.&nbsp; Oh, hello, Nadia.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Is the White House worried about the threat and counterthreat between Israel and Iran, and the high rhetoric with the threat of the Israelis launching a military strike against Iran?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, of course, Israel, as a sovereign country, has the right to defend itself, and we certainly recognize that first and foremost.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We, of course, are working with the international community and have concerns about the escalating activity we&#8217;ve seen as it relates to the seized tanker, the Asphalt Princess, also the Mercer Street attack.&nbsp; And these are all certainly issues that are of concern to us and of concern to the international community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We feel it follows a pattern of attacks and other belligerent behavior.&nbsp; And these actions also threaten freedom of navigation through crucial waterways &#8212; something that is posing a risk to a range of countries around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I would also note that we know our British partners have called for action, called for steps in a coordinated way from international bodies, including the United Nations, which we would certainly support.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks so much, everybody.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you support the booster shots?&nbsp; Jen, do you support the booster shots?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We support them if the FDA approves them.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have enough supply &#8212; that&#8217;s the good news.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;3325</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/bill-signed-h-r-3325/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, August 5, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 3325, which provides for the award of four Congressional Gold Medals to the United States Capitol Police and those who protected the U.S. Capitol on January 6, 2021.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, August 5, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 3325, which provides for the award of four Congressional Gold Medals to the United States Capitol Police and those who protected the U.S. Capitol on January 6, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the First Interagency Task Force Meeting on Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity&#160;(PAVE)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/readout-of-the-first-interagency-task-force-meeting-on-property-appraisal-and-valuation-equity-pave/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26305</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration Launches first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals Today, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development Secretary Marcia L. Fudge and Domestic Policy Advisor Ambassador Susan Rice convened the first principal-level meeting for the Interagency Task Force on Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity (PAVE). They were joined by senior leadership from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration Launches first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals</em></p>



<p>Today, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development Secretary Marcia L. Fudge and Domestic Policy Advisor Ambassador Susan Rice convened the first principal-level meeting for the Interagency Task Force on Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity (PAVE). They were joined by senior leadership from Cabinet and independent agencies that have been invited to participate in the Task Force.</p>



<p>Task Force members discussed how current appraisal practices are a significant contributor to the disparity in housing values. The practice of comparing properties within similar neighborhoods can be a proxy for racial demographics, which leads to the perpetuation and exacerbation of the legacy of segregation and redlining. The group identified near- and long-term opportunities to advance equity in home appraisals that will help narrow the racial wealth gap and reinvest in communities that have been historically left behind. The Task Force Members will work together and consult with civil rights organizations, advocacy groups, industry, and philanthropic entities to drive change.</p>



<p>Additionally, Task Force members agreed that the scope of the Task Force will be to:</p>



<ol><li>Ensure that government oversight and industry practice further valuation equity;</li><li>Combat valuation bias through educating the consumer and training the practitioner;</li><li>Ensure equity in valuation by making available high-quality data;</li><li>Create a comprehensive approach to combating valuation bias through enforcement and other efforts.</li></ol>



<p>The Task Force is chaired by Secretary Fudge and Ambassador Rice, and includes cabinet-level leaders from executive departments and additional members from independent agencies. The Task Force will deliver a final action report within 180 days.</p>



<p>The Task Force membership is comprised of the following officials:</p>



<ul><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (co-chair)</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy (co-chair)</li><li>Director of the National Economic Council</li><li>Attorney General of the United States</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Comptroller of the Currency (OCC)</li><li>Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve</li><li>Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC)</li><li>Chairman of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)</li><li>Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration and the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council</li><li>Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB)</li><li>Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency (FHFA)</li><li>Appraisal Subcommittee (ASC)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
