<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 22:22:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/02/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 22:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Duluth, Minnesota 12:13 P.M. EST      MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Hey, everybody.  Okay.  So, today, the President and the First Lady are traveling to Superior, Wisconsin, to discuss build &#8212; building a better America and how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers for the American people by rebuilding roads and bridges, and creating&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Duluth, Minnesota</p>



<p>12:13 P.M. EST</p>



<p>     MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Hey, everybody.  Okay.  So, today, the President and the First Lady are traveling to Superior, Wisconsin, to discuss build &#8212; building a better America and how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers for the American people by rebuilding roads and bridges, and creating good-paying union jobs.<br><br>     As the President said last night, we’re done talking about infrastructure week; we are moving into infrastructure decade.<br><br>     Thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we will see historic investments in infrastructure that will create a visible impact in the lives of American families across the country for years to come.<br><br>     Today, the President will visit the Blantnik &#8212; Blatnik &#8212; hopefully I said that right &#8212; Bridge &#8212; excuse me, for the Wis- &#8212; folks from Wisconsin &#8212; a bridge that serves as a critical link for the community and local economy but is nearing the end of its usable life.<br><br>     The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law includes a total of $40 billion in funding to repair, rehabilitate, and replace bridges. Over the next year, states will start repair on over 1,500 bridges. <br><br>     The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law also supports a number of projects in the region, including restoring the St. Louis River and Great Lakes, investing in port infrastructure for the Port of Superior, and help improve climate resilience in the region.<br><br>     Last night &#8212; just a little bit more about last night &#8212; you heard the President speak directly to the American people about his vision to build a better America, where he laid out the progress of the &#8212; of last year in the face of deep challenges; the character, courage, and resilience of the American people; and his optimism for the future; and his resounding belief that it’s never a good bet to bet against the American people.<br><br>     He sent clear a message to the world: The U.S. and our Allies are united against Russia’s aggression, and that Putin’s war of choice has already had devastating impacts on the Russian economy.  For those here at home and abroad, democracy will prevail over autocracy.<br><br>     He also laid out the economic strategy of his administration, which is producing historic results, which his plan &#8212; with his plan to lower costs for American families while continuing an historically strong economic recovery.<br><br>     The President also talked about how he &#8212; how we have entered a new phase in our battle against COVID-19 where, because of the tools we have, we are moving safely to our normal routines.<br><br>     He also discussed his Unity Agenda for this country and reminded Congress there are lots of places the two parties do agree.  And they should &#8212; they shouldn’t let politics get in the way of getting those things done for the American public.<br><br>     With that, Darlene, what you got for me?<br><br>     Q    Yes, thank you.  The President&#8217;s announcement last night about banning Russian flights from U.S. airspace: Do you have any more details on that, in terms of when does it go into effect?  Did it go into effect last night with his announcement or some date in the future?  The number of flights we&#8217;re talking about?  Those kinds of details.<br><br>     MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Sure.  So we are issuing orders blocking Russian aircraft and airlines from entering and using all domestic U.S. airspace, effectively closing U.S. airspace to all Russian commercial air carriers and other Russian aircraft &#8212; civil aircraft.<br><br>     Just to give you a little bit of update: Russia&#8217;s national airline, Aero- &#8212; Aeroflot has &#8212; has about 14 flights to the U.S. a week, in addition to private &#8212; private planes and cargo planes as well.<br><br>     Q    And is that effective now or &#8212;<br><br>     MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Let’s see.  I do have something on that.<br><br>     So, at the moment, the Department of Transportation and its Federal Aviation Administration are issuing orders today blocking Russian aircraft and airlines from entering and using all domestic U.S. airspace.<br><br>     Q    And then on a related Russia question: Yesterday, the governor of Oklahoma and also Senator Rob Portman called on the President to do two things.  They are interested in seeing the United States sanction Russia&#8217;s oil and gas industry.  And at the same time, they also would like to see the Biden administration increase domestic oil production.  Senator Wyden also would like to see the U.S. increase domestic oil production.<br><br>     MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So here&#8217;s what I have for you on that: As we have said, we&#8217;re intentionally &#8212; we &#8212; we have intentionally scoped our sanctions measures to maximize pain on the Russian economy and minimize any spillover to the U.S. and our Allies and <s>patterns</s> [partners].<br><br>     Given high oil and gas prices, cutting &#8212; cutting off Russian oil/gas will drive prices up to Putin&#8217;s benefit.  We carved out energy-related payments to allow for orderly transition of these flows away from sanction institutions.  And we will provide other licenses as necessary.<br><br>     President Biden has been very clear with the American people that because of Putin&#8217;s reckless and dangerous sanctions, this won&#8217;t be painless, as he has said before, as I just mentioned.  But we are closely monitoring energy supplies for any disruption and continuing to coordinate with major oil-producing consumers, producers to protect American businesses and consumers, including from rising prices at the pump.<br><br>     And that&#8217;s why he announced, last night, the International Energy &#8212; Energy Agency to release 60 million &#8212; million barrels of oil around the world.  And that&#8217;s what he did last night.<br><br>     Thirty of those million will be our share.  And so this is &#8212; this is in partnership with what we&#8217;ve done.    So this is, if you think about what he did in the fall, it was like a record 50 million barrels that we &#8212; that we&#8217;ve tapped into &#8212; into the SPR.  And we were able to do that with China, Japan, India, South Korea, and the United Kingdom.  The International Energy Agency is 30 members.  So this is &#8212; you know, this is what we&#8217;re able to do. <br><br>     So the President has a plan for addressing the real impacts to people&#8217;s pocketbooks.  I can give you a little bit more on what the &#8212; what that&#8217;s going to look like, because we have some updates here.<br><br>     So we put out &#8212; as far as the SPR, we put out the notice today to begin the bidding process &#8212; usually, it takes about 13 days for buyers &#8212; like major gas companies, Exxon Mobil, Chevron &#8212; or gas-trading entities to bid and win the millions of barrel &#8212; barrels released as part of our SPR.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By April or May, the crude oil will make the way out of the pipeline, get to a refinery to be made into gas; gas prices will decline thanks to the SPR release because there is an additional supply of oil coming.&nbsp; Price will stop &#8212; go up due to &#8212; will &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, it&#8217;s getting a little bumpy.&nbsp; Hold on, everybody.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; price &#8212; price will still go up due to conflict in Russia but less than it would have because of the agreement with the IEA &#8212; again, 30 members &#8212; helps countries around the world, not just USA.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if you look at what we did with the SPR back in the fall, it brought down &#8212; they brought down prices by 10 &#8212; more than 10 cents a gallon over the holiday season.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re optimistic.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So does &#8212; Karine, just to follow up on sanctions.&nbsp; Jen said this morning in some of her television interviews that sanctions against Russian oil and gas was on the table.&nbsp; And the President, I believe, echoed the same thing when he spoke to reporters before coming to JBA.&nbsp; But it sounds, from what you just said, like that is very unlikely.&nbsp; Is there &#8212; can you just explain that discrepancy?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And you must have been very early if you saw Jen this morning.&nbsp; You must have been up very early if you saw this morning, with Darlene.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, look, we don&#8217;t have a strategic interest in reducing the global supply of energy.&nbsp; So you&#8217;ve heard Jen talk about that &#8212; the effect of what would happen with the global supply here.&nbsp; So that would raise prices at the gas pump for Americans and pad Putin’s profits, right?&nbsp; So that&#8217;s something that we&#8217;re very aware of.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ve seen some American companies decide to cut ties with Russia, and we welcome those announcements.&nbsp; But, you know, we and our Allies and partners have a strong collective interest to degrade Russia status as a leading energy supplier over time.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve been talking about, you know, diversification, you know, and that&#8217;s why we shut down Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re helping to accelerate Europe&#8217;s diver- &#8212; diversification from Russian gas.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re denying critical technology inputs that Russia needs to sustain its production capacity in oil and gas.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that&#8217;s kind of our strategic focus at the moment.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There has to be at least some acknowledgement of the irony of the United States and Western countries sanctioning Russia but continuing to buy its fuel.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I mean, here&#8217;s the thing: Again, there&#8217;s the global supply of energy that we really have to think about.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want to pad Putin’s &#8212; Putin’s profits.&nbsp; And we want to make sure that we don&#8217;t raise prices on the American public.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that is our focus here.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re doing everything that we can.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s why we talked about diversification &#8212; make sure we&#8217;re not just relying on that source, on Russia&#8217;s oil.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to continue to work on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been assisting our European partners.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s going to be our focus right now.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other sanctions question.&nbsp; Can you confirm that the United States is preparing additional sanctions against Russian oligarchs and others in Russia?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any anything to preview at this time.&nbsp; As you know, we&#8217;re going after Russian oligarchs and their families supporting Putin&#8217;s war of choice.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, you know, look, Russia has become a global economic and financial pariah.&nbsp; Over 30 countries, representing well over half the world&#8217;s economy, have announced sanctions and export controls on Russia.&nbsp; Putin&#8217;s government is getting kicked off the international financial system.&nbsp; We are preventing Putin from accessing his war chest to soften the blow of our sanctions and support his invasion of Ukraine.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This week, alongside our Allies and partners, we announced unprecedented actions to prevent President Putin from accessing his war chest.&nbsp; We prohibited transactions with Central Bank of Russia, the single most important financial institution in Russia.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you know, again, we&#8217;ve done this with our partners and Allies.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s going to be what we&#8217;re going to continue to do: work &#8212; work in lockstep with European Allies.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are more in the works?&nbsp; That&#8217;s my question.&nbsp; Are more &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict at this time.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, can we ask you just to move in a little bit, maybe?&nbsp; Just to get &#8212; sorry.&nbsp; Getting lost in the doorway.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; The bumpiness &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; It’s a little hard to hear you.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I know, and I have a mask.&nbsp; I’m so sorry, guys.&nbsp; I will do my best.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last night, during the speech, we didn’t hear the President talk explicitly about Build Back Better.&nbsp; And is that the message he&#8217;s sending &#8212; that it&#8217;s officially dead right now on Capitol Hill?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, absolutely not.&nbsp; You know, he &#8212; what the President did last night is he highlighted the major part of his plans &#8212; right? &#8212; to fight inflation &#8212; in addition to continuing work to make more in America, bring more jobs back from overseas, and strengthen our supply chains &#8212; is by lowering costs and lowering the deficit.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is what he&#8217;s been talking about the past several months, about these very popular pieces of components.&nbsp; And so he will cut the cost of prescription drugs, energy, childcare, while making the tax system more fair.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He had the young &#8212; young kid, Joshua, that he met when we went to Ohio, who&#8217;s 13 years old, and they talked about lowering costs of prescription drugs.&nbsp; He has Type 1 diabetes, so does his dad.&nbsp; The cost of insulin is &#8212; has skyrocketed.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It costs companies $10 &#8212; insulin &#8212; insulin &#8212; to make.&nbsp; But, you know, what the companies do is they &#8212; they double &#8212; they raise that 30 &#8212; almost 30 times more.&nbsp; And so, what we&#8217;re trying to talk about is lowering those costs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, you know, by contrast, Republicans are against lowering costs for families because they want to protect tax cuts for the very wealthy and corporations.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we build on the manufacturing resurgence we’ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve overseen and historic job creation we&#8217;ve achieved last year, which the President leaned on when talking about the American Rescue Plan meeting the moment and that &#8212; what that was able to do.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we&#8217;re having constructive conversations with a range of members.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll keep those conversation private, as we&#8217;ve been trying to do these last couple of weeks, couple of months now.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to go comment into specific lawmakers &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But as to the parts of that last night, as you just went through, and you&#8217;re having conversations with lawmakers.&nbsp; But Senator Manchin said last night that he has not been &#8212; the White House hasn&#8217;t reached out to him for any formal conversations about the parts of Build Back Better that the President would like to see passed.&nbsp; Why not have those conversations with Senator Manchin?&nbsp; And when would they happen?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, you&#8217;ve heard Jen say this, you&#8217;ve heard me say this: We&#8217;re just not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are having conversation with members who are very much enthused and excited about what the President&#8217;s plan is and lowering costs, as I just laid out.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to &#8212; going to do.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, the President used the State of the Union as an opportunity to talk about his plan, to talk about lowering costs.&nbsp; And so, clearly, that is something that&#8217;s very important to him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also talked about &#8212; and when you think about those items I just laid out &#8212; prescription drugs, the things that &#8212; you know, that are important at the kitchen table &#8212; those are popular.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Those are really important.&nbsp; That&#8217;s part of, like, his Unity Agenda as well that he laid out yesterday as well.&nbsp; You know, like, we can work in a bipartisan way for the American people and deliver.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President still making calls directly to members about the items in Build Back Better or the package formerly called Build Back Better?&nbsp; Or is that White House aides or other senators that are doing that outreach?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, Nancy, I don&#8217;t have any calls to preview about the President’s di- &#8212; directly speaking to members.&nbsp; You saw him speaking to members on the floor yesterday.&nbsp; He does have conversation pretty regularly.&nbsp; Former senator &#8212; he has a lot &#8212; he knows a lot of those folks &#8212; former Vice President, clearly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview.&nbsp; But I can assure you that White House &#8212; my colleagues at the White House have been in regular contact and in regular touch with folks on the Hill.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s &#8212; what&#8217;s the status on the Iran deal?&nbsp; My colleagues overseas are hearing that a decision is coming one way or the other in the coming days, and I just wonder what you could tell us about where that stands.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, you know, we are in the final stages of complex negotiations.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve been saying, at this final stage, all participants are working to clarify their position on the most difficult issues.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;m not going to go into any specific on the positions of Iran or the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, the administration continues to consult with the P5+1, as well as with Israel and our regional partners, on the best way to move forward.&nbsp; But I would refer you to the State Department.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more question on Russia.&nbsp; In terms of Putin, what other steps is the White House or administration considering on how they would target his wealth personally?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more to add.&nbsp; I know the President was asked this when he was headed towards Air Force One, going on Marine One.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more specific or thing &#8212; anything to predict for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, you know, we have said this over and over again, which is: This is a &#8212; we have never seen such a unified West.&nbsp; We are very unified with our European leaders and part- &#8212; European partners and Allies.&nbsp; And NATO is &#8212; our NATO Alliance is also more unified than we&#8217;ve ever seen it before in history.</p>



<p>And so, you know, we are going to continue to work in lockstep and as we &#8212; as we move forward in trying to &#8212; you know, in trying to deal with this Russia aggression that we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; I mean, we &#8212; you know, we have to &#8212; I&#8217;m going to keep saying this: Russia is &#8212; you know, aggression with Ukraine &#8212; is attacking their territorial integrity, their sovereignty, their democracy.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s one thing that the President talked about yesterday: what our values are and fighting for democracy here and abroad.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, does the White House have a position on Americans who might, on their own, travel to Ukraine to answer President Zelenskyy’s call to join the fight?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So &#8212; so Ukrainians have shown their courage, and they are calling on every &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re calling on every resource and lever they have to defend themselves.&nbsp; You know, we applaud their bravery.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, our travel advisory remains.&nbsp; U.S. citizens should not travel to Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so that would specifically include &#8212; is that advice to Americans to not go and fight in another nation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, the State Department has &#8212; issues travel advisories and warnings to help Americans make the most informed decisions about their safety.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what I would refer you to.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you got a reaction to Sergey Lavrov’s latest nuclear saber-rattling?&nbsp; He said that World War Three would be “nuclear and destructive.”</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, again, you know, this is &#8212; this is a war of choice by President Putin.&nbsp; This is his decision that he has made.&nbsp; We are going to continue to work with our European Allies, our European partners, you know, and do &#8212; do that in lockstep.&nbsp; But this is &#8212; this is President Putin&#8217;s war that he has started.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the President did not mention January 6th last night.&nbsp; Was that a conscious decision to exclude that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President has talked about January 6th many times.&nbsp; And he has spoken about it &#8212; about the horrific events of January 6th, as well as the specific steps we must take to ensure something like that can never happen again, including move &#8212; moving &#8212; movingly in the Capitol itself to commemorate one year since the attack.&nbsp; That&#8217;s ju- &#8212; the anniversary that just passed &#8212; this past January 6th.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the President spoke last night about the need to uphold Constitution, protect democracy both here and around the world, as I just stated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; There&#8217;s an effort in North Carolina to throw Madison Cawthorn off the ballot for being an insurrectionist.&nbsp; Has the President given that approach any thought?&nbsp; Does he endorse that?&nbsp; What does he think about people who encouraged that to be able to run again?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I leave that the &#8212; the decision &#8212; or refer you to the state board of elections.&nbsp; That&#8217;s for them to decide.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, we haven’t seen &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a couple on COVID.&nbsp; Last night, the President talked about entering a new phase or new moment in the pandemic.&nbsp; A lot of the lawmakers and people who were at the State of the Union obviously didn&#8217;t wear a mask because the guidance has changed.&nbsp; Does the President now think that it&#8217;s safe for children in school to go mask-free indoors, in school also?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, you know, today the Biden administration released a National COVID Preparedness Plan, as you all know.&nbsp; This is a plan to keep America moving forward safely and keep getting us back to our normal routines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s a plan that focuses on three key goals, which is protect against COVID-19, prepare for new variants, prevent economic and educational shutdowns.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, on protection: Unlike at the start of the pandemic, we know &#8212; we now &#8212; pardon me &#8212; have multiple tools to protect ourselves.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; There&#8217;s vaccines, treatments, test, masks.</p>



<p>Second, we&#8217;re preparing for new variants.&nbsp; That includes early warning signs and stockpiling resources.</p>



<p>Third, preventing economic and educational shutdowns.&nbsp; We will continue to be an arsenal of vaccines for the world.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ve already donated just under 500 million vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Throughout this plan, we ensure we are protecting the most vulnerable, including the immun- &#8212; immunocompromised and those with disabilities.&nbsp; The immunocompromise have &#8212; -compromised have access to a fourth booster and priority access to new treatments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have free high-quality masks and more free tests than ever before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re launching a comprehensive response to prevent, treat, and better under &#8212; understand Long COVID and to address mental health.</p>



<p>Executing this plan will require additional congressional funding, which you heard the President talk about last night &#8212; that supplemental funding &#8212; soon.&nbsp; And so, the administration will send Congress a request for additional funding, given that virtually all Americans have used these tools and may want to, again, expect Congress &#8212; we expect Congress to pass it quickly.</p>



<p>Jeff Zients, Secretary Becerra, Dr. Walensky, and Dr. Fauci &#8212; they all briefed on &#8212; to your colleagues earlier today, about an hour ago.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s kind of where we are. &nbsp;But to your question, Darlene &#8212; I just wanted to kind of lay that out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, to your question: As we&#8217;ve always said, those decisions are left to the school &#8212; the school districts and to the schools to make.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve always said: Follow &#8212; you know, follow the experts, listen to the experts.&nbsp; And we try to follow the CDC guidance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more.&nbsp; Again, last night, you had a situation where people are free to go mask free, and a lot of them did that last night, but then you saw people sitting in a socially distant fashion.&nbsp; So was there kind of a mixed message there where, on the one hand, the President says to people, “You know, we&#8217;re in a new phase.&nbsp; Go back to work.&nbsp; Flood downtown again,” but you have people sitting socially distant (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; To that &#8212; to that in particular, that was a Cap- &#8212; that&#8217;s the Capitol.&nbsp; I refer you to them.&nbsp; That was &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I fully understand it was a decision by the Capitol.&nbsp; But just the image overall and what that says to people as we&#8217;re telling them, “It&#8217;s okay to go mask-free again.”</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, what I&#8217;ll say to that &#8212; look, we are in a different place than we are &#8212; than we were a year ago, and that&#8217;s just the fact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When the President walked into the administration, he was dealing with multiple crises.&nbsp; The economy and COVID were the two main ones that were front and center.&nbsp; And in that time &#8212; in that year&#8217;s time, the President has been able to &#8212; along with his team has been able to fully vaccinate more than 210 million people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, that is a success that we can all be proud of.&nbsp; And like &#8212; as I just laid out, we know &#8212; we now have the tools that help us figure out how to move forward and get to a place where things are more normal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is just, you know, a next part of the process.&nbsp; And so, you know, again, we&#8217;re going to follow the CDC guidance &#8212; guidelines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (The plane experiences turbulence.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Ah!&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; We almost lost Jeff Mason. &nbsp;My goodness.&nbsp; He has his cool Reuters jacket on, too.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, for the President personally last night &#8212; he hasn&#8217;t had an event like that where you had that many people in one space not wearing masks, and he seemed to be feeding off of that a bit.&nbsp; Can you talk about how he felt afterwards about being in an environment that we haven&#8217;t seen him in in maybe two years?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; As we all know, the President loves to communicate directly with people.&nbsp; And, you know, as we&#8217;ve been saying for the past week or so, the State of the Union was an opportunity to talk to millions of Americans.&nbsp; It&#8217;s once-in-a year opportunity to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know &#8212; and this is a President who was a senator for almost four decades, who was a vice president for eight years.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been in that room, and he knows what it means to have that bully pulpit, if you will, to have that &#8212; to have that microphone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, his goal yesterday was to talk about the &#8212; this past year &#8212; yes, the challenges, but how we&#8217;ve been able to be resilient and how the economy has thrived, where we are with COVID, but also the challenges that lie ahead; our support, clearly, for Ukraine with Russia&#8217;s aggression into the country &#8212; attacking their sovereignty &#8212; but also how we’re going to speak to those kitchen table issues that Americans deal with every day &#8212; those high costs.&nbsp; And also, he talked about his Unity Agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there was a lot that he covered.&nbsp; But, look, like I said, that &#8212; yesterday was an opportunity, which he understood very well, that &#8212; you know, to reach out to &#8212; directly to the American public.&nbsp; And he was happy to see some of his former colleagues and have that direct conversation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President &#8212; will he resume large, indoor maskless gatherings now?&nbsp; Is that what we can expect moving forward?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t &#8212; as we all know, the CDC guidance is &#8212; it all depends on the area that you&#8217;re in. Like we are about to land in Wisconsin.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to Superior, Wisconsin, as you all know, and we have to wear a mask because it is a red zone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it is really going to, you know, depend on where we are and what we &#8212; the CDC guidance that we need to follow for that particular area.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President have a reaction to the interruption last night by the &#8212; I think it was two Republican congresswomen right around the time when he was talking about his son?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, you know, we grieve alongside these Gold Star families.&nbsp; We do not pretend to understand the depths of their grief, but we respect their concerns and their unique perspectives about the loss of their loved ones.&nbsp; So, they were part of the bravest, most capable, and the most selfless military on the face of the Earth.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I actually wasn&#8217;t &#8212; I wasn&#8217;t actually asking about Gold Star families.&nbsp; I was asking about the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; One of the members actually &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was that Boebert?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; She was &#8212; yeah, that’s what she was talking about.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I see.&nbsp; I thought she said, “Build the wall.”</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was someone else that shouted “Build the wall,” I think.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It might’ve been someone else.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have one final question for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there &#8212; are you aware of any reaction or comment from the President to Major League Baseball&#8217;s decision to cancel Opening Day?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I do have something on that.&nbsp; So collective bargaining is a private dispute-resolution process in which the parties to the negotiation work out their differences and agree to the terms and conditions of employment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Major League Baseball negotiations are a matter for the players, the league, and the owners.&nbsp; Baseball fans may have some opinions as well.&nbsp; We leave that to them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The best role for government is to encourage the parties to comment &#8212; to commit themselves fully to collective bargaining that reaches an agreement.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how we feel here.</p>



<p>We encourage Major League Baseball and the Major League Baseball Players Association to stay at the bargaining table and reach an agreement as soon as they can so we can kick off the season and get back to enjoying baseball games.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>12:41 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House and HHS Public Health Officials, March 2,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/02/press-briefing-by-white-house-and-hhs-public-health-officials-march-2-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 20:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10:40 A.M. EST MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning.&#160; And thanks for joining us today as we release President Biden’s National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan. Today, I’m joined by Secretary Becerra, Dr. Walensky, and Dr. Fauci.&#160; We’ll each deliver some remarks, and then open it up for questions. As President Biden said in last night’s State of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>10:40 A.M. EST</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; And thanks for joining us today as we release President Biden’s National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan.<br><br>Today, I’m joined by Secretary Becerra, Dr. Walensky, and Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; We’ll each deliver some remarks, and then open it up for questions.<br><br>As President Biden said in last night’s State of the Union address, we’ve reached a new moment in the fight against COVID-19.<br><br>Because of the significant progress we’ve made as a country, the determination and resilience of the American people, and the work we’ve done to make tools to protect ourselves widely available, we are moving forward safely, getting back to our more normal routines.&nbsp; And under the latest CDC recommendations, most Americans in most of the country can now be mask free.<br><br>Last night, the President laid out four key goals for the path ahead:<br><br>First, protect against and treat COVID.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, prepare for any new variants.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, prevent economic and school shutdowns.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fourth, vaccinate the world and save lives.<br><br>The President’s National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan that we’re releasing today will help move us forward safely, sustaining and building on the progress we’ve made over the past 13 months.<br><br>The President’s National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan is robust and comprehensive.<br><br>The President’s plan is the product of many weeks of work with experts inside and outside of government &#8212; local public health leaders, governors, and partners across our federal agencies.&nbsp;<br><br>We thank them for sharing their ideas and expertise.&nbsp; This plan benefits greatly from their valuable input.<br><br>Importantly, executing the President’s plan requires additional congressional support and funding.<br><br>Today, we’ll provide an overview of this plan.<br><br>The first goal: protect against and treat COVID.<br><br>Two years ago, we had limited tools to protect ourselves: masks, isolation, and social distancing.&nbsp; But all of that’s changed.<br><br>Today, we have the tools we need to protect each other and treat COVID-19.&nbsp; They’re widely available for the American people.&nbsp; And with Congress’s help, the President’s plan will make sure that’s always the case.<br><br>We know that vaccines and boosters provide strong protection against severe illness and hospitalization.<br><br>Because of the unprecedented vaccination program we’ve established, 216 million Americans are now fully vaccinated.&nbsp; And two out of three eligible adults now have booster shots, which provide the strongest protection.<br><br>In fact, if you’re vaccinated and boosted, you have an extremely high level of protection against COVID, and it’s extremely unlikely you’ll end up in the hospital if you do get the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>The plan lays out how we’re going to keep working with governors, state and local health officials, and community partners to get even more shots in arms.<br><br>Importantly, we know parents of children under the age of five are eager to provide their kids the protection of a vaccine.<br><br>The President’s plan ensures that as soon as a vaccine is authorized, we’ll be ready with plenty of vaccines and prepared to help parents vaccinate their youngest kids at thousands of trusted and convenient locations across the country.<br><br>In addition to vaccines and boosters, we have filled our nation’s medicine cabinet with effective treatments and therapeutics: monoclonal antibodies, antiviral pills, and preventive therapies for our most vulnerable.&nbsp;<br><br>These treatments work to prevent the worst outcomes of COVID-19.&nbsp; And we have more treatments available for the American people than ever before &#8212; millions of treatments each month.<br><br>Pfizer’s pill is a gamechanger &#8212; 90 percent effective at keeping people out of the hospital.<br><br>We collaborated with Pfizer to accelerate development of the pill.&nbsp; And we’ve ordered 20 million courses.<br><br>As the President announced last night, Pfizer worked overtime to further accelerate delivery.&nbsp; This month alone &#8212; the month of March &#8212; we’ll have 1 million of these treatment courses available.&nbsp; And in April, that number will more than double.<br><br>To ensure these lifesaving treatments are easily accessible, the President’s Plan launches a new &#8220;Test to Treat&#8221; initiative to provide individuals access to testing and treatment for free, all in one stop.&nbsp;<br><br>Hundreds of one-stop sites will open across the country this month, located at local pharmacy clinics, community health centers, long-term care facilities, and veterans’ health centers.<br><br>The President’s plan, with support from Congress, ensures other important tools, like tests and high-quality masks are widely available, accessible, and free.<br><br>As the President announced last night, if you’ve already gotten your free tests from COVIDTests.gov &#8212; COVIDTests.gov &#8212; starting next week, you’ll be able to place a second order for tests delivered straight to your home.&nbsp;<br><br>And we continue to make hundreds of millions of high-quality N-95 masks available to Americans for free at local pharmacies, grocery stores, and community health centers across the country.&nbsp;<br><br>Vaccines, treatments, tests, masks &#8212; these tools are how we continue to protect people.<br><br>They enable us to move forward safely and get back to our more normal routines &#8212; going out to eat at a restaurant; taking that trip that’s been long delayed; arranging a playdate for your kids; attending a sports game, a movie, or a concert again.<br><br>To make sure people have the tools they need to protect themselves, we’ll launch a website later this month that will be a go-to place where you can find vaccines and masks at easy and convenient locations, and where you can find the latest information on COVID-19 in your community.<br><br>Now, let me turn it over to Secretary Becerra to cover how the President’s plan will allow us to keep distributing these tools and ensures we continue to advance equity.<br><br>Secretary?<br><br>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; And good morning to everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>Under President Biden’s leadership and in partnership with the White House, we have worked hard at HHS to fight this virus.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve authorized, procured, and distributed our national supply of tests, vaccines, and treatments to every corner of the country.&nbsp; We’ve conducted groundbreaking and lifesaving research to improve our understanding of the disease and how it impacts us.&nbsp; And now we move into this next phase to execute President Biden’s National COVID Preparedness Plan.<br><br>Our mission remains to protect the health and wellbeing of every American.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky will add further specifics, but I want to focus on how we’re going to reach every American who needs our support on COVID.<br><br>To ensure we can continue to accelerate and synchronize the research, development, production, and delivery of COVID vaccines and treatments to keep Americans safe, the President’s National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan makes our logistics and operational hub at HHS permanent.<br><br>We call this permanent hub the HHS Coordination Operations and Response Element &#8212; or H-CORE.&nbsp; Under the leadership of Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response Dawn O’Connell, she and her team at H-CORE build on the successful partnership HHS has had with our dedicated colleagues at DOD, as well as our state and local partners.<br><br>Through it, we have delivered more than 690 million doses of vaccines and 4 million treatments to families nationwide.<br><br>To date, we have distributed more than 270 million free N95 masks to local pharmacies and community health centers and helped get free COVID tests to 70 million households.<br><br>No matter what the future holds, H-CORE must be ready, and Americans deserve to know that we have the infrastructure in place to get critical services and supplies where they are needed.<br><br>Another key goal of the President’s plan moving forward is to address the long-term impacts of COVID, including Long COVID and mental health.<br><br>As the President said last night, his plan directs the federal government to accelerate its efforts to detect, prevent, and treat Long COVID, building on our ongoing work, already, at NIH.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ll further expand our research and ramp up our data-sharing across the federal government, in collaboration with academic, industry, and state and local partners.&nbsp;<br><br>And, if we get the funding from Congress, we will launch new Centers of Excellence in communities across the country to provide high-quality care to individuals experiencing Long COVID and better understand the symptoms they’re facing.&nbsp;<br><br>This is all part of our commitment to be there for Americans who have long-term physical and mental health needs caused by COVID.&nbsp; They know that numbers and statistics alone don’t capture the true toll of COVID-19.&nbsp; It&#8217;s lost job and piling bills.&nbsp; It’s the empty chair at the dinner table or the open seat in the bleachers, the quiet homes, and the crowded hospitals.<br><br>That’s why this administration will coordinate a whole-of-government effort to support children and families who have experienced the loss of a loved one due to COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>This includes leveraging every program at our disposal to address fundamental needs, like financial resources to cover funeral costs to trauma- and grief-informed services.&nbsp;<br><br>We will also launch new support for people dealing with mental health-related challenges, including an expanded program to prevent job burnout and support the mental wellbeing of our nation’s healthcare workforce.&nbsp; We want every frontline, essential healthcare worker to know: We’re with you, and we’ve got your back.<br><br>This week, we’ll launch a nationwide tour to strengthen mental and behavioral health services.&nbsp; We want to engage communities to hear how we can best support Americans who’ve been hit hard.&nbsp; I head to New Hampshire&nbsp;this Friday&nbsp;to kick things off.<br><br>Whether we are working to strengthen mental health, behavioral health; whether we’re authorizing therapeutics or distributing vaccines &#8212; at HHS, we bring our unique capabilities and expertise to the mission.&nbsp;<br><br>As it has from the beginning, fairness for everyone &#8212; equity &#8212; will remain at the center of our work.<br><br>We’ve already seen the power of this intentional approach.&nbsp;<br><br>We have closed disparities in vaccination rates for Black, Latino, and Asian American adults.&nbsp; This historic progress didn’t happen overnight or by accident.&nbsp; It’s the product of dedicated focus and hard work.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve surged resources, including tests and treatment, to our hardest-hit and highest-risk communities.&nbsp; And we’ve safely reopened schools, helping our most vulnerable students have more equitable access to learning and easing the burden on working parents across rural and urban areas.<br><br>Tackling barriers to vaccinations, boosters, testing, and treatments remains a priority for us.&nbsp; This includes making sure people can access these tools for free, wherever you are, and even if you don’t have health insurance.&nbsp;<br><br>And we will continue to address the specific needs of seniors, people living with disabilities, and people who are immunocompromised.&nbsp; These are the Americans who need our focus and attention right now.&nbsp; These are our friends and neighbors,&nbsp;<em>nuestros padres y abuelos</em>&nbsp;&#8212; our family.<br><br>We see you, and we will do everything in our power to protect and support you, including making sure you have access to boosters and treatment.<br><br>Bottom line: As we move forward, we will leave no one behind.&nbsp; President Biden made that clear last night.</p>



<p>With that, let me turn it over to Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Secretary.<br><br>Now, moving to the second goal of the President’s plan: preparing for any new variants.&nbsp;<br><br>We know this virus is unpredictable, so the President’s plan makes clear we’re continuing to take every action within our power to prepare for any possible new variants.<br><br>As Dr. Walensky will discuss in a moment, we’ve taken significant steps to improve monitoring for any new variants.<br><br>America’s variant monitoring system can now detect variants at a very, very low level.&nbsp; If a new variant emerges, we’re able to catch it earlier, faster, and with greater precision.<br><br>And when we do detect a new variant, we’ll be ready to respond quickly.<br><br>We have a COVID-19 variant playbook to rapidly assess a variant’s transmissibility and severity, and its potential impact on vaccines and treatment.<br><br>We’ve put it to the test over the past few weeks with tabletop readiness and response exercises against a fictional variant with HHS, CDC, NIH, FDA, FEMA, and other agencies at the table.<br><br>If needed, we have developed plans and processes that we can produce, authorize, and deliver new vaccines and treatments in just 100 days rather than in many months or years.&nbsp; Funding from Congress will be critical to these efforts.&nbsp;<br><br>The President’s plan also creates new stockpiles of at-home tests, antiviral pills, and high-quality masks, including masks for kids.&nbsp; So, we’re ready for whatever comes.<br><br>Next, the third goal of the President’s plan: prevent economic and school shutdowns.<br><br>We know how to keep our businesses and our schools open with the tools that we have at our disposal.&nbsp; And we’ve shown we can do it, even during the Omicron surge.<br><br>Under the President’s plan, we’ll continue to ensure that our schools, workers, and workplaces have the resources they need.<br><br>This includes the Environmental Protection Agency &#8212; the EPA &#8212; issuing a new clean air in buildings checklist, a set of recommendations to improve indoor air quality through effective ventilation practices.&nbsp;<br><br>As we move forward, the President believes Americans should be able to stay home if they do get COVID so they can protect others and take care of themselves and their loved ones without the added burden of missing a paycheck.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why the President’s plan calls on Congress to reinstate tax credits to help small- and mid-size businesses provide paid sick and family leave to those sick with COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Last, the fourth goal of the President’s plan: vaccinating the world and saving lives.<br><br>Clearly, the virus does not recognize national borders.&nbsp; To protect the American people and our economy, we must defeat the virus everywhere.&nbsp; That means vaccinating Americans and vaccinating people around the world.&nbsp; It’s both the right thing to do and it is in our own national interest.<br><br>Under President Biden, the United States has led the global vaccination effort.&nbsp; We’re donating 1.2 billion doses to the world.&nbsp; In fact, we’ve already shipped 480 million doses in total to 112 countries for free &#8212; no strings attached.&nbsp; That’s four times as many doses shipped as any other country.<br><br>The President’s plan includes continuing to donate more vaccines and doubling down on efforts to turn those vaccines into vaccinations.<br><br>We’re going to help get shots in arms around the world by supporting public education efforts, providing vaccinators in the field, and setting up vaccination sites.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, let me turn to Dr. Walensky to provide more detail on CDC’s work to improve and expand tracking and monitoring of COVID variants.<br><br>And then over to Dr. Fauci to discuss NIH’s work to support the development of new treatments and next-generation vaccines.<br><br>Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; I’m delighted to be with you for today’s announcement.<br><br>As you heard from Jeff and Secretary Becerra, a key element of the President’s National COVID Preparedness Plan is building on the strengths of our public health response to COVID-19, expanding our capacity to respond to new variants, clusters of cases, or outbreaks so we can effectively stay ahead of this virus and protect more people.<br><br>Today, I want to discuss some of CDC’s strategies for monitoring the virus, alerting people in real-time, and adjusting our response as needed.&nbsp;<br><br>These approaches include our National Wastewater Surveillance System and the National Syndromic Surveillance Program to better anticipate a rise in cases; expanded genomic sequencing to quickly identify new variants; and our approach to data modernization and our new Center for Forecasting and Analytics, which is designed to forecast and model emerging health threats and to help inform public health decision making.<br><br>First, surveillance.&nbsp; Last month, CDC publicly released our National Wastewater Surveillance data.&nbsp;&nbsp;For SARS-CoV-2, wastewater can detect an increase in cases four to six days before we might see these cases show up through a rise in positive tests.<br><br>When it was first released publicly two weeks ago, data from the National Wastewater Surveillance System included 400 testing sites across the country in 212 communities, representing over 50 million people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>With continued expansion, we now have 647 testing sites publicly reporting on COVID Data Tracker, and we are onboarding new sites each week.&nbsp; This adds to the National Syndromic Surveillance Program, which collects data on COVID-19 emergency visits from over 70 percent of emergency departments across the country to anticipate where cases are increasing.<br><br>Second, we are expanding our capacity in&nbsp;genomic surveillance so that we can readily detect variants of concern or interest.<br><br>Each week, CDC analyzes genomic sequences from all 50 states and uses these sequences to understand and map the spread of variants across the country, often&nbsp;sequencing tens of thousands of viral samples in a given week.&nbsp;&nbsp;These robust sequencing efforts mean we can reliably identify very low levels of variants, even variants that account for as little as 0.1 percent of all COVID-19 cases in the United States.<br><br>Finally, we continue to invest in and scale up our data modernization efforts, which improve COVID-19 data collection, reporting, analysis, and interoperability so America is better informed and ready to respond to whatever may come next.&nbsp; By connecting data from local public health to our national systems, we work to collect the data today that we will need to answer the critical questions of tomorrow.<br><br>These data can then be used by CDC’s Forecast &#8212; Center for Forecasting and Outbreak Analytics to forecast and model our public health threats and inform our prevention recommendations.&nbsp; CDC is working with state, county, and city jurisdictions to transform independent, local surveillance efforts into a robust, sustainable national system.<br><br>And, we continue to build and strengthen our global collaborations and communication networks to better understand and respond to COVID-19 variants as they emerge.&nbsp; All of these efforts are with a vision for not just COVID, but also to address any future infectious and non-infectious public health threats.<br><br>As we continue to move forward from this pandemic, I&#8217;m confident that CDC and our public health partners are well positioned to use our surveillance and our data to lead the way.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I’ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thanks, Dr. Walensky.<br><br>As Jeff said, vaccines and treatments are key parts of our toolkit moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>In this regard, it is important to point out the unprecedented global research effort that brought us to where we are today in our capability to intervene against COVID.&nbsp; Decades of U.S. investment in fundamental biomedical research provided the foundation for the rapid design and development of COVID-19 vaccines.&nbsp;<br><br>This work includes but is not limited to groundbreaking, structure-based vaccine design by U.S. government scientists at the NIAID Vaccine Research Center.&nbsp;<br><br>As soon as the sequence of SARS-CoV-2 was made available in January of 2020, these researchers rapidly generated a stabilized spike protein as the optimal immunogen for use in vaccine development.</p>



<p>This crucial breakthrough led to the development, in association with industry partners, of multiple COVID-19 vaccine candidates, several of which are now authorized or approved by the FDA.<br><br>These vaccines have now been administered to billions of people around the world, including over 250 million in the United States.&nbsp; They are safe and they work.<br><br>Moving forward, we will continue to prioritize this vital research, including towards a pan-coronavirus vaccine.<br><br>Now, if new variants emerge, we now have faster processes to assess the impact of the virus on our vaccines.&nbsp; And this plan ensures that we are ready to deploy personnel and resources to quickly update the vaccines.<br><br>These expedited plans and processes will help us reach our goal that updated vaccines can be developed, approved, and manufactured in approximately 100 days.<br><br>While we would always rather prevent a case of COVID-19 than treat one, we do have a growing number of therapeutic options, including monoclonal antibodies and antiviral drugs.<br><br>This, too, is a victory for science.&nbsp; NIH-supported basic research and clinical trials infrastructure within the United States and around the world helped the scientific community, in collaboration with our industrial partners, to undertake rigorously designed studies to give us robust data, not just speculation or anecdotes, about safety and efficacy of various treatment options.<br><br>As we face the threat of the Omicron variant, we are fortunate to have several powerful medications that work to keep people out of the hospital.&nbsp; The most recent of these is the Eli Lilly monoclonal antibody co-discovered by NIAID scientists and their collaborators in industry, which is already going out across the country.&nbsp; This powerful medicine works against all the variants that we’ve tested it against.<br><br>And Pfizer’s antivirals are highly effective at reducing the risk of hospitalization and death.&nbsp; One million courses are available just this month.<br><br>Also, the plan announced today calls for continued investment in treatment research for COVID-19.<br><br>NIH also established the COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines Panel to provide up-to-date recommendations to healthcare providers throughout the world regarding specific COVID-19 treatments based on the best available science.&nbsp; The panel meets regularly to evaluate possible treatment options for COVID-19, and they update the guidelines as new clinical evidence emerges.<br><br>However, our work is certainly not done.<br><br>The scientific community continues to conduct vital research to learn more about SARS-CoV-2 and the body’s immune response both during and following infection so that we can adapt and improve vaccines and treatments.&nbsp; In addition, as Secretary Becerra mentioned, we are working to understand better, prevent, and intervene in Long COVID.<br><br>We know that we will have to contend with COVID at some level for some time to come.&nbsp; Thus, we will continue to invest in research to develop better treatments and next-generation vaccines, ones that could provide even broader and longer-lasting protection.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This ongoing research investment is not only helping us turn the corner on COVID-19 but also is vital to preparing us for future pandemics.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, I will turn it back over to you, Jeff.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Doctors.<br><br>Let me close with this: By protecting against and treating COVID, preparing for any new variants, preventing economic and school shutdowns, and vaccinating the world and saving lives, the President’s COVID-19 Preparedness Plan will enable us to move forward safely, to get back to our more normal routines.<br><br>The President’s Plan is robust and comprehensive.&nbsp; And I want to emphasize that execution of the President’s Plan requires additional funding.<br><br>HHS has laid out some immediate funding needs for Congress.&nbsp; We’ll need additional funding for medium- and longer-term priorities, and we’ll be working with Congress in the weeks ahead.<br><br>President Biden came into office facing the worst public health crisis in more than a century.<br><br>Over the past 13 months, we’ve leveraged the full force of the federal government to fight COVID.&nbsp; And together, with the leadership of governors and local health officials, the innovation of the private sector, and the determination of the American people, we have made tremendous progress.<br><br>We’ve delivered the tools Americans need to protect themselves, reopened our schools, and gotten our economy moving again.<br><br>The President’s Plan will build on that progress.&nbsp; And with congressional support, we look forward to executing this plan in the year ahead.<br><br>With that, Kevin, let’s open it up for questions.<br><br>Kevin?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; We have a good amount of questions today and some limited time, so let’s keep it to one question.</p>



<p>First, let’s go to Jeremy Diamond at CNN.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks, all, for doing this.&nbsp; I’m curious &#8212; a couple things.&nbsp; First of all, when will it be the appropriate time to remove the domestic travel mask mandate, given the lowered risk of COVID and your new plan?</p>



<p>And secondly, you know, when you say and when the President said last night that you want to start treating this disease like others and having it be less disruptive to people&#8217;s daily lives, do you foresee a time where people no longer need to isolate when they test positive for COVID, particularly if they don&#8217;t have symptoms?&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, why don&#8217;t I take the first question, which was on domestic air travel.&nbsp; And then Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>Last week&#8217;s guidance from CDC on masking did not change air and rail travel requirements, including the requirements to wear a mask on public transportation.&nbsp; Those requirements are currently in place through March 18th, and they’ll continue to be so while we evaluate &#8212; leading up to March 18th &#8212; the duration of the requirement based on the state of the virus.</p>



<p>So, no change, but an evaluation taking place at this point.</p>



<p>Dr. Walensky?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for that question, Jeremy.</p>



<p>We always prefer to have people who might be infectious with an infectious disease home and not transmitting to others, certainly during your most infectious period of time &#8212; that first two or three before your symptoms and the two or three days after your symptoms is the time that you&#8217;re most infectious.</p>



<p>Certainly, we may consider to revisit that at some future time.&nbsp; But right now, with about 68,000 cases around the country daily, we&#8217;re not looking at revisiting that right now.</p>



<p>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I want to ask about one-way masking, since that seems to be the advice for anyone who isn&#8217;t ready to take their mask off yet and particularly kids under five or immunocompromised people.</p>



<p>So, specifically, what do you need to wear to ensure that you&#8217;re protected if you&#8217;re one-way masking?&nbsp; I know we&#8217;ve spoken about N95s, but if they&#8217;re not available to kids and aren&#8217;t very comfortable, can we lean on surgical masks or KN95s as good enough?</p>



<p>And my second question is: How much funding does this plan require in total?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, on masking?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, certainly.&nbsp; So, certainly, the best possible mask is one that you can keep on for a durable period of time.&nbsp; We have commented on our CDC website, and we have guidance for this, that you certainly want two-layered masks, something that fits snugly over your nose and mouth, generally with a wire bridge.</p>



<p>Of course, if you can tolerate a better-fitting mask, a higher-quality mask for a longer period of time, those are always preferred.&nbsp; So those would be your N95s and your KN95s, and then, as well, your surgical masks.</p>



<p>So, all of those data are complete on our CDC website.&nbsp; But really, we want to make sure that people can tolerate them for long periods of time and, if you can, that you increase the quality of the mask you wear.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; I think your second question was on funding.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll handle that.</p>



<p>HHS and the State Department, along with USAID, have identified and briefed bipartisan leaders in Congress on the near-term funding that is needed.&nbsp; This includes resources to secure more medical supplies, including vaccines, treatments, and boosters; sustaining the testing capacity in the country; investing, as Dr. Fauci talked, about in research and development of next-generation vaccines, including pan-coronavirus vaccines; and accelerating vaccine uptake globally.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s clearly broad support from the American people for securing these critical medical supplies so we&#8217;re protected and we&#8217;re prepared for any possible variant.</p>



<p>We will need additional funding beyond these immediate needs to effectively execute on the medium- and longer-term priorities and policies in today&#8217;s plan.</p>



<p>As we finalize these numbers, we will communicate that with Congress and look forward to working closely with Congress going forward.</p>



<p>Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Tamara Keith at NPR.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; Related to the masks, leads to another question &#8212; what about Title 42 that is in effect as a public health emergency?&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, are you reconsidering the status of Title 42, along with some of the other guidance?</p>



<p>Additionally, I noticed that Secretary Becerra is here at this briefing as you all move from a crisis footing to more of a long-term management mode.&nbsp; Are you shifting primary management of COVID to HHS from the White House?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, great.&nbsp; Thank you, Tamara.&nbsp; So, we continue to reevaluate Title 42 every several weeks, every four to eight weeks, and we will continue to do so throughout the duration of time of this pandemic.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; On Secretary Becerra, I&#8217;ll go first.&nbsp; And if you want to &#8212;</p>



<p>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; &#8212; add anything.&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve said before, Secretary Becerra has been an essential partner throughout the COVID response, and that work continues going forward.</p>



<p>The Secretary is leading many of the critical COVID efforts at HHS, like managing the operational and logistical structure to deliver hundreds of millions of vaccines, tests, and treatments across the country; focusing on the long-term impacts of COVID, as he discussed today, like Long COVID, mental health challenges, and the tragedy of losing someone they love.</p>



<p>So this is very much business as usual.&nbsp; We have a very close working relationship and partnership, talking and meeting many times, most weeks.&nbsp; Secretary Becerra?</p>



<p>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; I’ll only add that, from the beginning, the President put together a team, and that&#8217;s the way it&#8217;s continued to work.&nbsp; HHS is a principal partner in that team.&nbsp;<br><br>H-CORE, the new organization that I mentioned, is going to be indispensable for the execution of this plan.&nbsp; And H-CORE has learned from the lessons that we saw from Operation Warp Speed, when DOD had more jurisdiction and was more in charge.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But now that it is permanently housed here at HHS, you&#8217;ll continue to see much of the execution, once the plans are in place and the President gives a signal, emanating from HHS, as you can see from the presentations today.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, it&#8217;s all the team effort, and it&#8217;s about getting the job done.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Emma Court at Bloomberg.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for holding this.&nbsp; I was hoping you could speak about how confident the government is about its COVID monitoring systems moving forward, especially given that so many of the precautions are now being relaxed.&nbsp; Will we have enough notice if another surge develops?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, so that is instrumental in what we&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp; We have great collaborations globally so that if a variant were to &#8212; of concern were to emerge globally, we are in touch globally.&nbsp;<br><br>And then we have all of the systems that we talked about &#8212; our wastewater system; our syndromic surveillance system; our genomic surveillance system; our enhanced genomic surveillance system, which is how we found a case of Omicron within days of knowing that it existed in other countries.</p>



<p>So, yes, we are confident.&nbsp; We continue to scale up these efforts and are grateful for the resources from Congress to be able to do so.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Sheryl Stolberg, New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for doing this call.&nbsp; A couple of questions.&nbsp; First, to Dr. Walensky, we&#8217;re still at about 60,000 cases a day, which is more than five times the low of June 2021.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m wondering: Is there a threshold of daily cases at which you would feel comfortable recommending that the travel mask mandate be lifted?</p>



<p>And then, for Dr. Fauci, I&#8217;m interested in the likelihood of a universal coronavirus vaccine.&nbsp; A flu &#8212; universal flu vaccine has been a dream for a long time and it hasn&#8217;t happened, so how soon would you envision a universal coronavirus vaccine?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, first.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, I want to just comment, Sheryl, that the qualitative &#8212; how these cases are in February or March of 2022 is just very different than where we were in June of 2021.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is because of all the tools that we have now.&nbsp; It&#8217;s because Omicron in general is a milder variant.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s also because of the massive amount of vaccination we&#8217;ve been doing, the massive amount of boosting we&#8217;ve been doing, as well as the protection that we can get from our therapeutics in this moment.&nbsp; So I think that it&#8217;s not necessary that we compare it exactly the same number of cases.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That said, I will also say that we will be revisiting the the March &#8212; in the middle of March, the testing &#8212; the travel &#8212; the masking for travel order, and more to come on that.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah, Sheryl, well, when one thinks of a pan-coronavirus vaccine, it really is going to be an incremental process.&nbsp; So if you look at the entire phylogenetic tree of coronavirus &#8212; there are many, many coronaviruses, some of which are even the common cold coronaviruses that we&#8217;ve all experienced prior to COVID-19, generally year after year accounting for anywhere from 5 to 30 percent of the common colds.</p>



<p>Then there&#8217;s the beta-coronaviruses, which include not only SARS-CoV-2 but SARS-CoV-1, MERS, and others, and they are in another category of the beta-coronaviruses.</p>



<p>So when you ask about pan-coronavirus, that&#8217;s quite aspirational.&nbsp; And if we ever get there, that will take years.&nbsp; But what we&#8217;re focusing on first is a pan-SARS-CoV-2 vaccine, which means a vaccine that would be highly effective against ancestral strain &#8212; Alpha, Beta, Delta, Omicron &#8212; or any future SARS-CoV-2 that we might experience.&nbsp; I believe that is much, much closer than the pan-coronavirus vaccine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reason I can&#8217;t give you a timeframe is that when you&#8217;re in the element of discovery, as opposed to full development, you do not know when you will get the right situation, be it an immunogen or a platform or what have you.&nbsp; We are working intensively on that discovery phase.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Once you get a particular candidate that fulfills certain criteria, then, if you asked me that question again, Sheryl, I could give you an approximation of how long it would take.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But right now, we&#8217;re making good progress.&nbsp; We have several candidates that look good &#8212; some are in preclinical, some are in phase one.</p>



<p>So we will keep you posted.&nbsp; And I hope that you keep coming back and asking that question, because as we get more and more discovery, we&#8217;ll have a better approximation of when we will get to that goal.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Zeke Miller at the AP.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; First, simply to follow up on Jeremy&#8217;s question regarding air travel, what&#8217;s the science that says that people should wear masks on planes and on trains but don&#8217;t need to wear one at a, you know, crowded movie theater or arena?</p>



<p>Separately, does the CDC believe that schools in places that are in &#8212; have low spread should recommend that students not wear masks, given the potential unintended consequences that mask-wearing has had on children&#8217;s education?</p>



<p>And then more broadly, the President&#8217;s message last night was that people should be, you know, going back to work, we should would fill downtowns again.&nbsp; How does the administration plan to, sort, of get people to overcome three years of shutdown anxiety and work-from-home tendencies to actually go back and resume their normal activities?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, Zeke, you had a couple masking questions there.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; One was airplanes.&nbsp; Second was &#8212;</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Schools.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; &#8212; schools with low transmission.&nbsp; And then you had the federal workforce.&nbsp;&nbsp;So why don’t we turn it to Dr. Walensky on the masking questions and then I’ll handle the federal workforce.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; So, just in terms of travel, we have to look not only at the science with regard to transmission in masks but also the epidemiology and the frequency that we may encounter a variant of concern or a variant of interest in our travel corridors.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, all of those go into our equations, in terms of how much diseases out there, as well as the science, and as well as the control people have when they enter those travel quarters.&nbsp;&nbsp;We &#8212; people rely on those quarters for getting to work and for, you know, other reasons.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s among the reasons that we want to revisit this in a separate way.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of schools: As we released last Friday, we are confident in our guidance from last Friday that schools can now follow the COVID-19 community levels in terms of their masking recommendations.&nbsp;<br><br>Those recommendations, if you recall, is to maintain masking if you are in an area that is orange or high-level community COVID-19 level, and that you could remove those masks if you are yellow or green &#8212; where, in yellow, if you are high &#8212; are at high risk, that you would want to consult your healthcare provider to give you some advice as to whether you would want to continue.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; On the federal workforce and the workforce more generally: Throughout the pandemic, more than 4 million federal employees had been very hard at work protecting our country and providing critical services.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Over the past year, we&#8217;ve made significant progress in the COVID response.&nbsp; And thanks to their efforts, people working from home can feel safe to begin to return to the office.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing that here in the federal government.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Across the coming weeks, the vast majority of federal workers will once again work in person.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see public-facing federal government offices open for longer hours, more in-person appointments and walkups services.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You know, more generally, on worker safety: OSHA, at the Department of Labor, will update workplace guidance to better equip employees with the tools they need to ensure safer workplaces, including information, as we talked about earlier, on ventilation.<br><br>We will work with Congress to provide paid sick leave to workers who need to miss work due to a case of COVID-19 or to care for a loved one who has COVID-19.&nbsp; We want to reinstate the tax credits to help small and midsize businesses provide paid sick and family leave.&nbsp;<br><br>Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Alex Nazaryan at Yahoo!<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; Can you speak broadly to what else can be done to move us past the emergency stage of the pandemic?&nbsp; That&#8217;s clearly the message that we heard from the President last night. And how do we articulate that &#8212; how do you articulate that message in the weeks and months to come, you know, assuming that we don&#8217;t have some new variant?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, do you want to start there?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, you know, when you say “emergency” &#8212; “emergency” means different things to different people.&nbsp; We are still in a situation right now where, as you know, we have about 68,000 cases.&nbsp; We are coming down in the right direction.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We hope &#8212; and I believe we will get there &#8212; all the parameters that we have, pointing to this as well as the interventions that we have &#8212; that we will reach a stage where &#8212; further and further down to the point where some people call it “living with the virus,” some people call it “endemic.”&nbsp; If that is not an emergency, then, in fact, we&#8217;re out of the emergency situation.&nbsp;<br><br>But remember, whenever you talk about this, the thing you always must keep saying: We always must be prepared for the eventuality of another variant.<br><br>So we can go living our lives the way we&#8217;ve just described, the way Jeff and what Dr. Walensky and what the President described last night.&nbsp; We are in that situation where we can do that.&nbsp;<br><br>That doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean that the definition of an emergency, where there are other things that are important that one can do in much greater ease when you&#8217;re in a situation where you&#8217;re officially in an emergency.&nbsp;<br><br>But right now, if you look at the practicality of where we are, we are clearly going in the right direction. &nbsp;And with all the interventions we have, I believe that we are prepared for the possibility that we will get another variant with regard to vaccines, boosters, testing, good masks, and antivirals.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I would just add on to what Dr. Fauci said that, you know, over the past year, we&#8217;ve made significant progress and are in a very different position than we were when President Biden took office, with 215 million people fully vaccinated; two out of three eligible adults boosted; multiple treatment options, which we&#8217;ve talked about today, including millions of lifesaving pills; free at-home testing; 400 million high-quality masks going out for free.&nbsp; And because of this progress and the widely available nature of these tools, we&#8217;ve reached a new moment in the fight with COVID-19.<br><br>Today, we are in a position to move forward safely and to get back to our more normal routines.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s plan has been in the making for a long time.&nbsp; We started in early January.&nbsp; It was developed with the input from dozens of experts, local public health leaders, governors and partners across our federal agencies.&nbsp; And with additional support from Congress, we’ll ensure we protect more people with COVID &#8212; from COVID going forward, that we’re prepared for new variants, and we prevent shutdowns.<br><br>At the same time, I think it&#8217;s important to note that there is more work ahead of us.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ll roll out vaccines for kids ages two to five.&nbsp; It&#8217;s authorized by FDA and recommended by CDC.&nbsp; We’ll launch the &#8220;Test to Treat&#8221; initiative so people can get tested and treated for free in one stop.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll create new stockpiles of tests, pills, and masks so we have the tools ready to deploy if we need them.&nbsp;<br><br>So the President was very clear, as Dr. Fauci said, that we need to be prepared for any possible variant and invest in the next level &#8212; the next generation of treatments and vaccines.<br><br>Funding from Congress will be critical for these efforts so we’ll be working very closely with Capitol Hill going forward.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Pedro Rojas at Univision.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just wanted to give &#8212; make a question to Secretary Becerra.&nbsp; (Speaks Spanish.)<br><br>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; (Speaks Spanish.)<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; I want to thank everybody for today&#8217;s briefing.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s wonderful to be getting back to our more normal routine and to be doing these briefings with my colleagues in person.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you, everybody.<br><br>11:30 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The United&#160;States Continues to Impose Costs on Russia and Belarus for Putin’s War of&#160;Choice</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/02/fact-sheet-the-united-states-continues-to-impose-costs-on-russia-and-belarus-for-putins-war-of-choice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 18:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the United States, in coordination with Allies and partners, is imposing additional economic costs on Russia and Belarus in response to President Putin’s brutal invasion of Ukraine. The United States will take actions to hold Belarus accountable for enabling Putin’s invasion of Ukraine, weaken the Russian defense sector and its military power for years&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the United States, in coordination with Allies and partners, is imposing additional economic costs on Russia and Belarus in response to President Putin’s brutal invasion of Ukraine. The United States will take actions to hold Belarus accountable for enabling Putin’s invasion of Ukraine, weaken the Russian defense sector and its military power for years to come, target Russia’s most important sources of wealth, and ban Russian airlines from U.S. airspace.</p>



<p>As a result of our historic, multilateral coordination, Russia has become a global economic and financial pariah. Over 30 countries representing well over half the world’s economy have announced sanctions and export controls targeting Russia. Russia is further isolated from the international financial and trade system. We are preventing Putin from accessing his war chest to soften the blow of our actions and support his invasion of Ukraine. The United States and governments all over the world are going after Putin’s cronies and their families by identifying and freezing the assets they hold in our respective jurisdictions – their yachts, luxury apartments, money, and other ill-gotten gains. And the United States and our Allies are acting in concert to minimize the impact of these measures on our economies, including through a coordinated release of 60 million barrels of oil from strategic reserves. We will continue to impose costs with Allies and partners so long as Putin continues to escalate.</p>



<p>Today’s actions include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Sweeping restrictions on Belarus to choke off its import of technological goods in response to its support of Putin’s war of choice. </strong>The Department of Commerce will extend the stringent export control policies put in place for Russia to Belarus. This action will help prevent diversion of items, technologies, and software through Belarus to Russia and will significantly degrade both countries’ ability to sustain their military aggression and project power. This will severely limit the ability of Russia and Belarus to obtain the materials they need to support their military aggression against Ukraine, project power in ways that threaten regional stability and undermine global peace and security.<br></li><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on Russian defense entities. </strong>The Department of State will impose sweeping sanctions that target Russia’s defense sector to further restrict Putin’s war machine. This action will impose significant costs on Russian weapon development and production companies. In total, 22 Russian defense-related entities will be designated, including firms that make combat aircraft, infantry fighting vehicles, electronic warfare systems, missiles, and unmanned aerial vehicles for Russia’s military.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Export Controls Targeting Oil Refining, a Key Revenue Source that Supports Russian Military. </strong>Through export controls on oil and gas extraction equipment, the Commerce Department will impose restrictions on technology exports that would support Russia’s refining capacity over the long term. The United States and our Allies and partners do not have a strategic interest in reducing the global supply of energy – which is why we have carved out energy payments from our financial sanctions. But we and our Allies and partners share a strong interest in degrading Russia’s status as a leading energy supplier over time. These actions will help further that goal, while protecting American consumers.<br></li><li><strong>Targeting Entities Supporting the Russian and Belarusian Military. </strong>The Commerce Department, in coordination with its interagency partners, will add entities that have been involved in, contributed to, or otherwise supported the Russian and Belarusian security services, military and defense sectors, and/or military and defense research and development efforts to the Entity List. These actions will ensure that the military as well as the aerospace, maritime and high-technology sectors do not obtain U.S. technology goods and technology that can be used to support Russian technical maintenance and innovation. <br></li><li><strong>Banning Russian aircraft from entering and using domestic U.S. airspace.</strong> As the President announced, the United States will close off American air space to all Russian flights – further isolating Russia – and adding an additional squeeze on its economy. This includes aircraft certified, operated, registered or controlled by any person connected with Russia. This includes revoking all Russian airlines’ – both passenger and cargo – ability to operate to and from U.S. destinations, as well as refusing entry of any Russian-operated aircraft into U.S. airspace. With this action, the United States stands with over 30 of the world’s most important aviation markets in denying Russian carriers the ability to conduct business.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Visit of President Iván Duque Márquez of the Republic of&#160;Colombia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/02/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-visit-of-president-ivan-duque-marquez-of-the-republic-of-colombia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden looks forward to welcoming President Iván Duque Márquez of the Republic of Colombia to the White House on March 10, 2022. The visit provides an opportunity for the Presidents to celebrate 200 years of positive diplomatic relations and consult on a range of regional and global issues of mutual interest, including Russia’s unprovoked&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden looks forward to welcoming President Iván Duque Márquez of the Republic of Colombia to the White House on March 10, 2022. The visit provides an opportunity for the Presidents to celebrate 200 years of positive diplomatic relations and consult on a range of regional and global issues of mutual interest, including Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified military invasion of Ukraine, and the promotion of democracy, security, and prosperity in the hemisphere. During the meeting, the leaders plan to reaffirm the bilateral relationship and discuss COVID-19 response and future pandemic preparedness, economic recovery, and regional responses to migration. The President looks forward to this important meeting to deepen the strategic partnership between the United States and Colombia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/02/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10:23 A.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; What did you give up for Lent? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; All sweets. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; All sweets? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; And I&#8217;m &#8212; you know me, I start off with dessert.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; So, no ice cream? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; No ice cream.&#160; Nothing. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, how worried are you about President Zelenskyy?&#160; And do you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>10:23 A.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did you give up for Lent?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All sweets.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All sweets?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; you know me, I start off with dessert.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, no ice cream?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No ice cream.&nbsp; Nothing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how worried are you about President Zelenskyy?&nbsp; And do you think he should stay in Ukraine, or do you think he should try to leave?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think it’s his judgement to make, and we’re doing everything we can to help him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you made any other attempts to reach China or talk to them about the situation at all?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Not directly yet.&nbsp; We &#8212; the staff has been in contact with them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you support permanent U.S. military presence in Poland and other Eastern European countries now after what&#8217;s happening in Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always been there.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always been &#8212; all the NATO countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m talking about permanent bases.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I &#8212; that’s a decision for NATO to make.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you considering banning Russian oil imports?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; There’s &#8212; nothing is off the table.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe Russia is committing war crimes in Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We are following it very closely.&nbsp; It’s early to say that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Pope Francis asked for prayers and fasting today for the people of Ukraine on this Ash Wednesday.&nbsp; Pope Francis is asking for prayers and fasting.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your reaction to that that, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think he&#8217;s right.&nbsp; I was with the Cardinal this morning.&nbsp; He came over to give me ashes.&nbsp; We both prayed for that &#8212; for the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last night, you continued to support Roe v. Wade. As a Catholic, why do you support abortion as a Catholic, defying church teachings?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I tell you what, I don&#8217;t want to get in a debate with you on theology.&nbsp; But, you know &#8212; well, anyway.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But why?&nbsp; Why support abortion as a pro-life &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to make a &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to make a judgement for other people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you&#8217;re Catholic, why &#8212; why defy church teaching?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you believe Russia is intentionally targeting civilian areas?&nbsp; There are over 2,000 civilian deaths right now according to &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s clear they are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>10:25 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in State of the Union&#160;Address</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/02/remarks-by-president-biden-in-state-of-the-union-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 16:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. CapitolWashington, D.C. (March 1, 2022) 9:08 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Madam Speaker, Madam Vice President, and our First Lady and Second Gentleman, members of Congress and the Cabinet, Justices of the Supreme Court, my fellow Americans: Last year, COVID-19 kept us apart.&#160; This year, we’re finally together again.&#160; Tonight &#8212; (applause) &#8212; tonight we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">U.S. Capitol<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(March 1, 2022)</p>



<p>9:08 P.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Madam Speaker, Madam Vice President, and our First Lady and Second Gentleman, members of Congress and the Cabinet, Justices of the Supreme Court, my fellow Americans: Last year, COVID-19 kept us apart.&nbsp; This year, we’re finally together again.&nbsp;<br><br>Tonight &#8212; (applause) &#8212; tonight we meet as Democrats, Republicans, and independents, but, most importantly, as Americans with a duty to one another, to America, to the American people, and to the Constitution, and an unwavering resolve that freedom will always triumph over tyranny.<br><br>Six &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; Six days ago, Russia’s Vladimir Putin sought to shake the very foundations of the free world, thinking he could make it bend to his menacing ways.&nbsp; But he badly miscalculated.&nbsp; He thought he could roll into Ukraine and the world would roll over.&nbsp; Instead, he met with a mal- &#8212; a wall of strength he never anticipated or imagined.&nbsp; He met the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>From President Zelenskyy to every Ukrainian, their fearlessness, their courage, their determination literally inspires the world.&nbsp; Groups of citizens blocking tanks with their bodies.&nbsp; Everyone from students to retirees, to teachers turned soldiers defending their homeland.<br><br>And in this struggle &#8212; President Zelenskyy said in his speech to the European Parliament, “Light will win over darkness.”<br><br>The Ukrainian Ambassador to the United States is here tonight sitting with the First Lady.&nbsp; Let each of us, if you’re able to stand, stand and send an unmistakable signal to the world and Ukraine.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>She’s bright, she’s strong, and she’s resolved.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Yes.&nbsp; We, the United States of America, stand with the Ukrainian people.<br><br>Throughout our history, we’ve learned this lesson: When dictators do not pay a price for their aggression, they cause more chaos; they keep moving; and the costs, the threats to the America &#8212; and America, to the world keeps rising.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why the NATO Alliance was created: to secure peace and stability in Europe after World War Two.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States is a member, along with 29 other nations.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; American diplomacy matters.&nbsp; American resolve matters.<br><br>Putin’s latest attack on Ukraine was premeditated and totally unprovoked.&nbsp; He rejected repeated &#8212; repeated efforts at diplomacy.<br><br>He thought the West and NATO wouldn’t respond.&nbsp; He thought he could divide us at home, in this chamber, in this nation.&nbsp; He thought he could divide us in Europe as well.<br><br>But Putin was wrong.&nbsp; We are ready.&nbsp; We are united.&nbsp; And that’s what we did: We stayed united.&nbsp;<br><br>We prepared extensively and carefully.&nbsp; We spent months building coalitions of other freedom-loving nations in Europe and the Americas to &#8212; from America to the Asian and African continents to confront Putin.<br><br>Like many of you, I spent countless hours unifying our European Allies.<br><br>We shared with the world, in advance, what we knew Putin was planning and precisely how he would try to falsely and justify his aggression.<br><br>We countered Russia’s lies with the truth.&nbsp; And now &#8212; now that he’s acted, the three wor- &#8212; free world is holding him accountable, along with 27 members of the European Union &#8212; including France, Germany, Italy &#8212; as well as countries like the United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, Korea, Australia, New Zealand, and many others.&nbsp; Even Switzerland are inflicting pain on Russia and supporting the people of Ukraine.<br><br>Putin is now isolated from the world more than he has ever been.&nbsp;<br><br>Together &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; Together &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; Together, along with our Allies, we are right now enforcing powerful economic sanctions.&nbsp; We’re cutting off Russia’s largest banks from the international financial system; preventing Russia’s Central Bank from defending the Russian rubil [sic] &#8212; ruble, making Putin’s $630 billion war fund worthless.&nbsp; We’re choking Russia’s access &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we’re choking Russia’s access to technology that will sap its economic strength and weaken its military for years to come.<br><br>Tonight, I say to the Russian oligarchs and the corrupt leaders who’ve bilked billions of dollars off this violent regime: No more.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The United States &#8212; I mean it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; The United States Department of Justice is assembling a dedicated task force to go after the crimes of the Russian oligarchs.<br><br>We’re joining with European Allies to find and seize their yachts, their luxury apartments, their private jets.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re coming for your ill-begotten gains.<br><br>And, tonight, I&#8217;m announcing that we will join our Allies in closing off American air space to all Russian flights, further isolating Russia and adding an additional squeeze on their economy.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>He has no idea what’s coming.<br><br>The ruble has already lost 30 percent of its value, the Russian stock market has lost 40 percent of its value, and trading remains suspended.<br><br>The Russian economy is reeling, and Putin alone is the one to blame.<br><br>Together with our Allies, we’re providing support to the Ukrainians in their fight for freedom: military assistance, economic assistance, humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; We’re giving more than a billion dollars in direct assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; And we’ll continue to aid the Ukrainian people as they defend their country and help ease their suffering.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But let me be clear: Our forces are not engaged and will not engage in the conflict with Russian forces in Ukraine.&nbsp; Our forces are not going to Europe to fight [in] Ukraine but to defend our NATO Allies in the event that Putin decides to keep moving west.<br><br>For that purpose, we have mobilized American ground forces, air squadrons, ship deployments to protect NATO countries, including Poland, Romania, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.<br><br>And as I&#8217;ve made crystal clear, the United States and our Allies will defend every inch of territory that is NATO territory with the full force of our collective power &#8212; every single inch.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And we’re clear-eyed.&nbsp; The Ukrainians are fighting back with pure courage.&nbsp; But the next few days, weeks, and months will be hard on them.&nbsp;<br><br>Putin has unleashed violence and chaos.&nbsp; But while he may make gains on the battlefield, he will pay a continuing high price over the long run.<br><br>And a pound of Ukrainian people &#8212; the proud, proud people &#8212; pound for pound, ready to fight with every inch of (inaudible) they have.&nbsp; They’ve known 30 years of independence &#8212; have repeatedly shown that they will not tolerate anyone who tries to take their country backwards.<br><br>To all Americans, I’ll be honest with you, as I’ve always promised I would be.&nbsp; A Russian dictator infa- &#8212; invading a foreign country has costs around the world.&nbsp; And I’m taking robust action to make sure the pain of our sanctions is targeted at the Russian economy and that we use every tool at our disposal to protect American businesses and consumers.<br><br>Tonight, I can announce the United States has worked with 30 other countries to release 60 million barrels of oil from reserves around the world.&nbsp; America &#8212; (applause) &#8212; will lead that effort, releasing 30 million barrels of our own Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; And we stand ready to do more if necessary, united with our Allies.<br><br>These steps will help blunt gas prices here at home.&nbsp; But I know news about what’s happening can seem alarming to all Americans.&nbsp; But I want you to know: We’re going to be okay.&nbsp; We’re going to be okay.<br><br>When the history of this era is written, Putin’s war on Ukraine will have left Russia weaker and the rest of the world stronger.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>While it shouldn’t &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and while it shouldn’t have taken &#8212; while it shouldn’t have taken something so terrible for people around the world to see what’s at stake, now everyone sees it clearly.<br><br>We see the unity among leaders of nations, a more unified Europe, a more unified West.<br><br>We see unity among the people who are gathering in cities in large crowds around the world, even in Russia, to demonstrate their support for the people of Ukraine.<br><br>In the battle between democracy and autocracies, democracies are rising to the moment and the world is clearly choosing the side of peace and security.<br><br>This is the real test, and it’s going to take time.&nbsp; So, let us continue to draw inspiration from the iron will of the Ukrainian people.<br><br>To our fellow Ukrainian Americans who forged a deep bond that connects our two nations: We stand with you.&nbsp; We stand with you.&nbsp;<br><br>Putin may circle Kyiv with tanks, but he’ll never gain the hearts and souls of the <s>Uranian</s> [Ukrainian] people.&nbsp; He’ll never &#8212; he’ll never extinguish their love of freedom.&nbsp; And he will never, never weaken the resolve of the free world.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We meet tonight in an America that has lived through two of the hardest years this nation has ever faced.&nbsp; The pandemic has been punishing.&nbsp; And so many families are living paycheck to paycheck, struggling to keep up with the rising cost of food, gas, housing, and so much more.<br><br>I understand, like many of you did.&nbsp; My dad had to leave his home in Scranton, Pennsylvania, to find work.&nbsp; So, like many of you, I grew up in a family when the price of food went up, it was felt throughout the family; it had an impact.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why one of the first things I did as President was fight to pass the American Rescue Plan, because people were hurting.&nbsp; We needed to act and we did.<br><br>Few pieces of legislation have done more at a critical moment in our history to lift us out of a crisis.&nbsp; It fueled our efforts to vaccinate the nation and combat COVID-19.&nbsp; It delivered immediate economic relief to tens of millions of Americans.&nbsp; It helped put food on the table.&nbsp; Remember those long lines of cars waiting for hours just to get a box of food put in their trunk?&nbsp; It cut the cost of healthcare insurance.&nbsp; And as my dad used to say, it gave the people “just a little bit of breathing room.”<br><br>And unlike the $2 trillion tax cut passed in the previous administration that benefitted the top 1 percent of Americans, the American Rescue Plan &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; the American Rescue Plan helped working people and left no one behind.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And, folks &#8212; and it worked.&nbsp; It worked.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>It &#8212; (applause) &#8212; it worked and created jobs &#8212; lots of jobs.&nbsp; In fact, our economy created over 6.5 million new jobs just last year, more jobs in one year than ever before in the history of the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>The economy grew at a rate of 5.7 last year &#8212; the strongest growth rate in 40 years and the first step in bringing fundamental change to our economy that hasn’t worked for working people in this nation for too long.<br><br>For the past 40 years, we were told that tax breaks for those at the top and benefits would trickle down and everyone would &#8212; would benefit.<br><br>But that trickle-down theory led to a weaker economic growth, lower wages, bigger deficits, and a widening gap between the top and everyone else in the &#8212; in nearly a century.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Look, Vice President Harris and I ran for office &#8212; and I realize we have fundamental disagreements on this &#8212; but ran for office with a new economic vision for America: invest in America; educate Americans; grow the workforce; build the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, not from the top down.&nbsp; Because we know &#8212; because we know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; because we know when the middle class grows &#8212; when the middle class grows, the poor go way up and the wealthy do very well.<br><br>America used to have the best roads, bridges, and airports on Earth.&nbsp; And now our infrastructure is ranked 13th in the world.&nbsp; We won’t be able to compete for the jobs of the 21st century if we don’t fix it.<br><br>That’s why it was so important to pass the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; And I thank my Republican friends who joined to invest and rebuild America &#8212; the single biggest investment in history.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>It was a bipartisan effort, and I want to thank the members of both parties who worked to make it happen.&nbsp; We’re done talking about infrastructure weeks.&nbsp; We’re now talking about an infrastructure decade.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And look, it’s going to &#8212; it’s going to transform America to put us on a path to win the economic competition of the 21st century that we face with the rest of the world, particularly China.<br><br>I’ve told Xi Jinping: It’s never been a good bet to bet against the American people.<br><br>We’ll create good jobs for millions of Americans &#8212; modernizing roads, airports, ports, waterways &#8212; all across America.&nbsp; And we’ll do it to withstand the devastating <s>emfects</s> [effects] of climate crisis and promote environmental justice.<br><br>We’ll build a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations; begin to replace the poisonous lead pipes, so every child, every American has clean water to drink at home and at school.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We’re going to provide &#8212; provide affordable high-speed Internet for every American &#8212; rural, suburban, urban, and Tribal communities.&nbsp; Four thousand projects have already been announced.&nbsp; Many of you have announced them in your districts.&nbsp;<br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing that, this year, we will start fixing over 65,000 miles of highway and 1,500 bridges in disrepair.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks, when we use taxpayers’ dollars to rebuild America, we’re going to do it by buying American.&nbsp; (Applause.) Buy American products.&nbsp; Support American jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The federal government spends about $600 billion a year to keep this country safe and secure.&nbsp; There’s been a law on the books for almost a century to make sure taxpayers’ dollars support American jobs and businesses.&nbsp; Every administration &#8212; Democrat and Republican &#8212; says they’ll do it, but we’re actu- &#8212; we’re actually doing it.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ll buy America to make sure every &#8212; everything from the deck of an aircraft carrier to the steel on highway guardrails is made in America from beginning to end.&nbsp; All of it.&nbsp; All of it.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>But, folks, to compete for the jobs of the future, we also need to level the playing field with China and other competitors.&nbsp; That’s why it’s so important to pass the bipartisan Innovation Act sitting in Congress that will make record investments in emerging technologies and American manufacturing.<br><br>We used to invest almost 2 percent of our GDP in research and development.&nbsp; We don’t now.&nbsp; Can’t &#8212; China is.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me give you one example why it&#8217;s so important to pass.<br><br>If you travel 20 miles east of Columbus, Ohio, you’ll find a thousand empty acres of land.&nbsp; It won’t look like much.&nbsp; But if you stop and look closely, you’ll see a “field of dreams&#8221; &#8212; the ground on which America’s future will be built.<br><br>That&#8217;s where Intel, the American company that helped build Silicon Valley, is going to build a $20 billion semiconductor “mega site.”&nbsp; Up to eight state-of-the-art factories in one place.&nbsp; Ten thousand new jobs.&nbsp; And in those factories, the average job &#8212; about $135 &#8212; $135,000 a year.<br><br>Some of the most sophisticated manufacturing in the world to make computer chips the size of a fingertip that power the world and everyday lives, from smartphones, technology that &#8212; the Internet &#8212; technology that&#8217;s yet to be invented.<br><br>But that’s just the beginning.<br><br>Intel’s CEO, Pat Gelsinger, who is here tonight &#8212; and I don&#8217;t know where Pat is.&nbsp; Pat?&nbsp; There you go, Pat.&nbsp; Stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Pat &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Pat came to see me, and he told me they&#8217;re ready to increase their investment from $20 billion to $100 billion.<br><br>That would be the biggest investment in manufacturing in American history.&nbsp; And all they’re waiting for is for you to pass this bill.<br><br>So, let’s not wait any longer.&nbsp; Send it to my desk, I’ll sign it, and we will really take off in a big way.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks, Intel is not alone.&nbsp; There’s something happening in America.&nbsp; Just look around, and you’ll see an amazing story &#8212; the rebirth of pride that comes from stamping products “Made in America,” the revitalization of American manufacturing.<br><br>Companies are choosing to build new factories here when just a few years ago, they would have gone overseas.&nbsp; That’s what is happening.<br><br>Ford is investing $11 billion in electric vehicles, creating 11,000 jobs across the country.<br><br>GM is making the largest investment in its history &#8212; $7 billion to build electric vehicles, creating 4,000 jobs in Michigan.<br><br>All told, 369,000 new manufacturing jobs were created in America last year alone.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, powered by people I’ve met &#8212; like JoJo Burgess from generations of union steelworkers in Pittsburgh, who’s here with us tonight.&nbsp; Where are you, JoJo?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Thanks, buddy.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>As Ohio &#8212; as Ohio Senator Sherrod Brown says &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as Sherrod Brown says, &#8220;It’s time to bury the label &#8216;Rust Belt.'&#8221;&nbsp; It’s time to see the &#8212; the &#8212; what used to be called the Rust Belt become the &#8212; the home of a significant resurgence of manufacturing.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And with all the bright spots in our economy &#8212; record job growth, higher wages &#8212; too many families are struggling to keep up with their bills.<br><br>Inflation is robbing them of gains they thought otherwise they would be able to feel.<br><br>I get it.&nbsp; That’s why my top priority is getting prices under control.<br><br>Look, our economy roared back faster than almost anyone predicted, but the pandemic meant that businesses had a hard time hiring enough people because of the pandemic to keep up production in their factories.&nbsp; So, you didn&#8217;t have people making those beams that went into buildings because they were out &#8212; the factory was closed.<br><br>The <s>panic</s> [pandemic] also disrupted the global supply chain.&nbsp; Factories close.&nbsp; When that happens, it takes longer to make goods and get them to the warehouses, to the stores, and go &#8212; prices go up.<br><br>Look at cars last year.&nbsp; One third of all the inflation was because of automobile sales.&nbsp; There weren’t enough semiconductors to make all the cars that people wanted to buy.<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; Prices of automobiles went way up, especially used vehicles as well.<br><br>And so, we have a choice.&nbsp;<br><br>One way to fight inflation is to drive down wages and make Americans poorer.<br><br>I think I have a better idea to fight inflation: Lower your costs, not your wages.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks, that means make more cars and semiconductors in America, more infrastructure and innovation in America, more goods moving faster and cheaper in America, more jobs where you can earn a good living in America.<br><br>Instead of relying on foreign supply chains, let’s make it in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Look, economists &#8212; (applause) &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; USA!&nbsp; USA!&nbsp; USA!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Economists &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; USA!&nbsp; USA!&nbsp; USA!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; call this increasing the productive capacity of our ecomony [sic] &#8212; of our economy.<br><br>I call it building a better America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>My plan to fight inflation will lower your costs and lower the deficit.&nbsp; Seventeen Nobel laureates in economics said my plan will ease long-term inflationary pressures.&nbsp; Top business leaders and, I believe, most Americans support the plan.<br><br>And here’s the plan.<br><br>First, cut the cost of prescription drugs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We pay more for the same drug produced by the same company in America than any other country in the world.<br><br>Just look at insulin.&nbsp; One in ten Americans has diabetes.&nbsp; In Virginia, I met a 13-year-old boy &#8212; the handsome young man standing up there, Joshua Davis.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; He and his dad both have Type 1 diabetes, which means they need insulin every single day.<br><br>Insulin costs about $10 a vial to make.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it costs the &#8212; the pharmaceutical company.&nbsp; But drug companies charge families like Joshua and his dad up to 30 times that amount.<br><br>I spoke with Joshua’s mom.&nbsp; Imagine what it’s like to look at your child who needs insulin to stay healthy and have no idea how in God&#8217;s name you’re going to be able to pay for it &#8212; what it does to your family, but what it does to your dignity, your ability to look your child in the eye, to be the parent you expect yourself to be.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I think about.<br>You know, yesterday &#8212; Joshua is here tonight, but yesterday was his birthday.&nbsp; Happy birthday, buddy, by the way.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>For Joshua and 200,000 other young people with Type 1 diabetes, let’s cap the cost of insulin at $35 a month so everyone can afford it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And drug companies will do very, very well &#8212; their profit margin.<br><br>And while we’re at it &#8212; I know we have great disagreements on this floor with this &#8212; let&#8217;s let Medicare negotiate the price of prescription drugs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; They already set the price for VA drugs.<br><br>Look, the American Rescue Plan is helping millions of families on Affordable Care Act plans to save them $2,400 a year on their health premiums.&nbsp; Let’s close the coverage gap and make those savings permanent.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And second, let&#8217;s cut energy costs for families an average of $500 a year by combatting climate change.<br><br>Let’s provide an investment and tax credit to weatherize your home and your business to be energy efficient and get a tax credit for it; double America’s clean energy production in solar, wind, and so much more; lower the price of electric vehicles, saving another $80 a month that you&#8217;ve not going to have to pay at the pump.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks &#8212; third &#8212; the third thing we can do to change the standard of living for hardworking folks is cut the cost of childcare.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Cut the cost of childcare.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, if you live in a major city in America, you can pay up to $14,000 a year for childcare per child.<br><br>I was a single dad for five years, raising two kids.&nbsp; I had a lot of help, though.&nbsp; I had a mom, a dad, a brother, and sister that really helped.<br><br>But middle-class and working folks shouldn’t have to pay more than 7 percent of their income to care for their young children.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>My plan &#8212; (applause) &#8212; my plan would cut the cost of childcare in half for most families and help parents, including millions of women who left the workforce during the pandemic because they couldn’t afford childcare to be able to get back to work, generating economic growth.<br><br>But my plan doesn’t stop there.&nbsp; It also includes home and long-term care, more affordable housing, pre-K for three- and four-year-olds.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; All of these will lower costs to families.<br><br>And under my plan, nobody &#8212; let me say this again &#8212; nobody earning less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional penny in new taxes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Not a single penny.&nbsp;<br><br>I may be wrong, but my guess is, if we took a secret ballot in this floor, that we’d all agree that the present tax system ain’t fair.&nbsp; We have to fix it.<br><br>I’m not looking to punish anybody, but let’s make corporations and wealthy Americans start paying their fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Look, last year &#8212; (applause) &#8212; last year &#8212; like Chris Coons and Tom Carper and my distinguished congresswoman &#8212; we come from the land of corporate America.&nbsp; There are more corporations incorporated in <s>America</s> [Delaware] than every other state in America combined.&nbsp; And I still won 36 years in a row.&nbsp; The point is: Even they understand they should pay just a fair share.<br><br>Last year, 55 of the Fortune 500 companies earned $40 billion in profit and paid zero in federal taxes.&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo –<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, look, it’s not fair.&nbsp; That’s why I proposed a 15 percent minimum tax rate for corporations.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We’ve got &#8212; and that’s why in the G7 and other meetings overseas we were able to put together &#8212; I was able to be somewhat helpful &#8212; 130 countries to agree on a global minimum tax rate &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so companies can’t get out of paying their taxes at home by shipping jobs and factories overseas.&nbsp; It’ll raise billions of dollars.<br><br>And that’s why I’ve proposed closing loopholes for the very wealthy who don’t pay &#8212; who pay a lower tax rate than a teacher and a firefighter.<br><br>So that’s my plan.&nbsp; But we have &#8212; we’ll go into more detail later.&nbsp;<br><br>I’m going to grow &#8212; we will grow the economy, lower the costs to families.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what are we waiting for?&nbsp; Let’s get this done.&nbsp; We all know we&#8217;ve got to make changes.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, and while you’re at it, confirm my nominees for the Federal Reserve &#8212; (applause) &#8212; which plays a critical role in fighting inflation.<br><br>My plan will not only lower costs and give families a fair shot, it will lower the deficit.<br><br>The previous administration not only ballooned the deficit with those tax cuts for the very wealthy and corporations, it undermined the watchdogs &#8212; the job of those to keep pandemic relief funds from being wasted.&nbsp; Remember we had those debates about whether or not those watchdogs should be able to see, every day, how much money was being spent, where it &#8212; was it going to the right place?&nbsp;<br><br>In my administration, the watchdogs are back.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;And we’re going after the criminals who stole billions of relief money meant for small business and millions of Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing that the Justice Department will soon name a chief prosecutor for pandemic fraud.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, look &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I think we all agree &#8212; thank you &#8212; by the end of this year, the deficit will be down to less than half what it was before I took office &#8212; the only President ever to cut the deficit by more than $1 trillion in a single year.<br><br>Lowering your costs also meant demanding more competition.&nbsp; I’m a capitalist, but capitalism without competition is not capitalism.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Capitalism without competition is exploitation.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It drives up <s>profits</s> [prices].<br><br>When corporations have to compete, their profits go up and your prices go up &#8212; when they don’t have to compete.&nbsp;<br><br>Small businesses and family farmers and ranchers &#8212; I need not tell some of my Republican friends from those states &#8212; guess what?&nbsp; You got four basic meatpacking facilities.&nbsp; That’s it.&nbsp; You play with them or you don’t get to play at all.&nbsp; And you pay a hell of a lot more &#8212; a hell of a lot more because there’s only four.</p>



<p>See what&#8217;s happening with ocean carriers moving goods in and out of America.  During the pandemic, about half a dozen or less foreign-owned companies raised prices by as much as 1,000 percent and made record profits.<br><br>Tonight, I’m announcing a crackdown on those companies overcharging American businesses and consumers.  (Applause) <br><br>Folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and as Wall Street firms take over more nursing homes, quality in those homes has gone down and costs have gone up.  That ends on my watch.<br><br>Medicare is going to set higher standards for nursing homes and make sure your loved ones get the care they deserve and that they expect, and they will look at that closely.<br><br>We’re also going to cut costs to keep the economy going strong and giving workers a fair shot; provide more training and apprenticeships; hire them based on skills, not just their degrees.<br><br>Let’s pass the Paycheck Fairness Act and paid leave &#8212; (applause); raise the minimum wage to $15 an hour &#8212; (applause); and extend the Child Tax Credit so no one has to raise a family in poverty.  (Applause.)<br><br>Let’s increase Pell Grants; increase our historic support for HBCUs; and invest &#8212; (applause) &#8212; in what Jill, our First Lady, who teaches full-time, calls America’s best-kept secret: community colleges.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look, let’s pass the PRO Act.  When a majority of workers want to form a union, they shouldn’t be able to be stopped.  (Applause.)<br><br>When we invest in our workers and we build an economy from the bottom up and the middle out, together we can do something we haven’t done in a long time: build a better America.<br><br>For more than two years, COVID has impacted every decision in our lives and the life of this nation.  And I know you’re tired, frustrated, and exhausted.  That doesn’t even count the close to a million people who sit at a dining room table or a kitchen table and look at an empty chair because they lost somebody.<br><br>But I also know this: Because of the progress we’ve made, because of your resilience and the tools that we have been provided by this Congress, tonight I can say we’re moving forward safely, back to a norm- &#8212; more normal routines.<br><br>We’ve reached a new moment in the fight against COVID-19 where severe cases are down to a level not seen since July of last year.<br><br>Just a few days ago, the Center for Disease Control and Prevention issued a new mask guidelines.  Under the new guidelines, most Americans in most of the country can now go mask free.  (Applause.) <br><br>And based on projections &#8212; and based on projections, more of the country will reach a point across &#8212; that point across the next couple of weeks.<br><br>And thanks to the progress we’ve made in the past year, COVID-19 no longer need control our lives.  I know some are talking about &#8220;living with COVID-19.&#8221;  But tonight, I say that we never will just accept living with COVID-19; we’ll continue to combat the virus as we do other diseases.<br><br>And because this virus mutates and spreads, we have to stay on guard.  And here are four commonsense steps as we move forward safely, in my view:<br><br>First, stay protected with vaccines and treatments.  We know how incredibly effective vaccines are.  If you’re vaccinated and boosted, you have the highest degree of protection, and we&#8217;ll never give up on vaccinating more Americans.<br><br>Now, I know parents with kids under five are eager to see their vaccines authorized for their children.  Scientists are working hard to get that done, and we’ll be ready with plenty of vaccines if and when they do.<br><br>We’re already &#8212; we are also ready with anti-viral treatments.  If you get COVID-19, the Pfizer pill reduces your chances of ending up in the hospital by 90 percent.<br><br>I’ve ordered more pills than anyone in the world has.  Pfizer is working overtime to get us a million pills this month and more than double that next month.<br><br>And now we’re launching the &#8220;Test to Treat&#8221; initiative so people can get tested at a pharmacy and, if they prove positive, receive the antiviral pills on the spot at no cost.  (Applause.)<br><br>And folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; if you’re immu- &#8212; (applause) &#8212; if you’re immunocompromised or have some other vulnerability, we have treatments and free high-quality masks.<br><br>We’re leaving no one behind or ignoring anyone’s needs as we move forward.<br><br>On testing, we&#8217;ve made hundreds of millions of tests available, and you can order them for free to your doorstep.<br><br>And we&#8217;ve already ordered free tests.  If you already ordered free tests, tonight I&#8217;m announcing you can order another group of tests.  COVID &#8212; go to COVIDTests.gov, starting next week, and you can get more tests. <br><br>Second, we must prepare for new variants.<br><br>Over the past &#8212; we’ve gotten much better at detecting new variants.  If necessary, we’ll be able to <s>develop</s> [deploy] new vaccines within 100 days instead of maybe months or years.  And if Congress <s>presides</s> [provides] the funds we need, we’ll have new stockpiles of tests, masks, pills ready if needed.<br><br>I can’t promise a new variant won’t come, but I ca- &#8212; I can promise you we’ll do everything within our power to be ready if it does.  (Applause.) <br><br>Third, we can end the shutdown of schools and businesses.  We have the tools we need.<br><br>It’s time for America to get back to work and fill our great downtowns again with people.  People working from home can feel safe and begin to return to their offices.  (Applause.) <br><br>We’re doing that here in the federal government.  The vast majority of federal workers will once again work in person.<br><br>Our schools are open.  Let’s keep it that way.  Our kids need to be in school.  (Applause.)<br><br>With 75 percel [sic] of adult &#8212; 75 percent of adult Americans fully vaccinated and hospitalizations down by 77 percent, most Americans can remove their masks and stay in the classroom and move forward safely.<br><br>We achieved this because we provided free vaccines, treatments, tests, and masks.  Of course, continuing this costs money, so it will not surprise you I&#8217;ll be back to see you all.  (Laughter.)  And re- &#8212; I&#8217;m going to soon send a request to Congress.<br><br>The vast majority of Americans have used these tools and may want to again &#8212; we may need them again.  So I expect Congress &#8212; and I hope you&#8217;ll pass that quickly. <br><br>Fourth, we&#8217;ll continue vaccinating the world.  We’ve sent 475 million vaccine doses to 112 countries &#8212; more than any nation on Earth.  (Applause.)  We won’t stop, because you can&#8217;t build a wall high enough to keep out a &#8212;<br><br>A vaccine &#8212; the vaccine can stop the spread of these diseases. <br><br>You know, we&#8217;ve lost so much in COVID-19.  Time with one another.  The worst of all, the much loss of life.<br><br>Let’s use this moment to reset.  So, stop looking at COVID as a partisan dividing line.  See it for what it is: a God-awful disease.<br><br>Let’s stop sending &#8212; seeing each other as enemies and start seeing each other for who we are: fellow Americans.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look &#8212; we &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we can’t change how divided we’ve been.  That was a long time in coming.  But we can change how to move forward on COVID-19 and other issues that we must face together.<br><br>I recently visited New York City Police Department days after the funerals of Officer Wilbert Mora and his partner, Officer Jason Rivera.<br><br>They were responding to a 911 call when a man shot and killed them with a stolen gun.<br><br>Officer Mora was 27 years old.  Officer Rivera was 22 years old.  Both Dominican Americans who grew up in the same streets that they later chose to parol [sic] &#8212; to patrol as police officers.<br><br>I spoke with their families, and I told them that we are forever in debt for their sacrifices and we&#8217;ll carry on their mission to restore the trust and safety in every community it deserves.<br><br>Like some of you that have been around for a while &#8212; I&#8217;ve worked with you on these issues for a long time.  I know what works: <s>Investigating</s> [Investing in] crime prevention and community policing &#8212; cops who walk the beat, who know the neighborhood, and who can restore trust and safety. <br><br>Let&#8217;s not abandon our streets or choose between safety and equal justice.  Let’s come together and protect our communities, restore trust, and hold law enforcement accountable.<br><br>That’s why the Justice Department has required body cameras, banned chokeholds, and restricted no-knock warrants for its officers.<br><br>That’s why the American Rescue Plan that you all provided $350 billion that cities, states, and counties can use to hire more police, invest in more proven strategies &#8212; (applause) &#8212; proven strategies like &#8212; proven strategies like community violence interruption, trusted messengers breaking the cycle of violence and trauma and giving young people some hope.<br><br>We should all agree the answer is not to defund the police.<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  That&#8217;s right!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  It&#8217;s to fund the police.  (Applause.)  Fund them.  Fund them.  (Applause.)  Fund them with the resources and training &#8212; resources and training they need to protect our communities.<br><br>I ask Democrats and Republicans alike to pass my budget and keep our neighborhoods safe.<br><br>And we&#8217;ll do everything in my power to crack down on gun trafficking of ghost guns that you can buy online, assemble at home &#8212; no serial numbers, can’t be traced. <br><br>I ask Congress to pass proven measures to reduce gun violence.  Pass universal background checks.  (Applause.)  Why should anyone on the terrorist list be able to purchase a weapon.  Why?  Why?  (Applause.)<br><br>AUDIENCE:  Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And, folks, ban assault weapons with high-capacity magazines that hold up to 100 rounds.  You think the deer are wearing Kevlar vests?  (Laughter.)<br><br>Look, repeal the liability shield that makes gun manufacturers the only industry in America that can’t be sued &#8212; the only one.  (Applause.)  Imagine had we done that with the tobacco manufactures.<br><br>These laws don’t infringe on the Second Amendment; they save lives.<br><br>The most fundamental right in America is the right to vote and have it counted.  (Applause.)  And look, it’s under assault.<br><br>In state after state, new laws have been passed not only to suppress the vote &#8212; we&#8217;ve been there before &#8212; but to subvert the entire election.  We can&#8217;t let this happen.<br><br>Tonight, I call on the Senate to pass &#8212; pass the Freedom to Vote Act.  (Applause.)  Pass the John Lewis Act &#8212; Voting Rights Act.  (Applause.)  And while you’re at it, pass the DISCLOSE Act so Americans know who is funding our elections.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look, tonight, I’d &#8212; I&#8217;d like to honor someone who has dedicated his life to serve this country: Justice Breyer &#8212; an Army veteran, Constitutional scholar, retiring Justice of the United States Supreme Court.<br><br>Justice Breyer, thank you for your service.  (Applause.)  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)  I mean it.  Get up.  Stand &#8212; let me see you.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br><br>And we all know &#8212; no matter what your ideology, we all know one of the most serious constitutional responsibilities a President has is nominating someone to serve on the United States Supreme Court.<br><br>As I did four days ago, I&#8217;ve nominated a Circuit Court of Appeals &#8212; Ketanji Brown Jackson.  (Applause.)  One of our nation’s top legal minds who will continue in just Brey- &#8212; Justice Breyer’s legacy of excellence.  (Applause.)  A former top litigator in private practice, a former federal public defender from a family of public-school educators and police officers &#8212; she&#8217;s a consensus builder.<br><br>Since she’s been nominated, she’s received a broad range of support, including the Fraternal Order of Police and former judges appointed by Democrats and Republicans.<br><br>Folks, if we are to advance liberty and justice, we need to secure our border and fix the immigration system.  (Applause.)<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBERS:  Build the wall!  Build the wall!  Build the wall!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And as you might guess, I think we can do both.  At our border, we’ve installed new technology, like cutting-edge scanners, to better detect drug smuggling.<br><br>We’ve set up joint patrols with Mexico and Guatemala to catch more human traffickers. <br><br>We’re putting in place dedicated immigration judges in significant larger number so families fleeing persecution and violence can have their cases &#8212; cases heard faster &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and those who <s>don&#8217;t</s> [aren’t] legitimately here can be sent back. <br><br>We’re screening &#8212; we’re securing commitments and supporting partners in South and Central America to host more refugees and secure their own borders.<br><br>We can do all this while keeping lit the torch of liberty that has led the generation of immigrants to this land &#8212; my forebearers and many of yours.<br><br>Provide a pathway to citizenship for Dreamers &#8212; (applause) &#8212; those with temporary status, farmworkers, essential workers.  To revise our laws so businesses have workers they need and families don’t wait decades to reunite.<br><br>It’s not only the right thing to do, it’s economically smart thing to do.  That’s why the immigration reform is supported by everyone from labor unions to religious leaders to the U.S. Chamber of Commerce.  (Applause.)  Let’s get it done once and for all.  (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, advancing liberty and justice also requires protecting the rights of women.  The constitutional right affirmed by Roe v. Wade, standing precedent for half a century, is under attack as never before.<br><br>If you want to go forward not backwards, we must protect access to healthcare &#8212; (applause); preserve a woman’s right to choose &#8212; (applause); and continue to advance maternal healthcare for all Americans.  (Applause.)<br><br>And folks, for our LGBTQ+ Americans, let’s finally get the bipartisan Equality Act to my desk.  (Applause.)  The onslaught of state laws targeting transgender Americans and their families &#8212; it’s simply wrong. <br><br>As I said last year, especially to our younger transgender Americans, I’ll always have your back as your President so you can be yourself and reach your God-given potential.  (Applause.)<br><br>Folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as I&#8217;ve just demonstrated, while it often appears we do not agree and that &#8212; we &#8212; we do agree on a lot more things than we acknowledge. <br><br>I signed 80 bipartisan bills into law last year, from preventing government shutdowns, to protecting Asian Americans from still-too-common hate crimes, to reforming military justice.  And we’ll soon be strengthening the Violence Against Women Act that I first wrote three decades ago.  (Applause.)<br><br>And it’s important &#8212; (applause) &#8212; it’s important for us to show &#8212; to show the nation that we can come together and do big things. <br><br>So tonight, I’m offering a &#8220;Unity Agenda for the Nation&#8221;: four big things we can do together, in my view.<br><br>First, beat the opioid epidemic.  (Applause.)  There’s so much we can do: increase funding for prevention, treatment, harm reduction, and recovery; get rid of outdated rules and stop doctors and &#8212; that stop doctors from prescribing treatments; stop the flow of illicit drugs by working with state and local law enforcement to go after the traffickers.  (Applause.)<br><br>And if you’re suffering from addiction, you know &#8212; you should know you’re not alone.  I believe in recovery, and I celebrate the 23 million &#8212; 23 million Americans in recovery.  (Applause.)<br><br>Second, let’s take on mental health &#8212; especially among our children, whose lives and education have been turned upside down.<br><br>The American Rescue Plan gave schools money to hire teachers and help students make up for lost learning.  I urge every parent to make sure your school &#8212; your school does just that.  They have the money.<br><br>We can all play a part.  Sign up to be a tutor or a mentor.<br><br>Children were also struggling before the pandemic: bullying, violence, trauma, and the harms of social media.<br><br>As Frances Haugen, who is here tonight with us, has shown, we must hold social media platforms accountable for the national experiment they’re conducting on our children for profit.  (Applause.)  Folks &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.  Thank you for the courage you showed.<br><br>It’s time to strengthen privacy protections; ban targeted advertising to children &#8212; (applause); demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children. <br><br>And let’s get all Americans the mental health services they need &#8212; (applause) &#8212; more people can turn for help and full parity between physical and mental healthcare if we treat it that way in our insurance.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look, the third piece of that agenda is support our veterans.  (Applause.)  Veterans are the backbone and the spine of this country.  They’re the best of us.  (Applause.)<br><br>I’ve always believed that we have a sacred obligation to equip those we send to war and care for those and their family when they come home.<br><br>My administration is providing assistance and job training and housing, and now helping lower-income veterans get VA care debt free.<br><br>And our troops in Iraq have faced &#8212; and Afghanistan &#8212; have faced many dangers.  One being stationed at bases, breathing in toxic smoke from burn pits.  (Applause.)  Many of you have been there.  I’ve been in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan over 40 times.  These burn pits that incinerate waste &#8212; the wastes of war, medical and hazardous material, jet fuel, and so much more.<br><br>And they come home &#8212; many of the world’s fittest and best trained warriors in the world &#8212; never the same: headaches, numbness, dizziness, a cancer that would put them in a flag-draped coffin.  I know. <br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  You put them in.  Thirteen of them.<br><br>AUDIENCE:  Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  One of those &#8212; one of those soldiers was my son, Major Beau Biden.  I don’t know for sure if the burn pit that he lived near &#8212; that his hooch was near in Iraq and, earlier than that, in Kosovo is the cause of his brain cancer and the disease of so many other troops.  But I’m committed to find out everything we can.<br><br>Committed to military families like Danielle Robinson from Ohio, the widow of Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson.  He was born a soldier.  Army National Guard.  Combat medic in Kosovo and Iraq.  Stationed near Baghdad, just yards from burn pits the size of football fields.<br><br>Danielle is here with us tonight.  They loved going to Ohio State football games.  (Applause.)  And he loved building Legos with their daughter.  But cancer from prolonged exposure to burn pits ravaged Heath’s lungs and body.<br><br>Danielle says Heath was a fighter to the very end.  He didn’t know how to stop fighting, and neither did she.<br><br>Through her pain, she found purpose to demand that we do better.  Tonight, Danielle, we are going to do better.  (Applause)<br><br>The VA &#8212; the VA is pioneering new ways of linking toxic exposures to disease, already helping more veterans get benefits.  And tonight, I’m announcing we&#8217;re expanding eligibility to veterans suffering from nine respiratory cancers.<br><br>I’m also calling on Congress to pass a law to make sure veterans devastated by toxic exposure in Iraq and Afghanistan finally get the benefits and the comprehensive healthcare they deserve.  (Applause.)<br><br>And fourth and last, let’s end cancer as we know it.  (Applause.)  This is personal.  (Applause.)  This is personal to me and to Jill and to Kamala and so many of you.  So many of you have lost someone you love &#8212; husband, wife, son, daughter, mom, dad.<br><br>Cancer is the number-two cause of death in America, second only to heart disease.<br><br>Last month, I announced the plan to supercharge the Cancer Moonshot that President Obama asked me to lead six years ago.<br><br>Our goal is to cut cancer death rates by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years.  And I think we can do better than that: turn cancers from death sentences into treatable diseases, more support for patients and families.<br><br>To get there, I call on Congress to fund what I called ARPA-H &#8212; (applause): Advanced &#8212; Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health.  Patterned after DARPA in the Defense Department, projects that led &#8212; in DARPA &#8212; to the Internet, GPS, and so much more that make our forces more safer and be able to wage war more &#8212; with more clarity.<br><br>ARPA[-H] will have a singular purpose to drive breakthroughs in cancer, Alzheimer’s, and diabetes, and more.<br><br>A Unity Agenda for the nation.  We can do these things.  It&#8217;s within our power.  And I don&#8217;t see a partisan edge to any one of those four things. <br><br>My fellow Americans &#8212; (applause) &#8212; tonight we&#8217;ve gathered in a sacred space: the citadel of democracy.  In this Capitol, generation after generation of Americans have debated great questions amid great strife and have done great things.<br><br>We have fought for freedom, expanded liberty, <s>debated</s> [defeated] totalitarianism  and terror.  We built the strongest, freest, and most prosperous nation the world has ever known.<br><br>Now is the hour: our moment of responsibility, our test of resolve and conscience of history itself.  It is in this moment that our character of this generation is formed, our purpose is found, our future is forged.<br><br>Well, I know this nation.  We&#8217;ll meet the test, protect freedom and liberty, expand fairness and opportunity.  And we will save democracy.<br><br>As hard as those times have been, I’m more optimistic about America today than I&#8217;ve been my whole life because I see the future that&#8217;s within our grasp, because I know there is simply nothing beyond our camas- &#8212; our capacity.<br><br>We&#8217;re the only nation on Earth that has always turned every crisis we&#8217;ve faced into an opportunity, the only nation that can be defined by a single word: possibilities.<br><br>So, on this night, on our 245th year as a nation, I&#8217;ve come to report on the state of the nation &#8212; the state of the union.  And my report is this: The State of the Union is strong because you, the American people, are strong.  (Applause.)<br><br>We are stronger today &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we are stronger today than we were a year ago.  And we&#8217;ll be stronger a year from now than we are today.<br><br>This is our moment to meet and overcome the challenges of our time.  And we will, as one people, one America &#8212; the United States of America.  (Applause.)<br><br>God bless you all.  (Applause.)  And may God protect our troops.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Go get &#8217;em.<br><br>10:10 P.M. EST </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/02/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 15:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48148</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660 of March 6, 2014, which was expanded in scope in Executive Order 13661 of March 16, 2014, Executive Order 13662 of March 20, 2014, and Executive Order 14065 of February 21, 2022, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13685 of December&nbsp;19, 2014 and Executive Order 13849 of September 20, 2018, is to continue in effect beyond March&nbsp;6, 2022.&nbsp;<br><br>The actions and policies of persons that undermine democratic processes and institutions in Ukraine; threaten its peace, security, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity; and contribute to the misappropriation of its assets, as well as the actions and policies of the Government of the Russian Federation, including its purported annexation of Crimea, its use of force in Ukraine, and its purported recognition of the so-called Donetsk People&#8217;s Republic or Luhansk People&#8217;s Republic regions of Ukraine, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and&nbsp;foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; Therefore, I&nbsp;have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660 with respect to Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; March 2, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/02/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-ukraine-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 15:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 6, 2014, by Executive Order 13660, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions and policies of persons that undermine democratic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On March 6, 2014, by Executive Order 13660, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions and policies of persons that undermine democratic processes and institutions in Ukraine; threaten its peace, security, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity; and&nbsp;contribute to the misappropriation of its assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On March 16, 2014, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13661, which expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660, and found that the actions and policies of the Government of the Russian Federation with respect to Ukraine undermine democratic processes and institutions in Ukraine; threaten its peace, security, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity; and contribute to the misappropriation of its assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On March 20, 2014, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13662, which further expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660, as expanded in scope in Executive Order 13661, and found that the actions and policies of the Government of the Russian Federation, including its purported annexation of Crimea and its use of force in Ukraine, continue to undermine democratic processes and institutions in Ukraine; threaten its peace, security, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity; and contribute to the misappropriation of its assets.</p>



<p>On December 19, 2014, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13685, to take additional steps to address the Russian occupation of the Crimea region of Ukraine.</p>



<p>On September 20, 2018, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;13849, to take additional steps to implement certain statutory sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation.</p>



<p>On February 21, 2022, the President issued Executive Order&nbsp;14065, which further expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660, as expanded in scope in Executive Orders 13661 and 13662, and relied on for additional steps taken in Executive Orders 13685 and 13849, and found that the Russian Federation&#8217;s purported recognition of the so-called Donetsk People&#8217;s Republic or Luhansk People&#8217;s Republic regions of Ukraine contradicts Russia&#8217;s commitments under the Minsk agreements and further threatens the&nbsp;peace, stability, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of&nbsp;Ukraine, and thereby constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United&nbsp;States.</p>



<p>The actions and policies addressed in these Executive Orders continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660, which was expanded in scope in Executive Order&nbsp;13661, Executive Order 13662, and Executive Order 14065, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13685 and Executive Order 13849, must continue in effect beyond March&nbsp;6,&nbsp;2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of&nbsp;the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13660.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; March 2, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Addressing Addiction and the Overdose&#160;Epidemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-addressing-addiction-and-the-overdose-epidemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 03:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Drug overdose deaths have reached a historic high, devastating families and communities. More than 104,000 Americans died due to a drug overdose in the 12-month period ending in September 2021. We grieve these losses, and commit to continuing our work to save lives. Tonight, President Biden outlined the decisive actions his Administration is taking to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Drug overdose deaths have reached a historic high, devastating families and communities. More than 104,000 Americans died due to a drug overdose in the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nvss/vsrr/drug-overdose-data.htm">12-month period ending in September 2021</a>. We grieve these losses, and commit to continuing our work to save lives.</p>



<p>Tonight, President Biden outlined the decisive actions his Administration is taking to address addiction and the overdose epidemic and laid out a vision for how his Administration will continue to expand evidence-based prevention, harm reduction, treatment, recovery, and supply reduction approaches to save lives. <a>These efforts are bringing together Republicans and Democrats across the country because every community has been affected.</a></p>



<p>Specifically, the President outlined his comprehensive approach, including:</p>



<p><strong><em>Increasing Funding for Public Health and Supply Reduction</em></strong></p>



<p>According to the <a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/newsroom/press-announcements/202110260320#:~:text=The%20Substance%20Abuse%20and%20Mental%20Health%20Services%20Administration,had%20a%20negative%20impact%20on%20the%20nation%E2%80%99s%20well-being.">2020 National Survey on Drug Use and Health</a>, 40.3 million people aged 12 or older had a past-year substance use disorder. Meanwhile, more than four out of five Americans who need treatment for illicit drug use do not receive it. Mental health and substance use disorder services have been under-resourced for far too long, and the COVID-19 pandemic has placed an even greater burden on the system. The American Rescue Plan, which delivered nearly $4 billion to these services, was a down payment to support life-saving interventions. The President’s FY2022 budget request includes a historic $41 billion for drug policy efforts that will further these efforts. Specifically, the President is calling for:<br></p>



<ul><li>A historic proposed investment of $10.7 billion in discretionary funding for the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to fund research, prevention, harm reduction, treatment, and recovery support services, with a focus on meeting the needs of populations at greatest risk for overdose and substance use disorder. The President’s FY2022 budget proposes a total of $23.5 billion for public health approaches to reduce drug use and its consequences.</li></ul>



<ul><li>A proposed investment of $5.8 billion for interdiction efforts, which is an increase from the FY2021 enacted level. This funding would help reduce the availability of illicit drugs in the United States and abroad through air and maritime seizures; enhancement of drug source nations’ ability to interdict drugs; and efforts along the nation’s borders to stop the trafficking of illicit drugs, weapons, and bulk currency. The President’s FY2022 budget proposes a total of $17.5 billion for supply reduction efforts.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Removing Barriers to Treatment</em></strong></p>



<p>Medication for opioid use disorder (MOUD), such as buprenorphine and methadone, is a safe and effective treatment. However, <a>most Americans who need treatment for an opioid use disorder do not get it</a>. That is why President Biden has called for universal access to MOUD by 2025. To reach this goal, the Administration has advanced actions that remove unnecessary barriers that prevent medical providers from prescribing FDA-approved medications to their patients; lifted the moratorium on mobile vans providing methadone; supported states funding the purchase of such vans; and begun work on meeting individual treatment needs at times when people at high risk for an overdose need care and support.</p>



<ul><li>To further reduce burdens in accessing MOUD, the President supports eliminating outdated rules that place unnecessary administrative burdens on providers, discouraging them from prescribing effective treatments for addiction. The Administration will increase awareness and understanding of these medications so that patients and providers can make informed choices. This builds on last year’s action by HHS to <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/04/27/hhs-releases-new-buprenorphine-practice-guidelines-expanding-access-to-treatment-for-opioid-use-disorder.html">release</a>&nbsp;new Practice Guidelines for the Administration of Buprenorphine for Treating Opioid Use Disorder, which exempted eligible health care providers from Federal certification requirements related to training, counseling and other ancillary services that are part of the process for obtaining a waiver to treat up to 30 patients with buprenorphine. This action resulted in more providers registering to prescribe buprenorphine, thereby expanding access to evidence-based treatment.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Administration has extended and will propose making permanent the emergency provisions implemented during the COVID-19 pandemic concerning MOUD authorizations. This includes ongoing work allowing providers to begin treating patients with MOUD via telehealth, including by audio only, as well as the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/newsroom/press-announcements/202111181000">announcement</a> extending the methadone take-home flexibilities for one year, effective upon the eventual expiration of the COVID-19 Public Health Emergency.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Over the next year, the Administration plans to establish a set of hospital recommendations for overdose care and care coordination and create a model state law. Individuals who have experienced a non-fatal overdose are at greater risk of a fatal opioid overdose.&nbsp; Hospital emergency departments (EDs) offer a unique setting to initiate treatment, provide naloxone, and connect patients with peer support services.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Administration is working to expand MOUD throughout Federal incarcerated settings, in order to set an example for state and local jurisdictions. In conjunction with this effort, educational efforts will take place to support state and local jurisdictions in understanding the evidence and benefits of MOUD and community care connections upon release from incarceration – a time when individuals are at the highest risk for overdose. Recognizing that the prohibition of the use of federal funds for services behind bars acts is a barrier to states and counties in implementing evidence-based practices, an examination of federal funds usage and opportunities will take place during the coming year.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Reducing Harm and Saving Lives</em></strong></p>



<p>In reaction to the steep rise in overdose deaths and the increasingly lethal drug supply, the Biden-Harris Administration has prioritized engaging and building trust with people who use drugs in order to save lives and provide care. For the first time, harm reduction services – which include naloxone, fentanyl test strips, and syringe service programs – are a federal drug policy priority. These interventions are saving lives in red states and blue states, as years of research have demonstrated. People who use heroin and others who inject drugs who regularly utilize a Syringe Services Program (SSP) are <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/9633030/">five times more likely to initiate substance use disorder treatment</a>, compared with those who have never used an SSP. <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/19413790/">Syringe services sites can be effective platforms</a> to motivate people with opioid use disorder to enroll in substance use treatment and, over time, to reduce drug use and number of drug injections. Distribution of naloxone to reverse the effects of an opioid overdose <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32327162/">saves lives and is cost-effective</a>.</p>



<ul><li>The Administration has prioritized funds for harm reduction. The American Rescue Plan included <a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/grants/grant-announcements/sp-22-001">$30 million in support for harm reduction services</a> – a historic amount that will enhance interventions like syringe services programs. Additionally, CDC and the SAMHSA <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2021/p0407-Fentanyl-Test-Strips.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced&nbsp;</a>that federal funding may now be used to purchase fentanyl test strips in an effort to help curb the dramatic spike in drug overdose deaths.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Administration is including the input of people who use drugs in designing harm reduction interventions that will help save lives. In December, ONDCP, SAMHSA, and the CDC convened the first-ever Harm Reduction Summit. A steering committee made up entirely of people with lived experience is working to provide guidance and input on future Administration harm reduction efforts.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Administration plans to continue efforts to support syringe services programs through funding opportunities to provide these programs with needed supplies such as fentanyl test strips and sterile syringes, which have been proven to reduce diseases such as Hep-C and HIV.&nbsp; In addition, ensuring naloxone is easily and readily available to these programs will provide the overdose reversal medication to people who need it most.</li></ul>



<ul><li>In order to deliver resources to local communities, the Administration is working with states and communities to elevate harm reduction best practices. &nbsp;Last year, ONDCP released model laws for states to help expand access to naloxone and SSPs. This year, ONDCP plans to elevate best practices for harm reduction organizations initiating low-threshold treatment through warm hand-offs to care or colocation of treatment. The Administration plans to work with states to expand this strategy in communities most in need.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The overdose reversal medication naloxone is a critical tool for saving lives. However, equitable access to naloxone across the country is often defined by where you live. The Biden-Harris Administration is examining barriers to the acquisition and distribution of naloxone at the local level in order to increase access and availability where it is most needed.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Stopping the Trafficking of Illicit Drugs</em></strong></p>



<p>Transnational organized crime is a multi-billion-dollar enterprise that transcends geographical boundaries and threatens global stability.&nbsp; Every year, millions of lives are affected by transnational criminal organizations, including through drug overdose and addiction, violence, firearm deaths, human trafficking, and smuggling.&nbsp; Drug trafficking and transnational organized crime threatens our partners as well, especially in Latin America. It fuels corruption, unbalances economies, preys on the most vulnerable, and calls into question the very foundations of legitimate governance, all of which lead to internal population displacement and migration. Additionally, domestic drug trafficking organizations often contribute to public health challenges and violence in American communities. Addressing the core causes and sources of transnational and domestic criminal activities is an urgent priority for the Administration.</p>



<ul><li>In October, President Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/15/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-launches-new-efforts-to-counter-transnational-criminal-organizations-and-illicit-drugs/">announced</a> two Executive Orders to counter transnational criminal organizations and illicit drug trafficking: first, by formally establishing the U.S. Council on Transnational Organized Crime; and second, by modernizing and expanding the U.S. Government’s ability to target drug trafficking organizations, their enablers, and financial facilitators through sanctions and other related actions. With these new tools, the Administration will disrupt the drug traffickers’ ability to fund their business and deny them the benefits of their illicit activities.<br><br></li></ul>



<ul><li>Through its High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas (HIDTA) Program, ONDCP is funding new initiatives to reduce the violence associated with drug trafficking, refine interdiction efforts through enhanced data sharing and targeting, and go after illicit finance using innovative approaches, including cryptocurrency investigation. HIDTA baseline funds supporting these initiatives will be issued within 45 days of enactment of FY2022 appropriations. These efforts will leverage strategic partnerships with Federal agencies, academics, and private industry. ONDCP is evaluating emerging drug threats in a variety of geographic regions and is poised to expand the HIDTA Program, as needed, by designating new areas as HIDTAs to better equip these regions to disrupt and dismantle drug trafficking organizations. ONDCP plans to announce HIDTA designations this summer in the Federal Register.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The HIDTA Overdose Response Strategy, funded by ONDCP and CDC, brings together drug intelligence officers and public health analysts at the local and regional levels to share information and develop evidence-based intervention and support services that reduce overdoses.&nbsp; <a>The Strategy is piloting a range of innovative investigative, overdose prevention, and harm reduction approaches in all 50 states, Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and the District of Columbia.</a></li></ul>



<p>These actions build upon the significant efforts the Administration has advanced through its first-year drug policy priorities and the American Rescue Plan. These efforts delivered critical attention and resources to the communities that are tackling this crisis on the front lines. <strong>More information about </strong><strong>actions taken by the Biden-Harris Administration to address addiction and the overdose epidemic can be found&nbsp;</strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ondcp/briefing-room/2022/01/18/white-house-releases-list-of-actions-taken-by-the-biden-harris-administration-since-january-2021-to-address-addiction-and-the-overdose-epidemic/"><strong>HERE</strong></a><strong>.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks of President Joe&#160;Biden – State of the Union Address As Prepared for&#160;Delivery</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/01/remarks-of-president-joe-biden-state-of-the-union-address-as-delivered/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 02:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48125</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United States Capitol Madam Speaker, Madam Vice President, our First Lady and Second Gentleman. Members of Congress and the Cabinet.&#160;Justices of the Supreme Court. My fellow Americans.&#160;&#160; Last year COVID-19 kept us apart. This year we are finally together again.&#160; Tonight, we meet as Democrats&#160;Republicans&#160;and Independents.&#160;But most importantly as Americans.&#160; With a duty to one&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">United States Capitol</p>



<p>Madam Speaker, Madam Vice President, our First Lady and Second Gentleman. Members of Congress and the Cabinet.&nbsp;Justices of the Supreme Court. My fellow Americans.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Last year COVID-19 kept us apart. This year we are finally together again.&nbsp;<br><br>Tonight, we meet as Democrats&nbsp;Republicans&nbsp;and Independents.&nbsp;But most importantly as Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>With a duty to one another to the American people to the Constitution.&nbsp;<br><br>And with an unwavering resolve&nbsp;that freedom&nbsp;will always triumph over tyranny.&nbsp;<br><br>Six days ago, Russia’s Vladimir Putin sought to shake the foundations of the free world thinking he could make it bend to his menacing ways.&nbsp;But he badly miscalculated.&nbsp;<br><br>He thought he could roll into Ukraine and the world would roll over.&nbsp;Instead he met a wall of strength he never imagined.&nbsp;<br><br>He met the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;<br><br>From President&nbsp;Zelenskyy&nbsp;to every Ukrainian, their fearlessness, their courage, their&nbsp;determination, inspires the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Groups of citizens blocking tanks with their bodies.&nbsp;Everyone from students to retirees teachers turned soldiers defending their homeland.&nbsp;<br><br>In this struggle as President&nbsp;Zelenskyy&nbsp;said in his speech to the European Parliament “Light will win over darkness.”&nbsp;The Ukrainian Ambassador to the United States&nbsp;is here tonight.&nbsp;<br><br>Let each of us here tonight in this Chamber send an unmistakable signal to Ukraine and to the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Please rise if you are able and show that, Yes, we the United States of America&nbsp;stand with the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout our history we’ve learned this lesson&nbsp;when dictators do not pay a price for their aggression&nbsp;they cause more chaos.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>They keep moving.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And the costs and the threats&nbsp;to America and the world&nbsp;keep rising.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why the NATO Alliance&nbsp;was created&nbsp;to secure peace&nbsp;and stability in Europe&nbsp;after World War 2.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States&nbsp;is a member&nbsp;along with 29&nbsp;other nations.&nbsp;<br><br>It matters.&nbsp;American diplomacy matters.&nbsp;American resolve matters.&nbsp;<br><br>Putin’s latest attack on Ukraine&nbsp;was premeditated and unprovoked.&nbsp;<br><br>He rejected repeated efforts at diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>He thought the West&nbsp;and NATO&nbsp;wouldn’t respond.&nbsp;And he thought he could divide us at home. Putin was&nbsp;wrong. We were ready.&nbsp; Here is what we did.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We prepared extensively and carefully.&nbsp;<br><br>We spent months building a coalition of other freedom-loving nations from Europe and the Americas to Asia and Africa&nbsp;to confront Putin.&nbsp;<br><br>I spent countless hours unifying our European allies.&nbsp;We shared with the world in advance what we knew Putin was planning and precisely how he would try to falsely justify his aggression.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We countered Russia’s lies with truth.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And now that he has acted the free world is&nbsp;holding him&nbsp;accountable.&nbsp;<br><br>Along with twenty-seven members of the European Union including France, Germany, Italy, as well as countries like the United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, Korea, Australia, New Zealand, and many others, even Switzerland.&nbsp;<br><br>We are inflicting pain on Russia&nbsp;and supporting the people of Ukraine.&nbsp;Putin is now isolated from the world&nbsp;more than ever.&nbsp;<br><br>Together with our allies –we are right now&nbsp;enforcing powerful economic sanctions.&nbsp;<br><br>We are cutting off Russia’s largest banks from the international financial system.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Preventing Russia’s central bank from defending the Russian Ruble making Putin’s $630 Billion “war fund” worthless.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We are choking off Russia’s access to technology that will sap its economic strength and weaken its military for years to come.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Tonight I say to the Russian oligarchs and corrupt leaders who have bilked billions of dollars off this violent regime no more.&nbsp;<br><br>The U.S. Department of Justice is assembling a dedicated task force to go after the crimes of Russian oligarchs.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We are joining with our European allies to find and seize your yachts your luxury apartments your private jets. We are coming for your ill-begotten gains.&nbsp;<br><br>And tonight I am announcing that we will join our allies in closing off American air space to all Russian flights – further isolating Russia –&nbsp;and adding an additional squeeze –on their economy. The Ruble has lost 30% of its value.&nbsp;<br><br>The Russian stock market has lost 40% of its value&nbsp;and trading remains suspended. Russia’s economy is reeling and Putin alone is to blame.&nbsp;<br><br>Together with our allies we are providing support to the Ukrainians in their fight for freedom. Military assistance. Economic assistance.&nbsp;Humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>We are giving more than $1 Billion in direct assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>And we will continue to aid the Ukrainian people as they defend their country and to help ease their suffering.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Let me be clear, our forces are not engaged and will not engage in conflict with Russian forces&nbsp;in Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Our forces are&nbsp;not&nbsp;going to Europe to fight in Ukraine, but to defend our NATO Allies –&nbsp;in the event that Putin decides to keep moving west.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>For that purpose we’ve mobilized American ground forces, air squadrons, and ship deployments to protect NATO countries including Poland, Romania, Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.&nbsp;<br><br>As I have made crystal clear the United States and our Allies will defend every inch of territory of NATO countries with the full force of our collective power.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we remain clear-eyed. The Ukrainians are fighting back with pure courage.&nbsp;But the next few days weeks,&nbsp;months, will be hard on them.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Putin has unleashed violence and chaos.&nbsp; But while he may make gains on the battlefield – he will pay a continuing high price over the long run.&nbsp;<br><br>And a proud Ukrainian people, who have known 30 years&nbsp; of independence, have repeatedly shown that they will not tolerate anyone who tries to take&nbsp;their country backwards.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>To all Americans, I will be honest with you, as I’ve always promised.&nbsp;A Russian dictator, invading a foreign country, has costs around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’m taking robust action to make sure the pain of our sanctions&nbsp; is targeted at Russia’s economy. And I will use every tool at our disposal to protect American businesses and consumers.&nbsp;<br><br>Tonight, I can announce that the United States has worked with 30 other countries to release&nbsp;60 Million&nbsp;barrels of oil from reserves around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>America will lead that effort, releasing 30 Million barrels from our own Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp;And we stand ready to do more if necessary, unified with our allies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>These steps will help blunt gas prices&nbsp;here at home.&nbsp;And I know the news about what’s happening&nbsp;can seem alarming.&nbsp;<br><br>But I want you to know that we are going to be okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When the history of this era is written Putin’s war on Ukraine will have left Russia weaker and the rest of the world stronger. <br><br>While it shouldn’t have taken something so terrible for people around the world to see what’s at stake now everyone sees it clearly. <br><br>We see the unity among leaders of nations and a more unified Europe a more unified West. And we see unity among the people who are gathering in cities in large crowds around the world even in Russia to demonstrate their support for Ukraine.  <br><br>In the battle between democracy and autocracy, democracies are rising to the moment, and the world is clearly choosing the side of peace and security. <br><br>This is a real test. It’s going to take time. So let us continue to draw inspiration from the iron will of the Ukrainian people. <br><br>To our fellow Ukrainian Americans who forge a deep bond that connects our two nations we stand with you. <br><br>Putin may circle Kyiv with tanks, but he will never gain the hearts and souls of the Ukrainian people. <br><br>He will never extinguish their love of freedom. He will never weaken the resolve of the free world. <br><br>We meet tonight in an America that has lived through two of the hardest years this nation has ever faced. <br><br>The pandemic has been punishing. <br><br>And so many families are living paycheck to paycheck, struggling to keep up with the rising cost of food, gas, housing, and so much more. <br><br>I understand. <br><br>I remember when my Dad had to leave our home in Scranton, Pennsylvania to find work. I grew up in a family where if the price of food went up, you felt it. <br><br>That’s why one of the first things I did as President was fight to pass the American Rescue Plan.  <br><br>Because people were hurting. We needed to act, and we did. <br><br>Few pieces of legislation have done more in a critical moment in our history to lift us out of crisis. <br><br>It fueled our efforts to vaccinate the nation and combat COVID-19. It delivered immediate economic relief for tens of millions of Americans.  <br><br>Helped put food on their table, keep a roof over their heads, and cut the cost of health insurance. <br><br>And as my Dad used to say, it gave people a little breathing room. <br><br>And unlike the $2 Trillion tax cut passed in the previous administration that benefitted the top 1% of Americans, the American Rescue Plan helped working people—and left no one behind. <br><br>And it worked. It created jobs. Lots of jobs. <br><br>In fact—our economy created over 6.5 Million new jobs just last year, more jobs created in one year  <br>than ever before in the history of America. <br><br>Our economy grew at a rate of 5.7% last year, the strongest growth in nearly 40 years, the first step in bringing fundamental change to an economy that hasn’t worked for the working people of this nation for too long.  <br><br>For the past 40 years we were told that if we gave tax breaks to those at the very top, the benefits would trickle down to everyone else. <br><br>But that trickle-down theory led to weaker economic growth, lower wages, bigger deficits, and the widest gap between those at the top and everyone else in nearly a century. <br><br>Vice President Harris and I ran for office with a new economic vision for America. <br><br>Invest in America. Educate Americans. Grow the workforce. Build the economy from the bottom up  <br>and the middle out, not from the top down.  <br><br>Because we know that when the middle class grows, the poor have a ladder up and the wealthy do very well. <br><br>America used to have the best roads, bridges, and airports on Earth. <br><br>Now our infrastructure is ranked 13<sup>th</sup> in the world. <br><br>We won’t be able to compete for the jobs of the 21<sup>st</sup> Century if we don’t fix that. <br><br>That’s why it was so important to pass the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law—the most sweeping investment to rebuild America in history. <br><br>This was a bipartisan effort, and I want to thank the members of both parties who worked to make it happen. <br><br>We’re done talking about infrastructure weeks. <br><br>We’re going to have an infrastructure decade. <br><br>It is going to transform America and put us on a path to win the economic competition of the 21st Century that we face with the rest of the world—particularly with China.  <br><br>As I’ve told Xi Jinping, it is never a good bet to bet against the American people. <br><br>We’ll create good jobs for millions of Americans, modernizing roads, airports, ports, and waterways all across America. <br><br>And we’ll do it all to withstand the devastating effects of the climate crisis and promote environmental justice. <br><br>We’ll build a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations, begin to replace poisonous lead pipes—so every child—and every American—has clean water to drink at home and at school, provide affordable high-speed internet for every American—urban, suburban, rural, and tribal communities. <br><br>4,000 projects have already been announced. <br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing that this year we will start fixing over 65,000 miles of highway and 1,500 bridges in disrepair. <br><br>When we use taxpayer dollars to rebuild America – we are going to Buy American: buy American products to support American jobs. <br><br>The federal government spends about $600 Billion a year to keep the country safe and secure. <br><br>There’s been a law on the books for almost a century <br>to make sure taxpayers’ dollars support American jobs and businesses. <br><br>Every Administration says they’ll do it, but we are actually doing it. <br><br>We will buy American to make sure everything from the deck of an aircraft carrier to the steel on highway guardrails are made in America. <br><br>But to compete for the best jobs of the future, we also need to level the playing field with China and other competitors. <br><br>That’s why it is so important to pass the Bipartisan Innovation Act sitting in Congress that will make record investments in emerging technologies and American manufacturing. <br><br>Let me give you one example of why it’s so important to pass it. <br><br>If you travel 20 miles east of Columbus, Ohio, you’ll find 1,000 empty acres of land. <br><br>It won’t look like much, but if you stop and look closely, you’ll see a “Field of dreams,” the ground on which America’s future will be built. <br><br>This is where Intel, the American company that helped build Silicon Valley, is going to build its $20 billion semiconductor “mega site”. <br><br>Up to eight state-of-the-art factories in one place. 10,000 new good-paying jobs. <br><br>Some of the most sophisticated manufacturing in the world to make computer chips the size of a fingertip that power the world and our everyday lives. <br><br>Smartphones. The Internet. Technology we have yet to invent. <br><br>But that’s just the beginning. <br><br>Intel’s CEO, Pat Gelsinger, who is here tonight, told me they are ready to increase their investment from  <br>$20 billion to $100 billion. <br><br>That would be one of the biggest investments in manufacturing in American history. <br><br>And all they’re waiting for is for you to pass this bill. <br><br>So let’s not wait any longer. Send it to my desk. I’ll sign it.  <br><br>And we will really take off. <br><br>And Intel is not alone. <br><br>There’s something happening in America. <br><br>Just look around and you’ll see an amazing story. <br><br>The rebirth of the pride that comes from stamping products “Made In America.&#8221; The revitalization of American manufacturing.   <br><br>Companies are choosing to build new factories here, when just a few years ago, they would have built them overseas. <br><br>That’s what is happening. Ford is investing $11 billion to build electric vehicles, creating 11,000 jobs across the country. <br><br>GM is making the largest investment in its history—$7 billion to build electric vehicles, creating 4,000 jobs in Michigan. <br><br>All told, we created 369,000 new manufacturing jobs in America just last year. <br><br>Powered by people I’ve met like JoJo Burgess, from generations of union steelworkers from Pittsburgh, who’s here with us tonight. <br><br>As Ohio Senator Sherrod Brown says, “It’s time to bury the label “Rust Belt.” <br><br>It’s time. <br><br>But with all the bright spots in our economy, record job growth and higher wages, too many families are struggling to keep up with the bills.  <br><br>Inflation is robbing them of the gains they might otherwise feel. <br><br>I get it. That’s why my top priority is getting prices under control. <br><br>Look, our economy roared back faster than most predicted, but the pandemic meant that businesses had a hard time hiring enough workers to keep up production in their factories. <br><br>The pandemic also disrupted global supply chains. <br><br>When factories close, it takes longer to make goods and get them from the warehouse to the store, and prices go up. <br><br>Look at cars. <br><br>Last year, there weren’t enough semiconductors to make all the cars that people wanted to buy. <br><br>And guess what, prices of automobiles went up. <br><br>So—we have a choice. <br><br>One way to fight inflation is to drive down wages and make Americans poorer.  <br><br>I have a better plan to fight inflation. <br><br>Lower your costs, not your wages. <br><br>Make more cars and semiconductors in America. <br><br>More infrastructure and innovation in America. <br><br>More goods moving faster and cheaper in America. <br><br>More jobs where you can earn a good living in America. <br><br>And instead of relying on foreign supply chains, let’s make it in America. <br><br>Economists call it “increasing the productive capacity of our economy.” <br><br>I call it building a better America. <br><br>My plan to fight inflation will lower your costs and lower the deficit. <br><br>17 Nobel laureates in economics say my plan will ease long-term inflationary pressures. Top business leaders and most Americans support my plan. And here’s the plan: <br><br>First – cut the cost of prescription drugs. Just look at insulin. One in ten Americans has diabetes. In Virginia, I met a 13-year-old boy named Joshua Davis.  <br><br>He and his Dad both have Type 1 diabetes, which means they need insulin every day. Insulin costs about $10 a vial to make.  <br><br>But drug companies charge families like Joshua and his Dad up to 30 times more. I spoke with Joshua’s mom. <br><br>Imagine what it’s like to look at your child who needs insulin and have no idea how you’re going to pay for it.  <br><br>What it does to your dignity, your ability to look your child in the eye, to be the parent you expect to be. <br><br>Joshua is here with us tonight. Yesterday was his birthday. Happy birthday, buddy.  <br><br>For Joshua, and for the 200,000 other young people with Type 1 diabetes, let’s cap the cost of insulin at $35 a month so everyone can afford it.  <br><br>Drug companies will still do very well. And while we’re at it let Medicare negotiate lower prices for prescription drugs, like the VA already does. <br><br>Look, the American Rescue Plan is helping millions of families on Affordable Care Act plans save $2,400 a year on their health care premiums. Let’s close the coverage gap and make those savings permanent. <br><br>Second &#8211; cut energy costs for families an average of $500 a year by combatting climate change.  <br><br>Let’s provide investments and tax credits to weatherize your homes and businesses to be energy efficient and you get a tax credit; double America’s clean energy production in solar, wind, and so much more;  lower the price of electric vehicles, saving you another $80 a month because you’ll never have to pay at the gas pump again. <br><br>Third – cut the cost of child care. Many families pay up to $14,000 a year for child care per child.  <br><br>Middle-class and working families shouldn’t have to pay more than 7% of their income for care of young children.  <br><br>My plan will cut the cost in half for most families and help parents, including millions of women, who left the workforce during the pandemic because they couldn’t afford child care, to be able to get back to work. <br><br>My plan doesn’t stop there. It also includes home and long-term care. More affordable housing. And Pre-K for every 3- and 4-year-old.  <br><br>All of these will lower costs. <br><br>And under my plan, nobody earning less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional penny in new taxes. Nobody.  <br><br>The one thing all Americans agree on is that the tax system is not fair. We have to fix it.  <br><br>I’m not looking to punish anyone. But let’s make sure corporations and the wealthiest Americans start paying their fair share. <br><br>Just last year, 55 Fortune 500 corporations earned $40 billion in profits and paid zero dollars in federal income tax.  <br><br>That’s simply not fair. That’s why I’ve proposed a 15% minimum tax rate for corporations. <br><br>We got more than 130 countries to agree on a global minimum tax rate so companies can’t get out of paying their taxes at home by shipping jobs and factories overseas. <br><br>That’s why I’ve proposed closing loopholes so the very wealthy don’t pay a lower tax rate than a teacher or a firefighter.  <br><br>So that’s my plan. It will grow the economy and lower costs for families. <br><br>So what are we waiting for? Let’s get this done. And while you’re at it, confirm my nominees to the Federal Reserve, which plays a critical role in fighting inflation.  <br><br>My plan will not only lower costs to give families a fair shot, it will lower the deficit. <br><br>The previous Administration not only ballooned the deficit with tax cuts for the very wealthy and corporations, it undermined the watchdogs whose job was to keep pandemic relief funds from being wasted. <br><br>But in my administration, the watchdogs have been welcomed back. <br><br>We’re going after the criminals who stole billions in relief money meant for small businesses and millions of Americans.  <br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing that the Justice Department will name a chief prosecutor for pandemic fraud. <br><br>By the end of this year, the deficit will be down to less than half what it was before I took office.  <br><br>The only president ever to cut the deficit by more than one trillion dollars in a single year. <br><br>Lowering your costs also means demanding more competition. <br><br>I’m a capitalist, but capitalism without competition isn’t capitalism. <br><br>It’s exploitation—and it drives up prices. <br><br>When corporations don’t have to compete, their profits go up, your prices go up, and small businesses and family farmers and ranchers go under. <br><br>We see it happening with ocean carriers moving goods in and out of America. <br><br>During the pandemic, these foreign-owned companies raised prices by as much as 1,000% and made record profits. <br><br>Tonight, I’m announcing a crackdown on these companies overcharging American businesses and consumers. <br><br>And as Wall Street firms take over more nursing homes, quality in those homes has gone down and costs have gone up.  <br><br>That ends on my watch. <br><br>Medicare is going to set higher standards for nursing homes and make sure your loved ones get the care they deserve and expect. <br><br>We’ll also cut costs and keep the economy going strong by giving workers a fair shot, provide more training and apprenticeships, hire them based on their skills not degrees. <br><br>Let’s pass the Paycheck Fairness Act and paid leave.  <br><br>Raise the minimum wage to $15 an hour and extend the Child Tax Credit, so no one has to raise a family in poverty. <br><br>Let’s increase Pell Grants and increase our historic support of HBCUs, and invest in what Jill—our First Lady who teaches full-time—calls America’s best-kept secret: community colleges. <br><br>And let’s pass the PRO Act when a majority of workers want to form a union—they shouldn’t be stopped.  <br><br>When we invest in our workers, when we build the economy from the bottom up and the middle out together, we can do something we haven’t done in a long time: build a better America. <br><br>For more than two years, COVID-19 has impacted every decision in our lives and the life of the nation. <br><br>And I know you’re tired, frustrated, and exhausted. <br><br>But I also know this. <br><br>Because of the progress we’ve made, because of your resilience and the tools we have, tonight I can say  <br>we are moving forward safely, back to more normal routines.  <br><br>We’ve reached a new moment in the fight against COVID-19, with severe cases down to a level not seen since last July.  <br><br>Just a few days ago, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention—the CDC—issued new mask guidelines. <br><br>Under these new guidelines, most Americans in most of the country can now be mask free.   <br><br>And based on the projections, more of the country will reach that point across the next couple of weeks. <br><br>Thanks to the progress we have made this past year, COVID-19 need no longer control our lives.  <br><br>I know some are talking about “living with COVID-19”. Tonight – I say that we will never just accept living with COVID-19. <br><br>We will continue to combat the virus as we do other diseases. And because this is a virus that mutates and spreads, we will stay on guard. <br><br>Here are four common sense steps as we move forward safely.  <br><br>First, stay protected with vaccines and treatments. We know how incredibly effective vaccines are. If you’re vaccinated and boosted you have the highest degree of protection. <br><br>We will never give up on vaccinating more Americans. Now, I know parents with kids under 5 are eager to see a vaccine authorized for their children. <br><br>The scientists are working hard to get that done and we’ll be ready with plenty of vaccines when they do. <br><br>We’re also ready with anti-viral treatments. If you get COVID-19, the Pfizer pill reduces your chances of ending up in the hospital by 90%.  <br><br>We’ve ordered more of these pills than anyone in the world. And Pfizer is working overtime to get us 1 Million pills this month and more than double that next month.  <br><br>And we’re launching the “Test to Treat” initiative so people can get tested at a pharmacy, and if they’re positive, receive antiviral pills on the spot at no cost.  <br><br>If you’re immunocompromised or have some other vulnerability, we have treatments and free high-quality masks. <br><br>We’re leaving no one behind or ignoring anyone’s needs as we move forward. <br><br>And on testing, we have made hundreds of millions of tests available for you to order for free.   <br><br>Even if you already ordered free tests tonight, I am announcing that you can order more from covidtests.gov starting next week. <br><br>Second – we must prepare for new variants. Over the past year, we’ve gotten much better at detecting new variants. <br><br>If necessary, we’ll be able to deploy new vaccines within 100 days instead of many more months or years.  <br><br>And, if Congress provides the funds we need, we’ll have new stockpiles of tests, masks, and pills ready if needed. <br><br>I cannot promise a new variant won’t come. But I can promise you we’ll do everything within our power to be ready if it does.  <br><br>Third – we can end the shutdown of schools and businesses. We have the tools we need. <br><br>It’s time for Americans to get back to work and fill our great downtowns again.  People working from home can feel safe to begin to return to the office.   <br><br>We’re doing that here in the federal government. The vast majority of federal workers will once again work in person. <br><br>Our schools are open. Let’s keep it that way. Our kids need to be in school. <br><br>And with 75% of adult Americans fully vaccinated and hospitalizations down by 77%, most Americans can remove their masks, return to work, stay in the classroom, and move forward safely. <br><br>We achieved this because we provided free vaccines, treatments, tests, and masks. <br><br>Of course, continuing this costs money. <br><br>I will soon send Congress a request. <br><br>The vast majority of Americans have used these tools and may want to again, so I expect Congress to pass it quickly.   <br><br>Fourth, we will continue vaccinating the world.     <br><br>We’ve sent 475 Million vaccine doses to 112 countries, more than any other nation. <br><br>And we won’t stop. <br><br>We have lost so much to COVID-19. Time with one another. And worst of all, so much loss of life. <br><br>Let’s use this moment to reset. Let’s stop looking at COVID-19 as a partisan dividing line and see it for what it is: A God-awful disease.  <br><br>Let’s stop seeing each other as enemies, and start seeing each other for who we really are: Fellow Americans.  <br><br>We can’t change how divided we’ve been. But we can change how we move forward—on COVID-19 and other issues we must face together. <br><br>I recently visited the New York City Police Department days after the funerals of Officer Wilbert Mora and his partner, Officer Jason Rivera. <br><br>They were responding to a 9-1-1 call when a man shot and killed them with a stolen gun. <br><br>Officer Mora was 27 years old. <br><br>Officer Rivera was 22. <br><br>Both Dominican Americans who’d grown up on the same streets they later chose to patrol as police officers. <br><br>I spoke with their families and told them that we are forever in debt for their sacrifice, and we will carry on their mission to restore the trust and safety every community deserves. <br><br>I’ve worked on these issues a long time. <br><br>I know what works: Investing in crime preventionand community police officers who’ll walk the beat, who’ll know the neighborhood, and who can restore trust and safety. <br><br>So let’s not abandon our streets. Or choose between safety and equal justice. <br><br>Let’s come together to protect our communities, restore trust, and hold law enforcement accountable. <br><br>That’s why the Justice Department required body cameras, banned chokeholds, and restricted no-knock warrants for its officers. <br><br>That’s why the American Rescue Plan provided $350 Billion that cities, states, and counties can use to hire more police and invest in proven strategies like community violence interruption—trusted messengers breaking the cycle of violence and trauma and giving young people hope.  <br><br>We should all agree: The answer is not to Defund the police. The answer is to FUND the police with the resources and training they need to protect our communities. <br><br>I ask Democrats and Republicans alike: Pass my budget and keep our neighborhoods safe.  <br><br>And I will keep doing everything in my power to crack down on gun trafficking and ghost guns you can buy online and make at home—they have no serial numbers and can’t be traced. <br><br>And I ask Congress to pass proven measures to reduce gun violence. Pass universal background checks. Why should anyone on a terrorist list be able to purchase a weapon? <br><br>Ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines. <br><br>Repeal the liability shield that makes gun manufacturers the only industry in America that can’t be sued. <br><br>These laws don’t infringe on the Second Amendment. They save lives. <br><br>The most fundamental right in America is the right to vote – and to have it counted. And it’s under assault. <br><br>In state after state, new laws have been passed, not only to suppress the vote, but to subvert entire elections. <br><br>We cannot let this happen. <br><br>Tonight. I call on the Senate to: Pass the Freedom to Vote Act. Pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act. And while you’re at it, pass the Disclose Act so Americans can know who is funding our elections. <br><br>Tonight, I’d like to honor someone who has dedicated his life to serve this country: Justice Stephen Breyer—an Army veteran, Constitutional scholar, and retiring Justice of the United States Supreme Court. Justice Breyer, thank you for your service. <br><br>One of the most serious constitutional responsibilities a President has is nominating someone to serve on the United States Supreme Court. <br><br>And I did that 4 days ago, when I nominated Circuit Court of Appeals Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson. One of our nation’s top legal minds, who will continue Justice Breyer’s legacy of excellence. <br><br>A former top litigator in private practice. A former federal public defender. And from a family of public school educators and police officers. A consensus builder. Since she’s been nominated, she’s received a broad range of support—from the Fraternal Order of Police to former judges appointed by Democrats and Republicans. <br><br>And if we are to advance liberty and justice, we need to secure the Border and fix the immigration system. <br><br>We can do both. At our border, we’ve installed new technology like cutting-edge scanners to better detect drug smuggling.  <br><br>We’ve set up joint patrols with Mexico and Guatemala to catch more human traffickers.  <br><br>We’re putting in place dedicated immigration judges so families fleeing persecution and violence can have their cases heard faster. <br><br>We’re securing commitments and supporting partners in South and Central America to host more refugees and secure their own borders. <br><br>We can do all this while keeping lit the torch of liberty that has led generations of immigrants to this land—my forefathers and so many of yours. <br><br>Provide a pathway to citizenship for Dreamers, those on temporary status, farm workers, and essential workers. <br><br>Revise our laws so businesses have the workers they need and families don’t wait decades to reunite. <br><br>It’s not only the right thing to do—it’s the economically smart thing to do. <br><br>That’s why immigration reform is supported by everyone from labor unions to religious leaders to the U.S. Chamber of Commerce. <br><br>Let’s get it done once and for all. <br><br>Advancing liberty and justice also requires protecting the rights of women. <br><br>The constitutional right affirmed in Roe v. Wade—standing precedent for half a century—is under attack as never before. <br><br>If we want to go forward—not backward—we must protect access to health care. Preserve a woman’s right to choose. And let’s continue to advance maternal health care in America. <br><br>And for our LGBTQ+ Americans, let’s finally get the bipartisan Equality Act to my desk. The onslaught of state laws targeting transgender Americans and their families is wrong. <br><br>As I said last year, especially to our younger transgender Americans, I will always have your back as your President, so you can be yourself and reach your God-given potential. <br><br>While it often appears that we never agree, that isn’t true. I signed 80 bipartisan bills into law last year. From preventing government shutdowns to protecting Asian-Americans from still-too-common hate crimes to reforming military justice. <br><br>And soon, we’ll strengthen the Violence Against Women Act that I first wrote three decades ago. It is important for us to show the nation that we can come together and do big things. <br><br>So tonight I’m offering a Unity Agenda for the Nation. Four big things we can do together.  <br><br>First, beat the opioid epidemic. <br><br>There is so much we can do. Increase funding for prevention, treatment, harm reduction, and recovery.  <br><br>Get rid of outdated rules that stop doctors from prescribing treatments. And stop the flow of illicit drugs by working with state and local law enforcement to go after traffickers. <br><br>If you’re suffering from addiction, know you are not alone. I believe in recovery, and I celebrate the 23 million Americans in recovery. <br><br>Second, let’s take on mental health. Especially among our children, whose lives and education have been turned upside down.  <br><br>The American Rescue Plan gave schools money to hire teachers and help students make up for lost learning.  <br><br>I urge every parent to make sure your school does just that. And we can all play a part—sign up to be a tutor or a mentor. <br><br>Children were also struggling before the pandemic. Bullying, violence, trauma, and the harms of social media. <br><br>As Frances Haugen, who is here with us tonight, has shown, we must hold social media platforms accountable for the national experiment they’re conducting on our children for profit. <br><br>It’s time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children, demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children. <br><br>And let’s get all Americans the mental health services they need. More people they can turn to for help, and full parity between physical and mental health care. <br><br>Third, support our veterans. <br><br>Veterans are the best of us. <br><br>I’ve always believed that we have a sacred obligation to equip all those we send to war and care for them and their families when they come home. <br><br>My administration is providing assistance with job training and housing, and now helping lower-income veterans get VA care debt-free.  <br><br>Our troops in Iraq and Afghanistan faced many dangers. <br><br>One was stationed at bases and breathing in toxic smoke from “burn pits&#8221; that incinerated wastes of war—medical and hazard material, jet fuel, and more. <br><br>When they came home, many of the world’s fittest and best trained warriors were never the same. <br><br>Headaches. Numbness. Dizziness. <br><br>A cancer that would put them in a flag-draped coffin. <br><br>I know. <br><br>One of those soldiers was my son Major Beau Biden. <br><br>We don’t know for sure if a burn pit was the cause of his brain cancer, or the diseases of so many of our troops. <br><br>But I’m committed to finding out everything we can. <br><br>Committed to military families like Danielle Robinson from Ohio. <br><br>The widow of Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson.  <br><br>He was born a soldier. Army National Guard. Combat medic in Kosovo and Iraq. <br><br>Stationed near Baghdad, just yards from burn pits the size of football fields. <br><br>Heath’s widow Danielle is here with us tonight. They loved going to Ohio State football games. He loved building Legos with their daughter. <br><br>But cancer from prolonged exposure to burn pits ravaged Heath’s lungs and body. <br><br>Danielle says Heath was a fighter to the very end. <br><br>He didn’t know how to stop fighting, and neither did she. <br><br>Through her pain she found purpose to demand we do better. <br><br>Tonight, Danielle—we are. <br><br>The VA is pioneering new ways of linking toxic exposures to diseases, already helping more veterans get benefits. <br><br>And tonight, I’m announcing we&#8217;re expanding eligibility to veterans suffering from nine respiratory cancers. <br><br>I’m also calling on Congress: pass a law to make sure veterans devastated by toxic exposures in Iraq and Afghanistan finally get the benefits and comprehensive health care they deserve. <br><br>And fourth, let’s end cancer as we know it. <br><br>This is personal to me and Jill, to Kamala, and to so many of you. <br><br>Cancer is the #2 cause of death in America–second only to heart disease. <br><br>Last month, I announced our plan to supercharge  <br>the Cancer Moonshot that President Obama asked me to lead six years ago. <br><br>Our goal is to cut the cancer death rate by at least 50% over the next 25 years, turn more cancers from death sentences into treatable diseases.  <br><br>More support for patients and families. <br><br>To get there, I call on Congress to fund ARPA-H, the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health. <br><br>It’s based on DARPA—the Defense Department project that led to the Internet, GPS, and so much more.  <br><br>ARPA-H will have a singular purpose—to drive breakthroughs in cancer, Alzheimer’s, diabetes, and more. <br><br>A unity agenda for the nation. <br><br>We can do this. <br><br>My fellow Americans—tonight , we have gathered in a sacred space—the citadel of our democracy. <br><br>In this Capitol, generation after generation, Americans have debated great questions amid great strife, and have done great things. <br><br>We have fought for freedom, expanded liberty, defeated totalitarianism and terror. <br><br>And built the strongest, freest, and most prosperous nation the world has ever known. <br><br>Now is the hour. <br><br>Our moment of responsibility. <br><br>Our test of resolve and conscience, of history itself. <br><br>It is in this moment that our character is formed. Our purpose is found. Our future is forged. <br><br>Well I know this nation.  <br><br>We will meet the test. <br><br>To protect freedom and liberty, to expand fairness and opportunity. <br><br>We will save democracy. <br><br>As hard as these times have been, I am more optimistic about America today than I have been my whole life. <br><br>Because I see the future that is within our grasp. <br><br>Because I know there is simply nothing beyond our capacity. <br><br>We are the only nation on Earth that has always turned every crisis we have faced into an opportunity. <br><br>The only nation that can be defined by a single word: possibilities. <br><br>So on this night, in our 245<sup>th</sup> year as a nation, I have come to report on the State of the Union. <br><br>And my report is this: the State of the Union is strong—because you, the American people, are strong. <br><br>We are stronger today than we were a year ago. <br><br>And we will be stronger a year from now than we are today. <br><br>Now is our moment to meet and overcome the challenges of our time. <br><br>And we will, as one people. <br><br>One America. <br><br>The United States of America. <br><br>May God bless you all. May God protect our troops. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
