<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 20:36:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden&#160;and Prime Minister Draghi Of Italy&#160;Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/10/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-draghi-of-italy-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 20:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 2:02 P.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, Mr. Prime Minister, it’s great to have you here.&#160; You’ve been a good friend and a great ally.&#160; And it’s my pleasure to welcome you to the White House and have a chance to repay some of the hospitality that you &#8212; you extended to me at&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>2:02 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. Prime Minister, it’s great to have you here.&nbsp; You’ve been a good friend and a great ally.&nbsp; And it’s my pleasure to welcome you to the White House and have a chance to repay some of the hospitality that you &#8212; you extended to me at the G20 Summit and in Rome.</p>



<p>And I guess we’re &#8212; in the G7, we&#8217;re going to be meeting a little bit later.&nbsp; On Sunday, we had that meeting.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to have a second COVID meeting as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; So, we’re spending a lot of time together.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a></a><a></a>You’ve been one of the closest allies we’ve had in responding to (inaudible) brutality of Putin.&nbsp;&nbsp;And I just think that your cooperation at &#8212; sometimes at a greater cost to others to take on Putin and what&#8217;s going on in Ukraine has been really incredible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you know, Mr. Prime Minister, Italy and the United States have a long history of shared bonds and so many &#8212; so many Italian Americans who are so proud of their heritage here, as you’ve observed.</p>



<p>Congratulations on your award.&nbsp; That&#8217;s pretty good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; That’s pretty cool.</p>



<p>And so, welcome.&nbsp; We have a lot to talk about.&nbsp; And the floor is yours.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Let me say that it&#8217;s a great pleasure to be with you here today.&nbsp; Thanks for this invitation.&nbsp; Thanks for this magnificent hospitality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our two countries &#8212; the ties between our two countries have always been very strong.&nbsp; And, if anything, this war in Ukraine made them stronger.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I agree.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; If Putin ever thought that he could divide us, he failed.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question about that.</p>



<p>We stand together in condemning the invasion of Ukraine, on sanctioning Russia, and on helping Ukraine, as President Zelenskyy is asking us to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I have to tell you that in Italy and in Europe now, people want to put an end to this massacres &#8212; to these massacres, to this violence, this butchery that’s happening.&nbsp;&nbsp; And people think about what can we do to bring peace.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We certainly have to use any direct, indirec- &#8212; indirect channel of communication.&nbsp; But is that enough?&nbsp; What can we do?</p>



<p>People think that &#8212; at least they want to think about the possibility of bringing a ceasefire and starting again some credible negotiations.  That&#8217;s the situation right now.  I think that we have to think deeply on how to address this.  <br><br>We will continue, you and I, to work on energy security &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Yes, we will.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:  &#8212; food security, especially, which is now another issue there.  We&#8217;ll talk later about that, what to do. <br><br>And &#8212; and then, the other thing that I want to say, just at the opening &#8212; and then I don&#8217;t think we will discuss this later &#8212; but what happened in Ukraine is going to bring a drastic change in European Union. </p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I agree.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always been close.&nbsp; Now we&#8217;re going to be much closer.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I know I can &#8212; I can count on your support as a true friend of Europe and of Italy, of course.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, Joe.&nbsp;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, look, and just one &#8212; I want to add one thing that.&nbsp; I believe that a strong European Union is in the interest of the United States.&nbsp; Granted, that&#8217;s competition, economically, but it&#8217;s good.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I joked when the Union was formally formed, saying this is like &#8212; we have a thing called the “Commerce Clause.”<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You go from one state to the other &#8212;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; I remember.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; you don&#8217;t have to go through checkpoints.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s sort of Europe’s Commerce Clause.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And it&#8217;s good for everyone.&nbsp; And the thing that I most appreciate about you is that our effort from the very beginning to bring NATO and the EU in lockstep &#8212; Putin really believed he could split us.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER DRAGHI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And we got &#8212; we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve all stepped up.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But at any rate, I&#8217;m delighted you&#8217;re here, anxious to talk to you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And watch how they get out of here without getting hurt.&nbsp; They actually walk out of the room without knocking each other down.<br><br>2:08 P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden on the&#160;Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/10/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-economy-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 18:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:58 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today I’d like to talk about two potential paths forward to address the number-one challenge facing families today: inflation.&#160; This will not be my only speech on inflation, I’m sure.&#160; But when you look at the economy today, it’s clear that we’ve made enormous strides. And our plans&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:58 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today I’d like to talk about two potential paths forward to address the number-one challenge facing families today: inflation.&nbsp;<br><br>This will not be my only speech on inflation, I’m sure.&nbsp; But when you look at the economy today, it’s clear that we’ve made enormous strides.<br><br>And our plans and our policies have produced the strongest job creation economy in modern times.&nbsp; In addition, 8.3 million jobs in my first 15 months in office &#8212; a record.<br><br>Unemployment rates are down to 3.6 percent &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment to start a presidential term ever recorded.<br><br>And in addition, Americans have applied to start three- &#8212; 5.4 million new small businesses last year &#8212; 20 percent more than any other year on record.<br><br>And I see &#8212; and as I see it, everything &#8212; everything across the country is &#8212; as I go across the country, our economy has gone from being on the mend to on the move.<br><br>But for every worker I met who’s gained a little bit of breathing room to seek out a better-paying job, for every entrepreneur who’s gained the confidence to pursue their&nbsp;small-business dreams, I know that families all across America are hurting because of inflation.<br><br>I understand what it feels like.&nbsp; I come from a family where when the pr- &#8212; when the price of gas or food went up, we felt it.&nbsp; It was a discussion at the kitchen table.<br><br>I went &#8212; I want every American to know that I’m taking inflation very seriously and it’s my top domestic priority.<br><br>And I’m here today to talk about solutions.&nbsp; And there’s going to be more we’re going to have to talk about as well.<br><br>But first, I want us to be crystal clear about the problem.&nbsp;<br><br>There are two leading causes of inflation we’re seeing today.&nbsp; The first cause of inflation is a once-in-a-century pandemic.&nbsp; Not only did it shut down our global economy, it threw the supply chain and demand completely out of whack, especially in countries where more effective recovery responses weren&#8217;t available, especially in those sectors that rely on semiconductors.<br><br>These supply challenges have been further hampered by the onset of Delta and Omicron viruses.&nbsp; And you’ve all seen it and you’ve all felt it.&nbsp;<br><br>And this year we have a second cause &#8212; a second cause: Mr. Putin’s war in Ukraine.<br><br>You saw &#8212; we saw in March that 60 percent of inflation that month was due to price increases at the pump for gasoline.<br><br>Putin’s war has raised food prices as well, because Ukraine and Russia are two of the world’s major breadbaskets of &#8212; for wheat and corn &#8212; are, essentially, completely stalled.<br><br>Ukraine has 20 &#8212; 20 million tons of grain in storage in silos right now.&nbsp; They’re trying to figure out how to get it out of the country to market, which would reduce prices around the world.<br><br>Normally &#8212; normally, we’d have already begun to export them into the market.&nbsp; But it &#8212; but it hasn’t because of Putin’s invasion.<br><br>So we’re working with our European partners to get this food out into the world so that it could help bring down prices.&nbsp; But it’s difficult because, again, of Putin and the Russian invasion of Ukraine.<br><br>And those two major contributors to inflation are both global in nature.&nbsp; That’s why we’re seeing historic inflation in countries all over the world.<br><br>But here’s the good news: Because of the actions we’ve taken, America is in a stronger position to meet this challenge than just about any other country in the world.<br><br>Some of the roots of the inflation are outside of our control, to state the obvious.&nbsp; But there are things we can do and we can address and we need to do.<br><br>That starts with the Federal Reserve, which plays a primary role in fighting inflation in our country.<br><br>I’ve put forward a highly qua- &#8212; highly qualified nominees to lead that institution.&nbsp; And I strongly urge the Senate confirm them without delay.<br><br>The Fed has dual responsibilities.&nbsp; First is achieving maximum employment, and second is stable prices.<br><br>And while I’ll never interfere with the Fed’s judgments, decisions, or tell them what they have to do &#8212; they’re independent; they’re independent &#8212; I believe that inflation is our top economic challenge right now, and I think they do too.<br><br>I’ve built a strong ec- &#8212; we’ve built a strong economy with a strong job market.&nbsp; And I agree with what Chairman Powell said last week that the number-one threat is the strength &#8212; and that strength that we built is inflation.<br><br>So the Fed should do its job and it will do its job, I’m convinced, with that in mind.<br><br>Now, as I said when I came to &#8212; to what Congress and the President can do to fight inflation, Americans have two potential paths forward.&nbsp; The first is my plan, the Democratic plan.&nbsp; A plan put forward by congressional Republicans is a second alternative.<br><br>Here’s how each of us would tackle inflation:<br><br>My plan is to lower employer [sic] &#8212; lower everyday costs for &#8212; everyday costs for hardworking families and lower the deficit by asking large corporations and the wealthiest Americans to not engage in price gouging and to pay their fair share in taxes.<br><br>The Republican plan is to increase taxes on the middle-class families and let billionaires and large companies off the hook as they raise profit and &#8212; raise prices and reap profits at record number &#8212; record amounts.&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s really that simple.&nbsp;<br><br>But let me explain why this choice is so important.&nbsp; Let me start &#8212; let me start with the Putin price hike: high gas prices and energy prices.<br><br>My plan is already in motion.&nbsp; I led the world and other countries to join with us to coordinate the largest release of oil from our stockpiles of all the countries in history &#8212; 240 million barrels to boost global supply.<br><br>Here at home, U.S. oil and gas production is approaching record levels.&nbsp; In fact, we produced more oil domestically in my first year in office than my predecessor did in his first year.<br><br>To further drive down prices, my administration is allowing the sta- &#8212; the sale of gasoline using homegrown biofuels &#8212; biofuels this summer, which wasn’t allowed before.<br><br>And to reduce our dependence on foreign oil and reckless autocrats like Putin, I’m working with Congress to pass landmark investments to help build a clean energy future as well &#8212; from tax credits for businesses to produce renewable energy to tax credits for families to make their homes more energy efficient.<br><br>I met with nearly a dozen CEOs of America’s largest utility companies.&nbsp; And they, to a person, told me that &#8212; and including Southern Company, American Electric Power, and 10 others &#8212; they confirmed that if we pass the investments I’m talking about, it will immediately lower families’ utility bills by as much as $500 a year, according to one estimate.&nbsp; That’s &#8212; it’s going to make their homes more secure in terms of heat not getting out and air conditioning not escaping, because they have good insulation.<br><br>Now, what’s the congressional Republican plan with respect to energy?<br><br>First of all, their plan is to give oil companies a free pass.&nbsp; For example, right now, oil companies are sitting on 9,000 unused leases &#8212; oil leases &#8212; which are the property of the federal government &#8212; on the property of the federal government.<br><br>Under my plan, they would have to pay taxes and &#8212; if they don’t use those leases to produce more oil.&nbsp; They just can’t sit on it.<br><br>Unlike &#8212; under the Republican plan, they’d be allowed to continue to sit on this land without producing while shipping record profits back to their investors.<br><br>The fact is the average cost of a barrel of oil has been steady for weeks.&nbsp; So &#8212; so why do gas prices keep going up so high?<br><br>Republicans have offered plenty of blame but not a single solution to actually bring down the energy prices.<br><br>You know, we have no plan &#8212; they have no plan to bring down energy prices today; no plan to get us to a cleaner, energy-independent future tomorrow so, in the future, American families are no longer subject to the whims and &#8212; of dictators half a way around the world.<br><br>The next thing is: Let’s compare our plans when it comes to lowering everyday costs.&nbsp; My plan is to make concrete &#8212; concrete, commonsense steps to bring down the biggest expenses that families are facing.<br><br>Let’s take drug prices.&nbsp; My plan would let Medicare negotiate prices for prescription drugs, like they do with the &#8212; with the Department of &#8212; with the military as it relates to what the administration is able to negotiate for prices for military.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The cap &#8212; and I also call for a cap on the price of insulin, which 200 million &#8212; excuse me, I beg your pardon &#8212; 200,000 American children rely on because they have Type 2 diabetes, at $35 a month &#8212; it costs $10 to make the insulin; they make a significant profit &#8212; instead of the average price of about $640 a month.<br><br>Think of the difference it will make in millions of American families, like the family I met in Virginia about three weeks ago struggling every day, every single month to afford their son’s insulin.<br><br>On this and other issues, I’ve laid out specific proposals to Congress to bring down the cost of &#8212; everyday costs all American fam- &#8212; many American families face.<br><br>And that’s in addition to the work my administration has already done to lower prices.<br><br>Another reason why prices are up for products people need relates to whether or not the manufacturer has access to all the materials they need to build a product.<br><br>Think of the materials you need to build a house.&nbsp; If you can’t get materials from ship to shore, from the &#8212; from the shore to the home, the prices are going to go up.<br><br>That’s why we brought labor and industry together on the West Coast to improve operations at the ports to speed up the transfer of products from abroad to shore, from shore to the location where they’re going to be used so that those products can move more quickly and cheaply.<br><br>We haven’t had enough truckers, for example, to deliver the lumber or other goods.&nbsp; That’s why we’re executing a plan to get more truckers on the job.&nbsp; It reduces the time it takes to move the goods quickly.<br><br>Another problem we face is: In some industries, there’s just &#8212; there isn’t enough competition.&nbsp; And I’ve often said that capitalism without competition isn’t capitalism, it’s exploitation.&nbsp; So, we’re promoting competition for everything from Internet services to meat processing.<br><br>We basically have four meat processors in the whole country.&nbsp; They process the meat that goes into the hamburgers you buy, so they set the price.&nbsp; When there’s no competition, they can set the price higher and higher.&nbsp; So, we’re helping smaller companies get into the game to compete and help&nbsp;bring down the overall prices.<br><br>The bottom line is: Easing &#8212; easing these bottlenecks and making our supply chains more secure is a major focus of my economic strategy so things move more quickly, prices go down, not up.<br><br>You know, some parts of my plan I’ve been able to get done on my own &#8212; I mean, just without congressional approval.&nbsp; Some parts are being held up by Congress.&nbsp; But all of my plan is focused on lowering costs for the average family in America to give them just a little bit of breathing room.<br><br>Now, what’s the congressional Republican plan?<br><br>They don’t want to solve inflation by lowering your costs.&nbsp; They want to solve it by raising your taxes and lowering your income.<br><br>I happen to think it’s a good thing when American families have a little more money in their pockets at the end of the month.&nbsp; But Republicans in Congress don’t seem to think so.<br><br>Their plan has actually made working families &#8212; is going to make working families poorer.<br><br>You don’t have to take my word for it; it’s in writing.&nbsp;&nbsp; They’ve made their intentions perfectly clear.<br><br>Senator Rick Scott&nbsp;of&nbsp;<s>Wisconsin</s>&nbsp;[Florida], a member of the Senate Republican leadership, laid it all out in a plan.&nbsp; It’s the Ultra-MAGA Agenda.<br><br>Their plan is to raise taxes on 75 million American families, over 95 percent of whom make less than $100,000 a year, total income.&nbsp; The average tax increase would be about $1,500 per family.</p>



<p>They’ve got it backwards, in my view.&nbsp; I’ve proposed a minimum tax for billionaires.&nbsp; In recent years, the average billionaire has paid about 8 percent in federal taxes.<br><br>Congressional Republicans have proposed increasing taxes on teachers and firefighters.<br><br>Fifty-five&nbsp;<s>percent</s>&nbsp;of the largest corporations paid net zero in federal taxes in 2020 on $40&nbsp;<s>million</s>&nbsp;[billion] profits.<br><br>It just isn’t right.&nbsp; That’s why I’ve proposed a minimum tax for corporations.<br><br>Their plan would also raise taxes on 82 percent of small-business owners making less than $50,000 a year.&nbsp; But it would do nothing to help &#8212; to &#8212; to hold big co- &#8212; big corporations and companies accountable.&nbsp; Think about it.<br><br>Republicans in Congress are so deeply committed to protecting big corporations and CEOs that they would rather see taxes on working American families and try to depress their wages to take on inflation.<br><br>Never mind the fact that many of these companies are recording record profit margins, even as &#8212; as prices &#8212; as they raise prices records amounts.<br><br>Look, you’ve heard me say it before: I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; I’m not out to punish anybody.&nbsp; I have no problem with companies getting and generating reasonable profits.&nbsp; But in this moment of peril, with a war overseas and inflation surging around the world, the last thing we should be thinking about is rewarding companies for exploiting this situation.<br><br>While families struggle to pay their bills, some corporate &#8212; corporate executives are on earnings calls with investors on Wall Street, cheering their record profits and explaining how they’re using this period of inflation to cover the rise in prices far beyond what they need to do to cover their costs.&nbsp; And all this time, they’re not even paying for a fair share of taxes in the first place.<br><br>You want to bring down inflation?&nbsp; Let’s make sure the wealthiest corporations pay their fair share.<br><br>My plan asks those companies to pay their fair share in taxes.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The congressional Republican plan?&nbsp; Let them off scot-free.<br><br>And if&nbsp;<s>you</s>&nbsp;[it] weren’t extreme enough &#8212; the congressional Republican agenda &#8212; they put it in writing &#8212; it also calls on Congress to put special &#8212; excuse me &#8212; put Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid on the chopping block every five years.<br><br>Now, if I hadn’t seen it in writing, I’d think somebody is making this up.</p>



<p>But their proposal is: Every five years, all those programs would cease unless they’re re-voted &#8212; that the Congress comes along and says, “Yeah, we want to keep these plans,” affirmatively voting for them.</p>



<p>Well, imagine what &#8212; the changes that are going to take place then, man.&nbsp; Imagine all the bargaining that’s going to take place.&nbsp; “You Democrats want to maintain Social Security? &nbsp;You got give up such and such.”<br><br>Look, I want to give Medicare the power to negotiate drug prices, to make it stronger and lower your costs.<br><br>Republicans in&nbsp;Conre- [sic]&nbsp;want to make &#8212; in Congress want to put Medicare’s very existence up for a vote over and over again, along with Social Security and Medicaid.<br><br>Really, ask yourself: How well are we going to sleep at night knowing that every five years, MAGA Republicans &#8212; if they’re still the Republican &#8212; as I said, this is not your father’s Republican Party &#8212; if we’re going to have to vote on whether you will have Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid, and what amounts you’ll have in each of those programs?<br><br>You know what they’re likely to do?&nbsp; Use them as hostages every five years to get their way on other things.&nbsp; Think about it: “Give us another tax cut for billionaires, or Social Security gets it.”&nbsp; “Stop investing in clean energy, or you’re going to &#8212; or you’re going to &#8212; we’re going to kiss your Medicare goodbye.”&nbsp; It’s outrageous.&nbsp; It’s outrageous.<br><br>I can’t believe that the majority of Republicans buy on to Scott’s plan.&nbsp; But that’s a plan in writing, and he’s in the leadership.</p>



<p>Finally, let’s do one more comparison.&nbsp; Let’s compare our two&nbsp;plans when it comes to the deficit.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Republicans love to attack me as a big spender, as if that’s the reason why inflation has gone up.&nbsp; Let’s compare the facts.<br><br>Under my predecessor, the deficit exploded, raising &#8212; rising every single year under the Republicans.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Under my plan, we’re on track to cut the federal deficit by $1.5 trillion this year.&nbsp; Let me say it again: $1.5 trillion by the end of this fiscal year.&nbsp; The biggest one-year decline in all of history for America.&nbsp; And that’s in addition to last year we cut the budget $350 billion &#8212; the deficit, not the budget.&nbsp; The deficit: $350 billion.<br><br>My Treasury Department is planning to pay down the national debt this quarter, which never happened under my predecessor.&nbsp; Not once.&nbsp; Not once.<br><br>Because unlike my predecessor, the deficit has gone down both years I’ve been here.&nbsp; That is not an abstraction.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters to families, because reducing the deficit is one of the main ways we can ease inflationary pressures.<br><br>Look, the bottom line is this: Americans have a choice right now between two paths, reflecting two very different sets of values.<br><br>My plan attacks inflation and grows the economy by lowering costs for working families, giving workers well-deserved raises, reducing the deficit by historic levels, and making big corporations and the very wealthiest Americans pay their fair share.<br><br>The other path is the ultra-MAGA plan put forward by congressional Republicans to raise taxes on working families; lower the incomes of American workers; threaten the sacred programs Americans count on like Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid; and give break after break to big corporations and billionaires &#8212; just like they did the last time they held power when their top priority was a reckless $2 trillion tax cut going &#8212; the majority of that going to the very wealthiest Americans, which ballooned the deficit, and not a penny of it was paid for.<br><br>Look, I know you’ve got to be frustrated.&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; I can taste it.&nbsp; Frustrated by high prices, by gridlock in Congress, by the time it takes to get anything done.<br><br>Believe me, I understand the frustration.&nbsp; But the fact is congressional Republicans &#8212; not all of them, but the MAGA Republicans &#8212; are counting on you to be as frustrated by the pace of progress, which they have everything &#8212; they’ve done everything they can to slow down &#8212; that you’re going to &#8212; will hand power over to them and enact &#8212; so they can enact their extreme agenda.<br><br>Look at their agenda.&nbsp; They put up on a webpage somewhere &#8212; I think I can do this &#8212; the “Scott Plan,” and it’s in writing.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We need a government focused on what families actually need.&nbsp; So I urge all Americans to think about the path I’ve laid forward.&nbsp; We’re going to have to do more beyond what I laid forward.&nbsp; But then, think about what the Republicans in Congress are actually proposing.&nbsp; Which path is right for you and your family and, quite frankly, for America?<br><br>Let’s build on the extraordinary process and progress we’ve made instead of tearing it down.&nbsp; Let’s focus on what matters.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>It &#8212; this really matters to average Americans.<br><br>I want to thank you all.&nbsp; God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China tariffs?<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If you’re going to ask me about what I spoke about, I’ll try to &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, I have a question on tariffs.<br><br>Q &nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, why do you believe so many Americans believe that your administration is not doing enough to combat inflation?&nbsp; And do you believe that you and your administration bear some measure of responsibility for the inflation that we’re seeing across the country?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The first is, we’re in power.&nbsp; That’s the first thing.&nbsp; And you &#8212; justifiably right, we control all three branches of government.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Well, we don’t really.&nbsp; We have 50/50 in the Senate.&nbsp; You need 60 votes to get major things done.&nbsp; I’ve been pushing the things I’ve been proposing here, as you’ve heard me speak to today, since I got in office.&nbsp; And I have &#8212; I need to get 60 votes to be able to even pass them.&nbsp; Number one.<br><br>Number two, I think that, you know, it’s &#8212; they’re not focused.&nbsp; They’re &#8212; all they’re focused on, understandably, is the problem they’re facing.&nbsp; They get a 5 and a half percent raise &#8212; an average raise in their salaries, and yet inflation exceeds that.&nbsp; And they look around the world, and they know that a lot of it is extremely complicated.&nbsp; And so, they’re frustrated.&nbsp; And I don’t blame them.&nbsp; I really don’t blame them.<br><br>There’s a lot we have to do.&nbsp; And but &#8212; you know as well &#8212; I shouldn’t say “you.”&nbsp; I think what I have to do is explain in simple, straightforward language what’s going on.<br><br>Like, the reason why 30 percent of the inflation last year is because automobiles cost more.&nbsp; Why did they cost more?&nbsp; They couldn’t get the computer chips to make them.&nbsp; People are making a lot more money.&nbsp; They wanted to buy the automobiles.&nbsp; They couldn’t buy them because the costs went up so high because there were so few of them.&nbsp; The same way this year.&nbsp; The same way this year &#8212; the reason why prices are up.&nbsp;<br><br>They understand, but they don&#8217;t &#8212; they&#8217;re &#8212; look, most people &#8212; the vast majority of Americans are hoping that their government just takes care of the problem and they don&#8217;t have to think about it in detail at the kitchen table or at the dinner table.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s understandable no matter what their background.&nbsp;<br><br>But right now, it&#8217;s confusing.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re scratching their heads like, “What the heck is Russia doing?&nbsp; Should we be helping?”&nbsp; They think we should be helping the innocent Ukrainians.&nbsp; But what impact does that have?&nbsp; Do you think the average person, whether they have a PhD or they are &#8212; have any other job, sits and thinks, “Wow, there&#8217;s thousands of tons of grain in elevators in Ukraine that can&#8217;t get out”?&nbsp; And Ukraine is one of the biggest producers of corn and wheat.&nbsp; “Huh, I wonder whether that&#8217;s the reason my prices are up.”<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you take any responsibility for the inflation in this country?&nbsp; Do you take any responsibility &#8212; your policies?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think our policies help, not hurt.&nbsp; Think about what they say.&nbsp; The vast majority of the &#8212; of the &#8212; of the economists think that this is going to be a real tough problem to solve.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not because of spending. &nbsp;We brought down the deficit.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line is: How much does America owe?&nbsp; How much in the hole are we going?&nbsp; We&#8217;re reducing that.&nbsp; So &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, today you have retail gasoline prices and diesel prices at record highs &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; yet you have yet to ask Americans to consume less.&nbsp; You&#8217;re a train guy.&nbsp; Have you ever thought of your administration asking Americans to drive less, to take public transport?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, if you ever raised a family like mine, you don&#8217;t have to tell them.&nbsp; They&#8217;re doing everything in their power to figure out how not to have to show up at the gas pump.&nbsp;<br><br>The vast &#8212; and that&#8217;s why &#8212; for example, one of the things that’s going to help a lot, which is going to take time, is our infrastructure bill.&nbsp; The truth is they don&#8217;t have that many options, in terms of transportation, around the country right now.&nbsp;<br><br>If you live in the Northeast Corridor you do.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re driving back and forth between Baltimore or Washington, New York, et cetera.&nbsp; But you don&#8217;t have many choices.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t have a whole lot of choices to deal with other aspects of transportation in terms of local transportation.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, what happens is &#8212; and unless they&#8217;re electric, we find theirselves &#8212; the cost of flying &#8212; getting &#8212; buying a ticket on a plane costs more because of gas prices.&nbsp;<br><br>So this is a process, but it&#8217;s a process that I&#8217;ve been consistent about: wanting to lower prices for &#8212; and shift to renewable energy so we&#8217;re not as dependent.&nbsp;<br><br>I have conversations almost every &#8212; well, that’s not &#8212; that’s an exaggeration &#8212; at least twice a week with one of my European counterparts, heads of state, on what &#8212; how can we help them, in fact, wean themselves off of Russian oil, because they&#8217;re so totally dependent.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we&#8217;re liken [sic] like &#8212; we’re working like the devil to help them transition.&nbsp; Because as long as Russia is able to make money selling oil, they&#8217;re going to continue to be able to do the bad things they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;<br><br>So, there&#8217;s a lot.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really complicated.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not suggesting the American people can’t understand it.&nbsp; They understand it, but they have &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re working 8, 10 hours a day just to put food on the table.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I think what&#8217;s happened is we have &#8212; in a sense, I never expected &#8212; let me say &#8212; let me say this carefully: I never expected the Ultra-MAGA Republicans, who seem to control the Republican Party now, to have been able to control the Republican Party.&nbsp; I &#8212; I never anticipated that happening.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, a year ago, the administration was saying that inflation was transitory.&nbsp; That’s obviously not the case now.&nbsp; How long do you think it will be until we see prices coming down?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to predict that.&nbsp; It ranges depending on which economists you&#8217;re talking to. &nbsp;By the end of this year, and some say it’s going to be &#8212; it&#8217;s going to increase next year.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s others who say by the end of this year you&#8217;re going to see it come down &#8212; by the calendar year.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t know, but I know what we have to do to make sure that we can bring it down.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you support any restrictions on abortion?&nbsp; Or what limits do you believe there should be, as the Senate is taking that up?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;I&#8217;m not going to respond to anything because I don&#8217;t want &#8212; I want this story to be about inflation.&nbsp; And I’ll talk about that &#8212;<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You called out Rick Scott &#8212; you called out Rick Scott a little while ago in your remarks.&nbsp; Earlier today, anticipating your remarks, he said &#8212; and I&#8217;m just quoting here &#8212; that the best thing &#8212; “the most effective thing Joe Biden can do to solve the inflation crisis he created is resign.&nbsp; He&#8217;s the problem.”&nbsp;&nbsp; The senator added later &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Resign?&nbsp; That’s a good idea.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The senator added later, “Joe Biden is unwell.&nbsp; He’s unfit for office.&nbsp; He’s incoherent, incapacitated, and confused.”&nbsp; These are his words.&nbsp; I&#8217;m offering you a chance to respond to that.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think the man has a problem.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you drop former President Trump’s China tariffs?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;re discussing that right now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking at what would have the most positive impact.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To lower them or to erase them?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I didn&#8217;t say that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m telling you we&#8217;re discussing it, and no decision has been made on it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it. &nbsp;Thank you.<br><br>12:28 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: S. 1226 and S.&#160;2126</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/05/10/bills-signed-s-1226-and-s-2126/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52867</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, May 10, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 1226, which designates the United States Courthouse located at 1501 North 6th Street in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, as the Sylvia H. Rambo United States Courthouse. Thank you to Senators Casey and Toomey and Representatives Perry, Wild, Fitzpatrick, Cartwright, Keller, and Reschenthaler for their leadership. S.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, May 10, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 1226, which designates the United States Courthouse located at 1501 North 6th Street in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, as the Sylvia H. Rambo United States Courthouse.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Casey and Toomey and Representatives Perry, Wild, Fitzpatrick, Cartwright, Keller, and Reschenthaler for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 2126, which designates the Federal Office Building located at 308 W. 21st Street in Cheyenne, Wyoming, as the Louisa Swain Federal Office Building.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Lummis, Van Hollen, Cardin, and Barrasso for their leadership</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Media Advisory: Second COVID-&#8288;19&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/media-advisory-second-covid-19-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 16:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States as first COVID Summit Chair, Belize, as CARICOM Chair; Germany, holding the G7 Presidency; Indonesia, holding the G20 Presidency; and Senegal as African Union Chair, will co-host the second Global COVID-19 Summit, which will be held virtually on Thursday, May 12, 2022. We will be joined by countries, other partners, non-governmental organizations,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States as first COVID Summit Chair, Belize, as CARICOM Chair; Germany, holding the G7 Presidency; Indonesia, holding the G20 Presidency; and Senegal as African Union Chair, will co-host the second Global COVID-19 Summit, which will be held virtually on Thursday, May 12, 2022.<br><br>We will be joined by countries, other partners, non-governmental organizations, and private sector companies who have made financial or policy commitments. Some of those will include South Africa; Canada; Japan; India; Colombia; Republic of Korea; Italy; New Zealand; European Commission; Spain, Nigeria; Norway; Palau; Tanzania; Rwanda; Wellcome; Google; FIND, the global alliance for diagnostics; Rotary International; the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations; Clinton Health Access Initiative; Open Society Foundations; the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation; Gavi, The Vaccine Alliance; and the Mastercard Foundation. In addition, international and regional organizations will participate, such as the World Health Organization, World Bank Group; the World Trade Organization; the African Centres for Disease Control and Prevention; and the Caribbean Public Health Agency. We will share more about additional participants closer to the Summit. <br><br>Together, the Summit will redouble our efforts made at the first COVID Summit and will focus on four key objectives: </p>



<ul><li><strong>Recommitting Intensity to Global Response.</strong> The pandemic is not over, and now is the time to prepare for the next one.  The Summit will focus on securing new resources and policy commitments to control COVID-19 in 2022. </li><li><strong>Vaccinating the World. </strong>Vaccination remains the most important lifesaving tool in this pandemic. It is also the most effective means to fight emerging variants. This is true for the broad population, and particularly true for the most vulnerable. And it means focusing on both the quantity of vaccinations, but also the quality – including providing effective boosters.</li><li><strong>Protecting the Most Vulnerable.  </strong>The Summit will focus on getting vaccines, tests, and treatments to those at highest risk, like the elderly, the immunocompromised and frontline and health workers.</li><li><strong>Preventing future catastrophes.  </strong>By investing <em>now</em> to secure political commitment for pandemic preparedness globally.  The Summit will focus on expanding and financing country capacity, health workers, disease surveillance, and medical countermeasures, including through the new pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank. </li></ul>



<p>President Biden and fellow heads of state from the co-host nations will kick off the Summit with remarks on how fighting COVID-19 must remain an international priority. The Summit will then feature three sessions focused on getting shots in arms, expanding access to tests and treatments, and advancing health security and preventing future catastrophes.&nbsp;&nbsp;Ahead of the Summit, the U.S. called on the leaders of governments, civil society, businesses, and philanthropies to make significant new commitments.<br>To date, President has committed to sharing 1.2 billion doses of safe, effective vaccines with the world, and the U.S. has made good on that commitment. The U.S. has shipped over 530 million doses of vaccine to 115 countries around the world, over four times more than our next closest donor. And the U.S. has sent them for free with no strings attached.</p>



<p>The Summit builds the U.S.’s steadfast leadership in the global COVID-19 response and our efforts to engage with the world to do their part to end this acute phase of the pandemic and prepare for future threats. It also reflects the Biden-Harris Administration’s work to continue to push the global response forward, including by securing funding from Congress, because the virus is not waiting for Congress to act. It’s critical for Congress to act with the urgency that a once-in-a-generation pandemic warrants.  </p>



<p>The U.S. and the co-host nations look forward to another successful Summit to accelerate the international response to combat COVID-19 and to advance global pandemic preparedness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">You can join us for the Second COVID-19 Summit by tuning in here starting at 9 AM ET: WH.GOV/Live</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Democratic National Committee&#160;Fundraiser</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/10/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-democratic-national-committee-fundraiser-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 14:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Private ResidencePotomac, Maryland&#160;(May 9, 2022) 7:01 P.M. EDT  THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, thank you very much.  (Applause.)  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)  Well, I think now is the time I should probably leave.  (Laughter.)  You’re all very gracious.  Thank you.  Thank you very much. You know, I was &#8212; I came in and I saw two really&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Private Residence<br>Potomac, Maryland<br>&nbsp;<br>(May 9, 2022)</p>



<p>7:01 P.M. EDT <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, thank you very much.  (Applause.)  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.) <br> <br>Well, I think now is the time I should probably leave.  (Laughter.)  You’re all very gracious.  Thank you.  Thank you very much.<br> <br>You know, I was &#8212; I came in and I saw two really important people I shook hands with.  Because everybody knows I like kids better than people.  (Laughter.)  Thank you guys for being here. <br>Mom and Dad owe you a big prize for having to put up with this.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>CHILD:  Yes, sir. <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Folks &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; folks, you know, one of the things that I think is important is that we kind of remember who in God’s name we are. <br> <br>You know, you get to the point &#8212; I’ve been around the Senate for a while &#8212; a year or two &#8212; and the Vice President for a while, and now President of the United States. <br> <br>And, you know, I want to thank Dave and June for hosting this.  You know, he &#8212; his biggest operation, he tells me, is up in Claymont, Delaware, where I went to &#8212; I went to school in Claymont, Delaware.  It’s a &#8212; it’s a &#8212; it used to be a steel town and a working-class town. <br> <br>And I went to &#8212; there was a place called Archmere Academy, and across the street an old John Jakob Raskob estate turned into a school.  And &#8212; the little school called Holy Rosary. <br> <br>And up in Claymont, it’s real simple: They know &#8212; they know that &#8212; when you say something, whether you mean it or not.  And it&#8217;s pretty important that I think the Democrats communicate what we mean, as we&#8217;ve been doing here toni- &#8212; as they&#8217;ve been doing here tonight.<br> <br>You know, the fact is that, you know &#8212; you know, Anthony is going to be a hell of an attorney general.  Where are you, Anthony?  (Applause.) <br> <br>By the way, he won his House in spite of the fact that I campaigned for him.  (Laughter.) <br> <br>And Dutch &#8212; where are you, Dutch?  There you go, Dutch.  I can’t &#8212; good to see you, pal.  (Applause.)  Dutch is my kind of guy. <br> <br>And Ben &#8212; Ben Cardin has been a good friend for a long, long time now.  (Applause.) <br> <br>I &#8212; you know, the fact is that I&#8217;m proud of the progress we&#8217;ve made because of the folks I just named, including my host.<br> <br>You know, we went from having 2 million people with shots when we came into office &#8212; for COVID shots &#8212; to 220 million people being fully vaccinated.  We moved from &#8212; (applause) &#8212; <br> <br>The jobs report: We had 428,000 new jobs this month, and 8.2 million since we came to office, more than &#8212; more than any time &#8212; in 15 months.<br> <br>The deficit is down $350 billion last year.  (Applause.)  Republicans talked about it, but we actually brought the deficit down $350 billion.  And we’re on target to reduce the deficit by the end of this fiscal year by 1 trillion 500 billion dollars.  (Applause.)  And that’s a fact. <br> <br>And we’ve made historic investments in solar and wind and battery storage &#8212; a whole range of things. <br> <br>And we appointed the first African American woman to the Supreme Court.  (Applause.)  But equally important, we’ve appointed more African American Circuit Court judges than any time than all other Presidents combined.  (Applause.) <br> <br>Here’s the point: I made a commitment when I ran.  I said, “I want my administration to look like America.”  And it is.  It’s looking like America, across the board, from every &#8212; you cannot look at any part of our administration &#8212; from the appointees, to those requiring Senate confirmation, to members of my Cabinet &#8212; you can’t look anywhere and not see America.  Because that’s who we are.  That’s our strength.  We talked about that strength.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And, folks, you know, the fact is that we &#8212; we rallied the world as well &#8212; and I wish we hadn’t had to do it &#8212; to keep Putin in place. <br> <br>The fact is, what I&#8217;ve spent most of my time doing &#8212; and I&#8217;ve spent now well over 150 hours trying to keep the other heads of state on the same page and keep us together, constantly making sure we&#8217;re on the same page. <br> <br>Because I&#8217;m confident Putin believed &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I’m confident Putin believed that he could break up NATO.  I&#8217;m confident he believed he could break up the European Union, that we couldn&#8217;t hold it together.  But we&#8217;re doing it.  It&#8217;s not easy, and a lot of other countries have to make greater or lesser sacrifices than we.  But it&#8217;s not easy. <br> <br>But it&#8217;s critically important because Putin is a &#8212; I&#8217;ve known him for a while.  I&#8217;ve spent time with him.  He is a very, very, very calculating man.  And the problem I worry about now is that he doesn&#8217;t have a way out right now, and I&#8217;m trying to figure out what we do about that.  But that&#8217;s a different story. <br> <br>But here&#8217;s the deal: In the meantime, you sometimes &#8212; you know, we &#8212; we generated greater economic growth than any President has in their first 14 months, 15 months, but we also ran into some international crises, and they&#8217;re consequential and they&#8217;re really consequential.<br> <br>Inflation.  You know, we &#8212; the fact is that we stopped investing in ourselves about 20 years ago in any big way.  We used to invest in the United States of America.  We used to invest 2 percent &#8212; our government &#8212; 2 percent of our GDP was in research and development.  It&#8217;s less than 1 percent now.  And it&#8217;s been that way for a long time.<br> <br>We used to be number one in the world; now we&#8217;re number eight.  China used to be number eight; now they&#8217;re number two.<br> <br>The generic point is we have to invest in ourselves, invest in our people, so that we can, in fact, continue to lead the world on all the things that are so &#8212; there are so many incredible opportunities for not only us but for the rest of the world.<br> <br>And so what we&#8217;re doing here is we find ourselves in inflation being a incredibly difficult problem.<br> <br>For example, last year, because we lacked the ability to find the computer chips to build automobiles, we &#8212; we invented the computer chip here in America, we refined it here in America, and we stopped making it here in America, as my colleagues can tell you.  We&#8217;re now changing that.<br> <br>But the point is that the reason 30 percent of all the inflation was because of the cost of automobiles last year.  This year, it&#8217;s &#8212; well, it&#8217;s &#8212; this year, we have a similar problem, but it&#8217;s because of energy because of Putin&#8217;s gas tax, the gas tax of him causing such a disruption in oil markets around the world.<br> <br>And so we got a lot to do.  But here&#8217;s the point: I think that the fact is that I think we can, in fact &#8212; we can, in fact, grab hold of this issue and once again reassert ourselves as the lead country in the world across the board.  And &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I &#8212; it’s not hyperbole. <br> <br>But what I don’t want to do is go too long here.  But, you know, look, if you take a look at, you know, the Supreme Court, when the &#8212; remember, I&#8217;m the guy that led the fight to keep Robert Bork off the Court.  Because Robert Bork refused to acknowledge that there was anything remotely approaching a right to privacy and/or the Ninth Amendment.  I don&#8217;t want to get into a constitutional &#8212; my problem was I taught constitutional law for 18 years. <br> <br>But here&#8217;s the deal: The fact of the matter is it&#8217;s not just about choice that&#8217;s at stake here.  So much more is at stake &#8212; everything from contraception.  There used to be a law on the books in Connecticut &#8212; Griswold vs. Connecticut &#8212; that said a married couple could not &#8212; it was a crime to purchase contraceptives using the privacy of their own bedroom. <br> <br>There are a whole range of other issues that are susceptible if the reasoning of the Court opinion that was leaked ends up being what the Court opinion is.  And it&#8217;s not certain of that yet. <br> <br>There&#8217;s a lot at stake.  A whole lot at stake.<br> <br>And, folks, you know, we&#8217;re also coming &#8212; coming for the &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re coming for the right to vote.  I’ve never seen &#8212; I got involved in politics because my state of Delaware, not unlike Maryland, has the eighth-largest Black population in America as a percent of population.  That&#8217;s what got me involved as a kid in civil rights and as public defender.<br> <br>And the fact is that I&#8217;ve never seen such an onslaught.  I was chairman of the Judiciary Committee for years in the Senate as well as Foreign Relations Committee.  And I was &#8212; thought I really had made it when I was able to extend the Voting Rights Act for 24 years and got Strom Thurmond to vote for it.  Not a joke.  (Applause.)  I thought we &#8212; thought we&#8217;d lose. <br> <br>Look, for some people, it never changes.  They&#8217;ve never, ever given up. <br> <br>And, you know, if you take a look at what&#8217;s at stake &#8212; I&#8217;m going to cut to the chase so I can get some questions here.  But here&#8217;s the deal: If you take a look at where these guys are, this is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.  Did you ever think in the year that we&#8217;re in at this moment, 2022, there&#8217;d be governors and others banning books &#8212; banning books in schools?<br> <br>Did you ever think you&#8217;d be in a situation where we found that &#8212; you were in a position where they talk about how we should make Social Security and Medicare and Medicaid up for grabs every fo- &#8212; five years?  Because that&#8217;s what they&#8217;re doing. This is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.  This is a MAGA party.  This is the MAGA party.<br> <br>And the head of their Republican campaign committee, Senator Rick Scott &#8212; the Ultra-MAGA Agenda he put forward, he raises taxes on 70 million people who make less than &#8212; well less than $100,000.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp;&nbsp;No!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp;No, it’s a fact.&nbsp;&nbsp;Not a joke.&nbsp;&nbsp;And that’s 98 percent of the families earning less than $1,000 [$100,000], because he says everybody should pay taxes.</p>



<p>Secondly, he requires Congress, every five years, to vote to whether or not to keep Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Every &#8212; that&#8217;s their platform.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; We got to start talking more about what these guys are about.&nbsp; That&#8217;s literally their platform.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, folks, we need to control the House and Senate, which I wa- &#8212; listening to others people speak, you know the whole deal there.&nbsp; And we can do it.</p>



<p>Right now, when you have a 50-50 Senate and your president &#8212; and, fortunately, we have a Democratic Vice President.&nbsp; Every time she votes, we win. &nbsp;</p>



<p>But the point is this: You got 51 presidents.&nbsp; Any one member can be &#8212; and 48 percent &#8212; 48 Democrats vote with me on &#8212; literally 95 percent of the time; two change their mind.&nbsp; It just takes one to change their mind and you can&#8217;t get the 50 votes needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so there&#8217;s a lot at stake here &#8212; a whole bunch at stake.&nbsp; And I think there are at least four seats that are up for grabs that we could pick up in the Senate &#8212; two with almost certainty if we do the right thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re going to keep the House.&nbsp; Because if we don&#8217;t, just let me remind you: Just look at &#8212; what I always ask people when the press ask me, I say, “Can you tell me what the Republican Party stands for today?&nbsp; What are they for?”&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Tell me anything they are for, as a party.&nbsp; There&#8217;s good Republicans.<br>&nbsp;<br>I had a reputation, when I was a senator, of being able to walk across the &#8212; work across the aisle as well as anybody.&nbsp; I passed significant amounts of bipartisan legislation in those 36 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But today, if you look at the leaders of the Republican Party, what is their agenda?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a conservative agenda.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not an agenda.&nbsp; They have no agenda; to stop what we&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>And, folks, so there&#8217;s a whole bunch at stake here.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I want to say thank you, thank you, thank you, not only for helping me, but so many of you helped other members of the party who are seeking office and will be seeking office this off year.&nbsp; Because if we win, we have an opportunity to do such great things for this country on the environment, on matters relating to healthcare, on matters relating to mental health, on matters relating to the criminal justice system &#8212; a whole range of things that are within our reach to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have the votes to do it if we pick up these &#8212; at least two seats here.&nbsp; And I think we can do it.</p>



<p>With that, why don&#8217;t I, as my mother &#8212; if she were here, she’d say, “Joey, hush up and take the questions.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you for listening, and I’m prepared to &#8212; (applause) &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Press departs.)</p>



<p>7:15 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Office of the National Cyber Director Announces Senior&#160;Leadership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/office-of-the-national-cyber-director-announces-senior-leadership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Office of the National Cyber Director announced Kemba Walden as the first Principal Deputy National Cyber Director and Neal Higgins and Rob Knake as Deputy National Cyber Directors. These key personnel will join Deputy National Cyber Director for Federal Cybersecurity and Federal Chief Information Security Officer Chris DeRusha in fulfilling ONCD’s mission to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Office of the National Cyber Director announced Kemba Walden as the first Principal Deputy National Cyber Director and Neal Higgins and Rob Knake as Deputy National Cyber Directors. These key personnel will join Deputy National Cyber Director for Federal Cybersecurity and Federal Chief Information Security Officer Chris DeRusha in fulfilling ONCD’s mission to ensure every American can share in the full benefits of our digital ecosystem.</p>



<p>“As we continue to build this new office, the additions of Kemba, Neal, and Rob will accelerate our efforts to protect Americans in cyberspace,” said <strong>National Cyber Director Chris Inglis</strong>. “Each of these leaders brings impressive experience in cybersecurity policy making to our team, and their diverse perspectives will be invaluable as we strengthen our collective defense.”</p>



<p>More on these additions:</p>



<p><strong>Principal Deputy National Cyber Director Kemba Eneas Walden</strong> is an attorney with extensive experience in government and the private sector. She comes to ONCD from Microsoft, where she served as an Assistant General Counsel in Microsoft’s Digital Crimes Unit (DCU) responsible for launching and leading DCU’s Ransomware Program. Prior to joining Microsoft, Kemba spent a decade in government service at the Department of Homeland Security, most recently at the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency. She was appointed to the Cyber Safety Review Board and holds a J.D. from the Georgetown University Law Center, Master’s in Public Affairs from Princeton University, and B.A. from Hampton University.</p>



<p><strong>Deputy National Cyber Director for National Cybersecurity Neal Higgins </strong>comes to ONCD from CIA, where he served as Associate Deputy Director for Digital Innovation, responsible for CIA’s cyber operations, open source collection, data science, and secure global communications.&nbsp;Neal also served as CIA’s Director of Congressional Affairs and as deputy chief of the WikiLeaks Task Force.&nbsp;Before joining CIA, Neal served in several senior staff roles in the United States Senate and worked as an editor at <em>Foreign Affairs</em> and as a member of the trial team prosecuting Slobodan Milosevic. Neal is a graduate of Princeton University, Harvard Law School, and the Fletcher School of Law &amp; Diplomacy.</p>



<p><strong>Deputy National Cyber Director for Strategy and Budget Rob Knake</strong> is a cybersecurity policy expert with decades of experience in the field. Prior to joining ONCD, he was a senior fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations, a fellow at the Harvard Belfer Center’s Cyber Project, and an adviser to cybersecurity startups and Fortune 500 companies. During the Obama Administration, he served in the cyber directorate at the National Security Council and at the Department of Homeland Security’s National Protection &amp; Programs Directorate, the predecessor organization to CISA. He is a graduate of Harvard’s Kennedy School of Government and the co-author of two books on cybersecurity.</p>



<p>Higgins and Knake have already assumed their roles at ONCD while Walden will be joining the office in the coming weeks.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden to Host His Majesty King Abdullah II of&#160;Jordan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/president-biden-to-host-his-majesty-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is pleased to welcome His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan and his Royal Highness Crown Prince Hussein to the White House on May 13, 2022. King Abdullah’s visit to Washington, his second of the Biden Administration, will reinforce the close friendship and enduring partnership between the United States and Jordan. Jordan is a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is pleased to welcome His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan and his Royal Highness Crown Prince Hussein to the White House on May 13, 2022. King Abdullah’s visit to Washington, his second of the Biden Administration, will reinforce the close friendship and enduring partnership between the United States and Jordan. Jordan is a critical force for stability in the Middle East and strategic partner and ally of the United States.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Biden-&#8288;Harris Inflation Plan: Lowering Costs and Lowering the&#160;Deficit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/the-biden-harris-inflation-plan-lowering-costs-and-lowering-the-deficit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is in a stronger economic position than any other major advanced economy in the world. At the same time, inflation is too high and is putting a strain on working families. The President’s top economic priority is tackling inflation and reducing costs for American families – so we can sustain this historic economic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States is in a stronger economic position than any other major advanced economy in the world. At the same time, inflation is too high and is putting a strain on working families. The President’s top economic priority is tackling inflation and reducing costs for American families – so we can sustain this historic economic recovery in a way that benefits all Americans.</p>



<p>President Biden has a plan to tackle inflation – by lowering costs that families face and lowering the federal deficit by asking the large corporations and the wealthiest Americans to pay their fair share. Congressional Republicans, led by Senator Rick Scott, have called for a new minimum tax on the middle class – firefighters and teachers – that would mean an average of almost $1,500 less in families’ pockets each year. And, while part of President Biden’s plan to lower costs is to strengthen Medicare by giving it the power to negotiate prescription drug prices, the Congressional Republican plan would put Medicare – in addition to Social Security, Medicaid, the Affordable Care Act and other critical programs for American families – on the chopping block every five years.</p>



<p>The President understands that the Federal Reserve is the institution that plays a primary role in fighting inflation. The President has nominated highly qualified individuals to lead the Fed, and is urging the Senate to confirm all these individuals without delay. Beyond the Federal Reserve, President Biden is taking short-, medium-, and long-term actions to lower costs for families and lower the deficit:</p>



<p><em><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline"><u>Lowering the Cost of Gas and Energy and Achieving Energy Independence</u>:</span></strong></em> Congressional Republicans have put forward no real plan to lower energy costs. While they point fingers, the President is taking action:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Blunting the Impact of Putin’s Price Hike:</u></strong>&nbsp;Addressing Putin’s price hike at the pump by releasing 1 million barrels of oil per day from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve for the next 6 months; rallying our allies to release an additional 60 million barrels of oil from other countries’ reserves; allowing E15 gasoline (which uses homegrown biofuels) to be sold this summer; and calling on Congress to make companies pay fees on idled wells and non-producing acres on Federal lands – so that companies that continue to sit on excess capacity will have to choose whether to start producing or pay a fee.</li><li><strong><u>Lowering Energy Bills:</u></strong>&nbsp;Calling on Congress to pass clean energy and vehicle tax credits and investments that will reduce our dependence on reckless autocrats like Putin, save families an estimated $500 per year on their utility bills, and accelerate homegrown clean energy innovation – from producing more clean energy to bolstering our domestic supply chains that are critical for clean energy and clean transportation.</li><li><strong><u>Building Real Energy Independence:</u></strong>&nbsp;Advancing the strongest ever fuel economy standards for cars and trucks to enable drivers to go farther on every gallon, while increasing options for families to make the switch to electric cars via historic investment in charging infrastructure and collaboration with autoworkers and automakers to set America on course to ensure one of every two cars sold in 2030 burns no fossil fuels.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Lowering Other Everyday Costs for American Families:</u></em></strong>&nbsp;The Congressional Republican plan would increase 75 million middle-class families’ taxes by an average of nearly $1,500 this year alone, and raise taxes on nearly half of small business owners, including 82 percent of those making less than $50,000 per year. President Biden believes that instead of taking money out of middle-class families’ pockets, we should lower their costs, including in the following areas:</p>



<ul><li><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Lowering Prescription Drug and Health Care Costs:</span> </strong>Saving hundreds of thousands of families hundreds of dollars per month by fixing the Affordable Care Act’s “family glitch,” which has made it impossible for many families to use the premium tax credit to purchase an affordable, high quality Marketplace plan; and calling on Congress to lower prescription drug costs and health care premiums, including allowing Medicare to negotiate drug prices, capping insulin costs, penalizing drug companies that raise prices faster than inflation, and making other needed reforms to lower prices.</li><li><strong><u>Lowering Food Prices by Helping American Farmers Grow More, and Compete More Effectively</u></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">:</span> Calling for resources to help American farmers boost domestic food production in order to avert a potential global food crisis created by Russia’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine; taking actions to crack down on illegal price fixing and enforce the antitrust laws in the meat and poultry processing sector; investing federal resources to create more competition in meat-processing; and providing over one billion dollars in relief to small businesses and agricultural workers hurt by COVID-19.</li><li><strong><u>Lowering the Cost of Everyday Goods By Repairing Our Infrastructure, Supply Chains, and Manufacturing:</u></strong> Bringing together business, labor, federal and state governments to address supply chain bottlenecks at ports; helping more workers find good-paying jobs in the trucking industry; taking on unfair practices by global shipping companies; implementing the historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which will mean goods move to market more quickly and cheaper; and fostering new investments in the United States for critical goods that drove up inflation during the pandemic, including by calling on Congress to pass the Bipartisan Innovation Act. </li><li><strong><u>Lowering the Cost of Child Care and Long-Term Care</u></strong><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>:</strong></span> Calling on Congress to invest in lowering the cost of child care and long-term care, saving families thousands of dollars per year. Child care is one of the biggest costs that families with young children face, and care investments will lower prices across the economy over time by making it easier for parents and others with care responsibilities to join the workforce and be more productive.</li><li><strong><u>Lowering Housing Costs by Building More Homes</u><span style="text-decoration: underline">:</span> </strong>Calling on Congress to invest in building more than 1 million affordable homes, including through a set of tax credits that have received bipartisan support; expanding and improving federal financing for the construction of new housing; and using existing federal funding to reward communities that eliminate needless barriers that prevent new housing from being built.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Reducing the Deficit by Asking Large Corporations and the Wealthiest Americans to Pay Their Fair Share:</u></em></strong> While the federal budget deficit increased every year under President Trump – in part due to a reckless and unpaid for $2 trillion tax cut benefitting the wealthiest Americans and largest corporations –the deficit fell by $350 billion in President Biden’s first year in office because he prioritized rebuilding the economy from the bottom up and the middle out. And the deficit is now on track to fall by another $1.5 trillion this year. This matters to families because one of the main ways Congress and the executive branch can act to lower price pressures is to reduce the federal budget deficit. President Biden’s plan will make the wealthiest Americans and largest corporations pay their fair share, including through a new Billionaires’ Minimum Income Tax. By enacting reforms to make corporations and the wealthiest Americans pay their fair share, Congress can lower the deficit even more, while also lowering costs for families.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Bulgarian Prime Minister Kiril&#160;Petkov</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-bulgarian-prime-minister-kiril-petkov/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52839</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Prime Minister Kiril Petkov of Bulgaria. They exchanged views on Russia’s unprovoked military aggression against Ukraine, reaffirming their readiness to continue supporting the people and government of Ukraine and imposing costs on Russia. Mr. Sullivan underscored U.S. solidarity with Bulgaria in the face of Russia’s latest attempt&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Prime Minister Kiril Petkov of Bulgaria. They exchanged views on Russia’s unprovoked military aggression against Ukraine, reaffirming their readiness to continue supporting the people and government of Ukraine and imposing costs on Russia. Mr. Sullivan underscored U.S. solidarity with Bulgaria in the face of Russia’s latest attempt to use energy as a weapon, and discussed with the Prime Minister ongoing efforts to strengthen European resilience by further diversifying European energy supplies. Mr. Sullivan expressed support for the Bulgarian government’s focus on rule of law and anti-corruption reforms. They also discussed the importance of promoting stability and prosperity in the Western Balkans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: S.&#160;3522</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/05/09/bill-signed-s-3522/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 23:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52833</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On&#160;Monday,&#160;May&#160;9, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 3522, the &#8220;Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease&#160;Act of 2022,&#8221; which&#160;provides&#160;a different authority to lend or lease defense articles to Ukraine&#160;or to Eastern European countries. Yea Thank you to Senate leadership; Senators Cornyn, Cardin, Wicker, and Shaheen; House leadership; Chairman Meeks; Ranking Member McCaul; and Representatives Joe Wilson, Cohen, Cheney, Malinowski, Waltz, and Slotkin&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On&nbsp;Monday,&nbsp;May&nbsp;9, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 3522, the &#8220;Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease&nbsp;Act of 2022,&#8221; which&nbsp;provides&nbsp;a different authority to lend or lease defense articles to Ukraine&nbsp;or to Eastern European countries.</p>



<p>Yea Thank you to Senate leadership; Senators Cornyn, Cardin, Wicker, and Shaheen; House leadership; Chairman Meeks; Ranking Member McCaul; and Representatives Joe Wilson, Cohen, Cheney, Malinowski, Waltz, and Slotkin for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
