<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:05:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, April 21,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/21/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-april-21-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Portland, Oregon 1:32 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Good afternoon, and thanks for joining us on President Biden’s first trip to Oregon and Washington.&#160; I know you all got a background memo last night, but just a few points about this trip I wanted to highlight. The focus of the President’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Portland, Oregon</p>



<p>1:32 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good afternoon, and thanks for joining us on President Biden’s first trip to Oregon and Washington.&nbsp; I know you all got a background memo last night, but just a few points about this trip I wanted to highlight.</p>



<p>The focus of the President’s trip is fourfold.&nbsp; One, to underscore the historic economic growth and nearly 8 million jobs created as a result of his and congressional Democrats’ actions, including the American Rescue Plan and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and his administration’s work to lower costs for American families.</p>



<p>Number two, to emphasize the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s historic $25 billion investments in airports, such as Portland International Airport, which is upgrading its south runway so that the runway can survive an earth- &#8212; an &#8212; sorry &#8212; survive an earthquake.&nbsp; In 2022 alone, PDX will receive $20 million in funding from this program.</p>



<p>Number three, to mark Earth Day by speaking to the need to bolster our nation’s resilience in the face of threats like wildfire, and the need to rapidly deploy clean energy.&nbsp; We will have more details on Earth Day announcements later this evening for you all.</p>



<p>And finally, President Biden will call on Congress to pass his plan to lower healthcare and energy costs.&nbsp; He has already taken important steps to lower costs &#8212; from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve release and the extension of E15 gasoline to lower gas prices, to fixing the “family glitch” and enacting the Rescue Plan to save families that buy ACA coverage an average of $59 per person per month.</p>



<p><a>But he has also laid out an ambitious plan to continue to build on that work and lower the cost of healthcare, including prescription drugs.&nbsp; And Congress should act on that to ensure lower premiums; close Medi- &#8212; Medicaid coverage <s>cap</s> [gaps]; cap cost-sharing for Insulin; and let Medicare negotiate the price of prescription drugs.</a></p>



<p>In Portland today, the President will be joined by Governor Kate Brown; Senators Ron Wyden, Jeff Merkley; Representative Earl Blumenauer, Suzanne Bonamici, Peter DeFazio, and Kurt Schrader; and Portland Mayor Ted Wheeler.</p>



<p>And in Seattle tomorrow, he will be joined by Governor Jay Inslee, Senators Pat Murray and Maria Cantwell, Congresswoman Kim Schrier, and other state and local elected officials.</p>



<p>Today, as we get closer to the hot summer months, HHS is announcing more than $385 million to all 50 states, territories, and Tribes to help families lower their home energy costs through the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program &#8212; LIHEAP.</p>



<p>Together with the billions provided in the American Rescue Plan, this brings the total funding for LIHEAP this year to over $8.3 billion &#8212; the most relief ever in the history of the program to lower out-of- &#8212; to lower out-of-pocket heating and cooling costs for hard-pressed American families.</p>



<p>As you all know, we’re headed to the Pacific Northwest, which experienced record heat last year.&nbsp; Extreme heat kills more Americans than any other weather-related event.&nbsp; Over the last 20 years, the frequency of extreme weather events, including extreme heat, has increased dramatically.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement builds on previous LIHEAP funding allocated through the American Rescue Plan, which more than doubled typical annual appropriations.&nbsp; Oregon will receive a record total of $92.6 million in LIHEAP funding, and Washington will receive a record total of $151 million.</p>



<p>This month, President Biden has taken a number of actions to lower prices, including using executive action to fix the “family glitch” in the ACA.&nbsp; And he has taken action on student debt by freezing payments through August, providing immediate student debt cancellation for at least 40,000 borrows &#8212; borrowers, and helping another 3.6 million borrowers move closer to debt relief forgiveness.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; That was a lot.&nbsp; Thanks &#8212; thanks for listening through that, everybody.</p>



<p>All right, Josh.&nbsp; What you got for me? &nbsp;Why don’t you kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two subjects.&nbsp; First, Ukraine: The President talked about military aid today, but Ukraine says it needs $5 billion a month to support its government.&nbsp; Is the U.S. and its allies going to get Ukraine that money?&nbsp; And what would that look like?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, this $500 million combined &#8212; the $500 million today that was announced, combined with the $500 million that President Biden announced in March, is targeted to meet Ukraine’s most acute needs.</p>



<p>We will also continue to work with Congress to find ways to get more resources to Ukraine and bolster their ability to fight the war and restore its economy.</p>



<p>The United States is also committed to working with other bilateral and multilateral donors.&nbsp; For example, the international community has provided and pledged considerable support exceeding $24 billion for 2022 and beyond.&nbsp; And this comes on the top of the economic support provided since 2014 until 2021, which exceeds $60 billion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, with regard to Florida, did Governor DeSantis overstep by penalizing Disney on “Don’t Say Gay”?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, our view is this &#8212; is that the “Don’t Say Gay” bill is really crystal clear: It’s wrong.&nbsp; That’s our view: It is just wrong.</p>



<p>We oppose the governor taking action against a company because of their opposition to that bill.&nbsp; And we’re just going to leave it there for now; we’re not going to say anymore to that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a follow-up &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Excuse me, Josh.&nbsp; A follow-up &#8212; are you sure?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, please.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You guys are so nice to each other today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up on Ukraine.&nbsp; The President said, in his remarks this morning, that he would be asking Congress for more money.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of what dollar figure the administration will be asking for?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Anything in particular you’re talking about?&nbsp; Just &#8212; is it the security or the economic assistance?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All of the above.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All of the above.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, you know, as the President just said today, as you mentioned: With this latest disbursement, we will have almost exhausted &#8212; as we were talking about the security assistance &#8212; almost exhausted the drawdown authority that Congress authorized for Ukraine in the bipartisan spending bill last month.</p>



<p>We are committed to continuing to provide Ukraine with weapons and equipment that they are using so effectively to defend their country.&nbsp; And the administration will be in touch with Congress, as the mention- &#8212; as the President mentioned in his speech, next week on additional resource requirements to keep weapons and ammunition flowing without interruption to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we appreciate the bipartisan support that we have seen in Congress, we &#8212; so we have received so far, efforts to support Ukraine, and hope &#8212; and hope that continues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;ll be putting in a formal ask next week, but can you give us a sense of what that dollar figure will be?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a dollar figure for you.&nbsp; I think the President was asked this question earlier, and he said that the Department of Defense is working on that right now.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have a dollar figure to share with you right &#8212; at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other issue.&nbsp; Elon Musk has gotten enough &#8212; has gotten funding for his attempt to buy Twitter.&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s view right now on Musk and potential ownership of that company by one person?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not &#8212; that&#8217;s something I&#8217;m &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to comment on.&nbsp; The SEC is independent and would handle any review process moving forward, but we&#8217;re not going to comment.&nbsp; That is a private investor, and so we&#8217;re not going to comment on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do want to add one more thing because the funding information that I gave you, Jeff, was for the security component, but I just want to also give you the economic &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s the Treasury side of that as well.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; the economic assistance to that too so we just get that on the record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as &#8212; what remains there &#8212; there are some funds remaining, as it relates to the economic assistance.&nbsp; And the administration is working to get those out of the door quickly.</p>



<p>The administration will also be in touch with Congress next week, as I just mentioned, on additional resource requirements to continue delivering economic assistance to the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>Just wanted to make sure that was clear.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Congress coming back next week &#8212; obviously, a priority for the administration is pushing for a new COVID funding bill.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of what you&#8217;re doing on that?&nbsp; Is the ask still $10 billion?&nbsp; And is the administration open to joining that with the supplemental ask on Ukraine?&nbsp; Could it be the same funding bill?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, as we have said time and time again &#8212; is, like, we can&#8217;t move forward with securing vaccine as we look at the fourth dose for all Americans.&nbsp; You know, at this time last year, we were in the process of contracting for a booster campaign in the fall.&nbsp; Now we can&#8217;t and &#8212; and risk not having adequate doses if needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If experts decide we need different vaccines, including a variant-specific vaccine, we don&#8217;t have the funding to secure them, so our testing capacity won&#8217;t be able to support surge demand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Americans could, once again, face empty shelves, as we saw not too long ago.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t buy any more treatments, including preventative treatments for the immune compromised.&nbsp; These treatments take six months to manufacture, so we &#8212; so we&#8217;re &#8212; we risk losing out on supply that we intended to purchase.</p>



<p>So, we can&#8217;t do more to invest in the next-generation vaccines and treatments that will help us be prepared for future variants and provide more durable protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we just want to be very clear: If we don&#8217;t purchase these vaccines and therapies for the American people, other countries will step in to purchase them for their citizens.&nbsp; They already are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without new support, we will quickly &#8212; and we will quickly find ourselves at the back of the line for future vaccines, treatments, and tests.</p>



<p>So, this is something that we&#8217;re going to continue to work with Congress on and push for that additional funding.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a view on whether it can be rolled into the supplemental as well?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that one more time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could it be packaged in the same bill with Ukraine aid?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have more &#8212; I don’t have more to add.&nbsp; I &#8212; clearly, as I’ve &#8212; we’ve said, that we need more for &#8212; for the economic assistance and security assistance, as I just laid out. I don&#8217;t have anything more on how we&#8217;re going to be packaging any of that.&nbsp; What &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And part of the need is the fact that you owe $5 billion to Pfizer right now for the &#8212; to complete your purchase of Paxlovid.&nbsp; That would chew up half the $10 billion.&nbsp; Is $10 billion still the ask, or is twenty-two and a half still the ask?&nbsp; This &#8212; the USAID money &#8212; how much money are you seeking on COVID?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, are you asking about &#8212; asked me about Plaxlo- &#8212; Paxlovid as &#8212; as it related to the funding?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you &#8212; yeah, there are 20 million courses of Paxlovid ordered right now.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve only paid for about 11 million out of that.&nbsp; Is that order at risk of going under, if we want to talk about that?&nbsp; But more broadly &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yup.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what is the total dollar ask?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So it continues to be what we have discussed, which is $22.5 billion.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp; But on Paxlovid, I&#8217;ll give you an update.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s plenty of supply of Paxlovid available.&nbsp; We get more delivered each week, which we are quickly pushing out to places like pharmacies, hospitals and urgent care centers, nursing homes, and community health centers.&nbsp; There are more than 17,000 locations across the country where people can get prescription filled.&nbsp; It’s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not yet ubiquitous like vaccines are, but we&#8217;re getting there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re working to make sure doctors and patients know about Paxlovid.&nbsp; After it was authorized, it was in limited supply.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not &#8212; that&#8217;s not the case anymore.&nbsp; It&#8217;s widely available, and the eligibility criteria are pretty expansive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re working to make sure providers and patients know that.&nbsp; And we’re working to make it easier to access.&nbsp; One way is through our new test-to-treat program.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just about a month since the President announced this program, so we already got 2,000 locations up and running.&nbsp; We&#8217;re &#8212; continue to expand it and working our partners to improve patients&#8217; experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need funding to sustain this process to &#8212; this progress and are actively working beyond these actions to increase uptake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President finally was asked about Title 42 today, but he responded by talking about the mask thing.&nbsp; Can I ask the the Title 42 question again?&nbsp; Is the administration open to delaying that in order to get a COVID funding deal?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just clear &#8212; let me just kind of reiterate what the President said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We sent out &#8212; we sent out a pool note to all of you from him, which is &#8212; he &#8212; it says: “I want to clarify that in comments at the conclusion of my remarks this morning, I was referring to the CDC’s mask mandate and there is no Department of Justice action on Title 42.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just &#8212; also wanted to just reiterate what Jen Psaki said yesterday: The CDC made a determination that it can be lifted on May 23rd.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working hard to implement a plan to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She also &#8212; she also noted that, “As we prepare for the implementation of the end of Title 42, there are a range of steps that we&#8217;ve been taking to prepare for that, including surging resources, that includes moving officer, agents, DHS Volunteer Force personnel to rapidly decompress points along the border and more effectively process migrants.</p>



<p>It also entails the deployment of COVID-19 mitigation efforts, including the use of &#8212; continued use of PPE, providing the COVID-19 vaccines.&nbsp; It also includes expanding these efforts to cover migrants in CBP custody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the point is there are a range of steps in this comprehensive plan that we have to be ready to go by May 23rd.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that a “no” you won’t consider extending Title 42 if that’s what it takes to get COVID money?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I mean, extending Title 42 is not our decision.&nbsp; As Jen said yesterday, as we’ve been saying, that is Congress’s decision to make.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a follow-up on Title &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No &#8212; I just wanted to ask about the President’s approach to masking.&nbsp; Does he still believe it should be a per- &#8212; an individual choice, even though the Department of Justice is appealing the federal judge’s ruling?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, a couple of things.&nbsp; I just want to lay this out, because I think it’s very important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, first, you know, we’ve made a lot of progress on COVID.&nbsp; Thanks to vaccines, boosters, and treatments, severe cases of COVID and deaths are down 90 percent since the President entered office.&nbsp; Our economy is growing.&nbsp; Schools are open.&nbsp; People are getting back to work.&nbsp; We can feel much better about how things are today.&nbsp; But we know that this virus is tricky.&nbsp; It’s a tricky virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There can be new variants, as we have seen. &nbsp;We have to be ready.&nbsp; So, we all know that airplane and train travel are different than most places.&nbsp; You are stuck next to someone for a long time, as we are currently right now.&nbsp; But we have our masks on.&nbsp; And if that person is sick &#8212; if you are sick, you can spread the virus.&nbsp; And young kids can’t get vaccinated &#8212; kids five &#8212; under five years old, as we all know.&nbsp; People with weak immune systems aren’t protected and they need to travel safely.</p>



<p>I know that masks are uncomfortable.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp; But masking on planes and trains is a way to protect yourself and others.&nbsp; So, as the CDC recommends, the President thinks you should mask right now, especially as they learn more about BA.2.</p>



<p>The CDC should have the time and authority to make these decisions to protect the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re in a much better place now with &#8212; on COVID as I just listed out.&nbsp; But if things get worse or in the event of another public health crisis, CDC must have the essential public health authority, now and in the future, and the principle that public health decisions should be made by public health authorities.&nbsp; That is what is at stake right now, and that’s what the President stands on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the U.S. military is sending specialized weapons that suit Ukraine&#8217;s military needs.&nbsp; We are asking for hundreds of millions of dollars in military aid to send to the Ukrainians.&nbsp; The President is using active language to describe our involvement in this war.&nbsp; “…<s>walk</s> [speak] softly and carry a <s>big</s> [large] Javelin,” he said this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Is this a sign that Americans are going to continue to hear from him, even on a week-by-week basis as &#8212; does this mean we&#8217;re just going to continue to escalate our involvement in this war?&nbsp; And is this something Americans should just expect, even on a weekly basis?&nbsp; Where is this going?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just say a couple of things there.&nbsp; You know, the latest &#8212; the latest steps today that the President announced and talked about in his speech was to support the people of Ukraine, which is important as they&#8217;re protecting their democracy; to hold Putin accountable for the brutal and bloody war.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just very much reiterate &#8212; reiterating what the President said today.</p>



<p>You know, Russia has launched a refocus campaign, as we have been talking about, to seize new territory in eastern Ukraine.&nbsp; And we are in a critical window that &#8212; that will set the stage for the next phase of this war, as you have heard us talk about.&nbsp; So, you know, the U.S. and our Allies and our partners are moving as fast as possible to make sure that the Ukrainian forces have the weapons and equipment to defend their nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that is what we&#8217;re supporting &#8212; not just us alone, but in a &#8212; with our &#8212; again, our partners and Allies as we see a strong Western force here.&nbsp; And so this is why Ukraine has been able to stop &#8212; to stop Russia from taking over their country.&nbsp; This is what we have seen because we have come together &#8212; together to make sure to give them what they need.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re not sitting on the funding that Congress is providing for us to &#8212; is providing for us to give to Ukraine.&nbsp; And so, this is &#8212; this is what we&#8217;re &#8212; this is the announcement that he made today.</p>



<p>And he was asked &#8212; the President was asked how much longer can we do this for.&nbsp; And he said, you know, we can sustain this; we can continue to do this.&nbsp; He said the most important thing is to make sure that we are continuing to be aligned with our partners and Allies.&nbsp; And so that is going to be the focus, and we&#8217;re going to continue to help the Ukrainian people &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Jake &#8212; sorry to cut you off, but Jake came out a couple of weeks ago in the briefing room, after the reports in Bucha, and talked about the evidence gathering that would be required to declare Putin a war criminal in Russia, culpable of war crimes.&nbsp; Reports of widespread rapes and sexual violence have been cropping up of &#8212; about what&#8217;s going on across Ukraine.&nbsp; Where is the evidence gathering &#8212; what&#8217;s the status of that, and what&#8217;s going on?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have that &#8212; I don’t have anything to provide to you right now.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that the State Department clearly has the authority and is handling that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, as you&#8217;ve heard, the President has been very clear in calling it a war crime, and that is something that he believes.&nbsp; But I &#8212; we&#8217;re going to leave that to the State Department to go through the legal process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, two questions for you.&nbsp; One, the President is going to Seattle later today and then to talk tomorrow about climate and his agenda.&nbsp; What is the President &#8212; or what should Americans &#8212; Democrats, voters &#8212; expect to hear from the President?&nbsp; He came into office with this expansive proposal to fight and combat climate change.&nbsp; That seems to have stalled in Congress.&nbsp; This is a big priority for many Democrats, as you outlined in some of the announcements you&#8217;re going to make.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But on the whole, the President&#8217;s climate agenda has really stalled in Congress and in the courts, and so I’m wondering what voters &#8212; Democrats, Americans &#8212; should expect to hear from the President, given that the promises and the ambition that he showed running for President and then in the early months of his administration have largely not come to fruition?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just to &#8212; tomorrow is Earth Day, so we’ll have &#8212; we’ll provide more information on what tomorrow will look like and what the President will have to say.</p>



<p><a>But, look, the President is committed to doing everything he can to address &#8212; you know, to reach his climate goals.&nbsp; And so he is committed and will continue to be committed.</a></p>



<p>You know, he has mobilized a whole-of-government effort in every sector of the economy &#8212; sorry, Jeff &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s fine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; taking executive actions that will reduce greenhouse gas emissions, accelerate clean energy production and deployment, and create good-paying jobs that strengthen the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, tomorrow &#8212; I mean, today, in just &#8212; in a little bit, he&#8217;ll talk about the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which is a big part of &#8212; which is a big part of his &#8212; you know, reaching his climate goals.</p>



<p>But the administration approved the first largescale projects identifying new and energy areas in the Atlantic and the Pacific, and holding a record-breaking $4.3 billion lease sale in a New York Bight, putting his major new industry on track to achieve the President&#8217;s bold goal of deploying 30 gigawatts of offshore and wind by 2030, all while creating good-paying union jobs up and down the supply chain.</p>



<p>We fast-tracked clean energy projects to bring jobs and savings to communities by providing record levels of solar and other renewable &#8212; renewables on public lands, helping local governments advance community solar projects and rooftop installations, and launching a new initiative to deploy distributed energy resources in disadvantaged communities.</p>



<p>President Biden rallied automakers and autoworkers around an electric transportation future, setting a national target of 50 percent electric vehicle sales share in 2030 and spurring investments in new American factories to manufacture EVs and batteries and chargers.</p>



<p>Last year, the administration also launched an EV Charging Action Plan to deploy $7.5 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, as I just mentioned, to build out a national charge network that is &#8212; that is convenient, reliable, and equitable through a new joint office of energy and transportation.&nbsp; And we finalized the strongest passenger vehicle standards in American history to increase average fuel economy to 49 &#8212; 49 miles per gallon; reduce to &#8212; reduce greenhouse gas emissions; and protect communities from pollu- &#8212; pollution; and save drivers money at the pump.</p>



<p><a>So, it’s &#8212; we &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re cont- &#8212; the President has climate goals, and he wants to continue to fight for climate control, and he&#8217;s going to continue to do that.&nbsp; </a>And he has used the power of his office to do that.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not going to stop at just &#8212; what I just laid out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I hear that.&nbsp; But at the same time, the administration has issued a waiver on E15, which environmentalists are &#8212; and climate groups are concerned will hamper those goals.&nbsp; The administration has opened up more leases for drilling in oil.&nbsp; And today, John Kerry told my colleagues that he doesn&#8217;t see proof that nations are following through on their commitments to slow Earth’s warming.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So are there concerns or concessions from the White House that it has not done enough to meet the ambitious climate goals that the President has set out?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is not what we believe.&nbsp; We are going to continue to meet our climate goals.&nbsp; I mean, look, you talked about E15.&nbsp; The President is committed to doing everything that he can to address the pain Americans are feeling at the pump.&nbsp; You know, that was one of the reasons he made that announcement.</p>



<p>You know, but our &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, just to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that in &#8212; is trying to ensure that people don&#8217;t feel pain at the pump, is that in conflict with the President&#8217;s climate goals?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, we don’t &#8212; look, our strategy from day one has been to meet folks where they are.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about delivering solutions that help people take on the real challenges of real life.&nbsp; Addressing the emergency supply crunch while accelerating clean energy efforts is fully consistent with the theory of the case and what we&#8217;re trying to do.</p>



<p>We believe we can walk and chew gum, because families need to take their kids to school and go to work, get groceries, and go about their lives.&nbsp; And sometimes that requires gas today, this month, and this year.&nbsp; But at the very same time, we must speed up, not slow down, our transition to clean energy.&nbsp; So we are &#8212; we believe we&#8217;re going to reach our goals, and we are very committed to doing that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on masks, does the Biden administration plan to ask for an emergency stay to immediately reimpose the mask mandate on public transit?&nbsp; Is that something you all are considering at this point?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, (inaudible), I don&#8217;t have “JD” at the last &#8212; at the end my name.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not a legal strategist.&nbsp; I refer you to the DOJ; that is in their purview.</p>



<p>What I&#8217;ll say is that the CDC believes masking is needed right now.&nbsp; And DOJ is appealing accordingly.&nbsp; DOJ has a duty to preserve CDC’s authority in the event of the current and future public health crisis.&nbsp; And this is a route that ensures we do both.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on Title 42, just to loop back to that, what is the &#8212; how is the administration going to help the smaller border towns who say they expect a large influx of immigrants crossing over the border if Title 42 is ended?&nbsp; What are they doing to help?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that more agents?&nbsp; Is that more money?&nbsp; What is the plan for those towns?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as we&#8217;ve been talking about, DHS has a plan.&nbsp; DHS is implementing a comprehensive strategy to address &#8212; to address a potential increase in the number of border encounters.&nbsp; Their strategy includes acquiring and deploying resources to address increased volumes; that involves moving officers, agents, DHS Volunteer Force personnel to rapidly decompress points along the border and more efficiently process migrants.&nbsp; It also entails the deployment of COVID-19 mitigation efforts, including the continued use of PPE and providing the COVID-19 vaccines to non-citizens in ICE custody since summer of 2021.</p>



<p>Beginning March 28, 2022, DHS expanded those efforts to cover migrants in CBP custody so as to further safeguard public health and ensure the safety of border communities, the workforce, and migrants.&nbsp; And so that is what DHS has a comprehensive plan, and they&#8217;ll be executing that, and they have been.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then last one for me &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry if this is repetitive; it&#8217;s hard to hear on the plane.&nbsp; But in terms of Ukraine, as it looks more likely that the war is going to be going on for quite some time, is there talk of allowing more complex systems like Patriot missiles that would take longer to train up but could have a bigger effect on protecting Ukraine and the airspace?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, any specific materials that you just laid &#8212; that you just mentioned, I would refer you to the Department of Defense.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything here to preview on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just had another one.&nbsp; Increasingly, we&#8217;re seeing talks from Republicans directed at Democrats, allegations of grooming around LGBTQ issues.&nbsp; There was that speech that went viral from a Democrat state lawmaker in Michigan that rebutted some attacks against her of allegations of grooming.</p>



<p>From the White House&#8217;s perspective, these attacks that we&#8217;re seeing from Republicans &#8212; allegations, unsubstantiated &#8212; against Democrats, does the White &#8212; does the President plan to call out these attacks?&nbsp; Is this something that the White House is aware of, concerned about?&nbsp; Any comment that you might have on the increasing allegations that we&#8217;ve seen?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &nbsp;You mean like the attacks on the LGBTQ community and &#8212; in particular?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) but even also broader on Democrats and allegations &#8212; again, unsubstantiated &#8212; about grooming and things of that nature, as we saw &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if you saw the video of the Michigan &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’d have to say, I actually have &#8212; I heard of the video, but I have not watched it in its entirety.&nbsp; I’ve only seen clips of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the President has always stand &#8212; stood with the LGBTQ community in supporting them and seeing them &#8212; that community.&nbsp; Clearly, any attacks or &#8212; that we are seeing &#8212; you know, I was just asked about what Governor DeSantis is doing in Florida with Disney.&nbsp; And so, we think that type of behavior is wrong.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;ve been very clear about that at the podium.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been very clear about that anytime you all ask &#8212; ask us.</p>



<p>I have not had a conversation with the President &#8212; or we haven’t &#8212; about if he is &#8212; you know, what &#8212; if he&#8217;s going to say anything himself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But he has put out at least &#8212; you know, behind a podium or at &#8212; you know, at a mic, but we have put out statements in his voice when it comes to attacks that we have seen in that community specifically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve been very clear on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on Tyler&#8217;s question: The point is not necessarily attacks against the LGBT &#8212; the LGBT community; it&#8217;s rather Republicans accusing Democrats of being sexual predators and making that a broad strategy as an attack on the opp- &#8212; on the other party.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, you know, look, I asked if it was about the LGBT community.&nbsp; He said “yes.”&nbsp; But I hear your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, it&#8217;s &#8212; what the Republicans are doing is unfortunate.&nbsp; You know, instead of talking about the issues that&#8217;s going on currently, right now, with the pain the American families are feeling, and coming to the table and having a real discussion on how to &#8212; how to make Americans’ lives better, they want to have a culture war.&nbsp; And that &#8212; and that is unfortunate to see.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be steadfast and focused on what&#8217;s at &#8212; what&#8217;s at hand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today we&#8217;re going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be in Portland, as you all know, and we’re going to talk about the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law &#8212; which, by the way, as you all know, Republicans in Congress were able to come together with Democrats and we got something done &#8212; something that was historic, something that&#8217;s going to change the lives of American people, something that&#8217;s going to create jobs, that&#8217;s going to rebuild our infrastructure deal with supply chain as we&#8217;re &#8212; as we&#8217;re trying to, you know, deal with this once-in-a-generation pandemic.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we want to see.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the President was elected to do &#8212; is to bring people together and get things done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to talk about today, and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to talk about tomorrow in Seattle.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden in New Hampshire and in Iowa and, perhaps today, has put his foot forward on the deficit a lot.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talking a lot more about the deficit, including touting his proposal as an immediate deficit-cutting measure.&nbsp; I wanted &#8212; I wonder if you can talk about that shift.&nbsp; BBB used to &#8212; he used to talk about it cutting the deficit in the long term, and now he talks about it in the short term.&nbsp; Seems to be an olive branch to Senator Manchin.&nbsp; How big a priority is immediate deficit reduction for President Biden?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; because Manchin has talked about a bill that is sort of half deficit reduction.&nbsp; In other words, half the &#8212; you know, only half the new revenue would be spent and, therefore, the deficit would be immediately driven down.&nbsp; Is that something he would support?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, I &#8212; you know, as we&#8217;ve been saying for the past several months, I &#8212; we&#8217;re not just &#8212; we&#8217;re just not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp; Clearly, this is &#8212; when we think about Build Back Better &#8212; we took it &#8212; think about build &#8212; building back a better America, that is something that&#8217;s important to the President.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to continue to &#8212; continue to work towards that and continue to talk to folks on Congress, but I don&#8217;t have any specific details to share.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’s kind of negotiating in public though, a little bit, by telling Senator Manchin that he&#8217;s open to it.&nbsp; Isn’t he?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; right here, on this plane, I don&#8217;t have anything to share or any specifics (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just ask one more, Karine, as we &#8212;</p>



<p>Sorry, a quick one.&nbsp; Does the President still have confidence that Mayor Garcetti has the support in Congr- &#8212; in the Senate to be confirmed as Ambassador to India?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, he has confidence in Mayor Garcetti to &#8212; to move forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p> 2:05 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and President of the Senate on Providing Notice of Intent to Designate Colombia as a Major Non-NATO&#160;Ally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-president-of-the-senate-on-providing-notice-of-intent-to-designate-colombia-as-a-major-non-nato-ally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51578</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) In accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k), I am providing notice of my intent to designate Colombia as a Major Non-NATO Ally. I am making this designation in recognition of the importance of&#160;the U.S.-Colombia relationship and Colombia&#8217;s crucial contributions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>In accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k), I am providing notice of my intent to designate Colombia as a Major Non-NATO Ally.</p>



<p>I am making this designation in recognition of the importance of&nbsp;the U.S.-Colombia relationship and Colombia&#8217;s crucial contributions to regional and international security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After Air Force Two&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-air-force-two-arrival/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[San Francisco International AirportSan Francisco, California Q    Two questions for you, to start. THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Inaudible).&#160; (Laughs.) Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Okay, two questions for you.&#160; First, do you have any reaction to the latest sanctions from Russia that would bar your entry into the country? And then, second, on Title 42, would you be in favor&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>San Francisco International Airport</em><em><br><em>San Francisco, California</em></em></p>



<p>Q    Two questions for you, to start.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible).&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, two questions for you.&nbsp; First, do you have any reaction to the latest sanctions from Russia that would bar your entry into the country?</p>



<p>And then, second, on Title 42, would you be in favor of delaying the ending of it, especially as a few members of your own party have kind of pushed back?&nbsp; Is that something that’s under consideration?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So, let’s be very clear about where we stand in terms of Russia: As far as I’m concerned — and I think, objectively, many people will agree — that their invasion of Ukraine has not only been steeped in atrocities but will proof to be a strategic failure for Russia.</p>



<p>What we have done most recently, and the President did a speech this morning talking about what we will continue to do as a — one of our highest commitments to continue to support the Ukrainian people, President Zelenskyy with what we can in terms of economic assistance, humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; But also, with equal fervor, we are absolutely committed to continuing with the serious consequences and costs to Russia of its act of aggression and, as the President has rightly said, with its criminal conduct.</p>



<p>And so that has included what we will continue to do to issue sanctions, as we just announced, but all with an understanding that one of our highest priorities is sovereignty and territorial integrity as a — is solid principle that binds and unifies the NATO Alliance, to your point about NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so we’re going to continue to do that work, and we’re not going to give up.</p>



<p>Thank you. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Sullivan’s Meeting with Finance Minister Wong of&#160;Singapore</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-sullivans-meeting-with-finance-minister-wong-of-singapore/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Finance Minister Lawrence Wong of Singapore today at the White House. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Wong reflected on the strength of the U.S.-Singapore Strategic Partnership and reviewed opportunities to build on the momentum generated by Prime Minister Lee’s recent visit to the United States, including his discussions with President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Finance Minister Lawrence Wong of Singapore today at the White House. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Wong reflected on the strength of the U.S.-Singapore Strategic Partnership and reviewed opportunities to build on the momentum generated by Prime Minister Lee’s recent visit to the United States, including his discussions with President Biden at the White House.  Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Wong discussed regional and global issues, including Russia’s war against Ukraine, COVID-19 and health security, the crisis in Burma, and shared efforts to develop an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework that advances inclusive and sustainable prosperity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Responds to Putin’s Price Hike by Awarding First Barrels from Historic Strategic Petroleum Reserve Release &#038; Deploying Affordable Clean&#160;Energy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/fact-sheet-biden-administration-responds-to-putins-price-hike-by-awarding-first-barrels-from-historic-strategic-petroleum-reserve-release-deploying-affordable-clean-energy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the U.S. Department of Energy announced that it has awarded contracts for all of the initial 30 million barrels it put up for sale as part of President Biden’s historic Strategic Petroleum Reserve Release. These barrels will be delivered in May and June, and are the first U.S. sale in the largest release from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the U.S. Department of Energy announced that it has awarded contracts for <em>all </em>of the initial 30 million barrels it put up for sale as part of President Biden’s historic Strategic Petroleum Reserve Release. These barrels will be delivered in May and June, and are the first U.S. sale in the largest release from reserves from both the United States and the rest of the world in history. Together, these releases will put more than one million barrels per day on the market over the next six months, and will help address supply disruptions caused by Putin’s further invasion of Ukraine and the Price Hike that Americans are facing at the pump.</p>



<p>The initial sale of barrels from the release garnered strong interest and was substantially oversubscribed: DOE received bids for a total of 76 million barrels, or more than doublethe number of barrels put up for sale.</p>



<p>The Biden Administration also announced this week a set of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-creates-cost-saving-clean-energy-opportunities-to-combat-climate-crisis/">new actions and programs</a> this week that support the President’s mission to accelerate America’s move towards true energy independence and lowering costs for Americans with a clean energy economy.</p>



<p>With these announcement, President Biden is demonstrating both his unwavering commitment to doing everything in his power to ease the pain American families are facing today at the pump as a result of Putin’s Price Hike, while continuing to take strong action – right now and without delay – to achieve lasting American energy independence.</p>



<p><strong><u>Actions to Immediately Increase Supply and Lower Prices at the Pump</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Largest-Ever Release of Oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve. </strong>President Biden announced the largest-ever release of oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserves, which will put one million additional barrels on the market per day on average—every day—for the next six months. The release will provide a record amount of supply to the market until the end of the year, when domestic production is expected to increase by 1 million barrels per day. DOE will use the revenue from the release to restock the Strategic Petroleum Reserve in future years. This will provide a signal of future demand and help encourage domestic production today, and will ensure the continued readiness of the Reserve to respond to future emergencies.</p>



<p><strong>Historic Collective Release of Oil from the International Energy Agency</strong>. After around the clock diplomacy by the President and allies and partners, the International Energy Agency announced an unprecedented collective release with member countries outside the United States releasing an additional 60 million barrels. Together with the United States’ commitment, this will add a combined global amount of 240 million barrels to the market. It is the largest release from other IEA countries in history, and will support American consumers and the global economy.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding Americans’ Access to Affordable Fuel Options This Summer. </strong>President Biden announced that the EPA Administrator is planning to issue an emergency waiver allowing E15 gasoline—gasoline that uses a 15 percent ethanol blend—to be sold this summer. An emergency waiver can help increase fuel supplies, give consumers more choice to get lower prices, and provide savings to many families. At current prices, E15 can save a family 10 cents per gallon of gas on average, and many stores sell E15 at an even greater discount – adding up to real savings for working families. Allowing higher levels of blending will also reduce our dependency on foreign fuels as we rely more heavily on home-grown biofuels.</p>



<p><strong>Increasing Domestic Production Through a “Use it or Lose it” Policy. </strong>The United States is already approaching record levels of oil and natural gas production, with domestic production expected to increase by 1 million barrels per day this year and over 500,000 barrels per day next year. But too many companies aren’t doing their part and are choosing to make extraordinary profits and without investing to help with supply. Right now, the oil and gas industry is sitting on more than 12 million acres of non-producing Federal land with 9,000 unused but approved permits for drilling. President Biden called on Congress to make companies pay fees on idled wells and non-producing acres on Federal lands – so that companies that continue to sit on excess capacity will have to choose whether to start producing or pay a fee.</p>



<p><strong><u>Achieving Real Energy Independence and Lowering Costs for Families</u></strong></p>



<p>The President knows the true path to energy security runs through clean energy. This week, the Biden Administration announced <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-creates-cost-saving-clean-energy-opportunities-to-combat-climate-crisis/">new actions and programs</a> that accelerate and strengthen America’s move towards a clean energy economy and lower costs for consumers, furthering the path towards true U.S. energy independence. These actions build on the steps President Biden has taken this year to reduce energy costs for families: expanding clean energy, making clean energy more affordable and accessible, and increasing energy efficiency.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding Clean Energy</strong><strong></strong></p>



<ul><li>The Department of the Interior outlined a <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-outlines-roadmap-continued-renewable-energy-progress-public-lands">roadmap</a> this week to reach the President’s target to double clean energy permits on public lands, reaching 25 gigawatts of renewable power by 2025.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of Energy established a new <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/president-biden-department-energy-establish-bipartisan-infrastructure-laws-20-million">rebate program</a> this week through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to provide utilities with the resources to upgrade critical equipment that supports a cleaner and more efficient power grid.</li></ul>



<ul><li>President Biden launched the American offshore wind industry through the Department of the Interior, approving the first large-scale projects, identifying new wind energy areas in the Atlantic and the Pacific, and holding a record-breaking $4.3 billion lease sale, putting us on track to meet his target of 30 gigawatts of offshore wind by 2030.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of Energy fast-tracked clean energy projects by approving record levels of solar and other renewables on public lands and helping local governments advance community solar projects.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of Energy advanced power grid upgrades to increase reliability, lower costs, and unlock more clean energy through the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/oe/articles/building-better-grid-initiative">Building a Better Grid Initiative</a>.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Making Clean Energy More Affordable and Accessible</strong></p>



<ul><li>The Department of Energy deployed a software tool – SolarAPP+ – to cut permitting times for residential solar to less than one day, helping to fast-track families’ access to cheaper, cleaner, and more secure energy.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of Agriculture a new pilot program to help people in underserved rural communities cut energy costs via renewable energy, building on more than $450 million in investments in renewable energy fur rural communities last year.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Increase Energy Efficiency</strong></p>



<ul><li>The Biden Administration is advancing a series of <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-releases-energy-saving-rules-federal-buildings-and-proposes-new-standards-consumer">100 actions</a> to be completed this year, which together will save families $100 every year with more efficient home appliances and equipment.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of Energy <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-administration-announces-investments-make-homes-more-energy-efficient-and-lower">opened applications</a> for more than $3 billion in new Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding—ten times the historical funding levels—for the Weatherization Assistance Program, providing energy efficiency and electrification upgrades in homes and saving families on their utility bills.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Department of Transportation’s National Highway Traffic Safety Administration finalized <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/usdot-announces-new-vehicle-fuel-economy-standards-model-year-2024-2026">standards</a> for cars and trucks that will allow drivers to travel further on every gallon of fuel and save money at the pump.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Vice President Harris announced the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/04/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-action-plan-for-building-better-school-infrastructure/">Biden-Harris Action Plan to Build Better School Infrastructure</a>, including a $500 million grant program at the Department of Energy to save schools money by tackling energy costs—the second-largest expense after teacher salaries.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The White House joined leaders from state and city governments, labor, and industry to launch the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-coalition-of-states-and-local-governments-to-strengthen-building-performance-standards/">Building Performance Standards Coalition</a>, a first-of-its-kind partnership between more than 30 state and local governments covering nearly 20% of the nation’s building footprint, dedicated to deliver cleaner, healthier buildings with lower energy bills.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Jen&#160;Psaki on Awarding First Barrels from Historic Strategic Petroleum Reserve&#160;Release</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/statement-from-jen-psaki-on-awarding-first-barrels-from-historic-strategic-petroleum-reserve-release/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is using all the tools at his disposal to address Putin’s Price Hike at the pump. Today, the Department of Energy announced that it has awarded contracts for all of the initial thirty million barrels it put up for sale as part of the emergency release of 1 million barrels per day in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is using all the tools at his disposal to address Putin’s Price Hike at the pump. Today, the Department of Energy announced that it has awarded contracts for <em>all </em>of the initial thirty million barrels it put up for sale as part of the emergency release of 1 million barrels per day in oil for the next 6 months. This is an important step to addressing the supply shortage and the Putin Price Hike Americans are facing. These sales will continue. And because of round-the-clock diplomatic efforts, our partners and Allies have committed to releasing an additional 60 million barrels. </p>



<p>This is just the latest result of the Biden Administration’s efforts to do everything in our power to lower energy costs for American families, including accelerating the deployment of cost-saving clean energy with the urgency this moment requires. Last week, the President announced that his Administration is planning to allow the sale of E15 gasoline in all parts of the country this summer, so that Americans have access to more choices and lower prices. And the Administration continues to work toward <em>real </em>energy independence by rapidly reducing our dependence on oil—including this week’s announcement of critical investments to deploy clean energy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Earth Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/21/a-proclamation-on-earth-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 19:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; Fifty-two years ago, millions of people gathered across our&#160;country in a rally to protect our planet.&#160;&#160;This collective action gave birth to a new movement and spurred the creation of landmark environmental laws that protect the air we breathe and the water we drink.&#160;&#160;Today, we must recapture that spirit and, as I said in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; Fifty-two years ago, millions of people gathered across our&nbsp;country in a rally to protect our planet.&nbsp;&nbsp;This collective action gave birth to a new movement and spurred the creation of landmark environmental laws that protect the air we breathe and the water we drink.&nbsp;&nbsp;Today, we must recapture that spirit and, as I said in my Inaugural Address, heed&nbsp;a cry for survival that comes from the planet itself.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;In their most recent report, the Intergovernmental Panel on&nbsp;Climate Change provided yet another round of evidence that climate change is no longer in the distant future &#8212; it is here.&nbsp;&nbsp;Last year, extreme weather and climate disasters cost our communities $145 billion and claimed hundreds of lives.&nbsp;&nbsp;In the summer of 2021 alone, nearly 1 out of every 3 Americans experienced a weather disaster.&nbsp;&nbsp;The climate crisis is upending lives across the country and around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;Environmental injustices continue to exact a toll on&nbsp;the health of communities of color, low-income communities, and&nbsp;Tribal and Indigenous communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;A number of wildlife species in the United States and around the world are facing an&nbsp;extinction crisis unparalleled in human history.&nbsp;&nbsp;The&nbsp;environmental challenges of our time call for historic action, and we intend to meet the moment.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;That is why my Administration has launched the most ambitious environmental and climate agenda in history.&nbsp;&nbsp;We have made the bold&nbsp;commitment to reduce greenhouse gas emissions in the United States by 50 to 52 percent by 2030, reach 100 percent carbon pollution-free electricity by 2035, and achieve net zero emissions economy-wide by no later than 2050.&nbsp;&nbsp;To work toward these goals, we have taken action across every sector of the economy, including setting the strongest-ever standards for greenhouse gas emissions from passenger vehicles, tackling super-pollutants like methane and hydrofluorocarbons, investing billions in the deployment of clean technologies, and launching the American offshore wind industry.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;In addition, I was proud to start the &#8220;America the Beautiful&#8221; initiative, our first-ever voluntary national conservation goal to conserve 30 percent of America&#8217;s lands and waters by&nbsp;2030.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is a once-in-a-generation opportunity to build on these actions and accelerate our Nation&#8217;s ability to confront the environmental and climate challenges we face.&nbsp;&nbsp;It will allow us to remediate and reclaim abandoned mine lands and oil wells leaking methane while putting Americans to work in good paying jobs; invest in coastal wetlands and habitats that can protect infrastructure and homes during storms; replace lead pipes that plague underserved communities and remove dangerous chemicals from our drinking water; restore watersheds and rivers; create fish passage to protect iconic species, such as salmon;&nbsp;restore forests as carbon sinks; build resilience to climate impacts including droughts, heat, floods, and wildfires; and build a national network of electric vehicle charging stations to accelerate our transition to electric mobility.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;As my Administration implements this agenda, we are following through on our commitment to ensuring that our investments advance equity and justice and reach communities across the country &#8212; including rural communities, communities of color, and low-income communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;We will be guided by the steadfast conviction of Earth Day founder Gaylord Nelson, my friend and former colleague, that &#8220;every person has the inalienable right to a decent environment,&#8221; including those who&nbsp;have long been shut out of decisions that directly affect&nbsp;their lives and who are most likely to bear the brunt of pollution and climate change.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The responsibility to confront the climate crisis is not solely on the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;It requires leaders across the world committing to a clean energy future.&nbsp;&nbsp;On my first day in office, I fulfilled my promise to rejoin our Nation to the Paris Agreement to tackle the climate crisis at home and abroad.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;For the future of our planet, for our health, and for our children and grandchildren, we must act now.&nbsp;&nbsp;Let us stand united in this effort to save our planet and, in the process, strengthen our economy and grow more connected to each other and&nbsp;the world we share.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 22, 2022, as Earth Day.&nbsp;&nbsp;I encourage all Americans to participate in programs and activities that will deepen their understanding of environmental protection, the urgency of climate change, and the need to create a healthier, safer, more equitable future for all people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this&nbsp;twenty-first day of April, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Bilateral Meeting between President Joe&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of&#160;Greece</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-bilateral-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-prime-minister-kyriakos-mitsotakis-of-greece/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 18:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden looks forward to welcoming Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of Greece to the White House on May 16, 2022. The Prime Minister’s visit provides an opportunity to affirm our strong bilateral partnership and to celebrate 201 years of Greek independence. The leaders will discuss ongoing efforts with Allies and partners to support the people of Ukraine and impose&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden looks forward to welcoming Prime Minister Kyriakos Mitsotakis of Greece to the White House on May 16, 2022. The Prime Minister’s visit provides an opportunity to affirm our strong bilateral partnership and to celebrate 201 years of Greek independence. The leaders will discuss ongoing efforts with Allies and partners to support the people of Ukraine and impose economic costs on Russia for its unprovoked aggression. They will discuss our close cooperation on global challenges, including climate change and energy security. The leaders will take stock of our joint efforts to promote global security through NATO, as well as our shared goals for peace and prosperity in the region. They will also celebrate the history, democratic values, and trade and investment links that have united our peoples and countries for generations.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Veterans Unemployment Matching Historic&#160;Low</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/statement-by-president-biden-on-veterans-unemployment-matching-historic-low/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I believe that our nation has a sacred obligation to America’s veterans and their families. Among other things, this means providing veterans with the tools and resources for economic opportunity, security, and dignity. My Administration’s approach is working: today, the unemployment rate for veterans is 2.4 percent—tied for the lowest rate on record—and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I believe that our nation has a sacred obligation to America’s veterans and their families. Among other things, this means providing veterans with the tools and resources for economic opportunity, security, and dignity. My Administration’s approach is working: today, the unemployment rate for veterans is 2.4 percent—tied for the lowest rate on record—and down from an average of 6.5 percent in 2020.</p>



<p>Veterans of all backgrounds are finally being cut in on the deal. Unemployment rates for white, Black, Asian, and Hispanic veterans—male and female—fell and were the same or lower than their nonveteran counterparts in 2021. And, the unemployment rate for veterans with a service-connected disability declined to 3.4 percent.</p>



<p>This historic progress is the result of my Administration’s efforts to rebuild America’s economy from the bottom up and the middle out. We are continuing to build on this record with initiatives to bring veterans into critical industries like trucking and ensure they are good-paying, quality jobs. And, we are continuing our work to reduce the costs veterans and working families face.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden Providing an Update on Russia and&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-president-biden-providing-an-update-on-russia-and-ukraine-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 16:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51532</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 10:01 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160;&#160;Good morning, everyone.&#160; Sorry to keep you waiting a little bit.&#160; I had the honor of spending some time with the Ukrainian Prime Minister, who’s in town today.&#160; And he is meeting with some of my Cabinet members, including the Secretary of Treasury and others.&#160; And we had a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>10:01 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp;Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Sorry to keep you waiting a little bit.&nbsp; I had the honor of spending some time with the Ukrainian Prime Minister, who’s in town today.&nbsp; And he is meeting with some of my Cabinet members, including the Secretary of Treasury and others.&nbsp;<br><br>And we had a &#8212; a good discussion.&nbsp; I talked about what I’m about to tell you about today, as well as &#8212; he was thanking the American people for their support, understands it’s significant, and was &#8212; we talked about keeping everyone together, in terms of Europe, the European Union, and others, in the effort to stop Putin’s brutality.&nbsp;<br><br>But before I head out to the West Coast, I want to quickly update the American people on the latest steps we’re taking to support the people of Ukraine and to hold Putin accountable for his brutal and bloody war.&nbsp;<br><br>Russian forces have retreated from Kyiv, leaving behind them a horrifying evidence.&nbsp; And you’ve seen it and you reported it &#8212; your folks.&nbsp; And, by the way, I &#8212; I don&#8217;t say this often, but I think we should give enormous credit to the folks in your agencies that are on the ground in Ukraine, in these spots.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re really &#8212; I&#8217;ve spoken to several of them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a &#8212; we owe them.&nbsp; But uncovering these evidences of their atrocities and war crimes against the Ukrainian people &#8212; it’s so clear to the whole world now.<br><br>Now they’ve launched and refocused their campaign to seize new territory in eastern Ukraine.<br><br>And we’re in a critical window now of time where that &#8212; they’re going to set the stage for the next phase of this war.<br><br>And the United States and our Allies and partners are moving as fast as possible to continue to provide Ukraine the forces that they need &#8212; the weapons they need &#8212; excuse me &#8212; and the equipment they need &#8212; their forces need to defend their nation.<br><br>Last week, I signed an $800 million package of security assistance to Ukraine that included new capabilities like artillery systems and armored personnel carriers &#8212; equipment that is responsive to Ukraine’s needs and tailored to support the intensified fighting in the Donbas region, which is a different war than in other places because both &#8212; topographically it’s different.&nbsp; It’s flat, it’s not in the mountains, and it requires different kinds of weapons to be more effective.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I’m announcing another $800 million to further augment Ukraine’s ability to fight in the east &#8212; in the Donbas region.<br><br>This package includes heavy artillery weapons &#8212; dozens of Howitzers &#8212; and 144,000 rounds of ammunition to go with those Howitzers.&nbsp; It also includes more tactical drones.<br><br>In the past two months, we’ve moved weapons and equipment to Ukraine at record speed.<br><br>We’ve sent thousands of anti-armor and anti-[air] missile[s], helicopters, drones, grenade launchers, machine guns, rifles, radar systems.&nbsp;More than 50 million rounds of ammunition had already been sent.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States alone has provided 10 anti-armor systems for every one Russian tank that’s in Ukraine &#8212; a 10 to 1 ratio.<br><br>We’re sharing and will continue to share significant, timely intelligence with Ukraine to help defend them against Russian aggression.<br><br>And on top of this, these direct contributions from the United States, we’re facilitating; we’re the outfit facilitating the significant flow of weapons and systems to Ukraine from other Allies and partners around the world, like the S-300 long-range, anti-aircraft systems that Slovakia recently transferred to Ukraine.&nbsp; We are getting them in there.&nbsp;<br><br>We won’t always be able to advertise everything we &#8212; that our partners are doing to support Ukraine in its fight for freedom.&nbsp;<br><br>But to modernize Teddy Roosevelt’s famous advice: Sometimes we will speak softly and carry a large Javelin.&nbsp; Because we’re sending a lot of those in as well.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, but we’re not &#8212; we’re not sitting on the funding that Congress has provided for Ukraine.&nbsp; We’re sending it directly to the frontlines of freedom, to the fearless and skilled Ukrainian fighters who are standing in the breach.<br><br>You got to admit, you have &#8212; must be amazed at the courage of this country, the resolve that they’re showing, not just the milit- &#8212; their military, but the average citizen: men and women, young &#8212; young men, young women as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>It’s &#8212; you know, the sustained and coordinated support of the international community, led and facilitated by the United States, has a &#8212; is a significant reason why Ukraine is able to stop Russia from taking over their country thus far.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Every American taxpayer, every member of our Armed Forces can be proud of the fact that our country’s generosity and the skill and service of our military helped arm and repel Russia’s aggression in Ukraine, to beat back Putin’s savagery that tried to seize Ukraine’s capital and wipe out Ukraine’s government.<br><br>The Battle of Kyiv was a historic victory for the Ukrainians.&nbsp; It was a victory for freedom, won by the Ukrainian people with unprecedented assistance by the United States and our Allies and our partners.&nbsp;<br><br>Now &#8212; now we have to accelerate that assistance package to help prepare Ukraine for Russia’s offensive that’s going to be more limited in terms of geography, but not in terms of brutality &#8212; not in terms of brutality.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Combined with our recent drawdowns, it will ensure a steady flow of weapons and equipment into Ukraine over the next few weeks.<br><br>However, with this latest disbursement, I’ve almost exhausted the drawdown authority I have that Congress authorized for Ukraine in a bipartisan spending bill last month.<br><br>In order to sustain Ukraine for the duration of this fight, next week I’m going to &#8212; have to be sending to Congress a supplemental budget request to keep weapons and ammunition flowing without interruption to the brave Ukrainian fighters and to continue to deliver economic assistance to the Ukrainian people.<br><br>Hope &#8212; and my hope is and my expectation is Congress would move and act quickly.&nbsp; And I want to thank the Congress &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; for their support for the people of Ukraine.<br><br>Our unity at home, our unity with our Allies and partners, and our unity with the Ukrainian people is sending an unmistakable message to Putin: He will never succeed in dominating and occupying all of Ukraine.&nbsp; He will not &#8212; that will not happen.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to bolstering Ukraine’s resistance on the battlefield, we’re also demonstrating our support for the people of Ukraine.<br><br>Today, the United States is announcing that we intend to provide an additional $500 million in direct economic assistance to the Ukrainian government.<br><br>This brings our total economic support for Ukraine to $1 billion in the past two months.<br><br>This is money the government can help use to help stabilize their economy, to support communities that have been devastated by the Russian onslaught, and pay the brave workers that continue to provide essential services to the people of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, these past weeks have seen a terrible human cost of Putin’s ambition for conquest and control.&nbsp; Approximately two thirds &#8212; two thirds &#8212; of all Ukrainian children have been displaced from their homes.&nbsp; More than 5 million Ukrainians have fled their country.&nbsp; It’s an absolute outrage.&nbsp;&nbsp;The idea this is happening approaching the second quarter of the 21st century is just &#8212; (sighs).<br><br>Last month, when I was in Europe, I announced that the United States would welcome 100,000 Ukrainians so that we share in the responsibility of supporting Ukrainians fleeing Putin’s war machine.<br><br>We’ve already welcomed tens of thousands of Ukrainians to the United States.<br><br>And today, I’m announcing a program, “Unite for Ukraine” &#8212; a new program to enable Ukrainians seeking refuge to come directly from Europe to the United States.<br><br>This new humanitarian parole program will complement the existing legal pathways available to Ukrainians, including immigrant visas and refugee processing.<br><br>It will provide an expedient channel for secure, legal migration from Europe to the United States for Ukrainians who have a U.S. sponsor, such as a family or an NGO.<br><br>This program will be fast.&nbsp; It will be streamlined.&nbsp; And it will ensure the United States honors its commitment to go to the Ukrainian people and need not go through our southern border.<br><br>We’re also continuing to ratchet up the pressure on Putin and further isolate Russia on the world stage.<br><br>Yesterday, the Treasury Department rolled out additional measures to crack down on the entities and individuals attempting to evade our unprecedented sanctions &#8212; not just ours, but throughout the West.<br><br>Today, I’m announcing that the United States will ban Russian-affiliated ships from our ports, as they did in Europe.<br><br>That means no ship &#8212; no ship that sails under the Russian flag or that is owned or operated by Russian interests will be allowed to dock in a United States port or access our shores.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; None.<br><br>This is yet another critical step we’re taking in concert with our partners in the European Union, the United Kingdom, and Canada and &#8212; further to deny Russia the benefits of the international economic system that they so enjoyed in the past.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We don’t know how long this war will last.&nbsp; But as we approach the two-month mark, here’s what we do know:<br><br>Putin has failed to achieve his grand ambitions on the battlefield.&nbsp; After weeks of shelling Kyiv, Kyiv still stands.<br><br>President Zelenskyy and his democratically elected government still remain in power.<br><br>And the Ukrainian armed forces, joined by many brave Ukrainian civilians, have thwarted Russia’s conquest of their country.<br><br>They have been bolstered from day one by an unstinting supply of weapons, ammunition, armor, intelligence from the nations of the free world led by us, the United States.<br><br>As Russia continues to grind out the military advances and &#8212; their military advances and the brutalities against Ukraine, Putin is banking on us losing interest.&nbsp; That’s been my view; you’ve heard me say this from the beginning.&nbsp; He was counting on NATO, the European Union, our allies in Asia cracking, moving away.&nbsp; He’s betting on Western unity will crack.&nbsp; He’s still betting on that.<br><br>And, once again, we’re going to prove him wrong.&nbsp; We will not lessen our resolve.&nbsp; We’re going to continue to stand with the brave and proud people of Ukraine.&nbsp; We will never fail in our determination to defend freedom and oppose tyranny.&nbsp; It’s as simple as that.<br><br>So, again, I want to thank the American people &#8212; thank the American people for their support of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; This is our &#8212; this is our responsibility, it seems to me, and we’ve been able to hold the whole world together in this effort.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you very much.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m going to take just one or two questions.&nbsp; I’ve got a plane to catch.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does &#8212; what does Putin claiming control over Mariupol mean?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; how significant is that?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first of all, it’s questionable whether he does control Mariupol.&nbsp; One thing for sure we know about Mariupol: He should allow humanitarian corridors to let people on that steel mill and other places that are buried under rubble to get out &#8212; to get out.&nbsp; That’s what any, any, any head of state would do in such a circumstance.<br><br>And so, there is no evidence yet that Mariupol has completely fallen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on Title 42, sir, are you considering delaying lifting Title 42?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; What I’m considering is continuing to hear from my &#8212; my &#8212;<br><br>Well, first of all, there’s going to be an appeal by the Justice Department because, as a matter of principle, we want to be able to be in a position where if, in fact, it is strongly concluded by the scientists that we need Title 42, that we be able to do that.<br><br>But there has been no decision on extending Title 42.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how long can the U.S. maintain the level and pace of this military support for Ukraine?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I &#8212; well, we have the capacity to do this for a long time.&nbsp; The question is: Are we going to continue to maintain the support of the international community and keep the pressure on Putin to prevent him from overrunning the country?&nbsp; Number one.&nbsp; And, number two, make sure we continue to maintain the economic sanctions, which, over time &#8212; and we’re beginning to see it &#8212; are devastating their economy and their ability to move forward.<br><br>So, the most important thing right now is maintain the unity.&nbsp; So far, so good.<br><br>Thank you very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How much money are you going to ask for in the supplemental?&nbsp; How much money in the supplemental, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The answer &#8212; that’s being decided now.&nbsp; And I’m asking the Defense Department to put together what they think we need.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>10:14 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
