<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 21:26:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>U.S.-Canada Joint Statement on Gordie Howe International&#160;Bridge</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/u-s-canada-joint-statement-on-gordie-howe-international-bridge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 21:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the importance of infrastructure becomes clearer and clearer, our two countries have long been partnering on a once-in-a generation project of critical importance: the Gordie Howe International Bridge. By creating the first seamless highway-to-highway connection between Windsor, Ontario, and Detroit, Michigan—the location of one of North America’s busiest trade corridors—this new crossing, currently under&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As the importance of infrastructure becomes clearer and clearer, our two countries have long been partnering on a once-in-a generation project of critical importance: the Gordie Howe International Bridge. By creating the first seamless highway-to-highway connection between Windsor, Ontario, and Detroit, Michigan—the location of one of North America’s busiest trade corridors—this new crossing, currently under construction, will for decades serve to secure and spur bi-national economic growth. Canada is financing the project, and is working hand-in-hand with the State of Michigan (also co-owner of the Bridge), the Federal Highway Administration, a private-sector partner, and many other partners towards a scheduled completion by the end of 2024. As a top infrastructure priority for both our governments, we’re committed to continuing our support to ensure the project’s state-of-the-art ports of entry are fully funded so vehicles can begin crossing the architecturally stunning cable-stayed structure once completed for the benefit of our shared prosperity.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>April 2021 Visitor Log Records&#160;Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2021/07/29/april-2021-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Disclosures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in April 2021. This set includes 1509 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 4188. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in April 2021. This set includes 1509 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 4188.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Announce New Actions to Get More Americans Vaccinated and Slow the Spread of the Delta&#160;Variant</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-announce-new-actions-to-get-more-americans-vaccinated-and-slow-the-spread-of-the-delta-variant/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Six months into the Biden Administration’s vaccination effort, 164 million Americans are fully vaccinated, including 80 percent of seniors and more than 60 percent of adults. This is significant progress, and as a result, the country and economy are in a stronger position than January 2021. We are now faced with a much more transmissible&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Six months into the Biden Administration’s vaccination effort, 164 million Americans are fully vaccinated, including 80 percent of seniors and more than 60 percent of adults. This is significant progress, and as a result, the country and economy are in a stronger position than January 2021.<br><br>We are now faced with a much more transmissible strain of this virus—the Delta variant. The good news is that we are prepared for this. We know how to stop it: get more people vaccinated.<br><br>Today, the President will announce additional efforts to do just that—imposing requirements to protect our federal workforce and those they serve, offering additional incentives for vaccination, and making it even easier for people, especially young people, to get themselves and their loved ones vaccinated.<br><br>Today’s actions include:<br><br><strong>Strengthening Safety Protocols for Federal Employees and Federal Contractors. </strong>Today, the President will announce that to help protect workers and their communities, every federal government employee and onsite contractor will be asked to attest to their vaccination status. Anyone who does not attest to being fully vaccinated will be required to wear a mask on the job no matter their geographic location, physically distance from all other employees and visitors, comply with a weekly or twice weekly screening testing requirement, and be subject to restrictions on official travel.<br><br>The federal government employs more than 4 million Americans, including over 2 million in the federal civilian workforce, throughout our country and across the world.<br><br>These rules should not only apply to federal workers and onsite contractors. President Biden is directing his team to take steps to apply similar standards to all federal contractors. The Administration will encourage employers across the private sector to follow this strong model.<br><br><strong>Protecting Those Who Serve Our Country.</strong> Today, the President will announce that he is directing the Department of Defense to look into how and when they will add COVID-19 vaccination to the list of required vaccinations for members of the military. This is particularly important because our troops serve in places throughout the world—many where vaccination rates are low and disease is prevalent.<br><br>Earlier this week, like many health care employers across the country, the Department of Veterans Affairs took the common-sense and important step of requiring their health care providers and personnel to be fully vaccinated against COVID-19. Too many veterans have already lost their lives to this virus, and veterans and their families deserve nothing less than us doing everything we can to protect their health. The public health, health care, and medical community are unified in support of these actions—on Monday, over 50 leading health care societies and organizations called for all health care and long-term care employers to require their workers to receive the COVID-19 vaccine.<br><br><strong>Expanding Paid Leave to Get Families and Kids Vaccinated.</strong> The President will announce that small- and medium-sized businesses will now be reimbursed for offering their employees paid leave to get their family members, including their kids, vaccinated. In April, the President announced that, thanks to the American Rescue Plan (ARP), the federal government is fully reimbursing any small- or medium-sized business that provides workers with paid time off to get vaccinated. According to the Kaiser Family Foundation, by the end of June, half of all workers in America had access to paid time-off for vaccinations, and 75% of workers who were offered paid time-off for vaccinations from their employer reported being vaccinated. The President will also call on employers who have not offered paid time off to their employees for vaccination to do so.<br><strong> <br>Calling on State and Local Governments to Offer $100 to Get Vaccinated. </strong>Today, the President will call on states, territories, and local governments to do more to incentivize vaccination, including offering $100 to those who get vaccinated. Throughout America’s vaccination efforts, we have seen that financial incentives serve as a motivating factor for some people to get vaccinated. When the grocery store Kroger started offering $100 to their associates to get vaccinated, it saw vaccination rates increase from 50% to 75%. States like New Mexico, Ohio, and Colorado have piloted $100 incentive programs that have also helped move the dial on vaccinations. According to research from the University of California, Los Angeles, roughly one-third of unvaccinated individuals said a cash payment would make them more likely to get a shot. The American Rescue Plan (ARP) provided states, territories, and localities resources that can be used to offer incentives to increase vaccination rates, and today, the President will call on every state, territory, and local government to use this ARP funding to provide $100 to anyone who gets vaccinated.<br><br><strong>Increasing Vaccinations Among Adolescents as Kids Go Back to School. </strong>Today, the President will, in an effort to get more kids 12 and older vaccinated, call on school districts nationwide to host at least one pop-up vaccination clinic over the coming weeks. And, the Administration is directing pharmacies in the federal pharmacy program to prioritize this and to work with school districts across the country to host vaccination clinics at schools and colleges. In March, the Biden Administration prioritized K-12 educators, school staff, and child care workers for vaccinations. This directive worked: Today, almost 90% of educators and school staff are vaccinated. The President believes that every student—no matter their zip code—should have an easy and accessible way to get vaccinated. Vaccination is our leading public health strategy to end the COVID-19 pandemic—and it is our best way to prevent COVID outbreaks before they happen, so that schools and colleges can return to safe, in-person instruction all year long.<br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Six Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/president-biden-announces-six-key-nominations-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following six individuals to serve in key roles: Jonathan Eric Kaplan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Singapore Francisco O. Mora, Nominee for Permanent Representative of the United States of America to the Organization of American States, with the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following six individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Jonathan Eric Kaplan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Singapore</li><li>Francisco O. Mora, Nominee for Permanent Representative of the United States of America to the Organization of American States, with the rank of Ambassador&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Nicole Angarella, Nominee for Inspector General, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>John Plumb, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Space Policy, Department of Defense</li><li>Amy Searight, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for the Bureau for Asia, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Alex Wagner, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Manpower and Reserve Affairs, Department of Defense</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Jonathan Eric Kaplan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Singapore</u></strong></p>



<p>Jonathan Kaplan currently serves as Chairperson of the EducationSuperHighway, a nonprofit organization that works with governors and officials across the nation to provide American public school classrooms access to high-speed internet connections. An entrepreneur and innovator, Kaplan most recently was the Chairperson and CEO of FishSix Restaurant Corporation. Prior to that, as Chairperson and CEO of Pure Digital Technologies, he invented and marketed the revolutionary Flip video camera and, when Pure Digital was acquired by Cisco Systems, Kaplan became Senior Vice President and General Manager of its Consumer Products Division.&nbsp; Earlier Kaplan was President and CEO of Sega.com, Founder and CEO of MovieStreet, Vice President and General Manager of Geoworks, and Vice-President of Hands On Technology. Kaplan serves as an advisor for the Young Presidents Organization, meeting with corporate management and government leaders in dozens of countries.&nbsp; Kaplan earned a Bachelor of Science degree in industrial management from Carnegie Mellon University and was the 2010 Ernst &amp; Young Northern California Entrepreneur of the Year.</p>



<p><strong><u>Francisco O. Mora, Nominee for Permanent Representative of the United States of America to the Organization of American States, with the rank of Ambassador&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<p>Francisco O. Mora is a Professor of Politics and International Relations, and Senior Researcher, at the Jack D. Gordon Institute for Public Policy at Florida International University (FIU).&nbsp; Earlier, he was Director of the Kimberly Green Latin American and Caribbean Center at FIU’s Green School of International and Public Affairs.&nbsp; Mora served as Deputy Assistant Secretary for Defense for the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp; He held several teaching positions, including Professor of National Security Strategy and Latin American Studies at the National War College at the National Defense University, and Associate Professor and Chair in the Department of International Studies at Rhodes College.&nbsp; He is the author of four books and numerous articles and other publications.&nbsp; Mora earned a B.A. in International Affairs at The George Washington University.&nbsp; He received his M.A. in Inter-American Studies and a Ph.D. in International Affairs from the University of Miami.&nbsp; He also completed studies at universities in Peru and Costa Rica.&nbsp; He is a recipient of the Office of the Secretary of Defense Medal for Exceptional Public Service, Department of Defense.&nbsp; Mora is a native Spanish speaker and also speaks Portuguese.</p>



<p><strong><u>Nicole Angarella, Nominee for Inspector General, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Nicole Angarella serves as the general counsel to the USAID Inspector General. In that position, Ms. Angarella leads a team of attorneys and specialists that provides independent legal counsel to the Inspector General, deputy inspector general, senior managers, and staff. Her office provides comprehensive legal advice, research, and guidance to the Offices of Audit, Investigations, and Management within the Office of Inspector General (OIG). Her office also updates the Inspector General and staff on legal developments and represents OIG in Federal and administrative litigation.</p>



<p>Prior to her appointment as general counsel, Ms. Angarella served as a senior legal counsel at USAID OIG and at the Department of Transportation’s OIG. Ms. Angarella has spent her entire federal career in the Inspector General community. She is Chair of the Council of Counsels to the Inspectors General. Before joining the U.S. Government, she worked as an associate attorney in the General Litigation &amp; White Collar Criminal Defense Practice Group at Cozen O’Connor, an international law firm representing corporate and individual clients in Federal investigations and complex criminal and civil matters. She also worked as an associate attorney specializing in employment and labor relations law at a law firm in Washington, DC. Ms. Angarella has a B.A. in political science from the University of Mary Washington and a law degree from the Columbus School of Law at The Catholic University of America. Ms. Angarella is a member of both the Virginia State Bar and the District of Columbia Bar.</p>



<p><strong><u>John Plumb, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Space Policy, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>John F. Plumb, Ph.D.,&nbsp;is the Principal Director, Chief of Government Relations at the Aerospace Corporation, a federally funded research and development center focused on national security space programs.&nbsp; He has served in national security roles for over 25 years at the strategic, operational, and tactical levels.&nbsp; His expertise includes space, missile defense, nuclear and conventional deterrence, and submarines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Prior to his current role he was a senior engineer at RAND.&nbsp; He has served at the White House, the Pentagon, and the U.S. Senate in senior defense staff roles.&nbsp; His past positions include Director for Defense Policy and Strategy on the National Security Council staff, Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Space Policy at the Pentagon, Principal Director for Nuclear and Missile Defense Policy at the Pentagon, and Military Legislative Assistant to U.S. Senator Ken Salazar in the Senate.&nbsp; He ran for office in 2016 in New York&#8217;s 23rd Congressional District.&nbsp; Dr. Plumb has over 25 years active and reserve service as a U.S. Navy Submarine Officer and is currently a Captain in the Navy Reserve.&nbsp; He holds a Ph.D. in Aerospace Engineering from the University of Colorado, an M.A. in Physics from the University of Colorado, and a B.S. in Physics from the University of Notre Dame.</p>



<p><strong><u>Amy Searight, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for the Bureau for Asia, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Amy Searight is currently Senior Associate for Asia at the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS), where she previously served as Senior Advisor and Director of the Southeast Asia Program.&nbsp; Prior to joining CSIS, Amy served in the Obama-Biden Administration.&nbsp; From 2014-2016 she served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for South and Southeast Asia, and from 2012-2014 she served Principal Director for East Asia Security in the Office of the Secretary of Defense.&nbsp; In 2016 she was awarded the Secretary of Defense Medal for Outstanding Public Service.&nbsp; Before the Pentagon, Searight served as Senior Advisor for Asia in the U.S. Agency for International Development for two years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Earlier in her career, she worked in the State Department as an International Affairs Fellow of the Council on Foreign Relations, serving as Special Economic Advisor for Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation and on the Policy Planning Staff.&nbsp; She was assistant professor of political science at The Elliott School of International Affairs at The George Washington University and at Northwestern University.&nbsp; A native of New Jersey, she received her B.A. in political economy from Williams College, and an M.A. in East Asian Studies and Ph.D. in Political Science from Stanford University.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Alex Wagner, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Manpower and Reserve Affairs, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Alex Wagner is a lawyer who served in various positions in the Department of Defense during the Obama-Biden administration.&nbsp; In 2015, Mr. Wagner was appointed as Chief of Staff to the Secretary of the Army, shaping policy and outreach for the Secretary while guiding the Army&#8217;s civilian and military leadership with respect to the Secretary’s priorities, initiatives, and plans.&nbsp; In this role, he was closely involved in the development and implementation of policies opening all combat roles to women, enabling transgender Americans to openly serve their nation, and updating the Army&#8217;s uniform and grooming regulations to enhance recruiting and retention of soldiers of faith.&nbsp; From 2011 to 2014, he served as Senior Advisor for Rule of Law and Detainee Policy in the Office of the Secretary of Defense, where he represented the Department to the interagency and internationally on issues regarding human rights and the laws of war. From 2009 to 2011, Mr. Wagner served as the Special Assistant to the Assistant Secretary of the Defense (Global Strategic Affairs).</p>



<p>Mr. Wagner is currently Vice President for Strategic Initiatives at the Aerospace Industries Association, leading efforts on talent and workforce policy as well as developing strategic partnerships to tell the story of technological innovation and the people who drive it.&nbsp; He has also worked as a lawyer in private practice, specializing in intellectual property law and the First Amendment. He received his law degree from Georgetown Law, where he served as an adjunct professor from 2011 to 2017, and his undergraduate degree from Brown University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION&#160;SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Thea D. Rozman Kendler, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce, vice Richard Ashooh. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION&nbsp;SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Thea D. Rozman Kendler, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce, vice Richard Ashooh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Q2 GDP&#160;Data</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-q2-gdp-data/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s GDP data are further proof of the remarkable progress we’ve made in jump-starting our economy from one of the darkest moments in its history. With today’s numbers, the U.S. economy has now made up the losses of the last 18 months and surpassed the pre-pandemic GDP peak. In doing so, we’ve grown our economy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s GDP data are further proof of the remarkable progress we’ve made in jump-starting our economy from one of the darkest moments in its history. With today’s numbers, the U.S. economy has now made up the losses of the last 18 months and surpassed the pre-pandemic GDP peak. In doing so, we’ve grown our economy the first half of this year at the fastest rate in almost four decades, created three million new jobs, and halved new jobless claims.<br><br>Simply put, because of President Biden’s leadership, America is on the move again. This isn’t an accident: It’s the result of a successful campaign against the virus and an economic policy that has been focused squarely on getting help to the working and middle-class Americans who need it the most – ensuring that we’re rebuilding our economy in a way that puts them first. This wasn’t preordained – in fact, In fact, just one year ago, CBO predicted real GDP would be 3% below its pre-pandemic peak at this time. But, thanks to shots in arms and checks in pockets, we’ve been able to far outstrip that and power a recovery twice as fast as after the last recession.<br><br>That’s the story of this President’s economic plan: taking us from the worst time for our economy in history to one of the best. And we’re seeing signs of that across the economy. More than 600,000 jobs created each month since the President took office, the fastest pace for a new Administration in history. New unemployment claims slashed in half. Independent forecasts of economic growth doubled for 2021.<br><br>We still have work to do to build our economy back better, and we can’t be complacent when too many Americans are still facing the squeeze of economic uncertainty. That’s why the President and his team are going to continue focusing squarely on curbing this virus and getting our communities the economic support they need to thrive. And it’s why the President has put forward a historic, and bipartisan, plan to rebuild our infrastructure and invest in our global competitiveness which cleared an important hurdle last night. And it’s why he’s working with Democrats to deliver on additional support for our middle class that will create a fairer, more sustainable, and stronger economy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Eviction Prevention&#160;Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-biden-harris-administration-eviction-prevention-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For nearly 11 months, the CDC’s eviction moratorium has served as a critical backstop to prevent hard-pressed renters and their families who lost jobs or income due to the COVID-19 pandemic from being evicted for nonpayment of rent. &#160;This moratorium prevented hundreds of thousands of Americans from experiencing the heartbreak, homelessness, and health risks that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For nearly 11 months, the CDC’s eviction moratorium has served as a critical backstop to prevent hard-pressed renters and their families who lost jobs or income due to the COVID-19 pandemic from being evicted for nonpayment of rent. &nbsp;This moratorium prevented hundreds of thousands of Americans from experiencing the heartbreak, homelessness, and health risks that too often emanate from evictions –particularly during a pandemic. The Administration considered it a prudent public health decision when the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) extended the eviction moratorium until July 31<sup>st</sup>.</p>



<p>Given the recent spread of the Delta variant, including among those Americans both most likely to face evictions and lacking vaccinations, President Biden would have strongly supported a decision by the CDC to further extend this eviction moratorium to protect renters at this moment of heightened vulnerability. Unfortunately, the Supreme Court has made clear that this option is no longer available.&nbsp; In June, when CDC extended the eviction moratorium until July 31<sup>st</sup>, the Supreme Court’s ruling stated that “clear and specific congressional authorization (via new legislation) would be necessary for the CDC to extend the moratorium past July 31.”</p>



<p>In light of the Supreme Court’s ruling, the President calls on Congress to extend the eviction moratorium to protect such vulnerable renters and their families without delay. In addition, he has asked the U.S. Departments of Housing and Urban Development, Agriculture, and Veterans Affairs to extend their respective eviction moratoria through the end of September, which will provide continued protection for households living in federally-insured, single-family properties. The President has also asked these and other departments to do everything in their power so that owners and operators of federally-assisted and financed rental housing seek Emergency Rental Assistance to make themselves whole while keeping families in secure and safe housing – before moving toward eviction.</p>



<p>Finally, the President urges states and localities, which long ago received Emergency Rental Assistance – including through the American Rescue Plan – to urgently accelerate their efforts to disburse these funds given the imminent ending of the CDC eviction moratorium. With some cities and states demonstrating their ability to release these funds efficiently to tenants and landlords in need, there can be no excuse for any state or locality not to promptly deploy the resources that Congress appropriated to meet this critical need of so many Americans.</p>



<p>The Administration remains committed to doing everything in its power to keep people safely and securely housed, which is essential to the health, well-being and dignity of all of us.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration in Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-strategy-to-address-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 2, 2021, President Biden signed an Executive Order that called for the development of a Root Causes Strategy. Since March, Vice President Kamala Harris has been leading the Administration’s diplomatic efforts to address the root causes of migration from El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras. &#160;She has worked with bilateral, multilateral, and private sector&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 2, 2021, President Biden signed an Executive Order that called for the development of a Root Causes Strategy.<br><br>Since March, Vice President Kamala Harris has been leading the Administration’s diplomatic efforts to address the root causes of migration from El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras. &nbsp;She has worked with bilateral, multilateral, and private sector partners, as well as civil society leaders, to help people from the region find hope at home. &nbsp;This complements work done throughout the U.S. government over the last six months to learn lessons from prior efforts and to consult with a wide range of stakeholders to inform the development of this strategy.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing the Root Causes Strategy—a core component of our Administration’s efforts to establish a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system. &nbsp;This Strategy identifies, prioritizes, and coordinates actions to improve security, governance, human rights, and economic conditions in the region.&nbsp; It integrates various U.S. government tools, including diplomacy, foreign assistance, public diplomacy, and sanctions. &nbsp;<br><br>Implementation of the Strategy will rely on the expertise of a wide range of U.S. departments and agencies, with support from governments in and&nbsp;outside&nbsp;the region, civil society, the private sector, multilateral organizations, international financial institutions, and the U.S. Congress.&nbsp; These partnerships will bolster the impact of the Strategy through informing programmatic interventions, leveraging political will, and mobilizing necessary resources. The U.S. government will coordinate a place-based approach, targeting those areas where migrants are most likely to come from.<br><br>The Strategy is organized into five pillars:</p>



<ul><li>Pillar I:&nbsp; Addressing economic insecurity and inequality;</li><li>Pillar II:&nbsp; Combating corruption, strengthening democratic governance, and advancing the rule of law;</li><li>Pillar III:&nbsp; Promoting respect for human rights, labor rights, and free press;</li><li>Pillar IV:&nbsp; Countering and preventing violence, extortion, and other crimes perpetrated by criminal gangs, trafficking networks, and other organized criminal organizations; and</li><li>Pillar V:&nbsp; Combating sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence. &nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The Vice President and the Administration have already taken action – notable accomplishments include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing immediate humanitarian needs including vaccines.&nbsp; </strong>On April 26, Vice President Harris announced $310 million in urgent relief to help address the acute factors of migration, including from hurricanes, the pandemic, and drought caused by climate change. &nbsp;To date, we have allocated over $250 million of the total funds, reaching over two million people. &nbsp;We also provided over 10 million COVID vaccine doses to El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.<br></li><li><strong>Countering corruption and democratic backsliding.</strong> &nbsp;Vice President Harris has been direct and unwavering in highlighting the problems of corruption, the need for reforms, and the vital importance of demonstrating commitment to the rule of law, judicial independence, human rights, and a strong civil society—including during her bilateral meeting in Guatemala. &nbsp;Working with the Department of Justice, the Vice President launched an Anticorruption Task Force that will include U.S. prosecutors and law enforcement experts to investigate and prosecute corruption cases with a nexus in the United States and the region.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Addressing security concerns of mutual interest.</strong> &nbsp;Vice President Harris launched Anti-Migrant Smuggling Task Forces in both Mexico and Guatemala and secured commitments to increase border enforcement. &nbsp;She reached an agreement with the Mexican government to restart the high-level dialogue focused on the trafficking of weapons and drugs.<br></li><li><strong>Internationalizing our efforts. &nbsp;</strong>The Vice President has said, “The United States cannot do this work alone.” &nbsp;She has reached out to international partners to highlight the need for increased support for Central America and secured commitments from a number of countries. &nbsp;She successfully encouraged the United Nations to develop a regional Humanitarian Response Plan to mobilize international donor support for the region.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Working with the private sector.&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>On May 27, Vice President Harris launched a&nbsp;<em>Call to Action</em>&nbsp;for the private sector to make new commitments in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to expand economic opportunities.&nbsp; The initial group of 12 companies and organizations committed to helping over 13 million people, offered to provide $750 million in resources, and established a non-profit organization to support economic development efforts in the region – The Partnership for Central America.&nbsp; These initial commitments will provide financial services to small business owners, internet access and digital banking to rural communities, housing for low-income families, and reduced barriers to higher education.&nbsp; Since the&nbsp;launch, over&nbsp;150 companies and organizations&nbsp;have expressed&nbsp;interest in joining the&nbsp;<em>Call to Action</em>.</li></ul>



<p>Full report here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Root-Causes-Strategy.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Root-Causes-Strategy.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Collaborative Migration Management&#160;Strategy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-the-collaborative-migration-management-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25305</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 2, 2021, President Biden signed an Executive Order that called for the development of a Collaborative Migration Management Strategy (Migration Strategy).&#160; Over the last six months, the Administration has consulted with partner governments, Members of Congress and their staff, international organizations, civil society organizations, labor unions, and the private sector to inform its&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 2, 2021, President Biden signed an Executive Order that called for the development of a Collaborative Migration Management Strategy (Migration Strategy).&nbsp; Over the last six months, the Administration has consulted with partner governments, Members of Congress and their staff, international organizations, civil society organizations, labor unions, and the private sector to inform its development.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing the Migration Strategy.&nbsp; It is the first U.S. government strategy focused on strengthening cooperative efforts to manage safe, orderly, and humane migration in North and Central America.&nbsp; In line with our Nation’s highest values, the Migration Strategy contributes to a humane and secure approach by improving regional cooperation to manage migration, expanding protection, and enhancing access to lawful pathways for migration.&nbsp; It is driven by the U.S. government’s belief that all individuals should be able to find safety and achieve a stable and dignified life within their own countries.&nbsp; When that is not the case, asylum and other legal migration pathways should be available to those who need them.<br><br>The United States has strong national security, economic, and humanitarian interests in promoting safe, orderly, and humane migration.&nbsp; By enhancing humanitarian support, regional protections, and investing in migration management, the United States will help build a more stable region, strengthen legal pathways for those who must migrate, and reduce irregular migration.<br><br>The Migration Strategy includes the following lines of effort:</p>



<ul><li>Stabilize populations with acute needs</li><li>Expand access to international protection</li><li>Expand access to protection in countries of origin</li><li>Improve and expand temporary labor programs in the region with worker protections</li><li>Assist and reintegrate returned persons</li><li>Foster secure and humane management of borders</li><li>Strengthen regional public messaging on migration</li><li>Expand access to lawful pathways for protection and opportunities to the United States</li></ul>



<p>Implementation of the Migration Strategy will integrate various U.S. government tools, including diplomacy, foreign assistance, public messaging, and U.S. immigration initiatives.&nbsp; It will rely on the expertise of a wide range of U.S. departments and agencies, with support from governments in and&nbsp;outside&nbsp;the region, international organizations, civil society, the private sector, multilateral organizations, international financial institutions, and the U.S. Congress.&nbsp; These partnerships will bolster the impact of the Migration Strategy through informing programmatic interventions, leveraging political will, and mobilizing necessary resources.</p>



<p>Full report here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Collaborative-Migration-Management-Strategy.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Collaborative-Migration-Management-Strategy.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Immigration&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/29/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-biden-harris-administration-immigration-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (July 28, 2021) 4:01 P.M. EDT SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thank you so much, Josh.&#160; Hello, everyone, and welcome.&#160; On behalf of the NSC, I’d like to welcome you to this call on migration strategy. I&#8217;m going to introduce our speakers in a second, but I just want to go over the ground rules.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 28, 2021)</p>



<p>4:01 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Josh.&nbsp; Hello, everyone, and welcome.&nbsp; On behalf of the NSC, I’d like to welcome you to this call on migration strategy.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to introduce our speakers in a second, but I just want to go over the ground rules.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s call and the content, as well as the factsheets that we&#8217;ll send out to you later, are on background and embargoed until tomorrow morning at 6:00 a.m. or released by the White House.</p>



<p>For your reference, our speakers today are [senior administration officials].&nbsp; As a reminder, again, our speakers today are going to be referred to as &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;</p>



<p>And with that, I will turn it over to our first senior administration official.&nbsp; Over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Hi, everyone, and good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, we released a factsheet on the Biden administration&#8217;s blueprint for a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system.&nbsp; This administration launched a whole-of-government effort in January to responsibly manage the border and put in place immigration systems that align with our values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President also sent a bill to Congress that includes a path to citizenship, a proposal to manage the border and address the root causes of migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the blueprint yesterday includes four strategies: One, a humane and well-managed border.  This includes strategic use of the $15 billion a year that <s>CBC</s> [CBP] receives and implementing expedited removal for families who do not express fear of return to their home country. </p>



<p>It includes orderly and fair processing of asylum seekers.&nbsp; This includes allowing asylum officers to adjudicate asylum claims and a dedicated asylum docket.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, what you&#8217;ll hear about today is collaborative migration management with regional partners and addressing the root causes of migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, success in building a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system won&#8217;t come overnight, but we do have a blueprint to get us there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for being on the call.&nbsp; Really appreciate this opportunity to chat.</p>



<p>I want to begin by underscoring a couple of things that [senior administration official] mentioned.&nbsp; You know, when Joe Biden and Kamala Harris came into office on January 20th, they really inherited a broken and dysfunctional system.&nbsp; And you all know the history there, but there were a number of problems that pre-existed the Trump administration, but the Trump administration made them so much worse.&nbsp; And many of the things that we&#8217;re trying to deal with now have been exacerbated by the decisions that were taken then.</p>



<p>Four months ago, in March, when President Biden asked Vice President Harris to take on the root causes &#8212; for her to look at what are the drivers of migration in Central America, and how can we execute diplomacy with these countries, develop assistance with these countries that will get at those primary factors that are causing people to leave their home, and how can we pair that up in an integrated approach, as [senior administration official] has just mentioned, with the other aspects of our approach to migration.</p>



<p>And it really is an integrated approach.&nbsp; You have to work on all aspects of this strategy if we&#8217;re going to be successful over the long term.&nbsp; So, all of them are important.</p>



<p>The root causes piece that the Vice President is working on, in some respects, is the long pole in the tent.&nbsp; It certainly is going to be the longest-term effort, and it is one that needs to work on multiple levels simultaneously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The very first thing that the Vice President did when she took on this account was to deal with the very extreme humanitarian needs in the region.&nbsp; As you all know, there have been devastating hurricanes, COVID, the economic slump that had resulted in destroyed infrastructure, homelessness, food insecurity.</p>



<p>The Vice President put together a package of over $300 million of immediate humanitarian relief.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already disbursed $250 million of that and have brought a lot of really essential relief to people throughout the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time that she was taking that initial action on humanitarian relief, she also worked to lay the framework for extensive engagement. She worked intensively with the Cabinet, Congress, policy experts, civil society, philanthropic foundations, and foreign partners in both the region and around the world.</p>



<p>A couple of things that she produced that I want to highlight for you &#8212; and happy to come back in detail &#8212; but first, the United Nations is going to issue a humanitarian response plan in September.&nbsp; This is a direct result of the work that she and her team have done to &#8212; with all of the U.N. agencies, as well as the U.N. member states.</p>



<p>Second, the Vice President did extensive outreach with our international partners to highlight the needs of this region and to encourage responsible friends and allies to come forward.&nbsp; Many of them have &#8212; to include Japan, South Korea and Israel &#8212; to increase their aid, increase their engagement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe the Japanese foreign minister is in Central America today as we speak.&nbsp; And there are a number of other countries, both within this hemisphere and around the world, who have said that they are eager to help, recognizing the need there.</p>



<p>Third, the Vice President issued a call to action to the private sector, getting some of our most prominent corporations to commit to make investments and also to provide philanthropic support into the region.&nbsp; There was an initial sort of steering group of 12 major corporations.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had over 150 businesses express interest in participating in this very targeted program from private-sector businesses, and we&#8217;re very excited about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She also, as you know, engaged with the region itself, with the leaders in the region.&nbsp; She traveled to Mexico and Guatemala &#8212; as well as visited El Paso &#8212; and issued a number of really important initiatives there on anti-trafficking and anti-smuggling; also talked about a number of &#8212; launched a number of important assistance programs; and delivered very clear messages to the leaders of those governments about what our priorities were and what our expectations were.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m happy to come back to that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, finally, a very important accomplishment of the Vice President is the strategy that we&#8217;re rolling out now.&nbsp; And I will turn it over to my colleague here to talk about the strategy.&nbsp; But just want to note that for this strategy to be successful, we will have to undertake sustained effort, which is both hard work over time, but also a very hardnosed approach to having an impact on the ground for the people of the region who are suffering so badly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, let me turn it over to [senior administration official], who has been working on these issues for many years.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; On the front end, I want to mention, as somebody who worked on this when Vice &#8212; when Vice President Biden was working on it during the Obama-Biden administration, and has had the privilege to also work with the Vice President and her team on this, I want to kind of underscore here that what we&#8217;re talking about here is much more than U.S. assistance package.&nbsp; As [senior administration official] highlighted, we&#8217;re looking at actually building a broader coalition that includes not just the U.S. government and its support, but members of the private sector, the foundations, the international community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in the process of the Vice President&#8217;s leadership and the development of the plan, we did a very thorough study of then-Vice President Biden&#8217;s efforts &#8212; what succeeded, so we could build on it; what areas we needed to actually innovate on and build upon.&nbsp; And that really has informed the development, not just of this strategy, but the Vice President&#8217;s engagement, and as [senior administration official] mentioned, the entire blueprint approach that includes migration.</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ll just go really quickly through the five pillars of the strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is economic insecurity and inequality.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll run through them quickly and can answer any questions.&nbsp; So the United States is working to promote a strong investment climate in these countries.&nbsp; We want to create jobs so that people want to stay home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The rule of law, transparency, an independent and fair judiciary combating corruption &#8212; all of these elements are strong and vital to that (inaudible) climate.&nbsp; And as the Vice President made clear, economic growth should really be inclusive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A point is &#8212; the point here is that we&#8217;re working with local communities to deepen resilience to the extreme weather events that will only become more common due to climate change, including innovations in climate-smart agricultural practices, all that will be necessary to support economic security.</p>



<p>Pillar number two is combating corruption, strengthening democratic governance, and advancing the rule of law.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll just say that corruption corrodes the public trust, and as you all saw, there was a (inaudible) administration &#8212; administration-wide national security memorandum where combating corruption is really going to be central to everything that we do, not just in Central America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number three is promoting respect for human rights, labor rights, and a free press.&nbsp; The President and Vice President, I mentioned, were the most &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be the most pro-union administration in modern history.&nbsp; And labor rights is actually something that promotes economic prosperity in these countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our work not just with governments, but I think underscoring our work with civil society is really central to all of this.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s important not to leave out, really, the importance of women and girls, as the Vice President highlighted during her visit to Guatemala, indigenous persons, Afro-descendants, LGBTQI+ persons, and persons with disabilities to make sure that we&#8217;re engaging with all members of society.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number four is countering and preventing violence, extortion, and other crimes perpetrated by criminal gangs, trafficking networks, and other organized criminal organizations.&nbsp; It&#8217;s pretty straightforward, and I would just point out that that&#8217;s why the Vice President launched an anti-smuggling task force in both Mexico and Guatemala, and secured commitments to increase border enforcement in these countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last but not least, combating sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence.&nbsp; Across the region, sexual and gender-based violence significantly hinders the ability of women and girls to participate fully in society and contribute to their families and communities.&nbsp; We know that femicide is something that is rampant in many countries in Central America and that the future prosperity of the region is really one that is invested in the success of women and girls.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s something that has been central to the Vice President&#8217;s approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Women and youth from marginalized communities often face higher levels of violence, especially LGBTQI+ women and girls.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to work with partner governments, civil society organizations, and others to combat violence in the region and to provide protection and services to those who suffer such violence.</p>



<p>So, I’ll turn it over to my colleague.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Great to have a chance to speak with you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m going to be talking to you about the Collaborative Migration Management Strategy, which is the first of its kind and a companion to the root causes strategy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really premised on this idea that as we&#8217;re seeking to improve the conditions on the ground in Central America and build hope under the leadership of the Vice President, we understand that people will &#8212; there will continue to be a demand to migrate.&nbsp; And so, the CMMS addresses this head on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re not seeking to end migration as part of the fabric of this region.&nbsp; We have so many familial, cultural ties in Central America.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re seeking to change the ways in which people migrate, to provide an alternative to the criminal smuggling and trafficking rings, and to give people access to opportunity and protection through safe legal channels, safe legal pathways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know that people are leaving the north of Central America for a wide variety of reasons, including seeking employment, seeking access to protection for people that are fleeing a lot of the underlying &#8212; the root causes that [senior administration official] mentioned, and then to reunite with family.</p>



<p>So, the goal is to match these legal pathways with these drivers &#8212; these various, distinct drivers of migration.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve been doing a lot of work, a lot of consultation with the people in the region, with civil society actors on the ground, with the governments, trying to deeply understand why people are making the choice to migrate and how can we make sure that we are addressing them in our strategy &#8212; our Collaborative Migration Management Strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s a centerpiece of the CMMS that &#8212; is, you know, very ambitiously expanding access to legal pathways, both to the United States and to various other countries.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing a lot of work already to try to bring other countries to the table to multiply the number of legal pathways &#8212; countries like Canada, Costa Rica, Spain, and elsewhere.&nbsp; There&#8217;s actually a lot of momentum on that front, and it&#8217;s very encouraging.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These legal pathways are diverse, as I mentioned.&nbsp; It includes labor pathways; it includes expanding traditional resettlements and other protections pathways.&nbsp; It includes family reunification programs like the Central American Minors Program.&nbsp; That’s just the beginning of that kind of work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then legal pathways is just one piece of the CMMS.&nbsp; I won&#8217;t go through all of them, but you&#8217;ll see them tomorrow when we roll out the plan.&nbsp; There are eight lines of action in total.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, just a few other highlights: You know, we&#8217;re looking to build on a lot of the work that&#8217;s already being done to strengthen asylum throughout the region in countries like Mexico and, again, Costa Rica so that, you know, people have various options where they can access international protection.&nbsp; Also, to strengthen protection mechanisms inside countries of origin for internally displaced persons, IDPs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re looking to connect it to our legal pathways work to stand up migration resource centers &#8212; basically, physical structures where people can go to access this information and to be referred for legal pathways and other services in their countries.&nbsp; And then, we are &#8212; you know, the strategy calls for working with our partner governments in the region to foster secure management of borders and to strengthen regional public messaging on migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we’re really excited.&nbsp; And again, just to note, this is the first of its kind, and I think we really believe that with the combination of ambitious root causes and migration management strategy that we really and truly have an impact in this region.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We can open it up for questions.&nbsp; As a reminder to our participants, this call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The call contents are embargoed until 6:00 a.m. tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you so much.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; A few questions.&nbsp; For [senior administration official], I was hoping you could answer, like, be a little more specific: How much of the $15 billion that was, I guess, for the wall will be redirected?&nbsp; What kind of things will it be redirected for?&nbsp; Are we talking drones, cameras?&nbsp; Does border agents come into that?</p>



<p>I was also hoping you could give an update on ending Title 42 and how will that &#8212; if and when it&#8217;ll be ended, how will it be ended?&nbsp; Will it be done by a phased approach?</p>



<p>And for [senior administration official], I was hoping you could talk a little bit about updates on how we&#8217;ll be supporting prosecutorial efforts in Central America?  Would independent judges and prosecutors &#8212; is this &#8212; are there going to be something like trying to revive something like CICIG?  If you could talk about that as well.  Thank you so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; I can start.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce on Title 42.&nbsp; As we’ve said in the past, it&#8217;s a public health authority, and that authority rests with the CDC, and so we&#8217;ll continue to defer to them on those decisions.</p>



<p>On the border, the President&#8217;s FY22 budget request, I think, allocated a little over a billion dollars for technology and for ports of entry.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have a number for you in terms of redirection of wall money.&nbsp; I can pull it for you afterwards.&nbsp; But we are prioritizing, as I said, technology and ports of entry.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Great.  Hey, Franco.  Great to hear from you.  Look, you saw the announcement when the Vice President traveled to Guatemala on an anti-corruption task force so &#8212; and you’ll see that actually delivers on a campaign commitment made by the President during the campaign.  The rationale behind that is that organizations like CICIG took years to stand up, and we needed to act very quickly to do a couple things.</p>



<p>Number one, is, there are things that the United States can do in terms of investigations and prosecutions.&nbsp; You know we have officials that (inaudible) to pull visas, and we have the end goal list, which you&#8217;ve seen a lot on.&nbsp; And &#8212; but it also includes working with those judges and prosecutors that are ones that we see are having an active commitment to combatting anti-corruption efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Others are &#8212; as you may have seen after the firing of Mr. Sandoval, the chief of FECI in Guatemala, that we have decided to suspend some assistance to the office of the Prosecutor General.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing some of those programs that we see are advancing these anti-corruption efforts, but others we are freezing.&nbsp; So, those are a whole host of tools on the anti-corruption side.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, I got to underscore here this is something that the Vice President has really made central is that our engagement with the private sector is also an anti-corruption initiative.&nbsp; Because what we&#8217;re trying to do is introduce new private-sector actors who are advocating for creating a transparent and business-friendly environment for investment, and that&#8217;s something that I think provides, like, a profit-proposition to anti-corruption efforts.</p>



<p>So, a lot of this is multifaceted, it’s individual, it’s working with governments, but also trying to go out of government-to-government channel by getting civil society and in the private sector involved.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I have two quick questions.&nbsp; The first one to anyone who can respond.&nbsp; You were talking about the management of the borders.&nbsp; In the case of Mexico, the President Andrés Manuel López Obrador has just announced that he&#8217;s planning to integrate the National Guard under the conduction of the Secretary of Defense of Mexico.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are several reports about human rights abuses of the immigrants by the National Guard of Mexico and also by the members of the Mexican army.&nbsp; Is the Biden administration worried about this change in terms of the National Guard of Mexico guarding the border &#8212; the south border of Mexico and the northern border of Mexico, trying to control the immigration flow, if there&#8217;s will be any complaints about the human rights situation?</p>



<p>And the second question is for [senior administration official].&nbsp; In terms of the increase that were reported by the DHS about the arrest of illegal immigrants in the southern border of the United States, the numbers of Mexicans are going up.&nbsp; The government Mexico says &#8212; said recently that the economy of Mexico is better off than years &#8212; years before.&nbsp; Why do you guys see the reason that Mexicans are trying to cross illegally the northern border of Mexico to be in the United States if Mexico has a better economy now?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll take your first question there regarding Mexico border management.&nbsp; Just to note from the CMMS, you know, our pillar on that is, &#8220;to foster secure and humane management of borders.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, I think we recognize the need to work with governments throughout the region in managing migration and addressing, you know, these irregular movements.&nbsp; But we certainly want to do that in a way that&#8217;s humane and upholds the dignity and the human rights of those who are making the journey.</p>



<p>And so, you know, that includes, for instance, in Mexico, ensuring that people that would be interdicted by the National Guard &#8212; you know, under Mexican law, that they would (inaudible) and have access to asylum in Mexico, through COMAR, their refugee commission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, when we talk to Mexico and we discuss migration management, we also talked about the importance of access to asylum and protection.&nbsp; So just to note that we view this as some &#8212; the importance of that balance between enforcement and protection.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a &#8212; it is written, explicitly, in our strategy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And, Jesús, hola.&nbsp; Good to &#8212; good to hear from you.&nbsp; So, there are a number of reasons why people choose to leave their homes &#8212; not just Mexico, but Central America and even increasing numbers of migrants from Venezuelan, Haitian, and Cuban origin.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing one of those elements is, of course, that we&#8217;ve all been through a pandemic for the last year-plus, and we&#8217;re still in there.&nbsp; And that there&#8217;s been a pent-up migration demand that we are starting to see.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, frankly, that is one of the reasons why this administration is sharing &#8212; right now, I don&#8217;t have the exact count &#8212; but over 40 million vaccines with the countries of the region to try to be as responsive to a region that has been very hard hit by the impact of the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The other &#8212; just on the &#8212; you know, and I can&#8217;t speak to what President López Obrador&#8217;s characterization of Mexican economy, but I&#8217;ll say that it&#8217;s in our interest for Mexico to prosper.&nbsp; And that, you know, the United States prospers when Mexico prospers and the other way around.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, right now, assessments indicate that the U.S. economy is going to grow at 6.9 percent, at least.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that&#8217;s going to have incredible economic benefits for Mexico.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, GDP growth is one way to measure economic prosperity; inequality and economic opportunity is another one.&nbsp; And those are the conversations that the Vice President is really &#8212; in her meeting with President López Obrador, they talked about not just the trade relationship, but how to make sure that we&#8217;re investing in communities that &#8212; to ensure that we&#8217;re tackling together inequality, investing in Central America, and addressing the root causes of migration through various tools, including economic opportunity.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; My first question is for [senior administration official].&nbsp; (Inaudible) economic insecurity and inequality, can you provide a concrete example of how exactly you plan on addressing that?&nbsp; For example, are you thinking about cash-based transfers?</p>



<p>And then a question for [senior administration official]: In terms of the strategy that you mentioned, how much of that is based on enforcement south of our border?&nbsp; Are you sending more DHS personnel?&nbsp; And how do you anticipate addressing those migrants who have to leave the region, urgently?&nbsp; For example, as you know with asylum seekers, they sometimes have to leave within a 24-hour window, if less.&nbsp; So how does this strategy address those migrants?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, Priscilla, great to hear from you.&nbsp; We can get you specific programs, but I think when we&#8217;re trying to address issues of inequality and economic opportunity, it&#8217;s the whole package.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s not just working on, you know, for example, investing in opportunity for women and girls by promoting entrepreneurship.&nbsp; Others are, obviously, tackling corruption in these countries and engaging with civil society so that we&#8217;re trying to level the playing field so that prosperity is determined not &#8212; not by where you&#8217;re born, but rather your &#8212; your work ethic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so there are a series of programs that we’re undertaking, but it&#8217;s more than just U.S. assistance.&nbsp; It’s making sure that we&#8217;re working closely with the private sector.&nbsp; We&#8217;re actually working with foundations to have a coordinated approach to how we tackle some of these issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also, frankly, the &#8212; separate from foreign assistance, because no amount of foreign assistance is going to make a difference if these governments actually aren&#8217;t demonstrating political will &#8212; is making some very, sometimes, asks of these governments that may go against their own political interests on matters of corruption, on specific legislation, and a series of things that we&#8217;ve engaged on with all these governments and that are, I think, for us, part of the arrangement that if we&#8217;re going to make an argument for the U.S. taxpayer to support something like this, that the countries of the region are not just contributing their share, but also taking stepping up and advancing necessary reforms. &nbsp;</p>



<p>On the Haiti question, I&#8217;m going to ask my colleague to address just those migrants with an urgent need.&nbsp; So, right now, the &#8212; and you saw that the Special Envoy Dan Foote was announced last week.&nbsp; We went to Haiti a second time for the funeral of Moïse.&nbsp; Our focus is &#8212; is in a couple areas.</p>



<p>Number one is everything we can do to support the investigation.&nbsp; And so, we have, right now, these eight agents, including FBI, DHS, that are doing everything from tracing the weapons, cellphones, and the equipment of those individuals involved in the attack &#8212; in assassination of President Moïse.</p>



<p>And the second one is: What can we do to support Haitians and the Haitian National Police &#8212; their security needs?&nbsp; So, we have a list of requests that they&#8217;ve made.&nbsp; And Special Envoy Foote has &#8212; in the course of the meeting, they just came back &#8212; has been trying to figure out, in terms of the asks and actually needs assessment, what &#8212; you know, what we can actually do to be most responsive so that we&#8217;re supporting Haitian solutions to Haitian challenges, as opposed to, you know, coming as the United States and being prescriptive.</p>



<p>And so that includes the Department of Homeland Security, Homeland Security Investigations.&nbsp; We have the FBI, DEA, (inaudible) DOJ.&nbsp; But also, USAID is very actively engaged.&nbsp; We have a program with the World Food Program and doing an assessment of what more we can actually do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last point on this is that we have &#8212; we are working to expand U.S. aid of $6 million that they&#8217;re investing to expand our vaccination sites from 3 to 10.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re in almost every different department in Haiti, and we&#8217;re working very actively to finalize the distribution of the 500,000 Moderna vaccines.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also looking to see what more we can do to support &#8212; combat the pandemic in Haiti.</p>



<p>And so that, for us, is a kind of broad strategy, and the focus here is also to promote a broad and inclusive dialogue that includes civil society, as we&#8217;re trying to do everything we can to support the Haitian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Thank you so much.&nbsp; On your question on how do we address people with urgent needs that needs to need access to protection right away, I think you hit on one of the biggest challenges with this.&nbsp; You know, with traditional resettlement, we know that it can often take a few years.&nbsp; And with Central America, frankly, there haven&#8217;t even been enough resettlement slots.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re looking to not only expand the number of refugee admissions to the United States and to other countries, but look at ways in which we can address, sort of, you know, chokepoints in the resettlement process and ways that we can &#8212; you know, while upholding the integrity and the security elements of the program, you know, that we can &#8212; that we can make sure that we&#8217;re able to process people more quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there&#8217;s the Protection Transfer Arrangement in Costa Rica that is a way that people can be evacuated quickly &#8212; how can we expand that.&nbsp; And then, that&#8217;s, I think, where other countries that neighbor Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador really come in.&nbsp; We can &#8212; if we can expand complementary forms of protection to neighboring countries, I think that also can create an important &#8212; an important way that people can get somewhere safe quickly.&nbsp; So looking at temporary protection &#8212; you know, temporary protection programs that might be possible in Mexico or, you know, other countries in the neighborhood.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we hear you on that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s, I think, a really &#8212; a big challenge, but something that we&#8217;re seeking to try to address wholeheartedly through this strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Unfortunately, we&#8217;re out of time, but, again, we want to thank our participants and our speakers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, the ground rules: This call is on background and the contents of the call as well as the factsheet that we&#8217;ll send out later tonight is embargoed until 6:00 a.m. tomorrow or White House release.&nbsp; Our speakers will be referred to as “senior administration officials” for the purpose of the call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you have any additional questions, feel free to email me or email the NSC Press distro at <a href="mailto:DL.NSC.Press@nsc.eop.gov">DL.NSC.Press@nsc.eop.gov</a>.</p>



<p>Thank you all so much.&nbsp; Have a good day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:33 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
