<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 03:11:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Briefing on the Vice President&#8217;s Events in Munich,&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/18/background-press-briefing-on-the-vice-presidents-events-in-munich-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 03:11:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Munich, Germany AIDE:&#160; (Inaudible) on background with a senior administration official, and embargoed until the end of the conversation.&#160; And it’s just going to be [senior administration official]. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; This conversation. AIDE:&#160; Embargoed until the end of this conversation, on background with a senior administration official. So, [senior administration official] will give some opening thoughts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Munich, Germany </em></p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; (Inaudible) on background with a senior administration official, and embargoed until the end of the conversation.&nbsp; And it’s just going to be [senior administration official].<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This conversation.<br><br>AIDE:&nbsp; Embargoed until the end of this conversation, on background with a senior administration official.<br><br>So, [senior administration official] will give some opening thoughts and then happy to take questions.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, let me just sort of do a brief overview and walk you a little bit through the events of today and the plans for tomorrow.<br><br>But in the context of this overall trip &#8212; in the context of the overall trip, I think we already talked about a little bit, is that the context of this administration&#8217;s approach to this crisis and approach to our alliances and partnerships in general, which we stress was key to this administration&#8217;s foreign policy from the start.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s moments like these that they become particularly important.&nbsp;<br><br>And you&#8217;ve seen, I think in the recent weeks and days, a very deliberate, intentional, coordinated, and clear rollout on how we&#8217;re approaching this crisis.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard it multiple times from the President, from the Secretary of State, from the Secretary of Defense, and the Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>And she came here as part of that overall approach to this crisis to do a number of things: to continue the process of consulting as we continue to flesh out our response to Russia&#8217;s aggression and threats of aggression; coordinating that with our close partners in Europe who are involved in this; and delivering the message that we&#8217;ve been delivering all along to them &#8212; one of support and solidarity and commitment to some core principles, and to the Russians that we are and continue to be ready for diplomacy &#8212; and we put a lot of ideas on the table &#8212; but we&#8217;re also determined to respond as we need to respond and impose costs if they go ahead and continue with the further invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>So this is part of a real administration-wide process of consultation with our close allies.&nbsp;<br><br>So it was, in that context, fitting that her first meeting of the day was with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg.&nbsp; There are a lot of elements to our response, and they&#8217;re not only military and defensive and deterrence, but they include that.&nbsp; And NATO has been a big part of the response to Russia&#8217;s activities.&nbsp;<br><br>And she used this opportunity with the Secretary General to further coordinate how we as an Alliance of 30 countries are responding.&nbsp; And so they talked about some of what we&#8217;ve already done and some of what we might need to do in the future.&nbsp; And you know &#8212; we&#8217;ve already talked about some of the force posture adjustments we&#8217;ve made to reinforce our Allies to which we have Article 5 commitments in NATO.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve done a lot of that, including sending troops from the United States &#8212; further troops from the United States to Europe, and also what we&#8217;ve done for Ukraine, including the $650 million of defense assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>And she thanked the Secretary General for his leadership over the past eight years.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been a stalwart friend of the United States and a great leader of this Alliance and is called upon to lead at a really difficult time.&nbsp;<br><br>So they talked about Alliance unity, the way forward.&nbsp; I mentioned force posture adjustments and also the diplomacy.&nbsp; You saw that we, as recently as Secretary Blinken&#8217;s speech &#8212; either yesterday or the day before; it&#8217;s hard to even keep track &#8212; at the U.N. said that we&#8217;re still ready to meet and proposed a meeting with Russian Foreign Minister Lavrov.&nbsp; NATO has done the same &#8212; the Secretary for NATO-Russia Council.&nbsp;<br><br>So this was a real opportunity to coordinate on all those fronts, diplomatic and military.&nbsp;<br><br>Following a meeting with Secretary General Stoltenberg, she met with the three leaders of the Baltic states &#8212; Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.&nbsp; It was really important for her in that meeting &#8212; for the Vice President &#8212; to underscore our enduring and unshakable commitment to NATO’s Article 5.&nbsp; These are among the Allies who are most concerned about that because they feel the threat themselves directly, and not least from the massive Russian military presence in Belarus.&nbsp; And so she reassured them that the United States means what it says when it says it&#8217;s committed to Article 5.<br><br>And they, together, discussed some of the same themes from the meeting with the NATO Secretary General &#8212; the force posture adjustments that we made, the further troops and equipment that we&#8217;ve sent to Europe to, as we&#8217;ve said many times, be ready for any contingency.<br><br>The Vice President also discussed with them the issue of costs, which we all in this Alliance agree on it, if Russia goes in further.&nbsp; And that requires coordination of economic sanctions, which has been a priority for us as well.&nbsp; These are members of the European Union, and their role in that will be important.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, finally, she had a meeting with a bipartisan delegation from Congress &#8212; I think we&#8217;ve put out some information about that already &#8212; but delegations led by Speaker Pelosi and Senators Graham and Whitehouse &#8212; bipartisan, bicameral.<br><br>The Vice President, as a sort of a tradition at the Munich Security Conference, took the opportunity to meet with them.&nbsp;&nbsp;And that was not only useful to see them and discuss some of the issues, but to demonstrate that our approach to this crisis is really a bipartisan one.&nbsp; There are plenty of divisions in Washington on plenty of issues.&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s fair to say when it comes to standing up to Russia and its aggression, we&#8217;re quite unified.&nbsp; And that was a really important message and is an important message that the Vice President here is here leading our delegation.&nbsp; And there are important members of both houses of Congress here as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Sorry to go on for so long, but maybe a couple of things about tomorrow, and then after we&#8217;ll take a few questions.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the main element of tomorrow&#8217;s program is her speech to the Munich Security Conference.&nbsp; I think, as I mentioned before, you know, you&#8217;ve heard from other senior people in this administration, starting with the President &#8212; and you&#8217;ll see, I think, her speech fit into the message that we&#8217;ve been sending from the start of this crisis: that we are preparing for either contingency, diplomacy or a response &#8212; a tough response, as necessary.&nbsp;<br><br>We have been putting the world on notice of what we&#8217;re afraid of and seeing from the Russians &#8212; these provocations that we fear that they could use as a pretext for invading Ukraine.&nbsp; And in the past hours and days, unfortunately, we have seen some of those.<br><br>The Vice President &#8212; I think you can expect her to articulate some core themes.&nbsp; And I (inaudible) get into too much detail about the speech, but she will no doubt articulate some important themes, including “strength through unity.”&nbsp; The whole point of meeting with these close Allies is that we&#8217;re stronger when we&#8217;re acting together.&nbsp;<br><br>I think she&#8217;ll underscore some of the core principles that are at stake here &#8212; you know, not least that: One country simply can&#8217;t decide it&#8217;s just going to invade another country and violate the sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; It’s a core principle of NATO and many other organizations in which we’re a part, and certainly one that we believe in and the Vice President strongly believes in.<br><br>She will make clear, as we have been making clear for days and weeks and months, that we remain, even at this late hour, open to diplomacy.&nbsp; But if the Russians reject that diplomacy that we have offered, that will be a sign that they weren&#8217;t really serious about it.<br><br>I think you can expect the Vice President to be clear about the costs that would be imposed on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been pretty clear that those (inaudible) will include significant, severe, and swift financial sanctions and export controls that will be very costly to Russia and weaken Russia.&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s, in fact, one of the core points that, regardless of what happens, we, in this Alliance, believe we will emerge stronger and Russia will emerge weaker.&nbsp;<br><br>Then, the rest of the schedule I think we discussed on the call the other day: a bilateral meeting with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine, a bilateral meeting with Chancellor Scholz of Germany.&nbsp; And then a number of other, you know, what we call “pull-asides” with a number of other leaders &#8212; world leaders in town that she will be meeting with.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have a list for you, frankly, simply because the schedule, like the world is, is in flux.&nbsp; And we haven&#8217;t set a final schedule, but you can be sure there&#8217;ll be a number of other world leaders that she’ll spend some time with &#8212; once again, because &#8212; going back to the core point that we&#8217;re stronger when we&#8217;re together, this whole trip is about coordinating with key partners.<br><br>AIDE:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Let’s open it up to questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we &#8212; you mentioned the conversations today with the Baltic leaders and commitment to Article 5.&nbsp; They also were asked for a greater U.S. presence.&nbsp; (Inaudible) pretty blunt, and I thought that the wording was strong about “we&#8217;ve lost our freedom to Russia once; we don&#8217;t want to do it again” &#8212; is what Estonia&#8217;s Prime Minister said.&nbsp;<br><br>What commitments are you guys ready to make to them? &nbsp;And in the case of Lithuania, they formally asked to go from the rotational presence to something more permanent.&nbsp; Is this just necessary at this point in the world we live in for there to be a bigger and more permanent presence on the eastern flank?<br><br>And then, secondly, on Zelenskyy, is there any concern tomorrow about him coming, even if it&#8217;s just for several hours, to be seen outside of Ukraine at such a fluid and difficult time?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first, I don’t have any new announcements on force posture in Europe beyond those that, you know, our administration has already announced.&nbsp; Because I did say that we have adjusted force posture.&nbsp; And we do that to be ready for any contingency, and that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what we remain determined to do.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know, there is already NATO force posture presence in the Baltic states: battalions announced &#8212; rotational battalions after 2014, and also Baltic Air Policing, where NATO countries help them patrol the airspace.&nbsp;<br><br>But I think you will find that our force posture &#8212; we have said: If Russia further invades Ukraine, then we will continue to look at the force posture that is necessary to make sure Article 5 is preserved, protected, and all of our countries can be defended.&nbsp;<br><br>On Zelenskyy, I don&#8217;t have anything to announce that we announced the other day.&nbsp; I think you probably saw that his spokesman put out a statement that they were considering their trip, so I can only refer you to the Ukrainians as to President Zelenskyy’s plans about being in Munich.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any concern about him coming?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; What is important is that we continue our dialogue with the Ukrainians and continue to demonstrate support for the Ukrainians.<br><br>President Biden has spoken a number of times with President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken has been in Kyiv.&nbsp; We have, as a government, engaged very closely to demonstrate our support for Ukraine in this situation.&nbsp;<br><br>And when President Zelenskyy said he was going to be in Munich, this was another opportunity to continue that dialogue.&nbsp;&nbsp;And if he&#8217;s here, the Vice President will be &#8212; it will be an important opportunity for her to engage with him.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there is no effort to ask or encourage Zelenskyy not to leave Ukraine?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s really his call.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really up to him where he feels he needs to be.&nbsp; If he&#8217;s in Munich, the Vice President will look forward to meeting with him.&nbsp; If he decides he needs to be in Ukraine, we&#8217;ll find other ways of engaging with him to keep on the dialogue that we&#8217;ve had from the start.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up also on the Lithuanian &#8212;&nbsp;I mean, that was a very public request.&nbsp; It was made very directly to Vice President Harris about the permanent troops.&nbsp; I mean, what do you &#8212; what do you make of just the fact that it&#8217;s such a public request?&nbsp; I mean, is it &#8212; is that &#8212; you mentioned things will change if there&#8217;s invasion.&nbsp; Does that mean permanent rotation is under consideration?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; What it means is that we have had and continue to have a very fruitful and, I think, satisfactory dialogue with all of our NATO partners, including &#8212; or, you might even say, especially &#8212; the Baltic states in recent weeks and months about force posture, and we’ll continue to do so.<br><br>Secretary Austin was just at the NATO defense ministerial in Brussels.&nbsp; He then went on to Poland and is going to Lithuania to continue this discussion of what is the best and right force posture for the United States and NATO in Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t have anything beyond that to say except that, obviously, we&#8217;re constantly looking at what we need to do to defend all of our NATO Allies.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know, has President Putin &#8212; has President Putin made up his mind on whether to attack or not?&nbsp; Does the U.S. believe he knows now what he&#8217;s going to do?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I think you&#8217;ve heard us be pretty clear that we don&#8217;t try to figure out what&#8217;s in his mind.&nbsp; All we can do is watch what we’re watching.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, no determination has been made yet on whether he plans to attack or not, at this point?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We can&#8217;t know what&#8217;s in his head.&nbsp; We can’t know what’s in his head.&nbsp; We just have to prepare for what &#8212; you know, we have noted what we feared could precede an invasion as being alleged provocations and what could be a pretext.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing some of those things which are a great cause for concern.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why our diplomacy that the Vice President is leading here in Munich has been intensified.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not going to guess what&#8217;s in President Putin’s mind.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of quick questions.&nbsp; President Putin obviously did a news conference earlier today in which he sort of brushed off, you know, the threat of &#8212;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;I’m sorry, what news conference?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Putin did a news conference earlier today, which you’re obviously aware of, but there he spoke about sort of how the West always finds a pretext to impose sanctions on Moscow.&nbsp; So, essentially, kind of brushing off the threat that has been sort of the cornerstone of the, you know, the U.S. strategy.&nbsp;<br><br>How concerned are you that, you know, this has kind of failed to really deter him in the past?&nbsp; Do you &#8212; do you really think that that&#8217;s going to happen this time?<br><br>And also, separately, the Russian Defense Ministry said that he&#8217;s going to oversee nuclear drills in Russia on Saturday.&nbsp; Do you consider that to be a concerning sign &#8212; a sign of escalation?&nbsp; How &#8212; you know, how are you thinking about, sort of, Putin looking at nuclear drills in Russia in this situation?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first, you know, look, obviously there are no guarantees.&nbsp; All we can do is make clear that there will be severe costs if Russia decides to further invade Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also made clear, because you alluded to him saying that &#8220;they&#8217;ve put sanctions on us before&#8221;&nbsp;&#8212; which is true; we have done for other violations &#8212; we&#8217;ve made clear that these sanctions would go well beyond anything we&#8217;ve done in the past.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve put on some significant sanctions not just in 2014 after the invasion of Ukraine and annexation of parts of southeastern Ukraine and the annexation of Crimea, but well beyond anything we&#8217;ve done since then.&nbsp;<br><br>And I mention that that will include very severe financial sanctions, coordinated with our European allies, and export controls to weaken Russia&#8217;s industrial base, defense industrial base.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we hope President Putin really takes that to heart and gets that message, because if he thinks somehow invading or occupying Ukraine will strengthen Russia, we believe we&#8217;re going to demonstrate through these actions the opposite is the case.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;re confident that this is going to act as a deterrent?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;re confident that this is going to act as a deterrent?&nbsp; Everything you have planned, in terms of export controls and sanctions, that is going to deter him this time around?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not making any predictions about it.&nbsp; I’m just describing what the thinking behind what we&#8217;re doing is.&nbsp; We&#8217;re bolstering Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;re reinforcing our NATO Allies in Europe to make sure they&#8217;re safe.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to hit Russia with very severe economic costs if it goes in, while also saying, to this day: We are ready for and prefer a different path, which is diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;m not making any predictions.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just describing what we&#8217;re conveying with the hope that it will lead the Russians to see that they are better off and we are all better off if they choose the course of diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And could you please answer my question on the nuclear drills?&nbsp; The &#8212; you know, that the Defense Ministry said is going to happen tomorrow and Putin is going to actually be overseeing them.&nbsp; Do you think that is &#8212; would you classify that as escalation?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I think &#8212; obviously, in the context like this with so many military forces deployed and lots of tensions in the region, I think it&#8217;s fair to say that adding on top of that with nuclear and other strategic exercises is escalatory and unfortunate.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, can you talk about the coordination or whatever between the Vice President and the Secretary of State?&nbsp; Are they talking?&nbsp; Are they meeting regularly?&nbsp; Are they kind of staying in their own lane and all of that stuff?<br><br>And a second question: I wonder &#8212; one of the things that President Biden did was sort of speak directly to the Russian people, you know, in some of his speeches over the last week.&nbsp; I wonder if the Vice President plans to do something similar to issue a message or (inaudible) directly to the Russian people, directly to Putin in her speech, or whenever.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the latter, I&#8217;ll leave that to the speech.&nbsp; I described some of the key themes I thought &#8212; I think you can expect her to address.&nbsp; But I won&#8217;t preempt the speech further on that particular point.&nbsp;<br><br>Although, you know, we do think it&#8217;s important &#8212; and that&#8217;s why the President embraced it &#8212; and that&#8217;s, you know, linked to this issue of costs as well, because we want the Russian people to know this is not against the Russian people.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to defend Ukraine against an invasion, and have no ill will towards the Russian people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we prefer diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>As for the Vice President and Secretary Blinken: Yes, they are in extraordinarily close contact.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve met several times today, in fact &#8212; or at least a couple of times &#8212; including a private meeting this morning to coordinate and work together on how we&#8217;re going to advance our &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Blinken.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The VP.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The Vice President and Secretary Blinken (inaudible).<br><br>And so, you know, I actually began by talking about how, we as an administration, have been rolling out a deliberate, intentional, coordinated strategy with multiple actors doing multiple things as part of the same team, and that&#8217;s what this deployment to Munich is.<br><br>I mentioned the Vice President has had and will continue to have a number of bilateral meetings with her counterparts &#8212; as mentioned, the two presidents and prime minister of the Baltic states, Chancellor Scholz, Secretary General of NATO, and President Zelenskyy.&nbsp;<br><br>And Secretary Blinken has had and will continue to have numerous contacts with his foreign minister counterparts, both bilaterally and multilaterally.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we are &#8212; you know, in the context of what I mentioned about being here and coordinating, and, you know, this is all about strength, unity, dialogue, and coordination.&nbsp; That &#8212; you know, their activities here are a core part of that approach.<br><br>But, absolutely intimately in contact with each other, including, as I mentioned, discussions throughout the day.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you share &#8212; can you share anything of what they&#8217;ve talked about or specifics, like how, specifically, does he guide her &#8212; whether it&#8217;s in a specific meeting or a specific question, or is it more as a sounding board?&nbsp; I just want to understand it better.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, they&#8217;re implementing the same strategy.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve described &#8212; we&#8217;ve all described what we&#8217;re doing here: coordinating a joint approach with Europeans on sanctions, if it comes to that; looking together with our NATO partners on force posture adjustments; and discussing our support for Ukraine, which is not just military, but the sovereign loan guarantee.&nbsp; And so, they are implementing the exact same policy set by the President, and they&#8217;re doing it together.&nbsp;<br><br>AIDE:&nbsp; We have time, folks, for two more questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the SWIFT &#8212;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Let’s go to Molly.&nbsp; She hasn’t had a chance.&nbsp; And then come back to Jennifer.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the (inaudible) reports of the Russian separatists reporting mass evacuations and signaling that there&#8217;s a possible explosion that &#8212; a lot of reports coming out of that region.&nbsp;<br><br>You talked about the Vice President being willing to talk about some of these false-flag efforts in her speech.&nbsp; How specific do you expect her to get?&nbsp; And does the United States believe that these reports of mass evacuations that we&#8217;re seeing are part of a false-flag effort that are starting and could, perhaps, lead to a full-scale invasion by Russia?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m just not sure I specifically said she would talk about that in her speech.&nbsp; If I did, maybe I misspoke, because what I was suggesting is that that has been the predicate to her speech.&nbsp; Like, she&#8217;s giving a speech at a moment when we&#8217;ve already warned that we&#8217;re going to see a potential pretext for an invasion, and we&#8217;ve already started to do that.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s like where we are at the moment she&#8217;s giving her speech.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s been important to do that in advance because we&#8217;ve seen it play out.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as for confirming &#8212; I think I mentioned the other day when we talked about this &#8212; you know, this approach of throwing spaghetti at the wall.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve alleged many, many different things, most of which we can&#8217;t confirm.&nbsp; And that is concerning because they are all potentially in that category of things that they&#8217;re going to point to.&nbsp;<br><br>So you mentioned the specific one of evacuations.&nbsp; That&#8217;s troubling, as are the allegations of shelling and missile deployments and many of the other things that they have alleged that we&#8217;re not able to confirm, which makes us worry that this is part of what we were afraid of: that they&#8217;re coming up with some pretext for using force against Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any update on the troop levels?&nbsp; You know, since the 7,000, have there been &#8212; has the administration seen any additional troops come in the last &#8212; I guess, was it &#8212; has it been 24 hours since the 7,000?&nbsp; Or 48 hours?&nbsp; Does &#8212; do the numbers continue to rise?&nbsp; Are there more signs on the border of a potential invasion? &nbsp;<br><br>And also, you mentioned about seriousness of diplomacy.&nbsp; Does the administration now feel or is it increasingly feeling that Russia is not interested in diplomacy?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first, I won&#8217;t go beyond.&nbsp; I think the President, you know, yesterday said something about, you know, upwards of 150,000 troops.&nbsp; We do &#8212; we have been clear that we are not seeing the withdrawals that they are claiming.&nbsp; In fact, the 7,000 you refer to is &#8212; not only did we not see the withdrawals, but we saw an additional 7,000, and we have not seen withdrawals (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But have you seen increases since then?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don’t have any increases to announce here.<br><br>And the second part of your question is on diplomacy?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About diplomacy.&nbsp; And does the United States &#8212; you know, Harris said it’s up to &#8212; the onus is on Russia to take diplomacy seriously.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the consideration that &#8212; does the United States now acknowledge or think that Russia is not taking it seriously &#8212; diplomacy?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The next few days will tell us a lot.&nbsp; I think you heard Secretary Blinken at the United Nations the other day make that clear that he is ready to meet his counterpart.&nbsp; NATO did the same &#8212; the NATO-Russia Council.<br><br>If Russia invades, notwithstanding our offers to continue to talk following these specific things we put on the table in terms of diplomacy, I think we would be forced by that to conclude that Russia is not ready for diplomacy.&nbsp; That would be the sign.&nbsp; But until that happens, we’re still (inaudible), because that’s a far preferable approach for everybody.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And until that happens, can you not rule out that they are not willing to find some sort of diplomatic &#8212; I mean, it seems like we’ve been in this pattern, the status quo, for a while.&nbsp; The administration is saying that, you know, they’re poised to do something at any time.&nbsp; It’s been a couple weeks.&nbsp; Things haven’t happened.&nbsp; And I guess the question is, sort of &#8212; it seems like by saying you’re not closing the door, that you are leaving some room open for them to still come to the table and do that in a substantive way.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We are.&nbsp; The space has gotten narrower and narrower over time, with the troop buildup and the rejection of some of the specific ideas we put on the table.&nbsp; But we are not ruling it out.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in terms of what Putin said today about being willing to negotiate but needing the West and the U.S. to take seriously all of their demands, obviously the sticking point with NATO on foreclosing Ukraine’s membership in NATO is not somewhere that you’re going to go.&nbsp; Do you think that this can &#8211; that there can be some kind of, you know, point of compromise here?&nbsp; Or are both sides kind of talking past one another?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We continue to be ready to test the proposition.&nbsp; When the Russians first put their ideas forward, we said that some of them were non-starters but others provided a basis for discussion, and we proposed those discussions then and we continue to propose them now.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the SWIFT financial system, Daleep Singh at the briefing did say that that probably will not be part of the initial package of sanctions.&nbsp; Can you maybe explain a little bit why?&nbsp; Why wouldn’t the SWIFT &#8212; yanking them from SWIFT be part of the initial part of the sanctions?&nbsp; Is that something the VP is still talking with folks about?&nbsp; Was it because the Allies just were not quite comfortable with it for various reasons, which are understandable?&nbsp; Or can you just explain that a little?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I won’t go beyond what Daleep said about SWIFT, but I will say that coordinating specific sanctions with the Europeans remains a core part of our approach and remains part of the diplomacy that the Vice President is doing here in Munich.&nbsp;<br><br>We believe we are already quite united and are determined to be as united as possible.&nbsp; And this is something the Vice President has already brought up and will continue to bring up with our key partners in Europe.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, just had a quick last question on Anne, during the briefing in the White House, where she attributed the cyberattack on Ukraine on Russia.&nbsp; I was just wondering if you can give us any details on how the U.S. plan &#8212; or Allies plan to sort of respond to that.&nbsp; Are you planning to retaliate?&nbsp; I mean, how do you take that from here on?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I’ll have to leave that with what Anne had already to say about it, you know, except maybe to say: Obviously, cyber is part of this (inaudible) of things that we’re concerned about.&nbsp; We have heard that and the Vice President has heard it from partners here in Europe.&nbsp; You know that the Baltic states, Estonia in particular, has been the subject of cyberattacks.&nbsp;<br><br>So the only thing I would add is to just underscore that we obviously take that seriously as a part of the things that we’re going to speak about.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it fair to say the speech has been evolving because of all these &#8212; the attacks and everything over the last few days?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; It’s fair to say that we have taken a consistent approach.&nbsp; Obviously, there’s &#8212; it’s a fluid situation and new developments, and you always take those into account when you’re doing a speech.&nbsp; But I think you’ll find that the speech fits squarely into the consistent approach that this administration has been taking for weeks and months now.&nbsp; And it’s just one more part of this important project.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Providing an Update on Russia and&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/18/remarks-by-president-biden-providing-an-update-on-russia-and-ukraine-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 4:54 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Today, I made two vital calls, as I&#8217;ve been making for some months now &#8212; two vital calls that &#8212; on the situation in Russia and Ukraine.&#160; The first was to a bipartisan group of members of Congress who are currently representing the United States, along&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>4:54 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Today, I made two vital calls, as I&#8217;ve been making for some months now &#8212; two vital calls that &#8212; on the situation in Russia and Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first was to a bipartisan group of members of Congress who are currently representing the United States, along with Vice President Harris at the Munich Security Conference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second was the latest in a series of calls over the past many months with the heads of state of our NATO Allies and the European Union to bring them up to date on what the United States thinks is the current state of affairs, and what&#8217;s likely to happen in Ukraine in the coming days, to ensure that we continue to remain in lockstep &#8212; that is the European Union and NATO.</p>



<p>Despite Russia&#8217;s efforts to divide us at home and abroad, I can affirm that has not happened.&nbsp; The overwhelming message of both &#8212; on both calls was one of unity, determination, and resolve.&nbsp; I shared with all of those on the calls what we know about a rapidly escalating crisis in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Over the last few days, we&#8217;ve seen reports of a major uptick in violations of the ceasefire by Russian-backed fighters attempting to provoke Ukraine in the Donbas.&nbsp; For example, a shelling of a Ukrainian kindergarten yesterday, which Russia has falsely asserted was carried out by Ukraine.&nbsp; We also continue to see more and more disinformation being pushed out by &#8212; to the Russian public, including the Russian-backed separatists, claiming that Ukraine is planning to launch a massive offensive attack in the Donbas.</p>



<p>Well, look, there is simply no evidence of these assertions, and it and devies [sic] &#8212; it defies basic logic to believe the Ukrainians would choose this moment, with well over 150,000 troops arrayed on its borders, to escalate a year-long conflict.</p>



<p>Russia state media also continues to make phony allegations of a genocide taking place in the Donbas and push fabricated claims warning about Ukraine’s attack on Russia without any evidence.&nbsp; That&#8217;s just what I&#8217;m sure Ukraine is thinking of doing &#8212; attacking Russia.</p>



<p>All these are consistent with the playbook the Russians have used before: to set up a false justification to act against Ukraine.&nbsp; This is also in line with the pretext scenarios that the United States and our Allies and partners have been warning about for weeks.</p>



<p>Throughout these tense moments, the Ukrainian forces have shown great judgment and, I might add, restraint.&nbsp; They’ve refused to allow the Russians to bait them into war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the fact remains: Russian troops currently have Ukraine surrounded &#8212; from Belarus, along the Russian border with Ukraine, to the Black Sea in the south &#8212; and all of its border.</p>



<p>You know, look, we have reason to believe the Russian forces are planning to and intend to attack Ukraine in the coming week &#8212; in the coming days.&nbsp; We believe that they will target Ukraine&#8217;s capital, Kyiv, a city of 2.8 million innocent people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re calling out Russia’s plans loudly and repeatedly, not because we want a conflict, but because we&#8217;re doing everything in our power to remove any reason that Russia may give to justify invading Ukraine and prevent them from moving.</p>



<p>Make no mistake: If Russia pursues its plans, it will be responsible for a catastrophic and needless war of choice.&nbsp; The United States and our Allies are prepared to defend every inch of NATO territory from any threat to our collective security as well.</p>



<p>We also will not send troops in to fight in Ukraine, but we will continue to support the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This past year, the United States provided a record amount of security assistance to Ukraine to bolster its defensive &#8212; $650 million, from Javelin missiles to ammunition.</p>



<p>And we also previously provided $500 million in Ukrai- &#8212; in humanitarian aid and economic support for Ukraine.&nbsp; And earlier this week, we also announced an additional sovereign loan guarantee of up to $1 billion to strengthen Ukraine&#8217;s economic resilience.</p>



<p>But the bottom line is this: The United States and our Allies and partners will support the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; We will hold Russia accountable for its actions.&nbsp; The West is united and resolved.&nbsp; We&#8217;re ready to impose severe sanctions on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.</p>



<p>But I say again: Russia can still choose diplomacy.&nbsp; It is not too late to de-escalate and return to the negotiating table.</p>



<p>Last night, Russia agreed that Secretary of State Blinken and Foreign Minister Lavrov should meet on Feb- &#8212; on February 24th &#8212; February 24th in Europe.</p>



<p>But if Russia takes military action before that date, it will be clear that they have slammed the door shut on diplomacy.&nbsp; They will have &#8212; they will have chosen war, and they will pay a steep price for doing so &#8212; not only from the sanctions that we and our allies will impose on Russia, but the moral outrage that the rest of the world will visit upon them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there are many issues that divide our nation and our world, but standing up to Russian aggression is not one of them.&nbsp; The American people are united.&nbsp; Europe is united.&nbsp; The transatlantic community is united.&nbsp; Our political parties in this country are united.&nbsp; The entire free world is united.</p>



<p>Russia has a choice between war and all the suffering it will bring or diplomacy that will make a future safer for everyone.</p>



<p>Now I&#8217;m happy to take a few questions.&nbsp; Nancy from Bloomberg.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, sir.&nbsp; Do you think that it is wise for President Zelenskyy to leave Ukraine if an invasion is as imminent as the U.S. says it is?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a judgment for him to make and a determination as to whether or not.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve spoken with Zelenskyy a dozen times &#8212; maybe more, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it&#8217;s &#8212; and in the pursuit of a diplomatic solution, it may not be fal- &#8212; it may be the wise choice.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s his decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you have any indication about whether President Putin has made a decision on whether to invade?&nbsp; Do you feel confident that he &#8212; that he hasn&#8217;t made that decision already?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; As of this moment, I&#8217;m convinced he&#8217;s made the decision.&nbsp; We have reason to believe that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There seems to be a unanimity, a spirit to do &#8212; between the United States and Europe to do some sanctions &#8212; comprehensive sanctions.&nbsp; But are &#8212; is everyone on board with the exact same sanctions that you want to do?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; There will be some slight differences, but none &#8212; there will be more add-ons than subtractions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And President Putin is going to oversee some nuclear drills this weekend.&nbsp; How do you see that happening?&nbsp; What&#8217;s your reaction to that, sir?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think he is remotely contemplating nuclear &#8212; using nuclear weapons.&nbsp; But I do think it&#8217;s &#8212; I think he is focused on trying to convince the world that he has the ability to change the dynamics in Europe in a way that he cannot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t &#8212; how much of it is a cover for just saying, &#8220;We&#8217;re just doing exercises&#8221; and there&#8217;s more than that, I just can&#8217;t &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to read his mind.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To be clear &#8212; to be clear, you are convinced &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll &#8212; I&#8217;ll take some.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you are convinced &#8212; you are convinced that President Putin is going to invade Ukraine?&nbsp; Is that what you just said a few moments ago?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, I did.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, is diplomacy off the table then?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; There&#8217;s always &#8212; until he does, diplomacy is always a possibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What reason do you have to believe he is considering that option at all?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have a significant intelligence capability.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>5:03 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology Anne Neuberger, and Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics and Deputy NEC Director Daleep Singh, February 18,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/18/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-cyber-and-emerging-technology-anne-neuberger-and-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-international-economics-and-dep/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:43 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Friday.&#160; Okay, so we have two special guests with us today.&#160; Joining us are Deputy National Security Advisors Anne Neuberger and Daleep Singh. By way of a quick introduction, Anne is Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology.&#160; Previously,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:43 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Friday.&nbsp; Okay, so we have two special guests with us today.&nbsp; Joining us are Deputy National Security Advisors Anne Neuberger and Daleep Singh.</p>



<p>By way of a quick introduction, Anne is Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology.&nbsp; Previously, she served as the National Security Agency’s Director of Cybersecurity, where she led the NSA’s cybersecurity mission.</p>



<p>Prior to this role, Anne led NSA’s election security effort and served as Assistant Deputy Director of NSA’s Operations Directorate, overseeing foreign intelligence and cybersecurity operations.</p>



<p>Daleep is Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics and Deputy Director of the National Economic Council.&nbsp; He coordinates the administration’s policymaking process for a range of issues at the intersection of economic policy and national security.</p>



<p>Previously, he was the Executive Vice President and Head of the Markets Group at the New York Federal Reserve, where he led the implementation for most of the Fed’s emergency facilities launched during the pandemic.</p>



<p>He served as an Acting Assistant Secretary for Domestic Finance at the Treasury Department during the Obama-Biden administration, as well as a Deputy Assistant Secretary for International Affairs.</p>



<p>They will each give brief remarks, and then we&#8217;ll take some questions.&nbsp; Your introduction won&#8217;t be as fancy the second time you come, but &#8212;</p>



<p>So, I think Anne is starting, right?</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Jen.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good to see you all.</p>



<p>Over the last decade, Russia has used cyber as a major part of its military activity beyond its borders, including to undermine, coerce, and destabilize Ukraine.&nbsp; For that reason, and at the President’s direction, we&#8217;ve been working to prepare for potential cyberattacks since November.&nbsp; We’ve been focused on doing so in three ways:</p>



<p>First, we&#8217;ve continued our urgent work to shore up our cyber defenses at home.&nbsp; Second, we&#8217;ve boosted our efforts providing support to Ukraine.&nbsp; And third, we&#8217;ve worked closely with partners and Allies to defend against and disrupt malicious cyber activity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ll expand on each of these three areas.</p>



<p>First, we’re shoring up our defenses at home.&nbsp; While there are currently no specific or credible cyber threats to the homeland, the U.S. government has been preparing for potential geopolitical contingencies since before Thanksgiving.</p>



<p>The White House has coordinated extensive outreach by agencies with the private sector, specifically private sector owners and operators of critical infrastructure.</p>



<p>In that outreach, departments and agencies have gone to unprecedented and extraordinary lengths to share sensitive information and, most importantly, to outline specific steps companies can take to make their systems more secure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As one example of those specific steps, the Department of Energy shared technical indicators of techniques used by Russian cyber actors to conduct cyberattacks against Ukrainian electricity systems during prior crises in Ukraine.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also using the authorities we have to require companies to put in place the cyber defenses needed.&nbsp; For example, TSA issued directives that require oil and gas pipelines to report cyber incidents, conduct vulnerability assessments, and exercise their incident response plans.&nbsp; TSA is now working to expand that to both the aviation and railroad sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As many of you know, the government doesn’t own or operate critical infrastructure that provides critical services to our citizens &#8212; for example, our water systems and power systems.&nbsp; I cannot stress this enough: We urge our private sector partners to exercise incident response plans and put in place the cybersecurity defenses, like encryption and multifactor authentication, that make cyberattacks harder for even sophisticated cyber actors.</p>



<p>Second, we continue to support Ukraine as it works to shore up its cyber defenses.</p>



<p>The U.S. government believes that Russian cyber actors likely have targeted the U- &#8212; the Ukrainian government, including military and critical infrastructure networks, to collect intelligence and pre-position to conduct disruptive cyber activities.  These disruptive cyber operations could be leveraged if Russia takes further military action against Ukraine. </p>



<p>We&#8217;ve seen troubling signs of malicious cyber activity in the last month.  Earlier this week, we saw a kind of cyberattack known as a DDoS attack that overloads online services at the Ukrainian Ministry of Defense and state-owned banks.  There were also text messages sent to bank customers telling them that ATM services were unavailable.</p>



<p>Russia likes to move in the shadows and counts on a long process of attribution so it can continue its malicious behavior against Ukraine in cyberspace, including pre-positioning for its potential invasion.&nbsp; In light of that, we&#8217;re moving quickly to attribute the DDoS attacks.</p>



<p>We believe that the Russian government is responsible for wide-scale cyberattacks on Ukrainian banks this week.&nbsp; We have technical information that links Russian &#8212; the Russian Main Intelligence Directorate, or GRU, as known GRU infrastructure was seen transmitting high volumes of communications to Ukraine-based IP addresses and domains.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve shared the underlying intelligence with Ukraine and with our European partners.</p>



<p>While of limited impact, this recent spate of cyberattacks in Ukraine are consistent with what a Russian effort could look like in laying the groundwork for more disruptive cyberattacks accompanying a potential further invasion of Ukraine&#8217;s sovereign territory.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been preparing for this possibility.&nbsp; Since November, we further intensified our support to the government of Ukraine, specifically to network defenders, working to help them respond to and recover from cyber incidents as well as strengthen the resilience of cyber critical infrastructure.</p>



<p>Finally, we&#8217;re cooperating with Allies and partners to disrupt and respond to malicious cyber activity.&nbsp; That includes work to share intelligence regarding malicious cyber techniques and ensure the global community is ready to rapidly call out malicious cyber activity as appropriate.</p>



<p>Members of the administration have met with leaders across the region to discuss cyber resilience, deterrence of cyberattacks, and to ensure we&#8217;re prepared to address any cyber contingencies.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve met with our Polish and Baltic counterparts; our NATO Allies; and our European partners, including France and Germany.</p>



<p>The global community must be prepared to shine a light on malicious cyber activity and hold actors accountable for any and all disruptive or destructive cyber activity.</p>



<p>And as the President said earlier this week: If Russia attacks the United States or our Allies through asymmetric activities, like disruptive cyberattacks against our companies or critical infrastructure, we are prepared to respond.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; As President Biden has said: If Russia attacks Ukraine, we will respond decisively and forcefully to impose costs on Russia, alongside our Allies and partners.</p>



<p>The cost to Russia would be immense, both to its economy and its strategic position in the world.&nbsp; Our financial sanctions have been designed to impose overwhelming and immediate costs to the largest financial institutions and state-owned enterprises in Russia.&nbsp; They’ve been calibrated to maximize alignment with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; They’re flexible to allow for further escalation or de-escalation, depending on how Putin responds.&nbsp; And they’re responsible to avoid targeting the Russian people and to limit unwanted spillovers to the U.S. and global economy.</p>



<p>We’re also prepared to impose powerful export controls as part of our response package.&nbsp; Both financial sanctions and export controls deny something to Russia that it needs and can’t get from anywhere other than the United States or our Allies and partners.&nbsp; Financial sanctions deny foreign capital to Russia, and export controls deny critical technological inputs that Russia needs to diversify its economy and to deliver on Putin’s strategic ambitions in aerospace, defense, and high-tech.<br><br>Working in tandem, financial sanctions and export controls are embedded in a broader strategy that would undercut Putin’s aspirations to project power and exert influence on the world stage.<br><br>If Russia invades Ukraine, it would become a pariah to the international community, it would become isolated from global financial markets, and it would be deprived of the most sophisticated technological inputs.<br><br>Russia would face the prospect of intense capital outflows, mounting pressure on its currency, surging inflation, higher borrowing costs, economic contraction, and the erosion of its productive capacity.<br><br>Taken together, Russia would become more dependent on countries that cannot compensate for its losses.&nbsp; This would be a strategic defeat for Russia, pure and simple.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the West and international community would emerge more united and determined to defend shared values and core principles than at any point in the post-Cold War era.<br><br>We’re ready to impose costs in lockstep with our Allies and partners because we share the belief that Russia has no right to redraw its neighbors&#8217; borders by force and that countries have the freedom to set their own course and to choose their own destiny.<br><br>To be clear: The test of unity with our Allies and partners is not whether our actions are matched to the letter or whether our implementation mechanics are identical.&nbsp; The test of unity is whether we share a recognition of the core principles that are at stake, whether we share the resolve to defend those principles by imposing severe costs on Russia for its actions, and whether we’re willing to do all we can to support each other in managing the consequences.<br><br>I can tell you with confidence that we’ve met the test.&nbsp; And on this last point, since I know many of you have asked, let me say that we are in active engagement with major energy consumers and major energy producers to coordinate potential actions, to stabilize energy markets, and all of our tools are on the table.</p>



<p>Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Okay.  Steve.<br><br>Q    Daleep, are you still discussing elements of the sanctions package among yourselves, or is the package ready to go as soon as the invasion begins?<br><br>MR. SINGH:  You know, I would say, at this point, we are &#8212; we are converging on the final package.  And anybody who has worked on sanctions in the EU or the U.S. or any of our other Allies and partners would say that the unity and coordination that we&#8217;ve seen in the past few months is unlike anything we&#8217;ve experienced.  And that&#8217;s the reason I say that the West is likely to emerge more unified and determined coming out of this episode than any point in the post-Cold War era.<br><br>Q    And could you talk a little bit about the export control measures?  How would they impact Russian electronics?<br><br>MR. SINGH:  Yeah, so the reality is that the West and open societies &#8212; this is where innovation and entrepreneurship flourish.  We produce the most sophisticated technological inputs across a range of foundational technologies &#8212; AI, quantum, biotech, hypersonic flight, robotics.<br><br>As we and our partners move in lockstep to deny these critical technology inputs to Russia&#8217;s economy, Putin&#8217;s desire to diversify outside of oil and gas &#8212; which is two thirds of his export revenue, half of his budget revenues &#8212; that will be denied.<br><br>He&#8217;s spoken many times about a desire for an aerospace sector, a defense sector, an IT sector.  Without these critical technology inputs, there is no path to realizing those ambitions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kristen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Anne, this is a follow-up for you, if I can.&nbsp; It sounds like &#8212; and just to put a finer point on this &#8212; you have assessed now that Russia was behind the cyberattacks against the Defense Ministry and the banks in Ukraine.&nbsp; Can you tell us, specifically, when you assessed that, how extensive it was?&nbsp;<br><br>And obviously, you’ve been warning for days that that type of an action could be a precursor to a Russian invasion.&nbsp; Have you been able to determine whether those actions were taken to send a signal that, yes, we are going to invade?</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; So, yes, we &#8212; we have assessed that Russia was responsible for the distributed denial-of-service attacks that occurred earlier this week.&nbsp; And I will note that the speed with which we made that attribution, as you note, is very unusual.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve done so because of a need to call out the behavior quickly as part of holding nations accountable when they conduct disruptive or destabilizing cyber activity.<br><br>You asked how extensive that activity was.&nbsp; It was of limited impact because Ukrainian cyber defenders rapidly brought back the &#8212; both the state-owned banks and the Ministry of Defense networks.&nbsp; And indeed, we have provided support to our &#8212; those Ukrainian network defenders to ensure that they are prepared for even more potentially extensive behaviors or activities.<br><br>And then finally, we do believe, as I noted, that Russia does use cyber as part of its projecting force, whether that is influencing, coercing, or destabilizing.&nbsp; So we do expect that should Russia decide to proceed with a further invasion of Ukraine, we may see further destabilizing or destructive cyber activity.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been working closely with Allies and partners to ensure we&#8217;re prepared to call out that behavior and respond when needed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One quick follow, if I can.&nbsp; You talked about the extensive steps that you have taken and that you have tried to encourage the private sector to take as well to be prepared for potential cyberattacks.&nbsp; Are you confident &#8212; is the private sector prepared?&nbsp; Is the U.S. government prepared for a Russian cyberattack?&nbsp; Can Americans feel as though their money is safe and that U.S. entities are safe?</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; We are confident that we have worked closely with the private sector to press critical infrastructure owners and operators in the private sector to take the necessary steps to deploy cyber defenses.<br><br>We&#8217;ve shared sensitive information.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve shared, most importantly, the specific steps.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve exercised the maximum of government authorities to mandate those steps as needed.&nbsp; We know that should anything occur, we&#8217;ll work closely with the private sector to rapidly respond and recover.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kayla.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I have a question for each of you, but I&#8217;ll ask Daleep first.&nbsp; The administration and other world leaders have said now for months that sanctions will be swift and severe, and they will be the most powerful deterrent to an invasion.&nbsp; But now, with all of these signs that an invasion is going to come in the next few days or is likely, is that a sign that Vladimir Putin has calculated that the cost is bearable for Russia?<br><br>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; You know, look, I know there&#8217;s a lot of talk about whether Russia has a sanctions-proof economy, and there really is no such thing as a sanctions-proof economy.<br><br>If you &#8212; if you think about the term “sanctions-proof,” it means that a country is deciding to deintegrate from the global financial system.&nbsp; That means less foreign capital, higher borrowing costs, less investment, and lower growth.<br><br>And look, whether you&#8217;re an autocrat or small-“d” democrat, every leader cares about your economic conditions.&nbsp; It&#8217;s part of the social contract you have with your people.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s think about the baseline in Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, Russia has an inflation rate of 8.7 percent.&nbsp; The Central Bank of Russia has raised interest rates eight times over the past year to 9.5 percent.&nbsp; The ruble is the worst performer among any emerging market currency.&nbsp; That&#8217;s before &#8212; that&#8217;s before any sanctions have been imposed.&nbsp;<br><br>And if we impose these sanctions, which are the most severe measures we&#8217;ve ever contemplated against Russia, you don&#8217;t have to take my word for what would happen; look back to 2014 with a much less severe package.&nbsp; We saw record capital outflows.&nbsp; We saw a weakening of the ruble by up to 50 percent.&nbsp; We saw Russia spend 25 percent of its foreign reserves in a futile attempt to defend the ruble.&nbsp; We saw interest rates spike to 17 percent.&nbsp; We saw inflation spike to 17 percent.&nbsp; And the economy fell into recession.&nbsp; And the vicious feedback loop we saw in 2014 was determined by Putin’s own choices, not prescribed in advance by us.&nbsp; The more he escalates, the more pain he feels.<br><br>So, look, there&#8217;s no question in my mind that Putin is not playing a winning &#8212; winning hand.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not just sanctions.&nbsp; The export controls deny him the critical technologies he needs to develop his economy over time.&nbsp; If he invades, Europe is going to accelerate its diversification away from Russian energy supplies; we’ll fortify NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.</p>



<p>All of these actions, not just sanctions, deal Putin a very weak strategic hand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;And, Anne, you said that if Russia targets companies or institutions here, and I&#8217;m wondering what intelligence the U.S. has that it can share about how that may figure into Russia&#8217;s campaign.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; So, as I said, there are no specific or credible cyber threats against the homeland.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re making clear that we&#8217;re preparing for that in case of any contingencies.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Ed?&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; But on that note, what&#8217;s your level of concern that there could be an online or cyberattack against, say, the banking system in the U.S. should Russia decide to invade?</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; As we know &#8212; you know, as a society, we&#8217;re a very connected and digitized society, and that as a society, we don&#8217;t have the level of cyber resilience that we wish to.</p>



<p>Since the beginning of the administration, President Biden has made both domestic and physical resilience a priority, and we&#8217;ve urgently taken significant steps, whether they are new authorities, the President&#8217;s executive order, working closely with the private sector in unprecedented ways.&nbsp; Those serve as a foundation for a far stronger domestic cyber resilience we have today than at the beginning of the administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But on the other hand, one should always prepare for any contingencies, and we&#8217;ve been doing so &#8212; sharing sensitive information, encouraging private sector owners and operators to do the work they need to do to lock their digital doors and, essentially, do the equivalent of putting on an alarm so one can rapidly identify if there is an intruder and quickly contain and respond.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you already seen that probing from Russia?</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; We consistently see probing activity.&nbsp; I think the Department of Defense talks about the millions of probes it receives consistently from criminal and nation-state attackers.&nbsp; We see that regularly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The key is to have the resilience to be able to detect and rapidly recover from any destructive or destabilizing activity.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Phil?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, usually those sanctions affect the ordinary people.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen them in Africa and the other countries.&nbsp; Are you concerned that the sanctions that you may impose on Russia may end up affecting ordinary people and not Putin himself?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Yeah, I mentioned some of the &#8212; we have a set of guiding principles that drive our design of sanctions.&nbsp; They need to be strong enough to demonstrate our resolve.&nbsp; We calibrate them to maximize the chance of coordinating with allies and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They&#8217;re also responsible.&nbsp; We target them carefully to avoid even the appearance of targeting the average Russian civilian.&nbsp; And where you&#8217;ll see these sanctions applied is on the commanding heights of the Russian economy and the Russian state.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where they&#8217;re designed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, where you see most of the force of sanctions back in 2014 and where you&#8217;ll see them again now is through the financial sector and in areas where Putin needs critical technologies to develop an industrial base.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s where these measures are concentrated.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s meant to be responsible, not to have contagion to the average Russian civilian.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Phil.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then you just returned from West Africa.&nbsp; You went in DRC.&nbsp; And we see in Africa &#8212; we have coups in Africa &#8212; people (inaudible) an attempted coup.&nbsp; Is there anything the U.S. can do &#8212; maybe relocating Africans from Germany to Africa?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, our efforts in Africa and across the developing world are to give countries a better choice than they&#8217;ve been receiving.&nbsp; So we are &#8212; we&#8217;re on the road offering infrastructure finance that expresses our values &#8212; so, finance that is transparent, that&#8217;s inclusive, that’s sustainable; infrastructure financing that has high labor standards, high environmental standards; and infrastructure finance that mobilizes our private sector, which is our key competitive advantage.</p>



<p>For too long, countries have not had a choice.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve had an opaque course of &#8212; an extractive model of infrastructure finance, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re out to compete: because we think we have a better product.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Phil.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But can you say why the launch has been delayed though by &#8212; Daleep &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; If we can just try to &#8212; because we&#8217;re going to get through as many people as possible, and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re trying to do here.</p>



<p>Okay. &nbsp;Go ahead, Phil.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One for each of you if you don’t mind.&nbsp; Anne, you alluded to this, but the U.S. has assessed that the Russians likely have a foothold into critical Ukrainian infrastructure on the cyberspace right now.&nbsp; Is it the expectation or is it a likelihood that they will once again try and shut down Ukrainian power?&nbsp; And if so, is that considered a red line for the U.S. in terms of a cyber operation response?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; So, Russia has used offensive cyber activity to coerce and disrupt critical infrastructure in Ukraine during a prior crisis.&nbsp; So we would expect, based on prior activity, that should Russia decide to proceed with an invasion of Ukraine &#8212; and I want to be clear that our priority, as the President has noted, is really exercising every diplomatic option possible to avoid that &#8212; we are prepared for and have been working with Ukrainians and our European allies and partners to help the Ukrainians prepare for potential destructive or destabilizing activity.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And would that be a red line for the &#8212; like, for the U.S. in terms of its cyber response?</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; I think as the President has made clear, disruptive or destructive attacks against the U.S. or allies is of significant concern.&nbsp; It&#8217;s outside the boundaries of international norms, particularly attacks against critical infrastructure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But Ukraine isn’t an ally.&nbsp; Does that mean you &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Guys, if you could &#8212; we’re going to get to as many as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Daleep &#8212; Daleep &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It doesn’t help to scream over each other.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Daleep, real quick &#8212; and I think you alluded to this at the end of your opening statement &#8212; but we just heard from the Prime Minister of Italy, Mario Draghi, say that “sanctions should be focused on [a] limited number of sectors…without including energy.”&nbsp; Do you view that as a one-off?&nbsp; How do you address the fact that the different countries, particularly in Europe, have different equities here to try and actually stay unified as, you say, the West is right now?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH: &nbsp;Look, I&#8217;ll speak to the energy question.&nbsp; First of all, our measures are not designed to reduce or impair Russia&#8217;s ability to supply energy to the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, we think it would be a strategic mistake for Putin to weaponize his energy supply.&nbsp; Two thirds of Russia&#8217;s exports and half of its budget revenues come from oil and gas. And if Putin were to weaponize his energy supply, it would only accelerate the diversification of the world away from Russian energy consumption.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number three, we&#8217;re prepared for anything.&nbsp; So, if &#8212; if Russia decides to weaponize its energy supply, we&#8217;re ready.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been taking steps, as I mentioned in my statement, to coordinate with major energy consumers, major energy producers to ensure that we have steady energy supplies and we have stable energy markets.</p>



<p>On natural gas, we&#8217;ve been working with Europe in lockstep to surge natural gas to Europe from North Africa, from the Middle East, from other parts of Europe, from the U.S., and from Asia.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve succeeded in largely compensating for any shortfall that could unfold if gas that flows to Ukraine is cut.</p>



<p>But the last point I&#8217;ll make &#8212; it&#8217;s maybe the most fundamental one: Policy involves trade-offs.&nbsp; And the President said this week he&#8217;s not going to pretend that this is all painless.</p>



<p>But think of the counterfactual.&nbsp; Think if Russia&#8217;s aggression in the heart of Europe went unchecked.&nbsp; Possibly the largest land invasion in the post-Cold War era.&nbsp; Think of the uncertainties that would cause.&nbsp; Think of the chilling effect that would cause across the European continent.&nbsp; Think of the questions that will be asked about which other countries could be bullied by an autocrat looking to exert a sphere of influence.&nbsp; Those are costs we&#8217;re not willing to tolerate.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Rachel.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick follow-up to some of the intelligence that you mentioned.&nbsp; I know you said right now the administration is confident that there is no threat level to the United States, but how quickly do you expect that to change if there is an invasion and if and when sanctions are imposed?</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; I won&#8217;t get into the hypotheticals.&nbsp; What I will say is that we&#8217;ve focused on maximum preparedness across government systems, across private sectors, critical infrastructure, both in the United States and working closely with our Allies and partners.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Weijia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Anne, can you talk about what companies in the private sector are the most vulnerable?&nbsp; Obviously, you&#8217;ve talked about banking.&nbsp; You’ve talked a little bit about the water systems.&nbsp; But what other ones do you consider to be most at-risk right now?&nbsp; And then I have a question for Daleep too.</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; So, generally, as we look at ourselves as a society, we know that critical infrastructure is our focus &#8212; to rapidly improve our domestic resilience because of the degree to which critical services like power and water touch citizens across the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why some of the most urgent and innovative efforts that the President has initiated this year have focused on those sectors &#8212; from the Industrial Control Systems effort, to TSA’s first exercise of its emergency authorities, to NERC issuing an alert earlier this week for the utility sector as well.</p>



<p>So that is really the critical infrastructure.&nbsp; Particularly, power, communications and water have been a clear focus because of the fact that they touch Americans lives and because of the need to address the fact that these sectors digitized quickly, and we need to catch up from a security and resilience, which we have made significant progress on in this first year.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And, Daleep, a quick question on the export tool: What technologies and products can the U.S. and Allies withhold from Putin that he can&#8217;t get elsewhere &#8212; for example, from China?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; We think we have an asymmetric advantage when it comes to the foundational technologies of our time.&nbsp; So, think of AI, semiconductors, quantum, robotics, hypersonic flight.&nbsp; These are products that, in almost every case, are designed and produced in the West and in open societies.&nbsp; We define the productive frontier.&nbsp; So, there really is no ability for Russia to replace or compensate for the denial of these inputs from anywhere else, including China.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Patsy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, actually, just to follow up on the China question &#8212; I mean, as we&#8217;re dealing with the threats of Russia, we know that you&#8217;ve also been doing these tours to Africa and South America, in terms of promoting the Build Back Better World to counter the Belt and Road Initiative.&nbsp; Can you share a little bit &#8212; the level of interest to this program from the countries that you visited?&nbsp; And why has there been a holdup?&nbsp; Because the promise was that it will be launched earlier &#8212; early this week &#8212; this year.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;ll say there&#8217;s been enormous enthusiasm in every country we visited: Ecuador, Colombia, Panama, Ghana, Senegal, the DRC, parts of the Middle East, Indonesia, Thailand, and other parts of the world.&nbsp; And the reason there&#8217;s so much enthusiasm is that countries do want a choice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For a long time, China has been the only game in town for many of these countries.&nbsp; And in many cases, they have buyers regret.&nbsp; The loans that have been made to these countries have often been very opaque.&nbsp; They have non-disclosure agreements.&nbsp; They have termination clauses.&nbsp; They have confiscatory collateral arrangements.&nbsp; They&#8217;re extractive, in many cases &#8212; in the DRC, for example.&nbsp; This is a country that&#8217;s rich in minerals &#8212; over $20 trillion in critical minerals &#8212; but they&#8217;ve not seen the schools, the roads, the hospitals, the bridges they were promised.</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;re offering a different way with, as I say, high standards for transparency; inclusivity; development impact &#8212; local development impact; and very, very strong attention to the labor market impacts and environmental standards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, so we&#8217;re mobilizing along with our G7 partners, and we are going to launch early this year.&nbsp; You should see very soon a list of flagship projects that will exemplify exactly what Build Back Better World is all about.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jacqui.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Can you clarify: Is removing Russia from the SWIFT international banking system part of the financial sanctions package?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, all options remain on the table.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s probably not going to be the case that you&#8217;ll see SWIFT in the initial rollout package.&nbsp; We have other severe measures we can take that our Allies and partners are ready to take in lockstep with us, and that don&#8217;t have the same spillover effects.&nbsp; But we always will monitor these options, and we’ll &#8212; we’ll revise our judgments as time goes on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I thought you guys had said you were going to start at the maximum &#8212; that it wouldn&#8217;t be like a &#8212; you know, a ramping up of sanctions.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I can assure you the measures that we have prepared &#8212; the severity of those measures, and the institutions that we would impose them upon, and the immediacy of those sanctions &#8212; are among the most severe financial sanctions that have ever been contemplated.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Josh.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be the last one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the sanctions: If they’re severe as you say, how do you protect against the risks that Russia&#8217;s economy becomes stitched even tighter with China or others who might be able to avoid what the U.S. is doing?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; So, you can look at this question from both perspectives.&nbsp; From Russia&#8217;s perspective, if it wants to sequester itself from Western economies, Western technology, and Western capital markets, and try to substitute China for all that we provide, that&#8217;s a very bad miscalculation.&nbsp; The G7 alone represents more than 50 percent of the global economy.&nbsp; China is 15 percent.</p>



<p>If you look at the Dollar, the Euro, the British Pound, and the Yen &#8212; these are the dominant reserve currencies of the world.&nbsp; It’s how the world makes payments.&nbsp; It’s how it saves money.&nbsp; It’s how the world borrows money.&nbsp; The Renminbi here on these metrics is in the low single digits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you think about the foundational technologies of our time, they are, in almost all cases, designed or produced by the West and open societies where innovation and entrepreneurship flourish.</p>



<p>So, there is I don&#8217;t think any question that China could not be a substitute for all the West provides.</p>



<p>Now, for China&#8217;s part, if it decides to give tacit or explicit accommodation to the invasion of the sovereign nation in the heart of Europe, that would be a very bad signal for its vision of the world.&nbsp; The reputational effects that would have in Europe would be profound.&nbsp; The signals it would send all across the world about its willingness to accommodate coercion and force and aggression would have very long-lasting effects.</p>



<p>And let&#8217;s be real: The Russian economy is one tenth the size of the EU &#8212; one fifteenth the size of the U.S. economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, China may want Russia as its junior partner for cheap gas or cheap oil, but let&#8217;s not pretend it&#8217;s anything else.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I do a follow-up question, as well?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, both, so much.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; I think we have to wrap it up because they have to head back and do some work.&nbsp; Thank you both so much for joining us.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. NEUBERGER:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, I just have one item for all of you at the top &#8212; a week ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This weekend, including Presidents’ Day on Monday, the President will remain in D.C. throughout &#8212; obviously at the White House &#8212; throughout next week, the President will continue close coordination with our Allies and partners on Russia&#8217;s potential further invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Tuesday, the President will host an event announcing progress on reshoring critical supply chains, powering clean energy manufacturing, and creating good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>And on Thursday, the President will participate in a virtual G7 leaders meeting to discuss the ongoing situation with regard to Russia and Ukraine and priorities of the German G7 presidency this year.</p>



<p>With that, I will try to jump around as much as I can.</p>



<p>Josh, do you want to kick us off, though?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; The first one: Has the President read the Russian response on Ukraine, and is he giving any consideration to mobilizing additional troops in Europe?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, on the first part, I know that, as you all know, our Secretary of State has accepted the invitation to have a meeting with Foreign Minister Lavrov &#8212; or engage with him, next Wednesday, and certainly we are continuing to review.</p>



<p>In terms of the President&#8217;s status or process there, I don&#8217;t have anything to update you on.&nbsp; We have always said from the beginning that we are open to sending more troops should that be needed.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any update on that front.&nbsp; I would point to the Department of Defense.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, real quick: Separatists in Ukraine are evacuating civilians to Russia.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken warned about this as a type of false-flag operation.&nbsp; Now that you&#8217;re seeing these operations, does that mean a further invasion is forthcoming, if not inevitable?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that we believe &#8212; we continue to believe, as you heard our Secretary of State say yesterday, that Russia is positioned to attack Ukraine in the coming days.&nbsp; And that remains the case &#8212; just what the Secretary said yesterday.&nbsp; Obviously, the President will be speaking shortly to all of you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, the door to diplomacy remains open and it will continue to remain open.&nbsp; And, again, we &#8212; as is evidenced by the fact that our Secretary of State is planning to engage with the foreign minister.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of &#8212; in terms of these reports, yes, it is a good example of what we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; or what we have long anticipated and long predicted for all of you: that the Russians would take part in pretexts or steps that would lay a predicate for either war or to create confusion or spread misinformation on the ground about what&#8217;s actually happening on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think, again, it&#8217;s important to remember that they have been &#8212; we would consider eastern Ukraine &#8212; that the war began in eastern Ukraine back in 2014.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not waiting.&nbsp; It&#8217;s already began, back in 2014.&nbsp; There have been Russian separatists there.&nbsp; There have been efforts to spread misinformation and to create these pretexts for some time now.&nbsp; But certainly, we continue to watch closely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it wise for President Zelenskyy to leave Ukraine to attend the Munich Conference?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is a decision for him to make.&nbsp; But regardless of what decision he makes, he will find a strong partner in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what does the President want to hear from the transatlantic?&nbsp; I think the call is going on right now.&nbsp; What &#8212; what &#8212; is he going to talk about sanctions?&nbsp; What are they going to talk about?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think you have all seen the President engage quite a bit &#8212; extensively, I should say &#8212; in conversations, video conferences, calls with his counterparts around the world to ensure that we remain lockstep and coordinated and united.&nbsp; And that doesn&#8217;t happen on its own.&nbsp; It happens through a lot of work and effort and a lot of direction by the President of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is an effort to have a conversation with his counterparts about what we&#8217;re seeing, where things stand, and continue that close coordination that has been ongoing for months now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one question.&nbsp; There was a readout from Brett and Amos’s meeting &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; in the Middle East.&nbsp; And in that readout, it says they discussed with the Saudis a “collaborative approach to managing potential market pressures” if Russia invades.&nbsp; Can you give any details?&nbsp; Was anything concrete agreed to?&nbsp; Were there any promises made?&nbsp; What does the “collaborative approach” mean when it comes to the Saudis and the U.S.?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say a “collaborative approach” means trying to prevent impacts on the energy markets if there is a shortage as a result of an invasion.&nbsp; There are lots of ways to achieve that, and that was certainly part of the discussion.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any more details beyond what was in the readout.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would also note that in the readout, they also conveyed that a big part of their discussion was also related to Yemen, also related to Iran.&nbsp; So there are a range of topics that were discussed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to clarify: Is this the beginning of that discussion about a potential collaborative approach midway through or close to a final agreement?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect &#8212; we expect certainly our conversations with the Saudis will be ongoing.&nbsp; And the effort will be focused on ensuring that we&#8217;re in full coordination to handle any energy market pressures that could arise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; When we heard from President Biden yesterday, he had not yet read the written response from the Russians.&nbsp; Assuming that he has now, has that changed his assessment at all about the possibility of diplomacy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think Josh asked a similar question, but I would just say I don&#8217;t have an update on the internal discussions about the Russian response other than to convey that, as our Secretary of State noted yesterday, he has accepted the offer to &#8212; or he is &#8212; he will be engaging, I should say, with his counterpart, his Russian counterpart, on Wednesday, unless, of course, they invade.&nbsp; And there will continue to be a range of diplomatic discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think the Secretary of State was also very clear yesterday about the fact that we believe that Russia is positioned to attack Ukraine.&nbsp; They, of course, could change their mind, or they could decide not to, and we are going to remain &#8212; keep the door to diplomacy open, as we should.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, there&#8217;s no new assessment beyond what the Secretary of State said yesterday, which was quite forward-leaning, as I think you would all agree.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Has the U.S. in any way conveyed to Ukraine that it should not respond to the provocations by Russia?  We&#8217;re obviously seeing the increased shelling that’s happening right now.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  And they have not, I think as you have seen.  You know, I think we are &#8212; have been speaking vocally and privately, of course, about our expectation of these types of provocations and what their intended purpose is and whether their intended purpose is to create confusion; whether it is to create, you know, irritation; whether it is to prompt a response.  Obviously, that would not be a positive step at this point in time.<br><br>Q    And so you have conveyed that privately to the Ukrainians or (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  We have &#8212; we have conveyed that, certainly, in a range of ways.<br><br>Q    Okay.  And let me just, if I could, go back to the meeting between the Secretary of State and Lavrov that may happen next week.  What gives the administration hope that there&#8217;s still a path for diplomacy when the President has said that an invasion is all but certain to happen in the next few days?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we hope we&#8217;re wrong.&nbsp; You know, we hope that &#8212; if Russia doesn&#8217;t invade, we will be relieved.&nbsp; That would certainly be a good outcome.&nbsp; But at the same time, what&#8217;s the alternative?&nbsp; Us not to say we’ll &#8212; we will agree to diplomacy or diplomatic opportunities?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you gotten any assurances from Russian officials that they won&#8217;t invade until Lavrov meets with Secretary Blinken?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, Kristen, I think, as we&#8217;ve said in the past, I mean, it&#8217;s not just about what is said &#8212; they&#8217;ve said that publicly; it&#8217;s about what they do.&nbsp; And so, we continue to believe that they are positioned to invade Ukraine.&nbsp; If they decide not to, that is certainly a positive step.&nbsp; And we have a responsibility to the global community, to Ukrainians to leave the door to diplomacy open.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I could try one more time, on Zelenskyy.&nbsp; We do have reporting that a number of administration officials are concerned about him leaving at this critical moment.&nbsp; Obviously, he&#8217;s also scheduled to meet with the Vice President.&nbsp; Has anyone in this administration conveyed directly to Zelenskyy that there are concerns about him leaving right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to detail any private diplomatic conversations.&nbsp; But again, I’d reiterate it&#8217;s a decision that is up to him to make.&nbsp; That would &#8212; is what we convey privately as well.&nbsp; And regardless of what decision he makes, he will remain &#8212; he will have the support of the United States.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Blinken/Lavrov meeting, does the administration see this as a precursor to some kind of leaders summit, or perhaps a phone call between the President and Putin or a face-to-face meeting?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think where we are right now is that, you know, we are unclear &#8212; we&#8217;re ready to engage in diplomacy, but it&#8217;s unclear if the Russians are going to sit down in good faith.&nbsp; And, of course, if &#8212; while we are doing everything we can to prevent war, and including having the Secretary of State willing to engage further with his Russian counterpart, I don&#8217;t think we can get ahead of the process or ahead of where things stand, which is our continued belief that they&#8217;re positioned to attack Ukraine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And President Bolsonaro of Brazil met with Putin this week in Moscow.&nbsp; He expressed solidarity with Russia.&nbsp; I know the State Department put something out.&nbsp; But did the President feel betrayed by President Bolsonaro’s comments?&nbsp; And does this affect U.S.-Brazilian relations at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve not discussed his comments with the President.&nbsp; But what I would say is that the vast majority of the global community is united in their view &#8212; a shared view that invading another country, attempting to take some of their land, terrorizing their people is certainly not aligned with global values.&nbsp; And so, I think Brazil may be on the other side of where the majority of the global community stands.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s a report in Foreign Policy magazine that Russia intends to target Ukrainian politicians and dissidents for assassination or arrest.&nbsp; Are you aware of any plans to provide security for President Zelenskyy or others?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen those reports &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen those reports, and I can&#8217;t, of course, speak to intelligence matters or hypotheticals.&nbsp; We would be very concerned about any actions that would target political critics or vulnerable populations, as I think is what that report is conveying, if I&#8217;m correct, such as religious and ethnic minorities or LGBTQ persons.<br><br>We have, in the past, seen Russia try to force acquiescence through intimidation and repression.&nbsp; But given it’s a hypothetical and I can&#8217;t speak to it further, I can&#8217;t give you any prediction of security assistance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to ask you a question about gas prices specifically.&nbsp; Can you explain, if there is any, the reticence to embrace the calls for the gas tax holiday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve said every option is on the table, including that.&nbsp; But a decision has not been made.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any reticence here to do that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s called reticence.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just that a decision hasn&#8217;t been made in the process yet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just checking.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just a quick follow-up on the Russian response.&nbsp; Has the President reviewed it yet?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t have any update on that.&nbsp; What I can tell you is that our efforts remain having continued diplomatic conversations with our counterparts in Russia, as is evidenced by the Secretary of State&#8217;s plans for next Wednesday &#8212; unless they, of course, invade &#8212; and the President&#8217;s engagements that he is a part of at this point in time.</p>



<p>But I think it&#8217;s important to note that, you know, when we look at how we&#8217;re going to engage in diplomacy, it&#8217;s also important that we look at how Russia is responding.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And Russia&#8217;s threats of war if their demands aren&#8217;t met are inconsistent with diplomacy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are going to leave the door open, but I think the Secretary of State&#8217;s commitment to &#8212; or openness to meeting &#8212; or to engaging with his counterpart is evidence of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know you got a question on the call that&#8217;s</p>



<p>happening as we speak, probably, with the transatlantic leaders. Just on the President&#8217;s framing of this: Does he see this as getting the Allies on the same page as a final check-in before an anticipated invasion, given that he said he&#8217;s expecting it within the next several days?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a part of our ongoing engagement, so I wouldn&#8217;t put it in those terms.&nbsp; He &#8212; the &#8212; or we are united; we are with our Allies.&nbsp; I think you will hear him convey that when he speaks to all of you shortly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it is also important to stay in close touch.&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t say this is the last time he&#8217;s going to talk with them or talk with these counterparts in the coming days at all.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been talking with his counterparts nearly every single day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the point we&#8217;re at right now is, of course, over the last few days, we&#8217;ve seen reports of rapid &#8212; a rapid uptick of violence; violations of the ceasefire agreement, including the shelling of a Ukrainian kindergarten yesterday; more and more disinformation is being pushed out to the public.&nbsp; We know this is consistent with the playbook for invasion, and we believe they&#8217;re positioned to attack.</p>



<p>So, of course, it&#8217;s an important moment to have a conversation with his counterparts, but I would expect those to be ongoing.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did you accidentally leave off of the week ahead the President&#8217;s interviews of Supreme Court &#8212; Supreme Court candidates?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Very good.&nbsp; I was like, I may &#8212; I&#8217;m thinking, “Maybe I left something off.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, I can tell you that February is not that much longer; it&#8217;s 10 days if my math is correct.&nbsp; And we remain on track to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But that was like &#8212; that was going to be my &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; to make an announcement about a Supreme Court &#8212; the President&#8217;s selection for a qualified and credible nominee to serve on the Supreme Court ju- &#8212; before the end of the month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then that was my following question, which is &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; which is that, given what&#8217;s go- &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what seems poised to go on with Ukraine, is there any thought that if there is an invasion, the President would delay the announcement of the Supreme Court pick given, you know, what else could be going on at the time?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you know how I love hypotheticals, but what I will tell you is that he has every intention of making a decision this month.&nbsp; He&#8217;s on track to do so.&nbsp; That will mean he will have chosen a nominee faster than any Democratic President in decades.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And obviously, he&#8217;s somebody who has to, as leader of the free world and President of the United States, conduct business on a number of fronts at the same time.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Jumping off of that, actually: Yesterday in the briefing, it was mentioned that the President was planning to begin interviewing nominees as soon as this week.&nbsp; Given that we are on Friday, can you confirm if he did or did not interview anybody this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to provide you a day-to-day update, but I can tell you that this is not going to be that much longer lasting because we only have 10 more days left of the month.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s the good news.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it is always a late part of the process &#8212; the interviews &#8212; but I&#8217;m not going to be able to give you an update on that from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other thing.&nbsp; On COVID, I believe that only four, maybe five states still have indoor mask mandates as it holds right now.&nbsp; And I know that you all have been saying you&#8217;re going to follow the CDC’s guidance, but is there a point where the CDC’s guidance is out of step with a vast majority of what states across the country are doing?&nbsp; And how do you all reconcile that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what I can tell you is the CDC guidance follows data and science, and data and science moves at the speed of data and science.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can speak to any local leaders about what their decision-making has been based on.&nbsp; And we certainly respect their right to do that and respect their role in making decisions about their communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;ve said that the CDC is reviewing the guidance.&nbsp; They have been doing that.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re going to base any recommendations they make on science.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, is the assumption though that Democratic governors and Republican governors in all these states are not basing decisions on data and science?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak for how they&#8217;re making their decisions.&nbsp; I can speak for how we make our decisions from the federal government, which is to base it on data and science.&nbsp; And the CDC is the federal government&#8217;s entity where we &#8212; where we have all of our data and science housed.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The former Minneapolis &#8212; or suburban Minneapolis Police officer who was convicted of fatally shooting Daunte Wright was sentenced to two years in prison today.&nbsp; Is the President keeping track of this?&nbsp; Is he aware of this sentence?&nbsp; And does he think that this was a sentence that was fitting for this crime?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what I can say is that Daunte Wright should be here with his family and loved ones, and his death was the tragic result of a law enforcement officer’s error.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know we have a long way to go when it comes to criminal justice and racial equity in this country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we are committed to not only engaging in conversations about meaningful policing reform, but we will also continue to ensure that the law enforcement agencies have the resources they need to properly train and equip officers to protect our communities.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to speak to the specifics of the sentencing outcome.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on the State of the Union, which is obviously right around the corner.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about what specifically the President is doing to prepare for that, what tone he is hoping to set in that speech, what message he&#8217;s hoping to send to the country?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect we will have more as we get a little bit closer.&nbsp; I will say that as the President is in Washington, D.C. this weekend, at the White House, he will, of course, be closely monitoring developments in Ukraine, but he will also be, you know, working toward making a &#8212; finalizing his decision-making process as it relates to a Supreme Court justice nominee, and certainly preparing for the State of the Union as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I expect as we get a little bit closer to next week, we&#8217;ll have more to say.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back on Russia-Ukraine, the U.S. language seems to have changed from “imminent” to “highly likely” back to “imminent” again.&nbsp; Is that because you&#8217;re trying to second guess Vladimir Putin all the time, or were you closer to the escalation at one point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that, several weeks ago, I think for maybe a day, we used the word “imminent,” and we believe we sent the wrong message; that was not intended.</p>



<p>Our intended message we were sending at that time was that &#8212; was that he was &#8212; it was an option or he was prepared to.</p>



<p>Obviously, things have developed since then.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen a rapid uptick of violations of the ceasefire agreement.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen an increase in troops building at the border.&nbsp; And certainly, we&#8217;ve seen an esc- &#8212; escalatory actions.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why our Secretary of State went to the United Nations yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what we&#8217;re seeing is further progress for the regression over the last several days.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; One, back to Congress, as you know, Senate Republicans are blocking Federal Reserve nominees and other nominees.&nbsp; They argue that they don&#8217;t think those Federal Reserve delays have any actual effect.&nbsp; How do you respond to that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say: At a time where I think everyone &#8212; most people agree that inflation and costs are the top &#8212; if not one of the top &#8212; issues for every American in the country, the argument that it wouldn&#8217;t be best to have a fully confirmed full Federal Reserve Board just doesn&#8217;t seem to make a lot of sense.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on to &#8212; on Ukraine and the idea of cyberattacks on Ukraine, can you speak to the idea of those attacks; the effect they could have on neighboring NATO countries, like Poland; and whether that kind of effect could trigger Article 5 under NATO protections or not?&nbsp; Does a cyberattack affecting NATO countries include kind of &#8212; the kind of language we see in the NATO defense (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;m just not going to get into a hypothetical on that front.&nbsp; Obviously, they have a range of capacities.&nbsp; We work in lockstep with our NATO partners, but I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of any intended actions.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jacqui.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the attempted murder of a Louisville mayoral candidate, the man who was charged with this was released on bail a couple days after this happened with the assistance of a bail fund group.&nbsp; Knowing that the Vice President has in the past supported bail fund groups, what is the White House reaction to this case?&nbsp; And should there be restrictions on which cases these bail fund groups can help, given this is attempted murder?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to dig into this further, Jacqui, and I&#8217;m happy to do that after the briefing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Ukraine, the sanctions, we&#8217;ve learned, don&#8217;t include SWIFT, they don&#8217;t target energy, so the impacts to other countries are mitigated.&nbsp; You guys have attributed this cyberattack to Russia, and you&#8217;re warning that the prospect of war is &#8212; or peace, rather, is pretty dim.&nbsp; So, at what point do you break away from the strategy and say it&#8217;s not working and do something else &#8212; impose some of these sanctions now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think as we&#8217;ve talked about a little bit in here, our collective view from our national security team is that sanctions are meant to be a deterrent.&nbsp; They are not &#8212; if you put all of the sanctions in place now, what is stopping them from invading?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But are they working?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, Jacqui, I think that&#8217;s our assessment from the national security team and &#8212; you know, that we will continue to implement that strategy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;re waiting for people to die before implementing them in that case?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think, Jacqui, that’s in no way a fair statement &#8212; or accusation, I guess, if that&#8217;s what that is.</p>



<p>What we have done and what the President has done is unite hundr- &#8212; countries around the world on a strong package that will be crippling to the Russian economy.&nbsp; And we have done that in a way where we have stood up for the territorial integrity of &#8212; of Ukraine, and stood with our NATO partners and Allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It has always been up to President Putin and Russia to determine which path they were going to take.&nbsp; That has not changed.</p>



<p>But that leadership on the world stage is what has led to a united front and united opposition to these actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would also note that regardless of what decision President Putin decides to make, one of his intended objectives, I think, as we&#8217;ve seen out there, is to divide NATO &#8212; the opposite has happened; to divide, maybe, the United States and divide leadership in the United States &#8212; the opposite has happened.</p>



<p>So, if that was his objective, he&#8217;s already not achieving that.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Patsy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question on Iran.&nbsp; Earlier this week, more than 170 House Republicans wrote a letter to President Biden essentially saying that any new nuclear deals with Iran will meet the same fate as the 2015 JCPOA, meaning that the next Republican administration will just nullify it.&nbsp; Does the administration agree with this assessment?&nbsp; And are you concerned that this &#8212; this may create further complication in the talks in Vienna, which some are saying, optimistically, could wrap up in mere weeks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me say, first, on the talks in Vienna, they are &#8212; continue to be in the eighth round.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a long round, I guess we could say.</p>



<p>We feel substantial progress has been made in the last week and is continuing to be made, but nothing is agreed to until everything is agreed.</p>



<p>If Iran shows seriousness, we can and should reach an understanding on mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA within days.&nbsp; Anything much beyond that would put the possibility of return to the deal at grave risk.</p>



<p>While I&#8217;m not, certainly, going to predict &#8212; or &#8212; what it would look like in a future Republican administration, what I think is an important reminder to everyone, regardless of your political affiliation, is what happened over the last four years after the former president pulled out of the deal, which means &#8212; we &#8212; which we know what happened, which is we lost complete visibility into their capabilities.&nbsp; They made a significant amount of progress, leaving us at the point we are at today, and put us in a very difficult position in order &#8212; as we try to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>So regardless of your politics, hopefully people will factor that in.&nbsp; As we look ahead &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President planning to respond to the letter?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have any information on the letter.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another follow-up on Afghanistan, just real quick, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s continued fighting between the Taliban and the National Resistance Front of Afghanistan, which Russia has offered to mediate.&nbsp; Do you have any reaction on both the conflict as well as Moscow&#8217;s offer?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll check with our national security team and see if we can get more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>3:38 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency Concerning the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-&#8288;19)&#160;Pandemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/18/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-concerning-the-coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 22:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br></p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency declared in Proclamation 9994 of March 13, 2020, beginning March 1, 2020, concerning the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, is to continue in effect beyond March 1, 2022.<br><br>There remains a need to continue this national emergency.&nbsp; The COVID-19 pandemic continues to cause significant risk to the public health and safety of the Nation.&nbsp; More than 900,000 people in this Nation have perished from the disease, and it is essential to continue to combat and respond to COVID-19 with the full capacity and capability of the Federal Government.<br><br>Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Proclamation 9994 concerning the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency Concerning the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-&#8288;19)&#160;Pandemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/18/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-concerning-the-coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-pandemic-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 22:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 13, 2020, by Proclamation 9994, the President declared a national emergency concerning the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic.&#160; The COVID-19 pandemic continues to cause significant risk to the public health and safety of the Nation.&#160; For this reason, the national emergency declared on March 13, 2020, and beginning March 1, 2020, must continue&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On March 13, 2020, by Proclamation 9994, the President declared a national emergency concerning the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic.&nbsp; The COVID-19 pandemic continues to cause significant risk to the public health and safety of the Nation.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on March 13, 2020, and beginning March 1, 2020, must continue in effect beyond March 1, 2022. &nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing the national emergency declared in Proclamation 9994 concerning the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>&nbsp;and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>February 18, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Transatlantic&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/18/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-transatlantic-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 21:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden spoke today with Transatlantic leaders about the likelihood of further Russian aggression against Ukraine.&#160; Together they expressed deep concern over Russia’s continued build-up of forces, reiterated their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and discussed the importance of further economic assistance to Ukraine.&#160; They pledged to continue pursuing diplomacy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden spoke today with Transatlantic leaders about the likelihood of further Russian aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp; Together they expressed deep concern over Russia’s continued build-up of forces, reiterated their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and discussed the importance of further economic assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; They pledged to continue pursuing diplomacy to de-escalate tensions while ensuring readiness to impose swift, coordinated economic costs on Russia should it choose further conflict.&nbsp; The leaders also discussed efforts to ensure the defense and security of NATO’s eastern flank.</p>



<p>Participants in the call included Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada, European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen, European Council President Charles Michel, President Emmanuel Macron of France, Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy, NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg, President Andrzej Duda of Poland, President Klaus Iohannis of Romania, and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;6617</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/18/bill-signed-h-r-6617/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, February 18, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 6617, the &#8220;Further Additional Extending Government Funding Act,&#8221; which provides fiscal year 2022 appropriations to Federal agencies through March 11, 2022, for continuing projects and activities of the Federal Government.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, February 18, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 6617, the &#8220;Further Additional Extending Government Funding Act,&#8221; which provides fiscal year 2022 appropriations to Federal agencies through March 11, 2022, for continuing projects and activities of the Federal Government.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris’s Meeting with Baltic&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/18/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-baltic-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 17:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with President Egils Levits of Latvia, President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania, and Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia in Munich, Germany. This meeting was part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s extensive engagement with Allies on a unified approach to Russia’s aggressive actions. The leaders discussed their readiness for a swift Transatlantic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with President Egils Levits of Latvia, President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania, and Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia in Munich, Germany. This meeting was part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s extensive engagement with Allies on a unified approach to Russia’s aggressive actions. The leaders discussed their readiness for a swift Transatlantic response should Russia further invade Ukraine, including through adjustments to U.S. and NATO force posture, and implementation of financial sanctions and export controls.<br> <br>Vice President Harris emphasized that our commitment to Article 5 of the NATO Treaty is ironclad and that we stand united with our NATO Allies in opposing Russian aggression. The leaders also discussed efforts to strengthen NATO’s deterrence and collective defense.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris, President Levits of Latvia, President Nausėda Of Lithuania, and Prime Minister Kallas of Estonia Before Multilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-president-levits-of-latvia-president-nauseda-of-lithuania-and-prime-minister-kallas-of-estonia-before-multilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 17:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Commerzbank Filiale MünchenMunich, Germany 2:55 P.M. CEST VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I am here in Munich because it is a top priority for President Biden and myself that we are continuously engaged with and working with our Allies and partners around the world, and that we work always on strengthening those relationships.&#160; And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Commerzbank Filiale München<br>Munich, Germany</em></p>



<p>2:55 P.M. CEST<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I am here in Munich because it is a top priority for President Biden and myself that we are continuously engaged with and working with our Allies and partners around the world, and that we work always on strengthening those relationships.&nbsp; And certainly, the last several months have been evidence of the work we have done collectively, all of us, in that pursuit.</p>



<p>A lot of attention is obviously being given today and the last couple of months to the issue of Russia and its aggression on the Ukrainian border.&nbsp;<br><br>And the focus for us in working together is to further coordinate &#8212; in terms of the work that we have been doing, the dedication of resources, and, certainly, the dedication of priority &#8212; to address that issue and what may be the ramifications; to do this work at the highest levels of our governments, understanding that our work together and our unity is a sign of the strength of our nations individually and collectively.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m here to also talk with our friends and our Allies and our partners so that we can continue to strategize, understanding this is a dynamic situation and will require us to be in constant contact around, again, our priorities, whatever challenges may exist, but also the work that we will continue to do to strengthen and coordinate our resources.</p>



<p>Today, we will discuss a number of issues that surround our shared concerns about Russia&#8217;s activities and the responses that we are prepared to make.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our work together has been and will continue to be about strengthening our ability to deter activity in terms of aggressive activity by Russia as it relates to Ukraine; and about our collective defense and, again, the resources and the commitment that we have to our shared and collective defense.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m looking forward to the conversation and that being the basis of the work that we will continue to do to further reinforce our Alliance.</p>



<p>We have made clear and will continue to make clear that as we are willing and able and committed to the deterrence and the defense issue on this matter, we are also concerned and prioritize the importance of diplomacy.</p>



<p>We understand and we have made clear that we remain open to diplomacy.&nbsp; The onus is on Russia at this point to demonstrate that it is serious in that regard.</p>



<p>I recognize the threats at this moment, historically and going forward, to our friends &#8212; Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.&nbsp; We stand with you.&nbsp; I am here personally to say that.&nbsp; We stand with you on this and many other issues in the spirit of our Alliance and our mutual interests and priorities.&nbsp; And we stand together, all of us, as NATO Allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States remains committed to Article 5.&nbsp; And our position has always been and will continue to be that Article 5 is ironclad.&nbsp; And the spirit behind it &#8212; an attack on one is an attack on all &#8212; remains our perspective.</p>



<p>I do believe, I think we all know, our greatest strength is our unity.&nbsp; This is a moment that has made that clear: that our unity is evidence and is a measure of our strength.</p>



<p>And with that, I look forward to our conversation.&nbsp; And I thank you all for the work you do.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>And with that, I would like to turn to President Levits of Latvi- &#8212; Latvia.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LEVITS:&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; First of &#8212; first of all, I would like to thank you for this conversation and the possibility &#8212; occasion to exchange our views on the actual situation in Europe.</p>



<p>And I would like, also, to thank the United States for the engagement in Europe, for the security in our region, and for the deployment of additional military personnel and military equipment in our region in order to strengthen the eastern flank of NATO.</p>



<p>I would like to say that the aggression of Russia &#8212; and this is a Russian case, not a Ukrainian case &#8212; aggression of Russia against Ukraine is not only against Ukraine, but also against Europe, against the democracy, against the West et al.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because Russia is challenged by democracy, it is difficult for Russia to see that there could be a democratic Ukraine because it could have some repercussions in Russia.</p>



<p>I would say that our task is to avoid the hot phase of the confrontation.&nbsp; And it is only possible if the answer of the West is united and very strong, and so that the cost-benefit calculation for Russia is negative and clearly negative.</p>



<p>And what does this mean?&nbsp; I think this answer is our response consists of four elements.&nbsp; The first element is sanctions &#8212; very, very serious sanctions.&nbsp; And President Biden said already to President Putin this already a few times.</p>



<p>This is the second: military and economically and financial support of Ukraine so that Ukrainians can defend themselves.&nbsp; Also, this is a second element &#8212; very important.</p>



<p>The third element is the strengthening of the military defense capacity in the eastern flank, especially in Baltics, especially in Poland.&nbsp; And the co- &#8212; bilateral cooperation with U.S. in this respect is already going on, but we should strengthen that.</p>



<p>And the fourth element is a dialogue.&nbsp; It’s a dialogue in order to keeps the channel for Russia open to go back to, I would say, normal international behavior.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and all the four elements together, this should be a very strong answer to Russia so that we can say that avoiding of the hot phase of confrontation depends from us &#8212; from the West, from NATO.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; President Nausėda from Lithuania.<br><br>PRESIDENT NAUSĖDA:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Your Excellency, your Vice President, my colleagues: This is wonderful opportunity to meet you here in Munich and, of course, discuss those issues which are critically important for the security of our countries and also the security of the whole region.&nbsp;<br><br>You see here at the table the keen supporters of transatlantic bond, because the Baltics states understand probably so good that very effective security architecture could be built only with the contribution of United States.<br><br>You know that we have just celebrated the fifth anniversary of establishment of Enhanced Forward Presence in Lithuania.&nbsp; So, this is a good reason to say thank you for every Ally of NATO.<br><br>And now we are challenged by the events in Ukraine, but we should not take those events along the border with Ukraine only individually as a security problem of Ukraine.&nbsp; Of course, it means the security problem of the whole region.<br><br>And I like to say that there is no security of Ukraine without talking and discussion of security of the region.&nbsp; So, security for Ukraine means security for Baltic States; security of Ukraine means the security of Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>So today, the ghost of war is lingering in Europe.&nbsp; Unfortunately, we have to admit it.&nbsp; And we see provocation of possible military conflict in Ukraine.&nbsp; But in my eyes, I see that probably Russia keeping both alternatives open.&nbsp; While one al- &#8212; one alternative is to keep tension without the military conflict, the second alternative is open military intervention into Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>I think everything is our &#8212; in our hands in order to prevent this.&nbsp; And the best formula &#8212; peace formula &#8212; in my eyes is deterrence.&nbsp; The more we are united, the more we have firm stance on what is happening in Ukraine, the better we will send the signals to Russia not to start what they intend to do.&nbsp;<br><br>And in this regard, I would say that it is critically important for the security of our region to see more presence of United States troops.&nbsp; So, this is the reason why we really ask for permanent presence of United States troops in Lithuania.&nbsp; You know that we have these troops now on a rotational basis.&nbsp; And probably, this is very good time moment to talk about even more, higher, strong engagement into the security of our region.&nbsp;<br><br>So, Madam Vice President, thank you for this opportunity.&nbsp; I hope that we will have more details to discuss during our conversation.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And Prime Minister Kallas, Eston- &#8212; Estonia.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER KALLAS:&nbsp; Yes, thank you.&nbsp; Great to &#8212; we are very grateful for this meeting and also all the meetings that we have had with the U.S. administration.&nbsp; It means a great deal to us.&nbsp;<br><br>And, first of all, I would also like to stress what my Latvian colleague already said: It&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s about democracy, really.&nbsp; Why Russia is doing this is that he doesn&#8217;t want democracy to prevail in Ukraine.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, it is very important that we prevent this from happening.&nbsp;<br><br>We stay united, as you stressed as well.&nbsp; This is extremely important.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m super happy that we have been united all this &#8212; all this process.&nbsp; We are saying the same thing &#8212; all the Allies, independent, whether it&#8217;s a big one or a small one, which is very important.&nbsp;<br><br>And being a small country, like all the Baltic countries really are, we have all lost our independence to Russia once, and we don&#8217;t want it to happen again.&nbsp;<br><br>And therefore, we &#8212; we really think that this is &#8212; this is very important that we understand what is at stake here.&nbsp; And also, being a small country, it is very important.&nbsp; And we are very grateful that a big Ally like U.S. constantly consults with us; you know, gives us information; keeps us posted.&nbsp; This means &#8212; this means a great deal to us that we are, you know, equal Allies.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know it takes a lot of effort from your side, because there are lots of Allies to be in contact with, but &#8212; but I can speak for all of us: We are very grateful for this.&nbsp;<br><br>And we also feel that you are listening to our worries, which is &#8212; which is not that, you know, make a tick in the box that you have consulted, but actually we feel that you also hear us.&nbsp;<br><br>Our support to Ukraine is unwavering.&nbsp; And Ukraine needs all the political but also military support we can give.&nbsp; And of course, we as Allies decide the practical help regarding, you know, Ukraine &#8212; each country separately &#8212; but &#8212; but I think the message must be very clear.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and also, what &#8212; what my colleagues already said: The rapidly deteriorating security situation also reflects or influences our region.&nbsp; And it demands a stronger military presence in Europe.&nbsp; And also, Russian troops and &#8212; and missiles in Belarus have also deteriorated the situation in the Baltic countries.&nbsp;<br><br>If &#8212; if you look at the map, we are like a peninsula in terms of NATO.&nbsp; And therefore, we welcome the decisions already made by U.S. administration to deploy additional forces in Europe.&nbsp; And we also hope that you increase the presence in the Baltic countries.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3:08 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day Of Remembrance Of Japanese American Incarceration During World War&#160;II</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/18/day-of-remembrance-of-japanese-american-incarceration-during-world-war-ii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eighty years ago, on&#160;February 19, 1942, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066, stripping people of Japanese descent of their civil rights. &#160;That order and the subsequent actions carried out by the Federal Government represent one of the most shameful chapters in our Nation&#8217;s history. &#160;On this Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Eighty years ago, on&nbsp;February 19, 1942, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066, stripping people of Japanese descent of their civil rights. &nbsp;That order and the subsequent actions carried out by the Federal Government represent one of the most shameful chapters in our Nation&#8217;s history. &nbsp;On this Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration During World War II, we acknowledge the unjust incarceration of some 120,000 Japanese Americans, approximately two-thirds of whom were born in the United States.<br><br>Despite never being charged with a crime, and without due process, Japanese Americans were forcibly removed from their homes and communities and incarcerated, simply because of their heritage.&nbsp; For years, many Japanese Americans lived in harsh, overcrowded conditions, surrounded by barbed wire fences and armed guards. &nbsp;Not only did they lose their homes, businesses, property, and savings &#8212; they also lost their liberty, security, and the fundamental freedoms that belong to all Americans in equal measure.<br><br>I have always believed that great nations do not ignore their most painful moments &#8212; they confront them with honesty and, in doing so, learn from them and grow stronger as a result.&nbsp; The incarceration of Japanese Americans 80 years ago is a reminder to us today of the tragic consequences we invite when we allow racism, fear, and xenophobia to fester.<br><br>Today, we reaffirm the Federal Government&#8217;s formal apology to Japanese Americans whose lives were irreparably harmed during this dark period of our history, and we solemnly reflect on our collective moral responsibility to ensure that our Nation never again engages in such un-American acts.&nbsp; We acknowledge the intergenerational trauma and loss that the incarceration of Japanese Americans has caused. &nbsp;We also uplift the courage and resilience of brave Japanese Americans who, despite being unjustly incarcerated, formed powerful communities and marshalled incredible dignity and strength.<br><br>Many of those whose families were incarcerated volunteered or were drafted to serve in combat &#8212; courageously serving in the 100th Infantry Battalion, Military Intelligence Service, Women&#8217;s Army Auxiliary Corps, Army Nurse Corps, and the 442nd Regimental Combat Team with unwavering patriotism.&nbsp; The all-Japanese American 100th Infantry Battalion and the 442nd Regimental Combat Team became two of the most decorated and distinguished military units in our Nation&#8217;s history.&nbsp; Countless Japanese Americans carry forward this legacy of extraordinary service today, and their work to preserve the history of this period strengthens our Nation and our democracy.<br><br>We reflect on the bravery of civil rights leaders like Fred Korematsu, Minoru Yasui, Gordon Hirabayashi, and Mitsuye Endo, and that of every Japanese American who organized and sought redress. &nbsp;Their efforts helped bring about the first Day of Remembrance, led President Jimmy Carter to sign the law creating the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians, and spurred President Ronald Reagan to sign the Civil Liberties Act of 1988, which provided monetary reparations to living survivors and an official apology to the Japanese American community. &nbsp;At the same time, we also acknowledge the painful reality that Japanese Latin Americans, who were taken from their Central and South American homes and incarcerated by the United States Government during World&nbsp;War&nbsp;II, were excluded from the Civil Liberties Act of 1988.<br><br>Today, the National Park Service helps preserve several Japanese American incarceration camps. &nbsp;These tangible reminders of our history provide important spaces for reflection and learning about the injustices born of prejudice. &nbsp;Preserving incarceration sites as national parks and historic landmarks is proof of our Nation&#8217;s commitment to facing the wrongs of our past, to healing the pain still felt by survivors and their descendants, and to ensuring that we always remember why it matters that we never stop fighting for equality and justice for all.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to maintaining these national parks and landmarks for future generations and to combating xenophobia, hate, and intolerance &#8212; including through the reestablished White House Initiative on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders. &nbsp;In the words of&nbsp;Dr. Frank Kitamoto, who was incarcerated as a child, &#8220;This is not just a Japanese American story but an American story with implications for the world.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>The words we use to describe the historical and present treatment of communities of color and other underserved communities have profound meaning. &nbsp;Today, we recognize that euphemistic terms that we have collectively used in the past &#8212; such as &#8220;assembly centers,&#8221; &#8220;relocation,&#8221; or &#8220;internment&#8221; &#8212; do not adequately describe the injustice experienced by some 120,000 people; we recognize the forced removal and mass incarceration of Japanese Americans and others during World War II; and we reaffirm our commitment to <em>Nidoto Nai Yoni</em><em>,</em> which translates to &#8220;Let It Not Happen Again.&#8221;<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim&nbsp;February&nbsp;19, 2022, as a Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration During World War II. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to commemorate this injustice against civil liberties and civil rights during World&nbsp;War&nbsp;II; to honor the sacrifice of those who defended the democratic ideals of this Nation; and to commit together to eradicate systemic racism to heal generational trauma in our communities.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of February, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
