<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 13:03:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>White&#160;House Announces Theme and Activities for the 2022 Easter Egg&#160;Roll</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/white-house-announces-theme-and-activities-for-the-2022-easter-egg-roll/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 13:03:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51222</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President and First Lady to Host the White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll on Monday, April 18, 2022 The White House announced today the full program of activities for the 2022 White House Easter Egg Roll, a tradition&#160;dating back to 1878.&#160; A teacher for more than 30 years, First Lady Jill Biden created this year’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The President and First Lady to Host the White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll on Monday, April 18, 2022</em></p>



<p>The White House announced today the full program of activities for the 2022 White House Easter Egg Roll, a tradition&nbsp;dating back to 1878.&nbsp; A teacher for more than 30 years, First Lady Jill Biden created this year’s event theme, “EGGucation!,” with the South Lawn to be&nbsp;transformed into a school community, full of fun educational activities for children to enjoy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to the time-honored traditions of rolling and hunting eggs, this year’s White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll will also feature a School House Activity Area, Reading Nook, Talent Show, Field Trip to the Farm, Picture Day, a Physical “EGGucation” Zone, a Cafetorium and more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In total, approximately 30,000 people will take part in this year’s Easter “EGGucation” Roll, including thousands of military families, and the crew members and families from the U.S.S. DELAWARE, the U.S. Naval Submarine, for which the First Lady is the sponsor. Tickets for the general public were distributed to guests from all across the country through an online public lottery.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This year’s event will be broken into five sessions, beginning at 7:30 AM ET and end at 6:30 PM ET.&nbsp; Follow along with the White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll festivities with #EasterEggRoll and #EGGucation, and the official @White House, @POTUS, @FLOTUS social media accounts on Twitter, Facebook, and Instagram.<br><br><strong>Additional information about this year’s “EGGucational” Activities and Programming:&nbsp;</strong><br>&nbsp;<br><strong>EGG ROLL</strong><br>The tradition that started it all! Children will use wooden spoons to roll colorful eggs in a race across the South Lawn.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>EGG HUNT</strong><br>Children will run to find hidden eggs and collect special prizes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>SCHOOL HOUSE</strong><br>The School House area of the South Lawn will be full of fun educational activities for all to enjoy!<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>TALENT SHOW</strong><br>The Talent Show stage on the South Lawn will feature some of today’s most “egg-citing” kids’ acts and performances.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>CAFETORIUM</strong><br>Children and their families will learn how to make some tasty treats and then sample seasonal snacks!<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>FIELD TRIP</strong><br>It’s time to head to the farm for a school field trip!&nbsp; Children will learn from farmers about how they help feed our families.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>READING NOOK</strong><br>Families will come together for some special story time with children’s books authors, teachers, and some special guests!&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>PICTURE DAY</strong><br>Families will remember this day always with a fun photo! Snap a family picture with the White House in the background or capture a moment with your favorite costumed character.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>PHYSICAL EGGucation (PE)</strong><br>Children of all ages will hop, bounce, kick, run,&nbsp;and throw their way through the South Lawn’s “egg-citing”&nbsp;obstacle course and favorite school yard activities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>This year, the White House Easter “EGGucation” Roll will feature educational activities, school yard fun, and special performances on the South Lawn, which are supported by (in alphabetical order):</strong></p>



<ul><li>2021 National Teacher of the Year, Juliana Urtubey</li><li>4 Imprint&nbsp;</li><li>American Association for the Advancement of Science</li><li>American Egg Board</li><li>Baker, chef, author, Christina Tosi, Milk Bar</li><li>Baltimore Ravens</li><li>Beat Refinery DJ School</li><li>Chef Stephen Durfee, Culinary Institute of America</li><li>Children’s Book Author and host of The Tonight Show, Jimmy Fallon</li><li>Children’s Book Author and singer, Ciara&nbsp;</li><li>Children’s Book Author, Jeff Kinney</li><li>Children’s Book Author, singer, and actress, Kristin Chenoweth</li><li>Children’s Book Author Rocco Smirne (age 6) and his mother, Arioth Smirne</li><li>Cooper Middle School Concert Band from McLean, Virginia&nbsp;</li><li>DC United</li><li>DJ Diamond Kuts</li><li>DJ Mel</li><li>DJs and twin sisters, Amira &amp; Kayla</li><li>Duke Ellington High School for the Performing Arts student and singer, Alyssa Richardson</li><li>Eastern High School Marching Band from Washington, DC</li><li>Indiana Fever&nbsp;</li><li>Lawrence Hall of Science: University of California, Berkeley</li><li>Little Miss Murals chalkboard artist, Stacy Lazzara&nbsp;</li><li>Montgomery County Fire and Rescue</li><li>National Children&#8217;s Museum</li><li>Operation Gratitude</li><li>PBS KIDS</li><li>PBS KIDS Series Creator (Alma’s Way), Children’s Book Author and former Sesame Street character, Sonia Manzano&nbsp;</li><li>PBS KIDS Series Creator (Xavier Riddle and the Secret Museum) and Children’s Book Author, Brad Meltzer&nbsp;</li><li>Philadelphia Eagles</li><li>Professor of Art History and children’s book illustrator for the White House Historical Association, Dr. John Hutton &nbsp;</li><li>Sesame Street Live</li><li>Signature Brands, LLC / PAAS Registered Trademark Easter Egg Color Kits</li><li>Singer, songwriter, and actress Sofia Carson</li><li>Sweetgreen</li><li>The Coca-Cola Company / DASANI Water</li><li>The National Basketball Association</li><li>The National Football League</li><li>“The President’s Own” United States Marine Corps Band</li><li>The United States Navy Band Sea Chanters (singing the National Anthem)</li><li>The United States Air Force Band&nbsp;</li><li>The United&nbsp;States Army Band&nbsp;</li><li>The United States Navy Band&nbsp;</li><li>The Secretary of the Department of Education, Miguel Cardona</li><li>The White House Historical Association</li><li>The Women’s National Basketball Association</li><li>Virginia&nbsp;Egg Council</li><li>Washington Commanders</li><li>Washington DC radio personality Tommy McFly, emcee</li><li>Washington Spirit</li></ul>



<p><br><strong>The following costumed characters (in alphabetical order) will stroll the White House grounds, including:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Disney Characters Miguel: from Coco and Doc McStuffins&nbsp;</li><li>Dr. Seuss Characters: Cat in the Hat, and Thing 1 and Thing 2&nbsp;</li><li>Miffy Bunny</li><li>Milkshake the Cow, from the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA)</li><li>Paramount Pictures Characters: Sonic the Hedgehog and Gabby from Gabby’s Dollhouse&nbsp;</li><li>Patriotic Mouse, DJ Bunny, and DJ Mouse</li><li>PBS KIDS Characters: Alma from Alma’s Way, Donkey from Donkey Hodie, Daniel Tiger from Daniel Tiger’s Neighborhood, Molly from Molly of Denali, Xavier Riddle of Xavier Riddle and the Secret Museum, Dog from WordWorld, and Elinor from Elinor Wonders Why</li><li>Peanuts Characters: Snoopy and Charlie Brown</li><li>Peeps Characters</li><li>Poe, the mascot of the Baltimore Ravens</li><li>Sesame Street Characters: Rosita and Cookie Monster</li><li>Swoop, the mascot of the Philadelphia Eagles</li><li>The Nationals’ Racing Presidents Washington, Jefferson, Lincoln, Roosevelt, Taft, and Coolidge</li><li>Universal Pictures Characters: The Minions</li><li>Warner Brothers Characters: Ace and Kypto from DC League of Super Pets</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on His Intent to Nominate Michael Barr to Serve as Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal&#160;Reserve</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/statement-from-president-biden-on-his-intent-to-nominate-michael-barr-to-serve-as-vice-chair-for-supervision-of-the-federal-reserve/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, I am announcing my intent to nominate Michael Barr as the next Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal Reserve. &#160;Michael brings the expertise and experience necessary for this important position at a critical time for our economy and families across the country.&#160; Since I took office, the economy has created nearly 8 million&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, I am announcing my intent to nominate Michael Barr as the next Vice Chair for Supervision of the Federal Reserve. &nbsp;Michael brings the expertise and experience necessary for this important position at a critical time for our economy and families across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since I took office, the economy has created nearly 8 million jobs, and millions of families have the dignity a paycheck can provide and a little bit more breathing room. I know that rising prices and inflation are straining families’ budgets. While I’m doing everything in my power to lower prices for families, the Federal Reserve plays a critical role in fighting inflation and Barr will make a strong Vice &nbsp;Chair Supervision, joining my other nominees for the Federal Reserve that the Senate is considering. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Barr has spent his career protecting consumers, and during his time at Treasury, played a critical role in creating both the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau and the position for which I am nominating him. He was instrumental in the passage of Dodd-Frank, to ensure a future financial crisis would not create devastating economic hardship for working families. &nbsp;Barr has strong support from across the political spectrum – and has been confirmed by the Senate on a bipartisan basis. And, he understands that this job is not a partisan one, but one that plays a critical role in regulating our nation’s financial institutions to ensure Americans are treated fairly and to protect the stability of our economy.</p>



<p>I will work with Senate Banking Committee Chair Sherrod Brown to move Barr’s nomination forward quickly, and urge the Senate to swiftly confirm the four eminently qualified nominees for the Board of Governors—Jerome Powell, Lael Brainard, Philip Jefferson, and Lisa Cook— currently awaiting a vote.</p>



<p><strong>Michael Barr<br></strong>Michael S. Barr is currently the Joan and Sanford Weill Dean of the Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy, the Frank Murphy Collegiate Professor of Public Policy, the Roy F. and Jean Humphrey Proffitt Professor of Law at the University of Michigan Law School, and the founder and faculty director of the University of Michigan&#8217;s Center on Finance, Law &amp; Policy. At the Law School, Barr taught Financial Regulation and International Finance, and co-founded the International Transactions Clinic and the Detroit Neighborhood Entrepreneurs Project.</p>



<p>Barr served in the Obama Administration as the U.S. Department of the Treasury&#8217;s assistant secretary for financial institutions, and was a key architect of the Dodd-Frank Act. He also served the National Economic Council in the White House. In the Clinton Administration, Barr served as Treasury Secretary Robert E. Rubin&#8217;s special assistant, as deputy assistant secretary of the Treasury, as special adviser to President Clinton, and as a special adviser and counselor on the policy planning staff at the U.S. Department of State.</p>



<p>Barr served as a law clerk to U.S. Supreme Court Justice David H. Souter during October Term 1993, and previously to the Hon. Pierre N. Leval, then of the Southern District of New York. He received his JD from Yale Law School, his MPhil in international relations as a Rhodes Scholar from Magdalen College, Oxford University, and his BA, summa cum laude, with honors in history, from Yale University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary to the Vice President Kirsten&#160;Allen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/14/statement-by-press-secretary-to-the-vice-president-kirsten-allen-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 01:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Vice President spoke with International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers’ (IBEW) locals across the country to discuss the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to workers, and to encourage collaboration as we implement the historic, Bipartisan Infrastructure Law which will create good-paying, union jobs across the country. She also talked about her memorable visits to IBEW halls,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Vice President spoke with International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers’ (IBEW) locals across the country to discuss the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to workers, and to encourage collaboration as we implement the historic, Bipartisan Infrastructure Law which will create good-paying, union jobs across the country. She also talked about her memorable visits to IBEW halls, facilities, and programs through the years, including as Vice President, most recently during a trip to North Carolina.<br> <br>The Vice President thanked IBEW President Lonnie Stephenson for his leadership, and said she looks forward to their continued work together.  <strong>​</strong><br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>###</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/14/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 20:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Greensboro, North Carolina 12:43 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &#160;Good morning.&#160; As you all know, in Greensboro to- &#8212; we’re headed to Greensboro today.&#160; The President will visit the Harold L. Martin Sr. Engineering Research &#38; Innovation Complex at North Carolina Agriculture and Technical State University to talk about the Bipartisan&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Greensboro, North Carolina</p>



<p>12:43 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &nbsp;Good morning.&nbsp; As you all know, in Greensboro to- &#8212; we’re headed to Greensboro today.&nbsp; The President will visit the Harold L. Martin Sr. Engineering Research &amp; Innovation Complex at North Carolina Agriculture and Technical State University to talk about the Bipartisan Innovation Act and his economic plan.&nbsp; N.C. A&amp;T is the largest HBCU in the country, with the highest number of African American graduates in engineering of any university nationwide.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris administration provided over $5 billion in funding to HBCUs through the American Rescue Plan and other sources last year.&nbsp; And we are working to increase Pell Grants to support students attending two-year and four-year colleges.</p>



<p>After the Martin Complex, the President will deliver remarks highlighting provisions of the Bipartisan Innovation Act, key to retaining and strengthening our innovation and manufacturing capacity, as well as investing in STEM education and equity.</p>



<p>Greensboro is an example of a regional manufacturer &#8212; manufacturing ecosystem that the President’s agenda seeks to build across America.&nbsp; The Bipartisan Innovation Act would offer the sustained funding places like Greensboro need to create a globally competitive manufacturing industry that expands the middle class.</p>



<p>In Greensboro, the President will be joined by the EPA Administrator Michael Regan; members of his Board of Advisors on HBCUs; and several elected officials, including Governor Roy Cooper, Congresswoman Kathy Manning, Mayor of Greensboro Nancy Vaughan, and Chair of the Guilford County Board of Commissioners Skip Als- &#8212; Al- &#8212; Alston. </p>



<p>With that, Darlene.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Welcome back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now that the President has said that what is happening in Ukraine is a genocide, shouldn&#8217;t the U.S. now step up and try to end what&#8217;s happening there more forcefully?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there an obligation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me just say that &#8212; that right now, we are actively working to assist national and international efforts to (inaudible) document and investigate credible reports of atrocities, analyze the evidence, and identify any Russians responsible for the atrocities and war crimes that have been committed in Ukraine so they can be held accountable.</p>



<p>As part of that work, the U.S. is supporting the efforts of the war crimes unit under the Office of the Ukrainian Prosecutor General and a team of international prosecutors and war crimes experts who are in the region working with them.  We are also supporting Ukraine’s authorities and civil society organizations who are working on the ground to document atrocity crimes for prosecution.  And we helped establish investigations through the U.N. Human Rights Council <s>on</s> [and] the OSCE with &#8212; with release a &#8212; which released a report chronicling serious human rights violations today. </p>



<p>So that&#8217;s the process that we&#8217;re working through as we talk about &#8212; as we talk about genocide and war crimes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any reaction at this point from the White House to Florida Governor DeSantis signing the 15-week abortion ban earlier today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have any comments on that.&nbsp; Per what we normally say about what we&#8217;re seeing nowadays when it comes to abortion, you know, we believe in codifying &#8212; the President believes in codifying Roe v. Wa- &#8212; Wade.&nbsp; We do know that women&#8217;s constitutional rights are under attack all across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why the Biden-Harris administration is doing everything we can in response to these attacks on women&#8217;s rights.  And he&#8217;ll continue to stand with women and support their right to make their own healthcare decisions &#8212; a constitutional right that Roe v. Wade reaffirmed nearly five &#8212; five decades ago. </p>



<p>And the President, again, calls on Congress to act and send a bill to his desk to shut down these radical steps being taken.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another quick question on the trucking situation at the border in Texas.&nbsp; Does the White House understand the national security concerns that Governor Abbott is claiming is the reason that he&#8217;s ordered these inspections in the first place?&nbsp; And is &#8212; what is the White House doing or trying to do to reverse what&#8217;s happening down there?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, a couple of things.&nbsp; People are asking, “Isn&#8217;t this like the tougher enforcement &#8212; border enforcement?”&nbsp; No, these truck inspections hurt Texas and U.S. trade and commerce, and will have no effect on asylum seekers.<br><br>Texas DPS &#8212; DPS work is essential for truck safety, but our border is safer when state and federal government work together.<br><br>President Biden&#8217;s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is already making historic investments to improve security at our borders.&nbsp;<br><br>CBP is used to &#8212; is used to &#8212; to working collaboratively with Texas DPS and does so routinely.&nbsp; CBP officers are very good at their jobs.&nbsp; Texas DPS does not need to replace CBP at the southern border, and attempting to do so jeopardizes public safety and America&#8217;s economic security.<br><br>CBP has conducted a record number of drug seizu- &#8212; seizes and more than 900,000 pounds of narcotics seized since FY 2021, and their Office of Field Operations seizing over 730,000 pounds of drugs at ports of entry.&nbsp;<br><br>In fiscal year 2020 [sic] through &#8212; 2022 through the end of February, CBP has already seized over 250,000 pounds of drugs due theirs &#8212; due to their stringent inspection processes.<br><br>What we&#8217;re doing: We have called on Governor Abbott to stop these unnecessary and duplicat- &#8212; duplicative inspections that are choking a key trade artery into our country.&nbsp; Staff at Laredo Field Office remained in contact with the trade communities and expanded operations to surrounding ports of entry to assist with the diverted movement of trade based on businesses’ resumption contingency plans.&nbsp;<br><br>Surrounding ports of Progreso, Rio Grande, and Roma extended their hours of operations to assist the port &#8212; the port and notify trade stakeholders.&nbsp;<br><br>The Port of Laredo extended their hours of operations at World Trade Bridge to clear and process diverted traffic from Columbia Solidarity Bridge.&nbsp;<br><br>Staff at the El Paso Field Office notified stakeholders of extended hours at the Santa Teresa port of entry to assist with congestion at Ystella [sic] &#8212; Ysleta and remains in contact with trade community to address concerns.<br><br>In all instances, port personnel have stayed and worked after hours to clear and process all commercial truck shipments at international bridges because of the increased DPS safety inspections.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake Sullivan, this morning, talked about an announcement in the coming days on entities that are trying to evade Russia sanctions.&nbsp; Is there more you can share &#8212; what sectors we are looking at?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I know he said that, but I don&#8217;t have anything more to share or preview at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything you can say on whether or not this was a coordinated action with allies or just a U.S. announcement?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, we have &#8212; we have shown our strength by coordinating with our allies and showed unity in that way as we&#8217;ve talked about many sanctions that we have pushed forward in the past couple of weeks.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And specifically on the &#8212; on the coming &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; On this, I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have &#8212; go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the &#8212; to follow up what the President just said about making a decision on sending officials: Who would it &#8212; who &#8212; on the discussions of who you may be sending, is it going to be a Cabinet-level official?&nbsp; Or what are we looking at?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, as he also &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to repeat what he said &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; is that we&#8217;re still &#8212; we&#8217;re still in discussion, deciding this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, obviously, we&#8217;re in contact with the Ukrainian government, with Kyiv every &#8212; every day, pretty regularly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview any further.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more, sorry.&nbsp; If you have a reaction to Elon Musk&#8217;s hostile attempt to take over Twitter.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, and I saw &#8212; I know that happened this morning.&nbsp; Look, this is an offer by a private investor, and we don&#8217;t have any comment here.&nbsp; The SEC is independent and would handle any review processes if this moves forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, do you have any more details about the Russian ship that was apparently sunk by Ukrainian forces?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to share from here.&nbsp; I know the Department of Defense usually gives updates pretty regularly.&nbsp; I would send you to them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And following up on the sanctions question, Jen was asked about secondary sanctions yesterday.&nbsp; Can you give a sense of what secondary sanctions are being considered &#8212; financial sanctions?&nbsp; What else is in the docket?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview.&nbsp; Let me just reiterate: Our sanctions are unprecedented.&nbsp; In no other circumstance have we moved so swiftly in such a coordinated fashion to impose devastating costs on any other country as we have done to Russia and &#8212; done to Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The economy is forecast to contract as much as 15 percent of GDP in 2022.&nbsp; The economic &#8212; economic collapse will wipe out the past 15 years of economic gains in Russia.&nbsp; According to the Institute of International Finance, inflation in Russia is projected to spike about &#8212; above 20 percent and the Russian government rating has been downgraded to “junk” status by major credit rating agencies.&nbsp; Close to 400 multinational companies have left Russia in a mass exodus by the private sector, reversing 30 years of economic progress in a span of a few weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we continue to ratchet up the pressure on Putin’s oligarchs.&nbsp; We are working with our &#8212; with allies and partners to go &#8212; to go after corrupt gains from some of the individuals closest to Putin.&nbsp; No matter where they are held around the world, Putin’s elites have already lost out on their most prized possessions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As long as the &#8212; as President Putin continues this war, the United States and our allies and partners are committed to ensuring the Russian government feels and &#8212; compounding efforts of our current and future economic actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the President was an hour late leaving today.&nbsp; I wonder if you could tell us anything about his activities before he left.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President had a series of morning meetings that went long today.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more specifics to share.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And you mentioned the work you&#8217;re doing to support war crimes investigations in Ukraine.&nbsp; Is there anything you can tell us about the &#8212; are you sending on specific information now?&nbsp; Can you tell us anything about what that is &#8212; intercepts, satellite photos, testimony?&nbsp; And any sorts of examples that you could share?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I &#8212; we are actively working to assist national inter- &#8212; national, international efforts to identify and hold any Russians accountable for the atrocities and war crimes they have committed in Ukraine.&nbsp; And we are actively consulting with our allies and partners how we can support a broad range of mechanisms moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve helped establish investigations through the U.N. Human Rights Council and OSCE of possible violations by Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I mentioned earlier, the U.S. is supporting the work of the war crimes unit under the Office of Ukrainian Prosecutor General, as I mentioned, as well.</p>



<p>As the Attorney General said last week, Justice Department prosecutors were in Europe this week to meet with European prosecutors to discuss information-collection and -sharing efforts to hold Russia accountable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also welcomed the investigation opened by the ICC Prosecutor, in particular his focus on preserving evidence of possible &#8212; possible atrocity crimes.&nbsp; As evidence is gathered, prosecutors will determine whether criminal prosecutions should be pursued.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will do our part to support accountability using every tool available, including passing along the information we are able to gather to help build very strong dossiers of evidence for war crimes prosecutions where appropriate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s also important to remember that these mechanism will take time.&nbsp; We&#8217;re also working around the clock with allies and partners to flow weapons into Ukraine to help Ukrainians defend themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, maybe one last question.&nbsp; National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan said this morning that the administration doesn&#8217;t intend to give the frozen Russian assets back but wants to put them to better use.&nbsp; Does that mean that the administration intends to sell or liquidate those assets to finance the reconstruction of Ukraine, for example?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more to say than what Jake Sullivan, National Security Advisor, said this morning.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything else to add.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask one more on the trip today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, the President will focus, in his speech, on the Bipartisan Innovation Act.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re getting pretty close to the midterms here.&nbsp; And while this is a bipartisan process and, you know, the committee &#8212; the conference committee is going to, you know, do what it can, are you concerned at all that this is, like, butting up too closely to the midterms and Republicans will sort of, like, not cooperate when we get to the summer?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, here&#8217;s what I&#8217;ll say: The President wants to get this legislation, as you know, on his desk for his signature as soon as possible.&nbsp; We&#8217;re glad to see a bipartisan conference process starting, and we&#8217;re going to continue working closely with Congress to help iron out differences between the House and the Senate versions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the bottom line is this: The disruptions we&#8217;ve seen from the pandemic and the war in Ukraine have shown us clearly that we can&#8217;t afford to wait to make the kind of investments &#8212; like the Bipartisan Innovation Act contains &#8212; to make our economy more resilient to global shocks, to strengthen our supply chains, and to lower prices for working families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that’s what we’re going to do.&nbsp; We’re going to continue working with Congress to make this work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AIDE:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>12:56 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Regional Appointments for USDA and&#160;SBA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/14/president-biden-announces-key-regional-appointments-for-usda-and-sba-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51118</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Small Business Administration (SBA): Emily Cole, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Connecticut John Patterson, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Ohio Gail Greenman, USDA State&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Small Business Administration (SBA):</p>



<ul><li>Emily Cole, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Connecticut</li><li>John Patterson, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Ohio</li><li>Gail Greenman, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Oregon</li><li>Eric Scherer, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Rhode Island</li><li>Kelly Adkins, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Texas</li><li>Jill Floyd, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Arkansas</li><li>Thomas Carew, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Kentucky</li><li>Michele Weaver, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Utah</li><li>Aikta Marcoulier, SBA Regional Administrator, Region 8</li></ul>



<p>These regional appointees will be critical to the President’s efforts to rebuild communities most impacted by the pandemic, the economic recovery, and climate change. They bring deep expertise in their issue areas as well as critical relationships with federal, state, tribal, and local leaders. And, consistent with the President’s commitment to building an administration that looks like America, these regional appointees represent the diversity of America and the communities they serve.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE (USDA)</u></strong></p>



<p>The USDA’s Farm Service Agency implements agricultural policy, administers credit and loan programs, and manages conservation, commodity, disaster, and farm marketing programs in each U.S. State. Its mission is to equitably serve all farmers, ranchers, and agricultural partners through the delivery of effective, efficient agricultural programs for all Americans. State Executive Directors oversee this work, ensuring the needs of local constituents are met and that USDA resources are distributed equitably and fairly.</p>



<p>USDA’s Rural Development mission area is committed to helping improve the economy and quality of life in rural America. State Directors lead offices that offer grants, loans, and loan guarantees to help create jobs and support economic development and essential services.</p>



<p><strong><u>Emily Cole, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Connecticut</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Emily Cole previously served as the New England Regional Deputy Director for American Farmland Trust (AFT), a non-profit organization dedicated to protecting farmland, promoting sound farming practices, and keeping farmers on the land. As Deputy Director, she developed AFT’s New England regional Climate and Agriculture program focused on supporting farmers across New England in their efforts to adopt climate smart agriculture through innovative technical and financial assistance, which includes the largest soil health project in New England history.</p>



<p>Cole is passionate about improving all Connecticut farmers’ access to financial and technical assistance to support farm viability and the vitality of Connecticut agriculture. Cole has 18 years of experience as an educator in the field and in the classroom. She earned her Ph.D. in Plant and Soil Sciences from the Stockbridge School of Agriculture at the University of Massachusetts Amherst, and her research focused on improving soil health and carbon sequestration on farmland in the Connecticut River Valley. While at UMass, she was a part of the Crops, Dairy, Livestock, and Equine Extension Team. Cole also holds a Master’s degree in Science Education from Boston University and a Bachelor’s degree in Chemistry from Kenyon College. Cole lives in Simsbury, CT with her husband Ray, a professor at Southern Connecticut State University, and their daughter. She enjoys reading, gardening, and spending time outside with her family and their husky Sasha.</p>



<p><strong><u>John Patterson, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Ohio</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>John Patterson is a former state legislator and retired classroom teacher whose work experience spans over 40 years. He recently completed eight years in the Ohio House until term limits prohibited his continued service. During his time in the House, Patterson served on the Agricultural and Natural Resources Committee, including two terms as ranking member. Patterson was a co-author of HB 7, which provides funding for the H2Ohio initiative begun by Governor DeWine. He was also an original co-author of the Young Farmers Tax Credit bill. A Co-Chairman of the Finance Subcommittee on Primary/Secondary Education in his last term, Patterson co-authored the Cupp-Patterson Fair School Funding Plan which was incorporated into the state budget in 2021.</p>



<p>Prior to his time in the House, Patterson taught U.S. History at his alma mater, Jefferson Area High School in a small, rural district in northeast Ohio. He taught Advanced Placement, Honors, and General U.S. History, retiring in 2012. In addition to his teaching duties, Patterson served as the Model United Nations advisor for nearly three decades. Patterson was also the chief negotiator for his union for over twenty years—a position from which he learned much about compromise and the pursuit of mutually beneficial goals. He also coached basketball, baseball, golf, and cross-country. Patterson earned his Ph.D. in Education at Kent State University in 1996. He has been married to his wife Nancy for 38 years and has two sons, Joshua and Jeremiah.</p>



<p><strong><u>Gail Greenman, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Oregon</u></strong></p>



<p>Most recently, Gail Greenman served as the Executive Director of the Westside Economic Alliance (WEA), where she oversaw daily operations of the organization and brought together businesses and elected officials to further the advancement of transportation, workforce development, affordable housing, and other infrastructure issues critical to the Portland metropolitan region. Prior to her time at WEA, Greenman served as the lead federal public affairs professional at the Oregon Farm Bureau, where she cultivated relationships with Oregon’s congressional delegation. She also worked in the federal education policy arena, serving as the director of Government Affairs for the National Association of Federally Impacted Schools.</p>



<p><strong><u>Eric Scherer, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Rhode Island</u></strong></p>



<p>J. Eric Scherer is currently atechnical consultant to the public and private sector on natural resource issues, including land use and environmental impact. As a certified USDA Technical Service Provider and USDA Certified Conservation Planner, he also assisted agricultural producers on comprehensive nutrient management plans and grazing management plan for USDA program participation and the Rhode Island Farm, Forest and Open Space program, developing Conservation Farm Plans for individuals.</p>



<p>Scherer served as the Executive Director of the Southern Rhode Island Conservation District, where he provided program leadership for the Conservation District programs that assisted private landowners, municipalities and state government, conservation partners, and others with an interest in conserving and protecting natural resources. Scherer serves as an advisor to the Rhode Island State Conservation Committee and is currently working on the first statewide operational guide for the Committee and conservation districts. Scherer&#8217;s past work experience includes 37 years of federal service that began with a tour of duty with the Peace Corps in Belize, and has included working for the USDA Natural Resources Conservation Service in six states in various positions. Scherer enjoys living in the beautiful state of Rhode Island with his wife, Linda, of 38 years, sharing time with his three children and four grandchildren, and is still “learning” the game of golf.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kelly Adkins, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Texas</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>A native of Haskell, Texas, Kelly Adkins was raised on small family farm in Haskell County where he attended Haskell High School and later Texas Tech University. While a student at Texas Tech, Adkins was employed by Texas A&amp;M Agricultural Research and Experiment Station where he gained a further knowledge of agriculture. Upon graduation from college with a Bachelor of Business Degree and a minor in Agriculture, Adkins became employed by the Farm Service Agency of the U.S. Department of Agriculture.</p>



<p>Adkins enjoyed a career serving the farmers and ranchers of Texas and the Farm Service Agency in many capacities. Those positions included serving as County Executive Director in Grimes and Randall County in Texas, District Director for the agency, TASCOE Director, Mediation Coordinator, and as a County Office Trainee Program Trainer and Instructor. He is currently a resident of Canyon, Texas and is involved in a small farming/cattle operation in Randall County. Adkins has been involved in community activities and several state agricultural commodity associations.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jill Floyd, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Arkansas</u></strong></p>



<p>A native Arkansan, Jill Floyd is the Director of Community and Client Engagement with Little Rock-based CDI Contractors, a commercial general contractor and construction management firm, where she is responsible for developing relationships with potential clients and increasing spend with MWBE Construction Subcontractors. She also leads the company’s K-12 STEM initiative to encourage girls to consider careers in science, technology, engineering, math, and construction. Prior to her current role, she was a Project Manager responsible for delivering a variety of construction projects across central Arkansas.</p>



<p>Floyd began her career in manufacturing as a Project Manager with Cummins Engine, after which she joined Ford Motor Company as a Quality Engineer focused on improving processes and part quality at Supplier plants, and subsequently moving into procurement where she managed a global portfolio of purchased parts. Floyd holds several board and commission appointments, including on the Bill and Hillary Clinton National Airport Commission, and the Boards of Arkansas Capital Corporation (a CDFI) and the Women’s Foundation of Arkansas. She also serves on the Arkansas Governor’s Commission on the Status of Women. She previously served on the Mayor’s Opportunity Zone Task Force and Housing and Mobility Transition Team Task Force. Floyd received a Bachelor of Science degree in Chemical Engineering from the University of Oklahoma and MBA/MS Engineering in Quality and Manufacturing Management from Penn State University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Thomas Carew, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Kentucky</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Prior to joining USDA as Kentucky State Director for Rural Development, Dr. Thomas Carew worked in Central Appalachia with Fahe from 2008-2017 as Executive Vice President of Membership and Advocacy. While at Fahe, Carew was the Principal Author of the 502 Direct Packaging Demonstration with USDA. Through his leadership, Fahe’s membership grew from 44 to over 55 affordable housing nonprofits, and he led Fahe’s membership expansion into two new states, Alabama and Maryland.</p>



<p>Carew has deep roots in Appalachia, dedicating his 35-year career to the provision of affordable housing in the region. He served as the Director of the Appalachian Housing Program and the Design and Construction Department for the Commonwealth of Kentucky’s housing finance agency, Kentucky Housing Corporation (KHC), from 2000-2005. While at KHC, Carew oversaw the development of the Appalachian Housing Summit, an annual event for the Central Appalachian Housing Finance Agencies and the non-profit builders and developers working in these four states. Carew also created and implemented a Universal Design and Minimum Design Standard for KHC. Kentucky Housing was the first State Housing Finance Agency in the nation to develop these design standards. Prior to his work with KHC, Carew was the founding Executive Director of Frontier Housing, a non-profit affordable housing developer based in Morehead, Kentucky. He is the recipient of the Dorothy Williams Lifetime Achievement Award from Kentucky Housing Corporation, the highest award given in the Commonwealth for non-profit housing producers. In 1992, Carew received an Honorary Doctor of Law Degree from Fairfield University; and in 2010, Carew received the Cochran Collings award from the Housing Assistance Council for service to Rural America.</p>



<p><strong><u>Michele Weaver, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Utah</u></strong></p>



<p>Michele Weaver has brought a wealth of resources to housing and economic development efforts in rural Utah and across the western region. Her broad background includes small business owner, banking, and non-profit work. In 2018, she was appointed to the Utah Commission for Housing Affordability by Governor Herbert where she effectively highlighted challenges in rural communities and led efforts to increase funding and positively impact statewide policy. As a member of various boards and councils, she’s an instrumental advocate for rural Utah issues and its residents.</p>



<p>With more than 25 years of experience in affordable housing development, Weaver has been providing economic development technical assistance and training, assisting nonprofit organizations, tribal housing development, and administering small business lending programs. Her most recent work includes technical and management assistance and capacity building through Rural Development funding. A finance graduate from the University of Utah, Weaver can be found outdoors enjoying the unique variety of geography that Utah has to offer.</p>



<p><strong><u>SMALL BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (SBA)</u></strong></p>



<p>The 10 SBA Regional Offices, led by Regional Administrators, oversee the SBA’s 68 district offices and ensure the goals and objectives of the Agency are met by each district office and field operations staff. The district offices are the point of delivery for most SBA programs and services, providing quality service to the local small business community. They work with SBA resource partners and intermediaries to accomplish the SBA mission of assisting America’s small businesses.</p>



<p><strong><u>Aikta Marcoulier, SBA Regional Administrator, Region 8</u></strong></p>



<p>Aikta Marcoulier joined the&nbsp;Small Business Development Center&nbsp;(SBDC) team as the director of the Pikes Peak Center in May 2012. Prior to the SBDC, she was the Director of Partnership Marketing with the Professional Bull Riders. Marcoulier is also the program creator and manager of the Colorado SBDC’s Cyber: Cover Your Assets program providing education, training, and one-on-one consulting to small businesses throughout Colorado. She also serves as a regional coordinator for the NorthStar CMM program.<br><br>Marcoulier is involved in the El Pomar Emerging Leaders Program and is an active board member of the Pikes Peak Workforce Development Board and vice-chair of the Better Business Bureau of Southern Colorado. She is on the Pikes Peak Community College Business Advisory Board and is president of the Colorado Business Development Foundation. She serves on numerous committees for the Colorado Springs Business Journal and is on the technology and capacity committees for the Colorado SBDC Network. Additionally, she is a member of ROAR (Relationships, Opportunities, Acumen, and Readiness Committee) for the UCCS College of Business. Marcoulier received her MBA in global management from the University of Phoenix and undergraduate degrees in both economics and psychology from the University of Iowa. She&nbsp;has received several awards, including&nbsp;the University of Iowa Leadership Award in 2011, and was named one of the Colorado Springs Business Journal’s Rising Stars for 2013 and Women of Influence and is the 2021 Leadership Pike Peak Modeling the Way Award winner.</p>



<p>Region 8 serves Colorado, Montana, North Dakota, South Dakota, Utah, and Wyoming.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/14/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 18:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George’s County, Maryland 12:06 P.M. EDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; (Inaudible.) THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I couldn’t hear you. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Will you send officials to Ukraine?&#160; Will you send senior officials to Ukraine? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; We’ll &#8212; we’re making that decision now.&#160; Thank you. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Who would you send? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Are you ready to go? Q&#160;&#160;&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George’s County, Maryland</p>



<p>12:06 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I couldn’t hear you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you send officials to Ukraine?&nbsp; Will you send senior officials to Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We’ll &#8212; we’re making that decision now.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who would you send?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Are you ready to go?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>12:06 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Call with President Herzog of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/14/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-call-with-president-herzog-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 17:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris spoke today with President Isaac Herzog of Israel. She extended Passover greetings to him and the people of Israel and expressed condolences on behalf of the Biden-Harris Administration and the American people over Israeli deaths from recent terrorist attacks in Israel. The Vice President condemned these terrorist attacks in the strongest&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris spoke today with President Isaac Herzog of Israel. She extended Passover greetings to him and the people of Israel and expressed condolences on behalf of the Biden-Harris Administration and the American people over Israeli deaths from recent terrorist attacks in Israel. The Vice President condemned these terrorist attacks in the strongest terms and underscored that U.S. support for Israel’s security and self-defense is unwavering. The Vice President expressed support for continued efforts to reduce tensions. The Vice President reiterated that the bond between the United States and Israel is unshakeable and that we will continue to stay in close touch on these and other issues affecting Israel’s security and the stability of the region. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and National Economic Council Director Brian Deese on EXIM Bank’s Domestic Finance&#160;Initiative</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/14/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-and-national-economic-council-director-brian-deese-on-exim-banks-domestic-finance-initiative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 16:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As the world reels from the impact of geopolitical events, like Putin’s war of choice, and other supply chain shocks, it is clear that investing in domestic manufacturing is critical for our economic and national security. Today, the EXIM Bank Board of Directors voted unanimously to approve the Make More In America Initiative.&#160;This program will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As the world reels from the impact of geopolitical events, like Putin’s war of choice, and other supply chain shocks, it is clear that investing in domestic manufacturing is critical for our economic and national security. Today, the EXIM Bank Board of Directors voted unanimously to approve the Make More In America Initiative.&nbsp;This program will expand the export prowess of American manufacturing and support new jobs for Americans all across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Make More in America Initiative will help expand production capacity in the United States by providing vital access to capital—one of the barriers American manufacturers face when trying to expand their operations, especially the small and medium-sized businesses that are the core of America’s domestic industrial base.&nbsp; As American manufacturers compete with unfair practices overseas, this program is one step toward a more even playing field.&nbsp;This initiative will support the Biden-Harris Administration’s efforts to expand America’s global competitiveness in the industries of the future—from clean energy and clean technology to semiconductor production.</p>



<p>Establishment of this initiative was a key recommendation from the President’s Executive Order 14017 to build more resilient, secure, and sustainable supply chains. We applaud the EXIM Bank’s Board in moving forward to bring this initiative to life. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Releases Agency Equity Action Plans to Advance Equity and Racial Justice Across the Federal&#160;Government</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/14/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-agency-equity-action-plans-to-advance-equity-and-racial-justice-across-the-federal-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On his first day in office, President Biden signed&#160;Executive Order 13985, Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government. That historic Executive Order directed the whole of the federal government to advance an ambitious equity and racial justice agenda. Today, more than 90 federal agencies, including all Cabinet-level agencies, are releasing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On his first day in office, President Biden signed&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/20/executive-order-advancing-racial-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through-the-federal-government/">Executive Order 13985</a>, Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government. That historic Executive Order directed the whole of the federal government to advance an ambitious equity and racial justice agenda. Today, more than 90 federal agencies, including all Cabinet-level agencies, are releasing the first-ever Equity Action Plans that lay out more than 300 concrete strategies and commitments to address the systemic barriers in our nation’s policies and programs that hold too many underserved communities back from prosperity, dignity, and equality.<br><br>Advancing equity is not a one-year project—it is a generational commitment. These plans are an important step forward, reflecting the Biden-Harris Administration’s work to make the promise of America real for every American, including by implementing the first-ever national strategy on gender equity and equality; working to ensure the federal government is a model for diversity equity, inclusion and accessibility; working to deliver environmental justice through the Justice40 Initiative; and working to prevent and combat discrimination on the basis of gender identity or sexual orientation.<br><br>For more details on the Biden-Harris Administration’s efforts to advance equity and justice for underserved communities, visit <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/equity">www.whitehouse.gov/equity</a>.<br><br><strong>Delivering Greater Equity for the American People</strong><br><br>Across the federal government, agencies are taking ambitious action to expand federal investment and support in communities that have been locked out of opportunity for too long, including communities of color, Tribal communities, rural communities, LGBTQI+ communities, people with disabilities, women and girls, and communities impacted by persistent poverty. New agency commitments include:</p>



<ul><li>The <strong>Department of Labor</strong> is strengthening the enforcement of our nation’s wage and hour protections to support underserved workers who are the most vulnerable to wage theft and violations, especially women of color, and is in the process of launching a new initiative to address barriers that workers of color face in equitably accessing Unemployment Insurance benefits.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Housing and Urban Development</strong> is working to eliminate the racial gap in homeownership, address the disproportionate rates of homelessness among underserved communities, and reduce bias in home appraisals through the interagency Task Force on Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity.<br></li><li>The <strong>Environmental Protection Agency</strong> is developing a comprehensive framework for evaluating the cumulative impacts of pollution on underserved, low-income communities. &nbsp;EPA will also reinvigorate civil rights enforcement to ensure that environmental justice is at the heart of the agency’s mission.<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Transportation</strong> is increasing investments in underserved communities by launching a national technical assistance center to provide targeted support with planning, project development, grant applications, and project delivery for communities that face barriers to accessing transportation resources.<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Justice</strong> is improving language access to its programs so that Americans with limited English proficiency can better report crimes, access services, understand their rights, and otherwise have full and equal access to the Department’s programs and resources.<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of the Interior</strong> is providing technical assistance to Tribes to help them navigate grant application processes, and partnering with Tribal Colleges and Universities to build capacity for Tribes to apply for funding.<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Commerce</strong> is investing nearly $50 billion in broadband infrastructure deployment, affordability, and digital inclusion efforts to help close the digital divide, particularly for rural and Tribal communities.<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Health and Human Services</strong> is increasing outreach to communities of color to encourage enrollment in free and low-cost health care, and is addressing the maternal mortality crisis that disproportionately impacts Black and Native families, including by working with states to extend postpartum coverage in Medicaid and the Children’s Health Insurance Program.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Homeland Security</strong> is working to ensure that&nbsp;underserved communities are treated fairly in airport screenings by improving systems and enhancing training for&nbsp;officers. DHS is also engaging with and improving underserved communities’ access to grant programs that help counter domestic violent extremism to better address the terrorism-related threat to our country posed by white supremacists and other domestic terrorists.<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Defense</strong> is advancing the safe and equitable use of Artificial Intelligence (AI) technology to mitigate algorithmic bias by investing in agency-wide responsible AI development and investing in the development of a more diverse AI workforce, including through partnerships with Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) and Minority Serving Institutions (MSIs).<br></li><li>The <strong>State Department</strong> is increasing engagement with partners from underserved racial and ethnic communities, applying new equity analyses, and improving demographic data collection and analysis to better embed equity and gender equality into U.S. foreign policies.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Veterans Affairs</strong> is advancing health equity by further addressing the social and economic determinants of health for underserved&nbsp;veterans, including veterans of color, women veterans, and LGBTQI+ veterans. The Department is also launching a Data for Equity strategy, a veteran-centered model that will synchronize data on health care, disability benefits, and other services to identify and address gaps.<br></li><li>The <strong>U.S. Department of Agriculture</strong> is expanding equitable access to nutrition assistance programs and strengthening gender equity by implementing a national awareness campaign and expanding the implementation of online ordering in the&nbsp;Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) nutrition program.<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Education</strong> is advancing college access and college completion by investing in HBCUs, TCCUs, MSIs, community colleges, and other under-resourced public institutions, and supporting schools to raise college completion rates for underserved students.<br></li><li>The <strong>Department of Energy</strong> is ensuring equitable access to weatherization assistance programs so that low-income households have increased access to energy security.<br></li><li>The <strong>Small Business Administration</strong> is investing in improved technology to increase access to capital for businesses in underserved communities and minority-owned businesses by streamlining program applications and integrating data.<br></li><li>The <strong>National Aeronautics and Space Administration</strong> (NASA) is releasing Earth science data in more accessible formats, and providing free, multi-lingual training on how to use NASA data to help mitigate environmental challenges in underserved communities. NASA will also conduct an analysis to identify and address barriers to awards of its grants to HBCUs and MSIs.<br></li><li>The <strong>Social Security Administration</strong> is identifying inequalities and addressing systemic administrative barriers to participation in key safety net programs, such as disability benefits, and ensuring equitable service delivery for unrepresented individuals navigating the disability application appeals process, and increase gender equity in its services.<br></li><li>The <strong>Federal Emergency Management Agency</strong> (FEMA) is closing the flood insurance gap to increase the financial resilience of flood-prone, low-income households. FEMA is also promoting equitable outcomes for disaster survivors by increasing eligibility for and access to assistance programs for underserved and vulnerable applicants.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Embedding Equity in the Everyday Business of Government</strong><br><br>In addition to prioritizing greater equity in the services the federal government provides the American people, Agency Equity Action Plans also contain innovative new strategies to embed equity, racial justice, and gender equality in day-to-day governing. These approaches include:<br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Building accountability for equity through data collection and reporting. </strong>Better demographic data is key to advancing equity, offering insight into whether government programs, benefits, and services are reaching all communities. Recognizing this, President Biden established a first-of-its-kind Equitable Data Working Group to facilitate appropriate expanded collection and use of demographic data toward advancing equity. Cross-agency practices are being developed to address specific barriers to generating and using equitable data efficiently and appropriately, including how best to share and acquire disaggregated data and how to increase community access to data while protecting individual privacy and promoting public trust in the data. More information on the Working Group’s efforts, including initial recommendations, will be released in the coming weeks.<br></li><li><strong>Reducing administrative burdens and simplifying government services.</strong> Under newly-released <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/M-22-10.pdf">guidance</a> from the Office of Management and Budget, agencies are reducing the complexity of forms and enrollment procedures to address the often-hidden barriers to access for governmental services, ensuring that information is written clearly, and expanding from in-person interview requirements to telephone or virtual options.<br></li><li><strong>Reimagining federal service design and delivery through life experiences. </strong>&nbsp;The Biden-Harris Administration is building a new approach to delivering government services based on how people actually live their lives rather than an approach based on bureaucracy. This new approach requires agencies to work within and across government, to better serve Americans during significant events or transitions that often require interaction with multiple federal agencies and levels of government, like surviving a disaster.<br></li><li><strong>Engaging with stakeholders and communities who have been historically excluded</strong>. To ensure government policies are informed by the broadest cross-section of Americans, agencies are engaging trusted intermediaries and tailoring outreach to make meaningful and authentic participation possible for a wider range of Americans.<br></li><li><strong>Narrowing wealth gaps through federal contracting and procurement</strong>. As the largest buyer in the world, the federal government will address racial and gender wealth gaps by leveraging the power of federal procurement to drive greater investment in minority-owned and women-owned small businesses.<br></li><li><strong>Delivering equity through grantmaking</strong>. Persistent barriers make it difficult for under-resourced and underserved communities to be aware of, compete for, and effectively deploy federal grants for everything from infrastructure to medical research. Agencies are addressing these barriers by helping underserved communities learn about and navigate federal funding opportunities, expanding capacity-building efforts, and embedding a focus on equity into decision-making about how to award federal grants.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing equity through American Rescue Plan and Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Implementation</strong>. The President has made equity a priority in the implementation of two of the most ambitious legislative packages in generations, with the goal of ensuring an inclusive response and recovery from the pandemic and in rebuilding our nation’s infrastructure.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting the Child Tax Credit Right for Puerto Rico: The American Rescue Plan’s Permanent, Historic Changes to Tax Relief in Puerto&#160;Rico</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2022/04/14/getting-the-child-tax-credit-right-for-puerto-rico-the-american-rescue-plans-permanent-historic-changes-to-tax-relief-in-puerto-rico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 12:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By Gene Sperling, American Rescue Plan Coordinator and Senior Advisor to the President A deeply troubling truth in the American tax system over the last 25 years is that the children of Puerto Rico were never given equal status when it came to the Child Tax Credit. Since its passage in 1997, the Child Tax&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>By Gene Sperling, American Rescue Plan Coordinator and Senior Advisor to the President</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>A deeply troubling truth in the American tax system over the last 25 years is that the children of Puerto Rico were never given equal status when it came to the Child Tax Credit.</p>



<p>Since its passage in 1997, the Child Tax Credit was expanded and made gradually larger and more refundable for families with children in the 50 states and the District of Columbia. But it never reached the vast majority of Puerto Rico’s children – because Puerto Rico families were only eligible for the Child Tax Credit if they had three or more qualifying children. This limited eligibility meant less attention and focus and awareness even among families who were eligible.</p>



<p>The sad reality is that while well over 50% of Puerto Rico’s children were in poverty, <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/blog/tax-credit-expansions-expected-to-significantly-reduce-poverty-in-puerto-rico" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">only 10%</a> of the commonwealth’s families with children were eligible for the Child Tax Credit.</p>



<p>That all changed with the passage of the American Rescue Plan. For the first time ever, this year, all families in Puerto Rico – regardless of the number of children in their family – are eligible for the Child Tax Credit on the same basis as families in the 50 states and the District of Columbia. The difference is extraordinary. This tax filing season, <a href="https://mcusercontent.com/35b40b9cf147af1ed5717180c/files/812ac348-c1a4-ce60-c924-7856ccbe747e/Child_Tax_Credit_impacto_trascendental_a_las_familias_conmenores_IDJ_enero_2022_.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">97% of Puerto Rico’s families</a> are eligible for the expanded credit.</p>



<p>Ensuring all families in Puerto Rico file to receive the expanded Child Tax Credit this filing season is especially critical because in addition to increasing the Child Tax Credit to $3,600 for children under 6 and $3,000 for older children for tax year 2021, the American Rescue Plan made the Child Tax Credit fully refundable for all children. That means that the families of nearly <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/Treasury-and-IRS-Announce-Families-of-Nearly-60-Million-Children-Receive-%2415-Billion-Dollars-in-First-Payments-of-Expanded-and-Newly-Advanceable-Child-Tax-Credit" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">27 million children</a> nationwide – including <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/build-back-betters-child-tax-credit-changes-would-protect-millions-from" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">roughly half</a> of Black and Latino children – are receiving the full expanded Child Tax Credit, who would have previously received just a partial or no credit because they earned too little. And because Puerto Rico’s families were not able to receive monthly payments in 2021, those filing will receive the entire expanded credit as a lump sum, making filing this year all the more critical.</p>



<p>Perhaps what is most consequential and not fully understood is that the American Rescue Plan <em>permanently</em> ensures that, from now on, the children of Puerto Rico will be on equal footing with children elsewhere in the United States for the Child Tax Credit. While the Child Tax Credit in Puerto Rico will be more impactful with the President’s proposal to extend the expansion of the Child Tax Credit, and particularly full refundability, the principle of equal treatment is in law, forever, due to the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>This comes at a time when we have at long last ensured that workers in Puerto Rico will also be treated equally by the Earned Income Tax Credit (EITC). Before this year, Puerto Rico’s locally administered EITC, when it was available, had never received federal support – and as a result, the credit was significantly smaller than the federal EITC. While Puerto Rico workers will still claim their EITC through their commonwealth government, the American Rescue Plan is helping Puerto Rico fund a dramatic 10-year expansion of the credit. The American Rescue Plan is providing $600 million in annual federal dollars on top of $200 million in Puerto Rico tax dollars, allowing Puerto Rico to more than triple available EITC benefits for workers. This expansion increased the maximum EITC for a family with two children from $1,500 to $5,500 – bringing the credit broadly in line with the maximum benefit available to a similar family living elsewhere in the United States.</p>



<p>That’s why getting the word out in Puerto Rico about the importance of filing has been a top priority for the Government of Puerto Rico, major non-profit advocates, and those of us involved in the implementation of the American Rescue Plan. It is why the White House and the Treasury Department have worked with the Governor of Puerto Rico and Mayors and in constant partnership with key groups including the Youth Development Institute (IDJ), Espacios Abiertos, United Way of Puerto Rico, and the Hispanic Federation. And it is why we co-host a weekly call with UnidosUS that brings together government officials and non-profits and foundations from Washington D.C. to San Juan to coordinate outreach and work through barriers to getting wide sign up for the Child Tax Credit and the Earned Income Tax Credit.</p>



<p>The process hasn’t been perfect, but this working group of government officials and non-profits in Washington and Puerto Rico has stayed at it. The data we have so far shows dramatic improvement. We now expect ten times as many families with children to have filed for the Child Tax Credit this tax season as in previous years. This alone should have a major impact on lowering the child poverty rate in Puerto Rico.</p>



<p>That’s also why this week, First Lady Jill Biden, Education Secretary Miguel Cardona, House Chairwoman Nydia Velazquez, Deputy Secretary of the Treasury Wally Adeyemo, and I held an event along with the leading non-profits in Puerto Rico to do a final push for Puerto Rico families to file for the expanded Child Tax Credit and Earned Income Tax Credit benefits before the filing deadline.</p>



<p>And for families who do not file over the next week, we are working with Code for America to launch a simplified filing portal for families to claim the Child Tax Credit that will be available through the fall. The more successful we are in ensuring every eligible household in Puerto Rico gets the Child Tax Credit and the Earned Income Tax Credit, the more we meet the President’s goal to lift up every American, to ensure parents in Puerto Rico have, as the President says, “a little more breathing room” when raising their children, and the more we will significantly reduce the number of children living in poverty.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
