<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 01:49:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Inaugural Ceremony of the Ninth Summit of the&#160;Americas </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-inaugural-ceremony-of-the-ninth-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 01:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft TheaterLos Angeles, California 5:36 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Good evening.  Good evening.  (Applause.)  Well, I know our future is bright when I look at these young leaders. Governor Gavin Newsom, thank you for that introduction.  It is, of course, so good to be back in my home state of California.  (Applause.) And to everyone here,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Microsoft Theater<br><em>Los Angeles, California</em></em></p>



<p>5:36 P.M. PDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Good evening.  Good evening.  (Applause.)  Well, I know our future is bright when I look at these young leaders.<br> <br>Governor Gavin Newsom, thank you for that introduction. <br> <br>It is, of course, so good to be back in my home state of California.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And to everyone here, on behalf of our administration, it is my honor to officially welcome you to the ninth Summit of the Americas.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And, of course, we are here together with world leaders; local elected officials, including our host city Mayor Garcetti; business and civil society leaders; and, of course, the President of the United States, Joe Biden.  (Applause.)<br>    <br>As many of you may know, I am a proud daughter of California.  I represented this state as Attorney General and as a United States Senator.  And I am proud to call Los Angeles my home. <br> <br>As Vice President, I am pleased to acknowledge, as the Governor mentioned, California is a place where ambitions and dreams become reality.<br>  <br>And so, we all gather in Los Angeles this week for the Summit of the Americas with big ambitions &#8212; ambitions that began 28 years ago in Miami at the first-ever Summit of the Americas, when our nations, together, set the Western Hemisphere on a new path &#8212; a path to grow our economies and improve the lives of our people.  <br> <br>And together, we have made progress on this path &#8212; a path that I believe is critically important for so many of us and, I will speak, important for the American people, because the Western Hemisphere directly affects the security and prosperity of the United States.<br> <br>And so, this week, we gather once more to build a more prosperous and inclusive future.   <br> <br>I look out at this room, and I see representatives of so many different countries and communities. <br> <br>We are joined, of course, by heads of state, and we are joined by youth leaders.  We are joined by CEOs, and we are joined labor organizers, women entrepreneurs, activists, and advocates.<br> <br>So here’s how I see it: To realize a more prosperous future for our hemisphere, partnerships between those assembled here are essential.<br> <br>It is in this spirit that I have focused on bringing companies and organizations together to collaborate and coordinate and share lessons learned, and to galvanize billions of dollars in new investments.<br> <br>The challenges facing our hemisphere in the months and years ahead are significant: the climate crisis, food insecurity, economic inequality, corruption, and gender-based violence. <br> <br>When I think about these challenges, I know and I am certain they will require new and innovative coalitions to solve, which is why President Joe Biden and I see this week as an opportunity for all of us &#8212; an opportunity to launch new initiatives, to begin new conversations, and to build new partnerships.<br> <br>So let us enjoy this evening and to also commit ourselves to taking advantage of this time that we spend together under the same roof.  At this convening, let us build a more prosperous and inclusive future for the entire Western Hemisphere.<br> <br>Thank you and welcome.  (Applause.)  <br> <br>END                 5:40 P.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After Tour of Dream Big Children&#8217;s&#160;Center </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-tour-of-dream-big-childrens-center/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 23:58:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dream Big Children’s CenterMonrovia, California Q    All right.  Madam Vice President, welcome home. THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Hi, Alex.  Good to be home.  Q    Good to have you back in California. THE VICE PRESIDENT:  It’s really great to be home. Q    What does it mean for you to be at a summit like this in your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Dream Big Children’s Center<br><em>Monrovia, California</em></em></p>



<p>Q    All right.  Madam Vice President, welcome home.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Hi, Alex.  Good to be home. <br><br>Q    Good to have you back in California.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  It’s really great to be home.<br><br>Q    What does it mean for you to be at a summit like this in your home state, as one of the leaders of it?  And what are you most excited about in terms of the summit?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So I&#8217;ll talk about the summit.  But let&#8217;s just first talk about this business, because Dream Big &#8212; I&#8217;ve been hearing about this business and this business owner.  It’s a small business right here in the heart of California. She now has five.  And it&#8217;s a business that serves the parents and the children of the community, in particular special needs children.<br><br>And the reason that I&#8217;ve been hearing about her work is not only because of what she does in such a loving way to help parents parent, but she did it through the pandemic when she, for just a short while, was, you know, under the threat that so many small businesses were of closing. <br><br>And the parents that she serves were desperate to know that she would be able to stay open.  And she did.  And parents bring their children here five days a week for four hours a day.  The parents of this community rely on the support that she gives their children throughout these early stages of their development.  And if she had to close down, it would have had a profound if not lifelong impact on those children, much less their families.<br><br>So I&#8217;m here to highlight the importance of our small businesses, because they do this out of love, out of concern, and being a member of the community, and with a sense of responsibility to the community.<br><br>And I&#8217;m also here to highlight then that it is small businesses like this that have been supported through our Small Business Administration, the administrators here, because we give loans that are able to help these businesses grow and then expand the service they provide to the community.<br><br>So I&#8217;m here to talk about that and also the importance of the PPP program, which allowed her to stay open through the height of the crisis of the pandemic.<br><br>On the summit: So one of the important components of the summit, from my perspective, is the work that we&#8217;ve been doing with the Call to Action, which is bringing CEOs together at historic numbers to invest in the northern part of Central America. <br>And we announced yesterday that as a result of the work that we only started a year ago, we&#8217;ve already raised $3.2 billion, which is about investing in these countries that are our neighbors, as the United States &#8212; because we are also a member of the Western Hemisphere.<br><br>And one of the things that is without question: When we are able to improve the prosperity and stability of our neighbors, we as a nation benefit.  So the work that we have been doing in the summit has been to bring CEOs together, heads of state of a number of the organiz- &#8212; of the countries in the Western Hemisphere are going to be here, to talk about how we can continue to collaborate.<br>But specifically on the issue of the economic investment that our CEOs are making, specifically on this subject of the beauty and strength of public-private partnerships, I&#8217;m very excited about the work that is being done and that will continue to be done.<br><br>Q    And especially great to be here (inaudible).<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  And it&#8217;s &#8212; in particular, yeah, it&#8217;s kind of nice that it just happens to be in Los Angeles, where I live.  So it&#8217;s been nice to be home for a change.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Young Leaders on Reproductive Justice and Civil&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-young-leaders-on-reproductive-justice-and-civil-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 23:22:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55156</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, the White House Office of Public Engagement, the White House Gender Policy Council, and the Office of the Vice President convened a meeting with young leaders on reproductive health and rights. Participants discussed the devastating consequences that overturning&#160;Roe v Wade&#160;would have on young people, who overwhelmingly support reproductive rights, which have been guaranteed under&#160;Roe&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, the White House Office of Public Engagement, the White House Gender Policy Council, and the Office of the Vice President convened a meeting with young leaders on reproductive health and rights. Participants discussed the devastating consequences that overturning&nbsp;<em>Roe v Wade</em>&nbsp;would have on young people, who overwhelmingly support reproductive rights, which have been guaranteed under&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade&nbsp;</em>for nearly 50 years and are integral to equality and full opportunity.&nbsp;&nbsp; Advocates highlighted the importance of mobilizing and organizing young people in support of reproductive freedom, including on college campuses.</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials highlighted the President’s commitment to supporting reproductive health and rights and the Administration’s commitment to including young people in conversations on this critical issue and other key priorities.</p>



<p>Participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Advocates for Youth</li><li>Generation Progress</li><li>Generation Ratify</li><li>Gen Z For Change</li><li>Planned Parenthood</li><li>Unite for Reproductive &amp; Gender Equity (URGE)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Los Angeles,&#160;CA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/08/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-los-angeles-ca/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 22:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55150</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Los Angeles, California 1:51 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Okay.  Hey, everybody.  I have a topper for you, and then I’ll hand it over to Jake.  Okay.&#160; Whoa.&#160; Thanks for joining us for our trip to Los Angeles where the President looks forward to &#8212; (eye glasses fall off) &#8212; that&#8217;s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>1:51 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Okay.  Hey, everybody.  I have a topper for you, and then I’ll hand it over to Jake. </p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us for our trip to Los Angeles where the President looks forward to &#8212; (eye glasses fall off) &#8212; that&#8217;s not good &#8212; looks forward to hosting fellow leaders from throughout our hemisphere.</p>



<p>The United States actually hosted the first Summit of Americas in Miami in 1994.&nbsp; Now 28 years later, we are meeting to talk about some of the most pressing challenges of our time.&nbsp;&nbsp; The summit will focus on building a sustainable, resilient, and equitable future for our hemisphere.&nbsp; The summit is a place to discuss and advance solutions that help &#8212; that will help the people of the region.</p>



<p>On that note, we&#8217;ve worked hard over the last several months to negotiate hemispheric consensus on several topics.&nbsp; As you &#8212; as you may have seen, this morning we announced investments the United States is making to strengthen the region&#8217;s health systems and health security.</p>



<p>The pandemic revealed the many cracks in our global health systems and underscored the importance of strong, resilient, and accessible health systems for the entire population, health security, and pandemic preparedness and response.</p>



<p>Tonight, the President will announce the APEP, the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity &#8212; APEP.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have a preview tonight at 7:30 p.m. Pacific Time of deliverables to expect tomorrow.</p>



<p>And right now, I will hand it over to Jake Sullivan, the President’s National Security Advisor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And hold on, guys &#8212; it’s bumpy.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sorry we&#8217;re doing this in the middle of a slightly bumpy ride.&nbsp; So, as Karine said, the U.S. hosted the first Summit of the Americas back in 1994.&nbsp; And this is our second opportunity to host it some 28 years later.</p>



<p>It comes at a moment when the United States and many of our partners in the region are looking to pursue an affirmative vision for the hemisphere that will lead to an Americas that is secure, middle class, and democratic &#8212; from Canada to Chile and everywhere in between &#8212; but also at a moment of profound challenge, as we emerge from the COVID-19 pandemic, as we deal with the climate crisis, as we deal with the pressures of food prices, energy, and so much else.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, much of the substance of this summit is designed to tackle the challenges this region is facing head on.&nbsp; And in five areas, we will have significant, substantive deliverables in food, health, in climate, in economic growth, and on migration.</p>



<p>On food, the United States will be announcing $300 million &#8212; and the President will talk about this tonight, and then it will be rolled out in the days ahead &#8212; $300 million in food security financing, both for the acute challenges the region is facing right now and also to help build more resilient food systems to be able to withstand future shocks.</p>



<p>In addition, we&#8217;ll have a number of countries signing up to the Roadmap for Food Security that Secretary Blinken launched at the United Nations a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp; And this region is home to some of the largest food-producing countries in the world, and we&#8217;ll be working with our partners to come together around a shared declaration for how we can leverage the agricultural capacity of the Americas to help address the global food security issue.</p>



<p>On climate, the President will announce, and then the Vice President will lead, a Caribbean climate partnership that&#8217;s focused on two things: first, greater energy security, as we go through the transition, by getting Caribbean countries access to low-carbon energy sources; and second, climate adaptation and resilience.&nbsp; And the specifics of that will be laid out in a launch event that the Vice President hosts, I believe tomorrow, Thursday.</p>



<p>On health, the President will announce an initiative to help train 500,000 health workers in the Americas over the next five years so that they are equipped and empowered to be able to deal with a range of health challenges, including the remaining challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic, but also much more than that.&nbsp; That will be in partnership with the Pan American Health Organization.</p>



<p>On migration, the President will host a number of other countries, a number of other leaders for the announcement of the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection, which will lay out in four pillars an approach to a migration management that is rooted in shared responsibility and involves source countries, transit countries, and destination countries for the first time ever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We regard this as an unprecedented set of statements and actions by the countries of the region to deal with a hemispheric crisis that is affecting all of the countries of the hemisphere, not just the United States, and for which all of the countries in the hemisphere need to step up and help solve the problem.&nbsp; And the Los Angeles Declaration will be a very strong step in the direction of doing that.</p>



<p>Accompanying the declaration, the U.S. will have a variety of specific announcements on labor pathways, on cracking down on smuggling networks, and other steps that we will take.&nbsp; And other countries also will be making announcements to show that they&#8217;re putting skin in the game to help address this challenge.</p>



<p>And then, finally, as Karine mentioned on economic growth, we&#8217;ll be launching the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity tonight.&nbsp; And we will have a number of countries putting out supportive statements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This builds on the chain of free trade agreements we already have in the hemisphere.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s really designed to deal with 21st century challenges like supply chains and decarbonization, but also a vision of economic growth that is rooted in President Biden&#8217;s principles about economic growth having to come from the bottom up and the middle out rather than the top down.&nbsp; And we think that that will be highly welcomed in the hemisphere.</p>



<p>One of the elements of the Americas Partnership that we think is very significant and will have lasting effects is institutional reform of the Inter-American Development Bank &#8212; adjusting the way in which concessional financing is done, increasing the United States’ commitment to the private sector arm of the IDB, and also bringing other international financial institutions more into the work of the hemisphere, including the IMF.</p>



<p>So there will be some meaty elements to this economic partnership, in addition to setting forth a plan to end up discussing and then negotiating arrangements with other countries on issues like supply chain resilience and decarbonization of the economy.</p>



<p>So, again, on these five areas &#8212; food, health, climate, migration, economic growth &#8212; we think we will have a potent story to tell.&nbsp; And that story won&#8217;t be words, it will be actions both taken and pledged at this summit.&nbsp; And at the end of it, we’ll be better positioned to deal with the major challenges facing the &#8212; facing the hemisphere than we were going in.</p>



<p>So let me stop there, and I’m happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, a question on Venezuela.&nbsp; So why was Guaidó not invited?&nbsp; Did the Mexican President ask for him not to be invited?</p>



<p>And separately, what is the status of negotiations between the opposition and the Maduro regime at this point?&nbsp; Is there some indication that things might be stalled?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, we’re not responding to anything from President López Obrador when it comes to the invitation of Guaidó.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that he made any specific ask on that one way or the other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what I will say is the following: First, we continue to recognize Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela.&nbsp; Second, we support a Venezuelan-led dialogue that leads to free and fair elections and a better future for the Venezuelan people.</p>



<p>And third, we thought the best way to lift up our desire to see that Venezuelan-led dialogue and, ultimately, a better future for the Venezuelan people was to focus on the invitations to Venezuelan civil society activists who will participate in various aspects of the summit.</p>



<p>I also anticipate that President Biden will speak with Guaidó at some point here, and we&#8217;ll keep you posted on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, then on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know when it’s going to happen?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I can’t tell you right now.</p>



<p>In terms of the actual negotiations, I&#8217;ll leave it to the two sides to lay out where they are.&nbsp; The United States has made clear that we support the return to those talks, and we&#8217;re prepared to take steps if those talks move forward.</p>



<p>We still believe that there is scope for that to happen.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s ultimately going to be up to the two sides to make it happen and &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of those talks, it makes it sound like they&#8217;re not happening right now, that there is a (inaudible).</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry, by “those talks,” I mean Mexico City.&nbsp; Obviously, the two sides are in communication about getting back to Mexico City and getting a more formal political process underway that can ultimately lead to the outcome that we&#8217;re seeking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And let me just follow up on Venezuela very quickly.&nbsp; So &#8212; and what&#8217;s the status of our negotiations with Venezuela as far as getting them involved in getting oil and gas supply to the region and the energy crisis that we&#8217;re in right now?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, our position on this is quite clear. We&#8217;ve made it clear to them privately &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said it personally, publicly &#8212; which is that we&#8217;re prepared to take steps if they take steps, but it has to be action for action.&nbsp; And the first critical step would be to come to some set of agreements with the opposition that showed good faith, that showed progress, and then then gets meaningful traction going in a political dialogue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Where do Venezuelan hostages &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Brazil, real quickly: How does the President plan to handle, you know, President Bolsonaro’s climate record when he meets with him at the summit, and also the comments that he&#8217;s made about not only perhaps casting a question on his own reelection, but also on President Biden&#8217;s reelection?&nbsp; I think President Bolsonaro has actually said that President Biden shouldn&#8217;t bring up the topic.&nbsp; Does he plan to bring it up?&nbsp; And, again, how does he plan to handle those issues on Amazon and climate that they have disagreements on?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN: &nbsp;There are no topics off limits in any bilateral the President does, including with President Bolsonaro &#8212; first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, I do anticipate that the President will discuss open, free, fair, and transparent democratic elections.</p>



<p>Third, climate will be an important topic of conversation, and we believe that it can be an area of progress in the U.S.- Brazil relationship, particularly around concrete and tangible action to protect the Amazon.&nbsp; And the U.S. has already shown, going back to Glasgow, that we&#8217;re prepared to put a lot on the table when it comes to helping countries like Brazil protect the Amazon from further deforestation.</p>



<p>The President announced a major initiative on forests at Copenhagen.&nbsp; He pledged billions of dollars between now and 2030 to mobilize &#8212; that&#8217;s public dollars &#8212; to mobilize more private sector financing for the purpose of protecting the Amazon and other forests from further decarbonization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He supports the LEAF Coalition, which is all about a public-private effort to compensate landowners for not cutting down forests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And at this summit here, the Summit of the Americas, we&#8217;ll have a modest but meaningful slug of money particularly devoted to the Amazon for technical assistance and other purposes to help with protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of that, I think, should pave the way for a good-faith effort on the part of every country, every stakeholder in the Americas &#8212; Brazil included &#8212; to take the necessary action and the necessary responsibility.&nbsp; We’ll see what President Bolsonaro comes to the table with on his side.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, what kind of money &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say how much money is allocated for the Amazon?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, on &#8212; in terms of the commitment the President made at Glasgow, I believe the number is $9 billion globally.&nbsp; But a huge chunk of that would end up getting devoted to the Amazon, including &#8212; in terms of the announcement at the Summit of the Americas, I&#8217;ll come back to you with the precise dollar figure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on money, regarding the economic measures &#8212; I mean, the call today &#8212; there wasn&#8217;t much money discussed.&nbsp; I mean, does the plan really meet the moment of the day?&nbsp; I mean, you have China making more and more inroads there, basically with an open checkbook.&nbsp; I mean, what is &#8212; how does the administration, how does the United States compete with that?&nbsp; And what is Biden&#8217;s real vision in that area?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The United States has never seen its comparative advantage in the world as just leveraging huge numbers of state dollars, but rather leveraging all of the tools available to us &#8212; yes, some public financing, but really unlocking substantial amounts of private sector financing to be able to drive inclusive economic growth across the Americas.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what these countries most want.</p>



<p>So just as an example, at the summit, the President will make a financial commitment to IDB Invest, to the private sector financing arm of the Inter-American Development Bank.&nbsp; That will unlock significant amounts of private sector financing for infrastructure, for clean energy, for digital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on top of that, we will be putting specific dollars into producing tangible results that matter to people &#8212; training 500,000 workers, mobilizing hundreds of billions of dollars on food security.</p>



<p>When you tally all that up and look at the practical impact of what the summit deliverables from the United States will mean for the hemisphere, it is significantly more impactful on the actual lives and livelihoods of the people of this region than the kinds of extractive projects that China has been invested in.</p>



<p>So, we think we are mobilizing and coming to the table with a lot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will also add that one of the things he will talk to the leaders of the region about is a global infrastructure partnership that he first raised at the G7 last year and that he will formally launch at the G7 this year in just a few weeks’ time.&nbsp; That will include signature projects from major geographies around the world, including the Americas.</p>



<p>So, we believe that whether you&#8217;re talking about infrastructure, talking about food security, the clean energy transition, investments in health, and the use of the major multilateral investment tools &#8212; both the IDB and the World Bank and IMF &#8212; that, collectively, that is going to add up to a major investment by the United States and outcomes for the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on the immigration &#8212; on the migration declaration, how much support is the U.S. going to be providing to the countries that are willing to participate in this declaration and house migrants at various stages like you described?&nbsp; And what incentives are there for these countries to participate in this declaration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we have &#8212; and not to get ahead of the announcement with too much detail &#8212; but we are &#8212; have developed an innovative concessional financing facility that will be for countries that typically can&#8217;t get access to that kind of financing because they&#8217;re middle-income countries, but providing support on migration will unlock that.&nbsp; So, we think that provides one form of incentive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second form of incentive is that we&#8217;re putting on the table something that a lot of these countries are asking from us, which is labor pathways to the United States for both migrants transiting their countries and for the source countries, from citizens of their home country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’ll have announcements related to labor pathways as part of the Los Angeles Declaration and, actually, an interesting and very innovative new program between our Department of Agriculture and the United Farmworkers that is designed to ensure that those labor pathways meet the highest labor standards and are not used for abuse or for a race to the bottom.</p>



<p>So we think when you look at the set of things we&#8217;re putting on the table in conjunction with this declaration, and then the commitments other countries are signing up to along with the principles they will be signing on to with respect to the declaration itself, it amounts to a really significant paradigm shift in how the region is tackling this migration crisis.&nbsp; And I think people will look back at the Los Angeles Declaration as a new platform upon which we build a migration strategy collectively as a hemisphere for the years going forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we question how seriously Central America, though, is taking it if the three leaders of the Northern Triangle are not coming?&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s where most of the source &#8212; at least most of U.S. source of migration is coming.&nbsp; But those leaders are not coming.&nbsp; I mean, does that &#8212; is that a sign that they are not as committed to this as the United States?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a sign at all.&nbsp; They&#8217;re all coming.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll all be represented.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not the leaders.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The leaders are not coming for each individual idiosyncratic reason, none of which has to do with the migration issue.&nbsp; And in each case, those countries have committed to working with the United States in a collaborative way on the migration issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Mexico, whose leader also is not coming and will be represented at the foreign minister level, who will similarly be signing on to the Los Angeles Declaration, is making its own commitments with respect to what it&#8217;s doing on the migration front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I think there&#8217;s no way you can look the substantive outcomes of the summit and find that there is a link between the lack of leader-level representation from those countries and what those countries’ commitments are on the migration question.</p>



<p>And then finally, just on López Obrador: He&#8217;ll be coming to D.C. in July &#8212; actually, specifically to build on summit outcomes like this one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the substantive work of the summit has in no way, shape, or form been touched or adjusted or reduced by the participation question.&nbsp; These two things are operating in entirely distinct lanes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we&#8217;re happy to have senior-level participation from each of these countries, even though the leaders, each for their own reason, has chosen not to come to Los Angeles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up on migration very quickly?&nbsp; You mentioned the labor pathways initiatives that you have.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; any of that going to require congressional approval?</p>



<p>And, two, will it deal with the severe labor shortage that the United States has had for some time?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to pretend like what we announced today is going to solve the whole of the systematic challenge that we have, but it will make a &#8212; it will help us make progress on it.&nbsp; It will.</p>



<p>And then, the specific announcements we&#8217;re making don&#8217;t require new congressional legislation. &nbsp;But more broadly, we are looking to Congress to step up and be a partner on a bipartisan basis on the migration question in a way that they &#8212; that we haven&#8217;t seen over the course of the last year.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, does the absence of some of those Central American leaders undermine the role of the Vice President in building ties with them and in helping to combat some of the root cause issues of migration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think you really have to look to see what those countries are signing up to, what they are committing to on the major priorities of the United States and the major priorities to the Americas.&nbsp; And if you look at the substantive agenda, substantive outcomes, and where they&#8217;re putting their name on the bottom line, it shows that they&#8217;re invested in the agenda we&#8217;ve set forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact that their leaders aren&#8217;t coming is, in each case, its own reflection of, again, these idiosyncratic decisions each of them are making, and I honestly wouldn&#8217;t read too much into it one way or the other.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on (inaudible) actions, right now it doesn&#8217;t look like the President has a press conference on his schedule at the end of this summit, which we&#8217;re hosting.&nbsp; What message does that lead to &#8212; give to our neighbors about democracy, freedom of the press, especially to those neighbors that we&#8217;re trying to encourage to change their ways?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I mean, the President &#8212; I have now accompanied him on multiple foreign trips.&nbsp; This one is not foreign, although it involves foreign policy.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;d be hard to argue that he hasn&#8217;t taken many, many questions from the press.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;ll be, over the course of the next three days, obviously in front of and addressing the press in various ways.&nbsp; And I think by the end of this, you can be pretty confident that he will be displaying &#8212; putting on full display America&#8217;s raucous democracy in all of its wonderful and attractive forms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t see the kind of formal press conference issue as a particular litmus test.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question on democracy.&nbsp; I mean, given that a number of leaders are not coming because of concerns about authoritarian governments not being invited, does the administration see a fracturing of the consensus around democracy, given that previous summits have had a sort of a consensus that non-democratic governments were not going to be invited?&nbsp; Is there a concern about backsliding in the hemisphere &#8212; a concern that, you know, you&#8217;re not really getting that same push for democracy that you used to have?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think this doesn&#8217;t have to do with the fundamental question of democracy.&nbsp; I think it has to do with a difference of opinion &#8212; a diversity of opinion, frankly &#8212; across the hemisphere &#8212; frankly, across our Congress, across the American public sphere &#8212; as to what the right way to approach the invitation of a dictator or a non-invitation of a dictator is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s really, kind of, more of a question about the role and purpose of participation in a summit like this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a question about whether democracy is a good form of government or a bad form of government.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You don’t see that eroding?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You don’t see that eroding in the hemisphere &#8212; the support for democracy?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I definitely see challenges to democracy in the hemisphere; there&#8217;s no doubt.&nbsp; We see challenges to democracy all over the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And part of what the President wants to send a strong message of at this summit is that the United States is put &#8212; is putting its shoulder to the wheel in terms of supporting democratic principles and, very critically, that as the host of the summit, we are going to lift up a vision for the hemisphere that is fundamentally democratic.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On a different topic from a colleague: Can you respond to the react- &#8212; get a reaction on Tehran moving two of the IAEA monitoring cameras from its nuclear site?&nbsp; How will this &#8212; will this impact the resumption of Vienna talks?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We see the issue of the IAEA compliance by Iran with its Safeguards agreement, with its obligations at the NPT, and its negotiations with Grossi &#8212; particularly on the files that Grossi has expressed concerns about and that the board is speaking to today &#8212; as operating on one track.&nbsp; On another track is a negotiated resolution to Iran’s nuclear program through a compliance-for-compliance return to the JCPOA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From our perspective, we have to view these on separate tracks, and that’s how we’re going to proceed.&nbsp; What actually happens in those negotiations is something we will see.&nbsp; But there is, in our view, a deal on the table that would effectuate a compliance-for-compliance return to the JCPOA without dealing with extraneous issues.&nbsp; That deal is available to Iran.&nbsp; They should take it.&nbsp; If they don&#8217;t, that&#8217;s on them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Yellen said today that the administration is working to recalibrate tariffs on China.&nbsp; And she also said there&#8217;s consideration of an oil price cap on Russia.&nbsp; On both those items, can you give us a timeline of when there might be a decision?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on the oil cap in particular, is that something you&#8217;re aiming to finalize at the G7 later this month?&nbsp; And how much buy-in do you have from European partn- &#8212; or, I guess, partners outside of Europe?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I won&#8217;t go beyond what Secretary Yellen said generally because we want to be able to protect space for intensive consultations with our European partners.&nbsp; Those are taking place in multiple channels, but one of the channels is in the G7 Sherpa channel.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;ll see what kind of progress we make generally on the question of energy at multiple different options for reducing revenue to Russia that could be available to us as the G7 over the course of the next three weeks.</p>



<p>On the question of China tariffs, all I will say is there have been &#8212; I think the last time I was on this plane with some of you, I said we &#8212; the President has been presented with a variety of views on this.&nbsp; He’s sought more information.&nbsp; He&#8217;s actively considering options.&nbsp; He said that himself when we were in Tokyo.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you, but I don&#8217;t expect that it will &#8212; this will go on indefinitely.&nbsp; He will make a decision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on Ukraine &#8212; Jake, are you &#8212; is the U.S. concerned about the advance of Russian troops in the Luhansk region in the eastern part of the country?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you also just announced the NATO meeting &#8212; the trip the President will be taking later in the month.&nbsp; How difficult is it for the U.S. to maintain the Alliance, given the length of this war, the fact that fuel prices are going up in Europe, you know, the fact that we&#8217;ve seen some concern among France and Germany about providing Ukraine with longer-range weapons?&nbsp; Can you talk about just the strength of the unity right now?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s interesting &#8212; there is this natural instinct, I think, in the commentariat and in the press to presume the inevitable decline in Western unity, resolve, staying power.&nbsp; But all facts are to the contrary, as we stand here today.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve got European nations making new announcements of security assistance day by day.&nbsp; You have the European Union coming together not a month ago, but a week ago, to announce a far-reaching new package of sanctions, including on energy.</p>



<p>So, the notion that there is somehow, you know, signs of cracking or division or disunity, I think, is belied by what we&#8217;re actually seeing.&nbsp; And I think that both the G7 and NATO will be very impressive signs of strength and resolve.</p>



<p>And let&#8217;s remember also that the United States has allocated $40 billion to this effort.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not for a week or a month or three months; that is a commitment that we&#8217;re &#8212; will endure for many months to come and put us in a position to continue to very strongly support the Ukrainians.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re concerned by every act of aggression the Russians have undertaken, every inch of Ukrainian territory they sit upon, they wreck, they bomb, they destroy, both in the areas they&#8217;re moving on the ground and in the areas they’re raining missiles down on from afar.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so committed to providing the necessary equipment and tools to the Ukrainians to be able to resist Russian advances in where they can push them back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are we in a fundamentally different place when it comes to the willingness of OPEC-Plus to finally support the global economic recovery, as you&#8217;ve been asking them to do?&nbsp; And do you take credit for that, in terms of your outreach to Saudi?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a question for OPEC-Plus.&nbsp; I will simply note that at the last OPEC-Plus meeting, there was a recognition that the supply issue needs to be addressed.&nbsp; And we expect that it will continue to be addressed as we go forward.</p>



<p>And how&#8217;s that for a super clear and specific answer?</p>



<p>But, you know, that&#8217;s &#8212; we thought this last meeting was important, positive.&nbsp; And we look forward to continue our consultations to see OPEC-Plus playing a constructive role as we go forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What factors are complicating a presidential visit to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I said: What factors are complicating a possible presidential visit to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don’t have any &#8212; anything for you on an &#8212; on a trip to Saudi Arabia today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll only say the President is going to travel to places and meet with people with whom he wants to work to help solve problems for the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President had any conversations with Putin?&nbsp; Any updates on that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President plan to go to Latin America?&nbsp; Obviously, he&#8217;s been occupied with things happening in Asia, with Europe.&nbsp; The Vice President has only been to Latin America twice so far.&nbsp; Any more trips to Latin America?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We’re literally on our way to the Summit of the Americas &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, but (inaudible) to Latin America.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; and your question is whether he&#8217;s paying attention to Latin America?&nbsp; I mean, a little unfair.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we can fairly say that spending the next two and a half days engaging with the leaders of the hemisphere and, even more importantly, engaging with the challenges and opportunities in the hemisphere will be a display of the President&#8217;s commitment on these issues.&nbsp; And there will be an enormous amount of follow-up that comes out of that, including, by the way, already-scheduled plans to see additional leaders like the President of Mexico and the President of Argentina.&nbsp; And I think you can expect further announcements of him welcoming Latin American leaders to Washington coming out of the next three days.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jamal Khashoggi’s widow is asking to meet with the President as a sign that he hasn’t given up on the legacy of the journalist.&nbsp; Is that something that the President would consider doing before he goes anywhere in the Middle East?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I don’t want to speculate on a trip, so I don’t want to speculate on anything he would do in preparation for a trip.&nbsp; But, of course, he takes not just the principle of human rights seriously, he takes the personal impact of human rights very seriously.&nbsp; And that will always be true of Joe Biden.</p>



<p>So, if and when we have anything to announce, I’ll let you know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any plans to bring up, when he has a meeting with the Brazilians, the searching for Dom Phillips?&nbsp; He was a BBC &#8212; or a British journalist who disappeared a few days ago in the Amazon.&nbsp; Is there any movement or intention to bring that up or encourage the government to help find him?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we have, at various levels of the U.S. government, reached out to say we&#8217;re prepared to do what we can to try to be helpful on this.</p>



<p>And I don&#8217;t know if the President will end up raising it, but we&#8217;ll ask our team.&nbsp; If that would be helpful, then of course he would do it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has there been any update on North Korea?&nbsp; Has the U.S. heard &#8212; received any response from the North Korean government?&nbsp; And as these tests have continued over the last few months, is that a sign that maybe this approach is not working and there needs to be some sort of change in a way to engage North Korea on this issue?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIAN:&nbsp; We have not heard from North Korea.&nbsp; We continue to obviously monitor and respond to the tests that they have been conducting.</p>



<p>One thing that it has done is only further cemented the strength of our alliances with both the ROK and Japan, and we&#8217;ve been able to conduct joint exercises with both of them in response to some of these launches.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also watching very closely the continuing possibility of a nuclear test, to which we would also have a robust response.</p>



<p>And otherwise, we cannot do anything other than take the course of action that we think is strong, steadfast, and clear.&nbsp; And that is an openness and willingness to engage in diplomacy if North Korea is prepared to come to the table, and an absolute and resolute commitment to defending our allies in the ROK and Japan.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the position we&#8217;ve taken.&nbsp; We think it&#8217;s the right position, and it&#8217;s a position we will sustain as we go forward.</p>



<p>And maybe I’ll take one more question.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, I know you&#8217;ve laid everything out &#8212; all of what you&#8217;re hoping to get out of &#8212; out of this summit.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the kind of boilerplate success, you know, you walk away at the end of a couple of days?&nbsp; What do you want the American people to know or take away from this summit?</p>



<p>Well, what I want people to know &#8212; it might sound a little nerdy, but I think it&#8217;s super important in this moment &#8212; and that is that for all of the people of the Americas, the same set of interconnected challenges are pressing them &#8212; are pressing on their families, on their livelihoods, and in some cases, on their lives.</p>



<p>And this summit needs to produce tangible action against each of those challenges.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where I started, and that&#8217;s where I&#8217;ll finish.&nbsp; It’s food, it’s energy and climate, it’s health, it’s migration, and it&#8217;s inclusive economic growth.</p>



<p>And I think you guys should measure us against whether or not we are producing tangible results on those five things.&nbsp; And I would challenge you to go back and look at the last five Summit of the Americas and look at the results of those, and ask whether, in fact, what we&#8217;ve done here will end up exceeding that in terms of the substance, the ambition, and the roadmap we set going forward.&nbsp; And I think the answer to that question is going to end up being “yes.”</p>



<p>So, thanks, guys.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; I already had a topper, so &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I&#8217;ve done that part.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any response to the arrest of a man outside &#8212; near Brett Kavanaugh’s house?&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve been standing here, we&#8217;ve seen that he&#8217;s been charged with attempted murder as well.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President condemns the actions of this individual in the strongest terms and is grateful to law enforcement for quickly taking him into custody.</p>



<p>As the President has consistently made clear, public officials, including judges, must be able to do their jobs without concern for their personal safety or that of their families.&nbsp; And any violence threats &#8212; threats of violence or attempts to intimidate justices have no place in our society.&nbsp; He has said that himself, and we have been forceful from the podium many times.</p>



<p>Attorney General Garland has also blasted any threats to the justices, saying, “The rise of violence and unlawful threats of violence directed at those who serve the public is unacceptable and dangerous to our democracy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Department of Justice has U.S. Marshals providing support to the Supreme Court Marshal, and the President supports legislation to fund increased scrutiny for the Court and judges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Department of Homeland Security has said they are working with their partners across every level of government and the private sector to share timely information and intelligence to prevent all forms of violence and to support law enforcement efforts to keep our communities safe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just a quick question about the President&#8217;s statement to us as we boarded Air Force One this morning.&nbsp; By validating the voter recall of San Francisco&#8217;s district attorney, is the President giving into a right-wing narrative about rampant crime that needs to be met with severe punishment?&nbsp; And what does it say about the prospects for criminal justice reform that an advocate of progressive prosecutions was tossed out?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, first of all &#8212; and I&#8217;m just going to reiterate a little bit of what he said.&nbsp; The voters last night delivered a clear message: It&#8217;s time for both parties to get more serious about fighting crime and gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is something that the President has said throughout his first 16 months &#8212; that that&#8217;s why he has never supported “defund the police” &#8212; he&#8217;s been clear about that &#8212; and why he sent state and local government billions of dollars last year through the American Rescue Plan to hire more police.&nbsp; He said that right before coming on board, speaking to all of you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s past time that they put that money to use hiring accountable, well-trained police officers.</p>



<p>And the president &#8212; you know, the President has asked Congress in March for more funds to beef up policing coast to coast.&nbsp; We continue to call on Congress to pass the President&#8217;s budget.</p>



<p>And finally, it&#8217;s important for the Senate to move on gun measures.&nbsp; He thinks those things go hand in hand, like the ones President Biden discussed yesterday while he met with Senator Murphy to get guns out of the hands of dangerous people.</p>



<p>We don’t &#8212; we don’t need a bunch of speeches today on crime; we need state officials to &#8212; and Congress to move.&nbsp; So, he sees those things hand in hand as we talk about gun reform as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, but none of the things you talked about, the &#8212; when the President ran, he talked about criminal justice reform, he talked about cash bail, but none of those things are part of the conversation anymore.&nbsp; Has the President given up on criminal justice reform because of &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, absolutely not.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the GOP narrative on crime?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What &#8212; he ac- &#8212; he signed &#8212; he signed an executive order to deal with police reform.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; I mean, he poli- &#8212; criminal justice reform is something that he has supported from the moment that that &#8212; the moment that legislators on the Hill started talking about coming together, trying to have something to move forward with in Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, he signed an executive action on police &#8212; police reform, on measures that we can do from the executive &#8212; from the federal &#8212; from the federal side of things, from the White House, from the administration.</p>



<p>So, clearly, he hasn&#8217;t given up on that.</p>



<p>On bail reform, as you were just asking me: You know, on the campaign trail &#8212; to your point, Trevor &#8212; the President said that cash bail has become the modern-day debtor’s prison. No one should be held just because they are poor. &nbsp;And a person who is dangerous but has the money to pay bail shouldn&#8217;t have a get-out-of-jail card free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I mean, he still stands by that, from what he said at the campaign trail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll take another question.&nbsp; Who else has a question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President looked pretty friendly at yesterday&#8217;s bill signing with Senator Manchin.&nbsp; They were joking around a little bit.&nbsp; He was standing right behind the President when it was signed.&nbsp; How would you characterize their relationship at this point?&nbsp; And can you give us a temperature check on reconciliation talks?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as &#8212; as we say, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here, not from Air Force One heading to LA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have to tell you, I missed &#8212; I missed that interaction because I was preparing to come back out for my second briefing in front of you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, look, we&#8217;ve said this many, many times: Senator Manchin and the President have a good relationship.&nbsp; They are friends.&nbsp; They are long &#8212; longtime friends, and that continues, and you saw it for your very own eyes yesterday at the &#8212; you know, at the White House.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything else to share on any of the negotiations that are happening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) between the President or Senator Manchin that you can read out or plan &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don’t to have anything to read out or to announce.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, there&#8217;s going to be new consumer price index data coming on Friday while the President is in Los Angeles.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the overall assessment of whether inflation is beginning to moderate?&nbsp; And are we going to see the President talking about this at the end of the week, after the numbers come out?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on the CPI data, which is what you&#8217;re asking about, Ken: Given the impact of Putin’s price hike at the pump on gas prices in May, we expect the headline inflation number to be elevated.&nbsp; And we expect the war in Ukraine to have some effects on core inflation too, particularly when you look at things like airfares and the effect of higher jet fuel costs.</p>



<p>But despite these disruptions and the fact that the numbers can be volatile from month to month, as we say &#8212; we say pretty regularly, we continue to believe that the economy can transition from what has been a historic recovery from &#8212; of the economy &#8212; to stable, steady growth and inflationary pressures moderating, which is what experts have been saying for some time now.</p>



<p>And we are already &#8212; we already begin to see this happen in a range of measures.&nbsp; For example, core PCE, which is the inflation measure the Fed watches most closely, was around 4 percent at an &#8212; at an annualized rate in the last three months and is down from 6 percent annualized in the last months before that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are we going to hear him talk about it, though, on Friday?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything, you know, to lay out.&nbsp; I know last Friday he talked about the jobs numbers and &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out or to lay out for you about that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on inflation, retailers have actually started to warn that now they might have an opposite problem of having too much supply on their shelves.&nbsp; I mean, do you view that as a sign of success, or is that another kind of concern for you for the economy?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; that goes back to what we&#8217;ve been saying.&nbsp; Like, this has been an economic re- &#8212; historic recovery, and that is because of what this President has been able to do.</p>



<p>When you think about the American Rescue Plan more than a year ago that the President laid out and only Democrats signed &#8212; voted for the American Rescue Plan at a time when the President walked into the administration, the economy was in crisis, schools were closed, businesses were shutting down, there was no comprehensive plan to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; And he put all &#8212; he put that plan forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now we are in a place &#8212; just last Friday, as I was saying to Ken, he talked about the jobs numbers in May &#8212; 390,000 jobs that we saw in the last report for May.&nbsp; And that is part of the trajectory that we’re &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen with this economic, historical, you know, turnaround of the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, that is all important, and I think that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s one way to look at that now.&nbsp; Now, we&#8217;re &#8212; we’re going to be transitioning to a more stable &#8212; stable growth, which is going to help us tackle inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; and we&#8217;re &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re going to do our best.&nbsp; The President is going to continue to work very hard to make sure that we lower those costs when we think about food and we think about gas prices.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President plan to watch any of the January 6th hearing tomorrow?&nbsp; And, if not, how does he plan to monitor it?&nbsp; Is he going to comment on the first hearing?&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I mean, we&#8217;ve been very clear that it is an independent &#8212; we support the January 1st Committee hearings &#8212; Committee, I should say, to be more clear &#8212; on January 6th.</a></p>



<p>What we saw that day over a year ago was one of the darkest times in our democracy.&nbsp; But it is an independent committee.&nbsp; And clearly, he&#8217;ll be very busy, as you heard Jake lay out and myself lay out what the next couple of days are going to be.</p>



<p>You know, he might catch it here and there, but he&#8217;s going to be very focused on his trip, talking to Western Hemisphere leaders and making sure that he continues to deliver for the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the President&#8217;s approval rating in a new Morning Consult poll is his worst yet, with disapproving voters saying they&#8217;re more likely to vote GOP.&nbsp; Is he concerned about what this bodes for his party, for the Democrats in the upcoming elections?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, I can&#8217;t get into politics from my position, so I&#8217;m not going to, you know, give any political ana- &#8212; analysis as I&#8217;ve done in my past career.</p>



<p>But, you know, the President is going to continue to do what he&#8217;s doing right now, what he&#8217;s about to do, which is focus on the American people, make that &#8212; continue to make that his number-one goal as we talk about the economy; as we talk about, you know, the work that we have done to see, you know, jobs come back into &#8212; come back into the market; as we, you know, try to deal with costs, whether it&#8217;s gas prices as he&#8217;s doing all that he can to bring those down, the food prices as we&#8217;re really understanding what the American people are feeling.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s going to be his &#8212; his purpose.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be what he&#8217;s going to be focusing on and what his administration is going to be &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he seen the poll?&nbsp; Is he reading polls?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I &#8212; that &#8212; honestly, that is not the &#8212; that is not what is on &#8212; on the President’s &#8212; number one on the President’s mind.&nbsp; It’s the American people and how &#8212; what he can do to continue to deliver.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And back on negotiations again &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; Is he continuing to get updates &#8212; either daily, hourly &#8212; on the negotiations?&nbsp; Like &#8212; and do you have a sense &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Are you talking about the gun reform, the &#8212; yeah, specifically?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, specifically.&nbsp; And is he &#8212; is he optimistic &#8212; has he got a sense of optimism or pessimism about how things are going?&nbsp; And I know you&#8217;re not &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; He’s &#8212; he said he’s encouraged.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We have that the President is encouraged at what he is seeing in Congress, in particular with the Senate negotiations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I&#8217;ve said this yesterday, and he has said this as well: The House has &#8212; has taken some actions.&nbsp; They took some actions last week.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to take some actions this week, if they haven&#8217;t already.&nbsp; I already forgot what day it is of the week.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been going so fast this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, Senator &#8212; Senator Murphy came, as you all know, to the White House to give the President an update.&nbsp; We&#8217;re very appreciative of his leadership.&nbsp; We’re appreciative of what Senator Schumer and others &#8212; and their leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, there&#8217;s no deal to talk about right now.&nbsp; They are still working &#8212; working out the details.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what the President truly believes &#8212; and he has said this himself; you heard him say this last Thursday &#8212; is we have to “do something.”&nbsp; And that is the two words that he heard from the families in Uvalde, who &#8212; parents who lost their children in a horrific, horrific mass shooting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s calling on Congress to do &#8212; is to do something, to take a step forward so that we can deal with one of our public health epidemics, which is gun violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Venezuelan Interim President Juan&#160;Guaidó</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-venezuelan-interim-president-juan-guaido/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 21:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Venezuelan Interim President Juan Guaidó to underscore the United States’ recognition of and support for the 2015 democratically-elected National Assembly and Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela. President Biden expressed his support for Venezuelan-led negotiations as the best path toward a peaceful restoration of democratic institutions,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Venezuelan Interim President Juan Guaidó to underscore the United States’ recognition of and support for the 2015 democratically-elected National Assembly and Guaidó as the Interim President of Venezuela. President Biden expressed his support for Venezuelan-led negotiations as the best path toward a peaceful restoration of democratic institutions, free and fair elections, and respect for the human rights and fundamental freedoms of all Venezuelans. They discussed the role the United States and other international partners can play to support a negotiated solution to Venezuela’s crisis. President Biden reaffirmed the United States is willing to calibrate sanctions policy as informed by the outcomes of negotiations that empower the Venezuelan people to determine the future of their country.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 20:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Daniel B. Maffei, of New York, to be a Federal Maritime Commissioner for a term expiring June 30, 2027.&#160; (Reappointment) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Catherine J.K. Sandoval, of California, to be a Member of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board for a term of five years, vice Kristen Marie Kulinowski, term&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Daniel B. Maffei, of New York, to be a Federal Maritime Commissioner for a term expiring June 30, 2027.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Catherine J.K. Sandoval, of California, to be a Member of the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board for a term of five years, vice Kristen Marie Kulinowski, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Douglas J. McKalip, of the District of Columbia, to be Chief Agricultural Negotiator, Office of the United States Trade Representative, with the rank of Ambassador, vice Gregory Doud.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jessica Davis Ba, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Cote d&#8217;Ivoire.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Robert J. Faucher, of Arizona, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Suriname.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kenneth Merten, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Bulgaria.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWAL SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Maria Duaime Robinson, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Office of Electricity), vice Bruce J. Walker, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Labor Leaders on Health Care and Workers’&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-labor-leaders-on-health-care-and-workers-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 20:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with labor leaders—including nurses and teachers—on access to health care and workers’ rights. Participants shared their experiences of union women advocating and organizing for health care, including reproductive health care. They also discussed the challenges posed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with labor leaders—including nurses and teachers—on access to health care and workers’ rights. Participants shared their experiences of union women advocating and organizing for health care, including reproductive health care. They also discussed the challenges posed by extreme state laws that restrict access to critical reproductive health services and the direct impact these restrictions have on women in the workforce including impact on negotiated health care benefits.</p>



<p><br>Senior Administration officials underscored the President’s commitment to reproductive rights and thanked participants for their leadership and efforts to protect access to reproductive health care in their communities. The Administration also committed to continued engagement and collaboration with these labor leaders.<br> <br>Participants included:<br>Jessica Blue, Registered Nurse, SEIU 1199<br>Elise Bryant, President, Coalition of Labor Union Women<br>Karla Hernández-Mats, President, United Teachers of Dade<br>Paula Herbart, President Michigan Education Association<br>Deborah Burger, President, National Nurses United</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the CEO Summit of the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-ceo-summit-on-progress-made-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[InterContinental Los Angeles DowntownLos Angeles, California 11:05 A.M. PDT&#160;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Well, first, I want to thank the Chamber of Commerce for organizing this CEO Summit and for bringing together so many leaders from business across the hemisphere.&#160;&#160;We gather today in pursuit of a shared goal: to build a prosperous and inclusive future&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>InterContinental Los Angeles Downtown<br><em>Los Angeles, California</em></em></p>



<p>11:05 A.M. PDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Well, first, I want to thank the Chamber of Commerce for organizing this CEO Summit and for bringing together so many leaders from business across the hemisphere.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We gather today in pursuit of a shared goal: to build a prosperous and inclusive future for the people of the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp; This is a priority for President Joe Biden and me &#8212; a priority, I know, that everyone here shares.<br>&nbsp;<br>The economies of the Western Hemisphere are deeply intertwined.&nbsp; And the work we do to strengthen these ties directly impacts the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our neighbors in the Western Hemisphere comprise the largest market for American goods.&nbsp; The region accounts for nearly 50 percent of all American exports.&nbsp; And when we have resilient and secure supply chains that are close to us, disruptions will be less frequent, more goods will be available, and prices will come down.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>From Canada to Chile, a prosperous region benefits all our economies and creates more opportunities for our people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here&#8217;s how I see it: To realize a more prosperous future for our hemisphere, public-private partnerships are essential &#8212; partnerships that combine the private sector and its experience and expertise with the reach and capacity that only governments can provide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>By working together, we can unleash growth and opportunity that far exceeds what either the public or the private sector would achieve on its own.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to offer a scenario.&nbsp; Imagine what could happen when governments and companies collaborate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, picture this.&nbsp; Imagine a woman in Honduras who lives in a small rural town.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a single mother.&nbsp; She has two children.&nbsp; She does not have a formal education and has never had steady work.&nbsp; Instead, she takes on an odd job here or there.&nbsp; She often lays awake at night, worried about whether she can put enough food on the table, wondering if her children can break the cycle of poverty that is all too common where she lives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Then, let&#8217;s imagine a beverage company announces new investments sourcing coffee from her hometown in western Honduras.&nbsp; Imagine that the company then offers her a job cultivating that coffee.&nbsp; Imagine an international aid program provides lunch for her children at school, improving their nutrition and their health; that a financial company helps her open a bank account in the form of a digital wallet.&nbsp; Imagine that she now has some disposable income, and she saves, and she starts moving up the economic ladder.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, a telecommunications company makes an investment and connects her town to the Internet, and she gains access to new information and online tools that will help her really reach into her imagination about what she can achieve.&nbsp; And so, she then starts to think about an entrepreneurship based on her vision for herself and her community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Imagine that USAID provides her with a grant to establish her own eco-tourism business and that she accesses credit for the first time, and she hires employees, and her business grows, and she thrives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This story illustrates what I believe is possible when governments and business truly integrate our approach.&nbsp; This scenario is, then, our vision for millions of people as part of our strategy to address the root causes of migration from Central America.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Last year, I began work to lead this effort.&nbsp; And I approached this task with three basic principles.&nbsp; First, I do believe most people don&#8217;t want to leave home.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want to leave their grandmother.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want to leave the place where they worship and the community that they&#8217;ve always known.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, when they do, it is usually for one of two reasons: They are fleeing harm, or to stay means they simply cannot satisfy their basic needs or the needs of their family.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The second principle that is informing our call to action and this approach is my and our belief that governments alone cannot address this issue.&nbsp; We must partner with the private sector if we are to have lasting impact and if we are to maximize our capacity.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third, I believe that to attract meaningful investment, part of our agenda and strategy must include a priority that is to combat corruption, promote the rule of law, reduce violence, and empower women.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, these are the guiding principles that inform our Root Causes Strategy.&nbsp; And this Strategy is aligned with the importance that many of the of the leaders here know and live &#8212; the importance of paying attention to a good return on investment, consistency and predictability, a skilled workforce, and a reliable infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of this strategy, last year I launched the Call to Action focused on northern Central America and encouraged companies and civil society to deepen their commitment in the region and to expand collaboration, to invest, and to contribute to long-term development.<br>&nbsp;<br>In particular, I’d like to change &#8212; or thank the Chamber of Commerce, the Partnership for Central America, and the 40 companies and organizations that have made commitments thus far.&nbsp; These are long-terms efforts, and we are making progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yesterday, I announced we have now generated more than $3.2 billion.&nbsp; This investment is on track to generate tens of thousands of jobs.&nbsp; It will help more than 10 million people access banking services and credit.&nbsp; And 2 million people already have been connected to the Internet, with millions more to follow.<br>&nbsp;<br>In parallel, we are taking the steps that only government can.&nbsp; Our administration has made tackling corruption a top policy priority.&nbsp; This work incorporates an understanding that rule of law, consistency, and stability are necessary for economies to thrive.<br>&nbsp;<br>Another pillar of our Strategy is to train, protect, and empower women and to address gender-based violence.&nbsp; I think we all know protecting the safety and security of women is the right thing to do and empowering women drives economic growth.<br>&nbsp;<br>Experts and top universities are now in the midst of studying our Call to Action as an innovative model of public-private partnership &#8212; a model for development efforts in other regions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is apparent to me that the best approach entails the full involvement of the private sector, governments, and civil society.&nbsp; And, of course, the idea of a public-private partnership is not new.<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I believe distinguishes the Call to Action is the integration of so many efforts in one ecosystem.&nbsp; This ecosystem includes some companies that are even competitors with one another.&nbsp; This ecosystem also includes civil society organizations and the convening power of the United States government and our ability to scale.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Call to Action brings all of these sectors together to collaborate, coordinate, and share lessons learned.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yesterday, in fact, I met with several business executives who made new commitments as part of this initiative.&nbsp; We discussed how powerful it is to see how each investment &#8212; each investment fits into the larger picture.&nbsp; In corporate speak: We identified many synergies.<br>&nbsp;<br>And this coordination allows us to address the full spectrum of needs in a given region under one integrated plan.&nbsp; Together, we are creating an ecosystem of opportunity.<br>&nbsp;<br>And any good public policy, of course, must then be designed with an eye for replication.&nbsp; I believe truly that our approach can indeed be applied elsewhere on other issues, in other parts of our hemisphere, and even by other governments.<br>&nbsp;<br>When I think about all the challenges we face in the Western Hemisphere, I know that they will require new and innovative coalitions between the public and private sectors.&nbsp; One size does not fit all, of course.<br>&nbsp;<br>But think about it: Economic inequality in our hemisphere is among the worst in the world.&nbsp; Women and girls in our hemisphere face far too many barriers and far too few opportunities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Many countries in the region are still struggling to recover from the pandemic.&nbsp; Health systems are strained.&nbsp; The climate crisis is mounting.&nbsp; And we continue to see corruption, migration flows, and democratic backsliding, and violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>These issues affect all of us.&nbsp; And the solutions then must involve all of us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I believe there is untapped potential for us to partner in these areas and so many more &#8212; in the area of clean energy, food security, health, supply chains, infrastructure, and more.<br>&nbsp;<br>Later today, President Joe Biden will officially open the Summit of the Americas to lay out his ambitious vision for shared prosperity in our hemisphere, now and into the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our ongoing partnership with the private sector will play a crucial role in realizing this vision.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I urge all of the leaders here to consider what you can continue to do to partner within the context of the vision I know we share.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Needless to say, each of you here has the power to act to help solve some of the most pressing challenges of our time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our partnership can create new opportunities for individuals to not only succeed but to thrive.<br>&nbsp;<br>For companies, it can create new opportunities to grow and to innovate.<br>&nbsp;<br>And for our hemisphere as a whole, it can create new opportunities to connect and to prosper.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I look forward to partnering with all of you in the months and the years ahead.&nbsp; I thank you for your leadership.&nbsp; And I look forward to the work we will do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 11:19 A.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Andrzej Duda of&#160;Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland.  Following President Biden’s trip to Poland in March, the leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to further strengthening our bilateral security and economic cooperation. They also discussed their ongoing support for the people and government of Ukraine in response to Russian aggression. President Biden&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland.  Following President Biden’s trip to Poland in March, the leaders reaffirmed their shared commitment to further strengthening our bilateral security and economic cooperation. They also discussed their ongoing support for the people and government of Ukraine in response to Russian aggression. President Biden underscored the U.S. commitment to the security of Poland and NATO’s eastern flank, sending his best wishes for a successful Bucharest Nine (B9) Summit later this week.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials Previewing the 9th Summit of the Americas Economic&#160;Deliverables</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/08/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-previewing-the-9th-summit-of-the-americas-economic-deliverables/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 19:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you so much, and good morning, everyone.&#160; Thank you for joining us today.&#160; And for those of you in California already, I hope you have a nice cup of coffee in your hand, appreciate the early wake-up call.&#160; Before I turn it over to my colleagues to outline today&#8217;s deliverables, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much, and good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us today.&nbsp; And for those of you in California already, I hope you have a nice cup of coffee in your hand, appreciate the early wake-up call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before I turn it over to my colleagues to outline today&#8217;s deliverables, I just wanted to remind everyone of the ground rules.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And we will lift the embargo today at 11:00 a.m.&nbsp; Eastern.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You should have received &#8212; if not, it’s going out momentarily &#8212; a factsheet that&#8217;s also currently under embargoed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we really &#8212; we’ll have [senior administration official] kick off the call and then have [senior administration official] outline today&#8217;s econ deliverable, and then we&#8217;ll go over to questions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, [senior administration official]?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for joining us this morning.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve said, the President is very much looking forward to hosting the Ninth Summit of the Americas this week.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s already been a fairly active pace of activity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The theme yesterday, Tuesday, was on building strong and inclusive democracies, and you saw the Vice President announce $3.2 billion now in commitments from the private sector for nortern Central America women&#8217;s empowerment initiative.&nbsp; The Secretary of State announced deliverables on independent journalism and the digital agenda for transformation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, when the President arrives, the theme will be investments in the region&#8217;s health and prosperity.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll let my colleagues speak to the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Thursday, we&#8217;re going to focus on energy security and climate-smart recovery.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ll see meetings that the President and Vice President will have with the Caribbean and others to focus on this issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then lastly, on Friday, the focus is going to be on collaborative migration, where the President is going to meet with leaders to announce an unprecedented partnership on addressing migration challenges that are affecting all of us in the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that is the focus.&nbsp; And today, I will turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk about the economic deliverables for today.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And thank you all for joining this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, today in Los Angeles, President Biden will announce a new economic agenda for the hemisphere, based on a vision of a region that is secure, middle class and democratic with the announcement, as [senior administration official] mentioned, of what we&#8217;re calling the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it really is a fitting counterpart to the last time the U.S. hosted the Summit of the Americas 28 years ago, when then-President Bill Clinton really outlined an economic vision for that time that effectively laid the tracks for the next three decades of U.S. economic policy that followed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think today&#8217;s unveiling is a necessary update in matching that in scale and ambition, and really taking account of all the ways the world has changed and all the things that the region needs now to effectively run hard at the opportunities and address the challenges that the region has.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, a bit on the “what.”&nbsp;&nbsp; This historic agreement will be instrumental to deepening our economic cooperation, really focusing on the largest drivers of middle-out growth.&nbsp; And we think, going back actually to yesterday&#8217;s themes of democracy, we see this as really a necessary part of the foundation for shoring up democracy in the region.&nbsp; Because I think &#8212; hopefully, it&#8217;s obvious, but they&#8217;re saying that we see democracy as not simply the right of people to choose their leaders, but the agency to shape the kind of economy we live in and the values that that economy serves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think you will see three very clear through-lines of this effort.&nbsp; One is really building it, customizing it to run hard, fast, quickly, effectively at a set of challenges that we have today.&nbsp; I think that certainly the supply chain crisis that we&#8217;re still in the middle of stands out as high on that list.&nbsp; And what will be a new kind of supply chain negotiation really meant to make the supply chains in the hemisphere resilient to unexpected shocks, I think, will be a centerpiece of this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we will really think hard about innovation in both the public and private sectors, precisely to enable governments to better address society&#8217;s most pressing challenges.&nbsp; This goes as much to the “how” of effective public administration as to the “what,” mindful that the best way that people can claim agency over their economy is through their governments.&nbsp; And so, really thinking about how to make governments deliver better will be, I think, really key to a lot of this work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally is just, I think, another instantiation of what has been a through-line of the Biden administration&#8217;s work across its international economic style of really tethering, much more closely than I think previous administrations have, our efforts on climate to our efforts on international trade and economic engagement so that we create a better set of politics around climate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;ve seen that borne out in President Biden&#8217;s efforts domestically, when he says, “When I think climate, I think good jobs.”&nbsp; That is, I think, no less true in other countries.&nbsp; And so I think part of the idea here is to take that same logic on the road, multi-lateralize it as part of our international economic engagements.</p>



<p>So, just a few more highlights of what this kind of negotiation will feature and the “how” of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Following the conclusion of the summit, the U.S. will hold initial consultations with partners in the hemisphere and arrange U.S. stakeholders on the following areas.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just hit them briefly, and then we can take questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is really reinvigorating regional economic institutions and mobilizing investment.&nbsp; Together, we will reinvigorate the hemispheres (inaudible) flagship economic institution and the Inter-American Development Bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there, we are looking at the possibility of future capital for IDB Invest &#8212; that&#8217;s the private sector investment arm of the IDB &#8212; as well as looking at a lot of the global multilateral development banks and making sure that they are adequately indexing our own hemisphere, mindful that the acute inequality that so many of the countries in the hemisphere face creates a kind of bimodal tendency in these countries that on average has them appear to be middle income in ways that, frankly, mask a whole lot of need for a whole lot of the populations of these countries that can often have the result of putting them last in line for the kind of supports and financial stabilization that a lot of the global (inaudibles) and multilateral banks can offer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I think just thinking hard about a set of measures that would make sure that we are adequately weighting the need in our own hemisphere with all the institutions that we can bring to bear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, is really that body of work I mentioned earlier on &#8212; making more resilient supply chains in our hemisphere.&nbsp; I think we now know that our economic security rests on supply chains that are more diverse and secure and reliable and sustainable than, I think, the last 40 years of prioritizing a kind of narrow-minded efficiency that turned out to have been too fragile at the risk of other values like resilience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I think this work will really focus on helping our hemisphere reduce overt dependence and concentrations on certain countries and do the nearshoring and co-investment to run hard at those investments that make good economic and security sense for us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third would be what we&#8217;re calling “updating the basic bargain.”&nbsp; We are mindful that we have a generation of leaders in the region who pretty much (inaudible) are prioritizing a set of public investments in innovation and in the work of government to make life better and fairer for their respective citizens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes, a lot of that work is necessarily domestic facing.&nbsp; But in many cases, I think it happens to be the kinds of things that tools with U.S. (inaudible), like the Development Finance Corporation and like a newly revamped Inter-American Development Bank, can do good work on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This looks like investments and cooperation in areas like education, health, unemployment, retirement, childcare, women&#8217;s economic empowerment, as well as the kinds of reforms that make those investments enduring, by which I mean helping these countries mobilize the domestic revenue through a set of tax reform measures and anti-corruption measures that will ultimately sustain them over time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fourth is the climate work that I mentioned earlier, advancing clean energy jobs and decarbonization in ways that hopefully create virtuous cycle politics as well as faster progress on decarbonization.&nbsp; And I think we will obviously build this out together with partners.&nbsp; But roughly, I think it hangs together as a negotiation through our ability to develop a financing mechanism to support a set of new asks on things like the percentage of renewables in the grids of these countries and a set of measures on deforestation and a range of other things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, ensuring sustainable and inclusive trade.&nbsp; I think we know that, after the last two years of the pandemic, that we&#8217;ve seen the important role that digital technologies and services play in our economy and the continued importance of trade that is really putting workers and families at the center.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And here, I expect that we will focus on the sort of customs facilitation &#8212; when you look actually at the region&#8217;s sort of container dwelling times, import and customs clearance times, they&#8217;re actually lagging behind many other regions in the world.&nbsp; And as we get into year two or two and a half of a supply chain crisis, I think if you ask a lot of CEOs, they would point to anything we could do to bring these customs and trade facilitation times down is really incredibly valuable and overlooked set of wins that we can probably get at quickly, depending on how we design the negotiation around this.</p>



<p>Beyond that, it&#8217;s advancing transparency and good regulatory practices, pursuing high standards in the digital economy, responsibly supporting emerging technologies, building resilience in energy and food supply chains.&nbsp; Knowing that we are probably in the early days of a food security crisis handed to us by Russia&#8217;s war of choice in Ukraine, it feels incredibly important to do as much as we can as quickly as we can to shave down the worst effects of that food security crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think there&#8217;s also been a number of innovations in areas like labor standards and &#8212; especially on incentivizing corporate accountability, as well as environmental standards &#8212; that a lot of our existing FTAs in this region, because they are some of our oldest, just have not benefited from that thinking.&nbsp; And so, this will also create a venue for us to bring in those kinds of commitments as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, I will stop and look forward to your questions.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for taking questions.&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you elaborate on how countries will be approached and what countries will be invited to negotiate this?</p>



<p>And then similarly, I wonder if you can elaborate on the structure. &nbsp;Will this be like IPEF, where countries opt into particular pillars and it&#8217;s structured to be more flexible? Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And, yes, we are seeing this as effectively the beginning of a conversation that we want to have with, obviously, a set of countries in the region, really beginning with our most likeminded economic partners and &#8212; as well as U.S. stakeholders ranging from friends in Congress to labor and industry stakeholders &#8212; over the next, I would say, two to three months, aiming to, I think, really launch the beginning of formal negotiations once each of these five pillars I just outlined are scoped and we have a sense of country participation across them.&nbsp; That probably looks like a ministerial in early fall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And on your question about structure and design and its proximity to IPEF, we are imagining sort of a flexible structure that does, again, begin with a set of our most likeminded trading partners in the region but, I think, could be opened over time &#8212; and is quite standards based once we have a sense of what those standards are &#8212; through the three-month process that I just described, that would be flexible in the sense of countries being able to join just one, just two, three, four, or all five of these pillars.&nbsp; So, in that sense, I think there is some similarity to the structural mechanics of IPEF.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I actually think the comparison with IPEF is not quite right.&nbsp; So if I could softly push back in a couple of ways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, I think, in IPEF, you are &#8212; here, we are beginning with a set of, as I mentioned, likeminded partners where I think by and large we already have existing FTAs.&nbsp; And so, I think that just changes the kind of starting posture of this conversation from that of the partners that we&#8217;re dealing with in the Indo-Pacific and in IPEF.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s probably the largest difference.&nbsp; This really is about kind of updating a foundation laid by the several FTAs that we have in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And second is when &#8212; you know, when you go through the pillars that I mentioned, two fifths of them are totally bespoke to the hemisphere &#8212; I think, appropriately so: the (inaudible) reinvigorating regional economic institutions, as well as the updating the basic bargain work that would be, we think, clear demand signals for from the region itself and areas that we think just, again, are quite well suited to the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, the through-lines that do exist are, frankly, just a reflection of this administration&#8217;s top priorities.&nbsp; It would be, I believe, a little bit head scratching for us to attempt an update of our economic approach to the hemisphere in the scope that we&#8217;re doing here and not include something on climate or supply chain.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for taking the question.&nbsp; I was wondering if there is any money associated with what you&#8217;re announcing today, any U.S. dollar commitments?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think that we are looking at making some commitments around a potential expansion of IDB and IDB Invest &#8212; really the IDB Invest piece &#8212; that has certain procedural hoops that we need to jump through.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t want to prejudge the &#8212; that we would ultimately be successful there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if that does run its course, that would, I think, come with new resources.&nbsp; And I think this is really the beginning of a signal that the President himself is sending about the direction of travel for the kind of economic policy and priorities there that he wants, and I think he would expect to see that reflected in the upcoming budget cycles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for taking the question.&nbsp; You said: Following the conclusion of the summit, the U.S. will hold initial consultation with partners in the hemisphere.&nbsp; Can you talk &#8212; elaborate on that please and talk about what discussions have been held up to now on the contents of this and how you see that going forward?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, again, we&#8217;re not announcing this in ways that has country participation today attached to it.&nbsp;&nbsp; That, I think, will evolve over the next two to three months, as I think we are prioritizing a set of countries that really are our most likeminded.&nbsp; I would leave it to [senior administration official], if he&#8217;d like, to kind of elaborate there, but I think that is exactly the work that we expect to get into, effectively starting today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have, I think, done some very notional conversations with some of these countries as part of our broader brainstorming around the summit to make sure that the notional contours of what we have put out will be well received, just to make sure that we are in the right universe.&nbsp; And I think we do have that comfort that this is something that the region will quite appreciate and we will see a fair bit of uptake for and likely quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I&#8217;ll leave it at that.&nbsp;&nbsp; But, [senior administration official], I don’t know if you want to try to answer that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the first thing I would say is that: In the development of this partnership, we&#8217;ve been consulting with experts and have been talking to governments, even formally through our embassies, to get their feedback, because we have our own concept of what this is based on a recognition of everything [senior administration official] laid out as some of the core challenges of the region and the foundation established by our free trade agreements as being something that has informed U.S. policy over the last 30 years but has not addressed some of these, I think, issues &#8212; inequality issues related to climate and a number of other pillars that [senior administration official] listed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, what we want to do is really frame out a concept that (inaudible) receive widespread support from the countries of the region.&nbsp; And then identify, I think, a core set of countries that will help us set a very high ambition to this.&nbsp; And then have an open architecture where countries will self-select whether they&#8217;re ready really to do this.&nbsp; If not, we&#8217;re not negotiating a trade agreement that would go to Congress, but rather building on existing agreements to actually promote a race to the top.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I would add, I think, on a pretty ambitious timeline.&nbsp; I think we are building this on the presumption that there are quick gains to be had and inroads to be cut on some of our most acute challenges that we have &#8212; again, that we are in the midst of.&nbsp; And I start with the fact that, again, we do have so many FTAs with a lot of the countries that we would expect to be the inaugural members of this, point one.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, the U.S.’s overall average tariff rate is, as you know, seen as 2.5 percent. I think (inaudible) an undertaking that would be many, many years that we&#8217;re attempting to sort of (inaudible) the ability to run hard at things like the supply chain crisis, improvements that we think we can score on, shaving off the worst effects of the food security crisis, advance on climate, efforts around securing high standards and digital trade where there are no tariffs, our customs and trade facilitation, as I mentioned earlier &#8212; a few of the areas that we think that we could just manage some real wins for the bottom lines of American workers and families as well as countries in the region &#8212; that the ability to run quickly will be an added bonus for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think then it comes to ensuring we can do this in a way that is enduring domestically, which obviously serves all of our interests.&nbsp; And I think that really goes to the kind of consultations that we expect and intend to have with both parties in Congress and a range of U.S. stakeholders in making sure that we develop something that really does put U.S. workers and families at the center and shows that we can pursue those gains for our domestic stakeholders while we are also pursuing a set of geopolitical imperatives in the hemisphere &#8212; that those two things can and should happen simultaneously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, I was wondering if you could just give a little bit of a preview of President Biden&#8217;s remarks on this initiative and whether he&#8217;ll emphasize rising trade flows between the region and China, which is now the largest trading partner for many of these countries, and how that will be discussed in his remarks.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I want to like leave some space for him to make some headlines here as well, so I&#8217;m not going to get into the specifics of his actual remarks &#8212; other than, to your question on the China angle in particular, I don&#8217;t expect that to be a large feature of this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think, frankly, the best antidote to China&#8217;s inroads in the region is to ensure that we are fording our own affirmative vision for the region economically.&nbsp; And we think that that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that we do lay down a really ambitious, regionally comprehensive, updated vision for the kind of economic partnership we want to have and lead in our hemisphere and use the summit to do that. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I think in that vacuum is where China has made the recent inroads that it has.&nbsp; And so I think we do ourselves both economic service as well as advancing our geostrategic gains by just putting out an affirmative vision that I think these countries will see the clear value proposition in, especially given the way that a lot of China&#8217;s recent efforts through (inaudible) and some of its debt-trap diplomacy have really backfired, including in this instance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thank you so much, everyone, for joining today&#8217;s background call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just as a reminder, this is under embargoed until 11:00 a.m. this morning, and you may attribute the contents of the call to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And then also, thank you so much.</p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
