<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 04:30:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing the Visit of Prime Minister Lee of&#160;Singapore</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/29/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-the-visit-of-prime-minister-lee-of-singapore/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (March 28, 2022) 7:06 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks everyone for joining.&#160; I know it’s on the later side of the evening, so thanks again for your time. I&#8217;m just going to do a quick ground rules.&#160; So, this is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&#160; And the contents&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(March 28, 2022)</p>



<p>7:06 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks everyone for joining.&nbsp; I know it’s on the later side of the evening, so thanks again for your time.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just going to do a quick ground rules.&nbsp; So, this is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And the contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Tuesday, March 29th, 5:00 a.m. Eastern.</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, joining us today is [senior administration official].&nbsp; And they’re going to give a couple of remarks at the top, and then we’ll just do some questions.&nbsp; So, [senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thank you very much.&nbsp; And thank you all for joining.</p>



<p>We are very, very happy that tomorrow Prime Minister of Singapore Lee Hsien Loong will come to the White House to meet with the President and also, separately, with the Vice President.</p>



<p>He arrived in Washington over the weekend and, I believe, had a number of meetings today and will be doing other meetings over the course of the next few days.</p>



<p>We are very happy about this because we believe that the U.S.-Singapore Strategic Partnership is extremely strong and extremely valuable to both countries, and has supported peace and prosperity throughout the Indo-Pacific for many years.</p>



<p>Our two countries share strong security, economic, and people-to-people ties.&nbsp; And the President looks forward to continue deepening those ties, which we feel are very much in the interests of both of our countries.</p>



<p>The President and Prime Minister Lee will be meeting at a very critical time, one in which the rules-based international order faces unprecedented challenge.&nbsp; And I think it’s obviously shaped by Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable war against Ukraine, which poses an urgent threat not only for Europe but also for the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>From the Atlantic to the Pacific, we must all redouble efforts to support Ukraine and preserve a world in which borders cannot be changed by force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At this trying time, we have great respect for all Singapore has done to support the people of Ukraine, including sanctions and export controls against Russia.&nbsp; And I note that this is a very significant development and one that we deeply appreciate and which highlights what we see as a broader theme, which is countries in the Indo-Pacific stepping up to support the international rules-based order through taking meaningful actions with respect to Ukraine and Russia.</p>



<p>However, even as we address Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine, the United States remains a proud Indo-Pacific nation.&nbsp; And we will work closely with Singapore and other partners to implement our Indo-Pacific strategy and realize our shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific that is more connected, more prosperous, more secure, and more resilient.</p>



<p>As I’m sure all of you know, last August, Vice President Harris traveled to Singapore and broke new ground on a range of key issues.&nbsp; And this followed the visit to Singapore by Defense Secretary Austin.&nbsp; And we’ve obviously had a number of other senior visits, including by Commerce Secretary Raimondo and Deputy Secretary Sherman.</p>



<p>I think that what we see is a continued role for our two countries to deepen and strengthen our cooperation, to address climate change, cooperate on space and cyber threats, promote inclusive growth and innovation, as well as resilient supply chains, looking for ways in which we can further cooperate on fighting COVID-19, preparing for the next pandemic, facing common security challenges, and deepening people-to-people ties.</p>



<p>President Biden and Prime Minister Lee will review progress on those lines of efforts and continue to build stronger cooperation in these areas.</p>



<p>The President and Prime Minister will also discuss Russia’s war against Ukraine, our shared interest in elevating U.S.-ASEAN relations, upholding freedom of the seas, and promoting a return to democracy in Burma.</p>



<p>And then following the President’s meeting with Prime Minister Lee, the Vice President will host him for a bilateral meeting at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We believe our strong partnership with Singapore has important benefits for the American people, including strong support for security in the Indo-Pacific, as well as strengthening and reinforcing our shared commitment to a fair, rules-based economic and security order in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>



<p>So, I think that, you know, from our standpoint, this is very significant.&nbsp; Prime Minister Lee, as all of you know, is very experienced and has been a strong supporter of U.S. engagement in the region.&nbsp; We value very much his advice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the President and the Prime Minister have a long relationship and last saw each other in Rome on the margins of the G20.&nbsp; And I think that we are looking forward to a very, very good conversation that really finds ways to further our common interests.</p>



<p>So, with that, I’m happy to go over this more.&nbsp; I’m happy to answer any questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that there is some interest in the issue of the U.S.-ASEAN Summit.&nbsp; And, you know, I’m sure many of you have followed that it has been postponed.&nbsp; We’re still working with ASEAN on finding appropriate dates and look forward to continuing to make progress on that.</p>



<p>So, with that, let me turn it over to you all and take some questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me okay?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I was wondering &#8212; I mean, you mentioned that the war in Ukraine would come up in discussions, and I wondered if there&#8217;s anything specific that the U.S. President would like to see in terms of commitments from Singapore vis-à-vis its relationship with China and any ways that it could put pressure on China to comply with U.S. export controls on Russia?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, thank you very much for that question.&nbsp; I think that the first key point is that obviously we expect the leaders will talk about the war in Ukraine because that is an overarching challenge to international rules-based order going on right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Also, the United States is very appreciative and very grateful to Singapore &#8212; as are, I think, many other countries &#8212; for Singapore&#8217;s very strong stance on this issue, including its imposition of export controls and sanctions against Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that we also expect that the leaders will discuss how what is happening in Ukraine also has implications for the rest of the world, including the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that, you know, they will also inevitably, I&#8217;m sure, discuss key issues in the Indo-Pacific, including, of course, the role of the United States in the region, as well as the role of China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think that &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of ourselves in terms of specifics.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re very happy with what Singapore has done.&nbsp; And I think that the key is going to be to continue looking for ways in which we can expand our cooperation on this and other issues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Can you hear me?&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Can you hear me?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, wonderful.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I do have two questions.&nbsp; First, with the Indo-Pacific Strategy, I was asking the &#8212; in early March, the Singapore Foreign Minister Vivian Balakrishnan expressed concern over tension between the United States and China.&nbsp; He said, “In Asia, trade is strategy.”&nbsp; So how will President Biden address Singapore&#8217;s concern to Prime Minister Lee tomorrow about this tension between U.S. and China?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I think that it&#8217;s a very good question, and it&#8217;s obviously a very important topic.&nbsp; And I think that we have had extensive discussions with the Singaporean government in the past 14 months &#8212; as well as, obviously, before that &#8212; about the important role of U.S. economic engagement in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that, you know, this came up during the Vice President&#8217;s visit.&nbsp; It also came up during Commerce Secretary Raimondo’s visit to Singapore.&nbsp; And obviously, we expect to discuss that here.</p>



<p>And we should note as well that we&#8217;ve had a number of Singaporean cabinet ministers come to the United States, and we&#8217;ve had pretty extensive discussions on these issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that what I would expect is that there will be discussion that makes clear the U.S. is &#8212; already is a very extensive investor, has extensive trading relations with, obviously, Singapore, but also more broadly with Southeast Asia.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking for ways in which we can expand our engagement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We completely understand the argument that there is a tremendous need for an affirmative economic agenda in the region and that the region looks to the United States to continue playing a significant role.&nbsp; I&#8217;m confident that they will have a good discussion on that.&nbsp; The U.S. values very much the perspectives of Singapore.&nbsp; And obviously, we look forward and I&#8217;m sure the President looks forward to sharing the &#8212; what the U.S. &#8212; how the U.S. sees the situation and what we will be looking to do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right, thank you.&nbsp; And the second question will be related to the military engagement.&nbsp; You also mentioned Secretary Austin was there last year.&nbsp; So, we know that Singapore and the United States signed a space cooperation treaty today.&nbsp; At the same time, we know Singapore and Taiwan have been having military exchange since 1975.&nbsp; And just last December, Singapore army was training in Taiwan.&nbsp; So, with China rapidly militarizing the South China Sea, how does the U.S. see the importance of Singapore and Taiwan’s military force for ensuring a free and open Indo-Pacific?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, thank you for a complex question that covers a lot of different issues.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure I could really do justice to that with a single answer.&nbsp; But what I would say is that we have a great deal of appreciation for Singapore&#8217;s strong role in Indo-Pacific security &#8212; both our bilateral cooperation as well as other things that Singapore does.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, the relationship that Singapore has with Taiwan is their affair, and that&#8217;s not for us to take a position on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that we welcome, however, the fact that Singapore continues to seek ways in which they can play a positive role, and we very much appreciate the role that they play.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As far as the U.S.-Singapore security partnership, we believe this is very, very important to the United States and we think that it&#8217;s also valuable for Singapore.&nbsp; It is quite extensive, and we look forward to continuing to develop it in ways that support the interests of both of our countries but also support security in the broader region.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; I wanted to see if there might be some additional steps announced tomorrow on sanctions involving Russia or if there were additional economic partnerships that we should be ready for announcements tomorrow on that as well.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; I mean, you know that one of the delicate things here is, obviously, we &#8212; we are looking forward to very extensive and thorough discussions.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of ourselves, but I think that we expect that there will be some announcements.</p>



<p>I think that the &#8212; you know, they probably will reflect the extreme strength of the relationship.&nbsp; And they will be essentially about ways in which we&#8217;re looking to do more together, rather than anything that&#8217;s really fundamental.</p>



<p>At the same time, we think that what is key here is that we have had such good cooperation and such a strong relationship with Singapore in so many different areas and &#8212; that this is something which we believe very much serves U.S. interests and we believe also &#8212; you know, Singapore has a very good sense of its &#8212; how to advance its own interests.&nbsp; And therefore, we are confident that Singapore believes it serves their interests as well.</p>



<p>In terms of specifics, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of ourselves; I&#8217;d say watch this space.&nbsp; But I think that, you know, we are looking forward to very good discussions and a very, very good visit &#8212; to the White House, in particular, but also &#8212; more broadly, the Prime Minister&#8217;s visit to the United States, we think, is a very timely &#8212; comes at an excellent time and is one that further highlights the very strong relationship between our two countries.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for taking my questions.&nbsp; Two trade-related questions.&nbsp; The first: Do you expect the President or Vice President to delve deeply into the Indo-Pacific economic framework tomorrow and, kind of, the specifics of that arrangement?</p>



<p>And then secondly, you know, there&#8217;s been some talk that some of the ASEAN countries want to see more from the Biden administration in terms of market access and tariffs when it comes to trade.&nbsp; Will the President make any sort of commitment along those lines during the meeting tomorrow?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s an excellent point and excellent questions.&nbsp; I think, on the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, we expect that&#8217;s going to come up and that there will be discussion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that we have had extensive coordination with Singapore and extensive discussions and a lot of feedback already, so I&#8217;m not sure how much detail it will get into.&nbsp; But I think that there will be discussion about what we&#8217;re seeking to accomplish and ways in which we think we can work together.</p>



<p>In terms of, you know, the broader desire for market access and other and &#8212; you know, expanded trade, I think that we are looking for ways in which we can try and address these concerns and strengthen economic linkages.&nbsp; But I think &#8212; as you, no doubt, are aware &#8212; we&#8217;re looking for ways that can be done using existing frameworks rather than new market access.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I know you kind of alluded to it at the end of your remarks, but I was wondering if you could maybe flesh out a little bit more what happened behind the scenes with ASEAN, you know, being announced and then coming down.&nbsp; I know that there were some scheduling issues, but maybe you can explain a little more, you know, what happened there and what kind of timeframe we&#8217;re looking at for the future.</p>



<p>And then also on the subject of sort of international forums, Singapore was a special invitee to the G20.&nbsp; I know the President spoke a little bit over the weekend about how he wanted to address Russia&#8217;s participation in the G20.&nbsp; But I was wondering if that was going to be a topic of conversation or if there was any asks for Singapore as you sort of navigate the situation with Indonesia.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, those are great questions.&nbsp; I think that with regards to the ASEAN Summit, I mean, just to be very candid, these things were always hard to schedule.&nbsp; You&#8217;re talking about a bunch of leaders, and I think that it is clear that there was &#8212; you know, there were some challenges and that, much to our disappointment, we weren&#8217;t able to get this locked down.</p>



<p>On the other hand, you know, having done this in the past &#8212; these things have been hard to do in the past because you are trying to coordinate the schedules of a bunch of leaders and it involved fairly extensive travel.</p>



<p>And so I think that, from our standpoint, we&#8217;re disappointed but we are very committed to looking for ways in which we can find a good time to schedule this.&nbsp; We believe the clock is ticking, and we want to try and get this done.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working very closely with ASEAN to try and come up with an appropriate time to do this.</p>



<p>In terms of the G20 &#8212; it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; You know, I think that from our standpoint &#8212; you know, you made the point they&#8217;re a special guest.&nbsp; I think that, you know, we are very sensitive to the &#8212; what that status means and doesn&#8217;t mean.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of ourselves in terms of what will or won&#8217;t come up.&nbsp; But I think that, you know, we understand that this is something where G20 members will have to decide.&nbsp; And I think that, as a special guest, Singapore undoubtably will have a voice, but we don&#8217;t want necessarily to put them in a position where they&#8217;re being treated as if they are a full member of the G20.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great, thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; Just as a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official,&#8221; and it&#8217;s embargoed until tomorrow 5:00 a.m. Eastern.</p>



<p>If you have any other follow-ups or questions, feel free to reach out to me, and we&#8217;ll make sure to get back to you.</p>



<p>So, thanks, everyone, again, for joining and talk to you later.</p>



<p>7:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Senate Vote to Move Forward the Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/28/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-senate-vote-to-move-forward-the-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Senate took another step forward today in delivering on the President’s vision to strengthen our supply chains, make more in America, and outcompete China and the rest of the world for decades to come. We look forward to the House of Representatives moving quickly to start the formal conference process as well. Today’s vote&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Senate took another step forward today in delivering on the President’s vision to strengthen our supply chains, make more in America, and outcompete China and the rest of the world for decades to come. We look forward to the House of Representatives moving quickly to start the formal conference process as well.</p>



<p>Today’s vote demonstrates there is clear bipartisan support for the sorts of investments the President has long championed — like boosting domestic manufacturing, supporting our innovators and helping them take their ideas from the lab to the factory floor, as well as addressing supply chain bottlenecks like semiconductors that are raising prices on the middle class. The events of the last two years, including the pandemic and Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine, have underscored just how important it is to our economic and national security to make more of these critical components here in America.</p>



<p>We’ve made remarkable progress over the last year in rebuilding our industrial base, including by creating more manufacturing jobs last year than in any year in almost three decades, and by making a historic and long-overdue investment in our nation’s infrastructure. Competitiveness legislation like the Bipartisan Innovation Act is our chance to build on that success and create good-paying jobs, make more in America, and lower prices for working families.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Announcing the Fiscal Year 2023&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/28/remarks-by-president-biden-announcing-the-fiscal-year-2023-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 22:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 2:58 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good afternoon, folks.&#160; It’s been a busy couple of days for all of you.&#160; The &#8212; let me begin by saying that &#8212; thanking Director Young.&#160; You know, you’ve heard me say this before over the years: My dad had an expression.&#160; He said, “Don’t tell&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>2:58 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good afternoon, folks.&nbsp; It’s been a busy couple of days for all of you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The &#8212; let me begin by saying that &#8212; thanking Director Young.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, you’ve heard me say this before over the years: My dad had an expression.&nbsp; He said, “Don’t tell me what you value.&nbsp; Show me your budget, and I’ll tell you what you value.”&nbsp; “Don’t tell me what you value.&nbsp; Show me your budget, and I’ll tell you what you value.”</p>



<p>Well, the budget I’m releasing today sends a clear message to the American people that we &#8212; what we value.&nbsp; First, fiscal responsibility.&nbsp; Second, safety and security.&nbsp; And thirdly, the inv- &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; the investments needed to build a better America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first value is fiscal responsibility.&nbsp; The previous administration, as you all know, ran up record budget deficits.&nbsp;&nbsp; In fact, the deficit went up every year under my predecessor.&nbsp;&nbsp; My administration is turning that around.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last year, we cut the deficit by more than $350 billion.&nbsp;&nbsp; This year we’re on track to cut the deficit by more than 1 trillion 300 billion dollars.&nbsp; One trillion three hundred billion dollars. &nbsp;That would be the largest one-year reduction in the deficit in U.S. history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And here’s how we’re achieving it &#8212; this record deficit reduction: First, we’re growing the economy.&nbsp; We have created a record 6.7 million jobs since I took office.&nbsp; And we have generated a GDP growth of 5.7 percent, the best economic growth we’ve seen in this country in over 40 years.&nbsp; This has led to a substantial increase in government revenues and dramatically improved our fiscal situation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secondly, this record economic and job growth has made it possible for us to responsibly and significantly cut back on emergency spending.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Early in the pandemic, it was right to give people help to make ends meet and to keep their ec- &#8212; this economy going.&nbsp; But because of the progress we’ve made dealing with these emergencies, the labor market is strong, and unemployment &#8212; unemployment claims are at historic lows.&nbsp; We ended the pandemic unemployment assistance programs because Americans are back to work.&nbsp; I’m calling for new pandemic subsidies for large businesses &#8212; to not continue those because those businesses are back and moving again as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But because we have put this economy on a strong foundation, even the Delta and Omicron variants of COVID-19 and the cost of Putin’s aggression in Ukraine have not required additional &#8212; an additional fiscal package for state and local governments.&nbsp; But we still spend what we need to spend to continue to fight COVID.&nbsp; But those expenditures will be dramatically less than last year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Compared to 2020, we’re reducing the size of the deficit relative to our economy by almost two-thirds, reducing inflationary pressures and making real headway cleaning up the fiscal mess I inherited.&nbsp; After my president’s &#8212; my &#8212; excuse me &#8212; my predecessor’s fiscal mismanagement, we’re reducing the Trump deficits and returning our fiscal house to order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the budget I’m releasing today will continue this approach.&nbsp; It makes prudent investments in economic growth, a more equitable economy, while making sure corporations and the wealthy pay their fair share.&nbsp; And, I would add, nobody making less than $400,000 a year will pay a penny more in federal taxes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can do this by, one, passing legislation that lowers costs for families on things like childcare, healthcare, and energy costs while lowering our deficit at the same time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can give hardworking parents raising children tax relief that gives them just a bit of breathing room and lowers child poverty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can give Medicare the power to negotiate lower prescription drug prices.&nbsp; This will bring down the cost for seniors and reduce the deficit by hundreds of billions of dollars.&nbsp; Congress can do that &#8212; this all right now.&nbsp; They’re debating it now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can also restore fiscal responsibility.&nbsp; The Trump tax cuts added $2 trillion in deficit spending and largely helped the rich and the largest corporations.&nbsp; Under my plan, as I said, no one making less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional single penny in taxes.&nbsp; No one.&nbsp; If you don’t make 400 grand, you’re not going to pay a single penny in additional federal taxes.</p>



<p>And the wealthy and corporations will finally begin to pay their fair share.&nbsp; For most Americans, the last few years were very hard, stretching them to the breaking point.&nbsp; But billionaires and large corporations got richer than ever.&nbsp; Right now, billionaires pay an average rate of 8 percent on their total income.&nbsp; Eight percent &#8212; that’s the average they pay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I’m a capitalist, but just &#8212; I want &#8212; if you make a billion bucks, great.&nbsp; Just pay your fair share.&nbsp; Pay a little bit.&nbsp; A firefighter and a teacher pay more than double &#8212; double the tax rate that a billionaire pays.&nbsp; That’s not right.&nbsp; That’s not fair.&nbsp; And my budget contains a “Billionaire Minimum Tax” because of that.&nbsp; A 20 percent minimum tax that applies only to the top one-hundredth of 1 percent.&nbsp; One-hundredth of 1 percent of the Americans will pay this tax.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Billionaire Minimum Tax is fair, and it raises $360 billion that can be used to lower costs for families and cut the deficit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I said, my budget also ensures that corporations pay their fair share.&nbsp; In 2020, there were 50 Fortune 500 companies that made $40 billion in profit combined but didn’t pay a single, solitary cent in federal taxes.&nbsp; My budget raises the corporate tax rate to 28 percent, far lower than the rate it was between World War Two and 2017, when it was lowered &#8212; as of today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last year, I rallied more than a hundred- &#8212; some of you were overseas with me &#8212; 130 countries to agree to a global minimum tax for corporations doing business in their countries; to put an end to a tax system that rewards multinational corporations for shipping the jobs and profits overseas, and avoiding taxes at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s my hope that Congress enacts this law this year so I can sign it and we can get to work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second value my budget reflects is security &#8212; security at home and security abroad.&nbsp; My brudget [sic] &#8212; my budget tackles security in two keys ways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, it secures our communities at home.&nbsp; This is an issue families in every part of the country face.&nbsp; I’ve said it before: The answer is not to defund our police departments, it’s to fund our police and give them all the tools they need, training, and foundation, and partners and protectors that our communities need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The budget puts more police on the street for community policing so they get to know the community they’re policing;&nbsp;allows the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms and the FBI to hire the agents they need to help fight gun crime and other violent crimes in our communities; and funds body cameras and makes sure police work with our local communities and are accountable to these communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It funds crime prevention and community violence intervention, drug treatment, mental health, criminal justice reform, and reentry for people coming home after incarceration.&nbsp; All demonstrable ways to reduce crime &#8212; and &nbsp;proven ways.</p>



<p>Security also means national and international security.&nbsp; This budget provides the resources we need to keep Americans safe, ensuring that our military remains the best-prepared, best-trained, best-equipped military in the world.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This budget also provides additional funding to forcefully respond to Putin’s aggression against Ukraine and its economic, humanitarian, and security consequences.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The world has changed.&nbsp; In addition to dealing with terrorist organizations, for the second quarter of the 21st century, we’re once again facing increased competition from other nation states &#8212; China and Russia &#8212; which are going to require investments to make things like space and cyber and other advanced capabilities, incl- &#8212; including hypersonics.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And this will be among the largest investments in our national security in history.&nbsp; Some people don’t like the increase, but we’re in a different world today.&nbsp; America is more prosperous, more successful, and more just when it is more secure.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We can restore fiscal responsibility and safeguard our security at home and abroad while meeting a third value &#8212; what I call “building a better America.”<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s provide universal preschool, cap the cost of childcare at 7 percent of a family’s income.&nbsp; Like many families, that would cut the cost of childcare in half.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s make &#8212; and it’ll make college more affordable.&nbsp; My budget doubles the maximum Pell Grant to pe- &#8212; families making under $50,000 a year &#8212; to nearly $13,000.&nbsp; And it helps more than 8 million students who rely on Pell Grants pay for college.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My budget invests in building more homes to keep us up &#8212; to deal with the skyrocketing cost of housing for the middle class and the poor.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My budget lowers family energy costs with tax credits to help people make their homes more efficient, research and development to broaden the reach of solar and build a clean energy future.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My budget also invests in other areas of bipartisan common good &#8212; I call them “unity agendas;” I spoke to them at the State of the Union &#8212; beating the opio- &#8212; the opioid epidemic, taking on challenges of mental health, supporting our veterans, and ending cancer as we know it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This budget includes investments to get Americans the mental health services they need, and we need them.&nbsp; And when it comes to fighting cancer and other diseases, my budget funds a new organization called ARPA-H at the Health and Human Ser- &#8212; at the Department of Health.&nbsp; And it stands for Advanced Research Projects [Agency] for Health.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s based on DARPA, the Defense Department program that led to breakthrough technologies like the Internet, GPS, and so much more.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; ARPA-H will drive breakthroughs to prevent, detect, and treat diseases, including Alzheimer’s, diabetes, cancers, and more.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And here’s what this all adds up to: historic deficit reduction, historic investments in our security at home and abroad by modernizing our capabilities in both areas, and an unprecedented commitment to building an economy where everyone has a chance to succeed &#8212; a plan to pay for those investments that we need as a nation.&nbsp; That’s what we do.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I look forward to working with members of Congress &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, and independents &#8212; to deliver this budget and keep delivering for the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to thank you all.&nbsp; And may God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.</p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me &#8212; Kelly O’Donnell, NBC.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Do you believe what you said &#8212; (a microphone is handed to Ms. O’Donnell) &#8212; thank you, sir.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe what you said &#8212; that Putin can’t remain in power?&nbsp; Or do you now regret saying that?&nbsp; Because your government has been trying to walk that back.&nbsp; Did your words complicate matters?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, you asked three different questions, and I’ll answer them all.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number one, I’m not walking anything back.&nbsp; The fact of the matter is I was expressing the moral outrage I felt toward the way Putin is dealing, and the actions of this man &#8212; just &#8212; just the brutality of it.&nbsp; Half the children in Ukraine. &nbsp;I had just come from being with those families.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so &#8212; but I want to make it clear: I wasn&#8217;t then, nor am I now, articulating a policy change.&nbsp; I was expressing the moral outrage that I feel, and I make no apologies for it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Your personal feelings, sir?&nbsp; Your personal feelings?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Personal.&nbsp; My personal feelings.</p>



<p>Secondly, you asked me about &#8212; what was the second part?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does it complicate the diplomacy of this moment?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I don&#8217;t think it does.&nbsp; You know, the &#8212; the fact is that we&#8217;re in a situation where &#8212; what complicates the situation at the moment is the &#8212; the escalatory efforts of Putin to continue to engage in carnage &#8212; the kind of behavior that &#8212; that makes the whole world say, &#8220;My God, what is this man doing?&#8221;&nbsp; That&#8217;s what complicates things a great deal.</p>



<p>And &#8212; but I don&#8217;t think it complicates it at all.</p>



<p>Let me go to Steve Holland, Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; When you say that you&#8217;re not walking anything back, you do feel that Vladimir Putin should be remained from &#8212; removed from power.&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re saying?&nbsp; And &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, what I was &#8212; I was expressing just what I said.&nbsp; I was expressing the moral outrage I felt towards this man.&nbsp; I wasn&#8217;t articulating a policy change.</p>



<p>And I think that, you know, if he continues on this course that he&#8217;s on, he is going to become a pariah worldwide.&nbsp; And who knows what he’d come &#8212; becomes at home, in terms of support.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a follow-up. &nbsp;Are you concerned this remark might escalate the conflict?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m not.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not at all.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look &#8212; you know, look, the other thing is that a couple people have asked me, as well &#8212; might as well speak to it, unless you want to ask the question &#8212; but, you know, that other governments have suggested that this is a problem, I&#8217;m escalating things.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; And it has weakened NATO?&nbsp;&nbsp; No, it hadn&#8217;t.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NATO has never ever, ever, ever, ever, ever been as strong as it is today.&nbsp; Never.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, if saying he cannot remain in power does not mean regime change, what does it mean in your view?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It means that I would hope &#8212; I just was expressing my outrage.&nbsp; He shouldn&#8217;t remain in power.&nbsp; Just like, you know, bad people shouldn&#8217;t continue to do bad things.</p>



<p>But it doesn&#8217;t mean we have a fundamental policy to do anything to take Putin down in any way.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What made you add that?&nbsp; Because that wasn&#8217;t in your prepared remarks, we were told.&nbsp; So what made you add that at the end, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because I was talking about &#8212; I was talking to the Russian people.&nbsp; The last part of the speech was talking to the Russian people, telling them what we thought.&nbsp; And I was communicating this to not only the Russian people, but the whole world.</p>



<p>This is &#8212; this is just stating a simple fact that this kind of behavior is totally unacceptable &#8212; totally unacceptable &#8212; and the way to deal with it is to strengthen and pu- &#8212; and put &#8212; keep NATO completely united and to help Ukraine where we can.</p>



<p>Cleve, you had a question?&nbsp; Where is he?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Mr. President.&nbsp; On your &#8212; on your budget, you&#8217;ve said repeatedly at the State of the Union that you are not for defunding the police.&nbsp; I do wonder how much emphasis you think should be put on alternative forms of crime prevention &#8212; not just defunding the police, but, you know, crime reduction in communities.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, a significant amount.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve laid that out in detail in the budget.</p>



<p>For example, we do know that intervention programs work.&nbsp; We do know that what police need, they &#8212; they need psychologists in the department as much as they need extra rifles.&nbsp; They need people who are in the department who can deal with the crisis that the police are going through as well &#8211;dealing with their crises, dealing with their mental state and how they&#8217;re handling things.&nbsp; They need out &#8212; they need social workers engaged with them.&nbsp; I lay it all out.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a &#8212; and it all works.&nbsp; If you see these community intervention programs, they work.&nbsp; They actually reduce crime. &nbsp;They significantly reduce crime.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s a big piece of it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a follow-up.&nbsp; Is any &#8212; is any of it related to political pressure from Republicans saying that Democrats are soft on crime; that &#8212; you know, that you guys are careening to the left?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t it kind of fascinating?&nbsp; When I first got elected, I was being beat up because I supported the police too much for the previous 30 years.&nbsp; No &#8212; it&#8217;s what I think.</p>



<p>And Asma.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, hi.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Are you &#8212; are you willing to try to meet with Vladimir Putin?&nbsp; And I have a quick follow-up to that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you last met with him face-to-fact in Geneva, you described that as a productive conversation; you said that he did not want a Cold War.&nbsp; And do you feel &#8212; given the actions, though, that have happened over the last few months, I guess I’m asking: What has changed, in his mind?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if it’s changed his mind.&nbsp; His behavior has changed.&nbsp; When we met, remember what we were talking about.&nbsp; We were talking about setting up a strategic dialogue and talking about the relationship of NATO and Russia and facing off in the regions and how we could have more transparency and all the rest.&nbsp; It was a normal discussion I had, going all the way back to Kosygin and others, back in &#8212; a hundred years ago, when I was a young senator.</p>



<p>And so, what changed was: nothing &#8212; nothing remotely approaching that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember when he first met with me, he said, “I have two objectives.”&nbsp; This is the second or third time I met with him.&nbsp; He said, “I have two objectives.”&nbsp; One is to make sure that they never become part of NATO.&nbsp; And two, to make sure there are no long-range missiles in there &#8212; in Ukraine.</p>



<p>I said, “We can deal with the second one easily, but we can’t close the door on the first.”&nbsp; Because when we talk about missiles, we want to talk about what’s also on the Russian border heading towards Europe.&nbsp; Do both.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and then, if you noticed, that demand list of his &#8212; not with me, with others &#8212; have escalated significantly in terms of what he thinks is necessary.</p>



<p>Thank you ver- &#8212; I’m going to take another one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know you’re going to ask a really nice question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, it’s &#8212; it’s an important question, I think.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I’m kidding.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you worried that other leaders in the world are going to start to doubt that America is back if some of these big things that you say on the world stage keep getting walked back?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What’s getting walked back?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It &#8212; made it sound like, just in the last couple of days &#8212; it sounded like you told U.S. troops they were going to Ukraine.&nbsp; It sounded like you said it was possible the U.S. would use a chemical weapon.&nbsp; And it sounded like you were calling for regime change in Russia.&nbsp; And we know &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; None of the three occurred.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; None of the three occurred?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; None of the three.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You interpret the language that way.&nbsp; I was talking to the troops.&nbsp; We were talking about helping train the troops in &#8212; that are &#8212; the Ukrainian troops that are in Poland.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the context.</p>



<p>I sat there with those guys for a couple hours.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we talked about.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So when you said, “You&#8217;re going to see when you&#8217;re there,” you were not intending to send U.S. (inaudible)?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I was referring to with &#8212; being with and talking with the Ukrainian troops who are in Poland.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when you said a chemical weapon use by Russia would “trigger a response in kind”?</p>



<p>THE PRESDIDENT:&nbsp; It will trigger a significant response (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does that mean?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to tell you.&nbsp; Why would I tell you?&nbsp; You got to be silly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The world wants to know.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The world wants to know a lot of things.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not telling them what the response would be; then Russia knows the response.</p>



<p>All right, I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I’m going to take two more questions.&nbsp; One, two.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, I still want to get back to your</p>



<p>original words that he cannot remain in power.&nbsp; Can you help us understand: You have more foreign policy experience than any President who has ever held this office.&nbsp; Whether those are your personal feelings or your feelings as President, do you understand why people would believe you, as someone commanding one of the largest nuclear arsenals in the world, saying someone cannot remain in power is a statement of U.S. policy?</p>



<p>And also, are you concerned about propaganda use of those remarks by the Russians?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No and no.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tell me why.&nbsp; You have so much experience.&nbsp; You are the leader of this country.</p>



<p><a>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because it’s ridiculous.&nbsp; Nobody believes we’re going to take town &#8212; I was going to &#8212; I was talking about taking down Putin.&nbsp; Nobody who believes that.&nbsp; Number one.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number two, what have I been talking about all &#8212; since this all began?&nbsp; The only war that’s worse than one intended is one that’s unintended. &nbsp;The last thing I want to do is engage in a land war or a nuclear war with Russia.&nbsp; That’s not part of it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was expressing my outrage at the behavior of this man.&nbsp; It’s outrageous.&nbsp; It’s outrageous.&nbsp; And it’s more an aspiration than anything.&nbsp; He shouldn’t be in power.</a></p>



<p>There’s no &#8212; I mean, people like this shouldn’t be ruling countries, but they do.&nbsp; The fact they do &#8212; but it doesn’t mean I can’t express my outrage about it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last question.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; You’ve said that you’re confident that your comment won’t undermine diplomatic efforts, but just to be clear, are you confident that Vladimir Putin sees it that way &#8212; that he will not use this as an escalatory &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don’t care what he thinks.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, here’s the deal: He’s going to do what he’s going to do.&nbsp; Putin &#8212; look &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you’re not concerned that he may see your language and view that as a sign of a reason for escalation &#8212; use that as an excuse to escalate, given &#8212;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; his recent behavior?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Given his recent behavior, you should &#8212; excuse me, I shouldn&#8217;t say that to you &#8212; given his recent behavior, people should understand that he is going to do what he thinks he should do.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; He&#8217;s not affected by anybody else, including, unfortunately, apparently his own advisors.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is a guy who goes to the beat of his own drummer.&nbsp; And the idea that he is going to do something outrageous because I called him for what he was and what he&#8217;s doing, I think is just not rational.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You didn’t say whether you’d meet him again.&nbsp; Would you meet with President Putin ever again?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It depen- &#8212; no, it&#8217;s not a question of ev- &#8212; the question is: Is there something to meet on that would justify him being able to end this war and be able to rebuild Ukraine.&nbsp; That’s the issue.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there is a chance you would meet with him?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you about the Supreme Court &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; sir?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you &#8212; can you just say &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Real quick, on the Supreme Court?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, can you just say yes or no, Mr. President, whether or not you would be willing to meet with President Putin again?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It depends on what he wants to talk about.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; AIDE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Last question.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What if he wanted to talk about negotiations though?&nbsp; What if he wanted to &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Now, look, you said Supreme Court.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Now, don’t play games, okay?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you can’t leave that hanging.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Just real quick &#8212; two matters on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; There &#8212; while you were away, there were reports about the wife of Justice Thomas and texts that she had with former White House Chief of Staff, Mark Meadows.&nbsp; Should Justice Thomas recuse himself from any cases involving the January 6th insurrection or former President Trump at this point?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’d leave that to two entities.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on &#8212; okay, go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, go ahead.&nbsp; Ask your second question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, two entities.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;(Laughs.)&nbsp; One, the January 6th committee and, two, the Justice Department.&nbsp; That&#8217;s their judgment, not mine to make.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, on Justice Thomas recusing, you don&#8217;t think he should?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not &#8212; I said that &#8212; I told you: Those things get into legal issues; that, in fact, I told you I would not tell the Justice Department what position to take or not take.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to instruct the Congress either.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And did you get any chance to watch much of the Judiciary Committee hearings last night?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp; I didn’t get a chance to see any of it, unfortunately.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The fact that Republicans were questioning Judge Jackson on matters like former sentences related to child pornography cases or the definition of a “woman” &#8212; does that, as the former chairman of the Judiciary Committee, make sense to you?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, this is one of the most qualified nominees ever nominated for the Supreme Court in every respect &#8212; in terms of her disposition, her intellectual capacity, her experience and background, and serving on two &#8212; three additional courts. &nbsp;A woman who is totally, thoroughly qualified &#8212; totally, thoroughly qualified, and will be a great addition to the Court, in my view.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3:23 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Deputy Press Secretary Andrew Bates, OMB Director Shalanda Young, and CEA Chair Cecilia&#160;Rouse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/28/press-briefing-by-deputy-press-secretary-andrew-bates-omb-director-shalanda-young-and-cea-chair-cecilia-rouse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 22:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 3:54 P.M. EDT MR. BATES:&#160; Good afternoon. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good afternoon. MR. BATES:&#160; Today, we are pleased to welcome Shalanda Young and Cecilia Rouse to the briefing room to address your questions on the 2023 budget.&#160; We have just a few announcements before they go into the President&#8217;s budget. As we disclosed to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>3:54 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Today, we are pleased to welcome Shalanda Young and Cecilia Rouse to the briefing room to address your questions on the 2023 budget.&nbsp; We have just a few announcements before they go into the President&#8217;s budget.</p>



<p>As we disclosed to all of you, this morning the President tested negative as a part of his regular testing cadence.&nbsp; He was last tested Friday as a part of his regular testing rhythm and additional testing requirements for travel to and from Europe.</p>



<p>Moving forward, he will proceed on his regular testing schedule, and we will continue to update all of you out of an abundance of transparency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, of course, we wish Karine and Jen speedy recoveries.&nbsp; They are currently both following CDC guidance and will be back following a negative test.&nbsp; Jen shared this morning that she&#8217;s feeling stir-crazy and will be back soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, on Judge Jackson.&nbsp; Judge Jackson continued to build support last week after she spent over 20 hours in marathon confirmation hearings demonstrating her credentials, intellect, character, grace, and the value of her deep experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She reminded the country of why the President chose her and why she has been endorsed by conservative judges, the Fraternal Order of Police, the International Association of Chiefs of Police, dozens of police chiefs and sheriffs who lead many of the busi- &#8212; busiest departments in the United States and 83 former state attorneys general from both parties.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Polls keep showing that she has strong backing among the American people, with some indicating that she has the most support of any Supreme Court nominee since John Roberts, who she ties with and whom she shares &#8212; and with whom she shares a similar philosophy about judges serving as referees who decide cases based on the law and the facts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She has now met with more than a majority of the Senate and is continuing her engagement with senators today and throughout the week.&nbsp; Judge Jackson responded to Republicans&#8217; requests for in-person meetings by promising to sit down with any member who wanted to, and she is honoring that promise.</p>



<p>Something else that speaks to the strength of Judge Jackson&#8217;s qualifications &#8212; which a series of Republicans have affirmed make her unquestionably fit to serve on the Supreme Court &#8212; and to the strength of her record is the multitude of factchecks from the press, from retired judges, and from former prosecutors who have dismantled attacks brought by a small group of GOP senators.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The truth is that every single one of the specific senators who joined in these bad-faith attacks on her sentencing record with respect to child pornography has voted for numerous Trump-nominated judges who sentenced defendants for the same crimes in the same fashion, below guidelines widely considered to be out of date across the judiciary and below what prosecutors sought, which is also a norm.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, last week, the Washington Post factchecker wrote a piece headlined &#8220;These Trump Judges Failed Hawley&#8217;s Sentencing Test for Jackson.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The New York Times factchecking team also covered this, writing, &#8220;Critics of Jackson&#8217;s Child Sex Abuse Sentences Backed Judges with Similar Records.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Trump-nominated judges they surveyed received broad support and even included 6th Circuit Judge Amul Thapar, who was on Donald Trump&#8217;s shortlist for the Supreme Court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This was all on top of a raft of other factchecks already establishing that the basis of these criticisms was dishonest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, in terms of the budget, as you heard the President discuss earlier today, he has released his second budget, which builds on historic deficit reduction his agenda is delivering by means of the fastest economic growth in almost 40 years, on top of record-breaking job creation and unemployment reduction in 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s budget will help bring more jobs back to America, make us safer at home by increasing funding for police, and more secure in the world by investing in our national security and alliances.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it will pay for these crucial policies by asking the ultra-wealthy &#8212; the top one hundredth of 1 percent of Americans, in terms of income &#8212; billionaires, and hundred-millionaires to pay an income tax that&#8217;s aligned with what most people in the workforce pay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We encourage Republicans in Congress to support that approach rather than their proposal to raise taxes on half of working families and taking healthcare coverage away from millions while gutting protections for Americans with pre-existing conditions in order to hand out even more tax giveaways to the wealthiest.</p>



<p>Shalanda Young is joining us for the first time in the briefing room.&nbsp; She is the Director of the Office of Management Budg- &#8212; and Budget, having been confirmed by the Senate with bipartisan support earlier this month.&nbsp; As Director, she serves as a senior advisor to President Biden and plays a critical role in implementing the President&#8217;s vision across the executive branch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Previously, Shalanda was the Acting Director of OMB for the last year, and the Clerk and Staff Director for the House Appropriations Committee, where she oversaw the $1.3 trillion annual appropriations bills.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also joined by Cecilia Rouse, who has been here numerous times, who is the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers and a member of the President&#8217;s Families Cabinet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a quick introduction, she is a world-respected labor economist who recently served as Dean of the Princeton School of Public and International Affairs.&nbsp; She previously served as a member of the Council of Economic Advisers in the Obama-Biden administration, and on the National Economic Council in the Clinton administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I&#8217;m going to turn it over to each of them, who will give remarks, and then I&#8217;ll call on folks for questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then once we&#8217;re done, we&#8217;re happy to take more questions from you all throughout the day in the press office.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Be nice to the newbie.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>For an OMB Director, this is like prom day, so I&#8217;m &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; very happy to be here with you today.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve heard the President say this, you heard him say it this morning: Budgets are about values.&nbsp; And his 2023 budget puts our values to work in three key ways.</p>



<p>First, it’s fiscally responsible.&nbsp; The budget shows that we&#8217;re on track to reduce the deficit by more than $1.3 trillion.&nbsp; This is the largest year-over-year decline in history and less than half of the deficit the President inherited.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s no accident.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a result of the President&#8217;s strategy to combat the pandemic and grow our economy &#8212; a strategy that has built on smart investments and helped jumpstart our recovery.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that strategy has paid off.&nbsp; In 2021, we created more than 6.5 million jobs &#8212; the most our country has ever recorded in a single year.&nbsp; Our economy grew 5.7 percent &#8212; the most in 40 years.&nbsp; And the unemployment rate has fallen to 3.8 percent &#8212; the fastest decline in recorded history.&nbsp; Because of that progress, we’re able to responsibly draw down emergency spending measures and increase revenues.</p>



<p>The budget outlines the President&#8217;s vision to expand on this progress.&nbsp; Its investments are more than fully paid for through tax reforms, ensure corporations and the wealthiest Americans pay their fair share.&nbsp; It achieves significant deficit reduction over the next decade.&nbsp; And it ensures no one earning less than $400,000 pays a penny more in new taxes.</p>



<p>Second, the budget invests in security both here and abroad.&nbsp; Here at home, it includes investments to keep our community safe, put more cops on the beat for community policing, fight gun crime, and advance criminal justice reform.</p>



<p>The budget also strengthens our military and leverages our renewed strength at home to meet pressing global challenges, making one of the largest investments in our national security in U.S. history.</p>



<p>Third, the budget will help us build a better America by investing in education; making more here at home; combating the opioid epidemic; driving medical breakthroughs, including in cancer; and taking on the mental health crisis.</p>



<p>The budget also makes clear that the President is committed to working with Congress to pass legislation that reduces the deficit, cuts costs for families, and expands the productive capacity of our economy.</p>



<p>These are all things we can make progress on together.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re looking forward to working with Congress to advance these priorities for the American people.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; This budget builds on the solid economic gains of the first year of this administration.&nbsp; The recovery over the last year has been extraordinary &#8212; quicker than independent forecasters had projected.</p>



<p>Over 2021, real output grew by 5.6 percent &#8212; the fastest since 1984.&nbsp; The unemployment rate fell at its fastest pace since modern data began in 1948.&nbsp; The labor force participation rate of Americans ages 25 to 54 grew by the most since 1979.</p>



<p>This robust recovery has put us in a strong position today.&nbsp; The U.S. economy is more than 3 percent larger in inflation-adjusted terms than it was just before the pandemic &#8212; the fastest recovery in the G7.</p>



<p>Healthy household balance sheets and a strong labor market make us more resilient to external shocks.&nbsp; The strong recovery has also put us in a better fiscal position as faster growth helps lower the deficit.</p>



<p>The budget builds on this solid economic growth.&nbsp; It is a continuation of President Biden&#8217;s commitment to address longstanding issues in the economy and make investments that will ensure robust, sustainable, and equitable growth.</p>



<p>First, the budget is fiscally responsible.&nbsp; Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, revenues are up and pandemic relief can slow down.</p>



<p>The result is deficit reduction, which will help ease long-term inflationary pressures and make our fiscal trajectory more sustainable.</p>



<p>Second, the budge- &#8212; the budget bolsters domestic and foreign security.&nbsp; Increased security here and abroad not only protects lives, but it also reduces uncertainty, which allows economic activity the room it needs to renormalize and grow.</p>



<p>Third, the economy makes important investments in the American people.&nbsp; A healthy, cared-for workforce is a productive workforce, and it lowers costs for families, easing price pressures over the longer term.</p>



<p>Now, I&#8217;d like to close with a word about our forecast.&nbsp; In many ways, the forecast looks healthier today than it did when we locked it all the way back last November.</p>



<p>The economy has created, on average, 600,000 jobs per mo- &#8212; per month since then, including through the Omicron wave.&nbsp; And the unemployment rate has fallen an additional 0.8 percentage point.</p>



<p>Challenges have also arisen since last November as well.&nbsp; The most obvious is the Russian invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; This may well put upward pressure on energy and food prices.&nbsp; That, in turn, could reinforce inflation, which was already an issue prior to the invasion due to the pandemic supply chain constraints and a strong demand for goods.</p>



<p>But as I said earlier, the strength of our recovery has put us on solid ground to weather economic shocks.&nbsp; Independent forecasters anticipate that inflation will come down.&nbsp; Americans are back to work, and the economy is strong.</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s 2023 budget presents a fiscally fair and responsible approach to continue to invest in America and meet future challenges.</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Josh, would you like to start us?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Director Young, Josh Boak with AP.&nbsp; I want to understand the reserve fund for whatever comes out of negotiations with Congress.&nbsp; You said on the call this morning that talks are “ongoing.”&nbsp; The budget says, of the President&#8217;s priorities, they include the expanded Child Tax Credit, something that we previously believed was off the table.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of where negotiations are and what we could expect in terms of how active they are, such that you felt obligated to exclude those priorities from the total?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; One, let me start where you ended.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not excluded.&nbsp; What we didn&#8217;t do is detail things.&nbsp; So we did not get ahead of negotiations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You probably heard that I spent a little time on Capitol Hill.&nbsp; What we don&#8217;t do is get ahead of congressional negotiations.&nbsp; We certainly don&#8217;t negotiate in public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reserve fund is meant to hold revenues enough for whatever framework comes out of Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re not doing is double counting revenue.&nbsp; So the revenues we&#8217;re holding in the reserve fund are different.&nbsp; For example, we&#8217;re not counting the savings from prescription drug reform in the deficit-neutral reserve fund.&nbsp; That &#8212; they can use that if they want; we&#8217;re not counting that for our ‘23 budget.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, one, we&#8217;re not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp; Two, we need to leave revenues for legislation.&nbsp; And the President has consistently called on Congress to send to his desk.&nbsp; And that that is, I think, as clear as I can be.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s been an exhausting month, as we can all attest to, and I imagine that&#8217;s true for you as well.&nbsp; Have you had any talks or negotiations with regard to this in the last month with members of Congress?</p>



<p>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; Look, I think a easy way to not get anything done is to negotiate in public.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to do that.&nbsp; The ‘23 budget I think is the responsible thing to do to hold enough revenues so Congress can use those if it wants, to send legislation to the President that reduces the deficit and reduces costs for the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Sabrina.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; You&#8217;re placing a lot of emphasis with this budget on deficit reduction.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit more about that?&nbsp; Is it an effort to persuade Senator Manchin and other centrists who have raised concerns about the deficit?&nbsp; Or does your administration believe that the deficit is, in fact, getting too high?</p>



<p>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; Let me remind you this President sent out a budget; this is his second one.&nbsp; And in both budgets, he has paid for his proposals.&nbsp; This is a classic Joe Biden budget.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, just as he did last year, we&#8217;re putting forward proposals that do two things: establishes a tax system that’s fair, where corporations and the wealthiest pay their fair share, but it has the added benefit of paying for needs of the American people, like reducing childcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what other &#8212; what specific proposals, beyond the wealth tax, would lower the deficit by a trillion dollars over the next decade, as you say?</p>



<p>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; So, one, we&#8217;re already in the process &#8212; from last year to this year &#8212; of reducing the deficit by $1.3 trillion.&nbsp; The proposals in the budget would also bring about another trillion-dollar decrease.&nbsp; In addition to the billionaire income tax proposal that we have in the budget, we also believe that we should take the individual rate back to 39.6 percent, and also bring corporate &#8212; corporate tax rates back up &#8212; not even quite back up to where they were before the Trump tax cuts.</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Steve.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Cecilia, you mentioned that the Ukraine invasion is going to have a &#8212; complicate &#8212; complicate inflation.&nbsp; Could you talk a little bit more about that?&nbsp; What should Americans express [sic]?&nbsp; High &#8212; expect higher gasoline prices, food?&nbsp; What do you think?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So, as the President just said, this is &#8212; this is an important &#8212; this is an important place for the United States.&nbsp; This is an important moment for democracy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but what we do know is that Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine will have impacts on both energy prices and food prices.&nbsp; So, we &#8212; he has &#8212; as the President has said, we can expect that while our sanctions are going to have their focus and most of their impact on the Russian economy, that we can expect that we will see a bit of impact in the United States as well.</p>



<p>So, the first we&#8217;re seeing is some impact on gas prices and oil prices.&nbsp; We can also expect, through fertilizer and energy prices, to see some impact on food.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That said, the President is focused on doing what he can to ensure that those increases are contained and that they are not &#8212; that, you know, they&#8217;re doing what he can to ease them for the American people.&nbsp; So that is &#8212; he&#8217;s worked with our partners to increase an additional 60 million barrels from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; And he has &#8212; he has other options on the table that he will be considering as they come up.</p>



<p>In terms of food prices, you know, the U.S. &#8212; we don&#8217;t expect a shortage here because we are net exporters.&nbsp; But we are acutely aware of the fact that there are regions in the world that depend heavily on exports of wheat, in particular, and other grains from Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working with our partners to ensure to min- &#8212; to minimize the impacts globally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just &#8212; for Dr. Rouse &#8212; just following up on what you said: How is the White House preparing to deal with those food shortages, particularly when it comes to wheat in places like Africa, the Middle East, and the developing countries?&nbsp; And should U.S. farmers grow more wheat this year instead of corn and soybeans, given the possible food shortages?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So, first of all, we are a net exporter of many of those food commodities, and farmers respond to price signals.&nbsp; And so, with the price of food rising, they will be responding by doing &#8212; making additional plantings and trying to take advantage of the increased price signals.&nbsp; So the market will work as the market will work.</p>



<p>But the U.S. is working with our partners &#8212; USAID is right in the middle of it and other international food organizations &#8212; to get the food and to ease the price pressures for other countries around the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to just to follow up on that &#8212; I’m sorry, to follow up on that, is there &#8212; are you having &#8212; is there any &#8212; are you think- &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; Have you considered altering the sanctions to make it clear that there&#8217;s no restrictions on agricultural trade with Russia?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So the sanctions have always had carveouts for humanitarian needs.&nbsp; The focus of the sanctions was to be on Putin and his close circle but to not make &#8212; to minimize, to the extent possible, the impact on the Russian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there has been a carveout for humanitarian aid, and we will absolutely be working to ensure that they get the food that they need.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow up?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you just &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. BATES:&nbsp; No &#8212; no, sorry.&nbsp; Calling on the gentleman from USA Today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thanks, Andrew.&nbsp; I want to follow up on what the administration has proposed in police funding.&nbsp; So, $3.2 billion is for grants, local and state grants.&nbsp; And then the other $30 billion &#8212; the White House has called it, quote, “mandatory resources to support law enforcement.”&nbsp; What does it mean by “mandatory”?&nbsp; And how will that money flow to, presumably, local governments and states for police forces?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; So, as you know, the budget &#8212; two major spending categories: discretionary, which will go through the appropriations process &#8212; that is where we&#8217;re asking for the $3.2 billion.&nbsp; There are traditional accounts, like the community-oriented policing account in Byrne JAG that the Appropriations Committee already funds.&nbsp; We&#8217;re asking for increases in those accounts.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The mandatory side &#8212; it is a new proposal.&nbsp; We would have to work with and are planning to work with the authorizers who typically move mandatory legislation on the parameters of that funding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what is clear, and you heard the President talk about this earlier: In addition to cops on the beat, we want a community focus.&nbsp; We also know that it takes a comprehensive approach, that police forces around the country should have mental health services, psychiatrists.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why our community violence initiative &#8212; we&#8217;re asking for money not only in DOJ and in HHS on the discretionary side.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the plan is, on the mandatory side &#8212; is a new proposal to work with those authorizing committees to ensure that it is both strong on the policing side but also have these wraparound services.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the mandatory side, I mean, are there any goals in terms of how many more police officers could be added nationwide or any priorities &#8212; you&#8217;ve mentioned a couple of them, but in terms of what you want to see this money used on?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how much leeway will police forces have versus it coming down from the federal government on where the money can go?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; As you know, these decisions are best made at the local level, not even &#8212; state, most often, when it comes to policing efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So my &#8212; what we plan on doing is working with the judiciary committees to ensure that we provide flexible enough funding but be very clear that we expect a community focus and also that we have the wraparound services necessary, including mental health services, to make sure that we bring down violence in our communities.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when you talk about unemployment &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. BATES:&nbsp; MJ.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; do you take into account the millions &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You all have said that the &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; of Americans who have lost &#8212; who have left their job?&nbsp; Do you take that into account?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. BATES:&nbsp; Sir, we’re calling on MJ.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You all have said that the inflation estimates for this budget were set in November and if the invasion were to be taken into account, the outlook would look pretty different.&nbsp; So should we expect an updated analysis from this administration on that front to take into account the invasion?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, just in terms of the timeline, do you all have an estimate for when people can expect things to level out again?&nbsp; Can we expect that during this calendar year?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; So we will be doing a mid-session update of our budget later this summer.&nbsp; That is typically what we do.&nbsp; And obviously, for next year&#8217;s budget, it will be &#8212; we will use a new budget that will not be quite as old &#8212; at least for next year.</p>



<p>You know, outside forecasters who have been &#8212; you know, who are studying this as well &#8212; expect that inflation will be higher than they were anticipating back when we locked our budget, so then &#8212; at the beginning of the year before the invasion.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But they do expect that as we learn to maintain economic activity while we are still working through this pandemic; while we &#8212; while supply chains continue to improve &#8212; although, obviously, there is &#8212; there is uncertainty there with, for example, lockdowns in China, but we expect them to work through that &#8212; that we expect supply chain challenges to ease.&nbsp; We do expect inflation to ease this year and into next year.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. BATES:&nbsp; So we have a 4:15 out, so we&#8217;re going to need to go.&nbsp; But just send us any other questions you have in the press office (inaudible).<br><br>4:16 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sequestration Order for Fiscal Year 2023 Pursuant to Section 251A of the Balanced Budget And Emergency Deficit Control Act, as&#160;Amended</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/28/sequestration-order-for-fiscal-year-2023-pursuant-to-section-251a-of-the-balanced-budget-and-emergency-deficit-control-act-as-amended/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 20:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49942</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the laws of&#160;the United States of America, and in accordance with section&#160;251A of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act (the &#8220;Act&#8221;), as amended, 2 U.S.C. 901a, I hereby order that, on October 1, 2022, direct spending budgetary resources for fiscal year 2023 in each&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the laws of&nbsp;the United States of America, and in accordance with section&nbsp;251A of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act (the &#8220;Act&#8221;), as amended, 2 U.S.C. 901a, I hereby order that, on October 1, 2022, direct spending budgetary resources for fiscal year 2023 in each non-exempt budget account be reduced by the amount calculated by the Office of Management and Budget in its report to the Congress of March 28, 2022.</p>



<p>All sequestrations shall be made in strict accordance with&nbsp;the requirements of section 251A of the Act and the specifications of the Office of Management and Budget&#8217;s report of March 28, 2022, prepared pursuant to section 251A(9) of the&nbsp;Act.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;March 28, 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the Commemoration of the 50th Anniversary of the Vietnam&#160;War</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/28/a-proclamation-on-the-commemoration-of-the-50th-anniversary-of-the-vietnam-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 20:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On National Vietnam War Veterans Day, we honor all those who bravely served in the Vietnam War and who sacrificed, as did their families and caregivers, on behalf of our Nation.      For almost two decades, Americans raised their right hands and committed to serve and defend our Constitution as uniformed members of the United&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On National Vietnam War Veterans Day, we honor all those who bravely served in the Vietnam War and who sacrificed, as did their families and caregivers, on behalf of our Nation.</p>



<p>     For almost two decades, Americans raised their right hands and committed to serve and defend our Constitution as uniformed members of the United States Armed Forces during a tumultuous period in our country&#8217;s history.  Throughout the years of the Vietnam War, 9 million Americans earned the title of United States veteran.  Today and every day, we honor their bravery and commitment and give thanks to a generation of Americans who valiantly fought in service of the country they love while recognizing the continuing impact on so many veterans of the Vietnam conflict, along with their families, caregivers, and survivors.  We will always remember those we lost and honor those who came home.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In 2012, our Nation launched a 13-year long commemoration of the 50th anniversary of the Vietnam War to ensure that every veteran, family, caregiver, and survivor impacted by the difficult years in Vietnam feels our Nation&#8217;s gratitude for their sacrifice. &nbsp;Every service member of the Vietnam generation should know that their sacrifices mattered and that their service made a difference.&nbsp; The names etched in The Wall at the Vietnam Veterans Memorial remind us of our loved ones who gave their all and never came home.&nbsp; To the families, caregivers, and survivors of the more than 58,000 service members whose names are memorialized in the black granite, we pledge to never forget the eternal sacrifice of your loved ones&nbsp;and what you have sacrificed for the Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To the families of the over 1,500 service members who remain missing and unaccounted for, know that our Nation&#8217;s efforts to bring them home will never stop.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We pledge our steadfast care and support to our Vietnam veterans, as we do for all of our veterans. &nbsp;We will honor our&nbsp;sacred obligation to you and your family.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to each of the 6 million Vietnam War era veterans who are with us today, we honor your service and all that you have done for our Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby affirm this Nation&#8217;s commitment to commemorate the 50th Anniversary of the Vietnam War, which began on Memorial Day, May&nbsp;28, 2012, and which will continue through Veterans Day, November&nbsp;11, 2025. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to seek out and extend the Nation&#8217;s profound gratitude to each of our Vietnam veterans and their families and caretakers during public ceremonies and programs throughout the country, while expressing deep compassion for the families of the fallen, those who remain missing and unaccounted for, and all others who served yet no longer walk among us.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this</p>



<p>twenty-eighth day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s Historic Investment in Pandemic Preparedness and Biodefense in the FY 2023 President’s&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/28/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-historic-investment-in-pandemic-preparedness-and-biodefense-in-the-fy-2023-presidents-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[COVID-19 has exacted an unfathomable toll on our nation and the world, causing millions of deaths and trillions of dollars in economic losses globally, and highlighting the inter-dependency between our nation’s health security and that of the world. Throughout the pandemic, Americans and people around the world have personally experienced the health, social, and economic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>COVID-19 has exacted an unfathomable toll on our nation and the world, causing millions of deaths and trillions of dollars in economic losses globally, and highlighting the inter-dependency between our nation’s health security and that of the world. Throughout the pandemic, Americans and people around the world have personally experienced the health, social, and economic impacts caused by infectious diseases. The COVID-19 response has illuminated both longstanding and newly discovered limitations in our local, national, and international health systems and health security capabilities. It has also resulted in an unparalleled, multisectoral, whole-of-society response, which has galvanized breakthrough innovation. The Biden-Harris administration has made great progress in combatting COVID-19 and building better health security to protect against future pandemics and other health emergencies. However, much more is needed to prevent future biological catastrophes. In America and around the world, people want to know: what can we do to stop future pandemics? We must increase and sustain our investments across the U.S. Government to better prevent, detect, and respond to pandemics, and to build a world safe and secure from biological threats.</p>



<p>The FY23 President’s Budget includes a historic $88.2 billion request for mandatory funding, available over five years, across the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response (ASPR), the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), the Department of State, and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to prepare for future biological threats in support of objectives within U.S. national and global biodefense and pandemic preparedness strategies and plans. This investment will fund transformative improvements in our capabilities to prevent, detect, and respond to emerging biological catastrophes.  If we want to create a world free of pandemics and other biological catastrophes, the time to act is now.  </p>



<p>The Budget will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Transform our capability to rapidly produce and deliver countermeasures against pandemics and other biological threats. </strong>The Budget includes $40 billion for the HHS ASPR to invest in advanced development and manufacturing of countermeasures for high priority threats and viral families, including vaccines, therapeutics, diagnostics, and personal protective equipment (PPE). This funding would support development of novel technologies, including rapidly scalable vaccine production technologies; technologies to simplify the administration of vaccines; effective and broadly-acting therapeutics; next-generation PPE; rapidly scalable, affordable, and effective diagnostics; pathogen-agnostic detection technologies; and tools to suppress pathogen transmission in the built environment, including ventilation, sterilization, and antimicrobial and antiviral surfaces. This funding will also support manufacturing capacity to surge countermeasure production in response to future biological threats, whether from COVID-19 variants or another emergent biological threat. These investments build towards the ambitious goals of developing effective vaccines and therapeutics within 100 days of identifying a biological threat, producing sufficient quantities to vaccinate the United States population within 130 days, and supporting surge production to rapidly meet global needs.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Strengthen our public health infrastructure and early warning capabilities. </strong>The Budget provides $28 billion for the CDC to enhance public health system infrastructure, domestic and global threat surveillance, public health workforce development, public health laboratory capacity, and global health security. These efforts will ensure the nation is prepared to effectively contain and mitigate future biological threats and will enable States, localities, tribal nations, and Territories to mount a rapid and robust response to future outbreaks. These investments will complement discretionary funding to modernize public health data collection and increase capacity for disease early warning forecasting and analyzing future outbreaks, including at the Center for Forecasting and Outbreak Analytics. Funding will also promote health equity in pandemic response infrastructure through initiatives to support marginalized and underserved communities through community-based public health services and support state-based and international efforts to control antibiotic resistance.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in basic research to enable an effective response to novel pandemics and biological threats. </strong>The Budget provides $12.1 billion to NIH for research and development of vaccines, diagnostics, and therapeutics against high priority biological threats, including safe and secure laboratory capacity and clinical trial infrastructure. Developing a vaccine against COVID-19 built on twenty years of prior federally funded scientific research on coronaviruses. Accordingly, the Budget supports preclinical and clinical research and development of prototype vaccines and therapeutics against priority viral families. These investments will provide essential foundational knowledge to meet the goal of developing vaccines and therapeutics against novel biological threats within 100 days.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Modernize and streamline our regulatory infrastructure.</strong> The Budget provides $1.6 billion for the FDA to expand and modernize regulatory capacity, information technology, and laboratory infrastructure to support the evaluation of medical countermeasures.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Advance biosafety and biosecurity in the United States and globally to prevent biological incidents.&nbsp;</strong>The Budget&nbsp;provides $1.8 billion within the total $88.2 billion request to&nbsp;enable the CDC and NIH to expand efforts to strengthen biosafety and biosecurity practices domestically and globally. This includes applied research and innovation in biosafety and biosecurity, which will expand capabilities to identify and minimize safety and security risks in the design and development of biotechnology.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Transform global health security and pandemic preparedness for COVID-19 variants and future biological threats.</strong> A biological threat anywhere can turn into a health emergency everywhere.&nbsp; The most effective way to respond to biological threats is to respond to it at its source. The Budget includes $6.5 billion in mandatory funding for the Department of State and USAID to make transformative investments in pandemic and biological threat preparedness globally, which complements ongoing U.S. investments to also strengthen health systems. This includes $4.5 billion in seed funding to establish global, regional, and local capacity through a new financial intermediary fund at the World Bank focused on global health security and pandemic preparedness. This effort will build on U.S. global health security investments and provide a more structured platform to account for and measure international gaps and gains.&nbsp; It will also accelerate U.S. leadership to bring other donors to the table and will provide $500 million over five years to the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI) to support innovating science and technological capabilities to shorten the cycle for development of safe, effective, and affordable vaccines.</li></ul>



<p>These investments will build on and accelerate innovations to prepare for future COVID-19 variants, and ensure the capabilities we are building to combat COVID-19 are sustained for future pandemics.Acknowledging the possibility that future COVID-19 variants could have severe consequences for U.S. health and livelihoods, the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, HHS, and the White House COVID-19 team launched the Pandemic Innovation Task Force, which assembled science and technology leaders across the executive branch to accelerate pandemic innovations with the potential to have a major impact on our ability to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic and future biological threats.</p>



<p>Collectively, these activities will build capabilities the nation urgently needs to respond to future pandemics and biological threats from any source, strengthen international systems so that we can detect threats early and respond rapidly, and enable the nation to decisively act on the lessons from COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-the-Record Press Call by OMB Director Shalanda Young and CEA Chair Cecilia Rouse on the President&#8217;s FY23&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/28/on-the-record-press-call-by-omb-director-shalanda-young-and-cea-chair-cecilia-rouse-on-the-presidents-fy23-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 15:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[8:37 A.M. EDT MR. FRIEDLANDER:&#160;&#160;Good morning, everyone.&#160; Thanks for joining us for this on-the-record call about the President&#8217;s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget.&#160; We&#8217;re joined by OMB Director Shalanda Young and Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers Cecilia Rouse.&#160; They will each offer a few brief comments at the top, and then we&#8217;ll hold time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>8:37 A.M. EDT<br><br>MR. FRIEDLANDER:&nbsp;&nbsp;Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us for this on-the-record call about the President&#8217;s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget.&nbsp; We&#8217;re joined by OMB Director Shalanda Young and Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers Cecilia Rouse.&nbsp; They will each offer a few brief comments at the top, and then we&#8217;ll hold time for some questions at the end.<br><br>Again, this call will be on the record, and it&#8217;s embargoed until 11:00 a.m. Eastern time today.<br><br>You all should have received embargoed materials from our team a short while ago.&nbsp; If, for some reason, you haven&#8217;t, please reach out to us and we&#8217;ll make sure you get what you need.<br><br>With that, I will turn it over to Director Young.<br><br>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; Thank you, Rob.&nbsp; Thank you all for joining.&nbsp; And Happy Budget Day, as I like to call today.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ve heard the President say that budgets are about values, and his budget for fiscal year 2023 makes our values clear in three important ways.&nbsp;<br><br>First, this budget is fiscally responsible.&nbsp; It shows that we&#8217;re on track to reduce the deficit by more than $1.3 trillion this year.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the largest-ever one-year decline and less than half of the 2020 deficit the President inherited.&nbsp;<br><br>This progress was not an accident.&nbsp; It was a direct result of the President&#8217;s strategy to combat the pandemic and grow our economy from the bottom up and the middle out &#8212; a strategy that was built on smart, fiscally prudent investments that helped jumpstart our recovery.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ve seen that strategy pay off.&nbsp; In 2021, we created more than 6.5 million jobs &#8212; the most our country has ever recorded in a single year.&nbsp; Our economy grew at 5.7 percent &#8212; the strongest growth in nearly 40 years.&nbsp; And the unemployment rate has fallen to 3.8 percent &#8212; the fastest decline in recorded history.&nbsp;<br><br>The budget outlines the President&#8217;s vision to expand this progress.&nbsp; Its investments are more than fully paid for through the tax reforms that ensure corporations and the wealthiest Americans pay their fair share, including a new billionaire minimum income tax.&nbsp; It achieves significant deficit reduction over the next decade, and it ensures that no one earning less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional penny in new taxes.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Second, the budget invests in security both at home and abroad.&nbsp; Here at home, it includes critical investments to keep our communities safe, fund crime prevention and community violence intervention, put more cops on the beat for community policing, fight gun violence, and advance criminal justice reform.&nbsp;<br><br>And during what will be a decisive decade for the world, the budget makes one of the largest investments in national security in U.S. history, strengthening our military and leveraging our renewed strength at home to meet pressing global challenges.&nbsp;<br><br>And third, the budget delivers on the agenda the President laid out in his State of the Union Address to help build a better America.&nbsp; It advances a bipartisan Unity Agenda through proposals to take on the mental health crisis, combat the opioid epidemic, support our veterans, and accelerate progress against cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>And it makes other key investments in the American people, building a stronger economy and promoting job creation, improving our country&#8217;s public health infrastructure, combating the climate crisis, and advancing equity and opportunity across our economy and our country.&nbsp;<br><br>As the President made clear in his State of the Union, he&#8217;s also committed to working with Congress to pass legislation that reduces the deficit; cuts healthcare, energy, childcare, and other costs for families; and reforms the tax system.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Because those discussions with Congress are ongoing, the budget does not include specific line items for the investments associated with that future legislation, nor does it count any of the savings from the prescription drugs or tax reforms that the House advanced as part of its Build Back Better Act.&nbsp;<br><br>Instead, the budget incorporates a reserve for the legislation and lays out the President&#8217;s three principles:&nbsp; Legislation must cut costs for families, cut the deficit, and expand the productive capacity of the economy.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve been clear that the President wants to sign legislation that cuts costs for families and reduces the deficit.&nbsp; But to be conservative, the budget reflects this reserve fund as deficit neutral.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, stepping back, what this budget shows is that we can grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out, and invest in the American people, and that we can do it in a smart, fiscally responsible way.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>With that, let me turn it over to Chair Rouse to talk about the budget&#8217;s economic outlook and forecast.<br><br>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Thank you, Director Young.&nbsp; And thank you for your time today.&nbsp; I want to use this opportunity to cover two important elements of the budget: the economic motivation and the economic forecast behind this policy.&nbsp; This budget builds on the solid economic gains of the first year of this administration.&nbsp;<br><br>Remember where we were when President Biden took office.&nbsp; The pandemic still had a strong grip on the economy, and recovery was uneven and anemic.&nbsp; We actually lost 115,000 jobs in December of 2020 alone, and roughly 4 million workers had been unemployed for more than six months.&nbsp; Unemployment was forecast to come down but slowly.<br><br>Today, the country looks very different.&nbsp; The recovery over the last year has been extraordinary; quicker than independent forecasters projected.&nbsp; With over three quarters of the adult population fully vaccinated, the economy has been able to reopen and rebound.<br><br>Over 2021, real output grew by 5.6 percent &#8212; the fastest since 1984.&nbsp; The unemployment rate fell at its fastest pace since modern data began in 1948.&nbsp; The labor force participation rates of Americans 25 to 54 years old grew by the most since 1979.<br><br>This robust recovery has put us in a strong position today.&nbsp; The U.S. economy is more than 3 percent larger in inflation-adjusted terms than it was before the pandemic &#8212; the fastest recovery in the G7.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Healthy household balance sheets and a strong labor market make us more resilient to external shocks.<br><br>The strong recovery has also put us in a better fiscal position as faster growth helps lower the deficit.&nbsp;<br><br>The Fiscal Year ‘23 budget builds on this solid economic growth.&nbsp; It is a continuation of President Biden&#8217;s commitment to address longstanding issues in the economy and make investments that will ensure strong, sustainable growth that benefits all Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>First, the budget is fiscally responsible.&nbsp; Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, the economy recovered faster in 2021 than expected.&nbsp; Revenues are up, and the pandemic relief (inaudible).&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The result is that the expected deficit in Fiscal Year 2022 is $1.3 trillion smaller than it was in Fiscal Year ‘21.&nbsp; And we believe the policies in this budget will further reduce the deficit by another trillion over the next decade.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>A lower deficit will help ease long-term inflationary pressures and make our fiscal trajectory more sustainable.<br><br>Second, the budget bolsters domestic and foreign security.&nbsp; Increased security here and abroad not only protects lives, but it also reduces uncertainty, which allows economic activity the room it needs to renormalize and grow as the pandemic eases.&nbsp;<br><br>Third, the budget makes important investments in the American people.&nbsp; A healthy, cared-for workforce is a productive workforce.&nbsp; Moreover, the budget lowers costs for families such as healthcare, childcare, and energy &#8212; measures that will ease price pressures over the longer term.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;d like to close with a word about our forecast.&nbsp; In many ways, the economy looks healthier today than it did when we locked our forecast all the way back in last November.&nbsp; The economy has created an average of 600,000 jobs per month since then, including through the Omicron wave.&nbsp; And the unemployment rate has fallen an additional 0.8 percentage points since then.<br><br>Indeed, private forecasters now project the unemployment rate to be lower than the 3.9 and 3.6 percent we projected for 2022 and 2023, respectively.<br><br>But challenges have arisen since last November as well.&nbsp; The most obvious is the Russian invasion of Ukraine, which will have ramifications that are not reflected in our forecast.&nbsp;&nbsp;For example, the inflation [sic] will li- &#8212; the invasion will likely put upward pressure on energy and food prices.&nbsp;&nbsp;That, in turn, could reinforce inflation that was already an issue prior to the invasion due to the pandemic, supply chain constraints, and a strong demand for goods.&nbsp;<br><br>Independent forecasters therefore expect somewhat slower GDP growth but still anticipate that inflation will come down.&nbsp;<br><br>As I said earlier, the strength of our recovery has put us on solid ground to weather economic shocks.&nbsp; Americans are back to work, and the economy is stronger than anyone, including the federal government and private forecasters, imagined when President Biden took office.&nbsp;<br><br>The President&#8217;s 2023 budget presents a fiscally fair and responsible approach to build on the progress we&#8217;ve made so far to invest in America and meet our future challenges.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. FRIEDLANDER:&nbsp; Great. Thank you very much.&nbsp; Moderator, we&#8217;ll take a few questions now.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Happy Monday to everyone.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I was hoping to get more sense of how you&#8217;re looking at inflation, given that from 2023 onward there&#8217;s the expectation that CPI goes to 2.3 percent.&nbsp; Is the idea that we just need another year of adjustment?&nbsp; Or what’s kind of&nbsp;underlying that forecast?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; I’m sorry, the question about the forecast itself?&nbsp; Or is it &#8212; is the question about how we’re seeing inflation now, going forward?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The economic assumptions have inflation CPI at 2.3 percent in table S-9.&nbsp; And I’m curious for &#8212; is the implication there that &#8212; that, in a sense, like, we just have another year of rough inflation in that assumption, or kind of what you’re forward thinking on that is?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So we an- &#8212; so the &#8212; first of all, let’s remember that the forecast was locked on November 10th of 2021.&nbsp; So that was quite a while ago.&nbsp; So this &#8212; this economic forecast, if we were updating today, we would look at it somewhat differently.</p>



<p>But let’s understand where the inflation forecast comes from.&nbsp; We were living through a pandemic where we supported households, as we needed to do, to get through this health crisis, and at the same time, the supply chains crumbled beneath us.</p>



<p>As a result, we had a mismatch between supply and demand, which generated some inflation.&nbsp; We are not alone.&nbsp; This &#8212; we see this inflation across the developed world with other countries that were supporting their households, their workers, their businesses through the pandemic.</p>



<p>Nonetheless, we expected, back in November, that inflationary pressures would ease as the economy started to renormalize; as we learned to keep our economic activity going, supporting us through the pandemic, and as supply chain challenges started to renormalize.&nbsp; And as the extraordinary support both by the monetary policy &#8212; so, in our case, the Federal Reserve &#8212; and fiscal policy, which was no longer needed, could be eased, we expected these inflationary pressures to ease over the coming year.</p>



<p>Then Russia invaded Ukraine.&nbsp; That has created additional upward pressure on prices.&nbsp; That happened in February, well after our forecast was already completed.&nbsp; We do expect that that is going to create additional price pressures over the coming year.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, the fundamentals are that we expect that as we learn to keep economic activity going through additional waves of the pandemic &#8212; we hope there won’t be many &#8212; but as we continue to work through the challenge of the pandemic, that we will keep economic activity going, supply chain pressures will ease, the extraordinary measures will start to roll off as well, and we expect the economy to normalize.</p>



<p>But there&#8217;s tremendous uncertainty.&nbsp; But we and other external forecasters expect that inflation will ease over the coming year (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I have a couple of questions.&nbsp; The first is: If you could explain the Reserve fund a little bit more, because it looks like, from the &#8212; from the S-2 table, that the deficit reduction is including the tax proposals that you guys are putting forward.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m trying to understand how the reserve fund would work but also not impede the deficit reduction you guys are hoping to achieve over the next decade.</p>



<p>And then, just quickly, I was wondering if there are any changes to the top individual income rate in this and then also the provision on stock buyback.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t see that listed here just yet.<br><br>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; So, let me be clear &#8212; and thank you for the question and the opportunity to explain.&nbsp; The tax proposals we’re holding for the deficit-neutral reserve fund are different than the tax proposals we are accounting for our deficit reduction proposals.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re paying for our investments on top of what we&#8217;re holding in the deficit-neutral reserve fund.&nbsp; We felt it was the responsible thing to do to not double-count those savings, so those things &#8212; those are two separate proposals.&nbsp; So you don&#8217;t see a line item of those tax proposals in the deficit-neutral reserve fund, but they are separate and apart from the line items you do see included, as far as tax reforms in the budget.</p>



<p>As far as the individual rate, the top rate goes to 39.6 percent &#8212; the same as under President Obama and Biden administration.&nbsp; And so those are, I believe, the two major questions you had.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing &#8212; thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I’m hearing a weird echo, but we&#8217;ll try anyway.</p>



<p>Basically, my core question is: A lot of the budget experts are saying, you know, look, the reason the deficit is falling is because the expiration of inherently temporary economic programs, and it&#8217;s kind of absurd for the administration to be taking credit&nbsp;for the decline from inherently temporary economic programs.&nbsp; Can I get a response to that?&nbsp; Is that (inaudible), or do you think that (inaudible)?<br><br>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; Three letters: ARP.&nbsp; This was not by accident.&nbsp; And had the President not had the wisdom and the fortitude, as some people were saying it was time to retract and stop doing pandemic spending, I don’t believe and many experts don’t believe we’d be here.&nbsp; The growth we saw last year, the highest in 40 years, that added more jobs than ever recorded last year, we don&#8217;t believe was by accident.&nbsp; And without the American Rescue Plan, we don&#8217;t believe we would be here.&nbsp;<br><br>The scarring we&#8217;ve seen after past recessionary (inaudible) and after the last economic failure after Wall Street, we saw significant scarring that took years for the economy to come through.&nbsp; So, we believe that was the right medicine at the time.&nbsp; And everything that the President is rightfully taking credit for, you can find right back to the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Hi, this is Cecilia Rouse.&nbsp; And I would just add that if we go back to the Great Recession, it took about four years for us to return to this normal fiscal posture, and we&#8217;re doing it in two.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this question.&nbsp; One question on the inflation assumption.&nbsp; So, 2.3 percent this year and next year, and stable, is not realistic.&nbsp; Under a more realistic inflation assumption, can you still claim $1 trillion in deficit reduction?&nbsp; Would you still stand by that number?&nbsp;<br><br>And then, also the fact that you have a placeholder for Build Back Better, does that mean that the talks are close?&nbsp; Can you tell us how hopeful you are coming to a deal?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; Eric, I&#8217;ll take the first one, the &#8212; your second question first, before turning it over to Chair Rouse on inflation.&nbsp;<br><br>What we&#8217;re not going to do &#8212; and I think I mentioned in the opening remarks &#8212; is get ahead of congressional negotiations.&nbsp; The deficit-neutral reserve fund is meant to leave the space, the revenue specifically, to allow congressional negotiators the room to do what President Biden has asked.&nbsp; He has asked for legislation that reduce costs for Americans and reduces the deficit.&nbsp; So that is what the budget is putting forth.&nbsp;<br><br>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; And regarding the inflation: So, as I noted earlier, this budget was locked and our forecasts were locked before various factors, which have led forecasters, including the Fed, to raise their inflation expectations.&nbsp; Of course, the most recent example is the Russian invasion of Ukraine and its impact on energy and food prices.&nbsp;<br><br>We will have a chance to update our forecast for the next budget.&nbsp; And those will &#8212; and that update will reflect recent events that were unknown at the time of the forecast.&nbsp;<br><br>But regarding the impact of this inflation on deficit impacts, so what you see is that &#8212; this shows we have actually done analysis of the impact of unexpected changes in inflation on our budget.&nbsp; And based on that analysis, inflation above the forecast raises both expenditures and revenues by similar amounts, such that it will have little impact on the deficit overall.<br><br>MR. FRIEDLANDER:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, Moderator.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ve got time for one more.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; This question is for Chair Rouse and it also relates to the inflation forecasts.&nbsp; You also have a very low interest rate forecast, which I &#8212; you locked in last November.&nbsp; But as we&#8217;ve all seen, the Federal Reserve has accelerated its plans to tighten (inaudible), and it&#8217;s already set in plans to get the funds rate to 2.8 percent next year, and now it&#8217;s assumed that it will get there this year &#8212; perhaps as soon as this year and perhaps even further.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s quite a lot higher than the Treasury yield forecasts in your economic assumptions.&nbsp; Can you tell me how a more up-to-date interest rate assumption might affect the budget outlook, the deficits and debts, et cetera?&nbsp;<br><br>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s important to remember that our debt service line in our summary tables is based on real debt service and real interest rates.&nbsp; So even as nominal rates have been rising, real rates remain negative and will very likely remain negative in the near term.<br><br>In the longer term, our interest rate assumptions remain in sync with the market and other forecasters’ expectations, leaving to the fact that under the President&#8217;s budget, real interest rate payments remain below their historical average throughout the coming decade.<br><br>MR. FRIEDLANDER:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; And thank you all again for joining.&nbsp; A reminder this call is on the record and embargoed until 11:00 a.m. Eastern time today, as are the materials that we provided to you earlier.&nbsp;<br><br>If you have additional questions, feel free to be in touch with us by email or phone, and we will be happy to follow up.&nbsp; Hope everyone has a great day.&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp;<br><br>8:57 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking on Gun Crime and Violence with a Whole-of-Government&#160;Approach</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2022/03/28/taking-on-gun-crime-and-violence-with-a-whole-of-government-approach/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 15:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In his State of the Union address earlier this month, President Biden highlighted his comprehensive strategy to reduce gun violence. He emphasized the $350 billion in American Rescue Plan funds that we’ve made available for cities, counties, and states that enable them to hire more police and invest in proven strategies like community violence intervention.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In his State of the Union <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/02/remarks-by-president-biden-in-state-of-the-union-address/">address</a> earlier this month, President Biden highlighted his comprehensive strategy to reduce gun violence. He emphasized the $350 billion in American Rescue Plan funds that we’ve made available for cities, counties, and states that enable them to hire more police and invest in proven strategies like community violence intervention. He talked about our efforts to crack down on difficult-to-trace “ghost guns,” part of an aggressive array of executive actions to reduce gun violence, taking more steps than any other Administration in its first year. And he repeated his call for Congress to take further action tackle the gun violence epidemic that continues to take more than 100 lives each day.</p>



<p>We have made strong progress by rolling out and executing on the President’s comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy. This strategy contains five key components:</p>



<ul><li>Stemming the flow of firearms used to commit violence,</li><li>Supporting local law enforcement with federal tools and resources to put more cops on the beat and address violent crime</li><li>Investing in evidence-based community violence interventions</li><li>Expanding summer programming, employment opportunities, and other services and supports for teenagers and young adults to give them pathways away from crime</li><li>Helping formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities instead of re-offending.</li></ul>



<p>You can read a full summary of the progress we’ve made <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-bidens-historic-actions-to-make-our-communities-safer-by-reducing-gun-crime/">here</a>. We are pulling all of the levers of the federal government to address this crisis. For example:</p>



<ul><li>The President secured a bipartisan investment in fighting gun crime, including a new $50 million initiative to expand community violence interventions, additional funding for community policing, and the resources the Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) needs to continue to enforce our existing gun laws.</li><li>The Administration made American Rescue Plan funds available for fighting gun crime, and cities and states across the country have taken up this opportunity.</li><li>The Justice Department is taking regulatory action to rein in the proliferation of “ghost guns”—unserialized, homemade firearms that are difficult for law enforcement to trace.</li><li>The Justice Department launched five new law enforcement strike forces focused on addressing firearms trafficking, including on the “Iron Pipeline” – the illegal flow of guns sold in the south, transported up the East Coast, and found at crime scenes from Baltimore to New York City.</li><li>In part due to action by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Connecticut and Illinois enacted legislation that allows Medicaid to reimburse providers for hospital-based gun violence prevention services.</li></ul>



<p>That progress is made possible by the dedicated gun violence prevention team we have at the White House, working to combat gun violence—every day, from every angle. Under the leadership of Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, I coordinate the White House’s gun violence work. The solutions to gun violence are interdisciplinary, which is why we have built a multi-faceted, 12-person team of experts here in the heart of the Domestic Policy Council who have teamed up to drive forward our gun violence reduction agenda.</p>



<p><strong>Chiraag Bains </strong>(Deputy Assistant to the President for Racial Justice and Equity), <strong>Vanessa Chen </strong>(Special Assistant to the President for Criminal Justice and Guns), and <strong>Stephonn Alcorn </strong>(Associate Director for Racial Justice and Equity) all bring their expertise in criminal justice reform and racial justice to help guide our work to expand community violence interventions. I work side by side with this team, along with <strong>Erin Murphy</strong> (Senior Policy Advisor for Criminal Justice), on broader issues related to public safety that often intersect with gun violence.</p>



<p>Vanessa leads our interagency policy council on school safety, working closely with <strong>Mo-Tracey Mooney</strong>, Special Assistant to the President for Education and the Domestic Policy Council’s expert on K-12 education.</p>



<p>We’re also fortunate to have <strong>Terri Tanielian</strong> (Special Assistant to the President for Veterans Affairs), who specializes in veteran issues, mental health, and suicide prevention, supporting our work on reducing access to lethal means through methods such as safe storage.</p>



<p>And, <strong>Pronita Gupta</strong> (Special Assistant to the President for Labor and Workers), ensures that job training and job opportunities for young adults and formerly incarcerated individuals are a core component of our comprehensive approach to reducing gun crime.</p>



<p><strong>Jessica Schubel</strong>, Director for the Affordable Care Act and Health Care, contributes her expertise in utilizing Medicaid and private insurance to support violence intervention programs.</p>



<p><strong>Priya Singh, </strong>Deputy Chief of Staff and Senior Policy Analyst, and<strong> Clarence Wardell</strong>, Senior Advisor for Delivery, specialize in bridging the gap between policy and people, including making sure that our investments in community violence intervention are having an impact on the ground.</p>



<p>Last but not least, <strong>Erin Pelton</strong>, Special Assistant to the President and Chief of Staff for the Domestic Policy Council, helps shape our legislative, public engagement, and intergovernmental affairs strategies.</p>



<p>All of us on the Domestic Policy Council work closely with our colleagues in the <strong>White House Counsel’s Office</strong>, the <strong>Office of Public Engagement</strong>, the <strong>Office of Legislative Affairs</strong>, and the <strong>Office of Intergovernmental Affairs</strong>. And each of us coordinates with our counterparts in key agencies across government, from the Department of Justice to the Department of Education to the Department of Veterans Affairs. Together, we convene multi-agency meetings to coordinate on a specific goal, hold one-on-one meetings to drive the work of a particular agency, and meet with gun violence survivors and experts, as well as state and local policymakers.</p>



<p>The strength of this integrated approach is that it enables us to see <em>across</em> issue areas, and avoid the silos that too often stymie progress. When the President’s top advisors were hammering out the details of his Build Back Better Agenda, our team ensured that it included a historic $5 billion across the Department of Justice and Department of Health and Human Services to invest in community violence intervention. When workforce training was on the agenda, we were able to work with the Department of Labor to prioritize employment for formerly incarcerated individuals to reduce recidivism. After Medicaid policy advisors at the White House and the Department of Health and Human Services briefed states on how Medicaid funds could be used to reimburse CVI programs, Connecticut and Illinois became the first two states to adopt this promising approach. Policymakers often talk about taking a “whole-of-government” approach to an issue. This is what a whole-of-government effort truly looks like in practice.</p>



<p>Driven by President Biden’s career-long commitment to combating gun violence, and guided every day by the President’s top advisor on domestic policy, our team is able to combine a deep focus on this issue with the ability to deliver on it across the White House and the Administration as a whole. That’s how we’ve been able to carry out a comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy that’s done more through executive action than any President in their first year in history, and how we’ve backed it up with historic amounts of funding for cities and states to make their communities safer. And that’s also how we’ve continued to amplify the voices of survivors and advocates and elevate them with the President’s bully pulpit – from the halls of Congress to the Rose Garden – the vital need for Congress to act on common sense gun violence prevention measures.</p>



<p>As the President acknowledged in his State of the Union remarks, there is much more to do, which is why this team wakes up every day eager to advance this essential work. The President will continue to implement his comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy. Just as he did in his State of the Union Address, he will continue to call on Congress to takes steps that cannot be achieved through executive action and do not violate the Second Amendment – like universal background checks, a ban on assault weapons with high-capacity magazines, and repeal of the liability shield for gun manufacturers and dealers. He will continue to increase investments in community policing and community violence interventions. And we will help him get the job done in order to save lives.</p>



<p><em>Stefanie Feldman is Deputy Assistant to the President and Senior Advisor to the Domestic Policy Advisor</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the FY 2023&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/28/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-fy-2023-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Budgets are statements of values, and the budget I am releasing today sends a clear message that we value fiscal responsibility, safety and security at home and around the world, and the investments needed to&#160;continue our equitable growth and&#160;build a better America. My&#160;Administration is on track to&#160;reduce the&#160;federal&#160;deficit by&#160;more than $1.3 trillion&#160;this year, cutting in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Budgets are statements of values, and the budget I am releasing today sends a clear message that we value fiscal responsibility, safety and security at home and around the world, and the investments needed to&nbsp;continue our equitable growth and&nbsp;build a better America.</p>



<p>My&nbsp;Administration is on track to&nbsp;reduce the&nbsp;federal&nbsp;deficit by&nbsp;more than $1.3 trillion&nbsp;this year, cutting in half the deficit from the last year of the previous&nbsp;Administration and delivering&nbsp;the largest&nbsp;one-year&nbsp;reduction in the deficit in U.S. history.&nbsp;That’s the direct result of&nbsp;my Administration’s&nbsp;<a></a>strategy to get the pandemic under control and grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out. We spent less money than the last Administration and got better results:&nbsp;strong economic growth, which&nbsp;has increased&nbsp;revenues and&nbsp;allowed&nbsp;us to responsibly scale back emergency spending.&nbsp;My budget will continue that progress, further reducing the deficit&nbsp;by continuing to support the economic growth that has increased&nbsp;revenues&nbsp;and&nbsp;ensuring that billionaires and&nbsp;large&nbsp;corporations pay their fair share.</p>



<p>At the same time, my budget will&nbsp;make investments in securing our nation and building a better America. We willsecure our communities by putting&nbsp;more police on the street&nbsp;to engage in&nbsp;accountable&nbsp;community policing,&nbsp;hiringthe agents&nbsp;needed&nbsp;to help fight gun crime, and investing in&nbsp;crime prevention and community violence intervention.</p>



<p>I’m calling for&nbsp;one of the largest investments in our national security in history, with the funds needed to ensure that our military remains the best-prepared, best-trained, best-equipped military in the world. &nbsp;In addition, I’m calling for continued investment&nbsp;to forcefully respond to Putin’s aggression against Ukraine&nbsp;with US support for Ukraine’s&nbsp;economic,&nbsp;humanitarian,&nbsp;and security&nbsp;needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My&nbsp;budget&nbsp;also&nbsp;makes&nbsp;the investments needed&nbsp;to&nbsp;reducecosts for families&nbsp;and make progress on my Unity Agenda – including investments to&nbsp;cut the costs of child care and health care; help families pay for other essentials;&nbsp;endcancer&nbsp;as we know it;&nbsp;support our veterans;&nbsp;and&nbsp;get all Americans the mental health services they need.</p>



<p>All told, it is a budget that&nbsp;includes&nbsp;historic deficit reduction, historic investments in our security at home and abroad, and an unprecedented commitment to building an economy where everyone has a chance to succeed.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
