<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 13:55:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake&#160;Sullivan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/12/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 13:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room   3:50 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good afternoon. MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Thank you.&#160; All right.&#160; Today we have Jake Sullivan, the President&#8217;s National Security Advisor.&#160; Jake is here to preview the President&#8217;s upcoming trip to the Middle East, where he will build on a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p> </p>



<p>3:50 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Today we have Jake Sullivan, the President&#8217;s National Security Advisor.&nbsp; Jake is here to preview the President&#8217;s upcoming trip to the Middle East, where he will build on a new and more promising chapter of America&#8217;s engagement in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m going to let Jake take it away.&nbsp; And also, he&#8217;ll take some questions afterwards.&nbsp; Jake, it&#8217;s all yours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; And thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to lay out a little bit of the context for this trip, make a couple of comments on tomorrow&#8217;s bilateral meeting with President López Obrador of Mexico, and then I&#8217;ll be happy to take your questions.&nbsp; But I appreciate you bearing with me as I try to lay out some of the elements of the President&#8217;s thinking as we head into this very important trip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, President Biden will depart on a trip to Israel, the West Bank, and Saudi Arabia, where he will attend a major Middle Eastern summit.&nbsp; This trip will reinforce a vital American role in a strategically consequential region.&nbsp; And also, it will reinforce that our role is different today than it was 20 years ago on the eve of the war in Iraq.</p>



<p>This trip comes after a series of engagements with Indo-Pacific leaders in May, with Latin American leaders at the Summit of the Americas in early June, and with European leaders at the G7 and NATO Summits in late June.&nbsp; It is his first trip to the Middle East as President.</p>



<p>It is precisely because the world is becoming more geopolitically competitive, especially in the Indo-Pacific and Europe, that we need to remain intensively engaged in the Middle East.&nbsp; The Middle East is deeply interwoven with the rest of the world.&nbsp; And if we can act now to create a more peaceful and stable region, it will pay dividends for the American national interests and for the American people for years to come.</p>



<p>President Biden’s fundamental objectives when it comes to the Middle East are straightforward: a region with more stability and fewer wars that could draw the United States in, a region that is less hospitable to terrorism that threatens Americans, a region that is helping address global energy security at a moment when Russia’s war against Ukraine is roiling global energy markets, a region where no foreign power can dominate or gain strategic advantage over the United States, a region that is making progress towards greater human rights and greater human dignity.</p>



<p>And despite ongoing challenges, the Middle East President Biden will be visiting is more stable than the one we inherited 18 months ago.</p>



<p>We inherited a war in Yemen that was causing widespread death and suffering.&nbsp; We now have had more than three months of a ceasefire in Yemen &#8212; the longest peace in seven years.</p>



<p>In Iraq, we kept up pressure on ISIS, significantly degrading their capabilities, including by taking out its emir, allowing us to end the U.S. combat mission and transition our military presence in Iraq to focus on training Iraqis.</p>



<p>We’ve reunited our partners to ensure that it’s Iran, not the United States, that is isolated until it returns to the nuclear deal.&nbsp; And the frequency of Iranian-sponsored attacks against our forces in Iraq and Syria has dropped dramatically.</p>



<p>We’ve reestablished diplomatic ties with the Palestinians that had basically severed under our predecessor. Working with Congress, we’ve restored approximately $500 million in support for Palestinians.&nbsp; And we’ve reaffirmed unequivocal U.S. support for a two-state solution, which had come into question over the previous four years.&nbsp; And under President Biden’s leadership, we helped end a war in Gaza, which easily could have lasted months, in just 11 days.</p>



<p>In Saudi Arabia, we’ve reversed the blank-check policy that we inherited from the previous administration, while continuing to work with Saudi Arabia on critical priorities for the American people.&nbsp; We released the intelligence community report on the murder of Jamal Khashoggi.&nbsp; We issued new sanctions, including on the Rapid Intervention Force that was implicated in that murder.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our diplomacy with Saudi Arabia is now delivering results, including a truce in Yemen, a more integrated GCC, progress on energy security, and security cooperation against threats from Iran. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Our partnership with Israel is strong across the board.&nbsp; We passed the largest support package in Israel with the help of Congress &#8212; over $4 billion &#8212; in American history.&nbsp; We’re working closely across every dimension of the relationship &#8212; from finance and food security, to cyber and emerging technology, to intelligence and security cooperation.&nbsp; And President Biden’s deep personal commitment to the U.S.-Israel relationship and to the relationship between Israelis and Americans will be on full display this week.</p>



<p>In sum, the region is less pressurized and more integrated, with countries increasingly setting aside both old and more recent disagreements to work on practical initiatives in energy, technology, infrastructure, and more.</p>



<p>We are clear-eyed that the region remains full of challenges and threats from Iran, from terrorist groups that still operate in a number of countries; challenges in the ongoing conflict in Syria; challenges to human rights and human freedom.&nbsp; This is why the President believes there is no substitute for the power of face-to-face diplomacy.</p>



<p>In meetings on this trip, President Biden will seek to sustain and strengthen the fragile but real ceasefire in Yemen; deepen Israel’s integration into the region; provide material support to the Palestinian people while protecting the vision of a two-state solution; coordinate on the multi-faceted threat posed by Iran; advance energy security and food security objectives for the U.S. and our allies in the face of Russia’s aggression in Ukraine, while promoting a clean energy transition over time; enlisting support for Middle Eastern partners for significant initiatives in technology and infrastructure; and publicly and privately advocating for universal values including progress on human rights and political reform.</p>



<p>In Israel, the President will meet with the Prime Minister, the President, the leader of the opposition, as well as attend a reception with a number of other key Israeli leaders and public figures.&nbsp; He will also have the opportunity to receive a briefing on Israel’s missile defense capabilities, including the U.S.-supported Iron Dome and a new laser-enabled system called Iron Beam.&nbsp; He will pay his respects at Yad Vashem.&nbsp; And he will hold a four-way virtual summit with the leaders of Israel, the UAE, and India, with a focus on food security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden will also meet with President Abbas and attend a health event with Palestinian civil society.</p>



<p>In Saudi Arabia, the President will meet with the Saudi leadership with an aim to strengthen our partnership and also hold bilateral meetings with a number of other Middle Eastern leaders, before closing the trip with the summit with the GCC+3.&nbsp; At that summit, he will make a major statement on the Biden administration’s strategy &#8212; his vision &#8212; for the Middle East region.</p>



<p>There will be other engagements in a crowded and fast-paced schedule, and we will share them with you in due course.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, before we even leave, tomorrow morning President Biden will meet with President López Obrador here at the White House &#8212; the second time the two leaders will meet here &#8212; to build on the significant progress made at the Summit of the Americas, where Mexico expressed support for the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity and joined 20 other countries in adopting the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection.</p>



<p>We expect the two leaders to discuss their common vision for North America and common efforts to address global challenges, including Russia’s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>So, thank you for your patience, and I would now be happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, has the President reached out to Jamal Khashoggi’s family ahead of his trip to Saudi?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have had contact with Jamal Khashoggi’s family.&nbsp; The President has not himself spoken with them, but he has been focused on this issue from the beginning.</p>



<p>And as he said when he took office and as we have stuck by since then, our goal has been to recalibrate but not rupture the relationship with Saudi Arabia, to end the blank-check policy, and to seek accountability.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we released the intelligence community&#8217;s report on the murder of Jamal Khashoggi, and it&#8217;s why we have issued 76 visa bans, in addition to sanctioning the Rapid Intervention Force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in your remarks, you mentioned human rights multiple times.&nbsp; You know, during the campaign, the President said Saudi should pay a price.&nbsp; He referred to them as making them a pariah state.&nbsp; When it comes right down to it, isn&#8217;t this trip proof that strategic interests, including oil and gas, when it comes right down to it, are always going to override something like human rights?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; America&#8217;s values &#8212; human rights &#8212; are a strategic interest of the United States.&nbsp; So is energy security, so is stopping terrorism, so is seeking peace in a place like Yemen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are trying to do multiple things all at once to advance along a number of different tracks.&nbsp; One of those tracks is, in fact, ending the blank-check policy.&nbsp; And as I said before, the basic thrust and purpose of our policy with respect to Saudi Arabia has been to recalibrate the relationship but not rupture it.&nbsp; We have stayed true to that from the beginning of this administration.</p>



<p>The President believes that he can deliver concrete results for the American people, for the interests of America&#8217;s national security.&nbsp; One of those is the horrific war in Yemen, where I&#8217;ve stood before you before and been asked questions &#8212; very tough, but fair questions &#8212; about what the United States was doing to bring peace to Yemen and what a high priority that was.</p>



<p>We are now heading into the fourth month of a fragile but real ceasefire, the longest peace since the war began more than seven years ago.&nbsp; That is a genuine result of both intensive diplomacy in the Middle East and intensive engagement by American leaders starting with President Biden.&nbsp; That is just one of multiple priorities that every American should be able to agree can help contribute to a more stable, more just, more prosperous region that&#8217;s fundamentally in our interests.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re going to the Middle East.</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; One, will the President be photographed shaking hands with the Crown Prince or meeting with him while in Saudi?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President will have the opportunity to have a bilateral program that will involve the King, the Crown Prince, other ministers of the Saudi government.&nbsp; And in terms of the precise modalities, I&#8217;ll leave that to the folks who are actually organizing the trip.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as you&#8217;ve been planning this trip, has the President expressed any regret for the language that he used to describe Saudi Arabia on the campaign trail?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President has not expressed regret about his statements.&nbsp; What the President has been focused on is his view that the United States has important interests to advance and protect, including in partnership with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; And, among other things, we have to work on increasing the prospect for peace in the region; for Israel&#8217;s integration into the region; for the war in Yemen, as I mentioned before; for energy and food security; and for many other things.</p>



<p>And he also has a long and consistent record &#8212; going back to his days as senator, including his years as Vice President, including his time as President &#8212; where human rights is going to remain a feature of his agenda and an important feature of his agenda.&nbsp; And it will be on display while we&#8217;re on this trip as well.</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; Now, the President said at NATO that he would be asking GCC countries about increasing oil production.&nbsp; But the Saudis and UAE have indicated that their capacity to increase production is limited.&nbsp; So what does the administration view as possible as far as an output increase from those countries on this trip if that comes up?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;ve already seen OPEC take a meaningful step with respect to the increase in oil production in the months of July and August.&nbsp; That was a positive step; we welcomed it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will have the opportunity, among this very broad agenda, to talk about energy security with the leaders of the OPEC nations in the Middle East, just as we discussed energy security when he was on his trips in Europe and in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And we will see what results come from that.&nbsp; Ultimately, that will be up to the OPEC countries to determine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I don&#8217;t have anything to say from this podium right now because those discussions are best, you know, confined behind closed doors.&nbsp; But we do believe there is a capacity for further steps that could be taken.&nbsp; And we will see how that unfolds as we go.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you’re not asking for a specific figure as far as &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;re not asking them for a specific figure as far as output?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; In terms of specific figures, all I will say is that we will convey our general view &#8212; as we have, as I have publicly from this podium &#8212; that we believe that there needs to be adequate supply in the global market to protect the global economy and to protect the American consumer at the pump.&nbsp; We’ll always advocate for that.&nbsp; We’ll advocate for that publicly. We’ll advocate for that privately.&nbsp; We’ll coordinate with leaders around the world, including in the Middle East, on that issue.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.&nbsp; Just to follow up on Jordan’s question, does the President believe right now that Saudi Arabia is pumping enough oil to bring gas prices down?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to get into a specific characterization on what constitutes “enough.”&nbsp; What I will say is the President believes that the price of gas is too high and that we need to do more with respect to global energy supplies.&nbsp; And he will take every step in his power, both here at home and in terms of his diplomatic engagement in the world, to try to bring that about.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just more broadly on the trip’s purpose, do you see any potential to ease or smooth the relationship between Israel and Saudi Arabia on this trip?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It is our hope and expectation that as we look out into the future, we can help facilitate Israel&#8217;s deeper integration into the region across the board.</p>



<p>Specifically with respect to Israel and Saudi Arabia, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of very intensive work that will be done in the course of this trip.&nbsp; Any normalization of any kind would be a long process.&nbsp; But looking for progress and momentum in that direction is certainly something we are focused on as we head off to the Middle East.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, you mentioned “until Iran returns to the nuclear deal.”&nbsp; Is there a deadline that Iran has been given here?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have not marked a date on the calendar.&nbsp; We have indicated that we believe there is a deal on the table.&nbsp; It is a deal that we&#8217;re backing, that our European partners are backing that is available to Iran, and Iran should step forward and take that deal.</p>



<p>If they don&#8217;t, we&#8217;re not standing still.&nbsp; Even as we speak, we&#8217;ve already introduced two rounds of sanctions to crack down on their effort to evade the existing sanctions regime.&nbsp; We are curbing their ability to smuggle oil, for example, through the Quds Force and other entities within Iran.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll keep doing that.</p>



<p>So as far as we&#8217;re concerned, Iran has a choice: It can either come back on a compliance-for-compliance basis to the JCPOA, or it will face increasing pressure from the United States and increasing isolation from the international community to include a resolution at the IAEA Board of Governors that garnered the support of more than 30 nations.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can you confirm any of the details about &#8212; you know, you spoke about Israel&#8217;s greater integration into the region.&nbsp; We certainly heard reports about the idea that there are &#8212; there are some sort of negotiations that would allow Israel commercial flights to fly over Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; Is that something that you could sort of confirm for us?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got nothing to confirm or preview here.&nbsp; What I will say is that this broad topic of Israel&#8217;s integration into the region, and steps that we can take in that direction, will be a feature of this trip.&nbsp; And I will leave the rest of it to the President as he embarks on his engagements both in Israel and in Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>I will point out that the fact that the President himself will be flying from Israel to Jeddah is itself a meaningful step and an unusual step.&nbsp; And it shows the kind of promise that greater integration could hold.</p>



<p>But in terms of the specific kinds of steps you&#8217;ve talked about, I would simply say: Nothing from the podium today.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s see how things develop over the course of this week.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You talk about the importance of personal diplomacy as part of the reason for going.&nbsp; There are risks for the President politically to go to Saudi Arabia, with an expectation among the public that maybe there will be a specific deliverable when it comes to gas prices and so forth, and supply.&nbsp; What is the burden on the President to come home with something in that category?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; it&#8217;s up to you to characterize things like “burdens on the President.”&nbsp; What I can say is what the President intends to do.&nbsp; He intends to use every tool in his toolbox to try to create adequate global energy supplies and to bring the price of gas down for American working families at the pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that will be measured over time: Can we get that price down and can we keep it down?&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s going to be measured on Friday or Saturday of this week; I think it will be measured over the weeks and months to come.&nbsp; And, there, we will sustain intensive engagement in our effort to ensure that, at the end of the day, we&#8217;re having a positive impact on the price of oil and thereby a positive impact on the price of gas.</p>



<p>And I think the President sees this as an important component of his engagement, not just in the Middle East, but in his previous summits as well, and as one component of a broader agenda that includes peace, security, technology, preventing a nuclear Iran, and so much else that I&#8217;ve described today.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, thanks for this.&nbsp; Is the administration considering lifting its ban on offensive weapon sales to Saudi Arabia dependent on progress that the country makes with its war &#8212; ending its war with Yemen?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So you may recall that when this administration came in, we imposed restrictions on the supply of offensive weapons as part of our effort to help bring about an end to the war in Yemen.&nbsp; And right now, there&#8217;s no &#8212; nothing on the table to lift that ban.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re focused on strengthening and sustaining what is a fragile but real ceasefire, not make any fundamental changes to our weapons policy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secondly, if I may, former Governor Bill Richardson is planning to travel to Russia for talks aimed at finding a deal that would free Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Is this something that the White House is aware of?&nbsp; Have you had talks with Richardson about the trip?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have had communication from the National Security Council to former Governor Richardson.&nbsp; I won&#8217;t comment on his travel or what he intends to do.&nbsp; What I will say is that President Biden is laser-focused on a government-to-government solution to this issue.</p>



<p>As he indicated to Brittney Griner in the letter that he wrote to her, we are working directly with the Russian government, through appropriate channels, to try to bring a speedy resolution not just to her case but to Paul Whelan&#8217;s case as well.&nbsp; And we will continue to work until those two unjustly detained Americans and all unjustly detained Americans and hostages are home safely.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; Does the President plan to directly bring up the murder of Jamal Khashoggi in his meeting with &#8212; that will include the conference?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So I’m not going to characterize the &#8212; what the President will say privately in those sessions.&nbsp; I’ll let the President do that &#8212; you know, have the opportunity to have his engagement on human rights-related issues and other issues.&nbsp; And then, of course, you’ll have the opportunity to ask him about that after the trip occurs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Ukraine losing the war now, Jake?&nbsp; Is Ukraine losing the war?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sorry, I’ll come back to you on that question.&nbsp; But I think just so that I’m keeping regular order and not letting people just shout, we’ll come &#8212; but before we end the briefing, I’ll come to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; As the President goes to the Middle East, simultaneously, U.S. senators are being briefed on the importance &#8212; national security-wise &#8212; of investing in semiconductor production in the U.S.&nbsp; If we don&#8217;t pass that, what does that say to Israel and Saudi Arabia and other allies?&nbsp; What are the risks that we’re inviting?&nbsp; And does it set the President&#8217;s agenda in the Middle East back?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The national security stakes for passing this Bipartisan Innovation Act &#8212; what&#8217;s called USICA in the Senate and COMPETES in the House &#8212; are very high.&nbsp; America&#8217;s technological edge, our innovation edge, our capacity to invest in the next generation of leading technologies, the next generation of leading weapons is bound up in our ability to ensure that we have a secure and reliant, resilient supply chain for semiconductors.&nbsp; And that means getting the kinds of incentives and structures in place to increase semiconductor manufacturing, including the most sophisticated chips here in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why there&#8217;s bipartisan support for this bill.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why Democrats and Republicans have both rallied around the notion that for us to compete effectively with China, for us to be able to get the Javelins to Ukraine that we need to get to them &#8212; there are more than 20 semiconductors in every single Javelin &#8212; we need this bill.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it has been disappointing to us that Leader McConnell has been playing politics with national security.&nbsp; There are both Republicans and Democrats who are willing to step up and pass this, and we believe it should happen fast.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should the House just pass the Senate bill and get it over with?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There is a conference ongoing, and there is a pathway, in our view, to a bill that a strong, bipartisan majority of both the House and the Senate can get behind, that can be signed into law by President Biden, and that he can begin to execute in a way that enhances America&#8217;s national security, not to mention our economic competitiveness at the same time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So Secretary of State Tony Blinken visit Tokyo.&nbsp; He said he wrote a letter from the President to the former Prime Minister Shinzo Abe.&nbsp; So can you talk about the letter?&nbsp; It’s a message from the President to the former Prime Minister Shinzo’s family.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, the letter that he wrote was a private message, so it wouldn&#8217;t be appropriate for me to read it out.&nbsp; I will say that President Biden put out a very heartfelt statement that expressed his sympathies to the people of Japan, his deep sympathies and his &#8212; his heartfelt emotional connection for the loss of a family member to former Prime Minister Abe’s family.&nbsp; And for him, that came from the heart.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he went over to the Japanese Embassy and signed the guestbook.&nbsp; And I went with him.&nbsp; And actually, he sat at that table and wrote a message for several minutes &#8212; a very long message to the Japanese people in that book, in addition to the private letter that he handed to the ambassador to be taken back to Tokyo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is something that the President cares about, as a statesman, as an American President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also something that he cares about deeply as a human being, on behalf of the Prime Minis- &#8212; the former Prime Minister&#8217;s family, but especially on behalf of all of the people of Japan in their time of mourning.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If possible, will the President go to Tokyo sometime soon?&nbsp; We don’t know if (inaudible) funeral yet but is it possible for the President to go to Tokyo sometime soon?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce about any travel to Tokyo in the near term.&nbsp; But, you know, if we do have anything to share in terms of the American delegation, if there is a state funeral, we&#8217;ll let you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just coming back to the question, James, that you asked earlier on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; on Ukraine: Russia has already substantially failed to achieve its strategic objectives in Ukraine.&nbsp; Its strategic objective was to take Kyiv, the capital; to end Ukraine as a country; to eliminate Ukrainian identity from the map; and to subsume Ukraine to within Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They have failed at that.&nbsp; Kyiv stands.&nbsp; Kharkiv stands.&nbsp; Odessa stands.&nbsp; The major cities of Ukraine across much of the country are in Ukrainian hands and are being ably and bravely defended by the Ukrainian military with the support of the United States and other NATO Allies as well as countries around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when you take a step back and look at the trajectory of this conflict: What Vladimir Putin set out to do, he has failed to do and he will continue to fail in his ability to achieve his ultimate objectives because of the bravery of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, it is certainly the case that Russia has been able to grind out, kilometer by kilometer, inch by inch, some territory in the east.&nbsp; And the Ukrainians have made Russia pay a dear price for that.&nbsp; And the sanctions have made Russia pay a dear price for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will continue to work with the Ukrainian military and Ukrainian government on a strategy that ultimately achieves their objectives, both on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.&nbsp; And as President Biden said when we were at the NATO summit just 10 days ago, “We will do that for as long as it takes.”</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you still assess &#8212; do you still assess, Jake, that President Putin is receiving a sanitized or otherwise inaccurate fact set from his own advisors about the state of what&#8217;s going on the ground in Ukraine?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update for you, standing here today, on our intelligence assessment on Vladimir Putin&#8217;s consumption of information, but we&#8217;ll try to get that to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jake.&nbsp; So, today, Brazil’s President Bolsonaro said that a deal with Russia is close to buy much cheaper oil from Moscow, and other countries from &#8212; the Greeks are doing the same.&nbsp; So does this undermine the Western sanctions &#8212; the White House efforts to impose costs on Russia?&nbsp; And what is the White House reaction to that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And another question.&nbsp; Last week, some Democrats in the House proposed an amendment to defense &#8212; to the defense budgets to cut security assistance to Brazil if the Brazilian Armed Forces interfere in the Brazilian election in October?&nbsp; Does the White House support such an amendment?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I have not actually seen that amendment, so I&#8217;d have to take a look at it before commenting on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With respect to the question about the purchase of oil, you will have seen at the G7 &#8212; the G7 leaders discussed imposing a price cap on Russian oil in order to have it be trans- &#8212; transferred on ships carrying Western insurance.&nbsp; A price cap, meaning that countries would have to agree to pay less for Russian oil than what the global market price is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; If it turns out that countries are imposing their own price cap and it is a substantial denial of revenue to Russia in terms of their ability to sell oil, that is not the failure of sanctions; that&#8217;s actually the success of economic pressure, because it is driving down revenues for Moscow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, from our perspective &#8212; I don&#8217;t know about the specifics of what President Bolsonaro said today, but our fundamental goal, with respect to approaching Russia&#8217;s sale of oil onto the global market is twofold: One, reduce Putin’s revenues.&nbsp; And, two, do so while imposing the minimum amount of harm on consumers on the pump.&nbsp; That&#8217;s our goal.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to keep trying to do.</p>



<p>Yes, go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; I wanted to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And will there be any repercussion to Brazil or other countries who are buying the oil, Jake?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; I wanted to follow up quickly.&nbsp; Moment ago, you said that the United States was going to be working with Ukraine to craft “a strategy that ultimately achieves their objective both on the battlefield and at the negotiation table.”&nbsp; You also noted that the major cities in Ukraine stand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as you and the President work with Ukrainian leaders to figure out what that strategy is for both battlefield and negotiation table, if Ukrainians decide that they want to claw back “kilometer by kilometer, inch by inch,” the land that has been taken by Russia, will the United States have their back?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, we are in near daily contact with Ukrainians on the question of how to both deal with defending against Russian advances and be able to reclaim some of the territory that has been taken from them on a timetable that they are kind of working through.&nbsp; Those conversations are happening in military-to-military channels, and they&#8217;re also happening at the political level so we all have a comprehensive understanding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to read out exactly what the details of those conversations are.&nbsp; I will only say that we believe that the fundamental purpose of our strategy is to put the Ukrainians in as strong a position as possible on the battlefield so that they are in as strong a position as possible at the negotiating table when diplomacy comes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as President Zelenskyy himself has said: Ultimately, this conflict will have to be pursued through diplomacy.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where the United States’ thrust and purpose &#8212; that&#8217;s where the nature of our policy stands and will go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any limiting principle for the United States, in terms of either time or money?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;ve imposed limiting principles in terms of exactly the types of systems we are prepared to provide and for reasons related to seeking to deal with a circumstance in which some American capabilities, in our view, represent a benefit-risk analysis that runs against their provision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But from the point of view of a limiting principle on time, the President was absolutely clear on that.&nbsp; He said, “As long as it takes.&nbsp; He meant, “As long as it takes.”&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where the United States is prepared to stand.&nbsp; And we believe that&#8217;s where the broad global coalition of countries supporting Ukraine is prepared to go as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; You mentioned, during the President&#8217;s trip to Israel, that one of the meetings he will be having is with the opposition leader.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about that meeting and why are they meeting and what does the President hope to accomplish?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So it’s standard protocol for an American president to meet with leaders across the Israeli political spectrum, and the reason is simple: It’s because the President &#8212; this President and previous presidents have wanted to display that the relationship between the United States and Israel transcends politics.&nbsp; It transcends parties.&nbsp; It doesn’t matter who’s in charge in Washington or who’s in charge in Israel.<br><br>What matters is that we have a foundational, ironclad commitment to the security of the State of Israel and that our two peoples are joined in a common vision for the future.</p>



<p>That’s what he’s going to want to put on display, and that is the message that he will convey through the totality of his meetings in Israel.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Last question, and then I’ll move out.&nbsp; So &#8212; go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned earlier that Russia had failed to achieve its objectives, in particular taking Kyiv.&nbsp; Do you &#8212; are you confident then that, even if this war extends months, years in the future, that Russia will not be able to take Kyiv?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we do have confidence that the bravery of the Ukrainians and the support of the West to Ukraine will enable Ukraine to effectively defend and sustain its capital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would also point out, when I talked about the severe costs that Russia has had to endure on the battlefield as it tries to grind out territory in the east, this is coming at a cost to the sustainment of its own weapons.<br><br>And I&#8217;ll just give you one example before I leave, which is an example that I think is pretty newsworthy and noteworthy, and that is that our information indicates that the Iranian government is preparing to provide Russia with up to several hundred UAVs, including weapons-capable UAVs, on an expedi- &#8212; expedited timeline.<br><br>Our information further indicates that Iran is preparing to train Russian forces to use these UAVs with initial training sessions slated to begin as soon as early July.<br><br>It&#8217;s unclear whether Iran has delivered any of these UAVs to Russia already.&nbsp; But this is just one example of how Russia is looking to countries like Iran for capabilities that are also being used, I might add, or have been used before we got the ceasefire in place in Yemen, to attack Saudi Arabia.<br><br>So, from our perspective, we will continue to do our part to help sustain the effective defense of Ukraine and to help the Ukrainians show that the Russian effort to try to wipe Ukraine off the map cannot succeed.<br><br>And I&#8217;ll leave you guys. &nbsp;Thanks, guys.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I have a few things at the top.<br><br>So, on Wednesday, we will have new CPI inflation data, and we expect the headline number, which includes gas and food, to be highly elevated, mainly because gas prices were so elevated in June.</p>



<p>Gas and food prices continue to be heavily impacted by the war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And there are a few important points to keep in mind when we get this backwards-looking data:</p>



<p>First, June CPI data is already out of date because energy prices have come down substantially this month and are expected to fall further.<br><br>The average retail price of gas was 11 percent higher in June than it was in May.&nbsp; And the cost of gas in July is already down 7 percent from the June peak.</p>



<p>I have a chart here for you guys to &#8212; to see.&nbsp; The crude oil is the yellow.&nbsp; I’m sorry, the crude oil is the blue at the bottom, and the retail gasoline price is at the top.&nbsp; And you can see the difference there.</p>



<p>I would also note that even though gas prices shot up quickly when oil prices rose, they have not come down as quickly as oil has.<br><br>We continue to call on oil and gas companies to pass on their lower cost to consumers.&nbsp; American families should not be the first to pay and the last to benefit.</p>



<p>The President’s number one economic priority is tackling inflation.&nbsp; And looking ahead, there are a number of reasons why we expect those high prices to ease over the coming months.</p>



<p>Saturday marked the one-year anniversary of President Biden’s Executive Order to Promote Competition Across the American Economy.</p>



<p>This EO prompted a government-wide effort to help lower prices, raise wages, and encourage innovation.&nbsp; And one year in, we’re extraordinarily proud of the progress we’ve made.</p>



<p><a>Just a few example on this is: The Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission have already scored big wins for Americans.&nbsp; They have <s>locked</s> [blocked] megamergers in the insurance and sugar industries, and stopped a defense contractor megamerger that would’ve cost taxpayers billions of dollars.</a></p>



<p>In just a few months, Americans with hearing loss will be able to buy hearing aids over the counter at a &#8212; at a drug store, instead of requiring a prescription, which could save them thousands of dollars.<br><br>And the Department of Agriculture is cracking down on the meat-processing industry and supporting new competitors so farmer &#8212; farmer and ranchers get a fair price.</p>



<p>Our administration will continue driving structural change to produce lower prices, higher wages, and to make our economy dynamic and competitive.</p>



<p><a>Following a &#8212; following a briefing from NASA, the President and the Vice President will unveil the first [full]-color images NASA’s James Webb Space Telescope &#8212; the largest space telescope ever built.&nbsp; This is very cool.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>The high-resolution images will show light captured from galaxies that are more than 13 billion years old, formed shortly after the Big Bang.</p>



<p>Thanks to the incredible NASA team, this work will help scientists answer some of the biggest open questions about how and why stars form and the habitability of other worlds as well.</p>



<p>And that is it.&nbsp; Josh, do you want to kick us &#8212; kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two subjects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, how seriously is President Biden weighing a public health emergency regarding abortion access?&nbsp; And does he have any concerns about what kind of impact that emergency could have on access?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp;So, Jen Klein spoke about this when she was &#8212; when she joined the briefing room on Friday.&nbsp; And she is &#8212; for those who don&#8217;t know, she is &#8212; she chairs the Gender Policy Council, and she has been leading the effort along with other &#8212; other White House offices in &#8212; within the White House on our response to Dobbs decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also &#8212; we have to also remember that we started working on this prior to that, prior even when the decision leaked, which is when S.B. 8 in Texas was passed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is something that this administration has been very laser-focused on.&nbsp; But the team has been evaluating every option.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When we looked at declaring a public health emergency, we learned a couple of things &#8212; and she spoke to this as well; I&#8217;m just repeating what she said when she was in the briefing room, which is &#8212; one is: It &#8212; that it doesn&#8217;t free very many resources.&nbsp; There&#8217;s very little money left &#8212; about tens of thousands of dollars that are left because we have used it for other &#8212; for other reasons, in particular the COVID &#8212; our COVID-19 response, the monkeypox, which is an issue that we&#8217;re dealing with right now that we have been very aggressive on dealing with.&nbsp; And also, it also doesn&#8217;t release a significant amount of legal authority.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s why we haven&#8217;t taken that action yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as she has said and as the President has said, that everything is on the table; it doesn&#8217;t mean that it&#8217;s off the table.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to try and figure out every meaningful action to move forward.</p>



<p>So, we haven&#8217;t taken it off the table, but there are components of this potential decision that has kind of given us pause and made us think a little bit deeper about doing that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And secondly, what&#8217;s your message to gun control groups who say that today&#8217;s event here at the White House was premature, given the additional efforts that they say are necessary?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So one of the things that I’ll say about that is: So the President clearly welcomed the bipartisan bill on gun &#8212; gun reform, and he was proud to sign it.&nbsp; We had more than 2,000 people out on the South Lawn, many from different parts of the community; many families who have suffered from gun &#8212; gun violence personally, lost some loved ones; and folks who have been fighting for gun reform for a very long time; and also legislators and congressional members.</p>



<p>And so while he welcomed &#8212; while he has been proud to sign the bill, he understand that more can be done.&nbsp; He spoke about that in his speech today &#8212; in his remarks, specifically &#8212; talking about banning the assault weapon &#8212; something that he led back in 1994, which sunset 10 years later; this is something that he is still going to continue to fight for &#8212; high-capacity magazines.&nbsp; But we do believe and the President does believe that the bipartisan legislation that he signed today on gun reform will start to save lives.&nbsp; And when you think about the red-flag laws, when you think about how that &#8212; when it is enacted, it has been effective.&nbsp; When you think &#8212; look at Democratic states and red states, it has been effective.&nbsp; When you think about this so-called boy &#8212; “the boyfriend loophole,” those things will help to save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do we need to do more?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to continue to do everything that he can, understa- &#8212; and remembering that this is the President that has done more using executive action to deal with gun violence than any other President at this time in their administration.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One question &#8212; or two questions, but one question on the trip: Does the President plan to hold a press conference after his meetings with the Saudis?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right now, I believe &#8212; and we&#8217;ll have more to share &#8212; he has that one press conference in Israel.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything else to share on &#8212; on what else we’ll &#8212; on what are the activities of the press conference &#8212; other activity &#8212; other press conferences he may have.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We would definitely appreciate one if you &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Understood.&nbsp; Understood.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; scheduled one to ask him about the visit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Understood.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What was the President&#8217;s response to a new poll from the New York Times today showing that 64 percent of Democrats say that they would prefer a different candidate in 2024?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And I would also say from that very same poll, there were 92 percent of Democrats who support this President as well.&nbsp; Look, you know, not to be &#8212; not to get into, you know, politics from here or get into any political analysis: This is not something &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s going to be many polls.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to go up or they&#8217;re going to go down.&nbsp; This is not the thing that we are solely focused on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are focused on things like today&#8217;s signing &#8212; this bipartisan gun reform legislation, which will again save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do we have more work to do?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to &#8212; I was talking about inflation and how important &#8212; that is a priority for this President &#8212; and how we have seen gas prices go down by close to 30 cents a gallon in the past 25-plus days.&nbsp; That is something that the President is going to continue to work on because we still need to give Americans relief.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We saw &#8212; we have seen an economy that has bounced back from when he walked in to this administration over a year ago after dealing &#8212; or still dealing, really &#8212; in reality &#8212; with a once-in-a-generation pandemic and how he &#8212; we&#8217;ve been able to bring back jobs that we lost pre-pandemic, and also just continue to do that work.</p>



<p>And how we&#8217;ve seen unemployment at 3.6 percent.&nbsp; The jobs number that we saw last week at 375,000 jobs created in the last month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of these things are the &#8212; is what the President is going to continue to focus on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How do we deliver?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Somebody was asking Jake about USICA, also BIA and all the work that we&#8217;re putting behind that, because that is a top priority for this administration, because we need to continue to compete with countries like China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there is so much work to be done that we are &#8212; the President is going to focus on and deliver as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the event today included an interruption &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; by the father of a high school student who was killed in Parkland.&nbsp; The President first told him to sit down and listen, and then encouraged him to continue speaking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering what your reaction is and what his feeling was about that incident today?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, you know, our hearts go out to Man- &#8212; Manuel Oliver, who has suffered a deep, deep loss.&nbsp; The President met with him earlier today before the event.&nbsp; And as you know, the President understands what loss feels like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, the President agrees with him.&nbsp; He agrees that we need to do more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why, in his speech, he called on Congress to pass legislation that would ban assault weapons, as I just mentioned, and high-capacity magazines; strengthen background checks; and enact safe storage laws.&nbsp; This is something that is important &#8212; that has been important throughout the President’s career as Vice President, as senator.</p>



<p>The President has had the opportunity, as I just mentioned, to speak with Mr. Oliver in the past, and he knows and understands that he is frustrated and that he&#8217;s hurting, and rightfully so.&nbsp; His life was up &#8212; upended when gun violence took his son.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;ll continue to engage with Mr. Oliver, as &#8212; as Ambassador Rice has.&nbsp; When Cedric Richmond was here, he had met &#8212; they had met with him as well.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re just going to continue to do the work and to have &#8212; have engagement with Mr. Oliver.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to be clear: You said they met today before Mr. Oliver interrupted him.&nbsp; Can you tell us what they spoke about this morning?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I was not part of that meeting so I can&#8217;t speak to what they spoke &#8212; spoke on.&nbsp; But as I said, the President understands what loss feels like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, our hearts go out to Mr. Oliver, and I would never want to imagine what that feels like or want to go through what he&#8217;s going through &#8212; that grieving process.</p>



<p>And, again, we agree with him; we need to do more.&nbsp; The President stated that in his speech today.&nbsp; He has mentioned that almost every time that he has spoken about gun reform and what needs to be done, what else needs to be done to really make a change.</p>



<p>This is a &#8212; you know, this is a public health emergency that we&#8217;re dealing with when we talk about gun violence.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to continue to do the work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks for the question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gosh, I&#8217;m going to go here.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll come around.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on Kaitlan’s question earlier.&nbsp; You’d mentioned some of the accomplishments of the administration, but that same poll that came out said that 63 percent of Democrats believe the country is headed in the wrong direction.&nbsp; How &#8212; how do you explain that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we understand what the American people are feeling.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp; We understand that inflation is hurting families when they are around the kitchen table, when they&#8217;re trying to figure out, you know, how they&#8217;re going to deal with gas prices at the pump, how they&#8217;re going to deal with food prices as well.&nbsp; So, we understand that families are hurting right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is why the President has been laser-focused on &#8212; on making sure that we truly deal with inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, we&#8217;ve seen the gas prices go down.&nbsp; We believe that that is going to continue &#8212; that&#8217;s going to be a trend that we will continue to see.&nbsp; The President has been working on this for months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have to understand how we also got here.&nbsp; We got here with the &#8212; with the increase of gas prices and food prices because of Mr. Putin&#8217;s war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And what we &#8212; and how &#8212; in particular with food and gas, and how his unprecedented brutal war on Ukraine has cost &#8212; has caused prices to go up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, look, the President&#8217;s going to be focused.&nbsp; We have a strong economy.&nbsp; We are going to &#8212; you know, as we&#8217;re talking about inflation, our plan right now is to do that transition from that &#8212; the growth that we&#8217;ve seen in the economy to a more stable and steady growth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve seen that in the numbers last week, with the jobs numbers.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to focus on that, give the Federal Reserve its opportunity, its space to deal with inflation.&nbsp; They have the best monetary policy to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, again, this is what the President is going to be focused on.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to pay attention to polls.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not what we&#8217;re going to do here.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re going to focus on is delivering for the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, is the President monitoring the wildfires in Yosemite?&nbsp; Is there any commitment from the administration on that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I would have to get back to the team and lay out exactly what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; We are in close contact, for sure, with local government, with governors in the state.&nbsp; This is something that we do monitor and have &#8212; have in the past worked hand-in-hand with local officials on that &#8212; on the specifics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, is it &#8212; oh, my gosh.&nbsp; Is it time?&nbsp; Okay, let me take one more question.&nbsp; One more question.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Does the White House think abortion rights advocates are out of touch with the party, given the quote that Kate Bedingfield gave to the Washington Post this weekend?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I &#8212; let me just say &#8212; let me just say this: What happened almost two weeks ago now was an unprecedented attack &#8212; right? &#8212; on women&#8217;s right.&nbsp; It was an unprecedented attack on our freedoms.&nbsp; And the President has worked for not just &#8212; as I mentioned, not just since the leaked documents, but since we &#8212; since we have seen the S.B. 8 in Texas, to make sure that this administration, his administration, is doing everything that they can to deliver for &#8212; on this issue of making sure that we protect women&#8217;s rights.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what Kate was saying.&nbsp; She was trying to make sure that we laid out and spoke &#8212; continue to speak about what the President &#8212; the bold step that the President took.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we were responding to criticism in that particular article.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we were responding to.&nbsp; And we were responding to some activists and what they were saying in that article.&nbsp; And so, we were trying to be very specific in that as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But to say that the President has not been passionate, to say that this President has not been focused is just not true.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And even when Jen Klein was here after the President signed the executive order, she talked about NARAL.&nbsp; She talked about Planned Parenthood and how they welcome the steps that we took and what we are delivering on.</p>



<p>Now, is there going to be more work and more work to do?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And lastly, I will say &#8212; and then we have to go because you all have to gather &#8212; is that the President has always been honest about what needs to be done and what he believes needs to be done.&nbsp; Yes, we’re going to continue to do the work in the administration.&nbsp; But really, Americans have to take it to the ballot.&nbsp; They have to make sure their voices are heard.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he also said, “Keep protesting, protesting peacefully,” but also make sure that you take action and ask Congress to take action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s what we were speaking to.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the comments were all about.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to work on &#8212; on behalf of the American public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, everybody.</p>



<p>4:39 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Administration Outlines Strategy to Manage&#160;BA.5</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/fact-sheet-biden-administration-outlines-strategy-to-manage-ba-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House COVID-19 Team is announcing its strategy to manage BA.5. The strategy relies on ensuring that Americans continue to have easy and convenient access to the vaccines, treatments, tests, and other tools that protect against and treat COVID-19. These tools – even in the face of BA.5 – work to prevent serious&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House COVID-19 Team is announcing its strategy to manage BA.5. The strategy relies on ensuring that Americans continue to have easy and convenient access to the vaccines, treatments, tests, and other tools that protect against and treat COVID-19. These tools – even in the face of BA.5 – work to prevent serious illness, keep people out of the hospital, and save lives – and we can prevent nearly all COVID-19 deaths with them.</p>



<p>BA.4 and BA.5 – subvariants of the Omicron variant – now make up 80 percent of COVID-19 cases in the U.S., with BA.5 accounting for a majority of cases. Early indications signal that BA.5 may have some increased ability to escape immunity, including from prior infections, meaning it has the potential to cause the numbers of infections to rise in the coming weeks. This potential for increase is greatest where fewer people are up to date on their vaccinations and there is increased waning of immunity from vaccines.</p>



<p>In January 2021, the American people had limited tools to protect themselves against COVID-19. Today, that is no longer the case. Thanks to the infrastructure that the President’s comprehensive COVID-19 response has built and the tools that the Administration has worked to make widely available over the past 18 months, the U.S. is prepared to combat the challenge of BA.5. More than 222 million Americans are fully vaccinated, over 106 million people have at least their first booster shot, and virtually every American of every age is eligible for vaccination. And, we have more courses of lifesaving treatments available and being used than ever before, as well as widely available at-home tests and high-quality masks.</p>



<p>The President’s comprehensive COVID-19 response has produced tremendous results for the American people: COVID-19 is no longer the disruptive force it once was, and most COVID-19 deaths are now preventable because of the vaccines, treatments, and other tools the Biden Administration has made available to the American people. Daily COVID-19 deaths are down by 90 percent since the President took office. America’s schools are open. More Americans are working in the private sector than before the pandemic started. And, the vast majority of Americans are comfortable visiting with loved ones, eating out, traveling and doing other things that they did before COVID-19.</p>



<p>In March, the President released his National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan – a roadmap to continue our fight against the virus and to continue minimizing its impact on our lives. Since emerging from the Omicron surge this past winter, we have worked to make sure that the tools we have remain widely available and easily accessible to Americans.</p>



<p>To confront BA.5, the Administration will continue mobilizing the full strength and capabilities of the federal government and working with state and local leaders, health care workers, the private sector, and community- and faith-based organizations to ensure that the American people have easy and convenient access to and use vaccines, tests, and treatments.</p>



<p><strong>The Administration’s strategy to manage BA.5 includes:</strong></p>



<p><strong>Making it easy for people to get vaccines and boosters:</strong> The Administration will continue working with state and local leaders, doctors and pediatricians, pharmacies, community health centers, long-term care facilities, employers, and community- and faith-based organizations to drive additional uptake of booster shots, particularly among those age 50 and older and other at-risk populations, including long-term care facility staff and residents. Given the rise of BA.5, it is essential that Americans stay up to date on their COVID-19 vaccinations. The science is clear that COVID-19 vaccines remain our single-most important tool to protect people and prevent serious illness, hospitalizations, and deaths, and staying up to date on booster shots ensures that people have the highest level of protection possible. Based on the latest CDC data, adults who are up to date with their vaccinations are 3.5 times less likely to be hospitalized than unvaccinated adults; among those who are 50 and older, people who have received two booster shots are 42 times less likely to die from COVID-19 compared to those who are unvaccinated. Vaccines are free and easy to access at 90,000 convenient locations nationwide. And, the guidance is clear that every American age 5 and over should receive a booster five months after their primary series,  and individuals age 50 and older or those who are moderately or severely immunocompromised should receive a second booster shot at least four months after their first.</p>



<p><strong>Making it easy to access COVID-19 treatments and boost provider and patient awareness:</strong> The Administration will continue working across the federal government, with state and local leaders, health care providers, as well as the public and private sectors, to take additional actions to boost access and awareness of lifesaving treatments, particularly in areas where BA.5 is spreading. Today, the U.S. has three treatments that are effective against BA.5, including Paxlovid, a lifesaving antiviral pill that has been shown to reduce the risk of hospitalization or death by about 90 percent. Americans who test positive for COVID-19 should consult their health care provider about their eligibility for these treatments, or visit COVID.gov to find a Test to Treat location where they can get tested and treatments all in one place. The Administration has purchased 20 million treatment courses of Paxlovid – more than any other country in the world – and moved quickly to make these treatments widely available and to educate health care providers and patients about their availability and efficacy. Oral antivirals are now available at over 41,000 convenient locations nationwide, and nearly 90 percent of Americans live within 5 miles of a place where they can pick up a prescription. As a result of the Administration’s actions, the number of people benefiting from oral antivirals has dramatically increased over the course of this year, from about 18,000 prescriptions filled each week in January to more than 230,000 last week – a more than 12-fold increase. Each day, about one-third of confirmed and reported cases are receiving free and effective oral antiviral treatments.</p>



<p><strong>Making free COVID-19 testing, including at-home tests, widely available:</strong> Testing continues to be an important tool to help mitigate the spread of COVID-19, including BA.4 and BA.5. In the face of BA.5, the Administration is encouraging Americans to use at-home tests before attending large, indoor gatherings, traveling, or visiting indoors with immunocompromised individuals. COVID-19 testing is now more widely available and accessible to the American people than ever before, and there are now 17 over-the-counter, at-home, rapid tests authorized for the U.S. market – up from zero when the President took office. To help ensure that Americans have tests on hand if a need arises, the Administration opened COVIDtests.gov for a third round of ordering ahead of the summer, meaning that 16 free tests have been made available to each household since the launch of the program. To ensure equitable access for visually-impaired individuals, the Administration has also made available more accessible at-home tests to households with visually-impaired individuals. To date, the Administration has delivered approximately 530 million at-home tests directly to over 75 million American households for free through COVIDtests.gov. Additionally, private health insurers, Medicare, and all Medicaid programs are required to cover at-home COVID-19 tests for free; health insurance plans now cover eight free tests per month per individual which can be easily accessed at local pharmacies and online. And, there are over 15,000 federally-supported free testing sites across the nation. This free testing program has increased&nbsp; equitable access to testing, and 50 percent of individuals currently served by the pharmacy free testing program are racial and ethnic minorities or live in high social vulnerability communities.</p>



<p><strong>Making free high-quality masks widely available and communicate clear recommendations about when people should consider masking:</strong> Experts agree that masking in indoor, public spaces is an important tool to control the spread of COVID-19. The CDC’s COVID-19 Community Levels provide individuals with clear recommendations on when to consider masking in indoor, public spaces. As BA.5 drives an increase in cases, the Administration continues to encourage Americans to visit COVID.gov to find the level of COVID-19 in their community and follow CDC’s recommendations on wearing masks in public, indoor settings. Since January 2021, the Biden Administration has taken significant action, including using the Defense Production Act, to ensure that the U.S. has ample supply of high-quality masks for health care workers and that high-quality masks are also widely available to the American public online and in stores. To further increase access, over the past seven months, the Administration has made 400 million non-surgical N95 masks from the Strategic National Stockpile available to the American people for free at tens of thousands of convenient locations nationwide – the largest deployment of personal protective equipment in U.S. history. And, the Administration will continue to make masks available for health care and other essential workers through states, building on the over 75 million masks and respirators we have already distributed to states, Tribes, and territories across the country.</p>



<p><strong>Prioritizing protections for immunocompromised individuals: </strong>As BA.5 cases rise, the Administration will continue to provide support to individuals who are immunocompromised so that they have the support they need to live their lives safely. The Administration has initiated a communications campaign to ensure that immunocompromised individuals and their close contacts are up to date with COVID-19 vaccination and boosters. The availability of vaccines for kids as young as six months old also ensures that all close contacts of immunocompromised individuals can be protected by COVID-19 vaccines. The Administration also continues to make effective pre-exposure prophylactics such as Evusheld more widely available through enhanced distribution to clinicians’ offices and clinics. And, in the coming weeks, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will launch an easy-to-remember hotline to help individuals access this effective tool to prevent COVID-19.</p>



<p><strong>Encouraging all building owners to improve indoor ventilation: </strong>Improving ventilation can help prevent the spread of BA.4 and BA.5 indoors in buildings. The Administration has provided state and local leaders hundreds of billions of dollars in federal funds that can be used in schools, public buildings, and other settings to improve indoor air quality, and the Administration will continue to advance indoor air quality in buildings, including by increasing public awareness around ventilation and filtration improvements to reduce disease spread, as well as by recognizing buildings and organizations that have taken steps to improve indoor air quality. These efforts will expand on the Administration’s “best practices” guide for improving indoor air quality and reducing the risk of spreading dangerous airborne particles and the Clean Air in Buildings Challenge, which calls on all building owners and operators, schools, colleges and universities, and organizations of all kinds to adopt key strategies to improve indoor air quality in their buildings and reduce the spread of COVID-19. Additionally, CDC has released interactive tools to help individuals at home, in schools, and in other buildings to understand how air flows in their space and what they can do to help shore up air quality and improve ventilation indoors.</p>



<p><strong>Empowering people with the latest information on COVID-19 and where to access vaccines, treatments, tests, and masks at COVID.Gov:</strong> The Administration will continue to communicate clearly with the American people about COVID-19 and the steps that they can take to protect themselves and their loved ones. Earlier this year, the Biden Administration launched COVID.gov, a new one-stop shop website to help Americans find where to access lifesaving tools like vaccines, tests, treatments, and masks. People can also type in their county to find the latest updates on the level of COVID-19 in their community and related guidance. And, with a click of a button, people can access resources related to testing, ventilation, and other important COVID-19 topics. COVID.gov is available in English, Spanish, and Simplified Chinese and is accessible for those using assistive technologies. The Administration is also making all of these COVID-19 tools available over the phone through the National Hotline at 1-800-232-0233 (TTY 1-888-720-7489), which supports over 150 languages. For individuals with disabilities who may need additional support, the Disability Information and Access Line (DIAL) is also available to help at 1-888-677-1199 or via email at DIAL@usaginganddisability.org.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Vice President Harris Announces Commitments to Strengthen U.S. Partnership with the Pacific&#160;Islands</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-commitments-to-strengthen-u-s-partnership-with-the-pacific-islands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 12, Vice President Harris will participate virtually in the Pacific Islands Forum leaders’ meeting at the invitation of the Forum Chair Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama of Fiji. As part of this engagement with Forum leaders, the Vice President will announce new commitments to deepen U.S. partnership with the region and to deliver concrete&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 12, Vice President Harris will participate virtually in the Pacific Islands Forum leaders’ meeting at the invitation of the Forum Chair Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama of Fiji. As part of this engagement with Forum leaders, the Vice President will announce new commitments to deepen U.S. partnership with the region and to deliver concrete results for Pacific people. These actions advance the Biden-Harris Administration’s ongoing efforts to strengthen the U.S.-Pacific Islands partnership and to support Pacific regionalism, with a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum at the center.<br>&nbsp;<br>This milestone reflects the United States’ robust and growing commitment to the Pacific Islands region. It follows President Biden’s appointment of a Special Presidential Envoy for Compact Negotiations and the launch of the Partners in the Blue Pacific, a new coordination initiative among the United States, Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the United Kingdom to support Pacific priorities more effectively. It also builds on five decades of close cooperation with the Pacific Islands Forum, including as a founding Dialogue Partner; $350 million in annual U.S. assistance to the Pacific; and deep people-to-people ties, including among the 1.4 million Pacific Islanders who live across the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>With this foundation, the Vice President is announcing the following actions. The Biden-Harris Administration will:<br>&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Establish New U.S. Embassies in Kiribati and Tonga:</strong> The Biden-Harris Administration recognizes that our close partnership with the Pacific requires regular exchange between our governments at all levels, from our leaders to our diplomats around the world. To that end, the United States, subject to congressional notification, will commence discussions with Kiribati and Tonga about our interest in establishing U.S. embassies in those countries. The United States is on track to reopen its embassy in Solomon Islands.</li><li><strong>Triple Request for U.S. Funding for Economic Development and Ocean Resilience: </strong>For 33 years, the South Pacific Tuna Treaty has served as a cornerstone of political and economic cooperation between the United States and Pacific Islands, enabling U.S. fishing-fleet access to the Pacific, supporting livelihoods across the region, and providing a platform for broader cooperation, including to combat the scourge of illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing. Vice President Harris will announce that the United States is prepared to request from the U.S. Congress $60 million per year for the next ten years—nearly triple the current levels and $600 million in total—in connection with a new Economic Assistance Agreement with the Forum Fisheries Agency.</li><li><strong>Appoint the First-Ever U.S. Envoy to the Pacific Islands Forum:</strong> A resilient and prosperous Pacific Islands region requires a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum—the preeminent driver of action in the region. The Biden-Harris Administration will redouble our commitment to the Pacific Islands Forum by appointing, for the first time, a designated U.S. Pacific Islands Forum Envoy. In doing so, the United States will further increase our overall diplomatic footprint across the Pacific Islands.</li><li><strong>Design and Release the First-Ever U.S. National Strategy on the Pacific Islands</strong>: The Biden-Harris Administration will craft and publish the first-ever U.S. strategy on the Pacific Islands—a whole-of-government strategy to prioritize the Pacific Islands in American foreign policy and drive effective implementation. It will be nested under the Indo-Pacific Strategy of the United States, which the Biden-Harris Administration released earlier this year in Fiji. The U.S. National Strategy on the Pacific Islands will align with the goals, areas of focus, and principles of the Pacific Islands Forum’s 2050 Strategy for the Blue Pacific Continent.</li><li><strong>Bring the Peace Corps Back to the Pacific: </strong>The longevity of our ties with the Pacific Islands depends on close people-to-people relationships. Peace Corps volunteers will soon return to Fiji, Tonga, Samoa, and Vanuatu, and the Peace Corps will work with the region to explore program expansion to additional Pacific Island countries.</li><li><strong>Progress Toward&nbsp;Re-establishing&nbsp;a United States Agency for International Development&nbsp;(USAID) Regional&nbsp;Mission&nbsp;for the Pacific in Suva, Fiji:&nbsp;</strong>USAID provides life-saving&nbsp;humanitarian and development assistance&nbsp;across the Pacific Islands, from Kiribati in the wake of drought to Tonga in the wake of volcanic eruptions and tsunami waves&nbsp;to economic assistance in Papua New Guinea and Solomon Islands. The Vice President will announce that USAID&nbsp;is taking steps to&nbsp;expand&nbsp;its&nbsp;presence in the&nbsp;Pacific, subject to congressional notification,&nbsp;to&nbsp;improve&nbsp;close cooperation with its host country partners.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Implement and Advance the Partners in the Blue Pacific</strong>: Emerging challenges, from the climate crisis to infrastructure needs, require cooperation across borders. To that end, the United States and its allies and partners—Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the United Kingdom—established a new coordination mechanism, the Partners in the Blue Pacific (PBP). The PBP is dedicated to supporting Pacific priorities more effectively and efficiently, to bolstering Pacific regionalism, and to expanding opportunities between the Pacific and the world. Our countries provide a combined $2.1 billion in development assistance for the region, and we will seek to drive additional focus and resources by welcoming further members and observers, including in Europe and the Indo-Pacific. Above all, at every stage, the PBP will be led and guided by the Pacific Islands, including close consultations on its flagship projects. </li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Cyber Director Chris Inglis’s Travel to Israel and&#160;Europe</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/readout-of-national-cyber-director-chris-ingliss-travel-to-israel-and-europe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From June 26 to July 5, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis traveled to Israel, the Netherlands, and the United Kingdom to meet with government officials, private sector executives, and academic thought leaders to discuss efforts to promote the security of our common digital ecosystem and the integrity of our hardware and software supply chains. Director&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>From June 26 to July 5, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis traveled to Israel, the Netherlands, and the United Kingdom to meet with government officials, private sector executives, and academic thought leaders to discuss efforts to promote the security of our common digital ecosystem and the integrity of our hardware and software supply chains.</p>



<p>Director Inglis met with officials from the Governments of Israel, the Netherlands, and the United Kingdom to share lessons learned on enhancing national cybersecurity, growing the cyber talent pool, and ensuring the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure. He also solicited feedback on themes of the Biden-Harris Administration’s forthcoming National Cybersecurity Strategy. Director Inglis met with leaders from the private sector to discuss the Biden-Harris Administration’s priorities for public-private cyber collaboration and the vital role that the private sector plays in protecting national and international cybersecurity. Director Inglis met with educators and academic leaders to discuss efforts to promote the digital literacy and cybersecurity awareness of our citizens and expand the cyber talent pipeline.</p>



<p>Director Inglis’s visit served to strengthen and reinforce partnerships necessary to ensure a secure and resilient international cyber ecosystem that reflects democratic values, safeguards our individual and collective security, and supports U.S. interests abroad.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Upcoming Meeting with President López Obrador of&#160;Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-upcoming-meeting-with-president-lopez-obrador-of-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 01:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[5:30 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you very much, William.&#160; And thank you, everyone, for joining us today and for your patience as we had to push this back due to a long-running meeting.&#160; Appreciate you all joining our background press call to preview President Biden&#8217;s upcoming meeting with President López Obrador. As a reminder of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>5:30 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much, William.&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining us today and for your patience as we had to push this back due to a long-running meeting.&nbsp; Appreciate you all joining our background press call to preview President Biden&#8217;s upcoming meeting with President López Obrador.</p>



<p>As a reminder of the ground rules, this briefing will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and is embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time tomorrow, Tuesday, July 12.</p>



<p>For your awareness but not for reporting purposes, our speakers tonight will be [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll kick it over to [senior administration official] to do our opening remarks.&nbsp; And after that, we&#8217;ll open it up for Q&amp;A.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody, for joining the phone call and for accommodating the last-minute changes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, getting right to it, the President has invited President López Obrador to the White House with an objective of building on the significant progress made at the Summit of the Americas this past June and to discuss our broad and deep partnership.</p>



<p>This is the second &#8212; this will be the second time that the two leaders will meet at the White House, though they also had a virtual meeting during the pandemic.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve had a number of calls, as well as the Vice President making her first international trip to Mexico and also maintaining an active engagement with the Mexican leader.&nbsp; And then, of course, the wife of President López Obrador was hosted here by Dr. Biden for a Cinco de Mayo celebration.</p>



<p>So we’ve maintained a very active pace of bilateral engagement with Mexico.</p>



<p>So this &#8212; this just builds on the first virtual bilateral meeting that was held in March of last year, their bilateral at the North American Leaders Summit last November, and as I mentioned, several calls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the summit, you saw that Mexico supported the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity, which is a marquee economic initiative for the Biden administration.&nbsp; Mexico also joined the United States &#8212; a total of 21 countries if you include the United States &#8212; in adopting the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection, a framework to share responsibility and economic support for countries most impacted by refugee and migration flows.</p>



<p>Key is that it recognizes that the migration challenge is a hemispheric challenge.&nbsp; That is not just the migration challenge, it is also an economic and security challenge that all of us need to work together to address.&nbsp; We expect the two leaders to discuss their common vision for North America and efforts to address global challenges such as the impact of Russia&#8217;s aggression in Ukraine, which has affected working families in both countries as well as the rest of the hemisphere.</p>



<p>And following the meeting, we expect to announce joint actions to improve border infrastructure and address irregular migration; enhance law enforcement cooperation to disrupt the flow of fentanyl to both our countries; and promote clean energy, economic innovation, and prosperity.</p>



<p>Now, for example, we will commit to completing a multi-year joint U.S.-Mexico border infrastructure modernization effort for projects along the 2,000-mile border.&nbsp; The joint effort seeks to align priorities, unite border communities, and make the flow of commerce and people more secure and efficient.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll put a finer point on this.&nbsp; The point of entry at San Ysidro is the most &#8212; is the busiest land border crossing in the entire world.&nbsp; And that is a place where in &#8212; during the Obama administration, we made significant investments to make sure that it was functioning effectively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Similarly, we&#8217;re looking at other similar ports of entry like, for example, Otay Mesa II, which is &#8212; our objective ultimately is &#8212; a part of the &#8212; a joint venture is to create a 21st century border crossing for the San Diego/Baja California mega-region that will really enhance regional mobility and fuel economic growth and binational trade at the same time that we are, of course, working on very important migration issues.</p>



<p>We will also commit to deepen our cooperation to combat transnational criminal organizations that foment violence in both countries.&nbsp; To that end, we will establish a U.S.-Mexico operational task force under the bilateral Bicentennial Partnership on Security that was launched last October to ensure that we are accelerating our joint efforts to disrupt the flow of fentanyl into our countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as the United States and Mexico will also launch a bilateral working group on labor migration pathways and worker protections, as well as expand our diplomatic coordination on migration issues throughout the region.&nbsp; And first and foremost as well is just our economic agenda, as I had mentioned, under the Americas Partnership, and as well as the High-Level Economic Dialogue, which will meet in September of this year.</p>



<p>So, more to come on this tomorrow.</p>



<p>President Biden and his administration firmly believe our relationship with Mexico is a priority and critical to delivering for the American people and people in the hemisphere.&nbsp; And you will see that action on Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s also important to mention that the Vice President is going to host the Mexican President in a small breakfast tomorrow to also follow up on what has been really an active pace of engagement by the Vice President on our Root Causes Strategy, on our bilateral engagement with Mexico to make sure that we&#8217;re following up on a lot of the conversations that they&#8217;ve had since her visit to Mexico last year.</p>



<p>So I will now turn it back to the moderators and my other colleague.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, William.&nbsp; If you could please remind everyone on how to raise their hand to submit a question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thank you, guys, for doing this call.&nbsp; I wanted to ask if the U.S. is going to make specific demands on Mexico to stop migrants from reaching the border, and specifically what.&nbsp; And also, if you guys have seen an increase in immigration enforcement from Mexico in recent weeks.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, I can take that question.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; You know, migration cooperation is a top priority for both President López Obrador and President Biden.&nbsp; I think this will be a top subject of conversation tomorrow.<br><br>You know, I think we view each other as equal partners in this &#8212; two countries that have been significantly impacted by migration and refugee flows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, as [senior administration official] mentioned, I think we expect the focus to be a lot on how we can expand legal pathways to both countries, with a particular focus on labor pathways from Central America but also from other parts of the region; how we can continue to cooperate to combat the multibillion-dollar smuggling industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think we saw with the tragedy in San Antonio just the incredible impact of these smuggling networks and the need to, with great urgency, address that.&nbsp; Both countries are &#8212; continue to work to expand their asylum systems and also to repatriate those that don&#8217;t qualify.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So all of these are themes that are encapsulated in the Los Angeles Declaration that both countries championed.&nbsp; So, you know, I think that, just to sum it up, migration will be certainly a central focus of the discussion.<br><br>Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing that.&nbsp; To piggyback off of that question, can you elaborate more on what you mean by diplomatic coordination on migration and expanding legal pathways?&nbsp; For example, does that mean Mexico opening up more visas?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, also, is human smuggling and any efforts on tackling human smuggling networks expected to be part of the conversation, given the incident in San Antonio?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, Priscilla.&nbsp; I think you might have seen with the Los Angeles Declaration that Mexico made some concrete commitments related to expanding labor pathways to Mexico, and the U.S. did as well.<br><br>I think we both are recognizing that if we want to address irregular migration to our countries, we have to open up additional legal pathways.&nbsp; And legal migration can fuel economic growth.&nbsp; So this is an area of real common interest from both countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, as [senior administration official] mentioned, there will be &#8212; we will be announcing a&nbsp; binational labor pathways working group.&nbsp; And I think the hope is that the U.S. and Mexico can champion this and bring other countries to the table, because we see this as a real important way that we can combat irregular migration.</p>



<p>And then I think we will be looking at other legal pathways like refugee resettlement and family reunification.&nbsp; So this is an area where we&#8217;re really grateful to have Mexico as a partner and a leader.</p>



<p>And certainly, I think the tragedy in San Antonio is top of mind for both the U.S. and Mexico.&nbsp; We know many of those who perished in the incident were Mexican nationals.&nbsp; So we are already doing a lot to expand our cooperation on addressing these human smuggling networks.&nbsp; And so I think tomorrow will be really important in order to make sure that we&#8217;re able to advance together on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We can hear you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, we can hear you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ah, sorry.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about, like, the comments that President Obrador made a couple of weeks ago regarding the pardon for Julian Assange.&nbsp; It’s something that he has been insisting on, and he said that he was going to bring it up during his meeting with President Biden. &nbsp;And he even made some comments about the Statue of Liberty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I wanted to know how the White House (inaudible), and if you expect this to be addressed during the meeting that both leaders are going to have.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So I guess the way that I would answer is that presidents will raise what they want to raise.&nbsp; And for us, any issue is on the table.&nbsp; The President will be prepared to discuss whatever the President of Mexico raises.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to speculate on exactly whether or not it&#8217;ll be raised.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, our focus certainly remains on what is a broad and, I think, deep agenda with Mexico that goes from &#8212; as you&#8217;ll see from the joint statement, that includes everything from &#8212; everything my colleagues said on migration, and also our joint efforts that &#8212; advancing economic cooperation; issues related to energy and climate; issues related to food security, accelerating our efforts on security cooperation, border infrastructure, regional and global issues.</p>



<p>So there is a significant set of topics that we are focused on that represent, really, the core of the U.S.-Mexico relationship; the core of what really is &#8212; are some of the challenges facing the people of the United States, the people of Mexico, and the people of the Americas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, the two presidents will discuss whatever is on their mind.<br><br>Over.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello there.&nbsp; Thanks so much for having the call, [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Understanding that &#8212; what you just said about not wanting to speculate in the meeting, I am hoping, just since we&#8217;ve covered some other topics that are likely to come up in this meeting tomorrow, if you can say whether or not &#8212; just how much of a priority it is for the administration to also communicate any concerns around any of the criticism that&#8217;s been lodged against President López Obrador for his criticism against journalists and the free press at a time where we&#8217;re now seeing an increasing number of journalists go missing as well.&nbsp; How much that sense of sort of accountability, when it comes to democratic norms, will be brought to this meeting tomorrow?<br><br>And then, also, just to follow up on the legal pathways question, just hoping to kind of get a direct answer on whether or not the administration is prepared to announce any sort of expansion of work visas tomorrow.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; On the first, what I&#8217;ll say is that the issue of combating corruption, the issue of democracy and governance, the issue of the importance of a free press are issues that have been discussed between both leaders in the past.<br><br>We don&#8217;t always telegraph those issues publicly, but they&#8217;re generally the subject of a wide-ranging discussion between the two leaders as they think about, really, the importance of North America and, frankly, just how &#8212; as the President and Vice President really are thinking about the economic prosperity, security of the United States and the working families here &#8212; how, really, collaboration with Mexico is really central to that.<br><br>So these are topics that certainly may come up tomorrow, as they have come up in the past.<br><br>We have been very clear that this administration&#8217;s priority, not just as it relates to the relationship with Mexico but around the world, combating corruption is at the center of everything that we&#8217;re going to be doing internationally and, certainly, as you saw &#8212; may have seen at the Summit of the Americas &#8212; initiatives to really support independent journalism everywhere.<br><br>Because for us, I think an independent and free press is really the backbone of a functioning democracy, which is something the President cares deeply about, the &#8212; I think the global competition that we are seeing between autocracies and democracies.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the legal pathways, you know, just last month, President Biden did announce some specific numerical commitments: the 11,500 in H-2Bs, non-agricultural seasonal worker visas for North and Central America and Haiti.<br><br>He also announced our new fair recruitment practice guidelines, as well as the $65 million pilot project that the U.S. Agricultural Department will be launching to help U.S. farmers recruit workers from the region.<br><br>So, you know, Mexico also made very concrete commitments related to labor pathways and protection at the Summit of the Americas.&nbsp; So tomorrow, I think, will be much more focused on implementation and making sure that both of our countries lead by example.<br><br>As I mentioned before, we want to bring other countries on board to do similar things, to also make concrete commitments.&nbsp; We really think if we want to truly reduce irregular migration, it can&#8217;t just be the U.S. and Mexico; we need lots of other countries to come forward and offer a legal pathway.<br><br>So tomorrow will be much more about cooperation and implementation and not so much about specific numerical commitments.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Jorge Ramos here from Univision.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; One practical one: At what time are they going to be meeting?&nbsp; And is there going to be access to the press?<br><br>And the second question: Again, let me go back with &#8212; about the visas.&nbsp; As you know, the Mexican press has reported that López Obrador is going to be asking for another 300,000 visas, so half of them for Mexicans and half of them for people from Central America.&nbsp; Is the White House willing to &#8212; is the White House open to that possibility?</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, thank you, Jorge.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really great to hear your voice.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if the meeting time has been noticed, but it was &#8212; right now it is tentatively scheduled for the morning, so around 11 o&#8217;clock, though I think we&#8217;ll commit to just following up with you on the exact timings, as I know they&#8217;ll notice to press the call time.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ll leave it there.&nbsp; And maybe we can follow up via press channels because I don&#8217;t want to get out ahead of them.<br><br>And then I&#8217;ll turn to my colleague for the other.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes, and just to jump in on the on the guidance of the timing, we&#8217;ll have a press guidance out later tonight to all of you with specific details that we can make reportable at that time.</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And on visas, you know, I think we were all really pleased to see over 300,000 H-2 visas issued to Mexican nationals in FY21.&nbsp; I believe that was a record.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s good for Mexico, it&#8217;s good for the United States.&nbsp; It certainly fuels our economy.&nbsp; And as you know, the H-2A program is uncapped, and so there, the sky is the limit.<br><br>H-2B is capped, but we&#8217;ve seen, you know, multiple times, under the Biden-Harris administration, efforts to expand access to that program to address labor shortages in our tourism industry and other key industries where we can utilize the H-2B program.<br><br>So, you know, I think that, again, this is an area where the two countries are very much aligned.&nbsp; And so we expect that this will be &#8212; to be a subject of conversation between our two leaders tomorrow.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining our background call today.&nbsp; Unfortunately, we are out of time, but we appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility tonight and you all joining us to preview this exciting visit tomorrow.<br><br>As a reminder of the ground rules, this call was held on background with the contents attributable to “senior administration officials,” and it is embargoed until 5:00 a.m.&nbsp; Eastern tomorrow morning.<br><br>Thank you all, and I hope everyone has a great evening.<br><br>5:50 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris in a Briefing to Preview the First Images from the James Webb Space&#160;Telescope</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-in-a-briefing-to-preview-the-first-images-from-the-james-webb-space-telescope/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 6:13 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Well, good evening, everyone.&#160; I am very honored to be with you all.&#160; President Joe Biden and I talk often about our mutual passion for everything you all do.&#160; This is a very exciting moment to join you for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>6:13 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, good evening, everyone.&nbsp; I am very honored to be with you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Joe Biden and I talk often about our mutual passion for everything you all do.&nbsp; This is a very exciting moment to join you for the unveiling of the work that you have been laboring on for decades.</p>



<p>So, to our President, Joe Biden, thank you for your leadership around all of these issues.&nbsp; Our NASA Administrator, Bill Nelson, and the Office of Science and Technology Policy Acting Director, Dr. Alondra Nelson.</p>



<p>Thank you also to our colleagues from across the White House and NASA and everyone else joining us from home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, yes, as Chair of the National Space Council, I know that today represents an exciting new chapter in the exploration of our universe.&nbsp; From the beginning of history, humans have looked up to the night sky with wonder.&nbsp; And thanks to dedicated people who have been working for decades in engineering and on scientific marvels, we can look to the sky with new understanding.</p>



<p>When NASA launched the Hubble Space Telescope in 1990, we were able to see the stars unobstructed by the Earth&#8217;s atmosphere and understand the universe in ways we could have never imagined even a few decades earlier.</p>



<p>And now we enter a new phase of scientific discovery.&nbsp; Building on the legacy of Hubble, the James Webb Space Telescope allows us to see deeper into space than ever before and in stunning clarity.&nbsp; It will enhance what we know about the origins of our universe, our solar system, and possibly life itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This was made possible by partnership among nations.&nbsp; And it is an example of how the scientific endeavor can build upon the international rules and norms that govern our cooperation in space.</p>



<p>This telescope is one of humanity&#8217;s great engineering achievements.&nbsp; And the images we will see today are a testament to the amazing work done by the thousands of workers across our nation who dedicated years to this project.&nbsp; They embarked on this complex endeavor for the benefit of humankind, and in the process, accelerated American innovation, strengthened partnerships with our allies, and will undoubtedly inspire generations to look to the heavens with excitement and ambition.</p>



<p>With that, it is my great honor to introduce a leader who has always believed in the power of American innovation and international cooperation to achieve the remarkable: our President, the President of the United States, Joe Biden.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s great to be with you all.&nbsp; And I was going to say “good afternoon,” but we&#8217;re starting this meeting late because I was engaged in preparing for a trip to the Middle East.</p>



<p>But today is a historic day.&nbsp; And thank you, Vice President Harris, Chair of the National Space Council.&nbsp; And thank you, my dear friend and our outstanding NASA Administrator and the guy&nbsp;&#8212; the only guy here who’s been in space, Bill Nelson.&nbsp; Bill, you&#8217;re a good friend.&nbsp; Thank you very much for what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and, Dr. Nelson, you&#8217;re doing a great job leading this Office of Science and Technology Policy.&nbsp; It really is a matter &#8212; it really is amazing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Six and a half months ago, a rocket launched from Earth carrying the world’s newest, most powerful deep-space telescope on a journey one million miles into the cosmos &#8212; first of all, that blows my mind: a million miles into the cosmos &#8212; along the way unfolding itself<a>, deploying a mirror 21 feet wide, a sunshield the size of a tennis court, and 250,000 tiny shutters</a>, each one smaller than a grain of sand.</p>



<p>Put together, it’s a new window into the history of our universe.</p>



<p>And today, we’re going to get a glimpse of the first light to shine through that window &#8212; light from other worlds, orbiting stars far beyond our own.&nbsp; It’s astounding to me when I read this and saw the &#8212; I mean, it really is.&nbsp; It’s &#8212; it’s &#8212; anyway, I don’t want to &#8212; I’ll see what they think when we see this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But light where stars were born and from where they die.&nbsp; Light from the oldest galaxies.&nbsp; The oldest documented light in the history of the universe from over 13 billion &#8212; let me say that again: 13 billion years ago.&nbsp; It’s hard to even fathom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, when this image is shared with the world, it will be a historic moment for science and technology, for astronomy and space exploration, for America and all of humanity.</p>



<p>You know, as an international collaboration, this telescope embodies how America leads the world not by the example of our power, but the power of our example.&nbsp; A partnership with others, it symbolizes the relentless spirit of American ingenuity.&nbsp;&nbsp; And it shows what we can achieve, what more we can discover, not just about distant places, but about our very own planet and climate, like NASA’s Earth System Observatory that we launched last year.</p>



<p>That’s why the federal government must invest &#8212; must invest in science and technology, more than we have in the past.</p>



<p>These images are going to remind the world that America can do big things.&nbsp;&nbsp;And they’ll remind the American people, especially our children, that there’s nothing beyond our capacity &#8212; nothing beyond our capacity.</p>



<p>We can see possibilities no one has ever seen before.&nbsp; We can go places no one has ever gone before.&nbsp; You know, you’ve &#8212; you’ve heard me say it over and over again.&nbsp; America is defined by one single word: possibilities.&nbsp; Possibilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank the team at NASA for once again showing that that’s who we are &#8212; that’s who we are as a nation: a nation of possibilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now let&#8217;s take a look at the very first image from this miraculous telescope.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The image is displayed.)&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>NASA Administrator Nelson, I&#8217;m going to turn this over to you.&nbsp; So will you please tell us about what we’re seeing?</p>



<p>ADMINISTRATOR NELSON:&nbsp; Mr. President, if you held a grain of sand on the tip of your finger at arm&#8217;s length, that is the part of the universe that you&#8217;re seeing &#8212; just one little speck of the universe.&nbsp; And what you&#8217;re seeing there are galaxies.&nbsp; You&#8217;re seeing galaxies that are shining around other galaxies whose light has been bent.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re seeing just a small little portion of the universe.<br><br>You know, 100 years ago, Mr. President, Madam Vice President &#8212; 100 years ago, we thought there was only one galaxy.&nbsp; Now, the number is unlimited.&nbsp; And in our galaxy, we have billions of stars, or suns.&nbsp; And there are billions of galaxies with billions of stars and suns.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re getting our first glimpse.<br><br>As you said, Mr. President, we&#8217;re looking back more than 13 billion years.&nbsp; Light travels at 186,000 miles per second.&nbsp; And that light that you are seeing on one of those little specks has been traveling for over 13 billion years.<br><br>And, by the way, we&#8217;re going back further, because this is just the first image.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going back about 13.5 billion years.&nbsp; And since we know the universe is 13.8 billion years old, we&#8217;re going back almost to the beginning.<br><br>That is the discovery that we are making with this.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s another thing that you&#8217;re going to find with this telescope: It is going to be so precise, you&#8217;re going to see whether or not planets, because of the chemical composition that we can determine with this telescope of their atmosphere, if those planets are habitable.<br><br>And when you look at something as big as this is, we are going to be able to answer questions that we don&#8217;t even know what the questions are yet.<br><br>This is what&#8217;s happening, and it&#8217;s because of this wonderful team that&#8217;s out here, part of that team led by Thomas Zurbuchen.&nbsp; It was in trouble financially five years ago.&nbsp; He took it over.&nbsp; He got Greg Robinson, that you&#8217;re going to meet, to direct it.&nbsp; And the result is what you&#8217;ve seen.<br><br>So, what an incredible team &#8212; joined, by the way, with our international partners, the European Space Agency and the Canadian Space Agency.&nbsp; So this is an international endeavor.</p>



<p><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s amazing.&nbsp; I wonder what the press is like in those other places.</p>



<p>6:23 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate, on the Continuation of  the National Emergency with Respect to Hong&#160;Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 23:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#160;emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&nbsp;emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to Hong Kong that was&nbsp;declared in Executive Order 13936 of July 14, 2020, is to&nbsp;continue&nbsp;in&nbsp;effect beyond July 14, 2022.</p>



<p>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat, which has its source in substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the&nbsp;situation in Hong Kong.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Hong&#160;Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/11/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 23:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 14, 2020, by Executive Order 13936, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&#160;States constituted by the situation with respect to Hong Kong. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 14, 2020, by Executive Order 13936, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the situation with respect to Hong Kong.</p>



<p>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on July 14, 2020, must continue in effect beyond July 14, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section&nbsp;202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the situation in Hong Kong.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 11, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at an Event Commemorating the Passage of the Safer Communities&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-an-event-commemorating-the-passage-of-the-safer-communities-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 23:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 11:17 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; Doc, thank you.&#160; Your heroism in treating the wounded children in Uvalde, many of whom you’ve known their whole lives &#8212; their whole lives &#8212; and treated them with normal child problems as a pediatrician, it’s something we’ll never forget. And, Garnell, it’s good to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>11:17 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Doc, thank you.&nbsp; Your heroism in treating the wounded children in Uvalde, many of whom you’ve known their whole lives &#8212; their whole lives &#8212; and treated them with normal child problems as a pediatrician, it’s something we’ll never forget.</p>



<p>And, Garnell, it’s good to see you again.&nbsp; I know how tough it is.&nbsp; A lot of people in here have been victims of gun violence &#8212; lost sons, daughters, husbands, wives.&nbsp; They understand your pain.&nbsp; And every time you stand up to talk about it, even for a good cause, it brings it all back like it happened yesterday.&nbsp; But thank you for the courage to do it.</p>



<p>Jill and I will never forget the time we spent with you and your families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank &#8212; thank the Vice President Harris and the Second Gentleman; and members of the Cabinet, eight of whom are here today; as well as mayors and elected officials from across the country.</p>



<p>I want to particularly thank the Governor of Illinois and the Mayor of Highland Park for being here.&nbsp; We’ve had &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; We had a number of conversations immediately after the attack in Highland Park.&nbsp; And I’ve been impressed with the way they’ve handled things.&nbsp; It’s been extraordinary.&nbsp; And as the three of us have discussed, we have more to do.</p>



<p>I also want to thank the bipartisan group of senators who worked so hard to get this done, especially Senators Murphy &#8212; (applause); Sinema &#8212; (applause); Cornyn and Tillis.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I hope it doesn’t get you in trouble mentioning your name.&nbsp; Thank you for the courage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As well as all of the members of Congress who have worked on these issues for a long time, 80 of whom are with us today.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’m sorry Senators Schumer and Blumenthal can’t be here today, but they’re working from home, overcoming mild cases of COVID.</p>



<p>I know how hard it is to get things done because I know how hard it was to write the first gun legislation &#8212; at least the first from my career &#8212; that was passed nearly 30 years ago.&nbsp; That’s how long ago it was.</p>



<p>And as I look out in this crowd, I see so many advocates and families, many of whom have become friends, whose lives have been shattered by gun violence and who have made it their purpose to save other lives.</p>



<p>I’ve spent so much time with so many of you over the years that we’ve actually become personal friends.&nbsp; And I can’t thank you enough for your willingness to continue to fight for other families.</p>



<p>Nothing can bring back your loved ones, but you did it to make sure that other families don’t have to experience the same loss and pain that you’ve experienced.</p>



<p>And you have felt and you feel the price of inaction, that this has taken too long, with too much of a trail of bloodshed and carnage.&nbsp; And I know public policy can seem remote, technical, and distant from our everyday lives.&nbsp; But because of your work, your advocacy, your courage, lives will be saved today and tomorrow because of this.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>What we are doing here today is real, it’s vivid, it’s relevant.&nbsp; The action we take today is a step designed to make our nation the kind of nation we should be.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about the most fundamental of things &#8212; the lives of our children, of our loved ones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We face, literally, a moral choice in this country &#8212; a moral choice with profound, real-world implications.</p>



<p>Will we take wise steps to fulfill the responsibility to protect the innocent and while keeping faith with constitutional rights?</p>



<p>Will we match thoughts and prayers with action?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I say yes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And that’s what we’re doing here today.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Today is many things.  It’s proof that despite the naysayers, we can make meaningful progress on dealing with gun violence.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We have to do more than that!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because make no mistake &#8212; sit down.&nbsp; You’ll hear what I have to say if you think &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We have to do more than that!&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We have to open an office in the White House.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; I’ve been trying to tell you this for years.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; President Biden!&nbsp; Yeah!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have one.&nbsp; Let me finish my comments.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let him talk.&nbsp; Let him talk.&nbsp; No one &#8212; okay?</p>



<p>Because make no mistake about it: This legislation is real progress, but more has to be done.&nbsp; The provision of this new legislation is going to save lives.&nbsp; And it’s proof that in today’s politics we can come together on a bipartisan basi- &#8212; basis to get important things done, even on an issue as tough as guns.</p>



<p>And one more thing: It’s a call to action to all of us to do more &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to take away from the legislation, it is not &#8212; that’s not what we can do.&nbsp; It’s to take the &#8212; the take-away from this is that now &#8212; now we’re opening to get much more done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senator Murphy has said: When you look at the biggest social issues America has faced throughout our history, quote, “Success begets success.”&nbsp; And that’s when you, quote, “finally move that mountain.”&nbsp; You can &#8212; you can ignite a movement when you do that for more progress to follow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have finally moved that mountain &#8212; a mountain of opposition, obstruction, and indifference that has stood in the way and stopped every effort at gun safety for 30 years in this nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And now is the time to galvanize this movement, because that’s our duty to the people of this nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s what we owe those families in Buffalo, where a grocery store became a killing field.</p>



<p>It’s what we owe those families in Uvalde, where an elementary school became a killing field.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s what we owe those families in Highland Park, where, on July 4th, a parade became a killing field.</p>



<p>And that’s what we owe all those families represented here today and all over this country the past many years, across our schools, places of worship, workplaces, stores, music festivals, nightclubs, and so many other everyday places that have turned into killing fields.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we owe the families all across this nation where, every day, tragic killings that don&#8217;t make the headlines are more than passing mention &#8212; a little more than passing mention in the local news.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Neighborhoods and streets have been turned into killing fields as well.</p>



<p>Today&#8217;s legislation is an important start.&nbsp; And here are the key things that it does: It provides $750 million in crisis intervention and red-flag laws so the parent, a teacher, a counselor can flag for the court that a child, a student, a patient is exhibiting violent tendencies, threatening classmates, or experiencing suicidal thoughts that makes them a danger to themselves and to others.</p>



<p>Fort Hood, Texas, 2009: 13 dead, 30 more injured.</p>



<p>Marjorie Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, 1918 [2018]: 17 dead, 17 injured.</p>



<p>In both places, countless others suffering with invisible wounds.</p>



<p>In both places, red-flag laws could have stopped both those shooters.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know, this new law requiring &#8212; requires young people under 21 to [under]go enhanced background checks before purchasing a gun.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How many more mass shootings do we have to see where a shooter is 17, 18 years old and able to get his hands on a weapon and go on a killing spree?</p>



<p>You know, it closes the so-called “boyfriend loophole.”&nbsp; If you’re convicted of assault against your girlfriend or boy- &#8212; you can’t buy a gun.&nbsp; You can&#8217;t do it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>According to a recent study, in over 50 percent of mass shootings, the shooter shot a family member or a partner.</p>



<p>So if we keep guns out of the hands of domestic abusers, we can save the lives of their partners, and we can also stop more mass shootings.</p>



<p>One, this law includes the first-ever federal law that makes gun trafficking and straw purchases explicit federal crimes.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>It clarifies who needs to register as a federally licensed gun dealer and run background checks before selling a single weapon.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>It invests in anti-violence programs that work directly</p>



<p>with the communities most at risk for gun crimes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this law also provides funding vital for funding to address the youth mental health crisis in this country &#8212; (applause) &#8212; including the trauma experienced by the survivors of gun violence.</p>



<p>It will not save every life from the epidemic of gun violence, but if this law had been in place years ago, even this last year, lives would have been saved.</p>



<p>It matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; But it’s not enough, and we all know that.</p>



<p>In preparation for today’s signing, I asked to send me their story &#8212; people to send me their stories about their experience with gun violence.&nbsp; I received over 2,500 responses in 24 hours.&nbsp; I didn’t get to read them all, but I read some.</p>



<p>A 17-year-old wrote me saying, quote, “A school shooting sophomore year shattered every sense of normalcy I&#8217;ve ever felt.&nbsp; Almost three years later, I still have nightmares.”</p>



<p>A 24-year-old wrote about growing up in what was a, quote, “seemingly endless era of gun violence.”</p>



<p>A 40-year-old wrote me about two friends shot and killed by abusive partners and former partners.</p>



<p>Someone else wrote me about a 6-year-old child who was sitting near his father’s coffin, was asking, quote, “Why is Daddy in that scary box? &nbsp;Wake up, Daddy.&nbsp; Wake up Daddy.”&nbsp; His father had been gunned down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I read these stories and so many others.&nbsp; So many others.&nbsp; And, you know, I see the statistics.&nbsp; Over 40,000 people died from gunshot wounds last year in the United States, 25,000 by suicide.</p>



<p>I think: Can this really be the United States of America?&nbsp; Why has it come to this?&nbsp; We all know a lot of the reasons: gun lobby, gun manufacturers, special interest money, the rise of hyper-partisan tribal politics in the country where we don’t debate the issues on the merits and we just rather turn on each other from our corners and attack the other side.</p>



<p>Regardless, we’re living in a country awash in weapons of war &#8212; weapons that weren’t designed to hunt are not being used &#8212; the weapons designed that they&#8217;re purchasing are designed as weapons of war to take out an enemy.</p>



<p>What is the rationale for these weapons outside war zones?&nbsp; Some people claim it’s for sport or to hunt.&nbsp; But let’s look at the facts: The most common rounds fired from an AR-15 move almost twice as fast as that from a handgun.&nbsp; Coupled with smaller, lighter bullets, these weapons maximize the damage done coupled with those bullets, and human flesh and bone is just torn apart.</p>



<p>And as difficult as it is to say, that’s why so many people and some in this audience &#8212; and I apologize for having to say it &#8212; need to provide DNA samples to identify the remains of their children.&nbsp; Think of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s why trauma surgeons who train for years for these moments know it’s unlikely that someone shot with a high-powered assault weapon will make it long enough for the ambulance to get them to the hospital.</p>



<p>It’s why these scenes of destruction are resembling nothing like a weekend hunting trip for deer or elk.</p>



<p>And yet, we continue to let these weapons be sold to people with no training or expertise.</p>



<p>Case in point: America has the finest fighting force in the world.&nbsp; We provide our service members with the most lethal weapons on Earth to protect America.</p>



<p>We also require them to receive significant training before they’re allowed to use these weapons.</p>



<p>We require extensive background checks on them and mental health assessments on them.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>We require that they learn how to lock up and store these weapons responsibly.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>We require our military to do all that.&nbsp; These are commonsense requirements.&nbsp; But we don’t require the same commonsense measures for a stranger walking into a gun store to purchase an AR-15 or some weapon like that.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It makes no sense.&nbsp; Assault weapons need to be banned.&nbsp; They were banned.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I led the fight in 1994.&nbsp; And then, under pressure from the NRA and the gun manufacturers and others, that ban was lifted in 2004.</p>



<p>In that 10 years it was law, mass shootings went down.&nbsp; When the law expired in 2004 and those weapons were allowed to be sold again, mass shootings tripled.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re the facts.&nbsp; I’m determined to ban these weapons again and high-capacity magazines &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that hold 30 rounds and that let mass shooters fire hundreds of bullets in a matter of minutes.&nbsp; I’m not going to stop until we do it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Here’s another thing we should do: We should have safe storage laws, requiring personal liability for not locking up your gun.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The shooter in Sandy Hook came from a home full of guns and assault weapons that were too easy to access &#8212; weapons he used to kill his mother and then murder 26 people, including 20 innocent first graders.</p>



<p>If you own a weapon, you have a responsibility to secure it and keep it under lock and key.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Responsible gun owners agree: No one else should have access to it, so lock it up, have trigger locks.&nbsp; And if you don’t and something bad happens, you should be held responsible.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I have four shotguns; two are mine and two are my deceased son’s.&nbsp; They’re locked up, lock and key.&nbsp; Every responsible gun owner that I know does that.</p>



<p>We should expand background checks to better keep guns out of the hands of felons, fugitives, and those under domestic violence restraining orders.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Expanded background checks are something that the vast majority of Americans, including the majority of gun owners, agree on.</p>



<p>My fellow Americans, none of what I’m talking about infringes on anyone’s Second Amendment rights.</p>



<p>I’ve said it many times: I support the Second Amendment.</p>



<p>But when guns are the number one killer of children in the United States of America &#8212; let me say that again &#8212; guns are the number one killer of children in the United States.&nbsp; More than car accidents.&nbsp; More than cancer. <a>&nbsp;And over the last two decades</a>, more <s>high-school</s> [school-age] children have died from gun shots than on-duty police officers and active-duty military combined.&nbsp; Think of that.&nbsp; Then we can’t just stand by.&nbsp; We can’t let it happen any longer.</p>



<p>With rights come responsibilities.</p>



<p>Yes, there’s a right to bear arms, but we also have the right to live freely &#8212; (applause) &#8212; without fear for our lives in a grocery store, in a classroom, on a playground, at a house of worship, in a store, at a workplace, a nightclub, a festival, in our neighborhoods and our streets.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The right to bear arms is not an absolute right that dominates all others.</p>



<p>The perennial price for living in a community with others is being neighbors, of being fellow citizens, is that we obey the laws and customs that ensure what that Fra- &#8212; what the Framers called “domestic tranquility.”</p>



<p>That’s what civilization is.&nbsp; That’s what we have been at our best.&nbsp; That’s what America must always be: a place where we preserve the rights but fulfill our responsibilities.</p>



<p>I know this: There can be no greater responsibility than to do all we can to ensure the safety of our families, our children, and our fellow Americans.</p>



<p>When I spoke to the nation after Uvalde, I shared how a grandmother who had lost her granddaughter gave me and Jill a handwritten letter.&nbsp; We spent four hours, almost five hours with her.</p>



<p>And I read it.&nbsp; It reads, quote, “Erase the invisible line that is dividing our nation to come up with a solution and fix what is broken and to make the changes that are necessary to prevent this from happening again.”&nbsp; End of quote.</p>



<p>That’s why we’re here.&nbsp; That’s why we’re here.</p>



<p>Today, I want to thank those in Congress, both Democrat and Republicans, who erased that invisible line dividing our nation and moved us forward on gun safety.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s an important step.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And now we must look forward.&nbsp; We have so much more work to do.</p>



<p>And I might add, there is $75 million in there for mental health reasons &#8212; a whole range of other things I’m not going to take time to go into today, but it’s important.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>May God bless all of us with the strength to finish the work left undone and &#8212; on behalf of the lives we’ve lost and the lives we can save.&nbsp;</p>



<p>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:36 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Message to the Senate Regarding the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of&#160;Sweden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/message-to-the-senate-regarding-the-protocols-to-the-north-atlantic-treaty-of-1949-on-the-accession-of-the-republic-of-finland-and-the-kingdom-of-sweden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 21:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To the Senate of the United States: I transmit herewith, for the advice and consent of the Senate to its ratification, the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of Sweden (the &#8220;Protocols&#8221;).&#160; The Protocols were signed in Brussels on July 5, 2022,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>To the Senate of the United States:</p>



<p>I transmit herewith, for the advice and consent of the Senate to its ratification, the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of Sweden (the &#8220;Protocols&#8221;).&nbsp; The Protocols were signed in Brussels on July 5, 2022, on behalf of the United States and the other Parties to the North Atlantic Treaty.&nbsp; Also transmitted for the information of the Senate is an overview of the Protocols by the Department of State.&nbsp; Full ratification of the Protocols will allow Finland and Sweden to become Parties to the North Atlantic Treaty and members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</p>



<p>Article 10 of the North Atlantic Treaty, which outlines NATO&#8217;s Open Door policy, is part of the doctrinal foundation of the Alliance.&nbsp; It states that Allies may, by unanimous consent, invite any other European State in a position to further the principles of the Treaty and to contribute to the security of the North Atlantic area to accede.&nbsp; As further explained in the&nbsp;reports on the accession of Finland and Sweden to NATO, transmitted to the Congress on May&nbsp;19 and July 1, 2022, in light of section 3(2)(E) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the Czech Republic of April 30, 1998, Finland and Sweden more than meet these qualifications.&nbsp; They will be net contributors to the Alliance, in both capabilities and resources, and they share critically important values with the United States.&nbsp; Finland&#8217;s and Sweden&#8217;s accession will help further United States priorities within&nbsp;NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I ask the Senate to continue working with my Administration in advancing a strong and free Europe by providing its prompt advice and consent to ratification of the Protocols.&nbsp; We are encouraging all Allies to act expeditiously in their own ratification processes as well, given current global considerations. &nbsp;My Administration stands ready to brief and assist you in your deliberations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 11, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
