<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 13:25:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Meeting with Congressional Hispanic Caucus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-congressional-hispanic-caucus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 04:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today,&#160;National Economic Council Director&#160;Brian Deese&#160;met with the Congressional Hispanic Caucus (CHC) to discuss the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and the President’s legislative priorities. During a productive meeting, Deese and members of the CHC spoke about how elements of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, including investing in clean drinking water, public transit, and high speed internet, would directly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today,&nbsp;National Economic Council Director&nbsp;Brian Deese&nbsp;met with the Congressional Hispanic Caucus (CHC) to discuss the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and the President’s legislative priorities. During a productive meeting, Deese and members of the CHC spoke about how elements of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, including investing in clean drinking water, public transit, and high speed internet, would directly benefit the Latino community. Deese underscored the President’s two-track strategy and commitment to the rest of his agenda being pursued in the budget resolution and a reconciliation bill, and thanked the members for being partners in the fight to advance racial equity in underserved communities.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Surfside Condo Collapse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/01/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-surfside-condo-collapse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 03:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[St. Regis HotelSurfside, Florida 4:29 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, folks.&#160; Let me begin by saying that the degree of cooperation between local, state, and federal officials down here has been remarkable.&#160;&#160;I want to thank our FEMA Director for leading this national effort.&#160;&#160; But Governor DeSantis, Senators Rubio and Scott, Congresswoman Debbie Wasserman Schultz, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">St. Regis Hotel<br>Surfside, Florida</p>



<p>4:29 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, folks.&nbsp; Let me begin by saying that the degree of cooperation between local, state, and federal officials down here has been remarkable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank our FEMA Director for leading this national effort.&nbsp;&nbsp; But Governor DeSantis, Senators Rubio and Scott, Congresswoman Debbie Wasserman Schultz, and Mayor Cava –- Cava &#8212; they’ve been &#8212; they’ve all cooperated in ways that I haven’t seen in a long time.&nbsp; And it’s really a testament to &#8212; to what&#8217;s &#8212; how difficult things are down here.&nbsp; And it’s what, quite frankly, we miss a lot.&nbsp; You know, we all &#8212; we&#8217;ve all been working in tandem from the moment we got the news of the collapse of the building.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think my colleagues will tell you we cut through the bureaucracy.&nbsp; The one &#8212; the one order I gave federal folks was, “No bureaucracy.&nbsp; Just cut through it.&nbsp; Get to whatever they need.”<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s why we’ve decided to cover, for example, 100 percent of the search-and-rescue costs for the first 30 days.&nbsp; Not done often but necessary here, in my view.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And FEMA is going to provide temporary housing and other urgent needs for the survivors.&nbsp; The State Department is expedi- &#8212; expediting visas for family members from other countries &#8212; and there are from Latin America, South America, Europe, Israel.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to give a special shout-out to the first responders &#8212; International Association of Firefighters, one of the best organizations in the country.&nbsp; And I particularly want to thank the president.&nbsp; Ed came down from Boston, and he&#8217;s here with the entire &#8212; with the entire group.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, these folks are &#8212; these folks are always showing up, no matter what.&nbsp; They&#8217;re risking their lives.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s that old expression.&nbsp; I know, the press that travels with me is tired of hearing me saying it, but I&#8217;m not tired of saying it.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; that old expression &#8212; “God made man.&nbsp; Then he made a few firefighters.”&nbsp; They&#8217;re remarkable, remarkable people.&nbsp; There&#8217;s always &#8212; they&#8217;re always risking their lives to save lives, as well as the police and other first responders.&nbsp; I got to meet with a whole bunch of them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are able to deploy nearly 500 personnel, including five other search-and-rescue teams on the ground today here because of &#8212; our FEMA Director ordered it.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to compliment FEMA and, I might add, all those folks who are risking their lives to save lives, but also holding out hope that others will be found.&nbsp; Hope springs eternal.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When I talked to those first responders, I pointed out that they&#8217;re under a great deal of stress and we should take advantage &#8212; they should take advantage of the mental health facilities that are going to be available.&nbsp; Because, you know, we talk about our military suffering from post-traumatic stress.&nbsp; Well, seeing what they&#8217;re seeing and doing what they&#8217;re doing, understanding how &#8212; how much trauma is involved, I just don’t want them thinking that they should walk away from help if it’s needed.&nbsp; You know, they stand together, and it’s really impressive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there&#8217;s also the need, in addition to state and local assistance, to determine the cause of this collapse &#8212; and the adjacent buildings, how safe they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are two outstanding concerns.&nbsp; First, the remaining buildings may collapse &#8212; the remainder of the building may collapse.&nbsp; We need to determine if it&#8217;s safe for first responders to return to the site to continue their rescue mission.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s being done right now.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I asked the National Institute of Standards and Technology &#8212; NIST &#8212; to investigate, to see if it&#8217;s safe to go back and what caused the building to collapse in the first place.&nbsp; Because we&#8217;re committed not only to recover, but to restore the safety across the board.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the other reason I came down was to meet with the families.&nbsp; The whole nation is mourning with these families.&nbsp; They see it every day on television.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going through hell.&nbsp; And those who&#8217;ve survived the collapse, as well as those who are missing loved ones.<br>&nbsp;<br>I realize I&#8217;m a little late because I spent a lot of time with the families &#8212; a whole lot of time.&nbsp; And I apologize for taking so long to get here, because I thought it was important to speak to every single person who wanted to speak to me.&nbsp; So, after what you all covered when I opened up the &#8212; the meeting, I spent the remainder of the time, and I &#8212; and such incredible people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I sat with one woman who had just lost her &#8212; her husband and her little baby boy; didn&#8217;t know what to do.&nbsp; I sat with another family that lost almost the entire family: cousins, brothers, sisters.&nbsp; And to watch them and to &#8212; the &#8212; they&#8217;re praying and pleading that, &#8220;God, let there be a miracle.&nbsp; Let them be something happen for me that&#8217;s good.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Because I have, like many of you do, some idea what it&#8217;s like to suffer that kind of loss so many of them are suffering.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, they had basic heart-wrenching questions: &#8220;Will I be able to recover the body of my son or daughter, my husband, my cousin, my mom and dad?&nbsp; How can I have closure without being able to bury them if I don&#8217;t get the body?&nbsp; What do I do?&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>Jill and I wanted them to know that we&#8217;re with them and the country is with them.&nbsp; Our message today is that we&#8217;re here for you, as one nation.&nbsp; As one nation.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the message we communicated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ll be in touch with a lot of these families continuing through this process.&nbsp; But there is much more to be done.&nbsp; We&#8217;re ready to do it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, I thank the governor, I thank my colleagues, my &#8212; Senator Scott and Senator Rubio, I thank Debbie Wasserman Schultz for their total, complete cooperation.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no &#8212; there&#8217;s no disagreement, no bickering.&nbsp; Everybody is on the same team.&nbsp; It&#8217;s what America is all about.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about pulling together, leaving nobody behind.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what made me feel &#8212; the one thing that made me feel good about this is the &#8212; is a cohesion that exists.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no Democrat or Republican out there; they&#8217;re just people wanting to do the right thing for their fellow Americans.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, may God bless the victims and their families.&nbsp; And may God protect our first responders.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;ll take a couple questions right now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what were you told today about the likelihood &#8212; you said, “Hope springs eternal” &#8212; but that somebody will be able to be pulled out alive from this?&nbsp; And what were you able to convey to the families about that possibility?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, first of all, the families are very realistic.&nbsp; They know the longer it goes &#8212; and one of the things that the local FEMA personnel as well as the local first responders did is they took all of the families to the site to see &#8212; to see what it looked like up close.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re all realists.&nbsp; They all look, and they see those floors just literally feet &#8212; cement upon cement upon cement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I &#8212; when I talked to some of the families, some of the people who did escape, survived, and got out, they talked about watching the building collapse and watching as they were in the garage &#8212; one floor come down &#8212; literally a whole floor on top of another floor.&nbsp; They know that the chances are, as each day goes by, diminished slightly.<br>&nbsp;<br>But at a minimum &#8212; at a minimum &#8212; they want to recover the bodies.&nbsp; They want to recover the bodies.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of very religious people who are in there.&nbsp; Members of the &#8212; the rabbis in the Jewish community were talking about the need to make sure that they recover the body and be able to bury them.&nbsp; Give them &#8212; and, you know, the &#8212; anyway.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think they&#8217;re very realistic, Mike.&nbsp; But &#8212; but I don&#8217;t think that that, in any way, suggests that it’s too &#8212; that we should stop.&nbsp; I think that we should move on, continue to try to recover the bodies.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the meantime, that&#8217;s why NIST and others are determining whether or not it&#8217;s safe to send the first responders back.&nbsp; When they&#8217;d asked me about this, I&#8217;d point out that the last thing they would want and we would want is, in the process of trying to recover &#8212; and the possibility &#8212; there’s still a possibility someone could be alive, someone could still be breathing, someone could be there &#8212; that the last thing you want to have happen is have that building collapse and kill 10, 20, 30, 50 firefighters or wound them, or first responders.<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; but Mike, they&#8217;re &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re realistic.&nbsp; I &#8212; it just brought back so many &#8212; so many memories.&nbsp; It&#8217;s bad enough &#8212; it&#8217;s bad enough to lose somebody.&nbsp; But the hard part &#8212; the really hard part is to not know whether they&#8217;re surviving or not &#8212; just not have any idea.<br>&nbsp;<br>When the accident took my wife and my family, the hardest part was: Were my boys going to get out?&nbsp; Are they going to make it?&nbsp; And not knowing.&nbsp; Not knowing, when you&#8217;re flying home from Washington to get the news.&nbsp; You know, you just don’t know.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I was amazed &#8212; as you know, unfortunately, I&#8217;ve done a lot of these circumstances where I&#8217;ve met with families who have had great loss.&nbsp; And what amazed me about this group of people was the resilience and their absolute commitment, their willingness to do whatever it took to find &#8212; to find an answer.&nbsp; I walked away impressed by their strength.&nbsp; And &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>And Nancy, Bloomberg &#8212; do you have a question?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I was told.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thank you.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; What did you learn, if anything, about the collapse of the building?&nbsp; Is there anything more you learned from investigators or the FEMA administrators (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, it’s underway.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; and the director of FEMA is with me here.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any firm proof of what&#8217;s happened.&nbsp; There’s all kinds of rational speculation about whether or not the rebars are &#8212; were &#8212; were rusted; whether or not the cement &#8212; whether it was limestone or not; whether or not &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>But a lot of the &#8212; a lot the families who survived talked about how upset they were that, in the last years that they&#8217;ve been here, how there was one condominium complex built across the street and a road was purchased.&nbsp; And while they were living there, they would hear the drilling and they’d feel their building moving and shaking.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are all kinds of discussions about whether or not they thought that water level rising &#8212; what impact it had.&nbsp; And interesting to me &#8212; I didn&#8217;t raise it &#8212; but how many of the survivors and how many of the families talked about the impact of global warming.&nbsp; How much &#8212; and they didn’t know exactly, but they talked about sea levels rising and about how &#8212; how there were &#8212; and &#8212; and the combination of that and the concern about incoming storm &#8212; incoming tropical storms.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so &#8212; but I don&#8217;t think there is, at this point, any definitive judgment as to why it collapsed and what can be done to prevent it from happening and what other buildings may have to be inspected to determine if they have the same problems.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m supposed to head out and catch up with the governor.&nbsp; So I want to thank you all for taking the time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, can we ask you about two matters away from where we are now?&nbsp; The first is: While you’ve been speaking, a top associate of the former President has been in a New York court, pleading not guilty to various financial charges.&nbsp; Do you have a reaction to that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And secondarily, if I can, does the Supreme Court&#8217;s ruling today on an important voting rights decision add to the sense of urgency you feel about pursuing voting rights legislation at this time?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know nothing about the first circumstance because I&#8217;ve been gone.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any idea, so I&#8217;m not going to comment on that.&nbsp; And even if I did, I wouldn&#8217;t comment on an ongoing case if it&#8217;s an ongoing case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to the second point: I think I did get a summary on the way down on the plane of the Supreme Court decision.&nbsp; It is mildly positive, in the sense that there&#8217;s a remedy available based on the particular voting decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think that it is critical that we make a distinction between voter suppression and suspension.&nbsp; The ability of a state legislative body to come along and vote &#8212; their legislature &#8212; vote to change who is declared the winner, I find to be somewhat astounding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the Supreme Court rule did not rule that way today, to the best of my knowledge.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I&#8217;ll have much more to say about that because I plan on speaking extensively on voting rights and &#8212; as well as going on the road on this issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So thank you all very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:44 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/01/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-43/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 03:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 1:36 P.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good afternoon, and thank you for joining us.&#160; Today, we’re joined by Doctors Fauci and Walensky, who I’ll turn to in a few minutes. First, I want to report on the progress we are making to end the COVID-19 pandemic here at home and around the world.&#160; Here&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>1:36 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good afternoon, and thank you for joining us.&nbsp; Today, we’re joined by Doctors Fauci and Walensky, who I’ll turn to in a few minutes.<br><br>First, I want to report on the progress we are making to end the COVID-19 pandemic here at home and around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Here at home, going into the 4th of July holiday weekend, Americans have good reason to celebrate.&nbsp; Thanks to the President&#8217;s whole-of-government response and the American people stepping up, more than 180 million Americans, including 67 percent of adults &#8212; two out of three adult Americans &#8212; have now received at least one shot.&nbsp;<br><br>In cases or death &#8212; deaths are down by more than 90 percent since January 20th.&nbsp; As a result, we have exceeded our expectations for where we would be on July 4th.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re in a strong position to build on this progress going forward.&nbsp;<br><br>This weekend, millions of Americans will be able to get together &#8212; back together, not just with their families and close friends for small backyard cookouts, but with their community for larger festivals, parades, and fireworks, celebrating our country&#8217;s July 4th Independence Day and the progress we have made against the virus together.<br><br>We will celebrate this progress on July 4th.&nbsp; But, of course, our work does not stop &#8212; because as the President has said, our work to vaccinate the millions of Americans who still need protection against the virus continues across the summer months.&nbsp; And our resolve to reach those who have not yet gotten their shot is only strengthened because of the spread of the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>As we push to get more Americans vaccinated, we will also continue mobilizing and leading the effort to vaccinate the world.&nbsp; Earlier this year, the President committed that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world.<br><br>Through historic announcements and actions, we are delivering on the President&#8217;s commitment.&nbsp; Over the past several weeks, the President has committed to sharing 580 million doses of vaccine to the world, including a half billion doses of Pfizer vaccine that the United States will purchase and donate to 100 countries in need.&nbsp;<br><br>This is by far the largest-ever donation of COVID-19 vaccines by a single country.&nbsp; And this historic announcement builds on the prior commitment we made to share 80 million doses of our own surplus U.S. vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>These 80 million doses have all been shared with 46 countries, the African Union, and CARICOM through a combination of bilateral sharing and sharing through COVAX.&nbsp;<br><br>Each country has now received a specific number and type of U.S. vaccines they will be shipped.&nbsp; By the end of this week, we will have shipped out about 40 million doses, including doses to the Republic of Korea, Mexico, Canada, Brazil, Taiwan, Honduras, Colombia, Pakistan, Peru, Ecuador, Malaysia, and Bangladesh.&nbsp;<br><br>The remaining doses will be shipped in the coming weeks as countries complete their own domestic set of operational, regulatory, and legal processes that are specific to each country.&nbsp; These U.S. doses will boost vaccination efforts in these countries and save lives.&nbsp;<br><br>And just as our work to vaccinate Americans does not stop on July 4th, our work to help vaccinate the world does not stop at these 80 million doses.&nbsp; We will continue to share tens of millions more U.S. doses over the summer months as we help lead the fight to end the pandemic across the globe.&nbsp;<br><br>In a few minutes, I will discuss how the Biden administration is mobilizing to support states and communities experienced increasing cases of the Delta variant.<br>But first, let me turn to Dr. Walensky to provide us an update on the state of the pandemic, including the Delta variant, and then Dr. Fauci to discuss the essential role our vaccines are playing in curbing its spread, including the spread of the Delta variant.<br><br>With that, over to you Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp; Yesterday, CDC reported 14,875 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is about 12,600 cases per day.&nbsp; And while this is a 95 percent decrease, lower from our peak in early January, it does also reflect a 10 percent increase in the seven-day average from last week.&nbsp; The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 1,822 per day, a decrease of about 1 percent from the prior seven-day period.&nbsp; And the seven-day average of daily deaths was about 257.<br><br>Looking across the country, we have made incredible progress towards ending the pandemic.&nbsp; We continue to see overall low numbers of cases, hospitalizations, and deaths.&nbsp; However, looking state by state and county by county, it is clear that communities where people remain unvaccinated are communities that remain vulnerable.&nbsp; This is all true as we monitor the continued spread of the hyper-transmissible Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>The Delta variant is predicted to be the second most prevalent variant in the United States, and I expect that in the coming weeks it will eclipse the alpha variant.&nbsp; An estimated 25 percent of all reported SARS-CoV-2 sequences nationwide are the Delta variant.&nbsp; And in some regions of the country, nearly one in two sequences is the Delta variant.<br><br>There are communities that are vulnerable and where we are now seeing surges in cases, and indeed also hospitalizations, due to what could be the spread of the Delta variant and low vaccination rates in these communities.<br><br>Currently, approximately 1,000 counties in the United States have vaccination coverage of less than 30 percent.&nbsp; These communities, primarily in the Southeast and Midwest, are our most vulnerable.&nbsp; In some of these areas, we are already seeing increasing rates of disease.&nbsp; As the Delta variant continues to spread across the country, we expect to see increased transmissions in these communities, unless we can vaccinate more people now.<br><br>As you will hear from Dr. Fauci shortly, our authorized vaccines provide protection against the circulating variants in this country, including Delta.&nbsp; Vaccination is how we protect these individuals, families, and communities, and prevent severe disease, hospitalizations, and deaths from COVID-19.<br><br>Preliminary data from a collection of states over the last six months suggest 99.5 percent of deaths from COVID-19 in these states have occurred in unvaccinated people.&nbsp;<br><br>Any suffering or death from COVID-19 is tragic.&nbsp; With vaccines available across the country, the suffering and loss we are now seeing is nearly entirely avoidable.&nbsp; COVID-19 [vaccines] are available and free for everyone aged 12 and up, and I encourage everyone who has not been vaccinated, especially those in these vulnerable communities with low vaccine coverage, to roll up their sleeves and get vaccinated.<br><br>As we prepare to celebrate Independence Day, I want to remind those who remain unvaccinated to protect themselves by wearing a mask and avoiding crowds to prevent transmission and illness.&nbsp; If you have symptoms of COVID-19, please get tested.&nbsp; And, of course, please get vaccinated in one of the many places near you as soon as you can.<br><br>Please enjoy a safe family- and friend-filled holiday weekend.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; What I&#8217;d like to do over the next couple of minutes is to address the issue of the role of the COVID-19 vaccines that we have available to us and their ability to protect against the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>If I could have the first slide.<br><br>It is simple &#8212; simplified to think about it in three separate buckets: What is the protection against infection,&nbsp;against symptomatic disease, or against hospitalization?&nbsp; And we have data for all three.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>First, in a study published online on June 14, from Scotland, it was shown that the mRNA vaccine had about an 80 percent effectiveness against PCR-confirmed infection.&nbsp; In this situation, two doses of AZ was about 60 percent effective.<br><br>Next, with regard &#8212; next slide &#8212; to symptomatic disease: Again, in this study, in medRxiv, published on May 21st &#8212; 24th &#8212; two weeks after the second dose of Pfizer BioNTech vaccine, again, 88 percent effective against symptomatic disease from the Delta variant.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Next, what about hospitalization?&nbsp; Again, from Public Health England, from June 14, the Pfizer BioNTech vaccine was 96 percent effective against hospitalization from the Delta variant after two doses, and the AZ was 92 percent effective against hospitalization after two doses.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>The question then obviously arises: The direct data we have are from AZ and the mRNA vaccines; what about J&amp;J?&nbsp; A question often asked.&nbsp; There&#8217;s indirect evidence for effectiveness of J&amp;J against the SARS-CoV-2 Delta variant.&nbsp; And the reason is that the effectiveness of this vaccine is similar to a vaccine for which we do have data, namely the AZ &#8212; the data that I just showed you.&nbsp;<br><br>Since these vaccines &#8212; the AZ and the J&amp;J &#8212; are based on very similar platforms, one could anticipate and make a reasonable assumption that the results against the Delta variant would be at least similar, perhaps even better.&nbsp; We are now looking at neutralization data, and soon we will have more firm data which we will we make available to you as soon as it occurs.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Another question commonly asked: Is the WHO concerned about the Delta variant &#8212; has urged vaccinated people to keep wearing masks?&nbsp; There&#8217;s a reason for that.&nbsp; The WHO is responsible for the planet as a whole.&nbsp; It&#8217;s different in the world in general, from here in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>As shown here, if you look at the share of the population fully vaccinated in the United States and worldwide, they&#8217;re dramatically different, as is the dynamics of infection.&nbsp; And as we&#8217;ve always said, you can make general guidelines, but you also have to be flexible enough at various levels &#8212; be it a country level, or within a country at local levels.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Bottom line and finally, the good news we have is that we have a solution.&nbsp; The science is clear.&nbsp; The best way to protect yourself against the virus and its variants is to be fully vaccinated.&nbsp; It works.&nbsp; It&#8217;s free.&nbsp; It&#8217;s safe.&nbsp; It&#8217;s easy.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s convenient, as President Biden has said in a speech in North Carolina just several days ago.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll pass it back to Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; As both Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci just made clear, the Delta variant is a threat to unvaccinated Americans and to communities with low vaccination rates.&nbsp; And the best way for communities to protect themselves from the virus is by getting more people vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>From day one, the President&#8217;s whole-of-government response effort has been closely tracking the data on the pandemic and vaccination effort in states and counties.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve worked with governors and local public health officials to ensure they have the support they need to curb the spread of the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, given what we are seeing with the spread of Delta in some communities in the country, we&#8217;re intensifying our efforts to help states prevent, detect, and respond to hotspots among the unvaccinated by mobilizing COVID-19 surge response teams to be at the ready to deploy federal resources and, where needed, federal personnel.&nbsp;<br><br>These are dedicated teams working with communities at higher risk for or already experiencing outbreaks due to the spread of the Delta variant and their low vaccination rate.&nbsp;<br><br>Our COVID-19 surge response teams will be ready to, one, surge additional testing into communities to expand detection of the virus and allow public health authorities to do contact tracing to help contain outbreaks.&nbsp;<br><br>Two, provide therapeutics to help treat those infected with COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>Three, deploy federal personnel where needed and where requested to address gaps and augment local staff supporting vaccination, testing, and therapeutics work.<br><br>Four, leverage CDC&#8217;s technical expertise to help communities experiencing or at risk for becoming hotspots with containment, including assisting with epidemiology, data analysis, field investigations, and other public health response work.<br><br>And five, as Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky have both underscored, the most important step we can take to prevent these outbreaks is for more Americans to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the COVID-19 surge response teams will focus on increasing shots in arms in communities with low vaccination rates who are fighting outbreaks, including through targeted paid media into these areas.<br><br>To be clear: The federal government stands ready to meet the moment and work with our state partners to respond to the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>And as we continue to work with communities across the country to get more shots in arms, we will also be working with governors and state and local health authorities to identify and address the needs on the ground in places with emerging outbreaks, including potential deployment of federal personnel.&nbsp;<br><br>Before we open up to questions, I want to close with this thought: Thanks to the President&#8217;s whole-of-government response, we are further in our fight against the virus than anyone anticipated.&nbsp; And importantly, in the weeks and months ahead, we will continue mobilizing the whole of government to help state and local leaders bring an end to this pandemic by doubling down to get even more Americans vaccinated and stopping the spread as soon as possible when cases do increase.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, let&#8217;s open it up for some questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks Jeff.&nbsp; And a reminder to please keep questions to one question.&nbsp; First, we&#8217;ll going to Yamiche at PBS.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for taking my question.&nbsp; What are &#8212;&nbsp; can you tell us more about whether or not Americans may be having to go back to wearing masks in light of the Delta variant?&nbsp; We saw Los Angeles County and the WHO both recommending that even vaccinated people should wear masks.&nbsp; Where does that stand?&nbsp; Should people be preparing themselves to possibly going back to wearing masks if they&#8217;re vaccinated?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, as I was alluding to in my comments, you have a broad recommendation for the country as a whole, which is the CDC recommendation, that if you are vaccinated, you have a high degree of protection so you need not wear a mask either indoor or outdoor.&nbsp;<br><br>But also, as is said and as the CDC has recommended, is that there&#8217;s a degree of flexibility.&nbsp; People at the local level, depending upon the on-ground situation, will make recommendations or not according to the local situation.&nbsp; But the broad recommendation that the CDC makes, based on the high degree of effectiveness of the vaccine, remains unchanged.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Sharon LaFraniere at the New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, I wanted to ask: Why is the data on whether J&amp;J works against the Delta variant lagging behind the data for other vaccines?&nbsp; And what do you make of reports that J&amp;J recipients are now asking for Pfizer and Moderna doses as boosters?&nbsp; Do you recommend that?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, first of all, the reason is the paucity of direct clinical trial data in the context of Delta variant.&nbsp; So you have a much, much more wider use globally of the mRNAs in situations in which you can actually make data-based statements on that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the reason why I show that slide &#8212; that, from the standpoint of data right now, you have to make an extrapolation based on what you would predict from what it does with other variants and what it does comparable to other vaccine products such as AZ.&nbsp;<br><br>With regard to the idea of boosting: There&#8217;s a lot of talk about that, but right now I think we still need to remember that, in fact, the J&amp;J vaccine is a highly effective vaccine that has been recommended very clearly and has received an emergency use authorization.&nbsp;<br><br>The situation right now is that people, locally, will be making those kinds of decisions, but you should only be making a formal recommendation based on clinical data.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s the reason why, even though individual physicians will be doing that, from a clinical trial basis, there&#8217;s no real fundamental scientific reason to do that right now.&nbsp;<br><br>When those data become available, you will see recommendations change according to the data.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Meg Tirrell at CNBC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: You know, some folks have pointed to the vaccines still being under emergency use authorization as perhaps one reason that people may still be on the fence about getting them.&nbsp; Do you have any guidance about when you expect potential full approval &#8212; the process to kind of come to fruition for these vaccines? &nbsp;When would &#8212; might we see that from the FDA?&nbsp;<br><br>And a quick second follow-up.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; But, Dr. Walensky, are you concerned about, as people are taking their masks off and starting to circulate more, the rise of other respiratory infections other than COVID that you&#8217;re seeing right now?&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So why don&#8217;t we start with the second one, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Meg.&nbsp; You know, I think we saw actually a paucity of viral infections last year.&nbsp; Many of our pediatricians would say that they didn&#8217;t see a lot of people coming in with upper respiratory infections.&nbsp; I do think part of that was the distancing, the not being in school, and of course, the masking.&nbsp;<br><br>I do anticipate that in the months ahead, if people are not wearing masks &#8212; and we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; started to see some of this already &#8212; that there will likely be an increase of upper respiratory infections in places that are not wearing masks.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, in terms of the emergency use authorization and moving toward full approval, that&#8217;s at the FDA, and that&#8217;s obviously the FDA’s decision to make.&nbsp; I know that Pfizer and Moderna have provided data to the FDA, and the FDA is working on an expedited timeframe.<br><br>But, Dr. Fauci, you might want to just talk about the experience we have with the vaccines &#8212; the hundreds of millions &#8212; and what that should tell people about their safety and efficacy.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; You know, as always, we don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the FDA.&nbsp; You know, they have their process where they need to cross all the &#8220;T&#8217;s&#8221; and dot all the &#8220;i&#8217;s.&#8221;&nbsp; But if you look at the history of emergency use authorizations, they use for a wide range of emergency approval of interventions, often the criteria is: Does the benefit appear to be better than the risk involved?<br><br>Very infrequently do you have such an extraordinary amount of data of literally hundreds of millions of doses, and a lot of real-world effectiveness data, as well as safety, having been accumulated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, although it&#8217;s understandable how some people would say, “Well, we really want to wait to the full approval,” to have an emergency authorization and to have this amount of extraordinarily positive data, one would say &#8212; again, the caveat: You never want to get ahead of the FDA &#8212; but it would really be a most unusual situation not to see this get full approval.&nbsp; I believe it&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp;<br><br>The timing is such that I hope it does not get people to hesitate from taking a potentially lifesaving vaccine that already has an extraordinary amount of data as to its real-world effectiveness and its safety.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Tamara Keith, at NPR.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; My question is &#8212; I noticed that as you talked about the next steps and the next phase, you&#8217;re talking about these surge response teams going into states.&nbsp; Is that the next phase of this push?&nbsp; Is it more focused on the states?<br><br>You talked a lot &#8212; your language talked about states asking the federal government for help.&nbsp; At this point, is this shifting from Cabinet officials barnstorming the country, begging people to get vaccinated, to, &#8220;Welp, states, you figure it out&#8221;?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Not at all.&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; This &#8212; the surge response teams are important to be ready to work with, where called upon, states and counties that are in a situation where there&#8217;s fewer people vaccinated and cases are increasing.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s capabilities that we&#8217;ve had in place that we&#8217;re amping up to deal with the Delta variant.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s an important area of focus.&nbsp;<br><br>But even as vaccinations have slowed somewhat across the last month or so, we are still vaccinating millions of people each week.&nbsp; More than 2 million people each week in June have gotten their first shot, and millions more, importantly, are getting their second shot because Dr. Fauci&#8217;s data on the effectiveness &#8212; that&#8217;s about people getting their second shot, their full regimen.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ll double down on these efforts as we continue to vaccinate millions of people across the summer months.&nbsp; So this whole-of-government wartime response continues.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working, more and more, person by person, community by community &#8212; meeting people where they are: in places of worship, deploying pop-up clinics and mobile clinics.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to answer people&#8217;s questions, as we&#8217;ve talked about before.&nbsp;<br><br>Doctors are critical here.&nbsp; They are trusted messengers, and we are getting vaccines more and more into doctors&#8217; offices.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll work with employers and schools to bring vaccines on site as people go back to school and back to work.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, throughout all of our efforts, equity and fairness will continue to be at the center.&nbsp; So this whole-of-federal-government, wartime-like approach &#8212; it continues.&nbsp; And the surge response teams are just another approach, given the Delta variant and the time that we find ourselves in.&nbsp;<br><br>Last question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Andrea Shalal at Reuters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for taking my question.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky, I want to ask you a question that I asked at the White House briefing recently.&nbsp; Does it send a bad signal &#8212; given what we&#8217;re seeing now, in terms of the Delta variant and these increases in certain communities &#8212; that, in Washington, the nation&#8217;s capital, there&#8217;s going to be a large party at the White House on July 4th and there&#8217;s going to be fireworks on the National Mall?&nbsp; I mean, is that a little bit of a mixed signal, on one hand, to be sending to the country at this point?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Let me go first there.&nbsp; And then, Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky, please chime in.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the Fourth of July is a moment for us to step back and celebrate our progress.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made tremendous progress in our fight against the virus, with now two out of three adult Americans with at least one shot.&nbsp; And directly because of this work, deaths and hospitalizations have fallen 90 percent since January 20th.&nbsp;<br><br>The American people should be proud of the work that we&#8217;ve collectively done, and we want to recognize that progress and that work on July 4th.<br><br>People who are vaccinated have a high degree of protection, and those who are not vaccinated are at risk.&nbsp; And they need to continue to wear a mask and, as the doctors have said, get vaccinated as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, as we just talked about, there&#8217;s a lot more work to do.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to double down on our efforts to keep pushing more and more people to get vaccinated by making it, as Dr. Fauci said, easy.&nbsp; Lots of places to get vaccinated.&nbsp; It&#8217;s free.&nbsp; It&#8217;s convenient.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;re going to keep doing that, but, right now, it&#8217;s an appropriate time to step back and celebrate the progress we&#8217;ve made.&nbsp; At the same time, we&#8217;ve got a lot more work to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Dr. Fauci?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, Jeff, you said it very well.&nbsp; I mean, nothing has really changed in our policy.&nbsp; You&#8217;re dealing with the &#8212; a very important national holiday.&nbsp; The country, as a whole, as I&#8217;ve mentioned and we have mentioned several times, has done very well.&nbsp;<br><br>You can still celebrate at the same time as you get your message very, very clear.&nbsp; And the message for the situation in Washington is the same, and you said it very well.&nbsp; That is: If you are vaccinated, you have a high degree of protection.&nbsp; If you are not, you should wear a mask and you should think very seriously about getting vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in so many respects, nothing has really changed.&nbsp; We are celebrating, as a country, at the same time as we recognize the fact that we&#8217;re in a serious situation for those who have not been vaccinated.&nbsp; And the message is: Get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s close on: Get vaccinated if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, and happy Fourth of July weekend to everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>We look forward to seeing everybody next week.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:04 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_1July2021_for-transcript.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_1July2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh of Vietnam</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-deputy-prime-minister-pham-binh-minh-of-vietnam/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Vietnamese Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh. Mr. Sullivan emphasized the United States’ commitment to our comprehensive partnership with Vietnam, and discussed ways to deepen cooperation between the two countries in areas such as maritime security, the Mekong region, combatting climate change, and ending the COVID-19 pandemic.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Vietnamese Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh. Mr. Sullivan emphasized the United States’ commitment to our comprehensive partnership with Vietnam, and discussed ways to deepen cooperation between the two countries in areas such as maritime security, the Mekong region, combatting climate change, and ending the COVID-19 pandemic. Mr. Sullivan underscored the Biden-Harris administration’s commitment to ASEAN centrality and ASEAN’s essential role in the Indo-Pacific architecture and pledged that the administration would continue to engage at a high-level with Vietnam and partners throughout the region. Mr. Sullivan and Deputy Prime Minster Minh also discussed the South China Sea, including the United States’ support for the 2016 arbitral tribunal award. Additionally, Mr. Sullivan conveyed President Biden’s concern over the dire humanitarian and human rights situation in Ethiopia’s Tigray region and the urgent need for the UN Security Council to marshal support to address ongoing famine conditions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/u-s-covid-19-global-response-and-recovery-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 23:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More than&#160;600,000&#160;of our fellow Americans,&#160;and nearly 4 million people globally,&#160;have died due to COVID-19. The devastating impact of the pandemic has been felt at home and abroad, triggering health and economic crises. Globally, we are witnessing the first&#160;wide scale&#160;increase in extreme poverty in more than twenty years, the loss of decades of development progress,&#160;increases in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>More than&nbsp;600,000&nbsp;of our fellow Americans,&nbsp;and nearly 4 million people globally,&nbsp;have died due to COVID-19. The devastating impact of the pandemic has been felt at home and abroad, triggering health and economic crises. Globally, we are witnessing the first&nbsp;wide scale&nbsp;increase in extreme poverty in more than twenty years, the loss of decades of development progress,&nbsp;increases in gender-based violence,&nbsp;rising food insecurity, and increased unemployment—particularly among young people and women.&nbsp;Even as we gain confidence in&nbsp;United States (U.S.)&nbsp;domestic COVID-19 vaccination coverage, none of us are safe until all of us are safe. The risk of emergent, dangerous variants where COVID-19 transmission remains high poses a risk to us all.&nbsp; This disease knows no borders.</p>



<p>The U.S. will work with our partners to intensify the fight against COVID-19 around the world, pave the way to global recovery, and build back better national and global health security. Our first goal is to end the pandemic—at home and abroad. On January 21, 2021, President Biden released the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/National-Strategy-for-the-COVID-19-Response-and-Pandemic-Preparedness.pdf">National Strategy for the COVID-19 Response and  Pandemic Preparedness</a>, including Goal 7, which details the Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive plan to restore U.S. leadership globally and build better preparedness for future threats; re-engage with the World Health Organization (WHO) and seek to strengthen and reform it; urge the international COVID-19 public health and humanitarian response; restore U.S. leadership to the international COVID-19 response and advance global health security and diplomacy; and build better biopreparedness and expand resilience for biological threats.</p>



<p>In support of that strategy, the&nbsp;U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework&nbsp;provides a focused set of objectives and lines of effort under which U.S. departments of agencies are executing a whole-of-government response.&nbsp; This response&nbsp;aims to shorten the lifespan of and ultimately end the COVID-19 pandemic globally; mitigate its wider harms to people and economies and support the global recovery; and build back better to strengthen international readiness for future biological threats.&nbsp;The U.S. Government will pursue five objectives under the U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework that together constitute a comprehensive approach to managing the immediate global health crisis and ending the pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework<sup>&nbsp;</sup>also supports U.S. commitments to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/11/fact-sheet-united-states-and-g7-plan-to-defeat-the-covid-19-pandemic-in-2022-and-prevent-the-next-pandemic/">G7<sup>+</sup>&nbsp;Plan to Defeat the COVID-19 Pandemic in 2022 and Prevent the Next Pandemic</a>&nbsp;by supporting vaccination of the world’s most vulnerable populations, supporting last mile vaccination and getting shots in arms, providing personal protective equipment (PPE) and medical supplies where needed, strengthening supply, improving disease surveillance and early warning, supporting recovery, building resilience, and advancing global health security.</p>



<p>Read the full framework here:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/U.S.-COVID-19-Global-Response-and-Recovery-Framework.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/U.S.-COVID-19-Global-Response-and-Recovery-Framework.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/2021-annual-report-to-congress-on-white-house-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since 1995, the White House has been required to deliver a report to Congress listing the title and salary of every White House Office employee. Consistent with President Biden’s commitment to transparency, this report is being publicly disclosed on our website as it is transmitted to Congress. 2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since 1995, the White House has been required to deliver a report to Congress listing the title and salary of every White House Office employee. Consistent with President Biden’s commitment to transparency, this report is being publicly disclosed on our website as it is transmitted to Congress.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/July-1-2021-Report-Final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House Staff</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before a Command Briefing from Incident Commander Mayor Daniella Levine Cava, Governor Ron DeSantis, Local Leaders, and First Responders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/01/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-command-briefing-from-incident-commander-mayor-daniella-levine-cava-governor-ron-desantis-local-leaders-and-first-responders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 18:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[St. Regis HotelMiami, Florida 10:41 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  (In progress) &#8212; and I’ve got to say that, you know, having been to, unfortunately, a lot of &#8212; like many of us have &#8212; a lot of disaster sites because of natural disasters, it&#8217;s &#8212; what you&#8217;re doing, in coordination among you all, has been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">St. Regis Hotel<br>Miami, Florida<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">10:41 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (In progress) &#8212; and I’ve got to say that, you know, having been to, unfortunately, a lot of &#8212; like many of us have &#8212; a lot of disaster sites because of natural disasters, it&#8217;s &#8212; what you&#8217;re doing, in coordination among you all, has been just admirable.  It really is impressive.<br><br>And so I just want to say thanks and listen and find out what I can do as President and what I can unleash, in terms of help, for whatever you need.<br><br>The governor and the mayor have been completely open with me, asked whatever they &#8212; whatever they&#8217;ve asked, I think we’ve been able to deliver.  And I think there’s more that we can do, including &#8212; I think I have the power &#8212; and we’ll know shortly &#8212; to be able to pick up 100 percent of the cost for the county and the state for 30 days.<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  Oh, my goodness, Mr. President.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I think I’m quite sure I can do that.  And so we’re going to do that. <br><br>And there’s going to be a lot &#8212; you all know it because a lot of you have been through it as well &#8212; there’s going to be a lot of pain and anxiety and suffering and even a need for psychological help in the days and months that follow.<br><br>And so, we’re not going anywhere.<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, for real.  But, again, I just want to, you know, start the day, if I could, getting as thorough briefing as you’re able to give me, and tell me what you need.  And that goes for both the senators and the congresswoman and anyone in Florida, just to pick up the phone to the Oval.  For real.  I’m not joking about it. <br><br>And I think the Gov will tell you &#8212; anything you ask for, we got.  And we have another group of teams coming from FEMA today.  How many people will it be?<br><br>PARTICIPANT:  At the end of the day, there should about 500 on the ground.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Five hundred on the ground.<br><br>So, again, this is your show.  We just want to make sure that whatever you need &#8212; and, you know, including &#8212; well, anyway, I’m talking too much.  Why don’t I &#8212; I want to hear from you guys.<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  All right.  Well, Mr. President, we cannot thank you enough for being here with us, for showing your extraordinary support from day one.  You called me that morning.  We hustled into a little room in the Family Reunification Center so I could take the call, and you said whatever we need.  And I said, “Bring FEMA,” and here they are, on the ground.<br><br>So it’s been an incredible collaboration from the beginning, with the federal, with the state.  We had our Florida Emergency Management Director, Kevin Guthrie, here immediately.  The governor has been here every single day.  The senators, I believe, the same, and our state and municipal leaders as well.<br><br>So the collaboration from the elected leadership to the police departments; all the municipals, of course, under the leadership of our incredible Miami-Dade Police Department, and Freddy Ramirez, our director; and, without a doubt, the fire department and our chief &#8212; our Fire Chief, Alan Cominsky, who has led the effort of these first responders who are in the &#8212; in the world&#8217;s hands.  <br><br>Everybody is praying and watching these incredible men and women as they proceed, day after day, and literally have to be pulled off the pile, Mr. President.  They are here to save lives.  That is what they live for.  And it is truly &#8212; it is truly humbling.<br><br>So, we all know this is an unprecedented devastating disaster unlike anyone has ever seen.  It&#8217;s shocked the world.  And the fact that we&#8217;ve all come together is what gives us hope, is what gives us strength and inspiration; it does for me every single day &#8212; as we talk to the family members, as you&#8217;ll soon be doing, as they are waiting and waiting for news of their loved ones, as you said, and also those who have been displaced.  I mean, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s just a crisis all around.<br><br>But we are working together to handle the crisis to get the answers about what happened here.  And we can update you on that.  And we are going to be examining every inch of this catastrophe with the full might of the federal, state, and local government to do so.<br><br>So, we want to make sure we all &#8212; the world wants to make sure that a tragedy of this nature never, ever happens again.<br><br>So, I &#8212; we have a briefing for you.  And I want to start with our governor.  And I want to thank you, Governor DeSantis.  Your team has been amazing, but you personally have been amazing.  You&#8217;ve been a steady, calming, reassuring, but forceful voice every step of the way.  And it&#8217;s been a pleasure to partner with you, truly.  Thank you.  Thank you.<br><br>GOVERNOR DESANTIS:  Thank you.  Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Let me say just one more thing.  You know what&#8217;s good about this &#8212; the way you&#8217;ve cooperated?  We&#8217;re letting the nation know we can cooperate. <br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  Yes, sir.  That&#8217;s right. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And when it&#8217;s really important &#8212;<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  That&#8217;s right. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  &#8212; when it&#8217;s really important &#8212; I was talking to Debbie about it on the way down &#8212; we come together.  This is &#8212; this is life and death. <br><br>And so, I don&#8217;t think &#8212; I just got back from about 12 days in Europe.  They wondered whether we can do this.  And you&#8217;re doing it.  I mean, just the simple act of everybody doing whatever needs to be done is a &#8212; and it really makes a difference, Gov. <br><br>GOVERNOR DESANTIS:  Well, thank you, Mr. President.  And you’ve recognized the severity of this tragedy from day one.  And you&#8217;ve been very supportive. <br><br>We, in Florida &#8212; you know, you&#8217;ll drive up and down these coastal roads, you&#8217;ll see these buildings.  And I&#8217;ve driven by that building; probably never thought twice.  And then something like this happens and you recognize in each individual unit there&#8217;s an amazing story. <br><br>And lives have been shattered irrevocably as a result of this.  We&#8217;ve already identified, unfortunately, fatalities &#8212; people who&#8217;ve been 92 years old, have been a matriarch of a wonderful family.  We have families with kids missing.  And we even have young newlyweds who hadn&#8217;t even been married a year who were in the tower when it collapsed.<br><br>And so the cooperation has been great.  The local &#8212; both the municipal and the county have been fantastic.  And you guys have not only been supportive at the federal level, but we&#8217;ve had no bureaucracy.  When we&#8217;re dealing with FEMA, we&#8217;re literally getting requests routed from local to state to federal in no time &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I promise you, there will be none.<br><br>GOVERNOR DESANTIS:  &#8212; and the approval is happening.  Yeah.<br><br>And so that &#8212; that really, I think, is important.  And so we’ve had people &#8212; this is the first response in Florida’s history, outside of a hurricane, where all of our search-and-rescue teams were mobilized.  So they’ve been going in and out of the rubble, searching, trying to find people, trying to rescue people &#8212; at a minimum, trying to identify anyone who may be deceased to bring closure to the families, which is very important. <br><br>But they’re tired, and this has taken a toll on them.  And so, the fact that we now have that search-and-rescue team from Virginia here &#8212; and I know we have some more on the way &#8212; that’s going to be helpful because this is grueling. <br><br>And obviously, the families’ lives have been shattered.  Mental health is going to be important.  We’re going to need some mental health support for some of the folks who’ve been in that rubble because it’s not easy to do. <br><br>And &#8212; but we thank you for the support.  And we do appreciate the collaboration for local, state, and federal. <br><br>And, you know, what we just need now is we need a little bit of luck, we need a little bit of prayers, and, you know, we would like to be able to see some miracles happen. <br><br>But I can tell you this: We’re not going to stop until we identify everybody and until we do what we need to do.  So, thank you, Mr. President.<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  Thank you, Mr. President.  I want to acknowledge the leadership of the First Lady, Casey DeSantis, as well, who is very, very focused on children and mental health issues and is bringing that agenda to our discussions.  And, of course, we’ve been including all of that, as you&#8217;ll learn from the briefings.  But we know how important First Ladies are, so we just wanted to be sure to give a shout out.<br><br>(The press is escorted out of the briefing.)<br><br>10:52 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Miami, FL</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/01/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-miami-fl/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Miami, Florida 8:55 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Okay, good morning.&#160; Today in Surfside, the President and the First Lady will receive a command briefing from Incident Commander Mayor Daniella Levine Cava, Governor Ron DeSantis, and Unified Command on the current status of the search-and-rescue efforts and the federal, state, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Miami, Florida</p>



<p>8:55 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, good morning.&nbsp; Today in Surfside, the President and the First Lady will receive a command briefing from Incident Commander Mayor Daniella Levine Cava, Governor Ron DeSantis, and Unified Command on the current status of the search-and-rescue efforts and the federal, state, and local resources being deployed as part of the response.&nbsp; Then they will thank the heroic first responders, search-and-rescue teams, and everyone who has been working around the clock for their tireless work.</p>



<p>The President and the First Lady will meet with the families who have been forced to endure this terrible tragedy to offer them comfort during this unimaginable, difficult time as search-and-rescue efforts continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the end of the day, the President will deliver remarks on the tragedy, how he and the nation stand with the families and survivors, and the federal government&#8217;s response efforts in coordination with our state and local partners.</p>



<p>On those efforts: As of 6:00 a.m. this morning, FEMA has deployed over 60 FEMA staff to support response efforts in Sunrise, Florida.&nbsp; FEMA is also deploying an additional 400 personnel across five urban search-and-rescue teams to assist with ongoing operation at the request of local officials.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each of the &#8212; each of the urban search-and-rescue team has 80 personnel, and all five deployed US&amp;R teams will arrive on site and be operational today.&nbsp; Two additional urban <s>and research</s> [search and] rescue teams are on standby to rapidly deploy and provide relief to the first responders who are working tireless &#8212; tirelessly if needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last evening, FEMA awarded more than $20 million in federal funding to the Florida Division of Emergency Management for Emergency Protective Measures.&nbsp; Given the circumstances and the unprecedented response underway, led by the state &#8212; by state and local officials, FEMA expedited this request for funding from the state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These funds will support the state and local governments&#8217; on-going, unbudgeted costs to conduct rescue operations.&nbsp; This additional fund &#8212; federal support from FEMA is authorized under the emergency declaration the President approved to coordinate disaster relief efforts, reimburse response costs, provide equipment and resources to assist with debris removal and emergency protective measures in order to try to save lives, and to provide temporary shelter and housing to alleviate the hardship and suffering for those who have been displaced.</p>



<p>With that, Alex, you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;&nbsp; Most Florida counties don&#8217;t require condo inspections.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if the President believes that there needs to be a change in local or federal policy to require more inspections and to prevent future situations like this from occurring?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll say this, the National Institute of Standards and Technology &#8212; NIST &#8212; announced last night that they&#8217;re launching a full investigation into what caused the partial collapse of the Champlain Towers South building.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>So, as you know, the President supported an investigation in order to <s>undermine</s> [understand] what caused the terrible tragedy and ensure nothing like it ever happened again.&nbsp; </a>So, we look forward to NIST&#8217;s conclusions once the investigation is complete.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to see what the investigation shows, and that will answer, hopefully, some questions that we all have on what happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s reaction to the CFO of the Trump Organization being indicted in New York?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, that&#8217;s &#8212; so, at this moment, I &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve seen the coverage, clearly, for the past 12 hours or so.&nbsp; But I refer you to the parties involved by any further &#8212; for any further comment.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to comment on any specific case at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And generally, this &#8212; the President, you know, believes and has made clear that he &#8212; it&#8217;s long past due for wealthiest Americans to pay their fair share.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s announced a number of initiatives to crack down on tax evasion by high-income individuals and big corporations.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t have anything further to say on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he think fringe benefits is a serious enough issue to justify going after the organization of a former President?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have anything to say about &#8212; about this particular case at all.&nbsp; I refer you to the authorities that are a part of this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; It sounds like you&#8217;re saying &#8212; you&#8217;re not &#8212; are you suggesting there was something improper?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is &#8212; what I&#8217;m saying is, in general, the President believes that the wealthiest among us should pay their fair share.&nbsp; And we see that in policies and legislation that he&#8217;s put forward, when we talk about the American Jobs Plan, the American Families Plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, he truly believes, as he&#8217;s &#8212; as we look at his economic policy &#8212; that everyone should pay their fair share, especially the wealthiest among us.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re saying.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not commenting at all on the particular investigation.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying, in general.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do you know if he paid his fair share?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying this is what he believes, in general.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, does the President today want to get a sense of how the building collapsed, what factors led to the collapse?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, like I said, there&#8217;s going to be an investigation that was announced last night.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to see how that goes and let the &#8212; let the invest- &#8212; let NI- &#8212; NIST, the experts there, do their investigation, and we&#8217;ll see where that takes us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, to just reiterate: The President’s goal today, his message today &#8212; and the First Lady &#8212; is to go there and to give &#8212; offer up comfort to the families, thank the first responders for their tireless effort.&nbsp; They’ve been working 24/7, around the clock, with this search-and-rescue effort.&nbsp; And so he wanted to go there to be &#8212; to thank them and also to send a message of unity to show how state, local, and federal government are coming together in this time, especially this time of tragedy for the community.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything he wants to hear from Governor DeSantis while he&#8217;s there?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, he&#8217;s going to be &#8212; he&#8217;s going to be meeting with Governor DeSantis when he lands.&nbsp; They &#8212; we have been &#8212; the President and the governor talked on the phone on Friday, and so the White House and FEMA have been in close contact with the governor&#8217;s team to coordinate federal assistance throughout the entire process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we&#8217;re &#8212; what the President wants to do is continue to offer whatever assistance that we may provide.&nbsp; I just listed out what we &#8212; what FEMA announced last night &#8212; what we continue to do to help the community, to help the state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s going to be the focus of today: How &#8212; what &#8212; how can we offer up comfort?&nbsp; What else can we do?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just a message of unity to be there for the people, for the community.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a question on the schedule.&nbsp; Are we actually going to the site of the building collapse?&nbsp; Or will we be &#8212; is the President going to be meeting with the first responders in Surfside, but not at that location?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, right now, as you can imagine, things have been &#8212; things have been kind of moving in the last &#8212; the last couple of hours, because we want to make sure that we don&#8217;t take away any resources and we do this in a safe way.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ll have more updates on that for you all later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, as you know, he&#8217;s going to be meeting with the first responders.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to be meeting with the family.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll &#8212; guys, we’ll let you know more of what else that looks like as for the day.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaker Pelosi was at the White House yesterday, obviously, for the bill signing.&nbsp; Did she and the President have a chance to discuss some of the legislative strategy forward on the bipartisan bill, on the reconciliation package?&nbsp; And would he encourage her to delink those, as he&#8217;s been asked to on several occasions by some of the Republicans?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I’ll say this: I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; any conversation to provide to all of you that he had with &#8212; you know, any private conversation that he had with the Speaker.&nbsp; He trusts the Speaker.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; He supports the Speaker.&nbsp; And she&#8217;s &#8212; she&#8217;s been a tremendous leader and partner over these past several months.</p>



<p>And so, as far as the process, when it comes to the bipartisan infrastructure framework, he leads that &#8212; he leaves that process to Congress.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to do what he did in Wisconsin, which is talk to the American people about the important elements of that framework.</p>



<p>As you know &#8212; we&#8217;ve said this over and over again &#8212; it is a historic investment in our country and infrastructure.&nbsp; And so, this is an agreement that he&#8217;s very proud of, and he&#8217;s going to continue to talk about it and work closely with Congress on getting it done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There were some questions yesterday about whether the elements of the hard infrastructure that are included in the bipartisan compromise preclude the White House from pushing for further elements of his Jobs Plan in the reconciliation package.</p>



<p>Jen, yesterday, said he will continue to advocate for the full package.&nbsp; But can you be clear about whether that includes pushing for more funding for some of these areas in the reconciliation package?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Like Jen said, he&#8217;s going to continue advocating aggressively.&nbsp; This is &#8212; you know, these are legis- &#8212; what he put forth in his legislative priorities this year is something that he is &#8212; he is committed to and will continue to push for them.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll do that in the reconciliation package.&nbsp;&nbsp; And some of the things that &#8212; you know, that were left out of the package, including incentive rebates for electric vehicles; clean energy tax credit; and the components of his American Families Plan, including extension of the Child Tax Credit, universal pre-K, ensuring community college is a real option for millions of Americans.</p>



<p>So he&#8217;s going to continue pushing what he believes in is incredibly important and that&#8217;s going to help the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, can I ask about the timing of today&#8217;s visit?&nbsp; Because you all have spoken about the concerns about taking resources away from an ongoing search-and-rescue effort.&nbsp; So &#8212; and, I mean, the incident was relatively recent.&nbsp; So why today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so, you know, we have been in regular consultation with state government and the mayor&#8217;s office since &#8212; since early this morning.&nbsp; And I know it&#8217;s like, what, eight o&#8217;clock in the morning, right now &#8212; it&#8217;s still early &#8212; but we have.</p>



<p>And the message that we&#8217;ve been given is very clear from the mayor&#8217;s office, from the governor&#8217;s office, from local official, which is, like, they wanted us to come today.&nbsp; Now is the time to come to offer up, you know, some &#8212; offer up comfort and show unity and from &#8212; from not just from him, but from the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so this is why he and the First Lady decided to come today.&nbsp; It was &#8212; a lot was because he was asked to come and he thought this was the right time to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When he meets with some of the families, we&#8217;re at a point now in the timeline where those on the ground are saying we&#8217;re talking about simply a recovery mission at this point and not a rescue mission.&nbsp; Has the President been briefed about the likelihood of survivors still being found in the in the rubble there?&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if you&#8217;ve had a chance to talk to him, but how does he prepare for the conversations that he&#8217;s going to be having with some of these families today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as far as that, you know, as we said, this is a rescue-and-search mission and continues to be that.&nbsp; You know, we haven&#8217;t gotten any indication of it not being exactly that, to continue to search and res- &#8212; to do the search and rescue, and looking for loved ones that &#8212; that are there in &#8212; in the site.&nbsp; And search-and-rescue operations, like I said, are still going on, and we&#8217;re hoping for the best.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but we, you know, we will refer you to the officials on the ground for anything more specific about what &#8212; what the status of what is happening on the ground.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) organizing those family meetings with 145, I guess, unaccounted for.&nbsp; Is it in groups?&nbsp; Is it any family of anyone who&#8217;s missing or perished?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t &#8212; (the interior door to the press cabin swings open) &#8212; careful.&nbsp; We&#8217;re about to lose Mike Memoli.&nbsp; Oh, my goodness.&nbsp; Hold on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perish the thought.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Perish the thought, indeed.</p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;ve been working with local officials on the ground and making sure that we&#8217;re meeting with the families that were impacted by this.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more &#8212; any more to tell them about, like, the process of it.&nbsp; But the &#8212; the important thing to remember is that the President is coming here with the First Lady to make sure that they are offering up, you know, their &#8212; you know, their services &#8212; their service &#8212; or service and just comfort to the &#8212; in this &#8212; in this time of tragedy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s the most important thing.&nbsp; This is about the community.&nbsp; This is about the people and everything that they&#8217;ve had to endure this past &#8212; this past several days.&nbsp; You know, this is an incredibly tragic time.&nbsp; And this is the President &#8212; this is a President that understands what that means &#8212; loss means.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s going to be his focus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And like I said, we&#8217;ve worked closely with folks on the ground in making sure that the families were there when he &#8212; when he was &#8212; when he &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any scheduling information over the next few days &#8212; the holiday weekend?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that one more time.&nbsp; I’m so sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Scheduling information over the next few days?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have anything more to share.&nbsp; I think we announced that he&#8217;s going to Michigan on Saturday, and then he will be doing the Fourth of July event with first responders and military families on Sunday for Fourth of July.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have any more further to share with that, Steve.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) said he was going to speak about voting rights issues this week, last week.&nbsp; Obviously, today came up on the schedule and that wasn&#8217;t originally.&nbsp; Is there something on the decks for next week that we should be &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don’t have anything to preview, but clearly, that is something that&#8217;s incredibly important to the President &#8212; is the voting rights issue.&nbsp; And he is going to speak to that in the upcoming days.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;ll have more to share once we have &#8212; once we have something locked in.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, is the White House or HUD or any &#8212; any other agencies in the federal government considering any other actions just to prevent things like what happened in Surfside happening again?&nbsp; Are there any executive actions you can take, anything HUD is looking at as you guys wait for the outcome of the investigation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, right now, we don&#8217;t have anything else to announce or preview.&nbsp; I just listed out a bunch of efforts that FEMA is doing, on the funding that we&#8217;ve provided for the efforts on the ground.&nbsp; And once &#8212; I think the investigation will be incredibly important to kind of steer us and give us a sense of what could be next that we could do to prevent this from happening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen was asked yesterday about this situation &#8212; unusual situation in South Dakota with the National Guard where a private donation is being used to fund a deployment.&nbsp; I know she said she would get an answer.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you had an update on the White House&#8217;s view of the appropriateness of that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So the White House is focused not on political gestures but rather on putting in the work and delivering the solutions.&nbsp; The progress made at the southern border in the first 150 days under the administration is pretty clear.&nbsp; And so the administration has been significant &#8212; has made significant progress at establishing a well-managed and secure border while also treating people fairly and humanely. The American people support this approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Separately, DHS and CBP continue to leverage their longstanding relationship with state and local law enforcement, including deconflicting operations in the border region and responding to call &#8212; callouts from other law enforcement agencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Memoli, we may not &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; we may not make it to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; to Florida.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Karine, the former President is going to have a rally in Sarasota on Saturday night.&nbsp; Have you all taken a position on whether that should go ahead with?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, we&#8217;re in &#8212; we are not focused on the former President at all.&nbsp; We are focused primarily on the American people, what can the President do &#8212; this is what the President is focused on &#8212; what he can continue to do to make their lives better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, right now, today, is all about the community of Surfside: making sure we&#8217;re offering up our condolences, making sure we&#8217;re offering up all the help that we can provide to them at this time, and also lifting up our first responders who have been working tirelessly around the clock doing the work that they&#8217;re doing in their search and rescue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>9:12 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Today’s Agreement of 130 Countries to Support a Global Minimum Tax for the World’s Largest Corporations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-todays-agreement-of-130-countries-to-support-a-global-minimum-tax-for-the-worlds-largest-corporations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today marks an important step in moving the global economy forward to be more equitable for workers and middle class families in the United States and around the world. I want to thank all the signatories of the Paris OECD statement — 130 countries — for coming together to endorse a global minimum tax rate&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today marks an important step in moving the global economy forward to be more equitable for workers and middle class families in the United States and around the world. I want to thank all the signatories of the Paris OECD statement — 130 countries — for coming together to endorse a global minimum tax rate of at least 15 percent. These nations make up more than 90 percent of the world’s economy, which puts us in striking distance of full global agreement to halt the race to the bottom for corporate taxes.</p>



<p>With a global minimum tax in place, multinational corporations will no longer be able to pit countries against one another in a bid to push tax rates down and protect their profits at the expense of public revenue. They will no longer be able to avoid paying their fair share by hiding profits generated in the United States, or any other country, in lower-tax jurisdictions. This will level the playing field and make America more competitive. And it will allow us to devote the additional revenue we raise to making generational investments, which are necessary to keep America’s competitive edge razor sharp in today’s global economy.</p>



<p>I promised to lead the world to deliver a foreign policy for the middle class, and today, we are doing just that.</p>



<p>Reaching this consensus wasn’t easy. It took American vision, as well as a commitment to closely cooperate with our partners around the world. It’s a testament to how leadership rooted in our values can deliver important progress for families everywhere.</p>



<p>Building on this agreement will also require us to take action here at home. It’s imperative that we reform our own corporate tax laws, as I proposed in my Made in America tax plan. We must adopt the global minimum tax, among other measures I have proposed, to make sure corporations pay their fair share. Congress should pass my Made in America tax plan to bring good paying jobs home and make sure our tax code works for families, workers, and small businesses, not just profitable corporations and billionaires.</p>



<p>I commend Secretary Yellen for her efforts championing these discussions and look forward to continued productive negotiations. I look forward to full agreement in the fall.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the Supreme Court’s Voting Rights Decision in Brnovich v. Democratic National Committee</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-supreme-courts-voting-rights-decision-in-brnovich-v-democratic-national-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am deeply disappointed in today’s decision by the United States Supreme Court that undercuts the Voting Rights Act, and upholds what Justice Kagan called “a significant race-based disparity in voting opportunities.” In a span of just eight years, the Court has now done severe damage to two of the most important provisions of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I am deeply disappointed in today’s decision by the United States Supreme Court that undercuts the Voting Rights Act, and upholds what Justice Kagan called “a significant race-based disparity in voting opportunities.”</p>



<p>In a span of just eight years, the Court has now done severe damage to two of the most important provisions of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 – a law that took years of struggle and strife to secure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After all we have been through to deliver the promise of this Nation to all Americans, we should be fully enforcing voting rights laws, not weakening them. Yet this decision comes just over a week after Senate Republicans blocked even a debate – even consideration – of the For the People Act that would have protected the right to vote from action by Republican legislators in states across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While this broad assault against voting rights is sadly not unprecedented, it is taking on new forms. It is no longer just about a fight over who gets to vote and making it easier for eligible voters to vote. It is about who gets to count the vote and whether your vote counts at all.</p>



<p>Our democracy depends on an election system built on integrity and independence. The attack we are seeing today makes clearer than ever that additional laws are needed to safeguard that beating heart of our democracy. We must also shore up our election security to address the threats of election subversion from abroad and at home.</p>



<p>Today’s decision also makes it all the more imperative to continue the fight for the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act to restore and expand voting protections. The Court’s decision, harmful as it is, does not limit Congress’ ability to repair the damage done today: it puts the burden back on Congress to restore the Voting Rights Act to its intended strength.</p>



<p>That means forging a coalition of Americans of every background and political party – from advocates, activists, and business executives – to raise the urgency of the moment and demand that our democracy truly reflects the will of the people and that it delivers for the Nation.</p>



<p>That is what Vice President Harris and I will continue to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is our life’s work and the work of all of us.</p>



<p>Democracy is on the line.</p>



<p>We can do this together.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
