<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 11:17:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen in Joint Press&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/25/remarks-by-president-biden-and-european-commission-president-ursula-von-der-leyen-in-joint-press-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10:05 A.M. CET PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today I’m proud to once again be standing together with President von der Leyen as we announce a new groundbreaking initiative between the European Union and the United States.&#160;First, we’re coming together to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian energy.&#160; Putin has issued Russia’s energy resources to coerce and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>10:05 A.M. CET</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today I’m proud to once again be standing together with President von der Leyen as we announce a new groundbreaking initiative between the European Union and the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, we’re coming together to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian energy.&nbsp; Putin has issued Russia’s energy resources to coerce and manipulate its neighbors.&nbsp; That’s how he’s used it.&nbsp; He’s used the profits to drive his war machine.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that’s why, earlier this month, I announced the United States would ban all imports of Russian energy to make it clear that the American people would not be part of subsidizing Putin’s brutal, unjustified war against the people of Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the time, I noted that we were able to take those steps when others could not because the United States is a net energy exporter of energy, with a strong domestic industry.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the United States welcomed the European Union’s powerful statement earlier this month committing to rapidly reduce its dependence on Russian gas.</p>



<p>Today we’ve agreed on a joint game plan toward that goal while accelerating our progress toward a secure clean energy future.<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative focuses on two core issues: One, helping Europe reduce its dependency on Russian gas as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And, secondly, reducing Europe’s demand for gas overall.<br>&nbsp;<br>To address the first point, the United States, together with our international partners, they’re going to &#8212; we’re going to work to ensure an additional 15 &#8212; one-five &#8212; 15 billion cubic meters of liquified natural gas &#8212; LNG &#8212; for Europe this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as the EU works to discontinue buying Russian gas well before 2030, it will also work to ensure additional EU market demand for 50 billion cubic meters of LNG from the United States annually by 2030.<br>&nbsp;<br>To accomplish this, the European Commission is going to work with the member states to store gas across the continent, to build more infrastructure to receive LNG, and to take steps to increase the efficiency of gas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This build-out &#8212; this build-out will occur in a way that consists &#8212; is consistent with, not in conflict with, the zero &#8212; net-zero climate goal we &#8212; that we’re shooting for.&nbsp; It’s going to take some time to adjust gas supply chains and infrastructure as is built the last decade &#8212; for the last decade.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we’re going to have to make sure the families in Europe can get through this winter and the next while we’re building an infrastructure for a diversified, resilient, and clean energy future.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, this crisis also presents an opportunity.&nbsp; It’s a catalyst &#8212; a catalyst that will drive the investments we need to double-down on our clean energy goals and accelerate progress toward our net-zero emissions future.<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s what the second part of this initiative is all about.<br>&nbsp;<br>The United States and the European Union are going to work together to take concrete measures to reduce dependence on natural gas &#8212; period &#8212; and to maximize the available &#8212; the avail- &#8212; the availability and use of renewable energy. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re going to accelerate widespread adoption of energy-efficient technologies and equipment, like smart thermostats, the work &#8212; that work to &#8212; and work to electrify heating systems all across Europe.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re going to invest in innovative solutions and technologies to make the switch from fossil fuels.<br>&nbsp;<br>And together, we’ll advance the use of clean and renewable hydrogen to reduce our carbon emissions.<br>&nbsp;<br>This &#8212; these steps will increase energy security, economic security, and national security.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re going to stand up a joint task force to implement these changes and drive progress that will be co-chaired by representatives from the White House and the President of the European Union’s team &#8212; Commission’s team.<br>&nbsp;<br>Madam President, I know &#8212; I know that eliminating Russian gas will have costs for Europe.&nbsp; But it’s not only the right thing to do from a moral standpoint, it’s going to put us on a much stronger strategic footing.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’m proud to announce that we’ve also reached another major breakthrough in transatlantic data flows.&nbsp; Privacy and security are key elements of my digital agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>And today, we’ve agreed to unprecedented protections for data privacy and security for our citizens.<br>&nbsp;<br>This new agreement will enhance the Privacy Shield Framework; promote growth and innovation in Europe and the United States; and help companies, both small and large, compete in the digital economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just as we did when we resolved the Boeing-Airbus dispute and lifted the steel and aluminum tariffs, the United States and the EU are finding creative, new approaches to knit our economies and our people closer together, grounded on shared values.<br>&nbsp;<br>This framework underscores our shared commitment to privacy, to data protection, and to the rule of law.&nbsp; And it’s going to allow the European Commission to once again authorize<br>transatlantic data flows that help facilitate $7.1 trillion in economic relationships with the EU.<br>&nbsp;<br>So thank you again, Madam President, for your personal friendship, for your partnership, and above all, your leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>All of this is bringing the European Union and the United States even closer together, and that’s a win for all of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I thank you all, and I’m now going to yield the podium to the President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me pull this out.&nbsp; (Pulls out the step stool.)&nbsp; Got to earn my salary here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Is it out enough?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Mr. President, Dear Joe, your presence here in Brussels this week &#8212; at the NATO summit, at the G7, and at our European Council &#8212; sends a very powerful message to the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>The transatlantic partnership stands stronger and more united than ever.&nbsp; And we are determined to stand up against Russia’s brutal war.&nbsp; This war will be a strategic failure for Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our cooperation on the four successive waves of sanctions against Russia has been extraordinary and exceptional.&nbsp; The sanctions are now working their way deep into the Russian system, draining Putin’s resources to finance this atrocious war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our work on sanctions also shows that when we act together, we’re stronger and we really can make a difference.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are continuing to reinforce our cooperation in many strategic ways: on humanitarian and security assistance to Ukraine; on energy; on fighting the threats against our democracies; on solving outstanding issues in the EU-U.S. cooperation, including in data protec- &#8212; protection and privacy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In a world faced with disorder, our transatlantic unity upholds fundamental values and rules that our citizens believe in.&nbsp; Let me focus first on refugees.<br>&nbsp;<br>Until now, around three and a half million people have left Ukraine, half of them children.&nbsp; Every second refugee is a child.&nbsp; And the numbers will keep rising.&nbsp; So, together, we are mobilizing massive resources to support those displaced by the conflict, be it in Ukraine or in the neighboring countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Just this week, for example, I announced that the European Union will allocate an extra 3.4 billion euros for this purpose, and more will come.&nbsp; This demonstrates our deep support for Ukraine and its citizens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to tell the American people how grateful Europe is for their unwavering support.&nbsp; This support also extends to strengthening Europe&#8217;s energy security and independence from Russian fossil fuels.&nbsp; As you know, we aim to reduce this dependency on Russian fossil fuels and to get rid of it.&nbsp; And this can only be achieved through, of course, first of all, investment in renewables, but also through additional gas supplies, including LNG deliveries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we want, as Europeans, to diversify away from Russia, towards suppliers that we trust, that are friends, and that are reliable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And therefore, the U.S. commitment to provide the European Union with additional at least 15 billion cubic meters of LNG this year is a big step in this direction because this will replace the LNG supply we currently receive from Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>And looking ahead, the United States and Europe will ensure stable demand and supply for additional at least 50 billion cubic meter of U.S. LNG until 2030.&nbsp; And if we look at that, this amount, 50 bcm per year, is replacing one third already of the Russian gas going to Europe today.&nbsp; So, we are right in &#8212; on track now to diversify away from Russian gas and towards our friends’ and partners’ reliable and trustworthy suppliers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We need to secure our supplies not just for next winter but also for the years ahead.&nbsp; And this is a &#8212; an important, a big starting point to do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our partnership aims to sustain us through this war, to work on our independence from Russian fossil fuels, but it also focuses on building a greener future with climate neutrality.&nbsp; We will work together also with our energy-intensive industry.&nbsp; And the good news is that the infrastructure that we use for gas today can be used for clean hydrogen in the future.&nbsp; So, this investment we are doing right now is also an investment in the decarbonizing of our economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>The cooperation shows the power of our democracies.&nbsp; I particularly welcome that we will step up our respective action on strengthening democracies, the rule of law, the freedom of media in the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we also need to continue adapting our own democracies to a changing world.&nbsp; This is particularly true when it comes to digitalization, in which the protection of personal data and privacy has become so crucial.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And therefore, I&#8217;m very pleased that we have found an agreement in principle on a new framework for transatlantic data flows.&nbsp; This will enable predictable and trustworthy data flows between the EU and U.S., safeguarding privacy and civil liberties.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I really want to thank Commissioner Reynders and Secretary Raimondo for their tireless efforts over the past month to finish a balanced and effective solution.&nbsp; This is another step in our &#8212; strengthening our partnership.&nbsp; We managed to balance security and the right to privacy and data protection.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Mr. President, Dear Joe: Putin is trying to turn back the clock to another era &#8212; an era of brutal use of force, of power politics, of spheres of influence, and internal repression.&nbsp; I am confident he will fail.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are working together to forge a peaceful, prosperous, and sustainable future.&nbsp; And I know we will succeed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you very much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT VON DER LEYEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>10:18 A.M. CET&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement between the United&#160;States and the European Commission on European Energy&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/joint-statement-between-the-united-states-and-the-european-commission-on-european-energy-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 10:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49701</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PreambleThe United States and the European Commission are committed to reducing Europe’s dependency on Russian energy. We reaffirm our joint commitment to Europe’s energy security and sustainability and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy. In condemning in the strongest terms Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, we express our solidarity and support for Ukraine.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><strong>Preamble<br></strong><br>The United States and the European Commission are committed to reducing Europe’s dependency on Russian energy. We reaffirm our joint commitment to Europe’s energy security and sustainability and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy. In condemning in the strongest terms Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, we express our solidarity and support for Ukraine. We share the objective of addressing the energy security emergency – to ensure energy supply for the EU and Ukraine. We welcome the continued progress toward the physical integration of Ukraine with the EU energy markets. The energy security and sustainability of the EU and Ukraine are essential for peace, freedom and democracy in Europe.</p>



<p>Through the Joint European action for more affordable, secure and sustainable energy (REPowerEU), the EU confirmed its objective to reach independence from Russian fossil fuels well before the end of the decade, replacing them with stable, affordable, reliable, and clean energy supplies for EU citizens and businesses.</p>



<p>The United States and the EU are committed to meeting the goals of the Paris Agreement, achieving the objective of net zero emissions by 2050, and keeping a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on temperature rise within reach, including through a rapid clean energy transition, renewable energy, and energy efficiency. These policies and technologies will also contribute to making the EU independent from Russian fossil fuels. Natural gas remains an important part of the EU energy system in the green transition, including by ensuring its carbon intensity decreases over time.</p>



<p>The United States and European Commission confirm our strategic energy cooperation for security of energy supply and reducing dependence on fossil fuels. We share efforts to make available stable, affordable, reliable and clean energy supplies to citizens and businesses in the EU and its neighbouring partner nations. In this framework, we establish an immediate cooperation to address the emergency energy security objective of ensuring appropriate levels of gas storage ahead of next winter and the following one. We will continue our close cooperation on other measures to accelerate the green energy transition, lower energy consumption and reduce dependence on fossil fuels.</p>



<p><strong>Task Force on Energy Security<br></strong><br>The United States and the European Commission will immediately establish a joint Task Force on Energy Security to set out the parameters of this cooperation and execute its implementation. The Task Force will be chaired by a representative from the White House and a representative of the President of the European Commission.</p>



<p>This Task Force will focus on the following urgent issues: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The United States will strive to ensure, including working with international partners, additional liquified natural gas (LNG) volumes for the EU market of at least 15 bcm in 2022 with expected increases going forward.<br></li><li>The United States and European Commission will undertake efforts to reduce the greenhouse gas intensity of all new LNG infrastructure and associated pipelines, including through the use of clean energy to power onsite operations, the reduction of methane leakage, and the construction of clean and renewable hydrogen ready infrastructure.<br></li><li>The United States commits to maintaining an enabling regulatory environment with procedures to review and expeditiously act upon applications to permit any additional export LNG capacities that would be needed to meet this emergency energy security objective and support the RePowerEU goals, affirming the joint resolve to terminate EU dependence on Russian fossil fuels by 2027.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with the governments of EU Member States to accelerate their regulatory procedures to review and determine approvals for LNG import infrastructure, to include onshore facilities and related pipelines to support imports using floating storage regasification unit vessels, and fixed LNG import terminals.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with EU Member States and market operators to pool demand through a newly established EU Energy platform for additional volumes between April and October 2022. The European Commission will also support long-term contracting mechanisms and partner with the U.S. to encourage relevant contracting to support final investment decisions on both LNG export and import infrastructure.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with EU Member States toward ensuring stable demand for additional U.S. LNG until at least 2030 of approximately 50 bcm/annum, on the understanding that the price formula of LNG supplies to the EU should reflect long-term market fundamentals, and stability of the cooperation of the demand and supply side, and that this growth be consistent with our shared net zero goals. In particular, price formula should include consideration of Henry Hub Natural Gas Spot Price and other stabilising factors.<br></li><li>The EU is preparing an upgraded regulatory framework for energy security of supply and storage. This will enhance certainty and predictability regarding security of supply and storage needs and ensure closer cooperation within the EU and its neighbouring partner nations. The European Commission has proposed regulation on energy storage to ensure that the existing storage infrastructure is filled up to 90% of its capacity by 1 November each year, with specific phase-in provisions for 2022. The European Commission will coordinate with the Member States and provide transparency with respect to available LNG capacity in EU terminals.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Commission will engage key stakeholders, including the private sector, to formulate immediate recommendations that will reduce overall gas demand through accelerating market deployment and utilization of clean energy technologies and measures in Europe and the United States such as:</li></ul>



<ul><li>Partnering on technologies and energy efficiency solutions such as ramping up demand response devices (such as smart thermostats) and heat pump deployment and installations, scaling procurement for clean energy equipment, investing in innovative technologies and fuel-switching away from fossil fuels.<br></li><li>Expediting planning and approval for renewable energy projects and strategic energy cooperation including in offshore wind technologies.<br></li><li>Developing a strategy to accelerate workforce development to support the rapidly deployment of clean energy technologies, including an expansion of solar and wind.<br></li><li>Collaborating to advance the production and use of clean and renewable hydrogen to displace unabated fossil fuels and cut greenhouse gas emissions, including by investing in technology development and supporting infrastructure.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The European Commission is working to advance measures that reduce gas consumption by maximizing renewable energy generation and utilization, including by reducing curtailment rates.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Commission are resolved to negotiate and then implement an ambitious emissions-based Global Arrangement on Steel and Aluminum Trade that incentives industrial decarbonization and lowers energy demand.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and European Commission Announce Task Force to Reduce Europe’s Dependence on Russian Fossil&#160;Fuels</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/fact-sheet-united-states-and-european-commission-announce-task-force-to-reduce-europes-dependence-on-russian-fossil-fuels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen announced a joint Task Force to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels and strengthen European energy security as President Putin wages his war of choice against Ukraine. This Task Force for Energy Security will be chaired by a representative from the White&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden and European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen announced a joint Task Force to reduce Europe’s dependence on Russian fossil fuels and strengthen European energy security as President Putin wages his war of choice against Ukraine.<br><br>This Task Force for Energy Security will be chaired by a representative from the White House and a representative of the President of the European Commission. It will work to ensure energy security for Ukraine and the EU in preparation for next winter and the following one while supporting the EU’s goal to end its dependence on Russian fossil fuels.<br><br>The Task Force will organize its efforts around two primary goals: (1) Diversifying liquefied natural gas (LNG) supplies in alignment with climate objectives; (2) Reducing demand for natural gas.<br><br><strong>Diversifying LNG Supplies in Alignment with Climate Objectives</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States will work with international partners and strive to ensure additional LNG volumes for the EU market of at least 15 bcm in 2022, with expected increases going forward.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Commission will undertake efforts to reduce the greenhouse gas intensity of all new LNG infrastructure and associated pipelines, including through using clean energy to power onsite operations, reducing methane leakage, and building clean and renewable hydrogen-ready infrastructure.<br></li><li>The European Commission will prepare an upgraded regulatory framework for energy security of supply and storage, as well as working with EU Member States to accelerate regulatory procedures to review and determine approvals for LNG import infrastructure. The United States will maintain its regulatory environment with an emphasis on supporting this emergency energy security objective and the REPowerEU goals.<br></li><li>The European Commission will work with EU Member States toward the goal of ensuring, until at least 2030, demand for approximately 50 bcm/year of additional U.S. LNG that is consistent with our shared net-zero goals. This also will be done on the understanding that prices should reflect long-term market fundamentals and stability of supply and demand.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Reducing Demand for Natural Gas</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States and the European Commission will engage key stakeholders, including the private sector, and deploy immediate recommendations to reduce overall gas demand by accelerating market deployment of clean energy measures.<br></li><li>Immediate reductions in gas demand can be achieved through energy efficiency solutions such as ramping up demand response devices, including smart thermostats, and deployment of heat pumps. The REPowerEU plan estimates that reductions through energy savings in homes can replace 15.5 bcm this year and that accelerating wind and solar deployment can replace 20 bcm this year, and through EU’s existing plans such as “Fit for 55” contribute to the EU goal of saving 170 bcm/year by 2030.<br></li><li>As global leaders in renewable energy, the United States and the European Commission will work to expedite planning and approval for renewable energy projects and strategic energy cooperation, including on technologies where we both excel such as offshore wind.<br></li><li>We will continue to collaborate to advance the production and use of clean and renewable hydrogen to displace unabated fossil fuels and cut greenhouse gas emissions, which will include both technology and supporting infrastructure.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Alaska Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-alaska-disaster-declaration-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 01:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Alaska and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and straight-line winds from December 25 to December 27, 2021. Federal funding is available to state, tribal,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Alaska and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and straight-line winds from December 25 to December 27, 2021.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm and straight-line winds in Fairbanks North Star Borough, Denali Borough, and the City of Nenana.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Thomas J. Dargan as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp;FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Greek Independence Day: A National Day of Celebration of Greek and American Democracy,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/24/greek-independence-day-a-national-day-of-celebration-of-greek-and-american-democracy-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 21:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA A PROCLAMATION In forming a Government that reflected the burgeoning spirit of America and united our young Nation around the core principles of liberty, justice, and the rule of law, our Founders looked to the birthplace of democracy &#8212; Greece.&#160;&#160;Decades after the American Revolution, the people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">BY THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">A PROCLAMATION</p>



<p>    In forming a Government that reflected the burgeoning spirit of America and united our young Nation around the core principles of liberty, justice, and the rule of law, our Founders looked to the birthplace of democracy &#8212; Greece.&nbsp;&nbsp;Decades after the American Revolution, the people of Greece came together to bravely affirm their commitment to democracy and declare their own independence from the Ottoman Empire.&nbsp;&nbsp;Today, as we mark the anniversary of Greek independence, we honor our countries&#8217; deep and historic bond &#8212; forged in the struggle for liberty and self-governance &#8212; and the many contributions of the modern Hellenic Republic which promote international peace and stability and uphold our shared values.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Greek bicentennial in 2021 was a year of celebration for Greece, for the Greek American community, and for the strong bilateral relationship between our two nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;The seeds of friendship planted long ago continue to bear fruit for both our people, with Greece and the United States standing together to defend democracy around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;A crucial ally in the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, Greece promotes peace and prosperity in the Eastern Mediterranean, Black Sea, and Western Balkans regions, and the United States is grateful for Greece&#8217;s continuing hospitality to the United States Naval Support Activity Souda Bay on Crete.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Greece and the United States are standing together to confront the challenges of our time, from meeting the climate crisis and diversifying the region&#8217;s energy resources to proving that democracies deliver for our people and pushing back against the growing threat of authoritarianism.&nbsp;&nbsp;Through our ongoing Strategic Dialogue, Greece and the United States have increased cooperation across a range of critical issues, and last year&#8217;s update to our Mutual Defense Cooperation Agreement will boost our defense and security cooperation for years to come.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The deep political and historical bonds that unite Greece and the United States are further reinforced by strong ties of family and affection and by the estimated 3 million Americans of Greek descent across our Nation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Throughout my career, I have seen firsthand the courage and determination of the Greek American community, and these qualities have been an invaluable source of strength to our Nation over the past year.&nbsp;&nbsp;Greek Americans have been at the forefront of the fight against the COVID-19 pandemic and our efforts to vaccinate the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;And last November, as Greek Americans proudly celebrated the construction of the Saint Nicholas Greek Orthodox Church and National Shrine in Manhattan 20 years after the original church structure had been destroyed in the September 11th terrorist attacks, they embodied our shared values of perseverance, resilience, and hope for the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;As Greece and the United States look forward to what the next 200 years of partnership will bring, I am confident that our nations and our people will meet every challenge together.&nbsp;&nbsp;On this day, we recommit to the hard work ahead, to fortifying our democracies, and to reaffirming our ironclad friendship.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 25, 2022, as Greek Independence Day:&nbsp;&nbsp;<a>A National Day of Celebration of Greek and American Democracy.</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to observe this day with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-fourth day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Readout by the United&#160;States and the European&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/joint-readout-by-the-united-states-and-the-european-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the European Council was joined by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States. The leaders discussed the coordinated and united response of the European Union and the United States to Russia&#8217;s unprovoked and unjustified military aggression in Ukraine. They reviewed their ongoing efforts to impose economic costs on Russia and Belarus, as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the European Council was joined by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States. The leaders discussed the coordinated and united response of the European Union and the United States to Russia&#8217;s unprovoked and unjustified military aggression in Ukraine. They reviewed their ongoing efforts to impose economic costs on Russia and Belarus, as well as their readiness to adopt additional measures and to stop any attempts to circumvent sanctions. Leaders discussed the urgent needs caused by Russia’s aggression, committed to continuing providing humanitarian assistance, including to neighboring countries hosting refugees, and underscored the need for Russia to guarantee humanitarian access to those affected by or fleeing the violence. Leaders welcomed the opening of international investigations, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court, and ongoing efforts to gather evidence of atrocities. In addition, leaders discussed EU-U.S. cooperation to reduce dependence on Russian fossil fuels, accelerate the transition to clean energy, as well as the need to respond to evolving food security needs worldwide. The leaders also concurred on the importance of strengthening democratic resilience in Ukraine, Moldova, and the wider Eastern partnership region. Finally, leaders underscored the importance of enhancing transatlantic security and defense, including through robust NATO-EU cooperation as described in the EU’s Strategic Compass.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by President&#160;Biden and President von der&#160;Leyen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/joint-statement-by-president-biden-and-president-von-der-leyen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:48:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are united in our condemnation of Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine. We stand in solidarity with the Ukrainian people, who are bravely defending their homeland, and we call on Russia to end the brutal onslaught against its neighbor.&#160; We are united in our support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We are united in our condemnation of Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war of aggression against Ukraine. We stand in solidarity with the Ukrainian people, who are bravely defending their homeland, and we call on Russia to end the brutal onslaught against its neighbor.&nbsp; We are united in our support of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; And we are united in our resolve to defend our shared values, including democracy, respect for human rights, global peace and stability, and the rules-based international order.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we are continuing coordinated transatlantic efforts to support the Ukrainian people, impose severe costs on Russia for its unjustifiable actions, and strengthen the resilience of our democracies, economies, and societies. In particular,&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The United States and the European Union have strengthened and aligned their <strong>sanctions regimes</strong>, together with like-minded partners across the world. Additionally, efforts should be stepped up to coordinate responses against sanctions evasion.<br></li><li>We continue to mobilize and coordinate significant <strong>humanitarian relief</strong> to support people within Ukraine, those who have been forced to flee, and those affected by the severe impacts Russia’s war is causing around the world. This includes more than $1 billion in new humanitarian assistance the United States is prepared to provide on top of the nearly $300 million already contributed and €550 million from the EU.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Union are coordinating closely to ensure that their <strong>efforts on temporary protection and humanitarian admission, including resettlement or transfers,</strong> are complementary and provide much-needed support to Ukraine’s neighbors.<br></li><li>We are announcing new actions to bolster <strong>democratic resilience and defend human rights</strong> in Ukraine and neighboring countries.<br></li><li>The United States and the European Union are supporting the work of <strong>war crimes documentation experts</strong> who are gathering evidence on the ground in Ukraine.<br></li><li>We are taking further, concrete steps in our <strong>energy cooperation </strong>to ensure the security of supply and to reduce dependence on Russian fossil fuels.<br></li><li>In order to prevent a potential <strong>food crisis</strong> triggered by price hikes and disruptions to food supply sparked by Putin&#8217;s war in Ukraine, we intend to redouble our combined efforts to increase global food security and provide direct food aid, where warranted, to our partners worldwide.<br></li><li>We will advance our cooperation on <strong>cybersecurity</strong> through a variety of actions, from supporting the Government of Ukraine on cyber resilience and cyber defense to aiming to combat the abuse of virtual currency.</li></ul>



<p><strong>ANNEX – TRANSATLANTIC COOPERATION AND SUPPORT FOR UKRAINE<br></strong><br><strong>Imposing Additional Costs on Russia</strong><br><br>The United States and the European Union have strengthened and aligned their sanctions regimes, together with our like-minded partners across the world. Today, the United States is sanctioning more than 400 additional individuals and entities to align with measures taken by the EU and our allies and partners. This includes the Duma (Russia’s lower house of parliament) and 328 of its members, dozens of defense companies that fuel Putin’s war machine and sustain its military industrial base, and more than 20 financial elites, including the head of Russia’s largest financial institution. The Commission, in line with its competences, will continue to support further similar measures. Together, we should aim at holding accountable those responsible for the devastation and commit to imposing further costs on Russia until Putin ceases his aggression.<br><br>The United States and the European Union are jointly working to blunt Russia’s ability to deploy its remaining international reserves, including gold, to prop up its economy and fund its illegal war.<br><br>Additionally, as announced in today’s G7 leaders’ statement, we are establishing an initiative to monitor the full implementation of our sanctions measures and coordinate responses against sanctions evasion. This will ensure that Russia will not be able to backfill or find workarounds that undermine the effect of our sanctions.<br><br><strong>Providing Humanitarian Assistance to the Ukrainian People</strong><br><br>We reaffirm our deep support for the Ukrainian people, who are suffering from Russia’s devastating bombing of civilians and civilian infrastructure.&nbsp; We urge Russia to facilitate unhindered humanitarian access and permanent safe passage for civilians. We continue to mobilize humanitarian relief to support people within Ukraine and those who have been forced to flee.&nbsp;&nbsp;The United States and the European Union are responding to the humanitarian needs in Ukraine and in countries impacted by the situation in Ukraine. The United States and the European Commission are coordinating closely on the provision of aid, including a through a newly-established high-level dialogue and a U.S. government liaison in the EU’s Emergency Response Coordination Centre.&nbsp; Today, the United States is announcing it is prepared to provide more than $1 billion in new funding toward humanitarian assistance for those affected by Russia’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world over the coming months. The European Commission has made available EUR 550 million in emergency and humanitarian assistance and, through the Union Civil Protection Mechanism in cooperation with its partners, it has delivered almost EUR&nbsp;300 million worth of in-kind assistance.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Welcoming Ukrainians Fleeing Violence</strong><br><br>The European Union has generously welcomed almost three and a half million Ukrainians fleeing Russia’s violence, providing them food, shelter, school, and employment opportunities, paying particular attention to the plight of children and providing them protection for the time they need.&nbsp; The United States and the European Union are coordinating closely to ensure that their efforts on temporary protection and humanitarian admission, including resettlement, are complementary and provide much-needed support to Ukraine’s neighbors. Today, the United States is announcing plans to welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians fleeing Russia’s aggression through the full range of legal pathways, including the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Partnering to Promote Democratic Resilience and Human Rights</strong><br><br>We steadfastly support the democratic aspirations and fundamental freedoms of the Ukrainian people. Today, we are announcing new commitments to bolster societal resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighboring countries, including Moldova.<br><br>To support human rights defenders, anti-corruption watchdogs, journalists, and other members of civil society operating in and around Ukraine, the United States is launching the <em>European Democratic Resilience Initiative</em> (EDRI), which will provide at least $320 million in new funding to these groups and regional governments. The EDRI will support media freedom and counter disinformation, benefit the safety and security of activists and vulnerable groups, strengthen institutions and the region’s rule of law, and help ensure accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international law. And it will expand rapid response capabilities and technical assistance to build resilience to Moscow’s strategic corruption and kleptocracy.<br><br>The European Commission announced plans to reallocate funds from EU programmes to support civil society organizations, human rights defenders, journalists, and pro-democracy activists in Ukraine, Belarus and Moldova. In addition, the European Endowment for Democracy, with EU funding contributions, provided a significant number of emergency grants to contribute to saving and sustaining civic activism and media pluralism in Ukraine. It also opened a Centre for Ukrainian Activists (CUA) in Przemyśl, Poland, to provide support for activists and independent journalists in maintaining and sustaining their connections to their activities inside Ukraine.<br><br><strong>Promoting Accountability<br><br></strong>There should be accountability for any war crimes committed in Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;The United States and the European Union are supporting the important work of war crimes documentation experts who are gathering evidence on the ground in Ukraine. The coordination of documentation and evidence preservation efforts to ensure such accountability should be facilitated.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting Europe’s Energy Security<br></strong><br>We reconfirm our commitment to Europe’s energy security and to accelerating the global transition to clean energy. Energy security and sustainability for the EU and Ukraine are essential for peace, freedom and democracy in Europe.&nbsp; The EU has confirmed its objective to reach independence from Russian gas well before the end of the decade while working to ensure reliable, affordable, and clean energy supplies to citizens and businesses in the EU and its neighbourhood.&nbsp; The United States intends to partner with the EU on these efforts.&nbsp; We understand that the rapid transition to clean energy is essential to advancing EU independence from Russian fossil fuels and are committed to meeting the goals of the Paris Agreement, the objective of net zero emissions by 2050, and keeping a 1.5 degrees Celsius limit on temperature rise within reach. &nbsp;In line with this vision, the European Commission and United States will establish a joint Task Force to address the immediate energy security needs of the EU and accelerate the clean energy transition.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Securing Global Food Supplies</strong><br><br>We are deeply concerned by how Putin’s war in Ukraine has caused major disruptions to international food and agriculture supply chains and the threat it poses to global food security. We recognize that many countries around the world have relied on imported food staples and fertilizer inputs from Ukraine and Russia, with Putin’s aggression disrupting that trade.&nbsp; As the United States and EU comprise many of the world’s major agricultural producers and strong economies, we commit to redoubling our combined efforts to provide direct food aid and other forms of assistance, where warranted, and, to continue the necessary support for agricultural innovation and sustainable productivity growth to ensure global food security, while balancing enhancing climate resilience and reducing agricultural greenhouse gas emissions.<br><br>We are committed to working with partners to address the attendant supply challenges and maintaining strong, ruled-based, and open global markets for staple agricultural commodities that feed the world. Specifically, the United States, through Feed the Future and our nutrition commitments, is providing over $11 billion over the next five years to address food security threats and nutrition across the globe.&nbsp; Additionally, the United States will remain one of the top providers of humanitarian food and nutrition assistance globally, having contributed approximately $4.6 billion in humanitarian food and nutrition assistance in 2021.&nbsp; We are also identifying tools in the U.S. government’s existing food security tool kit and determining whether programs are fit for purpose for this situation and will make strategic adjustments as needed.<br><br>For the period 2021 &#8211; 2024, the EU is pledging at least EUR 2.5 billion for international cooperation related to nutrition.&nbsp; This international cooperation programme will support food systems in about 70 partner countries. The proposed EU Emergency Support Programme for Ukraine of EUR 330 million will secure access to basic goods and services for the Ukrainian population and also support Ukraine’s agricultural sector.<br><br><strong>Ensuring the Security of Cyberspace</strong><br><br>We are committed to advancing our cybersecurity cooperation, both in response to Russia’s illegal further invasion of Ukraine and in support of our longer-term strategic objectives.&nbsp; Together, we will enhance our efforts to coordinate cybersecurity assistance and provide Internet access to the Governments of Ukraine and Moldova, working with Member States and other likeminded partners. In the context of Ukraine and more generally, we will continue to reinforce responsible state behavior in cyberspace and to work together to increase cyber resilience in the face of destructive, disruptive, and destabilizing cyber activity by both States and non-State actors, while also working to hold accountable those responsible for such activity.<br><br>We will work towards establishing more structured cybersecurity information exchanges on threats and threat actors and deepen our cooperation on new cybersecurity technologies and standards.&nbsp; We are committed to our partnership in the Counter Ransomware Initiative to disrupt ransomware groups and reduce related threats to our citizens and businesses. We will enhance efforts to address the abuse of virtual currency; bolster cybersecurity resilience; increase partner capacity for detecting and responding to ransomware activity within their own borders; and work to jointly hold accountable states that act as safe havens for ransomware activity.<br><br><strong>Combatting Illicit Use of Digital Assets</strong><br><br>We intend to announce deeper collaboration to combat the illicit use of digital assets, including their potential misuse in evading multilateral sanctions imposed in response to Russia’s unprovoked military invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; Together, we intend to deepen our shared commitment to advance anti-money laundering and countering financing of terrorism (AML/CFT) for digital assets, consistent with the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) standards.<br><br>We will share best practices and coordinate capacity building efforts to help other countries implement AML/CFT frameworks for digital assets. We intend to form a transatlantic sprint between U.S. and EU government officials and, as appropriate, digital asset service providers, to expedite and increase sharing of financial intelligence on illicit use of digital assets. Finally, we will seek opportunities for joint actions against those who facilitate the misuse of digital assets for illicit activity.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and European Council President Charles Michel Upon Arrival at the European&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/24/remarks-by-president-biden-and-european-council-president-charles-michel-upon-arrival-at-the-european-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49667</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Europa Building Brussels, Belgium 7:19 P.M. CET&#160;PRESIDENT MICHEL:&#160; We are very pleased, dear President, dear Joe, to welcome you again in Brussels.&#160; Your presence here and your participation in this European Council meeting is a very strong signal.&#160;&#160;Our unity is rock solid, and we are very, very pleased to coordinate, to cooperate with you.&#160; These&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Europa Building <br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>7:19 P.M. CET<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT MICHEL:&nbsp; We are very pleased, dear President, dear Joe, to welcome you again in Brussels.&nbsp; Your presence here and your participation in this European Council meeting is a very strong signal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our unity is rock solid, and we are very, very pleased to coordinate, to cooperate with you.&nbsp; These are difficult times, challenging times, and we need to take the right and the intelligent decisions for the future and for the security, for the stability.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And thank you for this excellent cooperation and coordination.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I came to congratulate a man who just got reelected without opposition.&nbsp; I dream about that someday.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, from the very beginning, I was of the view: The single most important thing that we have to do in the West is be united.&nbsp; I’m not saying that &#8212; that’s not a euphemism.&nbsp; I mean it literally.&nbsp; Literally.<br>&nbsp;<br>I spent some time with Vladimir Putin back in November and December, and we had a conference in &#8212; in Switzerland, at the time.&nbsp; And it was clear to me, and it was to you, that his intentions were very different than benign intentions.<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the things that he’s tried to do &#8212; his overwhelming objective &#8212; and I’ve been speaking about it for a year and a half.&nbsp; His overwhelming objective is to demonstrate that democracies cannot function in the 21st century &#8212; because things are moving so rapidly, they require consensus, and it’s too difficult to get consensus &#8212; and autocracies are going to rule.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a matter of fact, we’ve lost more democratic in- &#8212; democratic countries &#8212; fewer democratic countries today than there were 10 years ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, from the very beginning, my objective &#8212; and I had a great partner in this &#8212; was to see to it that we built total, complete unity among the major democracies of the world.&nbsp; I’m not joking about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s why I called just a couple weeks ago and asked NATO to set up a new &#8212; a NATO meeting of the heads of state, and it was took &#8212; which took place today.&nbsp; And I fortunately am able to attend two other conferences.<br>&nbsp;<br>But my point is: unity.&nbsp; Unity.&nbsp; And the very thing that Putin has tried to do from the beginning &#8212; and I’ve been saying this since my days as Vice President of the United States &#8212; is to break up NATO &#8212; break up NATO.&nbsp; He’d rather face 30 independent countries than 30 united countries with the United States of America.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I’m being deadly earnest.&nbsp; I believe that’s been his intention from the very, very beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, what I want to thank Michel for is the &#8212; Michel &#8212; is that the whole idea of the unity of Europe as a whole, not just NATO &#8212; the G7 and this organization &#8212; really matters.&nbsp; It’s the single most important thing that we can do to stop this guy who’s &#8212; in our country, we believe he’s already committed war crimes.<br>&nbsp;<br>But thank you very much for the time, and thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT MICHEL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you trust China?&nbsp; Do you trust China?<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Well, we’ll discuss China.&nbsp; I’ve spent some time with Xi Jinping.&nbsp; And I hope we’re going to get a chance to discuss China.</p>



<p>7:23 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/24/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATO HeadquartersBrussels, Belgium 6:32 P.M. CET THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening, everyone.  With all the press that&#8217;s here, you must be getting very tired.  Am I the 16th or 17th?  At any rate, all kidding aside, thank you for taking the time. I &#8212; today marks one month since Russia began its carnage in Ukraine, the brutal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>6:32 P.M. CET<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening, everyone.  With all the press that&#8217;s here, you must be getting very tired.  Am I the 16th or 17th?  At any rate, all kidding aside, thank you for taking the time.</p>



<p>I &#8212; today marks one month since Russia began its carnage in Ukraine, the brutal invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; And we held a NATO summit the very next day.&nbsp; At that time, my overwhelming objective, wanting that summit, was to have absolute unity on three key important issues among our NATO and European allies.</p>



<p>First was to support Ukraine with military and humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second was to impose the most significant &#8212; the most significant sanctions &#8212; economic sanction regime ever, in order to cripple Putin’s economy and punish him for his actions.</p>



<p>Third was to fortify the eastern flank of our NATO Allies, who were obviously very, very concerned and somewhat at &#8212; worried what would happen.</p>



<p>We accomplished all three of these.&nbsp; And today, we&#8217;re determined to sustain those efforts and to build on them.<br>The United States has committed to provide over $2 billion in military equipment to Ukraine since I became President &#8212; anti-air systems, anti-armor systems, ammunition.&nbsp; And our weapons are flowing into Ukraine as I speak.</p>



<p>And today, I&#8217;m announcing the United States have prepared to commit more than $1 billion in humanitarian assistance to help get relief to millions of Ukrainians affected by the war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Many Ukrainian refugees will wish to stay in Europe, closer to their homes.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve also &#8212; will welcome 100,000 Ukrainians to the United States with a focus on reuniting families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will invest $320 million to bolster democratic resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighboring countries.</p>



<p>We’re also coordinating with the G7 and the European Union on food security, as well as energy security, and I’ll have more to say about that tomorrow.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also announcing new sanctions of more than 400 individuals and entities aligned with &#8212; in alignment with the European Union: more than 300 members of the Duma, oligarchs, and Russian defense companies that fuel the Russian war machine.</p>



<p>In addition to the 100,000 U.S. forces now stationed in Europe to defend NATO territory, NATO established, as you already know, four new battle groups in Romania, Hungary, Bulgaria, and Slovakia to reinforce the eastern front.</p>



<p>Putin was banking on NATO being split.&nbsp; In my early conversation with him in December and early January, it was clear to me he didn&#8217;t think we could sustain this cohesion.</p>



<p>NATO has never, never been more united than it is today. &nbsp;Putin is getting exactly the opposite of what he intended to have as a consequence of going into Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We built that same unity with our European &#8212; the European Union and with the leading democracies of the G7 &#8212; in the G7.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I want to thank you, and I&#8217;ll be now happy to take your questions.&nbsp; Since there&#8217;s so many people out there, I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I’ve been given a list.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, how about Chris with the Associated Press?&nbsp; First question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; So you&#8217;ve warned about the real threat of chemical weapons being used.&nbsp; Have you gathered specific intelligence that suggests that President Putin is deploying these weapons, moving them to position, or considering their use?</p>



<p>And would the U.S. or NATO respond with military action if he did use chemical weapons?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, on the first question, I can&#8217;t answer that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you intelligence data, number one.</p>



<p>Number two, we would respond.&nbsp; We would respond if he uses it.&nbsp; The nature of the response would depend on the nature of the use.</p>



<p>Josh, of Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perhaps I&#8217;ll just project, Mr. President.&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If I had your voice, I’d had been elected a lot earlier.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Microphone is extended towards press member.)&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll give &#8212; I&#8217;ll give it a try.&nbsp; It&#8217;s got a long arm.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Can you talk to us about two things, sir: One, since your conversation with President Xi of China, have you seen any indications of action or lack of action from China that has led you to believe whether they will intervene and help Russia either with the sale of arms or the provision of supplies to support this war in Ukraine?<br>And secondly, can you say whether this &#8212; the conversation today turned to the subject of food shortages, and what the U.S. will do to address wheat shortages, in particular, as a result of this war?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; On the first question relating to President Xi Jinping of China, I had a very straightforward conversation with Xi &#8212; now, I guess, it&#8217;s six days ago, seven days ago &#8212; in that range.</p>



<p>And I made it clear to him &#8212; I made no threats, but I made it clear to him that &#8212; make sure he understood the consequences of him helping Russia, as had been reported and as what was expected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I made no threats, but I pointed out the number of American and foreign corporations that left Russia as a consequence of their barbaric behavior.&nbsp; And I indicated that I knew how much he &#8212; because we had long discussions in the past about his interest in making sure he has economic relations and economic growth with Europe and the United States &#8212; and indicated that he&#8217;d be putting himself in significant jeopardy and those &#8212; in those aims if, in fact, he were to move forward.</p>



<p>I am not going to comment on any detail about what we know or don&#8217;t know as a consequence of that conversation.&nbsp; But tomorrow is &#8212; is it tomorrow or next Monday that Ursula is having that conference with China?</p>



<p>WHITE HOUSE AIDE:&nbsp; April 1st.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The 1st &#8212; on April 1st.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve had discussions &#8212; because I think that China understands that its economic future is much more closely tied to the West than it is to Russia.&nbsp; And so I &#8212; I&#8217;m hopeful that he &#8212; he does not get engaged.<br>We also did discuss today that there&#8217;s a need for us to set up, NATO to set up, and &#8212; and the EU &#8212; to set up a system whereby we have an organization looking at who has violated any of the sanctions, and where and when and how they violated them.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something we&#8217;re going to put in train.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not done yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with regard to Xi, I &#8212; I have nothing more to report.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to food shortage, yes, we did talk about food shortages.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it&#8217;s going to be real.&nbsp; The price of these sanctions is not just imposed upon Russia, it&#8217;s imposed upon an awful lot of countries as well, including European countries and our country as well.&nbsp; And &#8212; because both Russia and Ukraine have been the breadbasket of Europe in terms of wheat, for example &#8212; just to give you one example.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we had a long discussion in the G7 with the &#8212; with both the United States, which has a significant &#8212; the third-largest producer of wheat in the world &#8212; as well as Canada, which is also a major, major producer. &nbsp;And we both talked about how we could increase and disseminate more rapidly food. &nbsp;Food shortages.<br>&nbsp;<br>And in addition to that, we talked about urging all the European countries and everyone else to end trade restrictions on &#8212; on sending &#8212; limitations on sending food abroad.&nbsp; And so, we are in the process of working out, with our European friends, what it would be &#8212; what it would take to help alleviate the concerns relative to food shortages.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also talked about a significant, major U.S. investment, among others, in terms of providing for the need for humanitarian assistance, including food, as we move forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Tarini, of the Wall Street Journal.&nbsp; Watch out you don&#8217;t get hit in the head there now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, in your view, does President Zelenskyy need to cede any Ukrainian territory in order to gain a ceasefire with Russia?&nbsp; Or is that completely off the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then also, do you think that Russia needs to be removed from the G20?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; On the latter point, my answer is yes.&nbsp; That depends on the G20.&nbsp; I &#8212; that was raised today.&nbsp; And I raised the possibility, if that can&#8217;t be done &#8212; if Indonesia and others do not agree, then we should, in my view, ask to have both Ukraine be able to attend the meetings, as well as &#8212; well, basically Ukraine being able to attend the G20 meetings and observe.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to &#8212; what was the first question?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you think that Ukraine needs to cease &#8212; to give up any territory in order to get a ceasefire.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That is a total judgment based on Ukraine.&nbsp; &#8220;Nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine.&#8221;&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe that they&#8217;re going to have to do that, but that&#8217;s a judgment.&nbsp; There&#8217;s negotiations &#8212; that are discussions, I should say &#8212; that have taken place that I have not been part of, including Ukrainians.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s their judgment to make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Cecilia, ABC.&nbsp; There you are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Oop.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, (inaudible). &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Sir, you&#8217;ve made it very clear in this conflict that you do not want to see World War Three.&nbsp; But is it possible that, in expressing that so early, that you were too quick to rule out direct military intervention in this war?&nbsp; Could Putin have been emboldened, knowing that you were not going to get involved directly in this conflict?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No and no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You do not believe that?<br>&nbsp;<br>And to clarify, on chemical weapons: Could &#8212; if chemical weapons were used in Ukraine, would that trigger a military response from NATO?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It would re- &#8212; it would trigger a response in kind, whether or not &#8212; you&#8217;re asking whether NATO would cross; we&#8217;d make that decision at the time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my final question: Because you&#8217;re heading to Poland tomorrow, do you think that getting a firsthand look at the effects of this war on these millions of Ukrainians who have fled their country could change the way that you might respond?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think so, because I&#8217;ve been to many, many warzones.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been in refugee camps.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been in warzones for the last 15 years.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; it’s devastating.&nbsp; And what &#8212; the thing you look at the most is you see these young children, you see children without parents that are in those camps or in &#8212; or refugees.&nbsp; You see women and husbands &#8212; men and women who are completely lost and have no &#8212; you see the look &#8212; that blank look on their face, that absolute feeling of, “My God, where am I?&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to happen to me?”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, it &#8212; what it will do, it will reinforce my commitment to have the United States make sure we are a major piece of dealing with the relocation of all those folks, as well as humanitarian assistance needed both inside Ukraine and outside Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, this is not something that Poland or Romania or Germany should carry on their own.&nbsp; This is an international responsibility.&nbsp; And the United States, as the leader &#8212; one of the leaders in the international community, has an obligation to be engaged &#8212; to be engaged and do all we can to ease the suffering and pain of innocent women and children, and men, for that matter, throughout &#8212; throughout Ukraine and those who have made it across the border.<br>&nbsp;<br>I plan on attempting to see those folks, as well as I hope I&#8217;m going to be able to see &#8212; I guess I&#8217;m not supposed to say where I&#8217;m going, am I?&nbsp; But anyway, I hope I get to see a lot of people.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Markus, with Der Spiegel.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Mr. President.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a presidential election coming up in 2024.&nbsp; And as you know, there are wide- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You’re kidding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s true.&nbsp; And there are widespread concerns in Europe that a figure like your predecessor, maybe even your predecessor himself, might get elected president again.&nbsp; So, are there any steps, anything you&#8217;re trying to do and NATO is trying to do here, these days, to prevent what you&#8217;re trying to do becoming undone two years from now?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I &#8212; that’s not how I think of this.&nbsp; I’ve been dealing with foreign policy for longer than anybody that’s involved in this process right now.&nbsp; I have no concerns about the impact &#8212;</p>



<p>I made a commitment when I ran this time. &nbsp;I wasn’t going to run again, and I mean that sincerely. &nbsp;I had no intention of running for President again and &#8212; until I saw those folks coming out of the fields in Virginia carrying torches and carrying Nazi banners and literally singing the same vile rhyme that they used in Germany in the early ‘20s &#8212; or ‘30s, I should say. &nbsp;And then, when the gentleman you mentioned was asked what he thought &#8212; and a young woman was killed, a protester &#8212; and he asked &#8212; was asked what he thought, he said, “There are very good people on both sides.” &nbsp;And that&#8217;s when I decided I wasn&#8217;t going to be quiet any longer.<br>&nbsp;<br>And when I ran this time &#8212; and I think the American press, whether they look at me favorably or unfavorably, acknowledge this &#8212; I made a determination: Nothing is worth &#8212; no election is worth my not doing exactly what I think is the right thing.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I&#8217;m too long in the tooth to fool with this any longer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we&#8217;re a long way off in elections &#8212; a long way off.&nbsp; My focus of any election is on making sure that we retain the House and the United States Senate so that I have the room to continue to do the things that I’ve been able to do in terms of grow the economy and deal in a rational way with American foreign policy and lead the world &#8212; lead the &#8212; be the leader of the free world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; but it&#8217;s not a &#8212; it&#8217;s not an illogical question for someone to ask.&nbsp; I say to people at home: Imagine if we sat and watched the doors of the Bundestag broken down and police officers killed and hundreds of people storming in, or imagine if we saw that happening in the British Parliament or whatever.&nbsp; How would we feel?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the things that I take some solace from is: I don&#8217;t think you&#8217;ll find any European leader who thinks that I am not up to the job.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like, “Whoa…&#8221;&nbsp; It’s that &#8212; that &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>The point is that when &#8212; the first G7 meeting I attended, like the one I did today, was in Great Britain.&nbsp; And I sat down, and I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And one of the &#8212; one of my counterparts, colleagues, a head of state, said, “For how long?”&nbsp; “For how long?”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I don&#8217;t blame &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t criticize anybody for asking that question. &nbsp;But the next election, I&#8217;d be very fortunate if I had that same man running against me.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you very, very much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, no &#8212; yeah, one final question.&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Hey, well, wait &#8212; hold on a second, please.&nbsp; I was supposed to be, an hour ago, at the European Union meeting and &#8212; to speak.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I’m not thanking you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Someone I haven’t called on before.&nbsp; You.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Who are you?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m Christina Ruffini from CBS.&nbsp; Thank you, sir.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, deterrence didn&#8217;t work.&nbsp; What makes you think Vladimir Putin will alter course based on the action you&#8217;ve taken today?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let’s get something straight: You remember, if you’ve covered me from the beginning, I did not say that in fact the sanctions would deter him.&nbsp; Sanctions never deter.&nbsp; You keep talking about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Sanctions never deter.&nbsp;&nbsp;The maintenance of sanctions &#8212; the maintenance of sanctions, the increasing the pain, and the demonstration &#8212; why I asked for this NATO meeting today &#8212; is to be sure that after a month, we will sustain what we&#8217;re doing not just next month, the following month, but for the remainder of this entire year.&nbsp;&nbsp;That&#8217;s what will stop him.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe the actions today will have an impact on making Russia change course in Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not what I said.&nbsp; You &#8212; you &#8212; you&#8217;re playing a game with me.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; (Off-mic.)<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; The answer is no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think what happens is, we have to demonstrate &#8212; the purpose &#8212; the single-most important thing is for us to stay unified, and the world continue to focus on what a brute this guy is and all the innocent people&#8217;s lives that are being lost and ruined, and what&#8217;s going on.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the important thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, look, if you&#8217;re Putin and you think that the &#8212; that Europe is going to crack in a month or six weeks or two months, why not &#8212; they can take anything for another month.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have to demonstrate &#8212; the reason I asked for the meeting &#8212; we have to stay fully, totally, thoroughly united.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>6:51 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Leaders’ Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/g7-leaders-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 19:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the Leaders of the G7, met today in Brussels at the invitation of the German G7 Presidency, to further strengthen our cooperation in light of Russia’s unjustifiable, unprovoked and illegal aggression and President Putin’s war of choice against independent and sovereign Ukraine. We will stand with the government and people of Ukraine. We are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<ol><li>We, the Leaders of the G7, met today in Brussels at the invitation of the German G7 Presidency, to further strengthen our cooperation in light of Russia’s unjustifiable, unprovoked and illegal aggression and President Putin’s war of choice against independent and sovereign Ukraine. We will stand with the government and people of Ukraine.<br></li><li>We are united in our resolve to restore peace and stability and uphold international law. Following the United Nations General Assembly resolution on<br>2 March 2022, we will continue to stand with the overwhelming majority of the international community, in condemning Russia’s military aggression and the suffering and loss of life it continues to cause.<br></li><li>We remain appalled by and condemn the devastating attacks on the Ukrainian population and civilian infrastructure, including hospitals and schools. We welcome the investigations of international mechanisms, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court. We will work together to support the gathering of evidence of war crimes. The siege of Mariupol and other Ukrainian cities, and the denial of humanitarian access by Russian military forces are unacceptable. Russian forces must immediately provide for safe pathways to other parts of Ukraine, as well as humanitarian aid to be delivered to Mariupol and other besieged cities.<br></li><li>The Russian leadership is obligated to immediately comply with the order of the International Court of Justice to suspend the military operations that it commenced on 24 February 2022 in the territory of Ukraine, without any further delay. We also urge Russia to withdraw its military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine.<br></li><li>We further call upon the Belarusian authorities to avoid further escalation and to refrain from using their military forces against Ukraine. Moreover, we urge all countries not to give military or other assistance to Russia to help continue its aggression in Ukraine. We will be vigilant regarding any such assistance.<br> </li><li>We will spare no efforts to hold President Putin and the architects and supporters of this aggression, including the Lukashenko regime in Belarus, accountable for their actions. To this end, we will continue to work together, along with our allies and partners around the world.<br></li><li>We underline our resolve to impose severe consequences on Russia, including by fully implementing the economic and financial measures we already imposed. We will continue to cooperate closely, including by engaging other governments on adopting similar restrictive measures to those already imposed by G7 members and on refraining from evasion, circumvention and backfilling that seek to undercut or mitigate the effects of our sanctions. We task the relevant Ministers in a focused initiative to monitor the full implementation of sanctions and to coordinate responses related to evasive measures, including regarding gold transactions by the Central Bank of Russia. We stand ready to apply additional measures as required, continuing to act in unity as we do so. We commend those partners who have aligned with us in these efforts.<br></li><li>Russia’s attack has already risked the safety and security of nuclear sites in Ukraine. Russian military activities are creating extreme risks for the population and the environment, with the potential for catastrophic result. Russia must comply with its international obligations and refrain from any activity that imperils nuclear sites, allowing unhindered control by the Ukrainian authorities, as well as full access by and cooperation with the International Atomic Energy Agency.<br></li><li>We warn against any threat of the use of chemical, biological and nuclear weapons or related materials. We recall Russia’s obligations under the international treaties to which it is a signatory, and which protect us all. In this regard, we categorically denounce Russia’s malicious and completely unfounded disinformation campaign against Ukraine, a state in full compliance with international non-proliferation agreements. We express concern about other countries and actors that have amplified Russia’s disinformation campaign.<br> </li><li>We are resolved in our support to the Ukrainian people in their heroic resistance to Russia’s unjustifiable and illegal aggression. We will step up our support to Ukraine and neighbouring countries. We thank all those who are already providing humanitarian aid to Ukraine and ask others to join. We will furthermore collaborate in our efforts to bolster democratic resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighbouring countries.<br></li><li>We will continue efforts to support Ukraine in defending its networks against cyber incidents. In preparation for any Russian malicious cyber response to the actions we have taken, we are taking steps to increase the resilience of the infrastructure in our respective nations by strengthening our coordinated cyber defences and improving our shared awareness of cyber threats. We will also work to hold accountable those actors that engage in destructive, disruptive, or destabilising activities in cyberspace.<br></li><li>We further commend neighbouring states for their solidarity and humanity in welcoming Ukrainian refugees and third country nationals from Ukraine. We highlight the need to further increase international assistance to countries neighbouring Ukraine, and, as a concrete contribution to this end, underline our commitment to receiving, protecting, and supporting refugees and displaced persons as a consequence of the conflict. We thus all stand ready to welcome them on our territories. We will take further steps to broaden our support to Ukraine and neighbouring countries.<br></li><li>We are concerned by the escalating and reinforced repression against the Russian people and the increasingly hostile rhetoric of the Russian leadership, including against ordinary citizens. We deplore the Russian leadership’s attempt to deprive Russian citizens of access to unbiased information through censorship, and denounce its malicious disinformation campaigns, which we will not leave unaddressed. We express our support to those Russian and Belarusian citizens standing up against the unjustified war of aggression against their close neighbour Ukraine. The world sees them.<br></li><li>The people of Russia must know that we hold no grievances against them. It is President Putin, his government and supporters, including the Lukashenko regime in Belarus, who are imposing this war and its consequences on Russians and it is their decision that besmirches the history of the Russian people.<br></li><li>We are taking further steps to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, and will work together to this end. At the same time, we will ensure secure alternative and sustainable supplies, and act in solidarity and close coordination in the case of possible supply disruptions. We commit to actively support countries willing to phase out their dependency on Russian gas, oil and coal imports. We call on oil and gas producing countries to act in a responsible manner and to increase deliveries to international markets, noting that OPEC has a key role to play. We will work with them and all partners to ensure stable and sustainable global energy supplies. This crisis reinforces our determination to meet the goals of the Paris agreement and of the Glasgow climate pact and limit the rise in global temperatures to 1.5°C, by accelerating reduction of our reliance on fossil fuels and our transition to clean energy. <br></li><li>We stand in solidarity with our partners who have to bear the rising price of President Putin’s unilateral choice to wage war in Europe. His decision is putting the global economic recovery at risk, undermines the resilience of global value chains and will have severe impacts on the most fragile countries. We call on the international community to take action by fully recognising Russia’s responsibility and protecting the most vulnerable countries, with the support of international and regional institutions.<br></li><li>More immediately, President Putin’s war places global food security under increased pressure. We recall that the implementation of our sanctions against Russia takes into account the need to avoid impact on global agricultural trade. We remain determined to monitor the situation closely and do what is necessary to prevent and respond to the evolving global food security crisis. We will make coherent use of all instruments and funding mechanisms to address food security, and build resilience in the agriculture sector in line with climate and environment goals. We will address potential agricultural production and trade disruptions, in particular in vulnerable countries. We commit to provide a sustainable food supply in Ukraine and support continued Ukrainian production efforts.<br></li><li>We will work with and step up our collective contribution to relevant international institutions including the World Food Programme (WFP), in parallel with Multilateral Development Banks and International Financial Institutions, to provide support to countries with acute food insecurity. We call for an extraordinary session of the Council of the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) to address the consequences on world food security and agriculture arising from the Russian aggression against Ukraine. We call on all participants of the Agriculture Markets Information System (AMIS) to continue to share information and explore options to keep prices under control, including making stocks available, in particular to the WFP. We will avoid export bans and other trade-restrictive measures, maintain open and transparent markets, and call on others to do likewise, consistent with World Trade Organization (WTO) rules, including WTO notification requirements.<br></li><li>International organisations and multilateral fora should no longer conduct their activities with Russia in a business as usual manner. We will work closely with our partners to act as appropriate, based on shared interests, as well as rules and regulations of respective institutions.</li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
