<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 01:39:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in a Conversation With Keke Palmer at Essence&#160;Festival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/02/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-conversation-with-keke-palmer-at-essence-festival/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 01:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56792</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ernest N. Morial Convention CenterNew Orleans, Louisiana 4:31 P.M. CDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Wow.&#160; I mean &#8212; so you guys, I really got lucky.&#160; I got the opportunity to sit with the Madam VP &#8212; AUDIENCE MEMBER:&#160; I love you, Kamala! Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Yes!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; I love you.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; I got an opportunity when&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Ernest N. Morial Convention Center<br>New Orleans, Louisiana</em></p>



<p>4:31 P.M. CDT<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wow.&nbsp; I mean &#8212; so you guys, I really got lucky.&nbsp; I got the opportunity to sit with the Madam VP &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; I love you, Kamala!<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I love you.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I got an opportunity when I did “Lightyear.”&nbsp; Madam Vice President held a big event in our home where children got to come and watch and play and also meet astronauts from NASA.&nbsp; We got to talk about all the great things that you&#8217;re doing with NASA.&nbsp; And I got a chance to sit and talk with her and really, you know, kind of get to know her in a really casual way, which I feel really lucky to have gotten that chance.&nbsp;<br><br>But there was something I wanted to ask you.&nbsp; You know, we have something in common.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t get to say it then, but, you know, I&#8217;ve been meme’d a couple of times.&nbsp; But you are a part of my favorite meme with, “We did it, Joe.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And so, I have to ask you &#8212; obviously, the excitement of the election hitting you in that moment: What were you thinking when you saw how that just went so viral?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first of all, it is so good to be with you, Keke.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh my &#8212;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It is so good.&nbsp; And hello, Essence Fest.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We’re back!&nbsp; We are back.<br><br>It was &#8212; you know, that day &#8212; well, so you&#8217;ll remember, the election happened but it took a while for the &#8212; for it to be declared.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And so, my husband and I were staying in Delaware so we could be near the Vice President-elect &#8212; I mean, President-elect at the time.&nbsp; And I work out every morning.&nbsp; And so, he and I worked out together, and we were then going back to the house.&nbsp; And he was like, “I&#8217;m going to walk a little bit more and cool down.”&nbsp; And so, he started to walk.&nbsp; I went up to the house, and I went upstairs to go take a shower.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m just &#8212; I&#8217;m going to give you all kinds of information you weren&#8217;t expecting.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And so, I turned on the shower &#8212; because it was cold.&nbsp; Remember, it was winter.&nbsp; And so, I turn on the shower so the water could heat up.&nbsp; And I got a text.&nbsp; And it said, “They declared the race.”<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whooo!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I ran downstairs.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t even turn off shower.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ah!&nbsp; Water bill high.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I ran downstairs.&nbsp; And I come out the house, “Doug!&nbsp; Doug!”&nbsp; I’m trying to find my husband.&nbsp; He&#8217;s down the hall &#8212; or down the pathway, and he&#8217;s got his earbuds in.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m they&#8217;re saying, “They called the race.”&nbsp; And I&#8217;m waving at him.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s just waving back because he&#8217;s listening to music.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’s like, “Hey.”<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He’s just waving back.&nbsp;<br><br>And then he came up.&nbsp; And then the President called &#8212; Joe Biden called.&nbsp; And so that meme is from my husband standing there videotaping me having the call with the President.&nbsp; That’s what that was.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; “We did it, Joe.&nbsp; We did it.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; “You’re President of the America.”&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s just my favorite clip.&nbsp;<br><br>But I also have to ask you &#8212; right? &#8212; because I think I have &#8212; I think I have some unrealistic expectations on how it actually is to work in the White House.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; I think a lot of my peers and I &#8212; we often talk about it.&nbsp; In our minds, we think it&#8217;s like, “Okay, something comes in, and you&#8217;re like, ‘This is what we&#8217;re going to do.’”&nbsp; You know, but how is it really on a day to day?&nbsp; You know, are you and mis- &#8212; and the President sitting down and strategizing?&nbsp; Are you emailing?&nbsp; What is the process of actually trying to get things done and working there?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, like I said, I work out every morning.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just give you kind of a day in the life.&nbsp; I work out every morning.&nbsp; Then I start my day reading the Presidential Daily Brief.&nbsp; We call it the “PDB” for short.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Which is classified information generated by our intelligence community about hot spots around the world and threats to our national security.&nbsp; So I read that every morning.&nbsp;<br><br>And my office in the West Wing is &#8212; I don&#8217;t know how many feet; not very far &#8212; you know, a minute to get from my office to the Oval Office.&nbsp; And so, often when I arrive at the West Wing, I&#8217;ll walk down to the Oval Office and the President and I will have a meeting with the heads of our intelligence community &#8212; including, often the Secretary of Defense will be there, the Secretary of State will be there, the Director of the CIA will be there &#8212; and we will talk about the threats to our nation and the priorities that we face.&nbsp; And so that is often how the day will start.&nbsp;<br><br>And then there will be a series &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Heavy day to start.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, yeah.&nbsp; There are a lot &#8212; there’s a lot of decisions to be made.&nbsp;<br><br>And then the day will proceed.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ll tell you: One of my favorite days recently was the day that I went over to the Capitol.&nbsp; You see, as the Vice President, I&#8217;m also the President of the Senate.&nbsp; And right now, in the United States Senate we have a 50-50 split between Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; So it is often the case that I go to break the tie, so I&#8217;ll go up to the Capitol.&nbsp;<br><br>But this day I went up to the Capitol because there was a vote occurring on who would be the next justice on the United States Supreme Court.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We know.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And oh my &#8212; what a &#8212; you know, and I was in &#8212; very, very actively involved in that process of choosing her.&nbsp; And so, I went to the Senate so I could preside when she was then voted on to be the next Supreme Court justice.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And, of course, I am talking about Ketanji Brown Jackson.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whooo!&nbsp; Whooo!&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh my gosh.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And it was so special, Keke, because, you know, I got there and then it was taking a while for the vote to happen.&nbsp; And then two of my friends and colleagues when I was in the Senate &#8212; Raphael Warnock &#8212; Senator Warnock from Georgia.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get him reelected, please.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Senator Cory Booker from New Jersey.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And so the two of them walked up when I was in the chair because there was a pause.&nbsp; And I had just finished, on my stationery, writing a note to my goddaughter Helena &#8212; who&#8217;s actually here with me today &#8212; to talk to her about as a, you know, 17-year-old, young, Black woman what this day would mean for her and her life.&nbsp; And I wrote her a note.&nbsp; And I had some extra stationery.&nbsp; And so when the two of them came up, I said, “Well, y&#8217;all need to write a note to somebody too.”&nbsp; So I handed them my stationary, and then each of them also wrote a note to someone in their life about the meaning &#8212; the historic meaning of that day.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I don’t know if everybody, you know, has experiences like that, but it&#8217;s awesome to hear you talk about it not just in a logistical sense, but also an emotional sense.&nbsp; You know, because I think it&#8217;s important that we know that it&#8217;s &#8212; that it&#8217;s human &#8212; you know, to humanize the people that are working in government.&nbsp; And to know that, at least with you, Madam VP, that there&#8217;s heart going into it as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Speaking about the Senate and things you&#8217;ve done: One of the most important jobs you did in the Senate was holding Trump officials and nominees accountable as a member of the Judicidary [sic] &#8212; Judiciary Committee.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But most notably, when now Justice Kavanaugh struggled to identify any laws that give the government power to make decisions about the male body.&nbsp; Which brings me to what just happened last week, you know, where he and five other justices voted to overturn Roe vs. Wade.&nbsp;<br><br>I mean, I know personally, for me, that just seems ridiculous.&nbsp; And it really puts me in an apathetic space to feel like, “Well, if you can come back and change things that are already settled, what is going to happen next?”<br><br>So I have to ask you: What &#8212; where were you when you heard the news?&nbsp; And, I mean, what do we do now?&nbsp; How do you feel, you know?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; This is a serious matter.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And it requires all of us to speak up, to speak out, and to be active.&nbsp;<br><br>So I was on my way to Aurora, Illinois, to meet with Congresswoman Lauren Underwood &#8212; who is an outstanding member of Congress &#8212; because she and I, over the years when I was in the Senate and now as Vice President, have been working on the issue of maternal mortality and, in particular, Black maternal mortality.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been working on this issue for a very important reason, which is: In the United States, Black women are three times more likely to die in connection with childbirth.&nbsp; Native women are twice as likely to die.&nbsp; Rural woman, one and a half likely &#8212; more times likely to die.&nbsp; And understand that among all so-called “developed nations,” we are the worst on this issue.&nbsp;<br><br>So it has been a longstanding area of focus for me &#8212; to focus on women&#8217;s health and safety and wellbeing.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve been able to then as Vice President bring this issue to the stage of the White House to talk about what we need to do to protect and to ensure that women have the resources they need.&nbsp;<br><br>So, for example, we&#8217;ve been able to encourage states to extend Medicaid coverage &#8212; postpartum &#8212; from two months to twelve months because a woman needs &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; support beyond two months when she has just given birth &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Absolutely.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; to a human being.&nbsp; We &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We deserve these things.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have taught &#8212; we have dealt with the fact that there is racial bias in the healthcare delivery system.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, what we need to do &#8212; when we recognize that a Black woman walking into a clinic or a doctor&#8217;s office or an emergency room is less likely to be taken seriously.&nbsp; So this is the work we&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve been looking at it in the context of the unique stressors that women face and, in particular, Black women face, and what that does to have effects on their health and wellbeing.&nbsp;<br><br>So Lauren Underwood and I have been doing this work.&nbsp; I was flying from D.C. to Aurora, Illinois, to meet her in her district &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; to announce more work that we are doing on maternal health.&nbsp; And wouldn&#8217;t you know, on the course of that trip, the Supreme Court &#8212; with the Dobbs decision &#8212; for the first time in the history of our nation, took a constitutional right that had been recognized and took it from the women of America.&nbsp; Took a constitutional right.<br><br>And what is so outrageous about this on every level is: One, it is the taking of a right that was given and guaranteed and something that we took for granted to be settled law.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So what that means then, in terms of what else might be vulnerable that we otherwise thought was settled law, including issues like contraception, including issues like same-sex marriage, including the intimate decisions that people should be able to make &#8212; about what I call “heart and home” &#8212; without government interference.&nbsp;<br><br>What essentially has happened is the statement has been made that the government has a right to come in your home and tell you, as a woman and as a family, what you should do with your body.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh my gosh.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And the point has to be this: We have to recognize we&#8217;re a nation that was founded on certain principles that are &#8212; that are grounded in the concept of freedom and liberty.&nbsp;<br>We also know that we&#8217;ve had a history in this country of government &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Exactly.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; trying to claim ownership over human bodies.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Exactly!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Yes, that is right.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And we had supposedly evolved from that time and that way of thinking.&nbsp; So this is very problematic on so many levels.&nbsp;<br><br>The impact that it is going to have on women without means, what it will mean &#8212; for, you know, somebody who has financial means, this is really probably not going to have much of an effect on them.&nbsp; But imagine that &#8212; the facts are: The majority of women who get an abortion &#8212; the majority are mothers.&nbsp; So if she has to leave her state to go for the reproductive healthcare she needs &#8212; we&#8217;re looking at the fact that if she works, which she probably does, she&#8217;s going to lose time from work, potentially without leave &#8212; without paid leave.&nbsp; She&#8217;s going to have to &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Unacceptable.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; figure out what to do with her kids and the cost of the childcare at least for overnight, not to mention bus fare or train fare or airfare and a hotel room.&nbsp; All to make one of the most intimate decisions that she should have a right to make without government interference.&nbsp; That she should have a right to make with her pastor or her priest or her rabbi and her family, but not getting permission from the government.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; I mean, I &#8212; it’s so &#8212; it&#8217;s awesome to hear you say these things.&nbsp; I knew &#8212; I &#8212; in my heart, I knew that you &#8212; that you would feel this way.&nbsp;<br><br>But I just wonder then, what we can do?&nbsp; You know, what does &#8212; you know what I mean?&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In one hand, I&#8217;m looking at you and I know that, yeah, there has been evolution, that things have changed.&nbsp; We talk about our justice.&nbsp; You know, we talk about eight years &#8212; or however so &#8212; ago when we had Obama in office, and we see that things are somewhat different.&nbsp; But then now there&#8217;s all this delayed response to what we&#8217;ve experienced, you know, these four years prior.&nbsp;<br><br>And I just &#8212; you know, how do we move beyond the apathy that this gives us?&nbsp; What are we now then &#8212; what can &#8212; what can our move be?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; So, first, I&#8217;ll say this: You know, I did an analysis trying to look at the states that are attacking a woman&#8217;s right to choose and the states that are attacking voting rights, and there is an interesting intersection.&nbsp; At least 11 states are doing both at the same time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No surprise there, right, guys?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No surprise there.&nbsp;<br><br>When we look at this issue, I think we have to, one, remember the words of Coretta Scott King, who I&#8217;ll paraphrase.&nbsp; But she famously said: The fight for civil rights, which is the fight for freedom, the fight for liberty, the fight for justice &#8212; the fight for civil rights must be fought and won with each generation.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And when she said that, I think we know that, one, she was saying that the very nature of these fights is that whatever we gain, they will not necessarily be permanent.&nbsp; Therein lies the strength when we &#8212; when we achieve the rights with the fragility of those rights.&nbsp; Meaning, if we are not vigilant to secure and to fight for them, we can&#8217;t take it for granted.&nbsp; So there is that piece of it.&nbsp;<br><br>But I think the second point she was making is: Because it is the nature of it &#8212; that you have to be vigilant &#8212; don&#8217;t be overwhelmed.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Don&#8217;t be &#8212; don&#8217;t be overwhelmed to the point that we are disheartened and we think that we can&#8217;t do anything about it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the nature of it that these gains will not be permanent.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s great.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So we must be vigilant.&nbsp; And we must &#8212; remember, we are always going to have to fight to maintain these rights.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s such a good point, because I think we do get caught up in thinking, when there are great feats that have been accomplished, that “Oh, now it&#8217;s done” or, you know, we&#8217;re surprised when it happens again.&nbsp; But when I look at the generations before me and what they had to deal with &#8212; I mean, we go back to slavery.&nbsp; If they found a way to keep moving, I better find a way to keep moving.&nbsp; You know what I&#8217;m saying?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s right.&nbsp; That’s right.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because I mean, hey, I don&#8217;t know what it&#8217;s like to be in a field.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know what I&#8217;m saying?&nbsp;<br><br>I want to go quickly to &#8212; you mentioned some of the things you&#8217;ve been doing.&nbsp; And we were talking about all the things that the administration has accomplished when we were &#8212; you know, back when we were at your home in D.C.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned some great things about removing lead pipes also &#8212;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; which is a huge issue.&nbsp; You touched on a lot of things, but I just want to take a moment to speak to you guys about some of the things that specifically have been done: the Executive Order to Promote Access to Voter Registration and voting, where President Biden directed government resources to provide information about eglects [sic] &#8212; elections and increase access to voter registration opportunities; protecting Black Americans access to housing by combating housing discrimination, where President Biden directed the administration to address racial discrimination in the housing market.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah, let me &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Reducing &#8212; oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And let me add to that.&nbsp; So on the housing piece, it includes this piece.&nbsp; What we know is that, for generations, housing appraisers &#8212; the people who come in and tell you the value of your house &#8212; we have been tracking the racial bias in those assessments, such that we have examples of a Black family getting an appraisal that was far lower than they knew the value of their house was.&nbsp; So then they have friends who are a white family, and would have the white family come in and put up their family pictures, and then get the house appraised.&nbsp; And it appraised for much higher.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So we&#8217;re dealing with that too, which is a longstanding issue in terms of what needs to be reformed around just the appraisal system, much less what we need to do to make housing affordable and available to more families.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s just some of the things.&nbsp; I mean, from reducing college costs where you guys increased the maximum Pell Grant award $400.&nbsp; I mean, there&#8217;s so many things here, you guys, that I could go on about.&nbsp;<br><br>If you are interested in seeing everything that the administration has done up to date, you can go to WhiteHouse.gov.&nbsp;<br><br>But I want to say this to you too, Madam VP, because I know you see: People are always &#8212; you know, in your position, it&#8217;s a hard job.&nbsp; You know, as many things as you get done, there&#8217;s so many other things that people are saying, “You need to do.&nbsp; You need to do.”&nbsp;<br><br>You know, and there&#8217;s a quote that I&#8217;ve always loved from Mother Teresa, where she says, “There can be no great things done, only small things with great love.”&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Because there&#8217;s always going to be something.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I want to ask you: How, in your position, do you approach, A, that reality and, B, knowing what tasks to start on first with so much to deal with?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, one, we got to multitask.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Women are good at that.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And we are good at that.&nbsp; None of us would be sitting here if we didn&#8217;t figure that out at some point.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So we &#8212; we have to multitask.&nbsp;<br><br>But we have to look at, you know, what are the most critical issues.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So, for example: For me and for the President, one of the biggest issues that has been treated as maybe a small issue is &#8212; is anything that affects children.&nbsp; I think, you know, sometimes in public policy, I think folks think because they&#8217;re small people, it&#8217;s a small issue.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; If you impact in a positive way the needs of a child, the entire community benefits for generations.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we have been looking at what we need to do, for example, at also supporting children in the context of the family they are being raised &#8212; right? &#8212; so that grandmother or that auntie or that mother or that father.&nbsp;<br><br>So what we have done, for example, is we have a &#8212; we have instituted a tax cut for childcare expenses like medication and school supplies &#8212; $8,000 a year.&nbsp; A tax cut.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wow.&nbsp; Wow.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Not one Republican voted for it.<br><br>We have extended the Child Tax Credit, and in that &#8212; in so doing in the first year, reduced Black child poverty by almost 40 percent.&nbsp; Cannot get a Republican to help us extend it beyond.&nbsp;<br><br>But these are some of the things that we have been doing, understanding the generational impact, not to mention the work that we need to do that is about foreign policy.<br><br>I have met with, I don&#8217;t know, probably at least two dozen foreign leaders &#8212; prime ministers, presidents.&nbsp; I just recently convened the Caribbean prime ministers and presidents around what we should do, as the United States, seeing them as our neighbors in the Western Hemisphere and giving appropriate support there.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we have to multitask, looking at what we need to do domestically, what we need to do to bring down the cost of gas &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I seen a meme the other day that said, “Me Googling online, ‘How to make gas at home.’”&nbsp; Okay?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, don&#8217;t do that.&nbsp; Don’t do that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Please, don’t do that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hilarious.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But it’s true.&nbsp; I mean, there&#8217;s so many things.&nbsp; But you guys have been &#8212; have been working.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know some of the stuff is going to be a layover effect.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Just like we&#8217;re seeing layover effect from the last administration, a lot of the things you guys doing now are going to be immediate, but some things we&#8217;re going to see as time goes.&nbsp; And we appreciate you for putting that work in.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to take it back to something that we talked about also in D.C., where &#8212; you know, I knew that you were from the Bay, but what was interesting to learn was that you grew up around a lot of Civil Rights leaders because of your parents’ involvement with the Civil Rights Movement.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to ask you &#8212; because like I was saying earlier, you know, in the millennial generation, we&#8217;ve just seen so many people lie to us.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen so many things unfortunate happen, like Roe vs. Wade being overturned.&nbsp; And we take it very personally, where it does tend to bring on this apathy.<br><br>But when I do think back to the generations before me &#8212; I think about the Civil Rights Movement &#8212; I&#8217;m like, “Wow, they were up against a lot of even more daunting realities, maybe even the ones that we&#8217;re facing now.”&nbsp; Not to compare, but, like you said, there&#8217;s always a lot going on.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you being around those kinds of people, what were some of the ways that they were able to reinvigorate themselves?&nbsp; Or even more so, how did they mobilize?&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Because I don&#8217;t want to be that person that just looks at my government and says, “Oh, what are you doing?”&nbsp; Yes, there&#8217;s accountability that needs to be had, but I want accountability for myself as well.&nbsp; I want to know what I can do.&nbsp; You know what I&#8217;m saying?&nbsp; What can I do to get out there and encourage my peers, encourage myself, and make sure that I&#8217;m being an active member in my &#8212; in my society?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first and foremost &#8212; and I don’t need to say it to you, Keke, because you really do use your voice in such an extraordinary way.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, (inaudible).<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, you really do.&nbsp; You really do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You just &#8212; you &#8212; you have the courage to speak out.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re not concerned about putting your finger in the air to see if it&#8217;s popular.&nbsp; You speak truth.&nbsp; And I really appreciate and respect and admire that.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; But I will say: Let&#8217;s not discount what young leaders are doing right now, because there&#8217;s a lot of extraordinary leadership happening from our young leaders.&nbsp; And, you know, when I think about the Civil Rights Movement and my parents and what they were doing, you know, they were in their 20s.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t forget, Dr. King was a very young man.&nbsp;<br><br>So we have a history of these movements being fueled by students, by young leaders.&nbsp; And you could look at anything from who was taking to the street articulating with Black Lives Matter to who has been now out there marching on choice, who is out there leading on so many of the issues that are about the climate crisis that is pounding on the door for attention and swift response.&nbsp; So I see a lot of leadership happening among younger leaders.<br><br>But here&#8217;s what I would encourage folks to do who want to be more active.&nbsp; First of all, use your voice to talk to the people in your life &#8212; your family members, your neighbors, the people you work with &#8212; about how issues are impacting you.&nbsp; Talk about how you know that if you were born, like my goddaughter &#8212; who&#8217;s here &#8212; in 2004, well, the world has put in dates around 2030 that we need to reduce greenhouse gas emissions or we are looking at an inflection point.&nbsp; And so what that will mean for you and for your children and your grandchildren.&nbsp; Speak that in a way that people understand that you have an immediate investment in the outcome of the issue.&nbsp;<br><br>Similar when we&#8217;re talking about what&#8217;s happening in terms of the work that we&#8217;re doing on something like maternal mortality.&nbsp;<br><br>Similar to what we&#8217;re talking about in terms of voting, where they are taking the rights of people to be able to express their voice in a democracy through their vote.&nbsp;<br><br>Speak about that in a way that you can energize the people in your life to understand that when elections come up, “I know Keke, and she has passionately told me how this concerns her and how my vote could impact the outcome of this decision.”<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for that.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just &#8211; I could literally sit here and talk to you all day long.<br><br>I just want to say thank you to you so much.&nbsp; And that, for me personally, I want to be able to figure out all the ways that I can continue to be involved and get better and be more active.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;m 28, but, hey, I wish I &#8212; I thought I would know more by then.&nbsp; My parents were having four kids by now, and I don&#8217;t know how they got around to it.&nbsp;<br><br>So if there&#8217;s anything that I, myself, can do, or anywhere that I can go &#8212; a website or just any place &#8212; or anyone out there, please let us know.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, they &#8212; I will.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; what I&#8217;d encourage is &#8212; for example, I know that you have a variety of interests, choice being one of them.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So there are a number of organizations that are working on that issue.&nbsp; And then figure out how you can volunteer there, how you can be an advocate.&nbsp; Because the advocacy &#8212; the marching, the shouting &#8212; is what brings about a lot of what has happened in terms of people being vocal about how the issue impact them.&nbsp;<br><br>But &#8212; and I&#8217;ll tell you another &#8212; there&#8217;s something else that’s equally important, and that is the power of coalition building.&nbsp; So, for example, I mentioned earlier that there are &#8212; in many of the states that are attacking a woman&#8217;s right to choose, they&#8217;re also attacking voting rights.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, let&#8217;s think about the fact that, historically, it&#8217;s different communities that have worked on those issues, but we&#8217;re all under the same roof &#8212; if it&#8217;s about understanding how liberties are being attacked, how our democracy is being attacked.&nbsp;<br><br>So let&#8217;s work on the coalition also, which is bringing folks together, because there is power in those numbers.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And there is power in knowing that the vast majority of us have so much more in common than what separates us.&nbsp;<br><br>See, the people who are trying to attack our rights are trying to make people feel small and feel alone &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And different.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; because they &#8212; they want to &#8212; they want you to believe you don&#8217;t have power and that you&#8217;re out there by yourself.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re not going to let that happen.&nbsp;<br><br>And one of the ways that we won&#8217;t is to bring everyone together and remember that there is a community of people that is invested in this.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So don&#8217;t believe that it&#8217;s too &#8212; I’m too small to start.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t be afraid to collaborate with others, whether they look like me or not.&nbsp; As long as we believe in the same things, we can get to the common goal.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s right.&nbsp; That’s right.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And know that, hey, age is but a number, and we can all work together.<br><br>Okay, I want to ask you this final question.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be, maybe, a question about a conversation you would have with your younger self &#8212;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that maybe you didn&#8217;t know or maybe you did know and have these dreams of one day being the Vice President.&nbsp; What would you say to prepare yourself for this role?<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first of all, don&#8217;t hear “no.”&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Don&#8217;t hear, “It can&#8217;t be done.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Don&#8217;t hear, “Nobody like you has done this before.”&nbsp; I like to say, “I eat no for breakfast.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ah!&nbsp; I love when you say that.&nbsp; I love when you say that.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Surround yourself with a community of people &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t have to be a big group &#8212; who love you and who will cheer you on and who will sometimes push you out the door to go and do.&nbsp; Those people who love you and you trust enough that when you fall down, they&#8217;ll be there to laugh with you because you fell, but to help pick you up and keep you going.&nbsp;<br><br>So, choose &#8212; especially to the young leaders, I’d say, but to all of us have every generation &#8212; choose who is in your life based on loving yourself and requiring that from other people.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s so important.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s one thing.<br><br>I would say the other thing is that to really know that you have so much to bring, and you have to look inward.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, and also have faith.&nbsp; You know, have faith.&nbsp; And have faith in whatever it is you believe in, that &#8212; that you were destined to do great things, even when the obstacles are there.&nbsp; But to believe in yourself and to have faith in yourself, that&#8217;s so important.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And then, finally, just to remember you&#8217;re not alone.&nbsp; I mean, so many of us have had the experience of walking into a room where they’re &#8212; we&#8217;re the only one who looks like us or has had our life experience.&nbsp; And so, to you, I would say: When you walk in these rooms, remember this room for a minute.&nbsp; Remember this room.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, yes.&nbsp; Yes!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And remember when you walk into those rooms, that we’re walking into that room with you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp; We are all in that room with you, and we are applauding you.&nbsp; And we are expecting you will carry our voice into that room.&nbsp; And we are applauding you, and we are with you every step of the way.&nbsp; So shoulders back, chin up, and just be yourself.&nbsp; Be your marvelous self.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ah, yes!&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Just be yourself.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, Madam Vice President, I just thank you so much.&nbsp; I am so grateful to have gotten the opportunity to see you up close in this way &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and see you speaking.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And people just stand for you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an inspiration.&nbsp; You truly are.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Keke.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And thank you for your time.&nbsp; Thank you for being here.&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So good to be here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And thank you guys for being a part of the conversation as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Essence, obviously.&nbsp;<br><br>Take care, guys.&nbsp; Bye-bye.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 5:01 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What They are Reading in the States: Biden-&#8288;Harris Officials Lead a Nationwide Economic Travel&#160;Blitz</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/02/what-they-are-reading-in-the-states-biden-harris-officials-lead-a-nationwide-economic-travel-blitz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 19:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, as President Biden showcased America’s leadership on the world stage, Biden-Harris Cabinet members and administration officials led a nationwide economic travel blitz to highlight how the President’s economic agenda is delivering results for communities here in the states. &#160; Biden-Harris officials fanned out across the country – from Alabama to Alaska – and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, as President Biden showcased America’s leadership on the world stage, Biden-Harris Cabinet members and administration officials led a nationwide economic travel blitz to highlight how the President’s economic agenda is delivering results for communities here in the states. &nbsp;<br><br>Biden-Harris officials fanned out across the country – from Alabama to Alaska – and spoke directly to the American people about the actions the Biden-Harris Administration is taking to tackle inflation, lower costs for families, create good-paying union jobs, and how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and Bipartisan Innovation Act will help America win the competition for the 21<sup>st</sup> century.<br><br>See below for a sampling of what Americans are reading in the states following this week’s economic travel blitz.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://mcusercontent.com/c97630621baff8c44fe607661/images/f21e6037-0526-05fb-861c-68707f310fe1.jpg" alt="" /></figure>



<p><strong><em>Transportation Secretary Buttigieg, Office of Management &amp; Budget Director Young, EPA Administrator Regan and Infrastructure Coordinator Landrieu in Louisiana</em></strong><br><br><strong>New Orleans Advocate: <a href="https://www.nola.com/news/politics/article_83d6abe6-f98f-11ec-9ba5-d752156fe333.html">Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg has list of projects from Louisiana to consider</a></strong><br>Louisiana will get its share of the more than $1 trillion in infrastructure spending that President Joe Biden and Congress are sending to states, Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg said Friday. “A lot of the opportunities for passenger rail are in Louisiana and the Gulf Coast,” Buttigieg said. “Part of it is funding, but part of it is having the right support for passenger rail when it’s running on lines that are owned by the freight railways. Freight railroads have a business responsibility, but they also have a legal responsibility to be good hosts to passenger rail when it’s on their metal.”</p>



<p><strong>Times Picayune: <a href="https://www.nola.com/news/politics/article_efe86b06-f98c-11ec-a560-036948ffb803.html">Shalanda Young found her way from Clinton, via Loyola and Tulane, to head federal budget office</a></strong><br>“This” was to become in March the first Black woman to serve as director of the Office of Management and Budget, a federal agency that’s little known outside of Washington but that makes spending and regulatory decisions that affect all Americans. Young was speaking Friday after appearing on a panel at the Essence Festival with two other Biden administration cabinet officials – Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg and Environmental Protection Agency administrator Michael Regan. [….] Asked about the one Louisiana issue that captures her attention at OMB, Young replied, “Disaster, disaster, disaster response. It is something personal to me. After Katrina, I got to work on aid as an Appropriations baby staffer. I’ve kept that interest all through my career and have worked with the Louisiana delegation to make sure Louisiana has the resources.” [….] Noting that President Biden visited Lake Charles in May 2021, in the wake of hurricanes Laura and Delta, Young said, “I get to work with someone who wants to deliver for everybody. There shouldn’t be any partisan politics in disaster response.”<br><br><strong>NOLA.com: <a href="https://www.nola.com/news/environment/article_d61a1818-f965-11ec-a9d1-9bfca44a6115.html">EPA chief says Supreme Court ruling won&#8217;t block efforts to curb climate change</a></strong><br>With the EPA taking a lead role, President Joe Biden’s administration had aimed to slash carbon emissions in half by 2030 and eventually steer the power sector toward an emissions-free goal before 2040. Regan says that goal is still achievable. The EPA is still assessing the full impact of the decision on its ability to regulate power plants, but Regan said the agency can take an even more aggressive approach against other emitters, including vehicles and the oil and gas industry. “We’ve already (enacted) the most stringent emission standards on light-duty cars, and we’re proposing more for heavy duty vehicles,” he said. “And we’ve proposed rules for methane emissions for the oil and gas industry that are the most stringent in history.” The agency is also curbing the use of hydrofluorocarbons, the climate-warming chemicals used in air-conditioners and refrigerators.<br><br><strong><em>Commerce Secretary Raimondo at SelectUSA Summit in Maryland</em></strong><br><br><strong>Reuters: <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/us-commerce-secretary-presses-lawmakers-greenlight-52-bln-chipmaking-2022-06-27/">U.S. commerce secretary presses lawmakers to greenlight $52 bln for chipmaking</a></strong><br><br>US Commerce Department Secretary Gina Raimondo on Monday stepped up pressure on Congress to approve US$52 billion in funding for chip makers to expand operations, warning that firms would abandon American expansion plans without the legislation … Raimondo’s warning came after Taiwan’s GlobalWafers announced plans earlier on Monday to build a US$5 billion plant in Sherman, Texas to produce the silicon wafers needed for manufacturing chips. Raimondo said the company’s CEO told her the investment was contingent on Congress approving the funding.<br><br><strong>Bloomberg: <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-06-27/taiwan-s-globalwafers-plans-to-build-chip-wafer-factory-in-texas#xj4y7vzkg">Taiwan’s GlobalWafers to Build $5 Billion Chip Plant in Texas</a></strong><br>Speaking at an investment summit Monday, Commerce Secretary Gina Raimondo said the US currently produces 10% to 12% of the world’s microprocessor chips, down from nearly 40% in earlier years. “We took our eye off the ball,” the secretary said. “We stopped investing in chip manufacturing and chip R&amp;D. And, in search of cheap labor, we watched a lot of our manufacturing leave our shores.” The Biden administration has for months sought the passage of a bill that would appropriate $52 billion for domestic semiconductor manufacturing. The legislation would provide billions of dollars to boost research and development with an eye toward creating new technologies to help the US stay ahead of a rising China.<br><br><strong><em>Housing and Urban Development Secretary Fudge in Florida</em></strong><br><br><strong>WFOR (CBS Miami, FL): </strong><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/miami/news/us-hud-secretary-marcia-fudge-south-florida-affordable-housing/"><strong>HUD Secretary Marcia Fudge visits South Florida to get firsthand look at housing crisis</strong></a><br>Housing and Urban Development Secretary Marcia Fudge&#8217;s first stop was Lauderhill Point, a HUD apartment complex for 176 low-income families currently undergoing renovation. &#8220;It is so different when you see it for yourself, that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m here, it is important that we address the housing crisis,&#8221; she said…. The Biden administration has allocated $10 billion dollars for housing grants administered by HUD and has requested $30 billion more. Millions of dollars are headed to Florida….</p>



<p><strong>Florida Times-Union: </strong><a href="https://www.jacksonville.com/story/news/local/2022/06/27/hud-secretary-marcia-fudge-visits-jacksonville-apartments-homeless/7748240001/"><strong>HUD secretary calls Hilltop Village a &#8216;success story&#8217; following turnaround at Jacksonville apartments</strong></a><br>Local, state and federal officials convened in Jacksonville on Monday to tour several federally supported housing complexes and tout positive changes made at Hilltop Village apartments, a complex that has been rife with problems for years&#8230; During a news conference after the tours at St. Clair Evans Academy, Fudge said Hilltop has had a new management company for the last five months and work has continued on improving the complex and ridding it of a rodent infestation. Several residents of Hilltop also spoke and agreed that living conditions at the apartment complex have improved.</p>



<p><strong>Miami Herald: </strong><a href="https://www.miamiherald.com/news/local/community/miami-dade/article262956308.html"><strong>Biden’s housing chief calls Miami the ‘epicenter of the housing crisis in this country’</strong></a><br>The nation’s top housing official visited Miami on Tuesday and called the city the “epicenter” of a housing crisis in the United States. “I decided I was going to Miami, to the epicenter of the housing crisis in this country,” Marcia Fudge, secretary of Housing and Urban Development, said during a visit to Miami-Dade County’s Liberty Square complex. In Miami-Dade, HUD funding provides the bulk of the county’s $700 million budget for public housing, which includes complexes such as Liberty Square and rental vouchers under the federal Section 8 program, which subsidizes rents for low-income residents with requirements for stable rents and price caps.<br><br><strong><em>Energy Secretary Granholm in Pennsylvania &nbsp;</em></strong><br><br><strong>TribLive: </strong><a href="https://triblive.com/local/sewickley/energy-secretary-granholm-talks-western-pa-s-clean-energy-future-during-visit/"><strong>Officials say Western Pa. can lead way in clean energy industry</strong></a><br>On Tuesday, U.S. Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm visited the Pittsburgh region to meet regional leaders to discuss the Southwestern Pennsylvania’s future in the clean energy sector…First, Granholm toured a former steel factory in Leetsdale that has been converted into a solar manufacturing facility with U.S. Sen. Bob Casey, D-Scranton, and U.S. Rep. Conor Lamb, D-Mt. Lebanon…Then, Granholm joined a roundtable at the United Steelworkers Building in Downtown Pittsburgh to discuss the region’s efforts to rebuild the energy sector by embracing energy storage technology, hydrogen, natural gas, nuclear, and green buildings.<br><br><strong>WPXI (NBC Pittsburgh, PA): </strong><a href="https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/us-energy-secretary-sen-bob-casey-leetsdale-celebrate-grand-opening-new-steel-facility/GA5MMCBA45DANCZZZGP2OBZ7DM/"><strong>US energy secretary, Sen. Bob Casey in Leetsdale to celebrate grand opening of new steel facility</strong></a><br>U.S. Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm and Sen. Bob Casey (D-PA) were in Leetsdale, Allegheny County on Tuesday to celebrate the grand opening of a new BCI Steel production facility at the site of a former Bethlehem Steel plant…“Pittsburgh is the emblematic community that has risen from the ashes, like a phoenix,” said Granholm…“It’s going to put a lot of our people to work, but it also shows our commitment to investing in the future,” said Allegheny County Executive Rich Fitzgerald.<br><br><strong>Pittsburgh Post-Gazette: </strong><a href="https://www.post-gazette.com/business/powersource/2022/06/28/american-solar-energy-development-bci-engineering-nextrackers-steel-jennifer-granholm-dan-shugar/stories/202206290061"><strong>U.S. Steel meets U.S. solar in Leetsdale manufacturing facility</strong></a><br>Energy Secretary Jennifer Granholm knows how to work a metaphor…“This facility built landing craft for the invasion of Normandy,” she said on Tuesday…”What you’ll be delivering might be part of the biggest peace plan in the world,” she said…Ms. Granholm then headed to Downtown to hold a roundtable on energy jobs at the headquarters of United Steelworkers. The Department of Energy released its annual energy jobs report on Tuesday, which estimated that Pennsylvania now has more solar jobs than coal jobs (5,339 vs. 5,062).<br><br><strong><em>Transportation Secretary Buttigieg in Alabama</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Alabama Reporter: <a href="https://www.alreporter.com/2022/07/01/transportation-secretary-pete-buttigieg-visits-birmingham-to-announce-1-billion-program/">Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg visits Birmingham to announce $1 billion program</a></strong><br>U.S. Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg, joined by Congresswoman Terri Sewell, D-Alabama, visited Birmingham on Thursday to announce the U.S. Department of Transportation’s new Reconnecting Communities program, a $1 billion plan designed to restore community contact to transportation and increase economic opportunity. “Transportation can connect us to jobs, services, and loved ones, but we’ve also seen countless cases around the country where a piece of infrastructure cuts off a neighborhood or a community because of how it was built,” Buttigieg said. “Using funds from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we are proud to announce the launch of Reconnecting Communities: the first-ever dedicated federal initiative to unify neighborhoods living with the impacts of past infrastructure choices that divided them.”</p>



<p><strong>WIAT (CBS Birmingham, AL): <a href="https://www.cbs42.com/news/u-s-transportation-secretary-pete-buttigieg-promotes-new-birmingham-bus-system-as-part-of-infrastructure-pilot-program/">U.S. Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg promotes new Birmingham bus system as part of infrastructure pilot program</a></strong><br>U.S. Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg made a stop in Birmingham Thursday to promote a new bus transit system as an example of what further infrastructure funding can do to connect communities. The Birmingham Xpress is set to start running in September, a 15-mile bus route between Five Points West and Woodlawn. Buttigieg was in the city to support the $20 million project funded through the ‘Reconnecting Communities’ Pilot Program that’s part of the bipartisan infrastructure law passed last year. “It’s a major milestone that we have been working on throughout this administration,” Buttigieg said.</p>



<p><strong><em>Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator Landrieu in Colorado</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>KDVR (Fox Denver, CO):</strong><a href="https://kdvr.com/news/local/polis-state-leaders-highlight-new-money-for-central-70-project/"><strong>Polis, state leaders highlight new money for Central 70 Project</strong></a><br>The Central 70 Project, which completely redeveloped a 10-mile stretch of Interstate 70 through Denver and removed an aging viaduct in the area, will see a boost in funding from the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act… Wednesday, Gov. Jared Polis joined Senator Michael Bennet, Denver Mayor Michael Hancock and Congresswoman Diana DeGette to welcome White House Senior Advisor and Infrastructure Coordinator Mitch Landrieu to highlight how the new infrastructure act will impact the massive improvement to the highway.</p>



<p><strong>CBS Colorado: </strong><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/colorado/news/central-70-project-celebrated-construction-nears-completion/"><strong>Central 70 Project celebrated, construction nears completion</strong></a><br>The Colorado Department of Transportation is celebrating the near completion of the Central 70 Project. The White House infrastructure coordinator was invited to see the major milestone. The project improves safety through the 10-mile stretch between I-25 and Chambers Road by widening lanes and shoulders as well as improving ramps and bridges… Gov. Jared Polis, Senator Michael Bennet, Denver Mayor Michael Hancock, Rep. Diana DeGette all welcomed White House Senior Advisor and Infrastructure Coordinator Mitch Landrieu to Colorado on Wednesday morning.<br><br><strong><em>U.S. Trade Representative Tai in Alaska</em></strong><br><br><strong>KTUU (NBC Anchorage, AK): </strong><a href="https://www.alaskasnewssource.com/2022/07/01/alaskan-fishing-industry-leaders-meet-with-us-trade-ambassador-anchorage/"><strong>Alaskan fishing industry leaders meet with US trade ambassador in Anchorage</strong></a><br>Ambassador Katherine Tai, the United States trade representative, and Sen. Dan Sullivan held a roundtable discussion with leaders from the state’s fishing industry at Hotel Captain Cook on Thursday… The U.S. trade representative said Alaskan seafood exports totaled over $2 billion in 2021. She also touched on the work being done by the Biden administration to level the playing field for the American fishing industry against countries like China.<br><br><strong><em>Labor Secretary Walsh in Mississippi &amp; Arkansas</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Arkansas Times: </strong><a href="https://arktimes.com/arkansas-blog/2022/06/29/2-million-of-federal-funds-is-coming-to-little-rock-workforce-development-board"><strong>$2 million of federal funds is coming to Little Rock Workforce Development Board</strong></a><br>U.S. Secretary of Labor Marty Walsh visited Philander Smith College Wednesday to announce a $2 million grant for the Little Rock Workforce Development Board — one of 18 organizations to receive a grant nationwide. In total, $50.6 million of the federal funding — Pathway Home grants — will “provide training and employment services to adults reentering the workforce following incarceration in a local jail or state correctional facility,” according to a press release. “These grants will help people who are working for second chances,” Walsh said. “They’re about reducing crime. They’re also about meeting the needs of the local labor markets, like here, in Little Rock.”</p>



<p><strong>Mississippi Public </strong><a href="https://www.mpbonline.org/blogs/news/labor-officials-discuss-how-how-to-protect-mississippis-workforce/"><strong>Broadcasting: Labor officials discuss how to protect Mississippi&#8217;s workforce</strong></a><br>Mississippi is one of several states that limits the right to unionize, with laws that allow employers to terminate someone at any time. The state also does not have a Department of Labor, and Secretary Marty Walsh with the US. Department of Labor says that places his office as the closest governing body. He is speaking with workers&#8217; rights groups across the state about the hurdles facing Mississippi’s workforce. “Hopefully, working supporting people, continuing to fight for wage equity, gender equity, pay equity, and other issue pay equity,” says Walsh. “In this country, the fact that we pay women less than men, and make excuses for whey we do that, that’s just wrong. It’s 2022, it’s time to whatever job a man has and a woman does the same exact job, she would be paid the same exact rate.”<br><br><strong><em>Agriculture Secretary Vilsack in Iowa</em></strong><br><br><strong>Iowa Capital Dispatch: </strong><a href="https://iowacapitaldispatch.com/2022/06/28/vilsack-usda-grant-program-agricultural-waste/"><strong>Vilsack announces $10 million grant program to develop new uses for ag waste</strong></a><br>U.S. Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack, during an eastern Iowa visit Tuesday, announced a $10 million initiative to help farms and businesses find uses for waste byproducts. The grant program is one piece of President Joe Biden’s $1 trillion infrastructure law, passed in November.</p>



<p><strong>Cedar Rapids Gazette: </strong><a href="https://www.thegazette.com/government-politics/vilsack-announces-10m-grant-program-to-find-uses-for-ag-waste/"><strong>Vilsack announces $10M grant program to find uses for ag waste</strong></a><br>For U.S. Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack, infrastructure is not just about investing in roads and bridges and broadband internet. It’s also about investing in the future and inspiring innovation, he says… At an event Tuesday at Dan and Debbie’s Creamery in Ely, the head of the U.S. Department of Agriculture and former Iowa governor announced funding for a program created under the $1 trillion bipartisan infrastructure bill signed into law by President Joe Biden.</p>



<p><strong>Iowa Capital Dispatch: </strong><a href="https://iowacapitaldispatch.com/2022/06/29/vilsack-axne-urge-iowa-farmers-to-apply-for-derecho-relief-funds/"><strong>Vilsack, Axne urge Iowa farmers to apply for derecho relief funds</strong></a><br>Farms across Iowa – and much of the Midwest – faced billions of dollars of damage in August 2020, when the windstorm destroyed crops, silos and barns. But farms do not have to recover from those damages alone: They can take advantage of Emergency Relief Program funds to recoup financial losses, Vilsack and Axne said.<br><br><strong><em>Labor Secretary Walsh in Arkansas and Mississippi</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>KUAR (NPR Little Rock, AR): </strong><a href="https://www.ualrpublicradio.org/local-regional-news/2022-06-29/u-s-labor-secretary-announces-job-training-initiative-during-little-rock-visit"><strong>U.S. Labor Secretary announces job training initiative during Little Rock visit</strong></a><br>Arkansas is getting $2 million from the federal government to help adults re-enter the workforce after being incarcerated. The funding from the U.S. Department of Labor will go to the Little Rock Workforce Development Board to provide training and employment services for people recently released from jails and prisons. Labor Secretary Marty Walsh announced the funding in a visit to Little Rock’s Philander Smith College on Wednesday. “These grants will help people who are working for second chances, they’re about reducing crime. They’re also about meeting the needs of the local labor markets, like here in Little Rock,” Walsh said.<br><br><strong>Clarion Ledger: </strong><a href="https://www.clarionledger.com/story/news/2022/07/01/u-s-labor-secretary-marty-walsh-lead-labor-discussion/7788842001/"><strong>U.S. Labor Secretary Marty Walsh leads labor discussion at Jackson State University</strong></a><br>U.S. Labor Secretary Marty Walsh made his third stop in two days in the South on Thursday when he headlined a roundtable discussion on workers’ rights at Jackson State University. After stops in Little Rock, Arkansas, and Greenville, Walsh, the former mayor of Boston, spoke to a room of nearly 100 people on the struggles many in the Mid-South and across the nation are facing regarding workplace rights, compensation and conditions. He made note of the H-2A Visa Program, which is meant to help employers find workers where there aren’t enough workers. Instead, in the Mississippi Delta, Walsh said farmers are using the program to bring in foreign workers at a lower wage to replace Black farm workers who have been in place for many years. Walsh said that in his role as Labor Secretary, he wants to help make life better for people and hopes honest dialogue will help educate people in the South and the rest of the country. “I am taking much of this back with me to Washington, D.C., and see how we can make a difference,” Walsh said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to Certain Congressional Committees on the Republic of Finland&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty&#160;Organization</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/02/letter-to-certain-congressional-committees-on-the-republic-of-finlands-accession-to-the-north-atlantic-treaty-organization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 17:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Mr. Chairman&#160;&#160; (Dear Madam Chair:) I am providing the report on the Republic of Finland&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, prepared consistent with section 3(2)(E)(ii) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to the Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Mr. Chairman&nbsp;&nbsp; (Dear Madam Chair:)</p>



<p>I am providing the report on the Republic of Finland&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, prepared consistent with section 3(2)(E)(ii) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to the Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the Czech Republic of April 30, 1998.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to Certain Congressional Committees on the Kingdom of Sweden&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty&#160;Organization</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/02/letter-to-certain-congressional-committees-on-the-kingdom-of-swedens-accession-to-the-north-atlantic-treaty-organization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 17:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56773</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Mr. Chairman:&#160; (Dear Madam Chair:) I am providing the report on the Kingdom of Sweden&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, prepared consistent with section 3(2)(E)(ii) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to the Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Mr. Chairman:&nbsp; (Dear Madam Chair:)</p>



<p>I am providing the report on the Kingdom of Sweden&#8217;s Accession to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, prepared consistent with section 3(2)(E)(ii) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to the Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the Czech Republic of April 30, 1998.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden During a Virtual Meeting with Governors on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/02/remarks-by-president-biden-during-a-virtual-meeting-with-governors-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 13:07:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building (July 1, 2022) 1:16 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, everyone.  Thank you for doing this.  Thanks.  I’ll leave it to you.  I open it up?  Okay.  MS. KLEIN:  You open it up. THE PRESIDENT:  I know you’re all busy as I am.  Thank you for making the time with us.  I need not tell&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 1, 2022)</p>



<p>1:16 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, everyone.  Thank you for doing this.  Thanks. <br> <br>I’ll leave it to you. <br> <br>I open it up?  Okay. <br> <br>MS. KLEIN:  You open it up.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I know you’re all busy as I am.  Thank you for making the time with us.  I need not tell any of you we’re in a really important area here and we have to act. <br> <br>I’m joined by a group of Democratic governors as we work closely to protect women’s rights after this tragic reversal of Roe v. Wade &#8212; a terrible, extreme decision, in my view, upending the lives and impacting on the health and safety of millions of women. <br> <br>And I share the public outrage at this extremist Court that’s committed to moving America backwards with fewer rights, less autonomy, and politicians invading the most personal of decisions of not only women but we’ll find, if they expend &#8212; expand on this decision, men as well.<br> <br>But as I said last week, this is not over.  Last week, I announced two specific actions.  First, if extremist governors try to block a woman from traveling from her state that prohibits her from seeking the medical help she needs to a state that provides that care, the federal government will act to protect her bedrock right through the Attorneys General’s Office.<br> <br>Second, if states try to block a woman from getting medication the FDA has already approved and has been available for more than 20 years, my administration will act and protect that woman’s right to that medication. <br> <br>And there are many other unlawful actions, in my view, that states are preparing to take that will have &#8212; we’ll have to address as well. <br> <br>But ultimately, Congress is going to have to act to codify Roe into federal law.  And as I said yesterday, the filibuster should not stand in the way of us being able to do that.<br> <br>But right now, we don’t have the votes in the Senate to change the filibuster on &#8212; on &#8212; at the moment.  That means we need two more votes now &#8212; not now &#8212; when we vote, probably after November &#8212; more senators and House majority &#8212; and the House majority elected in November to get this bill to my desk.<br> <br>So, the choice is clear: We either elect federal Senators and Representatives who will codify Roe, or Republicans who will elect the House and Senate will try to ban abortions nationwide.  Nationwide.  This is going to go one way or the other after November. <br> <br>So let’s remember: The reasoning of this decision has an impact much beyond Roe and to the right to privacy more generally. <br> <br>Justice Thomas himself said that, under the reasoning of this decision, that the Court should reconsider marriage equality and contraception. <br> <br>And there’s a lot at stake. <br> <br>In the meantime, I want to hear what the governors are doing, talk about my plans, and discuss what we can do as &#8212; until Congress acts. <br> <br>This is not over.  This is not over. <br> <br>Now I’m going to turn it over to Jen Klein, the head of the White House Gender Policy Council.  And we’ll proceed with the discussions.<br> <br>Jen?<br> <br>MS. KLEIN:  Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  And I’d like to add my thanks to each of you for joining and for your leadership.<br> <br>We’d, as the President just said, really like to hear from you about both what you&#8217;ve done and further action that you&#8217;re planning to take.  So we&#8217;re going to start with you, Governor Hochul, from New York.  Over to you.<br> <br>GOVERNOR HOCHUL:  Thank you, Jen.  And thank you, Mr. President, for convening us with the sense of urgency that I feel that you are conveying, because this is a frightening time for women all across our nation.  A lot of fear and anxiety out there.  And I hear it from women all across the state, or they come up to me at subway stops in New York City, at farmers’ markets.  Literally, young women who never even had to think about this right are coming up and putting their arms around my neck and sobbing.<br> <br>So there is such stress out there.  So we &#8212; in the state of New York, this came the day after the Supreme Court also told us that we did not have the right to protect our citizens from people carrying concealed weapons in places like subways, in Times Square, et cetera.  So what I had to do is convene an extraordinary session &#8212; because they weren&#8217;t due back until January. <br> <br>I brought them back and, literally at 2:00 a.m. this morning, while we&#8217;re still working on the gun legislation, I changed my proclamation to say we&#8217;ll also include to give further protections for women in the state &#8212; what we call the Equality Agenda.  This will prohibit discrimination on the basis of pregnancy and pregnancy outcomes and reproductive healthcare and autonomy.<br> <br>So we&#8217;re one step closer as of this afternoon &#8212; I think it&#8217;s going to be passed by both houses &#8212; to enshrine abortion rights in our state constitution.  So as long as I&#8217;m Governor, these rights will not be rolled back.<br> <br>But we also are prepared to serve as a destination for women who will be looking to a place like New York and other states &#8212; some of my colleagues on the call &#8212; as a safe harbor.<br> <br>So even before the Supreme Court decision, I knew I had to beef up our opportunities for women to come from other states.  We allocated $35 million right off the bat to go to providers so they could hire more people, expand their space, and make sure that they can keep their staff safe from violence as well.<br> <br>And we also decided to mandate: All insurance companies doing business in the state of New York now have to cover abortion.  And I signed six bills related to protecting our providers after the decision came down.  We&#8217;ll stop the extradition of any &#8212; any search for &#8212; when our providers or a woman who&#8217;s in our state who are wanted under criminal charges.  That&#8217;s not happening in New York.  And we&#8217;re also defending our abortion providers from malpractice and other lawsuits.<br> <br>We also launched a public awareness campaign, because there&#8217;s a lot of misinformation.  Women in New York are seeing the national news; they don&#8217;t know whether their rights are protected here in New York. <br> <br>So we&#8217;re going to continue to be leaders in this fight, protect our providers &#8212; protect them from the vigilante justice, which has been unleashed by the states that are going to allow these private rights of action where they&#8217;re going to hunt down women and providers. <br> <br>This is, you know, chaos.  It&#8217;s frightening.  But also, we&#8217;re doing what we can to make sure that, you know, we are protected.<br> <br>What&#8217;s happening now: The rights of millions of women across this country are now falling on the shourder [sic] &#8212; shoulders of just a handful of states.  Just a handful of states are now going to have to take care of the healthcare of women from other states.<br> <br>So we believe as you do, Mr. President, that what&#8217;s available to New Yorkers and the other enlightened states should be available to all Americans.  And no one should have to travel.<br> <br>And that&#8217;s why, as you agree with us, Congress has to act.  And we sent a letter way back, to Congress, saying, “Please pass the Women&#8217;s Health Protection Act.  Let&#8217;s get it through the Senate.”<br> <br>So what we&#8217;re doing at the state level is key.  But I completely agree with you and I commend you, Mr. President, for standing up and talking about the fact that it is the filibuster that&#8217;s preventing the majority of senators, and it is the majority of senators who want to speak on behalf of the majority of Americans.<br> <br>But we understand our options are limited until next January, with a new Senate.  And we&#8217;re all going to be focusing very hard on that outcome because it is a matter of life and death for American women, because we do not want to go back to the days, anywhere in this country, of the back-alley abortions, which are real.  I talked to one of my neighbors down the hall who use- &#8212; whose husband used to perform these abortions before abortion was legal in New York State in 1970. <br> <br>And so this is not just hyperbole, it is real.<br> <br>So what we&#8217;re asking to help continue at the federal level: We believe that more can be done to fund family planning services more broadly to allow the providers and their clinics to have sta- &#8212; federal resources for these services, and<br>they can focus on private dollars for abortion services.<br> <br>And I&#8217;m really grateful that you&#8217;re putting an emphasis on what&#8217;s going to happen for women to be able to continue to receive abortion services by mail.  I mean, this is going to be a battle that when &#8212; that people would not have foreseen.  We want to make sure that there&#8217;s no unlawful interference.  And we have to do that to ease public concerns.<br> <br>And also, Mr. President, we&#8217;d ask that you consider your ability to use federal facilities.  What am I talking about?  Veterans’ hospitals, military bases, and other places where the federal government controls the jurisdiction in some of the states that are hostile to women&#8217;s rights, and make sure that those services can be available to other women. <br> <br>So those are just a few of the ideas that we encourage you to look at &#8212; an idea of what we&#8217;re doing at the New York State level.  But literally before close of business today, we will have the first step toward a process of changing our Constitution, which is the boldest step we can take.  And we just started that today.<br> <br>So &#8212; so thank you for convening us.  We are there to stand with you to do something that &#8212; protect a right that my mother&#8217;s generation had to fight for, I fought for, my daughter who&#8217;s in her 30s had to fight for, and now, Mr. President, I have a grand-new [sic] &#8212; brand-new granddaughter, and thank you for your note acknowledging that.<br> <br>I didn&#8217;t think we&#8217;d have to fight this battle for her generation as well, but apparently we do.  But we are ready to take on that fight. <br> <br>So, thank you.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, I didn&#8217;t think we would either.  I was worried we would.  But, you know, I think that a lot of the folks don&#8217;t understand what this decision means.  It means if &#8212; if you got a 11-year-old child who&#8217;s a victim of incest and finds herself pregnant, which occurs, that, you know, she can&#8217;t get choice, she &#8212; she can&#8217;t &#8212; her health can&#8217;t be protected.  You find, you know, if you&#8217;re raped, there&#8217;s no exception.<br> <br>I mean, there&#8217;s so many things that people really haven&#8217;t focused on yet, beyond the fundamental right of a woman to be able to choose. <br> <br>And so I just think that, as you pointed out, Kathy, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be a big deal that we get people out to vote, because here’s what&#8217;s going to happen, I predict: If we don&#8217;t &#8212; if we don&#8217;t take this &#8212; keep the Senate, increase it in the House, we&#8217;re going to be in a situation where the Republicans are going to pass a nationwide prohibition consistent with what the Supreme Court ruled.<br> <br>And so, there&#8217;s a lot at stake here.  But I&#8217;m sure glad you&#8217;re leading New York.  For real. <br> <br>GOVERNOR HOCHUL:  Thank you, Mr. President.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Thank you.<br> <br>MS. KLEIN:  Thank you, Governor Hochul.  I&#8217;m now going to turn to Governor Cooper.<br> <br>GOVERNOR COOPER:  Thanks, Jen.  Thanks, Mr. President, for convening this call and for your leadership, particularly on the filibuster.<br> <br>And unlike Governor Hochul in New York, our Republican legislature is not going to amend the Constitution, but this Democratic governor is going to hold the line to protect women&#8217;s reproductive freedom in our state.<br> <br>It has really been devastating for so many, as reproductive care really has been halted in its tracks in many places across the country.  That constitutional right that women have relied on for five decades has been ripped away.  And for now, at least, where you live will determine your rights. <br> <br>So, for now, it&#8217;s up to the states to determine whether can &#8212; women can get reproductive healthcare.  And in North Carolina, they still can.  And I&#8217;m determined to keep it that way. <br> <br>Because of our location in the southeast, Mr. President, North Carolina is already seeing an influx of patients coming to our state for safe care.  According to Planned Parenthood of the South Atlantic, their clinics in North Carolina have scheduled 192 patients from out of state for the next week alone.  That means about 10,000 extra patients from out of state coming to North Carolina in the next year, mostly from states that have bans and tighter restrictions. <br> <br>And those, Mr. President, are just the numbers from Planned Parenthood.  That doesn&#8217;t include our state&#8217;s other trusted providers, so we know those numbers will be a lot higher.<br> <br>Your ZIP code should not determine your rights.  North Carolina has a law that&#8217;s going to prevent obstructing access to these clinics.  And we&#8217;re working with law enforcement to make sure that that law is enforced. <br> <br>Women and doctors should not have these politicians in the exam room with them looking over their shoulders.  And I&#8217;m going to continue to trust women to make their own medical decisions.<br> <br>Now, a large part of that, at least for North Carolina, Mr. President, is keeping enough Democratic state legislators in our state to sustain my vetoes, as they have a time and again before. <br> <br>And it also means keeping and electing more Democratic governors across the country this November.  And that is my mission as Chair of the Democratic Governors Association this year.  Because, Mr. President, governors &#8212; right now, governors really are the last line of defense.  And they&#8217;re also the first chance at progress, which you&#8217;re going to hear today, especially with this Supreme Court on such a destructive path.<br> <br>Mr. President, the stakes are high, but they have never been clearer.  We are not &#8212; we are not backing down.  We are ready to do what is needed to protect women&#8217;s health.  And, Mr. President, I urge you to do everything you can on the federal level while we work hard in the states. <br> <br>Thanks.  Thanks for this opportunity.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, Gov &#8212; look, Roy, you&#8217;re doing a heck of a job, and a lot of your colleagues on this call are as well.  I &#8212; I assure you that &#8212; I got off the phone today with the Attorney General before I came in.  Matter of fact, it was one of the reasons I was &#8212; excuse me &#8212; a few minutes late.  And we&#8217;re going to do everything within the power of the federal government to make sure that any attempt to obstruct &#8212; obstruct anything from travel to access to &#8212; to medicine is just not &#8212; it does not occur. <br> <br>We also, by the way &#8212; I think we’re going to have to see &#8212; and this relates to Governor Hochul as well &#8212; that funding for family planning, not &#8212; not &#8212; not for abortion, but for family planning. <br> <br>And there&#8217;s a lot we have to do, because a lot of women are &#8212; for example, a lot of the family planning has to do with whether or not a woman gets access &#8212; poor women get access to &#8212; to cancer care or things unrelated to choice. <br> <br>And so there&#8217;s a lot we have to do.  I think we can get it done.  I think the American people are with us.  And &#8212; and again, I thank you for your &#8212; for your leadership.  And I&#8217;m not being solicitous.  But you&#8217;re always there.  So, thanks, pal.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br> <br>GOVERNOR COOPER:  Thank you, Mr. President.  Grateful for you. <br> <br>MS. KLEIN:  And now we&#8217;re going to turn to Governor Lujan Grisham. <br> <br>GOVERNOR LUJAN GRISHAM:  Thank you, Jen.  And thank you, Mr. President.  And I&#8217;m delighted, frankly, to join the fight with my incredible Democratic gubernatorial colleagues; that we are, in fact, that brick wall against this horrific Supreme Court decision. <br> <br>And I also, Mr. President, really appreciate that you&#8217;ve continued to lean in, that this privacy rights debate extends far beyond choice.<br> <br>And we &#8212; what we do today in the space for protecting reproductive rights absolutely should move in the direction to prepare to protect everyone&#8217;s additional privacy rights, including making sure that we don&#8217;t roll backwards on same-sex marriage and other related issues.<br> <br>So, New Mexico certainly saw this coming as a potential.  We quickly &#8212; a year ago, I signed into law repealing an antiquated, unconstitutional law that criminalized &#8212; that could criminalize abortion care and abortion providers.  That is now repealed.  We did that last year. <br> <br>And in doing that, we also increased resources for family planning, contraceptives, reproductive care, abortion, abortion care services through all of our network of providers and through state funds.  We&#8217;ll continue to do that.<br> <br>Most recently, we signed an executive order following the same kinds of efforts you&#8217;re seeing now across the country, joining Massachusetts, as an example, but now New York: this is not a place where the draconian efforts by neighboring states, such as Texas, who have stated that they will, in fact, criminalize providers.  They’re looking for providers that have multiple state operations and licenses.  And this whole notion that you can criminalize the patient, including asking your neighbors and churches to turn your &#8212; your loved ones, family members, and neighbors in.<br> <br>We will not cooperate as a state in any of those efforts or investigations.  We will not extradite.  We will provide coverage and protection for all our providers and any individual seeking abortion care and abortion services in the state of New Mexico.<br> <br>Like my colleagues, we are seeing an increase, and we are working diligently to make sure that when we say and we mean that abortion is “legal, safe, and accessible,” that, in fact, it is.<br> <br>So, as you talk about what we can do, given this Supreme Court decision and given that my colleague, like Chairman Governor Roy Cooper, not every state has a democratically led legislature.<br> <br>We are going to need the feds to think about ways &#8212; not just the FDA protection &#8212; for making sure that telemedicine is available for contraceptives and abortion care.  But, in fact, we&#8217;re going to need to make sure that through a public health vehicle, that we are, in fact, doing family planning.  We should educate people; that should be a national campaign.  We should talk about access points.  We should be using school-based health centers.  There&#8217;s a number of things that we could use your assistance and your leadership. <br> <br>And you&#8217;re already leaning in that direction, not just on preventing the criminalization, but making sure we&#8217;re talking about where resources can, in fact, go that would protect women in states that have signaled that they have no interest &#8212; in their wholesale bans &#8212; in protecting women and other populations and keeping government out of their personal, autonomous decision-making.<br> <br>Two, I agree wholeheartedly with Governor Hochul that there are more federal opportunities, and she mentioned several.  I think that our Indian Health Service Clinics could be another effective vehicle.  I will tell you that there &#8212; I&#8217;ve been reached out by a number of sovereign nations who I think would be very supportive and interested.<br> <br>I certainly can&#8217;t speak to that across the country, but they&#8217;re clear that even a new recent Supreme Court decision limiting sovereignty has the same draconian, absolute &#8212; right? &#8212; unfairness that is looking at being applied through the Supreme Court to them.<br> <br>So I think that may be yet another vehicle that we could expand that would protect women and particularly minority populations all across the country.<br> <br>We stand ready to fight hard across the country and making sure that you have what you need in Congress so that we can codify Roe v. Wade, so that your states that stand as that safe haven and brick wall will continue to do that, and support us as many women and their families all across America who are going to need us as we fight to win this battle.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, Michelle, you&#8217;re already standing up for folks on your neighboring states.  It matters.  It matters a lot. <br> <br>And one of the things that I&#8217;m finding is that we are looking &#8212; beginning the process &#8212; or in the process of looking at all the alternatives, including the sovereign nation question.  And &#8212; but there&#8217;s going to be a lot more that&#8217;s going to come through.<br> <br>I mean, I think people are going to be shocked when the first state &#8212; the first state that tries to arrest a woman for crossing a state line to get health services, and they’re &#8212; I don&#8217;t think people believe that&#8217;s going to happen.  But it&#8217;s going to happen and it&#8217;s going to &#8212; it&#8217;s going to telegraph to the whole country that this is &#8212; this is a gigantic deal that goes beyond.  I mean, it affects all your basic rights. <br> <br>And &#8212; so at any rate, I thank you for all you’re &#8212; all you&#8217;re already doing.  And we&#8217;re going to take a quick little hesitation here.  The press is about to leave so we can continue.  If you all have a few more minutes, I want to talk to all of you, if you can. <br> <br>And while we&#8217;re waiting, think about what you think I should be doing, if you were sitting in my seat, that I should be considering that we haven&#8217;t already considered and could be useful.</p>



<p>1:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on National Wildland Firefighter&#160;Day</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/02/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-national-wildland-firefighter-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, on the first annual National Wildland Firefighter Day, I join Americans across the country in expressing deep gratitude for our wildland firefighters who heroically protect our communities and natural resources from wildfires.&#160; Recognizing their service and sacrifice on this day is especially important because we continue to ask more of them year after year.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, on the first annual National Wildland Firefighter Day, I join Americans across the country in expressing deep gratitude for our wildland firefighters who heroically protect our communities and natural resources from wildfires.&nbsp;<br><br>Recognizing their service and sacrifice on this day is especially important because we continue to ask more of them year after year. In the past year and a half, I’ve met firefighters in Idaho, California, Colorado, and New Mexico who work night and day to keep people safe, all while fires are getting larger, more intense, and more difficult to control because of climate change, the accumulation of hazardous fuels in our forests, and evolving land development patterns.&nbsp;<br><br>Firefighters can spend months away from their loved ones, courageously working to save lives, homes, schools, businesses, natural resources, and wilderness areas.&nbsp; Beyond fighting fires, these dedicated women and men also work year-round to protect us from wildfires before they start by doing the important fuels management work needed to reduce the likelihood of catastrophic fire. This work is tough and extremely dangerous.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why my Administration continues to make supporting this workforce a top priority.&nbsp; <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-acts-to-address-the-growing-wildfire-threat/">Building on what I initiated last year</a>, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law authorized historic new initiatives and resources for wildland firefighters that we are implementing now. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-pay-raises-supports-for-wildland-firefighter-workforce-from-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/">This includes a substantial pay</a> increase, new programs to support wildland firefighter mental and physical health, and the creation of a wildland firefighter job series that will improve recruitment, retention, and opportunities for professional growth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are also building our firefighting workforce, including converting more temporary firefighting positions to permanent jobs.  And we’re further supporting our brave firefighters by doing everything we can to help reduce the risk of catastrophic fires, including proposing a nearly 60 percent increase in hazardous fuels management funds in my Fiscal Year 2023 Budget Request, and investing another $2.5 billion in this work over the next five years through my Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br>National Wildland Firefighter Day will occur annually during the previously established wildland firefighter Week of Remembrance.  I’ve attended too many memorial services for the fallen, including almost nine years to the day, honoring 19 Granite Mountain Hotshot firefighters who died fighting the Yarnell Hill Fire in Arizona.  They were some of the strongest, most disciplined, tenacious, physically fit firefighters in the world.  So, this week we will also reflect on those firefighters who have fallen in the line of duty and renew our commitment to wildland firefighter safety.  We pause to remember them, commemorate their selfless service, and thank their loved ones for their service and many sacrifices.<br><br>May God bless firefighters and their families across our Nation. <br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 2022 Visitor Log Records&#160;Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2022/07/01/march-2022-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Disclosures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in March 2022. This set includes 6065 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 50817. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in March 2022. This set includes 6065 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 50817.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ICYMI:  President&#160;Biden Pushes Forward on Tackling Climate Crisis Despite Supreme Court’s Attempt to Take Country&#160;Backwards</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/01/icymi-president-biden-pushes-forward-on-tackling-climate-crisis-despite-supreme-courts-attempt-to-take-country-backwards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 20:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, in response to the Supreme Court’s ruling in West Virginia v. EPA, President Biden issued a statement on his unwavering commitment to “continue using lawful executive authority, including the EPA’s legally-upheld authorities, to keep our air clean, protect public health, and tackle the climate crisis” and “tackle environmental injustice, create good-paying jobs, and lower&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, in response to the Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>West Virginia v. EPA</em>, President Biden issued a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/30/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-supreme-court-ruling-on-west-virginia-v-epa/">statement</a> on his unwavering commitment to “continue using lawful executive authority, including the EPA’s legally-upheld authorities, to keep our air clean, protect public health, and tackle the climate crisis” and “tackle environmental injustice, create good-paying jobs, and lower costs for families building the clean energy economy.”<br><br>Vice President Harris <a href="https://twitter.com/VP/status/1542631060789293058">emphasized</a> that while “the Supreme Court’s misguided ruling aims to take our country backward,” through “executive authority, legislation, and state and local action, we must charge forward.” National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy <a href="https://twitter.com/ginamccarthy46">stressed</a> that even though the Supreme Court is “siding with extreme special interests that want to dismantle our right to clean air,” President Biden will “keep moving us forward, using every tool we can to tackle the climate crisis,” and EPA Administrator Michael Regan <a href="https://twitter.com/EPAMichaelRegan/status/1542656005644902401">made clear</a> that the agency “will move forward using our Clean Air Act authority, consistent with the law, to set greenhouse gas standards for power plants.”<br><br><em>Read more about how the Biden-Harris Administration is pressing ahead:</em><br><br><strong>Time: </strong><a href="https://time.com/6192857/biden-climate-scotus-west-virginia/">&#8216;We Have to Be Creative.&#8217; How the Biden Administration Is Responding to the SCOTUS Climate Setback</a><br>[Justin Worland, 6/30/22]<br><br>Gina McCarthy, President Joe Biden’s national climate advisor . . . was surprisingly optimistic—not that the ruling would go the Administration’s way, but rather that the White House could chart a path to slash emissions even if it didn’t. <strong>“We’ve set very solid goals, we’re making significant progress on the transition to clean energy,” she told TIME on June 28. “And that is not going to live and die by the Supreme Court’s decision.”</strong> To meet the White House’s goals, she said, the Administration needs to get “creative” and find novel ways to galvanize the energy transition. That includes . . . the Administration’s engagement with the private sector, use of its own purchasing power, and use of the Defense Production Act to accelerate the production of domestic clean energy technology, she says.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>PBS NewsHour:</strong><a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/amp/show/epa-administrator-michael-regan-discusses-supreme-court-ruling-on-climate-change">EPA Administrator Michael Regan discusses Supreme Court ruling on climate change</a><br>[Interview, 6/30/22]</p>



<p>EPA Administrator Michael Regan: “Let me be clear. It doesn&#8217;t take us out of the game. <strong>We still will be able to regulate climate pollution. And we&#8217;re going to use all of the tools in our toolbox to do so </strong>. . . One tool that we will continue to look at is the authority that was in question with the Supreme Court. Again, that tool is still available. We have just lost some flexibility there . . . But it does not prevent us from continuing to make progress. And so we will have to be vigilant in terms of focusing on climate change pollution . . . We&#8217;re going to use every tool in the toolbox that we have to set and implement environmental standards that meet our obligation to protect all people and all communities from environmental harm.”<br><br><strong>Gina McCarthy on CNN:</strong><a href="https://twitter.com/TheLeadCNN/status/1542642048016293889">The Lead with Jake Tapper</a><br>[Interview, 6/30/22]</p>



<p>National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy: “We are not giving up, we’re actually going to double down. And we know that <strong>we have the legal authority, and frankly we have the mandate of the people in the United States and across the world</strong> who want to address this challenge of climate change and do it in a way that makes positive improvements in our lives.”<br><br><strong>Gina McCarthy on NPR:</strong><a href="https://www.npr.org/2022/07/01/1109275642/has-the-supreme-court-tied-the-biden-administrations-hands-on-climate-change">Morning Edition</a><br>[Interview, 7/01/22]</p>



<p>National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy: “The Court hasn’t tied our hands on climate change . . . <strong>it was a very disappointing decision, but it did not strip away the ability for EPA to regulate greenhouse gases</strong> . . . and more broadly, people should understand that this President didn’t come into office thinking that EPA was the sole way in which we could move forward on climate change . . . He recognized that special interests for decades have been funded by fossil fuel companies to really wage a long-term campaign to strip away all these environmental protections that keep our water and our air clean . . . but that’s why the President said we’re not just going to rely on EPA, we’re going to have a whole-of-government approach . . . we’re leaving no stone unturned . . . to invest in a clean energy future.”</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at Richmond and Henrico Health District&#8217;s East&#160;Clinic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/01/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-richmond-and-henrico-health-districts-east-clinic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 20:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56738</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Richmond, VA We’re here in Richmond because the President and I—and the entire Administration—care about this community. We care about your families and we want to make sure that everyone has the information they need to stay safe. So, I want to speak to the moms and dads for just a moment.  You know, when&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Richmond, VA</p>



<p>We’re here in Richmond because the President and I—and the entire Administration—care about this community. We care about your families and we want to make sure that everyone has the information they need to stay safe. So, I want to speak to the moms and dads for just a moment. </p>



<p>You know, when you become a parent, there’s a moment that we all go through: You look at that baby, with eyes like saucers and the tiniest fingers. And you feel an overwhelming sense of love, deep in your bones, and absolute terror.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because you know that this fragile life is depending on you. And from that moment on, you see dangers that you never even noticed before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we buy baby gates and cover our electrical outlets. We wrestle them into car seats no matter how much they complain. We make them eat their vegetables and slather them in sunscreen while they fight us with the strength of a linebacker! And after bedtime, when we’re exhausted from the day, we carefully close their bedroom door and feel a pang of gratitude.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because in that rare quiet, we know that everything is OK. That they are healthy and growing—that we are OK.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Parents, we do absolutely everything to protect our kids. And in this pandemic, you did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many of you had to go through birth without your own parents there to help you recover. You had to quarantine with your newborn and without the friends and neighbors who could come over and give you a few hours to yourself. You wrestled tiny masks onto children who couldn’t understand them; you weighed the risk of going to crowded areas or traveling to see loved ones.</p>



<p>And you waited. You waited to feel the same relief you saw in families of older children. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I know it’s been hard. But you’ve done an amazing job. You’ve protected your baby and carried your family through this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now, that relief is finally here: a vaccine for our youngest children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s been thoroughly reviewed and rigorously tested. It’s safe and effective. It’s free. And it’s available for every child in this country, as young as six months old. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, even though so many parents have been waiting for this day, I know you may have questions. So talk to your pediatrician. Get the answers that you need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you decide that this vaccine is right for your child, go to vaccines.gov to find a vaccine site near you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Parents, this is your choice—and we want you to have all of the information you need to make it.</p>



<p>Parenthood and worrying go hand-in-hand. And I can’t promise you that the dangers of the world are going to become any less frightening—just wait until your kids start driving!&nbsp;</p>



<p>But with this vaccine, we can take away at least one of those worries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From the day your sweet, fragile, little baby was born, you have made the choice, again and again, to keep your child safe. This is your choice too. So, make the decision to protect your children with the same vaccine that has already saved millions of lives. Because nothing is more important than our children’s health.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s up to us to keep them safe—and with this vaccine, we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/01/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 19:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $50&nbsp;million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
