<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:18:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s meeting with His Majesty King Abdullah II of&#160;Jordan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-his-majesty-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan and reaffirmed the close and enduring nature of the friendship between the United States and Jordan.  Jordan is a critical ally and force for stability in the Middle East, and the President confirmed unwavering U.S. support for Jordan and His&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan and reaffirmed the close and enduring nature of the friendship between the United States and Jordan.  Jordan is a critical ally and force for stability in the Middle East, and the President confirmed unwavering U.S. support for Jordan and His Majesty’s leadership.  The leaders consulted on recent events in the region and discussed urgent mechanisms to stem violence, calm rhetoric and reduce tensions in Israel and the West Bank. The President affirmed his strong support for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict and cited the need to preserve the historic status quo at the Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount. The President also recognized the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan’s crucial role as the custodian of Muslim holy places in Jerusalem. The leaders discussed the political and economic benefits of further regional integration in infrastructure, energy, water, and climate projects, with Jordan a critical hub for such cooperation and investment.  They agreed to remain in regular touch and further enhance the historic ties between our countries. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Andersson of Sweden and President Niinistö of&#160;Finland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-andersson-of-sweden-and-president-niinisto-of-finland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 17:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland to discuss the close defense and security cooperation between our countries as well as our respective efforts aimed at strengthening Transatlantic security.  President Biden underscored his support for NATO’s Open Door policy and for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland to discuss the close defense and security cooperation between our countries as well as our respective efforts aimed at strengthening Transatlantic security.  President Biden underscored his support for NATO’s Open Door policy and for the right of Finland and Sweden to decide their own future, foreign policy, and security arrangements.  The leaders also discussed the close partnership among our countries across a range of global issues, based on our common values and interests. They reiterated their shared commitment to continued coordination in support of Ukraine and the Ukrainian people affected by the war.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris on the Passing of Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al&#160;Nahyan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-the-passing-of-sheikh-khalifa-bin-zayed-al-nahyan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 15:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Second Gentleman and I send our condolences on the passing of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan. Our thoughts are with his family and with the people of the United Arab Emirates as they mourn this loss. Under his leadership, the strong partnership between the United States and the UAE has enhanced the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Second Gentleman and I send our condolences on the passing of His Highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed Al Nahyan. Our thoughts are with his family and with the people of the United Arab Emirates as they mourn this loss. Under his leadership, the strong partnership between the United States and the UAE has enhanced the security and prosperity of the American and Emirati people, and we are grateful for our work together across multiple Administrations. The legacy of this partnership can be found in the deep bonds between our countries, which our Administration will continue to strengthen.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on the Passing of Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed&#160;Al Nahyan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-sheikh-khalifa-bin-zayed-al-nahyan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 12:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I were&#160;deeply&#160;saddened to learn of the passing of His&#160;Highness&#160;Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed al Nahyan.&#160; Sheikh Khalifa was a true partner and friend of the United States throughout his decades-long tenure as President of the United Arab Emirates and Ruler of Abu Dhabi, and in his earlier role as Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I were&nbsp;deeply&nbsp;saddened to learn of the passing of His&nbsp;Highness&nbsp;Sheikh Khalifa bin Zayed al Nahyan.&nbsp; Sheikh Khalifa was a true partner and friend of the United States throughout his decades-long tenure as President of the United Arab Emirates and Ruler of Abu Dhabi, and in his earlier role as Crown Prince of Abu Dhabi. &nbsp;On behalf of the American people, I offer my condolences to Sheikh Khalifa’s family and all Emiratis as they mourn this great loss. We will honor his memory by continuing to strengthen the longstanding ties between the governments and people of the&nbsp;United States and the United Arab Emirates.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Issues Call for State and Local Leaders to Dedicate More American Rescue Plan Funding to Make Our Communities Safer – And Deploy These Dollars&#160;Quickly</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/13/fact-sheet-president-biden-issues-call-for-state-and-local-leaders-to-dedicate-more-american-rescue-plan-funding-to-make-our-communities-safer-and-deploy-these-dollars-quickly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden also highlights $10 billion in American Rescue Plan funding already committed to public safety and violence prevention and praises those states, cities, and rural counties that have answered his call to action. President Biden believes that Americans deserve to feel safe no matter where they live, and he is committed to using every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>President Biden also highlights $10 billion in American Rescue Plan funding already committed to public safety and violence prevention and praises those states, cities, and rural counties that have answered his call to action.</em></p>



<p>President Biden believes that Americans deserve to feel safe no matter where they live, and he is committed to using every tool at his disposal to fight violent crime. As the cornerstone of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">comprehensive gun crime reduction agenda</a>&nbsp;he issued in June 2021, President Biden called on cities and states to dedicate American Recue Plan state and local funding to proven strategies that will make our communities safer –&nbsp;including by putting more police officers on the beat for accountable community policing, expanding evidence-based community violence intervention programs, and preventing crime by making our neighborhoods stronger with more educational and economic opportunities.<br><br>Today, President Biden is announcing that $10 billion in American Rescue Plan funds have been committed to public safety – including at least $6.5 billion in State and Local funds committed by more than half of states and more than 300 communities across the country, who have answered the President’s call.&nbsp;Along with ongoing state and local support from the Justice Department, American Rescue Plan investments made 2021&nbsp;among the largest single-year commitments&nbsp;of federal resources for state and local law enforcement and public safety on record.<br><br>This American Rescue Plan funding has been a vital lifeline to communities around the country, who have been able to invest in public safety at a time of tremendous state, local, and county budget uncertainty because of the pandemic.&nbsp;Before the American Rescue Plan passed, the Menino Survey found that 27% of mayors anticipated making significant cuts to their police budgets and services.&nbsp;<br><br>The American Rescue Plan has enabled these mayors and other state and local leaders to shore up their budgets and invest in public safety. Unfortunately, every Republican in Congress voted against the American Rescue Plan public safety funding for cities and rural counties across the country.<br><br>While Congressional Republicans try to pull back this funding,&nbsp;<strong>President Biden is today renewing his call for communities to invest more American Rescue Plan funding in strategies to make our communities safer and to deploy as many dollars as possible before the summer months when many communities historically experience a seasonal increase in violent crime.</strong>&nbsp;This renewed call to action comes as the Treasury Department is releasing the second tranche of support for state and local governments.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>$10 Billion in Already Planned ARP Investments in Public Safety &amp; Violence Prevention as President Biden Calls for Increased Investment:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>$6.5 billion in State and Local Fiscal Recovery Fund investments over the past year</strong>, by over 300 communities and more than half of states,&nbsp;including:<br><ul><li><strong>$1 billion in bonuses for front-line public safety workers</strong>&nbsp;to help recruit and retain these public servants.</li><li><strong>Over $2 billion to prevent crime and ease the burden on police</strong>, including community violence interventions, crisis responders, and substance use disorder and mental health services.</li><li><strong>Nearly $1 billion&nbsp;to reduce domestic violence</strong>&nbsp;with immediate crisis intervention, health supports and safety for victims of domestic violence</li><li><strong>Over $350 million in job training</strong>&nbsp;and other assistance to help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter society and provide at-risk teens and young adults with meaningful job opportunities in the summer and during the year</li><li><strong>$450 million in public safety technology and equipment&nbsp;</strong>– like new police cars, upgraded radio systems, body-worn cameras, and gunshot detection systems&nbsp;</li><li><strong>$600 million to help clear court backlogs and support victims of crime&nbsp;</strong><br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Over $1 billion</strong>&nbsp;in proposed ARP investments in public safety have been documented this budget season. This understates the potential for new American Rescue Plan commitments to public safety. Indeed, for cities and counties, the numbers announced today reflect only the investments reported through 2021.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>$1.2 billion Medicaid Mobile Crisis Intervention Services</strong>&nbsp;– police departments are too often overburdened due to lack of crisis response support for people experiencing behavioral health crises. That’s why the American Rescue Plan included $1.2 billion to fund mobile crisis intervention units staffed with mental health professionals and trained peers.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>$1 billion Family Violence Prevention and Services Program&nbsp;</strong>to reduce domestic violence with immediate crisis intervention, health supports, and safety.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Examples of How Specific Communities Are Leveraging American Rescue Plan Funds to Shore Up Their Budgets and Make Our Communities Safer</strong><br>Today, President Biden will meet with mayors, police chiefs, and community violence intervention leaders who represent the following communities:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Houston’s One Safe Houston Plan – reducing crime in first 100 days: </strong>Mayor Sylvester Turner and Police Chief Troy Finner will describe the $52 million ARP plan to reduce violence, with $32 million in mental health and domestic violence response and victim service efforts, $11 million in police overtime (an additional 125 officers per day in areas of the most violent crime), $3 million for a new community violence intervention and prevention program, $1 million for a gun buyback initiative, $1.5 million for forensic science backlog assistance, $2 million for additional park rangers for park safety, and $1 million for a community reentry program.<br></li><li><strong>Kansas City, Missouri: Making Fiscal Room to Hire Up to 150 New Police Officers: </strong>Mayor Quinton Lucas and Police Chief Joe Mabin will discuss leveraging ARP funds to avoid public safety cuts and layoffs to and invest $10 million for new police radios, communication across departments, and how they are working toward providing hazard pay to police officers. The ARP was directly responsible for enabling the fiscal space for Kansas City to be able to hire up to 150 police officers, increase pay for officers and civilian staff, and budget $12.4 million for the Violent Crimes Division and $6.6 million for the communications unit and increased pay for 911 call-takers.<br></li><li><strong>Tampa, Florida: Avoiding Cuts in Public Safety and Investing in New Police Vehicles and Major Modernization of Fire Rescue: </strong>Mayor Jane Castor, a 31-year serving police officer and the city’s first woman to serve as police chief, and Police Chief Mary O’Connor will discuss the American Rescue Plan’s help in avoiding cutbacks of nearly $10 million in public safety while investing in police mental and behavioral health unit, body-worn cameras and new police vehicles. Tampa is also investing $13 million in a major modernization of Tampa Fire &amp; Rescue, including new rescue and fire vehicles, increased staffing during peak times, and fire station renovations. <br> </li><li><strong><strong>Detroit, Michigan: Increasing police patrols and expanding mental health response and community violence programs: </strong></strong>Mayor Mike Duggan and Detroit Police Chief James White began using ARP funds for public safety starting in July, 2021 and are continuing to expand public safety initiatives, with 6 primary strategies, totaling over $110 million. Investments include funds for an updated police training facility, $30 million for enhanced police patrols, $11 million for expanded mental health co-response, $12 million for community outreach gun violence prevention programs, $7 million for gunshot detection technology, $5 million for body cameras, and $8 million for firehouse expansion.<br></li><li><strong>Tulsa, Oklahoma: Police officer recruitment and hiring bonuses, new equipment and improved court processes. </strong>Tulsa Mayor G. T Bynum will share how the city has used ARP funding to provide $3,000 stipends for Academy Police Officer hires – with $2,000 at the beginning and $1,000 at the end of the Academy training. The city is also investing $7 million in body camera replacement and the police air support unit, as well as $6.5 million to reform and speed the court process. Finally, the city is investing in a new family safety center to reduce domestic violent crime. <br></li><li><strong>Baton Rouge, Louisiana: Investing in new police cars, increasing community policing, and innovative community violence interruption strategies. </strong>Baton Rouge Police Chief Murphy Paul, who is part of the White House’s Community Violence Intervention Collaborative, discussed the city’s major public safety investments, including $8 million to replace patrol and other vehicles, $3.3 million to implement gun violence reduction strategies and increase community policing, and $1.8 million for technology investments such as automated license plate readers.<br></li><li><strong>Toledo, Ohio: Funding training for a second cohort of new police recruits for the first time and plans for 100 new officers in the next few years. </strong>Toledo Mayor Wade Kapszukiewicz is leveraging ARP funds to not only avoid cutbacks and layoffs but used the additional resources to create a path to hiring 100 new police officers and invested $2.3 million in gun violence reduction strategies, including a violence interrupter program and other programs addressing root causes of violence, focused on neighborhoods with highest instances of gun violence. American Rescue Plan funds have allowed, for the first time ever, the city has funding to deploy not just one but two cohorts of new police officers, as it works to expand its police force. The city is also investing in gunshot detection technology and safety camera investments to tackle public safety issues.<br></li><li><strong>Mercer County, Pennsylvania: Nearly $12 million for a county-wide radio system and improved 911 system. </strong>Mercer County includes several rural towns, the largest having a population of just 18,000. The County Commissioner Timothy M. McGonigle will share the county’s nearly $12 million investment to design, purchase, and install a county-wide radio system to connect E-911, police, fire, and ambulance services.<br></li><li><strong>Milwaukee, Wisconsin: Bolstering Expanding Violence Intervention and Summer Youth Employment:</strong> From Governor Evers’ $100 million statewide anti-violence strategy, Milwaukee is receiving $8.4 million to match the city’s commitment for advancing a public health approach to violence prevention, that includes building an unarmed community response system that integrates licensed mental health clinicians into Milwaukee’s 911 center, and provides job training at Milwaukee County House of Correction, while using the city’s own ARP funds to invest in summer jobs for up to 1,500 young people. Of the $100M that Evers allocated, $10M has been allocated to establish a statewide violence prevention fund to be administered by the Medical College of Wisconsin. Communities across the state will be able to apply for funds for community-based violence Intervention programs to address gun violence, domestic violence, and suicides.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Appendix: 40+ Additional Examples of Cities, Counties, and States Are Using American Rescue Plan Funding&nbsp;</strong><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Allegheny County, PA</strong>&nbsp;has invested $10 million to provide radio equipment to over 300 fire, EMS and police departments throughout Allegheny County. The County has also invested $9 million to expand and provide new services including regional call centers, mobile crisis teams, and stabilization facilities. The funding will also support a recovery program designed as an alternative to jail for people who are experiencing a mental health crisis.<br></li><li><strong>Atlanta, GA&nbsp;</strong>has committed $7.5 million towards public safety and violence prevention initiatives, specifically community-based violence prevention programming. Atlanta will engage in street outreach and other holistic supportive services to actively remediate conflicts and prevent violence. The City plans to engage in the Cure Violence program model, an internationally renowned approach to violence prevention, leveraging disease control and behavioral health methods including conflict resolution, interrupting the transmission of retaliatory violence, and creating opportunities for community norms to change towards a nonviolence culture. Atlanta is also investing $2.5 million of these funds towards the purchase of additional cameras and license plate readers to enhance public safety technology.<br></li><li><strong>Baltimore, MD</strong>&nbsp;is investing $50 million over the next three years on a comprehensive violence prevention strategy, including community violence intervention programs, victim services support, youth justice efforts, and re-entry services (job training, mental health supports). The program will offer intensive case management, emergency housing and relocation assistance for people at imminent risk of being the victim of violence, and transitional employment programming – all part of the City’s Group Violence Reduction Strategy. This investment will also increase Baltimore’s capacity to provide mental health services and victim services to survivors of gun violence.<br></li><li><strong>Bridgeport, CT</strong>&nbsp;will provide over $4 million for a Second Chance Re-Entry Employment Program &#8211; working with returning citizens and formerly incarcerated individuals to provide a continuum of care, including workforce development, job training and placement, housing support, medical health services, mental health services, substance abuse treatment, education services, and more. Additionally, Bridgeport is investing over $1 million in new public safety and crime prevention programs, including those targeted at combating gun violence and interventions for at-risk populations, as well as over $500,000 in a domestic violence prevention program.<br></li><li><strong>Chandler, AZ</strong>&nbsp;has committed&nbsp;$3.8 million for early hiring of additional police officers to ensure that public safety staffing levels are maintained. Overall, the city plans to add 27 new police officers in the 2021-2022 year. In addition, Chandler is planning to spend nearly $750,000 to incentivize the hiring of approximately 40 public safety officers, as well as additional investment in remote police testing to ease the complexity of applying and testing for police positions.<br></li><li><strong>Chesterfield County, VA</strong>&nbsp;has invested $5.7 million towards public safety, including $1.5 million to purchase land to accelerate the construction of a new police station. The land will be in an identified economic revitalization area, and the station will improve public safety services in the community and support County revitalization efforts in the immediate area.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Chicago, IL&nbsp;</strong>has committed $10 million to expand workforce training opportunities for formerly incarcerated individuals to attain employment and other stabilization services. Chicago’s approach is modeled after previous initiatives in Philadelphia, PA, which resulted in a significant reduction in incarceration for new crimes and a lower recidivism rate. The City is also investing $45 million community safety and violence reduction initiatives, including $20 million for Youth Intervention Programs, $10 million for services and supports for victims of violent crimes and their families.<br></li><li><strong>Colorado&nbsp;</strong>is planning a $113 million investment in public safety and mental health supports over two years,&nbsp;which includes the addition of&nbsp;107 employees to investigate crimes, setting up a delinquency prevention and young offender intervention pilot program, supporting public safety recruiting efforts, and helping to pay for community college police academy training for recruits who otherwise would not be able to afford it. The plan includes a statewide alternative emergency response effort.&nbsp;The state has already invested $5 million for statewide access to crisis services for children and youth, $5 million for Jail based behavioral health services and $10 million for increasing access to effective substance use disorder treatment and recovery.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Colorado Springs, CO&nbsp;</strong>has invested $2.2 million to provide premium pay to public safety staff in the Colorado Springs Fire and Police Departments.<br></li><li><strong>Cumberland County, NJ</strong>&nbsp;has invested $15 million to upgrade all communications systems for emergency services within the county.&nbsp;&nbsp;Police, Fire and ambulance drop calls enroot due to inadequate equipment, as well as insufficient towers, antennae and fiber. This investment will address the interoperability of our various police, fire and ambulance departments by upgrading all hardware and software to the 700 MHz platform.<br></li><li><strong>DeKalb County, GA</strong>&nbsp;has invested over $6 million for $3,000 one-time Protect and Serve retention bonuses for approximately 2,300 public safety officers, including police officers, firefighters, sheriff’s deputies, probation officers, and more. This project is part of the county’s broader public safety and violence prevention initiative.<br></li><li><strong>Erie, PA</strong>&nbsp;has invested $14.1 million for funding to the Erie Police Department to add up to 21 new officers to re-establish critical programs. The funds will provide staffing and related equipment to re-establish the Crisis Car to address mental health and domestic violence issues and to increase community policing to mitigate the impact of COVID-19.<br></li><li><strong>Frederick County, VA</strong>&nbsp;has invested $20 million for provision of a new radio communications system to support mission-critical public safety communications within the county. The communications system will provide enhanced, two-way wireless communications capabilities to all public safety users.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Fresno, CA</strong>&nbsp;increased police staff time to address the rise in violent crime (including additional police vehicles). ARP also helped fund Fresno’s 911 call center to ensure 90% of all emergency calls can be answered in 15 seconds.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Indiana</strong>&nbsp;is investing $20 million in ARP funds towards body cameras for all state police officers.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Indianapolis, IN&nbsp;</strong>has invested $7.6 million in premium pay for police officers, sheriff’s office staff, firefighters, coroners, and more. As an example, Marion County Sheriff’s Office 911 dispatches received a 3 percent rate given their critical role in providing public safety services and their relative base pay amount, and sworn Indianapolis Metropolitan Police Department and Fire Department employees received a 1-3 percent rate, depending on their responsibilities. To address case backlogs, the city is also investing $1.8 million to hire attorneys for the Marion County Public Defender Agency and the Marion County Prosecutor&#8217;s Office.<br></li><li><strong>Jonesboro, AK&nbsp;</strong>is investing $7.8 million in ARP funding towards key public safety investments. Jonesboro is investing in comprehensive traffic and safety camera upgrades used by the police departments, high-definition cameras at each of the city’s 22 parks, and is replacing outdated technology for the city-county 911 department, and modern radio and personal protection equipment and medical supplies for firefighters.<br></li><li><strong>Killeen, TX</strong>&nbsp;has committed over $4.5 million to provide premium pay to over 500 fire and police civil service employees, for an annual maximum of over $4,000 per employee. Killeen is also investing in a police range and training in response to increased gun violence and mental health crisis experienced during the pandemic.<br></li><li><strong>King County, Washington</strong>&nbsp;has allocated $14.2 million towards its backlog of pending felony cases, which has risen to 6,450. The County has also allocated $2 million towards reducing the burden and impact of unsheltered populations on overuse of local jails congregate shelters and emergency rooms.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Knoxville, TN&nbsp;</strong>has committed over $2 million for $3,000 one-time lump-sum payments of premium pay to police and fire department employees.<br></li><li><strong>City of Los Angeles, CA</strong>&nbsp;has invested over $89 million towards public safety and violence prevention efforts. This investment is focused on expanding the system of care, supporting justice-focused community organizations, creating jobs for justice involved individuals, and addressing trauma and violence in communities. Los Angeles is investing $18.5 million towards jumpstarting its multiagency Alternative Crisis Response effort led by mental health professionals and first responders to promote the appropriate care and treatment of people in crisis as a primary alternative to a law enforcement response or jail. The city has also committed $10.5 million toward expanding the LA County’s community-based system of care for people experiencing serious mental illness and substance use disorder.<br></li><li><strong>Los Angeles County, CA:&nbsp;</strong>County of Los Angeles has committed $5 million to increase capacity for the Youth@Work program, which offers youth in priority populations, including but not limited to foster, probation, and LGBTQI+ youth, paid enrichment training, and work experience in public, non-profit, and private organizations in high-growth industry sectors. The county is also dedicating $1 million for job placement programming for individuals returning from serving sentences in jail or prison, with a focus on women and the LGBTQI+ community.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Louisville, KY</strong>&nbsp;is investing $8.5 million to create a three-year comprehensive Youth Development System for high-risk youth to access programs and supports, with a goal of improving public safety in the city.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Manchester, NH</strong>&nbsp;has invested $13.5 million for public safety, including $6.5 million for the Community Health Worker Program &#8211; a joint effort between the Manchester Health Department and Manchester Police Department. The city is hiring 13 community health workers who will respond to emergency calls that currently go to the police but do not involve any criminal activity.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Memphis, TN</strong>&nbsp;is investing over $13 million to fund public safety recruitment incentives. Memphis has also invested $4.8 million to hire street intervention workers and hospital violence interrupters, provide outreach services to youth, as well as other wrap-around services. The City plans to invest $1.3 million towards initiatives to promote youth employment, increasing family income and reducing crime.<br></li><li><strong>Mesa, AZ</strong>&nbsp;is investing another $4.5 million in public safety, including for five new ambulances and behavioral health clinicians for the fire department to use on crisis calls.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Minneapolis, MN</strong>&nbsp;has committed over $11 million to public safety over the next few years, including for the police force as well as violence interruption, and community engagement through street- and community-based outreach.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Missoula County, MT</strong>&nbsp;has invested $500,000 for behavioral health services to incarcerated individuals at the Missoula County Detention Facility for two years. The Missoula County Detention Facility estimates that between 30-60% of individuals incarcerated have significant behavioral health needs.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Newark, NJ</strong>&nbsp;is investing $19 million over the next three years, into programs that break cycles that of violence, substance abuse and crime by supporting participants with behavioral, mental and professional development.<br></li><li><strong>Pennsylvania</strong>&nbsp;is investing&nbsp;$23 million in grants for 25 projects focused on local strategies to stop gun and group violence, with an additional $15mm ARP committed. The grants provide funding to local organizations for a wide range of programs focused on reducing community violence, including street outreach and violence interruption programs, youth mentorship, and more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Philadelphia, PA</strong>&nbsp;is leveraging ARP to invest&nbsp;in a new co-responder program and mobile crisis unit. A police officer partners with a mental health professional to de-escalate mental health calls.<br></li><li><strong>Prince George’s County, MD</strong>&nbsp;has invested $3 million towards anti-violence and CVI initiatives, focusing resources on those at the highest risk of engaging in serious violence. The County will implement various interventions to focus on targeted, trauma–informed care designed to interrupt cycles of violence that can produce lifesaving and cost-efficient results. Prince George’s County has also allocated $9.2 million towards their behavioral health initiatives<br></li><li><strong>St Louis, MO</strong>&nbsp;is investing $5.5 million in community violence intervention programs to interrupt cycles of violence, $5 million in a ‘Cops and Clinicians’ program, which pairs mental health workers with dispatched police to divert calls for clinical help away from the police department. The city also provided an additional $5 million for uniformed police officer overtime/premium pay to maintain police coverage across the city.<br></li><li><strong>St. Paul, Minnesota&nbsp;</strong>has committed $2.7 million to reduce the backlog of criminal cases caused by COVID and nearly $1 million to support police overtime to respond to higher crime rates.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Trenton, NJ</strong>&nbsp;has invested $10.1 million towards public safety, which includes modernizing the City’s outdated emergency radio communications systems—supporting the safe and prompt response to emergencies by Trenton’s first responders. This funding will give Trenton police, fire, public works, and water utility personnel access to improved state radio frequencies and provide updated equipment needed. This investment will also replace the City’s 911 phone system.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Tucson, AZ&nbsp;</strong>is investing $6.5 million for community safety and violence interruption efforts, including Community Violence Intervention (CVI) programs, youth employment and programming, workforce development and apprenticeship programs, mental health and substance use disorder services.<br></li><li><strong>Vallejo, CA</strong>&nbsp;has invested $600,000 for Funds used to support community violence intervention programs including the City&#8217;s neighborhood watch program and the addition of three limited-term Police Assistants.<br></li><li><strong>Virginia&nbsp;</strong>is making significant mental health crisis investments, including $10 million to expand community-based crisis services, such as mobile crisis services and crisis receiving facilities and $5 million to expand community-based substance use disorder treatment services.<br></li><li><strong>Washington, D.C.</strong>&nbsp;is dramatically expanding its CVI efforts with a historic $10 million investment. This initiative will include over 80 violence interrupters (an increase of 50 people) working in 25 neighborhoods across DC. The City is also investing $4 million to expand their Pathways program to a second location with 4 cohorts of 25 participants, serving 100 additional residents at high risk of being involved in gun violence. DC is also creating a trauma-informed training academy and certification for violence interrupters, and potentially police. The City is also investing $8 million in Access to Justice Initiatives, as well as $15 million in Safe Passage initiatives, to promote student and family safety as they travel to and from school.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Wilmington, DE</strong>&nbsp;is leveraging $8 million to dramatically expand their community-based gun violence reduction efforts as well as expanding their&nbsp;neighborhood surveillance program. The city is using an evidence-based health approach to reduce shooting incidents and developing a plan for a community violent interrupter program.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Wisconsin&nbsp;</strong>is making a $100 million investment in a statewide comprehensive public safety strategy, which includes: $25 million for violence prevention programs across the state, $20 million to support victims of crime, $20 million to support local and tribal law enforcement agencies, over $14 million to reduce the backlog of criminal cases, funding to integrate licensed mental health clinicians into the city of Milwaukee’s 911 dispatch center, and job training programs at the Milwaukee County House of Correction.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on the Confirmation of Admiral Linda L. Fagan as USCG&#160;Commandant</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/statement-from-president-biden-on-the-confirmation-of-admiral-linda-l-fagan-as-uscg-commandant/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 02:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is with deep pride that I congratulate Admiral Linda L. Fagan on her confirmation by the Senate as Commandant of the U.S. Coast Guard. Admiral Fagan is the Coast Guard’s first woman to hold the rank of four-star admiral. Today, she again makes history not only as the first woman to lead the Coast&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>It is with deep pride that I congratulate Admiral Linda L. Fagan on her confirmation by the Senate as Commandant of the U.S. Coast Guard. Admiral Fagan is the Coast Guard’s first woman to hold the rank of four-star admiral. Today, she again makes history not only as the first woman to lead the Coast Guard—but also as the first woman Service Chief of any U.S. military service. Admiral Fagan’s leadership, experience, and integrity are second to none, and I know she will advance the Coast Guard’s mission to ensure our nation’s maritime safety and security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My administration is committed to seeing more qualified women in senior leadership and command roles; making sure women can succeed and thrive throughout their military careers. Today, Admiral Fagan’s confirmation as Commandant of the U.S. Coast Guard signals to women and girls across our nation they have a place in protecting their country at the highest level.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki,&#160;May 12, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/12/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-may-12-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 23:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:43 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone. &#160;All right.&#160; Just wanted to start with one topper for all of you.&#160; President Biden has directed the administration to work urgently to ensure that infant formula is safe and available for families across the country during the Abbott Nutrition voluntary recall.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:43 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone. &nbsp;All right.&nbsp; Just wanted to start with one topper for all of you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden has directed the administration to work urgently to ensure that infant formula is safe and available for families across the country during the Abbott Nutrition voluntary recall.&nbsp; This has been &#8212; this is work that&#8217;s been underway for months.</p>



<p>Today, President Biden spoke with retailers and manufacturers, including the CEOs of Walmart, Target, Reckitt, and Gerber to call on them to do more to help families purchase infant formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He discussed Reckitt and Gerber&#8217;s efforts to increase production, which have made up for the loss of production by Abbott, and asked them to identify other ways the administration can help them on top of the actions being announced today.</p>



<p>The conversation with the CEOs of Walmart and Target focused on how they are working to stock shelves, including in rural areas, and any regional disparities they are seeing.&nbsp; And the President asked what more his team can do to help move product and get more product to those communities.&nbsp; He also announced additional steps to get infant formula onto store shelves as quickly as possible without compromising safety.</p>



<p>These steps include cutting red tape to get more infant formula to store shelves quicker by urging states to provide consumers flexibility on the types of formula they can buy with WIC dollars; calling on the FTC and state attorneys general to crack down on any price gouging or unfair market practices related to sales of infant formula, like third-party sellers reselling formula at steep prices; and increasing the supply of formula through increased exports &#8212; imports.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris administration will continue to monitor this situation and identify other ways we can support the safe and rapid increase in the production and distribution of baby formula.</p>



<p>Today, we also marked &#8212; and you heard the President do this, this morning &#8212; a tragic milestone in the United States: 1 million lives lost due to COVID-19.&nbsp; Our hearts go out to those grieving a loved one and those families forever changed because of the pandemic.</p>



<p>As the President said this morning, we cannot grow numb to the urgency of this crisis.&nbsp; It is critical that we honor those who have been lost by doing everything we can to prevent as many deaths as possible.&nbsp; You saw that this morning from the President as he kicked off the COVID-19 Summit.</p>



<p>Today&#8217;s summit highlighted American leadership in action.&nbsp; Together with our co-hosting nations, we &#8212; we united the world to commit to vaccinating the &#8212; to vaccinating the world, saving lives, and building better health security with an inspiring response.&nbsp; We rallied $3 billion from other nations &#8212; more than three &#8212; 3.2 at this point in time, still counting &#8212; from other nations and partners around the world to address the global response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the President issued a stark warning about our ability to continue fighting COVID globally if Congress fails to act.&nbsp; As we heard through the summit, now is not the time for complacency.&nbsp; We need Congress to show up not with empty words, but with action, to fight COVID at home and abroad.</p>



<p>As we mark this tragic milestone, our hope is to avoid another tragic one like this, and that will only come if we act with urgency throughout the remaining fight against the pandemic.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Josh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, on the baby formula.&nbsp; Abbott says once the FDA gives them notice, it’ll take them two weeks to restart the site and then an additional six to eight weeks to get formula on the shelves.&nbsp; With what the President heard today, does he believe that we&#8217;ll have the tools to bridge what could be a two-month-plus shortage?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the President is going to continue to use every tool we have in order to bridge that gap.&nbsp; And this has been work that has been underway for weeks and months now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know that as &#8212; if they get approval, obviously, as you noted, it will take them some time to get up and running again.&nbsp; So what we need to do, and what you&#8217;ve seen the President announce earlier today and I just reiterated, is steps we can take from here to increase supply, make sure it&#8217;s on the shelves.&nbsp; That includes increasing imports.&nbsp; It also includes ensuring we&#8217;re working with retailers, as the President did during his calls, to make sure that shelves are stocked.&nbsp; It also includes ensuring that lower-income families can access different brands of baby formula by working through &#8212; with the WIC &#8212; for the exemptions for the WIC program.</p>



<p>So, we recognize that this is certainly a challenge for people across the country, something the President is very focused on.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to do everything we can to cut red tape and take steps to increase supply on the marketplace.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secondly, AAA is saying, you know, record-high nominal gasoline prices again today, but Americans are also seeing news about oil leases and auctions not going forward.&nbsp; What was the administration&#8217;s thinking on not having those auctions?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the Department of Interior, who &#8212; they have put out some comments on this.&nbsp; And what they have made quite clear is that the Cook Inlet cancellation, which you&#8217;re referring to, was due to a lack of industry interest.&nbsp; And the Gulf sales were as a result of delays due to a number of factors, including conflicting court rulings.&nbsp; So those were the two areas where you&#8217;ve seen the pause.&nbsp; But there was not interest.</p>



<p>I would note that if we take a step back and look at what is available out there and look at the supply needed, as you noted at the top of &#8212; as part of your question, leasing and production offshore is a lengthier process.&nbsp; It can take up to 10 years to create supply.&nbsp; So, let&#8217;s start there.</p>



<p>Secondly, of the more than 10.9 million offshore acres currently under lease, industry is not producing on 8.26 million acres.&nbsp; That&#8217;s about seven point &#8212; 75 &#8212; more than 75 percent that is non-producing.&nbsp; Of the 24.9 million onshore acres under lease, industry is not producing on 12.3 million acres.&nbsp; That&#8217;s almost 50 percent.&nbsp; And there are also over 9,000 onshore permits that have been approved and are waiting to be used onshore.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, just to reiterate what we expect: U.S. production is expected to increase by over 1 million barrels a day this year and hit a new record &#8212; record next year.&nbsp; This &#8212; these specific actions were as a result of lack of industry interest and a &#8212; and conflicting court rulings.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I guess, sort of the bottom line is, you know &#8212; on formula &#8212; this is a problem.&nbsp; I mean, I think other parents here in the room can probably attest.&nbsp; I, myself, went to three stores this morning, still haven&#8217;t found what &#8212; what we need.&nbsp; When will parents be able to get the formula they need?&nbsp; What is your best sense of when store shelves will be stocked again?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s also important to note that the reason we&#8217;re here is because the FDA took a step to ensure that babies were taking safe formula.&nbsp; There were babies who died from taking this formula, so they were doing their jobs.</p>



<p>We have been working &#8212; this administration has been working for weeks now to address in anticipation of where we thought there could be shortages.&nbsp; We have also seen an increase over the last four weeks of supply available, which has been an increase over the four weeks prior to the recall.&nbsp; That is a good sign.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But obviously the steps the President took today are an acknowledgement and a recognition that more needs to be done, that we do not want parents, mothers, families out there to be stressed and worried about feeding their babies.&nbsp; That is why the President today had conversations with the CEOs of Walmart and Target, why he had conversations with Reckitt and Gerber about efforts to increase production, why we&#8217;re taking steps to ensure that we are making &#8212; we are making WIC dollars available to a range of other supply.</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re working.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing increases over the last couple of weeks.&nbsp; More needs to be done.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to cut every element of red tape we can cut.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to work with manufacturers.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to import more to expedite this as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if you are a parent who is looking for formula right now, struggling to find what you need, do you have even a rough guess of how long these shortages are going to last?&nbsp; What should parents be bracing for here?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve already seen an increase in supply over the past couple of weeks.&nbsp; What we are seeing, which is an enormous problem, is hoarding.&nbsp; People hoarding because they&#8217;re fearful &#8212; that is one element of it &#8212; and people hoarding because they are trying to profit off of fearful parents.&nbsp; So that is also something we&#8217;re focused on taking efforts to track and adjust &#8212; and address and look into.</p>



<p>But again, more infant formula has been produced in the last four weeks than in the four weeks preceding the recall.&nbsp; We&#8217;re taking every step to increase that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, our message to parents is: We hear you, we want to do everything we can, and we&#8217;re going to cut every element of red tape to help address this and make it better for you to get formula on the shelves.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as you mentioned, this obviously stems from the FDA taking necessary steps to try and deal with a very serious problem.&nbsp; And as Josh noted, you know, Abbott says that “subject to FDA approval,” they could restart at this site “within two weeks.”&nbsp; Do you have a sense of why it may be taking so long to get this factory back up and running or what the holdup is from the FDA&#8217;s perspective?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would point you to the FDA.&nbsp; But, again, I&#8217;d go back to why this decision was made in the first place, which was to save babies&#8217; lives.&nbsp; And the FDA is not going to approve manufacturing again unless they are certain of the safety.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the President spoke with Philippines’ President-Elect Ferdinand Marcos last night, did they discuss either the dispute with China in the West Philippine Sea or the court &#8212; U.S. court judgments against the president-elect?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of those being a part of the discussion, but I can check and see after the briefing if there&#8217;s more details.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then, on NATO: If Finland and Sweden are successful in their attempts to join NATO, that would put the U.S. on the hook, again, for military &#8212; defending those countries, even potentially with nuclear weapons.&nbsp; What benefit is that to U.S. citizens?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that we would support &#8212; the United States would support a NATO application by Finland and/or Sweden should they choose to apply.&nbsp; We, of course, will respect whatever decision they make.&nbsp; Both Finland and Sweden are close and valued defense partners of the United States and of NATO.</p>



<p>I would note that even without them being members of NATO, our militaries have worked together for many years.&nbsp; We&#8217;re confident that we can find ways to work with them, address any concerns either country may have about the period now or whatever is required if they were to join NATO.</p>



<p>I would say, in terms of how this benefits the American people &#8212; I think is sort of what you&#8217;re asking about &#8212; having a strong NATO Alliance, a strong Western alliance &#8212; which is a defensive alliance, by the way &#8212; is good for our security around the world.&nbsp; And certainly, having a strong partnership with a range of countries, including Sweden and Finland, if they decide to join, should be reassuring to the American people about our own security interests.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally, when the President visits South Korea next week, does he intend to visit the demilitarized zone?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s your current assessment of the threat of a North Korean nuclear test?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, on the first question, we&#8217;re still finalizing details of the schedule for the trip and what it looks like.&nbsp; Obviously, that is a step that is taken by many who visit the region.&nbsp; But I expect we&#8217;ll have our National Security Advisor here in the briefing room next week with Karine to preview the trip.</p>



<p>In terms of whether we expect a test, we &#8212; the United States assesses that the Democratic Repub- &#8212; People&#8217;s Republic of Korea could be ready to conduct a test there as early as this month.&nbsp; This would be its seventh such test.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve shared this information with allies and partners and are closely coordinating with them.</p>



<p>As you noted, the President is traveling to the Republic of Korea and Japan next week, where he will continue strengthening these alliances and make clear our commitments to the security of the Republic of Korea.</p>



<p>Our intelligence assessment is consistent with the DPRK’s recent public statements and destabilizing actions, including the test launch of multiple intercontinental ballistic missiles.</p>



<p>But this is information, again, we&#8217;ve shared with our partners and allies and, of course, will certainly be a topic of discussion when the President travels next week.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more on the baby formula shortage.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, some parents are feeling panicked and they&#8217;re feeling desperate.&nbsp; And a big reason for that is because there&#8217;s no substitute for formula if you don&#8217;t have access to breast milk.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just wondering: If you&#8217;re a parent today and you go to the store, you can&#8217;t find any formula on the shelves, as is being reported across the country, what is the step that they should take?&nbsp; What is the administration&#8217;s guidance on the immediate step that they should take?&nbsp; Is there a hotline that they can call?&nbsp; Should they take a baby to the hospital?&nbsp; What should they do?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say those are important public health questions.&nbsp; But what I can report on here, or what I can convey to all of you, is what we&#8217;re doing to address exactly that concern, which is taking every step we can to ensure there is supply on store shelves, and we have increased the supply over the last four weeks.</p>



<p>And as the President &#8212; as I noted at the top of this briefing, we&#8217;re going to take every step we can to cut red tape, to ensure we&#8217;re working with retailers like Walmart and CEOs, that we&#8217;re working with Reckitt and Gerber and others who can produce more to ensure we are getting supply out to stores and out to retailers so that parents don&#8217;t have that concern.</p>



<p>But beyond that, that&#8217;s what I can read out for all of you from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since you said it was a public health question, which agency should that question be directed to &#8212; just the very practical, immediate question of: If you can&#8217;t find formula and you need it for your baby to eat, what should they be doing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We would certainly encourage any parent who has concerns about their child&#8217;s health or wellbeing to call their doctor or pediatrician.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just had one more.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just quickly on the student loan debt cancellation, can you give us a sense of whether the President is any closer to making a decision and just sort of his frame of mind as he&#8217;s thinking about what amount he would be willing to cancel?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think as I&#8217;ve mentioned in here before, on the campaign, when he was talking about student loans, he talked about a frame of about $125,000 a year.&nbsp; That is not related to necessarily what this final policy will look like, but I&#8217;ve used that as a point of reference to remind everyone &#8212; some who covered the campaign and some who did not &#8212; that he&#8217;s always felt it should be targeted, this type of relief, and focused on the people who need help the most.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have any update on a final decision.&nbsp; I would remind you all that, again, no one has paid a dime in federal student loans since the President took office, and he&#8217;s continuing to consider a range of options and policy here.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the formula shortage, just two quick ones.&nbsp; You said that this has been something that&#8217;s been in the works for several months, mostly through the FDA.&nbsp; When was the first time the President was briefed on the shortage?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into internal briefings.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been made aware of it through the process.&nbsp; And there’s been steps &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Before this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It would have been, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Has there been any consideration of using the Defense Production Act to accelerate production?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are a range of &#8212; there are a range of options, including that, under consideration, Ed.&nbsp; But I would note the issue here is that a manufacturer was taken offline because they did not produce a safe baby formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what we&#8217;re doing here at this point in time is working with other manufacturers who can produce safe baby formula.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve had success in increasing our productivity &#8212; their productivity over the last four weeks, and we&#8217;re going to continue to work on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he would have known about this before this week.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t like this suddenly popped up.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This has been something the administration has been working on for some time now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On Ukraine: Senator Rand Paul has delayed passage of the aid for Ukraine by insisting a new inse- &#8212; inspector general be established to track how the taxpayer money is being spent on the war.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to delay passage of this probably now until next week.&nbsp; Would the President support establishing some kind of watchdog office to track this?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve asked about this before; it&#8217;s now a congressional issue.&nbsp; Any consideration of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that we agree oversight is critical.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the package already includes millions of dollars to support additional oversight measures, including additional funding for existing inspectors general.&nbsp; And we encourage all senators to promptly pass the bill as it stands.&nbsp; We feel what&#8217;s in there is sufficient.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one other thing that was left out of it, at least in the House, was an attempt to legalize the status of tens of thousands of Afghan evacuees brought into the U.S. last year.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House see opportunity somewhere else soon to convince Congress to get that across the finish line?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have been having conversations with congressional leadership about this &#8212; they are ongoing &#8212; on the best path forward for this and other priorities that were not included in the package.</p>



<p>We know this bill sends a clear message to Ukraine, to Russia, and to the world that we stand with the people of Ukraine.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean every component of it has everything we want in it, including that as an example.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s important to move it forward.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jacqui.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; A couple of quick follow-ups on baby formula and then I want to get to something else.</p>



<p>It does seem like we should have seen this coming that maybe the FDA could have done more on the baby formula shortage.&nbsp; The whistleblower who used to work at that Sturgis plant warned the FDA top officials about safety concerns in October, but they didn&#8217;t interview that whistleblower until December.&nbsp; The inspection was until January 31st.&nbsp; The recall happened February 17th.&nbsp; So is that timeline acceptable to the White House?&nbsp; And if not, what is the White House doing to correct that at the FDA?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure there will be plenty of time to take a look at if there are any issues that could have been improved here.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any specific analysis of that at this moment in time.</p>



<p>What I will note is that there has been work ongoing on this for months.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we increase the supply and how we&#8217;re able to, you know, increase the sales based on the month of April overall.</p>



<p>But there&#8217;s more that needs to be done.&nbsp; Clearly, we don&#8217;t want any parent to fear about not being able to provide formula to their child.&nbsp; And as I noted at the top, the President is, you know, leaving no stone unturned in addressing this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I didn’t see anything in the factsheet related to possible antitrust concerns.&nbsp; According to one report, 89 percent of the market is controlled by four companies.&nbsp; I know the President has tried to increase competition in other areas where it&#8217;s consolidated, like meatpacking.&nbsp; So is there going to be any call for increased competition in that industry coming from the White House?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jacqui, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I have not been made aware of that being a concern here, but I&#8217;m happy to raise it and see if there&#8217;s more to tell you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then I wanted to ask &#8212; shift gears only slightly &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to crack pipes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said in February that no money from a $30 million harm reduction program would fund distribution of crack pipes in safe smoking kits.&nbsp; The Washington Free Beacon reported that they went to harm reduction facilities in five cities, and all of those facilities had crack pipes in their kits.&nbsp; HHS would not say which programs had applied for funding, and the recipient list is not out yet.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m just wondering if the White House can say if any taxpayer dollars paid for these crack pipes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No federal funding has gone to it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any oversight to ensure that when that money goes out for the program, that these organizations will not use federal dollars for crack pipes?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This policy does not allow for crack pipes to be included.&nbsp; I would just note that this is a bit of a conspiracy theory that&#8217;s been spread out there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not accurate.&nbsp; There&#8217;s important drug treatment programs for people who have been suffering from what we&#8217;ve seen as an epidemic across the country, and money is not used for crack pipes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I wanted to ask about the President’s comments last night.&nbsp; He went off about MAGA again.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; MAGA king.&nbsp; King MAGA.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; He referred to former President Trump as the “ultra-MAGA king.”&nbsp; He&#8217;s been decrying ultra-MAGA Republicans and saying he’s going to be doing it more.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But Hillary Clinton expressed some regret not too long ago for referring to Trump voters as “deplorables” who couldn&#8217;t be redeemed.&nbsp; And considering that Trump got 74 million votes in the last election, I&#8217;m just wondering if this is the best strategy for Biden to win people over &#8212; win over support ahead of the midterms, especially given his inaugural theme being “America united”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the President is not afraid to call out what he sees as extreme positions that are out of line with where the American people stand, and whether that is supporting a tax plan that will raise taxes on 75 million Americans making less than $100,000 a year; or whether it is supporting efforts to overturn Roe v. Wade, something that two thirds of the American people in a Fox News Poll, may I add, supported.&nbsp; And there are countless examples from there.</p>



<p>The President believes that there is still work we can do together.&nbsp; The Bipartisan Innovation Act is a good example of that.&nbsp; But, again, he is not going to stand back and stand aside while people are pushing for extreme positions that are not in the interests or supported by the vast majority of the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On inflation, today, Ro Khanna &#8212; just sort of feeding into his comments about last night &#8212; from last night about inflation &#8212; and the President was talking about the economy when he was referring to ultra-MAGA.&nbsp; And Ro Khanna said today that “blaming Putin may not be effective.”&nbsp; He said, “We need to say inflation is a real threat.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an emergency.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it seems like the President has been ratcheting up this rhetoric &#8212; you know, blaming Republicans, blaming Putin.&nbsp; We’ve heard all of the reasons why the pandemic is a factor.&nbsp; But Ro Khanna is asking, you know, this White House to call inflation an emergency and call up the National Guard to help with supply chains.&nbsp; Are those things that you’d consider &#8212; this White House would consider?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Jacqui, I don&#8217;t think anyone doesn&#8217;t think inflation is an issue.&nbsp; The President has said that countless times.&nbsp; The question is &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it an “emergency,” though?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It doesn’t matter what you call it.&nbsp; The President just gave a speech on it yesterday.&nbsp; The issue &#8212; the question is what is your plan to address it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>He laid out a very &#8212; a multipart plan yesterday.&nbsp; He has taken a range of steps, including steps that he even announced this week to lower the price of high-speed Internet for tens of millions of Americans; to give farmers the tools and resources they need to boost production; to lower the deficit, something that happened on his watch last year, which will help; to release 1 million barrels of oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; to fix the “family glitch.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>What is the plan on the other side?&nbsp; We all recognize it&#8217;s a problem.&nbsp; But if you open the cupboard door, there&#8217;s nothing there.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the flags are flying at half-staff above the White House and at federal locations across the country.&nbsp; Kristin Urquiza &#8212; her dad died in June of 2020.&nbsp; You likely know he was in an Arizona hospital.&nbsp; The only person there to hold his hand in the ICU was the nurse.&nbsp; She is now the founder of a group called “Marked By COVID.”&nbsp; They have about 100,000 members right now.&nbsp; They&#8217;re advocating for a National Day of Remembrance &#8212; a COVID Memorial Day of sorts.&nbsp; Does the President support a national day of remembrance, a COVID Memorial Day?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, I would say that we&#8217;re still in a fight against COVID and a battle against COVID.&nbsp; There are still far too many people getting sick, getting hospitalized, and dying.&nbsp; And this is not the last time we will commemorate or the last step that the President will take to commemorate.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict about the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I imagine the same applies to a COVID monument.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; You don&#8217;t have any decisions made on that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Those are all important questions.&nbsp; And as the President has said before, people who have lost loved ones &#8212; obviously, a million lives have been lost; there are a lot of people across this country still in mourning.&nbsp; He recognizes that.&nbsp; We need to continue to commemorate that.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re still a fight &#8212; in a fight with the virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So on this day, 1 million American lives lost, an unimaginable figure.&nbsp; Only two-plus years ago at 400,000 lives lost, the President &#8212; then President-Elect and Vice President-Elect &#8212; were there at the Lincoln Memorial &#8212; 400 lights for 400,000 lives.&nbsp; For 500,000 lives lost, there was a moment of silence on the South Lawn.</p>



<p>Today was a bit different.&nbsp; His only public comments were prerecorded remarks to the Global COVID Summit.&nbsp; I guess I&#8217;m asking why not a more prominent remembrance for today&#8217;s anniversary &#8212; for today’s marking?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first, the President publicly addressed this day and marked it.&nbsp; We also lowered the flags for five days &#8212; they will be lowered for five days.&nbsp; And we will continue to mark and commemorate the lives lost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What people care about &#8212; the country &#8212; though most is our action and what actions the President will continue to take.&nbsp; And, obviously, since he took office, according to a Yale study, it&#8217;s estimated we&#8217;ve saved over 2.2 million American lives and $900 billion in healthcare costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s more work that needs to be done, more work to fight misinformation, more work to get more people vaccinated.&nbsp; And action is what people care about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And people care about transparency, as you indicate as well.&nbsp; So my last question on this topic is: Can you help people better understand what data Dr. Ashish Jha was pointing to when he warned that the U.S. could potentially see 100 million infections in the U.S. if COVID relief isn&#8217;t passed now &#8212; over the course of the fall and winter waves expected?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a range of studies that are ongoing.&nbsp; Dr. Jha talks to a range of people internally &#8212; health experts &#8212; and externally.&nbsp; And this is in the range of what they have conveyed to him directly.&nbsp; And I expect there&#8217;ll be more studies that come out in the coming months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; As you know, North Korea is on lockdown because a case of COVID there.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Just one case?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Remarkable.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The country &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; the country has previously rejected offers from COVAX for vaccinations.&nbsp; I’m wondering if the White House will launch a renewed push to try to get vaccines to North Korea.&nbsp; Obviously, almost their entire population &#8212; or their entire population has not been vaccinated.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, you&#8217;re right.&nbsp; And as you noted, the DPRK has repeatedly refused vaccine donations from COVAX.&nbsp; We do not &#8212; the United States does not currently have plans to share vaccines with the DPRK.&nbsp; We do continue to support international efforts aimed at the provision of critical humanitarian aid to the most vulnerable North Koreans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is, of course, a broader part of the DPRK continuing to exploit its own citizens by not accepting this type of aid.&nbsp; As you know, it&#8217;s not just vaccines; it&#8217;s also a range of humanitarian assistance that could very much help the people in the country.&nbsp; And instead, they divert resources to build their unlawful nuclear and ballistic missiles programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, yes, we support international efforts.&nbsp; No current plans for the U.S. to donate sp- &#8212; you know, from the United States supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just briefly on crypto.&nbsp; As you know, the crypto market is in something of a tailspin.&nbsp; There has been an executive order that was put out in March to look into regulations and study the issue.&nbsp; Does &#8212; does the process need to be sped up now, given what we’re seeing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that was significant at the time &#8212; I know, it was, you know, only about two months ago &#8212; because there had not been an acknowledgement about the need to look into crypto &#8212; both the benefits and the challenges.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an ongoing effort to do exactly that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that those who are running it from the Department of Treasury and otherwise want to make sure it&#8217;s thorough and that they&#8217;re assessing both of those important questions: the opportunities and the challenges.&nbsp; So I would point you to them on whether there could be any effort to expedite or whether that&#8217;s possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rory Hu is from Nick News.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know Rory.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve met.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; She’s excited.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Rory, go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; I just have a question and a follow-up.&nbsp; So, first, there are concerns about the negative impacts of social media on the mental health of children.&nbsp; Will the White House take any actions to prevent these adverse effects?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As a mom myself, Rory &#8212; my daughter is younger than you; she’d think you were very hip and cool, no doubt &#8212; this is a huge concern that I have, we have, the President has &#8212; is the impact of social media platforms, their enormous power, and the fact that it is largely unchecked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is certainly something that our Surgeon General, Dr.&nbsp; Vivek Murthy, has talked about, in terms of the impact of social media platforms and what the impact they&#8217;re having on the mental health, the self-esteem of young people.&nbsp; And so, I would say the President, the First Lady, all of us believe that more needs to be done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the Internet has become a tool for children&#8217;s education.&nbsp; A lot of students use the Internet to learn.&nbsp; So how will the White House prevent children from getting misinformed from the Internet?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Such a good question, too.&nbsp; Well, I know reporters, like yourself, and people that other kids listen to are good voices to provide accurate information.&nbsp; And you ask &#8212; coming here and asking tough questions is an important part of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say that, you know, one of the things that we encourage parents to do is, you know, make sure you are educating yourself on all of these platforms and what information is available, and working with your kids to make sure they understand what&#8217;s accurate and inaccurate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are certainly steps the government can take.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s also an ongoing development of new tools.&nbsp; And we, as parents, need to keep educating ourselves about what&#8217;s out there so we can make sure our kids have access to good information, informative information &#8212; we watch a lot of animal videos in my house; that&#8217;s all good and positive &#8212; and not access to information that&#8217;s inaccurate and misleading or problematic.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; She’s much better than Portnoy.&nbsp; So &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Hard con- &#8212; hard confirm.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our friends at Reuters reported that there&#8217;s no executive order being drafted to give HHS and DOJ new powers to block Chinese access to vulnerable &#8212; to Americans’ sensitive information.&nbsp; And so, I was wondering if you have a sense of timeline on this.&nbsp; But also, the idea that there&#8217;s been frustration with the administration &#8212; frustration within the administration over some of the slow-walking at Commerce on rulemaking and investigations that that may have prompted this action by the President.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say that, certainly, the protection of the privacy of American citizens and ensuring that no foreign actors, whether state owned or otherwise, have access to the information of Americans is of utmost concern to the President and to our National Security Advisor and others.<br><br>These processes can take some time to develop, to investigate, to finalize.  It’s not a surprise if there is a frustration by anyone who’s a part of that process.  But I can’t speak to that from here.  But I can tell you, certainly, ensuring we are protecting Americans’ privacy is of utmost concern to the President.<br><br>Q    A minister in the Bolsonaro government said that he may skip the Summit of the Americas coming up because he wants to campaign.  If he is not going, Mexico says that they may not go, and because Venezuela, Cuba, Nicaragua may not be invited.  Are we reaching a point where the summit may no longer be successful because so many key leaders in the hemisphere &#8212; even though ones, obviously, that the President has had key disagreements with &#8212; won’t be attending?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, no invitations have gone out for the summit, so that is obviously something that will happen in short order, given the summit is coming up in June.<br><br>I would note that Secretary of State Tony Blinken spoke today with his counterparts and reiterated not only his appreciation for the continued collaboration we have with Mexico but also noted that Special Advisor for the Summit of the Americas, Christopher Dodd, will travel to Mexico later this month to further discuss preparations for the summit.<br><br>So these conversations are ongoing.  Obviously, important questions about what the final invitation list will look like.  We are certainly eager to host the summit, something that, you know, is our highest priority for the hemisphere.  And it would be an important opportunity to talk about a range of issues, including democracy, including climate goals, including the COVID-19 response, and addressing the root causes of migration.<br><br>So we are fully planning and moving forward, but no final decisions about the invites have been made yet.<br><br>Q    And then a last one: There was a report earlier this week that the President may be meeting with or speaking to the King of Jordan.  Obviously, also, I think we asked last week about this possibility of a regional summit in Israel.  So I&#8217;m wondering if you could confirm either of those things, and, specifically on the last, whether Saudi Arabia is being weighed as a participant in that summit &#8212; oil production obviously a kind of primary concern for many Americans right now.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Yes.  Okay.  First, yes, he will be meeting with the King of Jordan.  I can get you the details of that after the briefing.<br><br>And on the second part of your question, I think you&#8217;re referring to what his travel might look like in June around the other summits.  We&#8217;re still finalizing what that looks like.  There have been good questions about whether or not he will go to Israel, given he has committed to Prime Minister &#8212; or, accepted the invitation of Prime Minister Bennett.  But that trip &#8212; we&#8217;re not quite there yet.  We&#8217;re still finalizing the next trip. </p>



<p>We have had senior members of the national security team travel to Saudi Arabia to talk about a range of issues, including regional cooperation, obviously the war in Yemen, and supply on the global marketplace.<br><br>But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict in terms of an upcoming visit by the President.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, back on infant formula, Senator Gillibrand, in an interview with NPR, said that this is a “life or death issue” and that the other companies aren&#8217;t stepping up, they aren&#8217;t producing as much formula as they should or could be, and that she is going to ask the President to invoke the Defense Production Act on this.&nbsp; Is that the kind of request that will be entertained?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, we&#8217;re exploring every option.&nbsp; I think when you look at the Defense Production Act, you have to ensure that it would actually achieve what you&#8217;re trying to achieve.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re also looking at that, as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have been working &#8212; this is one of the reasons, obviously, the President called CEOs today of some of these vital companies to determine what more can be done, because we know that with one major supplier having part of their supply off the marketplace, the &#8212; one of the easiest and fastest ways to address that is to increase supply from some of the other suppliers, and, also, to import more, which is a step we&#8217;re working to take as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t happen to ask him to invoke the Defense Production Act, did they?&nbsp; When &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of that being a specific ask from them.&nbsp; I can see if there&#8217;s more to read out from the &#8212; from the calls as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just quickly on the COVID deaths: Going back to the group Marked By COVID, they&#8217;re also asking the President to meet with people who&#8217;ve lost loved ones to, you know, express his empathy and also sort of feel what they&#8217;re feeling.&nbsp; When is the last time he met with the loved ones of people who have died from COVID?&nbsp; And would he consider such a meeting?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He certainly would.&nbsp; And I think there &#8212; even people who may not like the President may &#8212; probably would not question his level of empathy and compassion for people who have lost loved ones.&nbsp; And certainly, addressing and talking about that impact is something you hear him do every time &#8212; nearly every time he talks about COVID.<br><br>He certainly would be open to doing that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to predict in terms of the future schedule, but yes.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, two of the &#8212; or, some of the steps, at least two of them, announced today on infant formula seem like things that could have been announced and steps that could have been taken earlier.&nbsp; And any woman following this on any mom&#8217;s list or whatever has known of rumblings of this crisis since nearly the plant shut down in February.&nbsp; Why &#8212; why did it take so long to announce the steps you announced today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, some of these steps we&#8217;ve been working on, just because we haven&#8217;t been announcing them publicly, including increasing supply and working with producers and suppliers.<br><br>Some of the challenges we&#8217;re also seeing &#8212; let me just note it, and I noted this a little bit earlier &#8212; is this hoarding issue.&nbsp; And we are also &#8212; have been also calling on retailers to impose purchasing limits to prevent the possibility of hoarding, because we know that that is an issue.<br><br>Again, sometimes it&#8217;s people who are fearful, but &#8212; which is understandable.&nbsp; But also &#8212; it is also &#8212; there&#8217;s an element of people who are trying to benefit financially off of that fear, which is where we have a concern.&nbsp;<br><br>But since the reca- &#8212; recall, we&#8217;ve been working nonstop to address and alleviate supply issues by working with these retailers, engaging with the FDA on additional steps we could take, and obviously, we&#8217;re talking about laying all the specifics out now.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And briefly, on a different topic of “ultra-MAGA” &#8212; now, you saw Representative Elise Stefanik saying, “I&#8217;m ultra-MAGA, and I&#8217;m proud of it.”&nbsp; Former Trump super PAC blasted out a t-shirt of him as an ultra-MAGA Superman.&nbsp; He, on his own Twitter-alternative platform, released a meme of him as the ultra-MAGA king.&nbsp;<br><br>I guess I&#8217;m curious what the administration makes of Republicans and the former President sort of co-opting this and elevating what President Biden clearly intended as a pejorative.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think if that means that the individuals you’ve mentioned are embracing their opposition to a woman&#8217;s right to make choices about her own healthcare, if they&#8217;re embracing a plan that will raise taxes on 75 million Americans, if they&#8217;re embracing the importance of fighting Mickey Mouse over virtually any other issue, I guess that&#8217;s their platform.&nbsp; Good for them.&nbsp; We&#8217;re happy to have a debate about that.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, at the risk of sending you back to your State Department days, I was wondering if you could come back to the embrace of Sweden and &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Finland for NATO, and walk us through the distinction now between their qualifications and Ukraine, now that we have invested so much more heavily in making sure that Ukraine remains an independent state and that it irreversibly could not be invaded again.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would leave that to my NATO spokesperson colleague to speak to.&nbsp; What I would say, David, is that what we support is a NATO application by Finland or Sweden should they choose to apply.&nbsp; We know that they have been close and valued defense partners.&nbsp; There are a range of requirements I&#8217;m sure my NATO counterparts could speak to, including addressing a range of issues like corruption and how you would participate in the defense of the collective NATO Alliance.<br><br>But I will let them to speak &#8212; speak to that.&nbsp; We, of course, support the NATO&#8217;s &#8212; NATO&#8217;s open-door policy and the aspirations of any country to apply to join.<br><br>But I think this speaks to our longstanding relationship and military partnerships with Finland and Sweden.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;re saying that for Finland and Sweden, you&#8217;re supporting their application, their right to apply, but you&#8217;re not embracing yet whether or not you would actually vote (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We would support a NATO application by Finland and Sweden, yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then take that &#8212; the next step for us, if you can, which is to say that &#8212; you’ve heard what the Russians &#8212; how they reacted to this.&nbsp; Given the debate that took place back in the &#8212; 15, 20 years ago about expanding NATO, and the President&#8217;s concerns at that time, does he think that expanding it again just risks further provocation here?&nbsp; And is that &#8212; is the benefit at this point of having them in the Alliance greater than the risk of the provocation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would go &#8212; I would just like to quote the President of Finland and what he said &#8212; which I don&#8217;t think I could state it better &#8212; in response to this question, which is: “As it relates to Russia, you caused this.&nbsp; Look at the mirror.”</p>



<p>And, you know, that is &#8212; NATO is a defensive alliance.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not an offensive alliance.&nbsp; Both Finland and Sweden are close and valued defense partners of the United States and NATO.&nbsp; They&#8217;re thriving democracies.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve worked closely with NATO for years.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no aggressive intent from NATO, from the United States, from Finland or Sweden &#8212; obviously they can speak for themselves &#8212; to Russia.</p>



<p>But again, this is President Putin who caused this.&nbsp; “Look at the mirror.”&nbsp; And I think that also probably is the reason for what you&#8217;ve seen as public support for joining NATO increase in these countries as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; One on the COVID Summit, and then, if I can, a follow-up &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to what Tam was asking about the DPA.</p>



<p>During the summit today, did the U.S. hear any concerns from other countries about the delay in securing U.S. funding for the global effort or that there&#8217;s a potential that that funding will not come through if Congress doesn&#8217;t move forward on it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a thorough readout, and I’d point you to other countries to speak to what they did or didn&#8217;t express.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that the Vice President, in her comments, specifically highlighted the need to get additional funding, including the $5 billion that is up for international COVID relief, which is part of the $22.5 [billion] we requested.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And she did that because there&#8217;s a recognition, an acknowledgement that we want to continue to be part of this effort to continue to lead this effort.&nbsp; And without that funding, we won&#8217;t be as well positioned.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that what is a success from this summit is, of course, the fact that we have been able to put together $3.2 billion in contributions from a range of countries attending to this global effort.&nbsp; And that is part of &#8212; was part of the purpose to ensure that we were elevating this, working together, coordinating, you know, to prevent complacency, to prevent deaths, to prevent and plan for future variants.</p>



<p>And that kind of money from other countries is an important step forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to follow up on the DPA question: Obviously, baby formula is a very specific product.&nbsp; But is there a lesson that can be learned from the COVID supplies of PPE and vaccines and scaling up production that the administration could apply to this situation right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a very good question, Karen.&nbsp; I think one of the challenges in this cycle of the supplies here is that companies are going to produce what the market needs.&nbsp; Right? &nbsp;And if you look at things like tests or masks &#8212; you know, back in the fall &#8212; remember? &#8212; we had a shortage of tests.&nbsp; This summer, we had an abundance of tests to the point where companies were shutting down manufacturing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the challenge is &#8212; is that it&#8217;s about what the demand is in the marketplace.&nbsp; And obviously, now there&#8217;s high demand because there&#8217;s a shortage because of this recall, which was done, again, to save babies’ lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, clearly, our efforts and focus now is on increasing supply from other suppliers and importing more so that we can meet the current demand and needs now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Another one on baby formula &#8212; that families with babies who are sick and relying on specialty mix &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and that I understand that are only manufactured in this plant that is offline now.&nbsp; So what&#8217;s the plan for those families?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I addressed this a little bit yesterday or the day before &#8212; I guess it was the day before &#8212; which is: Part of our effort is to ensure and work with other suppliers, who can ma- &#8212; who make baby formula, who can meet the same needs of children who have special needs or who have specific needs for what formula they can take to ensure that supply is on the marketplace as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just on this &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And the FDA has been doing that, but go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this whole supply chain issue, we often hear the President saying the solution to supply chain problems is to produce in the United States.&nbsp; In this case, we have a product that is manufactured, I think, 98 percent in the United States. So how do you reconcile these two messages &#8212; you know, “Made in America”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there &#8212; because the reason for this shortage is not because there was a supply chain issue in a foreign country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a different issue.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one supply chain issue.</p>



<p>This issue is because there was unsafe product that the FDA recalled to save babies’ lives.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s just a different issue.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; A senior administration official yesterday said that the President&#8217;s trip to South Korea and Japan later this month is part of his plans to (inaudible) policy.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s the first administration to be &#8212; raise it to the leadership level.&nbsp; Does the President have plans to visit the other two countries &#8212; India and Australia &#8212; and when that is going to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure he will in the future, but we have two foreign trips we&#8217;re still trying to finalize at this point, and so I don’t have any predictions about when.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it going to be in the first term of the President?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t make a prediction of that.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s a lot of time left in the first term, so that&#8217;s the good news.&nbsp; A lot of time for travel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the second question, what is U.S. expectations from India on the two wars the world is fighting &#8212; one is the Ukraine war, the other is COVID-19?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we continue to remain in close touch with India about, you know, our efforts to rally the world, to stand up against Russian aggression.&nbsp; That means implementing and abiding by sanctions that have been put in place.&nbsp; And as you know, Daleep took a trip &#8212; our Deputy National Security Advisor took a trip just a few weeks ago there to have a conversation about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We continue to encourage countries to speak out about Russian aggression.&nbsp; And obviously, on COVID-19, we&#8217;ve been an important partner with India in providing supply and vaccines and needs &#8212; in their times of need over the course of the last 15 months, and certainly we&#8217;ll continue to work with them on that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; One on Finland, one on Israel.&nbsp; When Russia threatened military technical means against Ukraine many months ago, you were sounding the alarm bells, you were doing very specific projections as to what the Russians were going to do.&nbsp; They invoked that term again after Finland&#8217;s announcement. What do you make of it?&nbsp; What are your concerns about Russia&#8217;s response to this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; About Russia&#8217;s con- &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About Russia&#8217;s response to a Finnish application for NATO membership.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the facts are important here, which is that NATO is a defensive alliance.&nbsp; NATO has no aggressive intent, again- &#8212; against Russia, nor does the United States, nor do Finland and Sweden.&nbsp; We have long supported &#8212; before the invasion, after the invasion &#8212; the open-door policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certainly, given Finland and Sweden are &#8212; have longstanding important partnerships with the United States, with NATO countries.&nbsp; They&#8217;re longstanding democracies.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we support their application.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, beyond that, I think it&#8217;s important to note what the facts are here, which is that there&#8217;s no aggressive intent at all.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the killing of Shireen&nbsp; Abu Akleh in Jenin, you called for an investigation &#8212; a swift investigation.&nbsp; I guess the question is: What kind of investigation?&nbsp; The Israelis have extended an offer for the Palestinians to participate in a joint investigation.&nbsp; Should they be accepting that offer?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they&#8217;ve also asked for U.S. oversight over some examination of, for example, the bullet that killed Shireen.&nbsp; You know, what &#8212; have you responded to that offer?&nbsp; What would you like to see?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we understand that both Israel and the Palestinian Authority are already conducting investigations into the circumstances of the killing.&nbsp; We encourage both parties to do so thoroughly and transparently and to share their findings to ensure that all evidence in this case is available and fully assessed.</p>



<p>We stand ready to assist either party in any way that we can.&nbsp; Neither side has asked for our assistance at this time, and such a request would be required in order for us to do so.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, as part of this ultra-MAGA rollout, the President has talked a lot about, sort of, what the Republican &#8212; what he thinks the Republican Party now stands for.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also, you know, thrown out some tough language, saying they were &#8220;petty&#8221; and &#8220;mean spirited&#8221; and, sort of, cowering to former President Trump.&nbsp; Does he &#8212; but he&#8217;s also said he&#8217;s been surprised by that.&nbsp; Does he still feel like the fever will break in Washington?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you mean, in terms of the ultra-MAGA followers of the former president?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just in terms of if ultra-MAGA, you know, as he says, controls the party, that would be the party that he thought would come around.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I just want to make sure I understand your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Are you asking me if he thinks that there will ever be a period of time where there will not be a ultra-MAGA party or if &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he does he feel like there will be a period in time when he is president in which the ultra-MAGA wing of the Republican Party doesn&#8217;t control it and that the fever will break in Washington?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s certainly his hope.&nbsp; The President has long believed that Democrats and Republicans can work together &#8212; can work together to get things done.&nbsp; He signed 80 bipartisan bal- &#8212; bills into law last year.&nbsp; The Bipartisan Innovation Act is something we&#8217;re still working to get through.</p>



<p>And his view is that this is a conversation &#8212; a lot of it&#8217;s happening in Washington.&nbsp; And they are &#8212; for the American people and the American public, a lot of these policies that the ultra-MAGA wing, the MAGA King &#8212; all the different terminology where the President is using out there &#8212; does not align with where the vast majority of the public is, and elected officials should be doing what the vast majority of the public wants them to do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White &#8212; I &#8212; and excuse me if you guys have already reacted to this: Does the White House have a comment on the latest round of subpoenas by the January 6th commission?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly support the work of the January 6th Committee.&nbsp; We’ll continue to support their work.&nbsp; We believe it&#8217;s vital and essential to get to the bottom of what happened on January 6th, one of the darkest days in our democracy.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll continue to support their work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, last question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, last one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Staying on ultra-MAGA and the Rick Scott &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, the President himself is not subject to the Hatch Act.&nbsp; But as the midterms start to take over basically everything, can you just talk about how the White House is navigating the distinction between political speech and official events?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; For the Pres- &#8212; in what the President is doing or how he spends his time?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of the appropriateness of making explicitly political or campaign-focused messages during official White House events?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that I am subject to the Hatch Act, as I have noted &#8212; in a sternly written letter to me &#8212; but the President is not, as you know.&nbsp; And he is the leader of the Democratic Party.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also the Commander-in-Chief.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also the leader of the free world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what he is pointing out is what he sees to be a troubling trend in our democ- &#8212; into our country that&#8217;s a threat to our democracy, a threat to progress.&nbsp; And certainly, he&#8217;s going to continue to draw the contrast for the American people on what the options present.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, I&#8217;m just going to do Patsy and April, because I &#8212; Patsy, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; So, on the U.S.-ASEAN Summit, can you give us a sense of how hard the President will push on the issue of Ukraine?&nbsp; For example, whether the administration will be pushing to include the word “Russia” in the final communiqué.&nbsp; As you know, ASEAN have, so far, avoided using that word on any of their statements on the Ukraine crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I have a follow-up on Afghanistan, if you don&#8217;t mind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>So, on the ASEAN Summit, Ukraine will absolutely be on the agenda.&nbsp; In terms of what the final communiqué will look like, I don&#8217;t expect it will be ready for more than 24 hours.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s lots of conversations that need to happen between now and then, so I can&#8217;t make a prediction of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I will say that a number of the ASEAN participants have been important partners in calling out the aggressive action of Russia and invading Ukraine, in participating and in supporting sanctions and, certainly, abiding by them.&nbsp; And obviously, the conflict we&#8217;re seeing is a unique moment in modern global history.&nbsp; So it will certainly be on the agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Last thing, and then I’ll go to April.&nbsp; And then I got to go.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you confirm reports that Jake Sullivan recently met with the chief of the Pakistani spy agency in Washington, D.C.?&nbsp; Can you share anything from that meeting and whether the two sides discussed counterterrorism cooperation in Afghanistan?</p>



<p><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any details on that reported meeting.&nbsp; I can certainly check and see if there&#8217;s more.&nbsp;<br><br>Okay, April, wrap it up.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Wrapping it up.&nbsp; I’m going to share on another meeting &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; if there’s more information.&nbsp; Congressman Greg Meeks, the chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee, met with the President; he was part of a group meeting with the President this week.&nbsp; And he talked about issues that he talked with &#8212; was it President Zelenskyy.&nbsp;<br><br>And one of those issues that President Zelenskyy specifically brought up to Meeks and the contingent was Ukrainian grains and how it is impacting &#8212; the lack of Ukrainian grains going out to the world is impacting Africa.&nbsp; Meeks said the President spoke about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Can you drill down a little bit more about this?&nbsp; Has &#8212; the President has said he wants it to go out to the world.&nbsp; Can you drill down a little bit more, especially when it comes to Africa?&nbsp; Because there&#8217;s a concern about many of those countries, to include Ethiopia and the Congo &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that’s already going through crisis.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s an important issue.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing food shortages in the world, including in parts of Africa, other parts of the Middle East.&nbsp;<br><br>This is one of the reasons why the President went to Chicago and raised the issue of doing everything we can to increase supply here in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>While we don&#8217;t expect shortages here, we want to be providers of American grains to the rest of the world as we&#8217;re seeing shortages in part because of the war in Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also provided a large amount of assistance to global food programs, global aid programs in anticipation of what we see as a potential shortage of food.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to work on it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk by reporter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; Does this give the President more pause that President Zelenskyy himself brought that issue of grain for Africa up &#8212; specifically Africa, the continent?</p>



<p><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we are working on this issue and have been working on this issue for months now.&nbsp; That is &#8212; the President went on a trip just yesterday to elevate and talk about the steps we&#8217;re taking to increase supply of grains and wheat here in the United States to address exactly this issue.&nbsp; And we are far and away the world&#8217;s largest provider of assistance in aid to global food programs in order to address what we know could be a shortage around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, everyone.</p>



<p><br>4:36 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-66/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 22:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53125</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Claria Horn Boom, of Kentucky, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2023, vice William H. Pryor Jr., term expired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; John Gleeson, of New York, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Claria Horn Boom, of Kentucky, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2023, vice William H. Pryor Jr., term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; John Gleeson, of New York, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2023, vice Rachel Elise Barkow, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Laura E. Mate, of Iowa, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2027, vice Charles R. Breyer, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Claire McCusker Murray, of Maryland, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2025, vice Danny C. Reeves, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Carlton W. Reeves, of Mississippi, to be Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission, vice Patti B. Saris.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Carlton W. Reeves, of Mississippi, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2027, vice Patti B. Saris, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Luis Felipe Restrepo, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2025, vice Ketanji Brown Jackson, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Candice C. Wong, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the United States Sentencing Commission for a term expiring October 31, 2027, vice Dabney Langhorne Friedrich, term expired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 1245(d)(4)(B) and (C) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year&#160;2012</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/12/presidential-determination-pursuant-to-section-1245d4b-and-c-of-the-national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2012/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 22:04:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53122</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential DeterminationNo.        2022-12         MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE               THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY               THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT:       Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 1245(d)(4)(B) and (C) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right">Presidential Determination<br>No.        2022-12        </p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE<br>               THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY<br>               THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 1245(d)(4)(B) and (C) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, after carefully considering the reports submitted to the Congress by the Energy Information Administration, including the report submitted in April 2022, and other relevant factors, including global economic conditions, the level of spare capacity, and the availability of&nbsp;strategic reserves, I determine, pursuant to section 1245(d)(4)(B) and (C) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012, Public Law 112-81, and consistent with prior determinations, that there is a sufficient supply of petroleum and petroleum products from countries other than Iran to permit a significant reduction in the volume of petroleum and petroleum products purchased from Iran by or through foreign financial institutions.</p>



<p>I will continue to monitor this situation closely.</p>



<p>The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Virtual Meetings with Retailers and Infant Formula&#160;Manufacturers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/readout-of-president-bidens-virtual-meetings-with-retailers-and-infant-formula-manufacturers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 21:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden spoke with the leadership of Walmart and Target, and the infant formula manufacturers Reckitt and Gerber to receive an update on actions the companies are taking to address the shortage of infant formula caused by a voluntary recall of infant powdered formula by Abbott and the subsequent closure of its manufacturing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden spoke with the leadership of Walmart and Target, and the infant formula manufacturers Reckitt and Gerber to receive an update on actions the companies are taking to address the shortage of infant formula caused by a voluntary recall of infant powdered formula by Abbott and the subsequent closure of its manufacturing facility in Sturgis, Michigan.</p>



<p>The manufacturers and retailers thanked the President for the actions his administration has taken—including those by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration and the U.S. Department of Agriculture—that has enabled them to serve the families in need, including low income mothers and children who are most vulnerable.</p>



<p>The President discussed Reckitt and Gerber’s efforts to increase production—which have made up for much of the loss of production by Abbott—and pledged to work closely with them to identify ways the Administration can help, on top of the actions being announced today. Both companies stated that they are operating 24/7 with Gerber, increasing the amount of their infant formula available to consumers by approximately 50% in March and April. Reckitt is supplying more than 30% more product year to date.</p>



<p>The conversation with the CEOs of Walmart and Target focused on how retailers are working to stock shelves. The CEOs discussed state specific disparities and the President asked what more his team can do to help move product and get more product to communities in need. These calls build off the work the Administration has done since February to increase the supply of infant formula.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
