<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 23:14:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Roundtable on Mental Health with Young Women and Girl&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/31/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-on-mental-health-with-young-women-and-girl-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 23:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the last day of Women’s History Month,&#160;Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice&#160;and&#160;Gender Policy Council&#160;Director Jennifer Klein&#160;hosted a roundtable at the White House with&#160;young women leading&#160;their communities&#160;in&#160;improving&#160;mental health.&#160;Participants&#160;were joined by the&#160;leadership&#160;of national&#160;girl’s&#160;advocacy organizations, each&#160;of&#160;which have prioritized mental health policy and supported young women leaders&#160;tackling&#160;this&#160;issue. With&#160;studies continuing to highlight the toll that the COVID-19 pandemic has taken&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On the last day of Women’s History Month,&nbsp;Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice&nbsp;and&nbsp;Gender Policy Council&nbsp;Director Jennifer Klein&nbsp;hosted a roundtable at the White House with&nbsp;young women leading&nbsp;their communities&nbsp;in&nbsp;improving&nbsp;mental health.&nbsp;Participants&nbsp;were joined by the&nbsp;leadership&nbsp;of national&nbsp;girl’s&nbsp;advocacy organizations, each&nbsp;of&nbsp;which have prioritized mental health policy and supported young women leaders&nbsp;tackling&nbsp;this&nbsp;issue.</p>



<p>With&nbsp;studies continuing to highlight the toll that the COVID-19 pandemic has taken on youth mental health, participants&nbsp;shared&nbsp;their experiences and&nbsp;insight into the unique&nbsp;mental health&nbsp;challenges that women and girls face.&nbsp;The young women leaders also&nbsp;shared policy recommendations for&nbsp;strengthening mental health for girls, including&nbsp;the&nbsp;need to meet girls where they areand&nbsp;the importance&nbsp;of&nbsp;reducing stigma and other&nbsp;barriers that make it difficult for young women and girls to access mental health services.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senior White House officials&nbsp;reinforced the Administration’s commitment to addressing our mental health crisis,&nbsp;a core&nbsp;pillar of the Unity Agenda that&nbsp;President&nbsp;Biden outlined in his&nbsp;State of the Union Address. This&nbsp;commitment includes:&nbsp;increasing&nbsp;the size and diversity of the mental health workforce;&nbsp;expandingcoverage and reducing costs for mental health services;&nbsp;and&nbsp;integrating&nbsp;mental health&nbsp;care and services across settings, from schools&nbsp;to community centers.&nbsp;&nbsp;Senior White House officials emphasized that&nbsp;the President’s FY23 budget&nbsp;proposes&nbsp;a historic$829&nbsp;million&nbsp;to strengthen and advance youth mental health.&nbsp;They&nbsp;also&nbsp;discussed the Administration’s work to address the mental health impacts of social media,&nbsp;including addressing the intersection of online harassment and abuse and gender-based violence, a commitment that is part of the first-ever&nbsp;U.S. government&nbsp;National Gender Strategy&nbsp;released by the Biden-Harris Administration last fall. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Young women leaders that participated&nbsp;in today’s roundtable include:•&nbsp;Belen Buckley,&nbsp;Youth Advisor, Georgetown&nbsp;Law&nbsp;Center on Poverty and Inequality; California<br>•&nbsp;Enshalla Dunlop, National Agenda for Black Girls (NABG)&nbsp;Advisor, Girls for Gender Equity;&nbsp;New York<br>•&nbsp;Marley Dias, Author and Literary Activist; New Jersey<br>•&nbsp;Elmirah Marcus Garcia, Youth Advocate,&nbsp;National Crittenton; New Mexico<br>•&nbsp;Kiran Kadiyala,&nbsp;Girls Inc. National Teen Advocacy Council Alumna; Florida<br>•&nbsp;Ava Macomber,&nbsp;Youth Leader,&nbsp;Girl Scouts of the USA; District of Columbia&nbsp;<br>•&nbsp;Mahogany Morris, Health and Education Intern, Justice for Black Girls Community Organization; New York<br>•&nbsp;Delgracia Sainvil, Young Women’s Advisory Council Member, Girls for Gender Equity;&nbsp;New York</p>



<p>The following organization leaders also joined for the roundtable:•&nbsp;Lisette Engel,&nbsp;Vice President for Policy and Systems Change, National Crittenton<br>•&nbsp;Rebecca Epstein,&nbsp;Executive Director, Georgetown Law Center on Poverty and Inequality&nbsp;<br>•&nbsp;Stephanie Hull,&nbsp;President and CEO, Girls Inc.<br>•&nbsp;Margaret Mitchell,&nbsp;President and CEO, YWCA<br>•&nbsp;Monique Morris,&nbsp;President and CEO, Grantmakers for Girls of Color<br>•&nbsp;Sue Santa, Senior Vice President&nbsp;for&nbsp;Public Policy &amp; Advocacy, Girl Scouts of the USA<br>•&nbsp;Joanne Smith,&nbsp;President and CEO, Girls for Gender Equity</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Actions to Lower Gas Prices at the Pump for American&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/31/remarks-by-president-biden-on-actions-to-lower-gas-prices-at-the-pump-for-american-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 22:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 1:48 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; As I said in my State of the Union Address, I’m going to always be honest with the American people.&#160; Today, I want to talk with you about the costs here at home of Putin’s decision to brutally and savagely invade a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>1:48 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; As I said in my State of the Union Address, I’m going to always be honest with the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I want to talk with you about the costs here at home of Putin’s decision to brutally and savagely invade a sovereign nation.&nbsp; The fact is, he’s causing thousands of deaths and untold destruction.</p>



<p>Working with our NATO Allies and our European partners and beyond that, we &#8212; we’re responding.&nbsp; We’re aiding the Ukrainian people both economically and militarily while levying the most punishing economic sanctions against Russia ever used against another nation in place and increasing them.</p>



<p>Thus far, these actions are crippling Russia’s economy, isolating Putin from the world, and helping Ukrainians fight for their country and ease their suffering.</p>



<p>But as I’ve said from the start, Putin’s war is imposing a cost on America and our allies and democracies around the world.</p>



<p>Today, I want to talk about one aspect of Putin’s war that affects and has real effects on the American people: Putin’s price hike that Americans and our allies are feeling at the pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know how much it hurts.&nbsp; As you’ve heard me say before, I grew up in a family, like many of you, where when the price of a gallon of gasoline went up, it was discussed at the kitchen table.&nbsp; Our family budgets, your family budgets to fill a tank &#8212; none of it should hinge on whether a dictator declares war.</p>



<p>So, today, I’m laying out a two-part plan not only to ease the pain that families are feeling right now, but to end this era of dependence and uncertainty, and to lay a new foundation for true and lasting American energy independence.</p>



<p>Parenthetically, just imagine if, in fact, Europe didn’t have to count on Russian oil &#8212; if they were energy independent.&nbsp; It would change the nature of so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The problem we’re facing with gas prices has two roots.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, the pandemic.&nbsp; When COVID struck, demand for oil plummeted, so production slowed down worldwide.&nbsp; Because of the strength and the speed of our recovery, demand for oil shot back up much faster than the supply.&nbsp; That’s why the cost of gas began to rise last year.</p>



<p>The second root is Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; At the start of this year, gas was about $3.30 a gallon.&nbsp; Today, it’s about &#8212; averaging $4.20, $4.22.&nbsp; It’s higher in many states.&nbsp; Nearly a dollar more in less than three months.&nbsp; And the reason for that is because of Putin’s war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now, many people are no longer buying Russian oil around the world.&nbsp; I banned the Russian import of oil here in America; Republicans and Democrats in Congress called for it and supported it.&nbsp; It was the right thing to do.</p>



<p>But as I said at the time, it’s going to come with a cost.&nbsp; As Russian oil comes off the global market, supply of oil drops and prices are rising. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Now Putin’s price strike &#8212; price hike is hitting Americans at the pump, which brings me to the first part of my plan: to immediately increase the supply of oil.</p>



<p>Our prices are rising because of Putin’s actions.&nbsp; There isn’t enough supply.</p>



<p>And the bottom line is: If we want lower gas prices, we need to have more oil supply right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For U.S. oil companies that are recording their largest profits in years, they have a choice.&nbsp; One, they can put those profits to productive use by producing more oil, restarting idle wells, or producing on the sites they already are leasing &#8212; giving the American people a break by passing some of the savings on to their customers and lowering the price at the pump.</p>



<p>Or they can, as some of them are doing, exploit the situation: sit back, ship those profits to their investors, and &#8212; while American families struggle to make ends meet.</p>



<p>Look, this is a moment of consequence and peril for the world and pain at the pump for American families.</p>



<p>It’s also a moment of patriotism.&nbsp; I want to acknowledge those companies that have already announced they’re increasing immediate production.&nbsp; They’re investing money to produce more oil and also clean technologies we need to reduce our dependence on oil in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They have everything they need.&nbsp; Nothing is standing in their way.&nbsp; And they’ve indicated they will be producing an extra 1 million barrels of oil per day, probably starting as early as this fall.&nbsp; That’s progress.</p>



<p>But some companies have been pretty blunt.&nbsp; They don’t want to increase supply because Putin’s price hike means higher profits.</p>



<p>One CEO even acknowledged that they don’t care if the price of a barrel of oil goes to $200 a barrel.&nbsp; They’re not going to step up the production.</p>



<p>I say: Enough.&nbsp; Enough of lavishing excessive profits on investors and payouts and buybacks when the American people are watching, the world is watching.</p>



<p>U.S. oil companies made nearly $80 billion in profit last year.&nbsp; And this year, those profits are expected to continue to soar.</p>



<p>This is a time &#8212; not the time to sit on record profits.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s time to step up for the good of your country, the good of the world; to invest in immediate production that we need to respond to Vladimir Putin; to provide some relief for your customers, not investors and executives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; I have no problem with corporations turning a good profit.&nbsp; But companies have an obligation that goes beyond just their shareholders: to their customers, their communities, and their country.</p>



<p>No American company should take advantage of a pandemic or Vladimir Putin’s actions to enrich themselves at the expense of American families.</p>



<p>Investing those provits [sic] &#8212; profits in production and innovation &#8212; that&#8217;s what they should do.&nbsp; Invest in your customers.</p>



<p>And it isn&#8217;t just like &#8212; it&#8217;s not the patriotic thing to do; it’s good for your business as well.</p>



<p>Right now, the oil and gas industry is sitting on nearly 9,000 unused but approved permits for production on federal lands.&nbsp; There are more than <s>a</s> [12] million unused acres they have a right to &#8212; to pump on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Families can’t afford that companies sit on these &#8212; their hands.</p>



<p>So, to help execute this first part of my plan, I’m calling for a “use it or lose it” policy.</p>



<p>Congress should make companies pay fees on wells on federal leases they haven’t used in years and acres of public land they’re hoarding without production.</p>



<p>Companies that are already producing from these wells won’t be affected.&nbsp; But those sitting on unused leases and idle wells will either have to start producing or pay the price for their inaction.</p>



<p>Look, the action I’m calling for will make a real difference over time.&nbsp; But the truth is it takes months, not days, for companies to increase production.</p>



<p>That’s why the next part of my plan is so important.</p>



<p>Today, I’m authorizing the release of 1 million barrels per day for the next six months &#8212; over 180 million barrels &#8212; for the Strategic &#8212; from the &#8212; from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</p>



<p>This is a wartime bridge to increase oil supply until production ramps up later this year.&nbsp; And it is by far the largest release from our national reserve in our history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It will provide a historic amount of supply for a historic amount of time &#8212; a six-month bridge to the fall.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ll use the revenue from selling the oil now to restock the Strategic Petroleum Reserve when prices are lower so we’ll be ready &#8212; we&#8217;ll be ready for future emergencies.</p>



<p>Folks, I’ve coordinated this release with allies and partners around the world.&nbsp; Already, I have &#8212; we have commitments from other countries to release tens of millions of additional barrels into the market.</p>



<p>Together, our combined efforts will supply well over a million barrels a day &#8212; nations coming together to deny Putin the ability to weaponize his energy resources against American families, and families and democracies around the world.</p>



<p>Now, for the first part of my plan is about meeting an immediate crisis.&nbsp; The second part is about declaring real American energy independence in the long term so that we never have to deal with this problem again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ultimately, we and the whole world need to reduce our dependence on fossil fuels altogether.&nbsp; We need to choose long-term security over energy and climate vulnerability.&nbsp; We need to double down on our commitment to clean energy and tackling the climate crisis with our partners and allies around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we can do that by passing my plan that is literally before the Senate right now &#8212; the United States Congress right now &#8212; it&#8217;s been there for well over a month &#8212; to speed the transition to a clean energy future that is made in America with American products and American values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to embrace all the tools and technologies that can help us free us from our dependence on fossil fuels and move us toward more homegrown clean energy technologies made by American companies and American workers so we can bolster democratic supply &#8212; excuse me &#8212; domestic supply chains here at home and export those technologies around the world to reduce greenhouse gases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why, today, I am issuing a directive to strengthen our clean energy economy.&nbsp; I’m going to use the Defense Production Act to secure American supply chains for the critical materials that go into batteries for electric vehicles and the storage of renewable energy: lithium, graphite, nickel, and so much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to end our long-term reliance on China and other countries for inputs that will power the future.&nbsp; And I’ll use every tool I have to make that happen.</p>



<p>Yes, building a made-in-America clean energy future will help safeguard our national security.&nbsp; Yes, it will help us tackle climate change.&nbsp; Yes, it’s going to help us ensure that America creates millions of good-paying jobs for generations to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But most important &#8212; the most important thing my plan will do right away is save your family money.&nbsp; And here’s what I mean: Under my plan, which is before Congress now, we can take advantage of the next generation of electric vehicles that a typical driver will save about $80 a month from not having to pay gas at the pump.</p>



<p>If your home is powered by safer, cheaper, cleaner electricity, like solar or heat pumps, you can save about $500 a <s>month</s> [year] on average.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Don’t take my word for it.&nbsp; The CEOs of 11 of America’s largest utility companies came to see me at the White House several weeks ago.&nbsp; They told me if we pass my plans before the Congress now, typical families will see savings show up in their utility bills immediately.&nbsp;&nbsp;And costs will come down even more as we innovate and develop cutting-edge energy storage technologies, clean hydrogen technology, advanced nuclear technology, carbon capture- and sequestration technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, this weeks, the benefit I included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to help families weatherize their homes are being delivered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My administration is making $3.2 billion available from this legislation to provide up to $6,500 direct payment for working-class families to be able to weatherize their homes, to save them money, to keep them warm in the winter and cool in the summer.&nbsp; It’s a direct grant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This program has been around for a while, and in the past, it’s delivered to families &#8212; average families another <s>$327</s> [$372] in savings when they weatherize.&nbsp; But now we have the ability to reach 10 times as many families because of the legislation that we already passed in the legislation.&nbsp; But now we have the ability to reach 10 times as many families because of the legislation that we already passed in the legislation.</p>



<p>In addition to that, we’re also setting new standards to boost fuel economies for new vehicles sold in America.&nbsp; Within five years, we’re going to travel 10 miles more on every single gallon we have, because the average fuel economy of 49 miles to the gallon is going to be required.&nbsp; That means hundreds of dollars in savings for families at the pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re also setting similar standards for appliances &#8212; from your air conditioner to your microwave to your refrigerator, washers, dryers.&nbsp; It’s just one of a hundred actions we’re taking to save the average family $100 per year in utility bills.</p>



<p>Look, the bottom line is this: Between rapping up &#8212; ramping up production in the short term and driving down demand in the long term, we can free ourselves from our dependence on imported oil from across the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I know gas prices are painful.&nbsp; I get it.&nbsp; My plan is going to help ease that pain today and safeguard again &#8212; against it tomorrow.&nbsp; I’m open to ideas to strengthen the plan, but I will not be &#8212; put off and put it on hold.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s time to deliver true long-term energy independence in America once and for all.&nbsp; And I’m going to continue to use every tool at my disposal to protect you from Putin’s price hike.&nbsp; This is not time for politics.&nbsp; Americas &#8212; Americans can’t afford that right now.&nbsp; So let’s meet this moment together.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, we’re the only nation that has turned every crisis we ever faced into an opportunity.&nbsp;&nbsp; We have a crisis: the price at the pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So let’s show some true strength of this nation &#8212; show our unity, our resolve, our innovative spirit in America &#8212; and come out of this, long term, much better off.&nbsp; If &#8212; we stand up to the bullies of the world, the autocrats and the dictators.&nbsp; We stand up for who those who are &#8212; who are ready to unite.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unite with us, the United States of America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, may God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how badly is Vladimir Putin being misinformed by his advisors?&nbsp; How badly is Vladimir Putin being misinformed by his advisors?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s an open question.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of speculation, but he seems to be &#8212; I&#8217;m not saying this with a certainty &#8212; he seems to be self-isolating.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s some indication that he has fired or put under house arrest some of his advisors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I &#8212; I don&#8217;t want to put too much stock in that at this time because we don&#8217;t have that much hard evidence.</p>



<p><a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how much, in monetary terms, do you estimate today’s announcement will reduce gas prices?&nbsp; And when can Americans expect to see these changes?</a></p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really important question, and there&#8217;s no firm answer to it.&nbsp; But prices already came down when it was announced ahead of time that Biden was going to release so much &#8212; so much energy fr- &#8212; so many barrels of oil from the SPRO.&nbsp; They&#8217;re already come down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My guess is we&#8217;ll see it come down &#8212; continue to come down.&nbsp; But how far down, I don&#8217;t think anyone can tell.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s going to be a slight delay, because if you go out there and you&#8217;re a gas station and you purchased X amount of gas at a certain price, you&#8217;re not going to lower the price of the pump until you&#8217;re able to get back what you invested.&nbsp; And that &#8212; I&#8217;m talking a matter of, I think, you know, days and weeks.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s hard to tell.</p>



<p>And the other thing is &#8212; exact.&nbsp;&nbsp; But it will come down.&nbsp; And it could come down fairly significantly.&nbsp; It could come down the better part of &#8212; you know, anything from 10 cents to 35 cents a gallon.&nbsp; It’s unknown at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m also waiting to see whether or not our allies &#8212; exactly how many &#8212; how many barrels they released from their supplies.&nbsp; Now, my guess is it could be as high &#8212; somewhere between 30 million to 50 million barrels.&nbsp; And the higher the number, the more likely the prices will come down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, have you seen any sign &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, is buying oil &#8212; Mr. President, is buying oil from Venezuela out of the table?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, have you seen any signs that Putin is pulling back his forces?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he’s not pulling back his forces?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At pre-war level, sir?&nbsp; Are the sanctions still working, sir?&nbsp; Are the sanctions still working, sir?&nbsp; The ruble is back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll answer one question &#8212; your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The question is: Is he pulling back his forces?&nbsp; Whoever asked that question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I asked that.&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The question of whether he is pulling back his forces &#8212; it depends on how you read exactly what&#8217;s going on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thus far, there is no clear evidence that he&#8217;s pulling all of his forces out of Kyiv.&nbsp; And there is also evidence that he is beefing up his troops down in the Donbas area.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Depending on your view of Putin &#8212; I&#8217;m a little skeptical &#8212; it&#8217;s an open question of whether he&#8217;s actually pulling back and going to say, &#8220;I&#8217;m just going to focus on the Donbas, and I&#8217;m not worried about the rest of the country.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m a skeptic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have proof that, in fact, he is not going &#8212; he is taking a pause, doing all he can to use all the troops he has in the Donbas and continue to keep an eye on and try to move beyond the rest of the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don’t know the answer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it appears, so far, that he has not pulled all of his &#8212; the idea he&#8217;s pulling all of those troops out from around Kyiv and moving south &#8212; there&#8217;s no evidence that he&#8217;s done that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>2:05 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Director of Communications Kate Bedingfield and NEC Director Brian&#160;Deese</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/31/press-briefing-by-director-of-communications-kate-bedingfield-and-nec-director-brian-deese/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 22:45:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:24 P.M. EDT MS. BEDINGFIELD:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160;&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; So, today we have a very special guest, a friend of the briefing room returning today.&#160; You all know National Economic Council Director Brian Deese.&#160; Brian is joining us to give some brief comments and answer some questions on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:24 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; So, today we have a very special guest, a friend of the briefing room returning today.&nbsp; You all know National Economic Council Director Brian Deese.&nbsp; Brian is joining us to give some brief comments and answer some questions on the President&#8217;s actions today to respond to Putin&#8217;s price hike by increasing the supply of oil and achieving lasting American energy independence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m going to turn it over to Brian, who&#8217;s going to make some comments, and then we&#8217;ll take some of your questions.</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; Just wanted to say thank you, Kate.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So, I just wanted to give a little bit of additional background on a couple of the elements of what the President announced today and then happy to take your questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is on the release of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; As you all just heard from the President, he today authorized the largest release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve in American history: 1 million barrels a day for six months.&nbsp; And I just want to give you a little bit of context.</p>



<p>First, the Strategic Petroleum Reserve itself is our national asset to deal with emergency supply disruptions in energy markets.&nbsp; There&#8217;s currently 568 million barrels in the reserve, which is actually in four locations across southern Louisiana and Texas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the President authorized this reserve under his extraordinary emergency powers associated with supply disruptions, which we have seen in the market are associated with Putin&#8217;s unjustified actions and the reaction from the United States and alliesin the world in no longer purchasing Russian oil.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The scale of the release is unprecedented &#8212; so, a million barrels a day &#8212; and the duration is also unprecedented &#8212; six months.&nbsp; The duration is &#8212; was really designed and calibrated to operate as a bridge &#8212; a medium-term bridge to the period where we anticipate and expect U.S. production to come back online.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The &#8212; most estimates based on commit- &#8212; commitments by companies are that we will see an additional million barrels a day from U.S. industry by about the end of the third quarter of this year.&nbsp; So, this &#8212; the time period operates as a bridge until then.</p>



<p>And the amount &#8212; a million barrels today &#8212; is unprecedented but feasible based on the technical capabilities&nbsp; of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also know there is significant demand in the market.&nbsp; We are operating in a supply-constrained market.&nbsp; That is the core challenge that is addressed &#8212; that has driven prices up.&nbsp; But we saw for example, the last &#8212; the last sale that the Strategic Petroleum Reserve conducted was oversubscribed by about two and a half times.&nbsp; So there is demand out there in the market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last thing that I would say is that a very important element of the President&#8217;s announcement today was that the President authorized the sale but also the commitment to repurchase oil.&nbsp; And that will happen in coming years at a lower price.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s important for two reasons.&nbsp; One is, yeah, it provides that bridge to &#8212; during this period of extraordinary supply constraint.&nbsp; But it also provides stability to the market in the future that there will be a buyer to purchase oil at a lower price.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it also allows us to actually maintain and increase the resilience of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve over the long term.&nbsp; We will be refilling the reserve.&nbsp; And if we&#8217;re buying at a lower price, we&#8217;ll actually be in a position to refill at a &#8212; more barrels, ultimately.&nbsp; So, the current 568 million barrels will come down but then will go back up, and that&#8217;s how the reserve functions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secondly, just briefly, I wanted to touch on the presidential directive that the President signed today authorizing the Defense Production Act for usage for the critical materials that go into large-capacity batteries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the President took this action under Title 3 of the Defense Production Act, which provides for prioritizing and subsidizing the production domestically of key inputs that are critical to the national defense.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the Secretary of Defense has undertaken a study and identified that large-capacity batteries are critical to the national defense &#8212; and the components that go into them, including lithium and nickel, cobalt, graphite, manganese.&nbsp; My guess is that&#8217;s the first time in the White House briefing room someone has said &#8220;manganese.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>These are critical minerals.&nbsp; And we are currently vulnerable to unreliable supply chains, which affects our national security.&nbsp; It also affects our economic security as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, taking &#8212; by taking this action, the President is authorizing the government to use the DPA authorities to build domestic production capability in these key materials.&nbsp; And this is going to be a key driver for building a domestically resilient supply chain to build large-capacity batteries &#8212; those are the batteries that go into electric vehicles, but also used for storage in other applications &#8212; and also to accelerate what the President talked about today of how we move to true energy independence by reducing our dependence on oil, the amount of oil that we consume, and reducing our dependence on fossil fuels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, those are &#8212; those are two.&nbsp; We &#8212; the President touched on other issues as well I&#8217;m happy to take questions all about, but I wanted to put a little bit more context on those two.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll start with Kristen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Kate, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Two questions, Brian.&nbsp; Thank you for being here.&nbsp; One, to the figure &#8220;1 million barrels per day&#8221; and to the skepticism that that sounds unrealistic, why should Americans have confidence that you&#8217;re going to be able to meet that benchmark on a daily basis?&nbsp; And when can Americans expect to actually see the price of gas come down?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, on the first one, the Department of Energy&#8217;s Strategic Petroleum Reserve have now committed, per the President&#8217;s direction, to release a million barrels a day into the market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number one, we have the full operational capacity to do that. &nbsp;As I mentioned, there are actually four locations that make up the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; For purposes of this release, we will be releasing from all four of those locations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you look at the actual operational capacity across all four of them, it is actually up to 4 million barrels a day in operational capacity.&nbsp; So, actually executing a million barrels a day is well within the operational constraints.&nbsp; And a big part of that is because a lot of that moves by pipeline, and so they &#8212; to established offtake points.&nbsp; That&#8217;s point number one.</p>



<p>Point number two: There&#8217;s been some question about will there be sufficient market interest or sufficient demand, including on the transport side.&nbsp; And I would say there that the most &#8212; the best indicator is what just happened in the market when &#8212; in the last &#8212; the last sale that the SPR tendered was two and a half times oversubscribed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, certainly, there is significant demand in the market and that you would expect because supply is constrained and prices are high.&nbsp; So, we fully expect that the Strategic Petroleum Reserve will execute against this, per the President&#8217;s direction.</p>



<p>To your question about the timing of &#8212; of the impact, we&#8217;ve already seen &#8212; and as we came in here, you know, oil is trading down about 6 percent today &#8212; but the way that we think about this is in terms of supply and the market constraint.</p>



<p>And so, the supply in the global market &#8212; obviously, the price of oil is set at the global &#8212; at the margin, the global market.&nbsp; The global supply is down because of Russian oil.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The million barrels a day plus what our allies and partners are intending to deliver &#8212; and there&#8217;s a &#8212; there is a meeting tomorrow morning of the International Energy Agency in Paris, an emergency meeting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I won&#8217;t get ahead of the specific commitments in that context, but as the President said, we&#8217;re confident that our allies and partners will provide tens of millions of barrels additional into the market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re looking at well in excess of a million barrels a day of additional supply onto the market for an &#8212; importantly for several months &#8212; that that is the most ambitious, aggressive, historic effort to try to replace supply in the short term.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, certainly, there is uncertainty about pricing, and lots of different factors affect price across time, but we &#8212; we are confident that this is about the largest effort that oil &#8212; that countries with oil reserves have ever taken to supply the market in this way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And could prices come down in a matter of days or weeks?&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s difficult to pinpoint, but just for Americans who budget based on how much they have to spend on gasoline, what should they be bracing for?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Well, the &#8212; as the President spoke to today, that is uncertain.&nbsp; And so, you know &#8212; and being &#8212; being very clear, the market price is impossible to predict with certainty.</p>



<p>One thing that I will say for sure is that as the price of oil comes down, it&#8217;s incredibly important that the &#8212; that it flows through to the consumer, in terms of the price of gas, as quickly as feasible.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that be a problem in the past, and it&#8217;s definitely an issue that we are focused on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Justin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Brian.&nbsp; I have two.&nbsp; One is &#8212; to follow on, I think, what you just said, which is &#8212; you&#8217;ve identified there&#8217;s been a problem between crude oil prices and what folks are paying at the pump, and laid some of the blame for that at oil companies in the past.</p>



<p>The President today, in his remarks, spoke to some extent about how there were good actors and bad actors in terms of folks who are ramping up production right now versus the folks who are sort of banking profit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I wanted to give you an opportunity &#8212; for Americans who want to do the patriotic thing, where should they be going to buy their gas right now?&nbsp; Are there &#8212; are there good companies that have worked with the administration and folks that you&#8217;re frustrated with right now?</p>



<p>And then, my other question was on your former friends, kind of, in the green community that have expressed, I think, some level of frustration with the announcement today &#8212; feeling like it&#8217;s doubling down on fossil fuels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, I know that you&#8217;ve kind of made this argument that, long term, you&#8217;re trying to pivot towards green energy, especially with the second part of the announcement today.&nbsp; But what do you say to climate activists who are sort of frustrated right now?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; So, on the first &#8212; on the first part of the question, I would say our goal is to provide relief to all Americans in all geographies across the country.&nbsp; And that means doing everything we can to bring down the price of gas at the pump everywhere.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s our &#8212; that&#8217;s our focus.</p>



<p>And the issue of the prices of gas going up very quickly and tracking oil prices and coming down much more slowly is not new.&nbsp; It&#8217;s old enough that economists have a particular term associated with it called “rockets and feathers.”&nbsp; But just because we can identify it doesn&#8217;t mean that it is &#8212; it reflects an efficient market or a competitive market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that &#8212; that has been &#8212; that has been our focus.</p>



<p>On your second question, I want to be really clear.&nbsp; And I think the President &#8212; you know, the President said this better today, but I will just underscore it.&nbsp; The circumstances in global oil markets today and global energy markets today provide the clearest possible signal why the United States needs to do everything it can to accelerate toward energy security and true energy independence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the only way that we can ultimately do that is to reduce and eliminate our dependence on fossil fuels &#8212; that&#8217;s what the President was clear about today &#8212; and that, in fact, in the very near term, making sure that we have adequate supply is critically important for American families who are suffering.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the opportunity to actually work in partnership with our European allies &#8212; for example, to help them reduce their own dependence by reducing demand for fossil energy &#8212; by moving forward on the plan that the President underscored today, we have a historic opportunity to do that.&nbsp; And we are wasting no time and we are taking no &#8212; this is not causing us to do anything but move even more quickly in the steps that we can take.</p>



<p>I think the message that we have is that not only &#8212; not only can we do these things together, but we have to do these things together.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Alex.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up about the allies and partners who would be participating.&nbsp; Can you give any additional detail?&nbsp; Will China be participating in the oil release?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any specific commitments, but I&#8217;ll say a couple of things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is that, as with every action that we have taken in relation to the war in Ukraine, the President and our entire team have been consulting and working incredibly closely with allies and partners on this.&nbsp; This was a significant topic in the President&#8217;s call with the Quint on Monday, at the leader level.&nbsp; Our teams have been working around the clock together, before going into that and in the period since.</p>



<p>The IEA is the body of countries that have significant stocks and reserves, and the formal process that they, under &#8212; that they go into &#8212; and the United States is a member of the IEA &#8212; is to bring forward a proposal for a collective release.&nbsp; And the que- &#8212; the decision is whether there is a collective release and then how much each country will contribute into that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s the process that will &#8212; that will happen starting tomorrow morning.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The only thing that I would say &#8212; and I think this is probably implicit in what we have done here &#8212; is we, the United States and the President, made an explicit decision that the United States would lead here and lead with a historic use of our reserves.&nbsp; We have those reserves; we have the capability to do that.&nbsp; And so that was a &#8212; that was an explicit decision, at the same time looking to partner with allies.&nbsp; And I think we will see that reflected over the course of the next couple</p>



<p>of days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, all of the IEA members are the only ones participating in the release?&nbsp; Is that accurate?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Well, what I can tell you is that the IEA &#8212; the meeting tomorrow will be of IEA me- &#8212; of IEA members, and that will be &#8212; the question will be about a collective release in that context.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We continue to engage with non-IEA members &#8212; China and other countries &#8212; around their reserves, and we’ll continue to do so.&nbsp; But the immediate &#8212; the immediate step at hand will be the IEA.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said gas might drop between 10 and 35 cents a gallon, Brian.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does sound about right to you &#8212; 10 and 35 cents a gallon?&nbsp; Does that sound about right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s what President Biden said.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; have any reaction to OPEC failing to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that 10, 35 cents &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Brian.&nbsp; On this “use it or lose it” push &#8212; you know, the President had discussions with leaders in the oil industry ahead of this announcement.&nbsp; What, if any, assurances were given about increasing production?&nbsp; Were there any guarantees made?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, what we have engaged with oil companies and energy companies on, they have been public about.&nbsp; So you can see &#8212; the reason why the market expectation has now increased to an expectation of about a million barrels a day of additional production online is because many of those companies have gone out and been quite explicit about their intention to ramp up production across time.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s an outgrowth of a number of the conversations that we have had.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the “use or lose it” approach is consistent in the sense that those companies that are looking to ramp production or to to bring back online shuttered wells, those permitted areas would obviously be unaffected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, does 10 to 35 cents sounds &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; April.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m asking a question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Brian &#8212; I’m sorry.&nbsp; Brian.</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; As I said, it&#8217;s uncertain, and so I&#8217;ll let the President &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Brian, so since &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does that &#8212; what’s a fair price &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, they called on me.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What’s a fair price &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Brian.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that you would accept, the White House, for gas?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Brian, as you just spoke about China, what are the conversations with India &#8212; another country that’s dealing with major oil issues, gasoline issues?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, what are the guarantees with this 1 million a day for six months for Americans?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, there &#8212; our conversations with all countries that have reserves is similar in encouraging them to participate and to contribute in, consistent with their stocks &#8212; their available stocks and their &#8212; and their circumstances.</p>



<p>We have seen to date a quite extraordinary willingness to participate &#8212; including IEA and non-IEA members &#8212; to participate in those coordinated releases, including the Indian government to date.&nbsp; And so, the work of diplomacy and engagement with our allies and partners is aimed to make sure that that continues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But isn&#8217;t it more about the United States, China, and India, when you are looking at these three &#8212; top three consumers of oil?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, in terms &#8212; what &#8212; when we’re talking about collective releases, the issue is actually where are the countr- &#8212; who are the countries that actually have the largest reserves &#8212; not the largest consumers, but the largest reserves.&nbsp; So those are the IEA.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But consumption does play into this as well, though.</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Certainly.&nbsp; But in terms of releasing supply onto the market, that&#8217;s a function of the reserves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, what are the guarantees for the American consumer in these six months, in the midst of COVID, in the midst of this war, in the midst of Russia doing whatever it&#8217;s doing?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Well &#8212; and I think this goes to the question &#8212; the gentleman&#8217;s question as well.&nbsp; What the President &#8212; what the President has said is &#8212; is that, in terms of guarantees, he&#8217;s going to do everything that he can.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to stay at this, even in a very uncertain period, to do everything within his power to try to provide relief to families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we can now commit that we will deliver a million barrels a day into the &#8212; into the market, consistent with the President&#8217;s directive across time.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, I think Brian has time for one more.</p>



<p>Ed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Brian.&nbsp; In talking about countries that may or may not get involved, I’m curious if there&#8217;s been any more conversation with Venezuela, Iran, Saudi Arabia about boosting the production or about working out how we can potentially see more of their oil get back on the market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, on the “use or lose it” proposal he talked about &#8212; the idea that companies would be fined if they don&#8217;t use their leases &#8212; is there existing legislation he&#8217;s referring to?&nbsp; Or how would that work?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how is that &#8212; if not legal, how is that in keeping with sort of the capitalistic &#8212; he says he&#8217;s a capitalist.</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Of course.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who is the government to be telling businesses what to do with something they’ve leased, I guess?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, on your first, there are conversations, engagements ongoing, but I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any new update on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the &#8212; on the second, the &#8212; we start from the premise that all of these are leases on public land, so it&#8217;s federal &#8212; it&#8217;s federal land, and so it&#8217;s a &#8212; your assets as a &#8212; as citizens and as taxpayers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the way the process works is that companies lease tracts of land.&nbsp; They then &#8212; in areas where they are more interested in potentially discovering, they then seek a permit within their leased areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the way that this policy would operate would be to say: Going forward, in those areas where you are holding leased land but you are not exploring, then you &#8212; then you would pay incrementally on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say two things.&nbsp; One is: When companies lease, they’ll lease with the federal government.&nbsp; Again, this is companies operating with the federal government on public land.&nbsp; The lease is to explore and to pursue production.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the stated &#8212; those are the stated lease terms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it is &#8212; it’s appropriate for the federal &#8212; and number two, companies can always rescind their leases or transfer their leases as well.&nbsp; So they can &#8212; they can &#8212; they can provide their leases back to the federal government if they no longer have any use for them, or they could transfer them as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is really about a very practical issue, which is everybody &#8212; Republicans, Democrats &#8212; everyone is saying we need to figure out how to increase more supply.&nbsp; And so, in those areas where we already know that the leases have occurred, the permits have occurred, there&#8217;s nothing more that needs to happen, we should be encouraging companies to operate.&nbsp; And if they don&#8217;t intend to, or they don&#8217;t &#8212; they don&#8217;t want to, then they could hand those leases back to the government.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you still concerned that gas prices could hit record highs this spring and this summer?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, the &#8212; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to predict where the &#8212; where the market will go.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll &#8212; you&#8217;ll find me not predicting on any particular forward data point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I will say is that because of the President&#8217;s actions today, because of a historic effort to put a million barrels a day of supply into the market, and because of the effort to work with allies and partners and galvanize a global response on this front, the market will be significantly more well supplied and prices will be lower than if we didn&#8217;t take this historic action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that’s &#8212; you know, that’s what &#8212; our focus is actions that we can take to make sure that the &#8212; that prices come down as much as we can.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Brian, one on food security real quick.&nbsp; Do you have updates on the President&#8217;s efforts to prevent real food shortages sparked by the war?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, we are &#8212; it&#8217;s a issue of &#8212; a top focus, and we will have more to say on that issue in the coming days.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have a specific announcement for you today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any reaction to OPEC only incrementally raising production?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s the same answer as the question earlier.&nbsp; We continue to have those conversations, but I don&#8217;t have anything new for you today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any message to low-income Americans getting clobbered right now at the pumps?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; You have a President who &#8212; you have a President who is doing everything that he possibly can to try to address that situation, including, I would say, the President announced today, and I would encourage you all to &#8212; to really cover it and look into it: $3.2 million through the weatherization program that goes directly to low-income families.&nbsp; A low-income family could get a $6,500 grant to make their home more energy efficient, bring down their energy costs by hundreds of dollars a year, and improve the health of their home.&nbsp; That’s something the President did this week, putting that money out, in addition to the other issues that we discussed today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Thanks, Brian.&nbsp; Thank you all very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, if you will just indulge me for a minute, I have a few announcements I&#8217;d like to make at the top here, so just bear with me.</p>



<p>So, today we&#8217;re marking Transgender &#8212; the Transgender Day of Visibility by celebrating transgender Americans who are thriving and making their communities stronger.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, transgender Americans, particularly children, continue to face unacceptably high levels of bullying and discrimination.&nbsp; As you know, the President signed one of the most comprehensive executive orders on LGBTQI+ rights in history, shortly after taking office.&nbsp; And this administration has repeatedly and forcefully called out state legislatures that are advancing legislation that discriminates against trans children and their families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, the State Department and Department of Homeland Security announced new steps that will improve the travel experience for transgender Americans.&nbsp; And the Department of Health and Human Services has released new resources for transgender kids and their families to help protect their mental health and ensure they receive the care they need to thrive.</p>



<p>Finally, the President is reiterating his call for the Senate to pass the Equality Act to provide long-overdue civil rights protections to transgender and LGBTQI+ Americans.</p>



<p>As the President told transgender Americans in his State of the Union Address, this administration will always have your back so you can be yourself and reach your God-given potential.</p>



<p>Today, we&#8217;re also celebrating the life and legacy of César Estrada Chávez &#8212; a champion for social justice, an advocate for farmworkers and working people who build and sustain our nation; a leader who has inspired generations of people to fight, organize, and expand opportunities for workers.</p>



<p>When President Biden became President, he placed a bust of César Chávez in the Oval Office as a reminder of the values and his vision to fight for respect, social justice, and equal dignity for all workers.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris administration remains committed to building an economy from the bottom up and the middle out that works for all.&nbsp; We fought hard to pass the American Rescue Plan that helped Latino workers, families, and small businesses to ensure that they had the support they needed through the pandemic.&nbsp; And we created a historic Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment to help workers to organize to provide an earned pathway to citizenship.</p>



<p>Today, we join people across the country celebrating and honoring César Chávez’s legacy while we continue to advance the rights and dignity of working people.</p>



<p>Today, new CDC data further underscored the mental health impact of the pandemic, including the fact that nearly half of high schoolers reported that they felt persistently sad or hopeless during the past year.</p>



<p>As a mother of young kids, I know this is a huge concern for so many parents.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has been acutely aware of the mental health impact of the pandemic on young people, which is why he made it a Day One priority to get schools reopened safely and secure much-needed resources through the American Rescue Plan to address youth mental health &#8212; a bill which every single Republican, I would note, voted against.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve invested five and a half billion dollars in programs that support mental health and wellbeing, including tens of millions for programs that specifically address youth mental health.</p>



<p>For instance, schools across the country are using American Rescue Plan funds to hire school counselors and social workers to address this crisis &#8212; according to this new CDC data, the very kind of connection that helps protect youth mental health.</p>



<p>President Biden remains deeply focused on this very real crisis and providing the resources to address it.&nbsp; As part of the Unity Agenda that he laid out during the State of the Union Address and his budget, the President put forward a historic increase in funding to strengthen and expand youth mental health services.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to build on this progress and do everything we can to support the mental health and wellbeing of our young people.</p>



<p>And then lastly, but certainly not least, today we announced additional sanctions on Russian technology companies that enable Putin&#8217;s war of choice.&nbsp; We will prevent them from procuring Western technology and evading our severe sanctions.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also expanding our sanctions authority to target additional sectors of the Russian economy important to Putin, including aerospace, maritime, and the electronics sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the coming days, the Commerce Department will also take further action to degrade Russia&#8217;s defense, aerospace, and maritime sectors by adding 120 entities in Russia and Belarus to the Entity List, bringing the number of Russian and Belarusian parties added to the list to over 200 since the invasion began.&nbsp; Being added to this list means that these entities can no longer get U.S. cutting-edge technology without a license, which will &#8212; which will in most, if not all, of these cases be denied.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Compared to the same time period last year, U.S. exports to Russia of items subject to our new export controls have decreased by 99 percent by value.&nbsp; The power of these restrictions will compound over time as Russia draws down any remaining stockpiles &#8212; for example, spare parts for certain planes and tanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will continue to impose unprecedented costs, strengthen Ukraine&#8217;s hand, and make Putin&#8217;s war of choice a strategic failure.</p>



<p>So, thanks for hanging with me.&nbsp; I told you I had a lot.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m happy to take questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Darlene?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; A couple on Russia.&nbsp; Can you elaborate first on the President’s comment a while ago that there is some indication that Putin has either fired some of his top officials or put some of them under house arrest?&nbsp; What evidence or information does the White House have?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, the President&#8217;s words on that speak for thems- &#8212; for themselves.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a lot to add by the way of detail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would point to is certainly information that we made public yesterday about Putin and his military.&nbsp; You know, I think, writ large, we have seen this invasion has been a strategic failure for Putin and for Russia.&nbsp; They are working to re-define the intentional the &#8212; the initial, I should say &#8212; the initial aims of their invasion.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen, time and again, that the sanctions that have been applied are providing &#8212; are exacting extreme costs on their economy.</p>



<p>So, I don&#8217;t have anything to add to what the President said, except to say we have seen incontrovertible evidence that this has been a strategic disaster for Russia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the second question is: The United States, the UK have been working together to release intelligence information since before Russia invaded Ukraine.&nbsp; And I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about the value of that relationship and how the White House thinks it&#8217;s affected Putin’s conduct in the war &#8212; releasing that kind of information.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak to how it&#8217;s impacted Putin&#8217;s conduct.&nbsp; That&#8217;s again &#8212; as I said yesterday, I&#8217;m not a spokesperson for the Kremlin.</p>



<p>What I can say, though, is that we&#8217;ve made every effort to be transparent.&nbsp; Even from the time before Putin invaded, we worked to make sure that we were providing information that gave a sense of what we knew Russia was going to do.</p>



<p>I think it &#8212; you know, to call them out in that way, and to be clear that we knew what their intentions were, had the impact of putting them on their back foot.</p>



<p>I can&#8217;t &#8212; again, I can&#8217;t speak to how that&#8217;s impacted their calculus; that&#8217;s for them to say.&nbsp; But I think we&#8217;ve seen, writ large, that the invasion has been a strategic error, is leaving Russia weaker.&nbsp; Putin himself has said that the sanctions have imposed unprecedented costs on the Russian economy.</p>



<p>And our role in this &#8212; our role is to continue to strengthen Ukraine on the battlefield, as we&#8217;ve been doing with an unprecedented amount of security assistance, and to continue to strengthen their hand at the negotiating table.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more, quickly.&nbsp; Going back to the information that you mentioned you all released yesterday, is that some sort of an attempt to sow division among the Russian leadership?&nbsp; And if so, does the White House think that is</p>



<p>working?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; It is simply an effort to continue to paint the picture of what a strategic blunder this decision has been for Vladimir Putin.</p>



<p>Mary.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that, it seems you&#8217;re releasing even more information today.&nbsp; A U.S. official says you have information that indicates that some Russian government senior officials likely disagreed with Putin&#8217;s decision to invade Ukraine, that their disillusionment is probably amplified by Russia&#8217;s military underperformance.&nbsp; Is it your understanding that Putin is losing the support of some of his top officials?&nbsp; And why release this as well?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, again, I don&#8217;t have anything further to add to the specifics there.&nbsp; I can only speak to what this underscores, which is the larger sense that this has been a failure for Russia.</p>



<p>You know, I think we&#8217;ve seen reporting that morale amongst the Russian military is low.&nbsp; And I think that would not come as a surprise to anyone who&#8217;s seen what the Russian military is &#8212; is enduring here.&nbsp; You have conscripts.&nbsp; You have people who&#8217;ve been brought in to fight this incredibly grueling battle.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a surprise to anybody that morale is low.</p>



<p>But beyond that, I don&#8217;t have anything specific that I can add.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the President&#8217;s comments about, you know, people being put under house arrest or arrested, can you say &#8212; is it your understanding that those who are being arrested under house arrest are ones who sort of broke the bad news to the President about the military&#8217;s performance, or are they ones who now are disagreeing with &#8212; disagree with the decision to invade in</p>



<p>the first place?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any further additional detail that I can add.</p>



<p>Mike.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;You keep saying though that, though &#8212; that this is to try and, you know, paint a picture of Putin’s strategic blunder or strategic error, but it certainly seems like you&#8217;re needling and trolling Vladimir Putin here.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Those are your words, not ours.&nbsp; I &#8212; we have been very clear that we are &#8212; everything that we are doing here is designed to advance our ultimate strategic aim, which is strengthening &#8212; as I said, strengthening Ukraine on the battlefield, strengthening their hand at the negotiating table, giving them what they need to push back on Russian aggression.</p>



<p>And I think it is self-evident based on what we&#8217;ve seen since Putin invaded on February 24 &#8212; as we&#8217;ve seen their economy collapse; we&#8217;ve seen the ruble collapse.&nbsp; You know, the <a></a><a>impact of his choice has been significant.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to advance our strategy of doing everything we can to ensure that Ukraine is &#8212; has what they need to continue to push back on Russian aggression.</a></p>



<p>Mike.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This may be a little late &#8212; late-breaking, I don&#8217;t know, but there have been reports in the last hour or so about concerns at Chernobyl, with Russian &#8212; with Russians leaving the nuclear plant because of some kind of exposure.&nbsp; Do you have any &#8212; does the U.S. government have any information about what might be going on there and whether &#8212; sort of how broad the danger is there?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I have not seen that since we came into this room, but I&#8217;m happy to go look into it, and we can come back to you with answers.</p>



<p>Yeah.&nbsp; Cleve.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; On COVID, I wonder if you can comment on reports that there&#8217;s an “agreement in principle” for $10 billion in additional COVID aid.&nbsp; I think Senator Romney talked about it earlier today.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, as we talked about yesterday, we are obviously very hopeful that Congress is making progress as we need to get this urgent funding that we need to fight COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has been very clear there is a strong sense of urgency here.&nbsp; You know, you heard him say yesterday that Congress&#8217;s failure to act is already having severe consequences, including on our supply of monoclonal antibodies and treatments for the immunocompromised.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, these are, as you note, ongoing active negotiations on this, and so we&#8217;re certainly not going to negotiate from the podium.&nbsp; But I will say that the President has been very clear that there&#8217;s an urgent need for this funding, and we&#8217;re very hopeful that Congress is going to come to a solution on this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One follow on that.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think the plan calls for slashing some of the foreign aid.&nbsp; You know, Biden has said repeatedly that we can&#8217;t just, you know, take care of ourselves; that we have to &#8212; you know, the pandemic isn&#8217;t going to stop.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no wall we can build.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Would he sign a bill or would he veto a bill that doesn&#8217;t include significant foreign aid?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, what I would say to this is: We have been very clear and the President has been very clear, both publicly and in private, about the acute need for funding of our global response for weeks, if not months.&nbsp; And in the past day, our position has been very clear about the importance here.</p>



<p>Right now, countries, in fact, are declining our doses because they don&#8217;t have the infrastructure in place to take our lifesaving vaccines.&nbsp; Funding will obviously help solve this issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I actually want to read to you a letter to the President signed by 14 U.S. senators, half of whom are Republicans.&nbsp; Quote, “We urge you in the strongest possible terms to do more to lead global efforts to end this pandemic and increase global vaccine access.”</p>



<p>So, we hope that these senators will follow their own advice and provide resources for the global response, because now is the time to act, and we&#8217;re not going to be able to put this pandemic behind us until we stop the spread and proliferation of new variants globally.</p>



<p>So, the President has been very clear he believes this funding is important.&nbsp; But again, we&#8217;re going to let Congress work through, and we&#8217;re very hopeful that they are going to come to a solution.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Russia follow-up.</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Kristen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; I want to ask you again about the President&#8217;s comments today when he was asked about the information that Putin is being left in the dark by his advisors.&nbsp; He seemed much less confident in the intelligence than you were from the podium and other top officials here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When he was asked about it today, he said it&#8217;s “an open question.&#8221;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of speculation.&nbsp; “He seems to be self-isolating,” he said, “but we don&#8217;t have hard evidence.”&nbsp; You said from the podium, “We have information that Putin felt misled by the Russian military.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why the disconnect?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t see a disconnect there.&nbsp; We were clear yesterday that we shared a piece of information that helps paint a picture about how this has been a strategic failure for Russia.&nbsp; There &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said, “There&#8217;s a lot of speculation.”&nbsp; He didn&#8217;t say, “We have hard evidence.&nbsp; We&#8217;re confident.”</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; And there&#8217;s &#8212; there is plenty of discussion.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of what we did yesterday, was put additional information into the public sphere, into the conversation.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a disconnect between those two things.&nbsp; The President was making a statement about where things currently stand &#8212; where he understands things to currently stand.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s &#8212; I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s in any way at odds with what we said yesterday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is the administration confident that Putin is being left in the dark by his top advisors?&nbsp; You stand by everything you said from the podium yesterday?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We put forward information yesterday, and I think you can draw the appropriate conclusion from that.&nbsp; We would not put it forward if we didn&#8217;t have confidence in it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on Hunter Biden, who has been in the headlines again recently.&nbsp; During the last presidential debate, then-Vice President Biden was asked if there was anything inappropriate or unethical about his son&#8217;s relationships, business dealings in China and/or Ukraine.&nbsp; The President said, “Nothing was unethical.”&nbsp; He went on to say, “My son has not made money in terms of this thing about, what you&#8217;re talking about, China.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Does the White House stand by that comment that the then-Vice President made?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We absolutely stand by the President&#8217;s comment.&nbsp; And I would point you to the reporting on this, which reference statements that we made at the time that we gave to the Washington Post, who worked on this story.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but as you know, I don&#8217;t speak for Hunter Biden, so there&#8217;s not more I can say on that.</p>



<p>Jacqui.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp; On releasing barrels from the Strategic Reserve: This move does not resolve the structural deficit that we have.&nbsp; In the last two times the administration released barrels of oil, it didn&#8217;t have a measurable impact on gas prices.&nbsp; So what makes this administration believe that this move is going to have an impact this time?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, this is &#8212; as you heard Brian say, this is a historic and unprecedented release in terms of size.&nbsp; It is going to help meet the mismatch between supply and demand in the market.&nbsp; A million barrels a day is a significant addition to the marketplace and is going to &#8212; as I say, is going to address the &#8212; some of the mismatch between supply and demand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think what Americans should take away from this announcement today is that President Biden is relentlessly focused on doing everything he can to ensure that Putin&#8217;s price hike does not hit them at the gas pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what they&#8217;ve seen from him, I think, since the day he took office is a focus on doing what he can to address kitchen table issues, to address the things that people across the country are worried about, including gas prices.</p>



<p>And so today, you know, not only is it historic in scope, but it &#8212; as you heard Brian talk about, this has also been &#8212; the President has led a global effort to galvanize a response to this because he knows that rising prices at the pump hurt families, and he&#8217;s doing everything in his power to bring those prices down.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is going to bring up the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Oh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is going to bring up the &#8212; the supply in the short term, but it&#8217;s not, you know, a long-term solution.&nbsp; And you know, one analyst has said that if the market maintains a structural deficit for a long period of time, releasing reserves might actually keep prices higher.&nbsp; So if this does not work in the way that you think it&#8217;s going to work, will the administration stop releasing a million barrels a day?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We will cer- &#8212; well, I won&#8217;t &#8212; I won&#8217;t speak to what we might do in the hypothetical depending on where the market goes.&nbsp; What I will say broadly is, of course, we would always adjust our strategy to do what is most effective to bring prices down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would say about the long term, to your &#8212; to your question about the long term, is, you know &#8212; and I think you heard Brian articulate this really well, and of course, the President spoke to it very powerfully today too &#8212; which is: This ultimately shows that dependence on fossil fuels, dependence on foreign oil is not in the sustainable, long-term best interests of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why the President has put forward a really aggressive plan to move us to clean energy sources of energy that we can make here in the United States.&nbsp; That&#8217;s part of, as you heard Brian talk about, the Defense Production Act announcement that he made today to help us make electric vehicle batteries in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, the President feels very strongly that we need to move &#8212; we need to make significant strides toward a clean energy economy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something he&#8217;s been very focused on.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll remember, for those of you who covered the campaign, it&#8217;s something he ran on.&nbsp; And so, he&#8217;s very focused on ensuring that we&#8217;re taking those strides, because that is &#8212; that is actually the long-term solution here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On sanctions, the Russian ruble has almost returned to its pre-war levels.&nbsp; So does the administration believe that the sanctions are still working?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; And what I would say about &#8212; what I would say about the ruble is: What we&#8217;re seeing here is an artificial propping up of the ruble by the Russian Central Bank and by &#8212; and by the Russian government.&nbsp; There are avenues that were closed off to allow the sale of rubles.&nbsp; They are basically taking artificial measures to keep the ruble propped up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would also say that in the first &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what are we doing about that?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; &#8212; you know, in the first few days &#8212; in the first &#8212; I would say also, in the first few days after the conflict began, the ruble was a reliable measure of where the Russian economy is, but it is not any longer, in part because of these artificial steps that are being taken.</p>



<p>So if you look at things like dramatic inflation in Russia, if you look at private investment pulling out of Russia, if you look at Putin himself saying that the sanctions have imposed unprecedented costs, I think that&#8217;s a better metric of where the Russian economy is right now.</p>



<p>Steve.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to follow up on Kristen’s question about the President’s son.&nbsp; Is it your understanding it&#8217;s the President&#8217;s view that as he looks at all of Hunter Biden&#8217;s business dealings with his uncle, that neither Hunter Biden nor James Biden committed any crimes or did anything that was unlawful?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have anything further to add from this podium.&nbsp; We addressed this with the Washington Post.&nbsp; We pointed to statements that were made in the fall of 2020 when we addressed these questions.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have anything additional to add from this podium.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you if there have been &#8212; if you&#8217;re aware if there have been any discussions here inside this White House about whether the President might use his pardon or commutation power with respect to either his son or his brother?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a hypothetical I&#8217;m going to entertain.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to add from this podium.</p>



<p>Justin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; The President met with progressive lawmakers last night here at the White House.&nbsp; And afterwards, they said that they&#8217;d pressed him on sort of a laundry list of executive orders and actions that they&#8217;d like him to take: canceling student debt, raising the overtime threshold, prescription drug costs.</p>



<p>Are any of those sort of live here in the White House right now?&nbsp; Are they under consideration &#8212; especially, I think, relative to this negotiation that&#8217;s going on about elements of Build Back Better and whether, you know, push-and-pull with those executive actions might help or hurt that effort?</p>



<p>MS. BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have any specific announcements on any of those specific pieces.&nbsp; What I would say more broadly is that, from day one, the President has used the full array of tools at his disposal to achieve his objectives, and that&#8217;s included legislative action, regulatory action, and executive orders.&nbsp; And he will certainly continue to do so.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any specific coming actions to preview for you right now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then &#8212; sorry, real quick.&nbsp; Jordan ask you yesterday about the meeting in India with senior administration officials.</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering now that those have wrapped up, do you have any newfound confidence that India will decide against maintaining oil trade with Russia or a sense of, you know, what came out of the talks?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have any specific &#8212; I knew you were going to ask this, and I need to follow up with specifics because I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any additional specifics to read out beyond the fact that they were productive conversations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, Daleep Singh, the Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics had really good discussions with his counterparts, and I know that the conversation was productive.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have additional specifics to read out, but I will.</p>



<p>And, by the way, I should be clear, I meant, generically, &#8220;I know you will ask&#8221; &#8212; not you, specifically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tarini.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; So, on the SPR, some Republicans &#8212; for example, Senator Cassidy &#8212; have said that the President, with this move today, in terms of the unprecedented drawdown of the SPR, that he&#8217;s risking long-term energy security to salvage poll numbers.&nbsp; Is that something that has played into the White House&#8217;s calculus at all?&nbsp; And how would you respond &#8212; respond to that?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; What the President is doing is using every tool available to him to bring prices down for the American people at the pump.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been clear that his focus is working to relieve the pain and the burden that working families, middle-class families are feeling as a result of price hikes.&nbsp; So every policy decision that he makes is driven by a desire to do everything he can to ease that burden on working families.</p>



<p>Ed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just two quick &#8212; quick ones.&nbsp; Following up Kristen&#8217;s line of inquiry as well.&nbsp; I know Hunter Biden is not a government employee; you don&#8217;t speak for him.&nbsp; Has the President read these reports?&nbsp; Do you guys take them to him when the inquires come in?&nbsp; And what has been his reaction to them?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I don’t have anything additional to add on this from the podium, but thank you.</p>



<p>Kaitlan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on &#8212; on Title 42, you&#8217;re preparing to end this policy at some point soon here.&nbsp; There has been some concern expressed by Democrats, as well as Republicans &#8212; but Democrats, notably &#8212; about how the administration is preparing to wind that down and prepare for a surge.&nbsp; I believe some administration officials say they&#8217;re anticipating a record surge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What is the administration doing to not only alleviate those concerns from moderate Democrats &#8212; some of whom may face voter ire for that &#8212; but then, more broadly, how is, you know, the administration preparing for that surge?&nbsp; If you can sort of generally summarize.</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well &#8212; so thank you for the question.&nbsp; First, I would note &#8212; as I said yesterday and we have said many, many times &#8212; obviously this is a decision that the CDC will make.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That said, of course, we are preparing for contingencies.&nbsp; And so, what I would say is: You know, our goal is going to be to process migrants in a safe and orderly manner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also, to be clear: Most individuals who cross the border without legal authorization will be promptly paced &#8212; placed into removal proceedings.&nbsp; And if they are unable to establish a legal basis to remain in the United States, they&#8217;ll be expeditiously removed and returned to their country of origin.</p>



<p>As a reminder, economic need and flight from generalized violence is not a basis for asylum, but rather asylum is for those with a well-founded fear of persecution on a protected ground.&nbsp; And so, asylum and other legal migration pathways should remain available to those seeking protection.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working to expand legal pathways in the region so that people don&#8217;t make this treacherous journey.</p>



<p>Obviously, trying to enter the United States illegally carries consequences and no one should try to make this dangerous journey or try to unlawfully enter the United States.</p>



<p>The Department of Homeland Security, as I noted yesterday, put together a preparedness plan to address the number of people coming to our border and work with our partners in the region to provide safe options for people outside the United States.</p>



<p>We are obviously working to deliver a more efficient and fair processing system through, for example, a dedicated docket to conduct speedier and fair immigration proceedings for families who arrive between ports of entry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there is a significant amount of work we obviously inherited when we came into this administration.&nbsp; We inherited an immigration system that had been systematically dismantled by the previous administration.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a tremendous amount of work from day one to rebuild that, and we are certainly focused on continuing to assert order at the border.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; One point of clarification: When the President says he believes Putin is firing or putting senior advisors on house arrest, he&#8217;s talking about military advisors, right?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I have nothing additional I can add beyond the President&#8217;s comments on this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can&#8217;t say that he&#8217;s referencing the Russian Foreign Minister?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I think his words speak for him &#8212; speak for themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And &#8212;</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Alex.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, no &#8212; sorry, I&#8217;ve got one more.</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden has not spoken to President Putin in quite some time.&nbsp; Are there any plans being made for the two of them to speak?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Not currently.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been very clear that any reengagement of diplomacy at that level would require significant demonstration from the Russians of serious de-escalation, and we have not seen that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, you need to see de-escalation before he&#8217;ll speak to President Putin again?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been very clear about that.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you take &#8212; do you take any responsibility &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The White House has previously &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible) President Biden approval &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The White House has previously considered a gas tax holiday but, basically, kind of ruled against it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious if this is still off the table.&nbsp; And what does the White House think about individual states that are considering or have already enacted their own gas tax holidays?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; So, it is &#8212; it is not off the table, in fact.&nbsp; The President is looking at every option to provide relief to consumers around &#8212; around gas prices.&nbsp; Obviously, a lot of these conversations are happening in Congress.&nbsp; But, again, the President is not taking anything off the table at this stage.</p>



<p>Alex.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; European countries have rejected Putin&#8217;s demand to pay for gas in rubles.&nbsp; Does the U.S. stand with them in rejecting that as well?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; We do.&nbsp; And the German Chancellor, I think, has been very clear that the contracts exist as they exist and there&#8217;s going to be no change there.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate, do you &#8212; do you &#8212; I have a question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up?&nbsp; My question and a question of a colleagues who cannot be here.&nbsp; My question is, again, on allies and partners and the oil reserves: The President referred to 30 to 50 million barrels.&nbsp; Brian didn&#8217;t want to name any countries, but where did he get this number?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Canada being the main exporter of oil to the U.S., has it been &#8212; has the country been (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak to specific bilateral engagements, but I would note that obviously the President discussed this &#8212; the G7 when he was in Europe last week.&nbsp; This is a continuing ongoing conversation with our allies and partners.&nbsp; It is a key priority of maintaining stability in our energy markets.&nbsp; So, you know, those conversations are ongoing, and we obviously consult very closely with our allies and partners.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kate, sorry.&nbsp; Sorry, but from the colleague?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry &#8212; from the colleague who cannot be here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about: The Prime Minister of Pakistan accused the U.S. of working with the opposition to remove him from power.&nbsp; He just said that today.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House reaction?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; There is absolutely no truth to that allegation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kate.&nbsp; To go back to the COVID deal.&nbsp; I know you say you&#8217;re not going to negotiate from the podium, and the President has obviously warned about the severe consequences if there is no funding.&nbsp; But if there is a $10 billion deal, which some of the top negotiators say they&#8217;re getting close to, what would the administration then be able to cover?&nbsp; That long list the President went through yesterday of everything that stops over the coming months, what is saved over the coming months and what is still then at risk?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, obviously the specifics of this deal are continuing to be worked out, so I don&#8217;t have a breakdown for you of exactly where that funding would go.&nbsp; This is a live negotiation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;And again, obviously, we&#8217;re not going to negotiate from here except to say, broadly, that this is incredibly &#8212; an incredibly urgent need.&nbsp; And we really hope that the Congress is coming to a solution on this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a top priority that you say, &#8220;That is the &#8216;must thing&#8217; we have to find over the next couple of months&#8221;?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to lay that out as the negotiation is happening.&nbsp; Obviously, this is being worked through on Capitol Hill, and we&#8217;re hopeful that they&#8217;re going to come to a solution.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, Kate, I wanted to ask about the “use it or lose it” policy that the President announced today.&nbsp; It requires congressional approval.&nbsp; And I know Brian was briefly asked about this, but I just wanted to clarify: I mean, has the White House prepared legislation on this?&nbsp; Does it have support lined up in Congress?&nbsp; And what is the timeline you&#8217;re hoping to pass this measure?&nbsp; And is it really even realistic in an evenly divided Senate right now with midterms coming up in the fall?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Well, you know, the proposal would actually build on the version that&#8217;s in the House bill.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s a version of this &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; &#8212; that is already &#8212; yeah, there&#8217;s a version of this that&#8217;s already been put forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, the President looks forward to working with Congress on it.&nbsp; He believes it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a critically important piece of helping to move our energy dependence from overseas back home and to move us toward a clean energy economy.</p>



<p>So, we intend to work very closely with Congress.&nbsp; This will be a priority for the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t &#8212; in terms of a specific timeline, I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; anything further on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;re going to pass it with that House bill?&nbsp; Or you&#8217;re &#8212; you saying you&#8217;re building on that.&nbsp; What does that look like?</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; That will be an ongoing negotiation.&nbsp; We will continue to build on it.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a discussion that we&#8217;ll have with Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, this announcement just came today, so that work will be ongoing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Kate.</p>



<p>MS.&nbsp;BEDINGFIELD:&nbsp; Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>&nbsp;END&nbsp; 4:18 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Adjusting Imports of Steel into the United&#160;States</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-adjusting-imports-of-steel-into-the-united-states-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 21:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1.  On January 11, 2018, the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) transmitted to the President a report on the Secretary&#8217;s investigation into the effect of imports of steel mill articles (steel articles) on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1862).  The Secretary found and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1.  On January 11, 2018, the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) transmitted to the President a report on the Secretary&#8217;s investigation into the effect of imports of steel mill articles (steel articles) on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1862).  The Secretary found and advised the President of his opinion that steel articles are being imported into the United States in such quantities and under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security of the United States.<br><br>2.  In Proclamation 9705 of March 8, 2018 (Adjusting Imports of Steel Into the United States), the President concurred in the Secretary&#8217;s finding that steel articles, as defined in clause 1 of Proclamation 9705, as amended by clause 8 of Proclamation 9711 of March 22, 2018 (Adjusting Imports of Steel Into the United States), are being imported into the United States in such quantities and under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security of the United States, and decided to adjust the imports of those steel articles by imposing a 25 percent ad valorem tariff on such articles imported from all countries except Canada and Mexico.  The proclamation further stated that any country with which we have a security relationship is welcome to discuss with the United States alternative ways to address the threatened impairment to the national security caused by imports from that country, and noted that, should the United States and any such country arrive at a satisfactory alternative means to address the threat to the national security such that the President determines that imports from that country no longer threaten to impair the national security, the President may remove or modify the restriction on steel articles imports from that country and, if necessary, adjust the tariff as it applies to other countries, as the national security interests of the United States require.<br><br>3.  The United States has successfully concluded discussions with Japan on satisfactory alternative means to address the threatened impairment to the national security posed by imports of steel articles and derivative steel articles from Japan.  The United States and Japan have agreed to expand coordination involving trade remedies and customs matters, monitor bilateral steel and aluminum trade, cooperate on addressing non-market excess capacity and carbon intensity in these sectors, and annually review their arrangement and their ongoing cooperation.<br><br>4.  The United States will implement a number of actions, including a tariff-rate quota that restricts the quantity of steel articles imported into the United States from Japan without the application of the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9705.  Under the arrangement, steel articles that are melted and poured in Japan are eligible for in-quota treatment.  In my judgment, these measures will provide an effective, long-term alternative means to address any contribution by Japanese steel articles imports to the threatened impairment to the national security by restraining steel articles imports to the United States from Japan, limiting transshipment, discouraging excess steel capacity and production, and strengthening the United States-Japan partnership.  In light of this agreement, I have determined that imports of specified volumes of eligible steel articles from Japan will no longer threaten to impair the national security and have decided to exclude such imports from Japan up to a designated quota from the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9705.  The United States will monitor the implementation and effectiveness of the tariff-rate quota and other measures agreed upon with Japan in addressing our national security needs, and I may revisit this determination, as appropriate.<br><br>5.  The alternative means, including the tariff-rate quota, advance the recommendations contained in the Secretary&#8217;s January 2018 report.  The agreed-upon aggregate tariff-rate quota volume specified in the agreement between the United States and Japan, totaling 1.25 million metric tons, is consistent with the objective of reaching and maintaining a sufficient capacity utilization rate in the domestic steel industry.<br><br>6.  In light of my determination to adjust the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9705 as applied to eligible steel articles imported from Japan, I have considered whether it is necessary and appropriate in light of our national security interests to make any corresponding adjustments to such tariff as it applies to other countries.  I have determined that it is necessary and appropriate, at this time, to maintain the current tariff level as it applies to other countries.<br><br>7.  Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended, authorizes the President to adjust the imports of an article and its derivatives that are being imported into the United States in such quantities or under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security.<br><br>8.  Section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (19 U.S.C. 2483), authorizes the President to embody in the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTSUS) the substance of statutes affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended, section 301 of title 3, United States Code, and section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended, do hereby proclaim as follows:<br><br>(1)  To establish a tariff-rate quota on imports of steel articles from Japan as set forth in paragraph 4 of this proclamation, U.S. Note 16 of subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is amended as provided for in the Annex to this proclamation.  Imports of steel articles from Japan in excess of the tariff-rate quota quantities shall remain subject to the duties imposed by clause 2 of Proclamation 9705, as amended.  The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the United States Trade Representative, shall recommend to the President, as warranted, updates to the in-quota volumes contained in the Annex to this proclamation.  Steel articles from Japan imported under an exclusion granted pursuant to clause 3 of Proclamation 9705, as amended, shall count against the in-quota volume of the tariff-rate quota established in clause 1 of this proclamation.<br><br>(2)  Clause 2 of Proclamation 9705, as amended, is revised to read as follows:  <br>     &#8220;(2)(a) In order to establish certain modifications to the duty rate on imports of steel articles, subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is modified as provided in the Annex to this proclamation and any subsequent proclamations regarding such steel articles.<br>     (b) Except as otherwise provided in this proclamation, or in notices published pursuant to clause 3 of this proclamation, all steel articles imports covered by heading 9903.80.01, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to an additional 25 percent ad valorem rate of duty with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, as follows:  (i) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on March 23, 2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, South Korea, and the member countries of the European Union; (ii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, and South Korea; (iii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 13, 2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, South Korea, and Turkey; (iv) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 20, 2019, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, South Korea, and Turkey; (v) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 21, 2019, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea; (vi) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on January 1, 2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea, and except the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.80.65 through 9903.81.19, inclusive; and (vii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 1, 2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea, and except the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.80.65 through 9903.81.19, inclusive, and from Japan, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.81.25 through 9903.81.80, inclusive.  Further, except as otherwise provided in notices published pursuant to clause 3 of this proclamation, all steel articles imports from Turkey covered by heading 9903.80.02, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to a 50 percent ad valorem rate of duty with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 13, 2018, and prior to 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 21, 2019.  All steel articles imports covered by heading 9903.80.61, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to the additional 25 percent ad valorem rate of duty established herein with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern time on the date specified in a determination by the Secretary granting relief.  These rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported steel articles, shall apply to imports of steel articles from each country as specified in the preceding three sentences.&#8221;<br><br>(3)  The first two sentences of clause 1 of Proclamation 9980 of January 24, 2020 (Adjusting Imports of Derivative Aluminum Articles and Derivative Steel Articles Into the United States), are revised to read as follows:<br>&#8220;In order to establish increases in the duty rate on imports of certain derivative articles, subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is modified as provided in Annex I and Annex II to this proclamation.  Except as otherwise provided in this proclamation, all imports of derivative aluminum articles specified in Annex I to this proclamation shall be subject to an additional 10 percent ad valorem rate of duty, and all imports of derivative steel articles specified in Annex II to this proclamation shall be subject to an additional 25 percent ad valorem rate of duty, with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, as follows:  (i) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on February 8, 2020, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, the Commonwealth of Australia (Australia), Canada, and the United Mexican States (Mexico) and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea; (ii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on January 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, and Mexico and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Mexico, and South Korea; and (iii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, and Mexico and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Japan, Mexico, and South Korea.&#8221; <br><br>(4)  Steel eligible for treatment under clause 1 of this proclamation must be melted and poured in Japan in order to receive such treatment.  The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the United States Trade Representative, is authorized to take such actions as are necessary to ensure compliance with this requirement.  Failure to comply could result in applicable remedies such as the collection of the tariff set forth in clause 2 of Proclamation 9705, or penalties under United States law.<br><br>(5)  The modifications to the HTSUS made by clause 1 of this proclamation shall be effective with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 1, 2022, and shall continue in effect, unless such actions are expressly reduced, modified, or terminated.<br><br>(6)  Any imports of steel articles from Japan that were admitted into a U.S. foreign trade zone under &#8220;privileged foreign status&#8221; as defined in 19 CFR 146.41, prior to 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 1, 2022, shall be subject upon entry for consumption made on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 1, 2022, to the provisions of the tariff‑rate quota in effect at the time of the entry for consumption.<br><br>(7)  Any provision of previous proclamations and Executive Orders that is inconsistent with the actions taken in this proclamation is superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Appointments to Board of Advisors on Historically Black Colleges and&#160;Universities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/31/president-biden-announces-appointments-to-board-of-advisors-on-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint qualified and diverse leaders to the President’s Board of Advisors on Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs). The President’s Board will advance the goal of the HBCU Initiative, established by the Carter Administration, to increase the capacity of HBCUs to provide the highest-quality education to its&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint qualified and diverse leaders to the President’s Board of Advisors on Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs). The President’s Board will advance the goal of the <a href="https://thehilltoponline.com/2021/09/03/exclusive-biden-harris-administration-announces-white-house-initiative-targeting-hbcus/">HBCU Initiative</a>, established by the Carter Administration, to increase the capacity of HBCUs to provide the highest-quality education to its students and continue serving as engines of opportunity.<br> </p>



<p>In 2021, President Biden appointed Drs. Tony Allen and Glenda Glover to serve as Chair and Vice Chair of the President’s Board of Advisors on HBCUs, respectively. In February, he appointed Dr. Dietra Trent as executive director of the White House HBCU Initiative.</p>



<p><br>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to supporting the vital mission of HBCUs. Through the American Rescue Plan, grant funding, and by forgiving capital improvement debt of many these institutions, the Biden-Harris Administration has already committed more than <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-%E2%81%A0harris-administrations-historic-investments-and-support-for-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/">$5.8 billion in support</a>. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/09/03/executive-order-on-white-house-initiative-on-advancing-educational-equity-excellence-and-economic-opportunity-through-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reestablishing the White House HBCU Initiative</a>&nbsp;– and appointing qualified and diverse individuals to the Board – will allow the administration to build on that financial commitment with continued institutional support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve as members on the board:</p>



<ul><li>Makola M. Abdullah</li><li>Javaune Adams-Gaston</li><li>Paige Blake</li><li>Thasunda Brown Duckett</li><li>Willie A. Deese</li><li>Patrick Cokley</li><li>Monica Goldson</li><li>Brett J. Hart</li><li>Taraji P. Henson</li><li>Beverly W. Hogan</li><li>Lisa P. Jackson</li><li>Shevrin D. Jones</li><li>Walter M. Kimbrough</li><li>William F. L. Moses</li><li>Christopher E. Paul</li><li>Quinton T. Ross Jr.</li><li>Ruth J. Simmons</li><li>Janeen Uzzell</li></ul>



<p><strong>Makola M. Abdullah</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Makola M. Abdullah is the 14<sup>th</sup> President of Virginia State University (VSU). He is a member of numerous boards and committees including: Council of 1890s Presidents for Association of Public Land-Grant Universities (APLU); Board of Trustees for the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools Commission on College, and the Council of Presidents for Virginia Institutions of Higher Education, and Board member of Big Brothers Big Sisters of America. Prior to his appointment as President of Virginia State University, Dr. Abdullah served as provost and senior vice president at Bethune-Cookman University in Daytona Beach, provost and vice president for academic affairs at Florida Memorial University in Miami Gardens, and dean and director of 1890 land grant programs at Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University in Tallahassee. Dr. Abdullah is a Chicago native. He earned his undergraduate degree from Howard University in civil engineering and his doctorate and master’s degrees in civil engineering from Northwestern University. He is the youngest African American to receive a Ph.D. in engineering. He is a member of Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity. He and his wife, Ahkinyala Cobb-Abdullah, Ph.D., are the proud parents of a son, Mikaili, and a daughter, Sefiyetu, who both are college graduates.</p>



<p><strong>Javaune Adams-Gaston &nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Javaune Adams-Gaston, Ph.D., serves as the seventh President of Norfolk State University, the Commonwealth of Virginia’s largest Historically Black College and University in Norfolk, Virginia. Dr. Adams-Gaston is committed to the mission of Norfolk State University to transform the lives of students through access to higher education and excellence in scholarship, career preparation, and service. Dr. Adams-Gaston is committed to student success and the development of the student holistically through academic excellence, mentorship, mental and physical wellness, internships, and civic engagement. Since her arrival on campus in June 2019, Dr. Adams-Gaston has advocated for increased financial support for the benefit of students, faculty and staff and the stability of the institution. Dr. Adams-Gaston was pivotal in securing a $40 million gift from philanthropist MacKenzie Scott—the largest single gift in NSU’s history. She has led the university in successful efforts to secure grants and partnerships from corporations such as Microsoft, Netflix, Apple, IBM, Dominion Energy, and others. Under her tenure, NSU has been designated a Top 20 HBCU for consecutive years in U.S News and World Report Rankings. Prior to becoming President at Norfolk State University, Dr. Adams-Gaston served as Senior Vice President for Student Life at The Ohio State University. During her career at the University of Maryland, Dr. Adams-Gaston held numerous positions including psychologist, associate dean in academic affairs, assistant athletic director, equity administrator, and graduate faculty member. Dr. Adams-Gaston had a practice for 25 years as a licensed psychologist and as an educator, she is frequently asked to provide speeches, lectures, and to serve on panels regarding student success and leadership.</p>



<p><strong>Paige Blake</strong></p>



<p>Paige Blake is a 20-year-old native of Prince George’s County, Maryland. She is a junior at Bowie State University where she majors in Biology and is on the pre-med track. Paige plans to attend medical school to study Neurology to help others with Spina Bifida and other neurological conditions. Paige was diagnosed at age 4 with a rare form of Sacral Agenesis (a form of Spina Bifida). Over time she’s learned the importance of advocacy after having her own share of hardships in her life with her disability. Paige has used her personal experiences to advocate and help others in various ways, such as organizing donation drives with her Girl Scout troop where they sent medical supplies to countries overseas and working with The Congressional Black Caucus and President Obama’s White House Initiative on African American Excellence to advocate for disabled students. Currently, Paige has been named the 2021-2022 White House Initiative HBCU Competitiveness Scholar for Bowie State University. She also is working with The University System of Maryland Student Council as the Director of Student Affairs, where she advocates for students to ensure that present and future college students in the state of Maryland will have positive and equal opportunities.</p>



<p><strong>Thasunda Brown Duckett</strong></p>



<p>Thasunda Brown Duckett is President and Chief Executive Officer of TIAA, a Fortune 100 provider of secure retirements and outcome-focused investment solutions to millions of people working in higher education, healthcare and other mission-driven organizations. As TIAA’s CEO, Duckett leads a company whose mission is defined by financial inclusion and opportunity – goals and values she has upheld throughout her career. Duckett joined TIAA after serving as Chief Executive Officer of Chase Consumer Banking, where she oversaw a banking network with more than $600 billion in deposits and 50,000 employees. Duckett serves on the boards of NIKE, Inc., Brex Inc., Robert F. Kennedy Human Rights, Sesame Workshop, National Medal of Honor Museum, Economic Club of New York, University of Houston Board of Visitors and Dean’s Advisory Board for the Baylor University’s Hankamer School of Business. She’s a member of the Executive Leadership Council, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority Inc. and Jack and Jill of America Inc. She holds a Bachelor’s degree in Finance and Marketing from the University of Houston and an MBA from Baylor University.</p>



<p><strong>Willie A. Deese</strong></p>



<p>Willie A. Deese is a retired pharmaceutical executive and corporate board member whose career spans 5 decades.&nbsp; He most recently served as Executive Vice President of Manufacturing at Merck and Co. Inc.&nbsp; He is a graduate of North Carolina A&amp;T State University and credits his alma mater with providing him the foundational platform on which he was able to build a successful career.&nbsp; He is recognized for his expertise in manufacturing and supply chain management as well as his proactive contributions defining healthy, engaged corporate cultures, implementing environmental and sustainability standards, DEI practices and policies, and leadership development.&nbsp; He fervently believes that when we level the playing field by providing equitable resources and opportunities for all, it leads to positive outcomes that have an exponential impact on society.&nbsp; Recently, North Carolina A&amp;T named its College of Business and Economics in his honor.</p>



<p><strong>Patrick Cokley</strong></p>



<p>Patrick Cokley works to bring issues of inclusion to the forefront of all communities. In his role as Chief of Organizing Advocacy and Learning at Civic Influencers, Patrick believes in the importance of giving all young people the tools they need to be engaged citizens with the ability to bring positive change to their communities. Patrick’s dedication to service stems from the values he learned from his family as well as time at an HBCU. As a graduate of Howard University, Patrick believes that it is imperative that the disability and traditional diversity communities learn to work together as they both share the core values of inclusion. Only together can our communities realize the success of an America that is inclusive of all of its citizens. Originally from South Carolina, Patrick now makes his home in New Jersey. In addition to being a person who is low vision, Patrick is also the parent of two children with disabilities.</p>



<p><strong>Monica Goldson</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Monica Goldson, Chief Executive Officer for Prince George’s County Public Schools (PGCPS), is the dedicated and dynamic leader of the 20th largest school district in the nation. A three-time HBCU graduate, she is committed to creating transformative experiences that propel students to their highest levels of excellence. Dr. Goldson focuses on doing what is best for students and educators, especially amid the challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic. Her longtime advocacy for public education was key in mobilizing the PGCPS community to provide laptops, internet service and technology assistance to families in need while building virtual learning from the ground up. Beyond the schoolhouse, she is a member of Chiefs for Change, a graduate of Leadership Greater Washington, and a board member of Nonprofit Prince George’s and the Prince George’s Chamber of Commerce. Dr. Goldson holds a bachelor’s degree in Mathematics from Florida A&amp;M University, a master’s degree in Elementary and Secondary School Administration from Bowie State University, and a doctorate in Educational Administration and Policy from Howard University. She has two adult sons, both graduates of Prince George’s County Public Schools.</p>



<p><strong>Brett Hart</strong></p>



<p>Brett Hart is President of United Airlines and is responsible for leading the company’s external-facing teams as well as operational workgroups including Technical Operations, Airport Operations, Corporate Safety, United Ground Express and Network Operations. He also oversees business-critical functions such as the customer experience, government affairs, corporate real estate, human resources, and labor relations teams.&nbsp; Mr. Hart previously served as executive vice president and chief administrative officer for United.&nbsp; A longtime resident of Chicago, Mr. Hart has been extensively involved in social, cultural, and economic causes impacting his home community.&nbsp; Brett serves on the boards of World Business Chicago, the Herbie Hancock Institute of Jazz, Northwestern Medical Group, and the Obama Foundation Inclusion Council. Brett received his Bachelor of Arts in philosophy and English from the University of Michigan and a Juris Doctor from the University of Chicago Law School. He is married and has three sons.</p>



<p><strong>Taraji P. Henson</strong></p>



<p>Academy Award-nominated and SAG and Golden Globe-winning actor, filmmaker, and activist, Taraji P. Henson quickly rose to fame after her breakout performance in the critically acclaimed film <em>Hustle &amp; Flow.</em>&nbsp; In 2020, Henson wrapped her iconic run as “Cookie Lyon” in Fox’s hit musical drama <em>Empire</em>, which has earned her three Emmy nominations, a Golden Globe Award, a Critics Choice Award, and three BET Awards. Prior credits include <em>Hidden Figures</em>, which won her a SAG for Best Ensemble, and <em>The Curious Case of Benjamin Button </em>with Brad Pitt, for which she earned an Academy Award nomination.&nbsp; In Summer 2022, she has <em>Minions: The Rise of Gru</em> and is currently in production on Blitz Bazawule’s <em>The Color Purple</em>, where she will star as Shug Avery.&nbsp;Henson launched TPH Entertainment with upcoming projects including <em>Two-Faced</em> with Bron Entertainment, which will mark Henson’s feature film directorial debut, Alessandro Camon’s <em>Time Alone</em>, which Henson will also star in, and <em>Sorcerority</em>, which she will co-produce with Game Changer Films and Gabrielle Union’s I’ll Have Another Productions. In October 2016, Henson released her New York Times bestselling novel “Around The Way Girl.” Henson launched the Boris Lawrence Henson Foundation in 2018 in honor of her late father, which provides scholarships to African-American students majoring in mental health, offers mental health services to youth in urban schools, and works to lower the recidivism rates of African-American men and women. Henson recently co-hosted the Facebook Watch series on mental health called <em>Peace of Mind with Taraji</em>, for which she received a Daytime Emmy Award nomination. In 2019, Henson received her star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame.</p>



<p><strong>Beverly W. Hogan</strong></p>



<p>Beverly Wade Hogan has a long and distinguished career as a public administrator, educator, community leader and humanitarian. As the first woman to lead the historic institution, Hogan served as President at Tougaloo College for 17 years. She retired with the distinction of President Emerita. She had also served the College as the founding director of the George A. and Ruth B. Owens Health, Wellness and Human Resources Center, Vice President for Institutional Advancement and Interim President. During her presidential tenure, she and her team enhanced the college’s curricula with new undergraduate and graduate degree programs and&nbsp; expanded partnerships with major research institutions for three plus two degree programs in law, engineering, and public health; established the Undergraduate Research Center, the Center for International Studies and Global Change, the Institute for the Study of Modern Day Slavery, the Early College High School; and made significant improvements in campus physical and technological infrastructure. Prior to becoming a college president, Hogan served as Commissioner of the Workers’ Compensation Commission; Executive Director of the Governor’s Office of Federal State Programs; Executive Director of the Mental Health Association. She is a national voice for higher education, having served on the board of directors for the Council of Independent Colleges, National Association for Independent Colleges and Universities, NAFEO and UNCF. She was appointed by former President Barack Obama to the Board of Advisors for the White House Initiative on HBCUs.</p>



<p><strong>Lisa P. Jackson</strong></p>



<p>Lisa P. Jackson is Apple’s vice president of Environment, Policy and Social Initiatives, where she leads the company’s environmental initiatives, racial equity and justice initiative, global education policy programs, product accessibility efforts, corporate giving and philanthropic partnerships, and worldwide government affairs. Her work includes driving Apple’s support for HBCUs through coding initiatives, innovation partnerships and the launch of the Propel Center. Under President Barack Obama, she served as Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, becoming the first Black person to hold the position. She also served as Chief of Staff to New Jersey Governor Jon S. Corzine and as Commissioner of New Jersey’s Department of Environmental Protection, following nearly 20 years with the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. Lisa has been recognized as a leader in business and sustainability by numerous publications, including Ebony’s Power 100, Black Enterprise’s Women of Power, Essence Magazine’s 40 Women Who Have Influenced the World lists, and Women of Color magazine. She is the recipient of Princeton’s James Madison Medal and Tulane University’s Distinguished Alumni Award, among others. Lisa holds a master’s degree in Chemical Engineering from Princeton University and a bachelor’s degree in Chemical Engineering from Tulane University. She also holds an honorary degree from Spelman College and maintains close ties to Xavier University in New Orleans. She serves on the boards of Tulane University, the American Film Institute, and Conservation International and is an honorary member of Delta Sigma Theta sorority. Lisa and her husband Kenneth reside in San Francisco.</p>



<p><strong>Shevrin Jones</strong></p>



<p>Florida State Senator Shevrin “Shev” Jones is an educator, public servant, and consensus builder who has dedicated his life to serving others and building pathways to opportunity. Thanks to the encouragement of his close-knit family and supportive teachers, Jones recognized from a young age the power of education as the great equalizer, a foundation that drove Shevrin into teaching to help students reach their full potential. A proud graduate of Florida A&amp;M University, Jones taught high school chemistry in Broward Public Schools before founding L.E.A.D. Nation, a South Florida nonprofit organization committed to youth leadership development and social entrepreneurship training. Jones’ firsthand look at the inequities in education and society at large propelled him to enter public service, and since 2013, he has served in the Florida legislature, championing meaningful bipartisan legislation including two consecutive bills to secure dignity for incarcerated women; statewide expansion of a clean syringe exchange program; safety and oversight for athletic coaches for youth athletic teams; increased investment in underserved communities; and greater transparency and accountability for law enforcement. The first LGBTQ State Senator elected in Florida history, Jones served on President Barack Obama’s College Promise Task Force and is an active member of the Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity Inc., Young Elected Officials Network, and Millennial Action Project’s Florida Future Caucus. Today, Jones is completing his Ph.D. in Educational Leadership at Florida Atlantic University.</p>



<p><strong>Walter M. Kimbrough</strong></p>



<p>A native of Atlanta, Dr. Walter M. Kimbrough was his high school salutatorian and student bodypresident, and went on to earn degrees from the University of Georgia, Miami University in Ohio, and a doctorate in higher education from Georgia State University. He has enjoyed a fulfilling career in student affairs, serving at Emory University, Georgia State University, Old Dominion University, and Albany State University. In October of 2004, at the age of 37, he was named the 12th President of Philander Smith College. In 2012, he became the 7th President of Dillard University in New Orleans, Louisiana. Kimbrough has been recognized for his research and writings on HBCUs and African American men in college. Recently he has emerged as one of the leaders discussing free speech on college campuses. Kimbrough also has been noted for his active use of social media. He was cited by Education Dive as one of 10 college presidents on Twitter who are doing it right and was profiled in the text, “Digital Leadership In Higher Education.” In 2020 he was named by College Cliffs as one of 50 Top U.S. College and University Presidents.</p>



<p><strong>William F. L. Moses</strong></p>



<p>William F. L. Moses serves as Managing Director for the Kresge Foundation’s Education Program, which supports postsecondary access and success for low-income, first-generation and underrepresented students in the United States and South Africa. The key architect of Kresge’s education programming, Bill leads the team’s continuum of grant activities and for more than 20 years has awarded grants to HBCUs and MSIs, including UNCF, Thurgood Marshall College Fund, Spelman College, Morehouse College, Paul Quinn College, Delaware State University, Jackson State University, and Xavier University, among others. Prior to joining Kresge, Bill served as Executive Director of the Thomas J. Watson Foundation, a Senior Analyst at the Investor Responsibility Research Center, a research officer at TechnoServe, and in various positions at the Alaska State Legislature, and the federal government, including the U.S. Embassy in Cape Town, South Africa. A graduate of Claremont McKenna College, Bill holds a master’s degree in international relations from Yale University, and is the author of <em>A Guide to American State and Local Laws on South Africa</em> and co-author of <em>Corporate Responsibility in a Changing South Africa</em>. &nbsp;Bill currently serves on the advisory committees or boards of the Africa Grantmakers’ Affinity Group, APIA Scholars, California Community Colleges Chancellor’s External Leadership Council, College Promise, Detroit College Access Network, and the Seal of Excelencia.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Christopher Paul</strong></p>



<p>Christopher “Chris” Paul is a twelve-time NBA All-Star with the Phoenix Suns, two-time Olympic Gold medalist and is listed as one of the NBA’s 75 greatest players in NBA history. Off the court, he’s a father, husband, entrepreneur, activist, and philanthropist. His leadership and impact are well noted in the sports industry as he recently ended an eight-year tenure as the President of the National Basketball Players Association. His advocacy for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) is extremely important and through his Chris Paul Family Foundation, he has actively expanded a Business of Entertainment Media and Sports special topics course at NC A&amp; T, Southern University, Winston Salem State and Clark Atlanta University.&nbsp; His production company, Ohh Dip!!! creates content across multiple platforms, which includes the Why Not Us franchise of shows with NC Central Men’s Basketball and FAMU Football. Paul co-launched the Social Change Fund United dedicated to investing in and supporting organizations focused on empowering communities of color and advocating for the human rights of all black lives. His philanthropic efforts have earned him the 2016 ESPYs “Humanitarian of the Year” award, 2016 Mannie Jackson Human Spirit Award, the NBA Community Assist Award five times, and most recently the inaugural Kobe and Gigi Bryant Advocacy Award for his significant contributions to the advancement of girls’ and women&#8217;s basketball and advocacy for the WNBA.</p>



<p><strong>Quinton T. Ross Jr.</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Quinton T. Ross, Jr.,&nbsp;is entering his fifth year as President of Alabama State University, having assumed the leadership role at his alma mater on October 3, 2017. His tenure has been marked by transformative and innovative leadership that has included a 130 percent increase in fundraising, expansion of national and global partnerships, advancement of strategic initiatives under the brand of “CommUniversity,” and an increased emphasis on student success. President Ross is a three-time graduate of Alabama State University, where he earned a Bachelor of Science degree in Political Science, a Master of Education degree in Secondary Education English, and a Doctorate of Education in Educational Leadership, Policy, and Law. Dr.&nbsp;Ross&nbsp;is a distinguished career educator with more than 28 years of experience in Higher and K-12 public education. Prior to becoming the University’s 15th&nbsp;President, Dr. Ross served with distinction as a senator in the Alabama Legislature for four terms.</p>



<p><strong>Ruth J. Simmons</strong></p>



<p>Ruth J. Simmons is President of Prairie View A&amp;M University. Prior to joining Prairie View, she served as President of Smith College from 1995 to 2001 and President of Brown University from 2001 to 2012. She holds a Bachelor’s degree from Dillard University and a Ph.D. in Romance Languages and Literatures from Harvard University. Simmons serves on the Council of the Smithsonian National Museum of History and Culture and the Board of the Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas, Houston Branch.</p>



<p><strong>Janeen Uzzell</strong></p>



<p>Janeen Uzzell is the Chief Executive Officer at the National Society of Black Engineers (NSBE), the largest Black STEM community impacting society and industry. In her former role as the Chief Operating Officer for the Wikimedia Foundation, which operates Wikipedia, Janeen drove process improvement and helped launch the Wikimedia Knowledge Equity Fund to address racial inequities in free knowledge. For nearly two decades, she held various roles at General Electric, working in healthcare technologies in some of the world’s most challenging environments. As the head of Women in Technology, she accelerated the number of women in technical roles. Her previous roles at GE included Global Director of External Affairs and Technology Programs, Director of Healthcare Programs at GE Africa (where Janeen lived for several years as an Ex-Pat in Accra, Ghana), Director of Global Healthcare Programs, Director of Healthcare Disparity Programs, and Director of Service Operations. She is a recipient of numerous awards, including the United Nations Global Leadership Award and one of ADWEEK’s Top Black Women Trailblazers in Tech. Janeen received her Bachelor of Science in mechanical engineering from North Carolina Agricultural and Technical State University, and an MBA in International Business from Fairleigh Dickinson University. Janeen fuses her passion for social justice and her leadership to shine light on inequality in tech spaces and forge opportunities for others. In her spare time, she enjoys playing tennis and spending time with her family and friends in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>###</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Second Chance Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-second-chance-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 19:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[April marks Second Chance Month, when we reaffirm the importance of helping people who were formerly incarcerated reenter society.&#160; America is a Nation of second chances, and it is critical that our criminal and juvenile justice systems provide meaningful opportunities for rehabilitation and redemption. &#160;It is also vital that we address both the root causes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>April marks Second Chance Month, when we reaffirm the importance of helping people who were formerly incarcerated reenter society.&nbsp; America is a Nation of second chances, and it is critical that our criminal and juvenile justice systems provide meaningful opportunities for rehabilitation and redemption. &nbsp;It is also vital that we address both the root causes of crime and the underlying needs of returning citizens using resources devoted to prevention, diversion, reentry, trauma-informed care, culturally-specific services, and social support. &nbsp;By supporting people who are committed to rectifying their mistakes, redefining themselves, and making meaningful contributions to society, we help reduce recidivism and build safer communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every year, over 640,000 people are released from State and Federal prisons. &nbsp;More than 70 million Americans have a criminal record that creates significant barriers to employment, economic stability, and successful reentry into society. &nbsp;Thousands of legal and regulatory restrictions prevent these individuals from accessing employment, housing, voting, education, business licensing, and other basic opportunities. &nbsp;Because of these barriers, nearly 75 percent of people who were formerly incarcerated are still unemployed a year after being released.</p>



<p>     We must rethink the existing criminal justice system and whom we send to prison and for how long; how unaddressed trauma and abuse create pipelines to incarceration; how people are treated while incarcerated; how prepared they are to reenter society once they have served their time; and how the racial inequities that lead to disproportionate numbers of incarcerated people of color and other underserved groups.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration recognizes that making the criminal and juvenile justice systems more equitable, just, and effective requires a holistic approach.&nbsp; It requires eliminating exceedingly long sentences and mandatory minimums that keep people incarcerated longer than they should be. &nbsp;It requires quality job training and educational opportunities during incarceration. &nbsp;It requires providing formerly incarcerated individuals with opportunities to enter the workforce, reunite with their families, find stable and safe homes, and access health care.&nbsp; It requires expunging and sealing certain criminal records so that people&#8217;s futures are not defined by their past.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is why my Administration is working across Federal agencies to eliminate barriers to reentry. &nbsp;We are expanding avenues for employment, housing, education, health services, civic engagement, and other benefits. &nbsp;Last fall, the Department of Justice convened the Reentry Coordination Council in collaboration with the Departments of Housing and Urban Development, Agriculture, Education, Health and Human Services, Veterans Affairs, and Labor. &nbsp;I am confident that our collective efforts will help make our communities safer and stronger by reducing crime, recidivism, mass incarceration, and elements of the justice system that foster harmful disparate impacts on people of color and other historically disadvantaged communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But despite our progress, much more work remains.&nbsp; Our&nbsp;Federal, State, local, territorial, and Tribal governments, private employers, philanthropies, and community leaders play a significant role in preparing individuals returning to our communities for success.&nbsp; Together, let us recommit to empower Americans who have paid their debt to society and to provide them with a second chance to participate, contribute, and succeed.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United&nbsp;States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States, do hereby proclaim April&nbsp;2022 as Second Chance Month.&nbsp; I call upon all government officials, educators, volunteers, and all the people of the United States to observe the month with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Sexual Assault Awareness And Prevention Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-national-sexual-assault-awareness-and-prevention-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 19:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; I was raised to believe that one of the greatest sins is the abuse of power –- whether it is economic, psychological, or physical. &#160;The cruel fact is that people of every age, ability, race, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, national origin, socioeconomic background, and religion suffer the pain and trauma of the abuse&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was raised to believe that one of the greatest sins is the abuse of power –- whether it is economic, psychological, or physical. &nbsp;The cruel fact is that people of every age, ability, race, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, national origin, socioeconomic background, and religion suffer the pain and trauma of the abuse of power that is sexual assault. &nbsp;Sexual violence can occur anywhere &#8212; and millions of assaults occur each year at the workplace, in the home, at school, and online. &nbsp;These assaults are an intolerable affront to our shared humanity.&nbsp; During National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month, we renew our commitment to ensuring that every person can live a life free from sexual violence.&nbsp; We continue in our commitment to stand with survivors, hold perpetrators accountable, and dismantle a culture that is complicit in allowing sexual violence to continue.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sexual assault is also a public health crisis.&nbsp; According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, nearly 1 in 5 women in America experiences a rape or attempted rape, and nearly 44 percent of women and about 25 percent of all men experience some form of sexual violence in their lifetime.&nbsp; Tragically, many of those assaulted are young, and research shows that these assaults can have lifelong effects on health and are linked to chronic illnesses. &nbsp;Too often, this trauma is compounded by lost productivity, the challenge of seeking accountability, and the ensuing costs of medical and mental health care.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is committed to supporting survivors and alleviating the public health crisis of sexual assault.&nbsp; That is&nbsp;why we included $450 million in the American Rescue Plan to&nbsp;provide funding for domestic violence and sexual assault services, including rape crisis centers.&nbsp; We also included a historic commitment to funding culturally-specific community-based organizations to address the needs of survivors who face systemic barriers to accessing support and resources, including survivors of color, survivors with disabilities, and LGBTQI+ survivors.&nbsp; My Administration continues to fund innovative programs to support sexual assault survivors in rural and remote communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am committed to addressing sexual violence wherever it occurs.&nbsp; Last year, I issued an Executive Order directing the Department of Education to review Title IX regulations and other agency actions to ensure that all students have an educational environment that is free from discrimination on the basis of sex.&nbsp; Because 1 in 3 women under the age of 35 has experienced sexual harassment online, I have made addressing online forms of sexual violence, harassment, and abuse a priority, and my Administration recently launched a new Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sexual violence is also a matter of national security and military readiness.&nbsp; To advance the goal of eliminating sexual assault in our Armed Forces, I signed the 2022 National Defense Authorization Act, which includes the historic shift of legal decisions in cases of sexual assault from commanders to independent, specialized military prosecutors. &nbsp;To implement the I Am Vanessa Guillén Act, I also issued an Executive Order to add sexual harassment as a specific offense under the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was proud to support and sign into law the Ending Forced Arbitration of Sexual Assault and Sexual Harassment Act of 2021.&nbsp; This law advances efforts to prevent and address sexual harassment and sexual assault and promotes access to justice by guaranteeing that people who have experienced sexual assault and sexual harassment in the workplace are not forced into binding arbitration and are instead allowed to choose whether to go to court.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ending violence against women and eliminating sexual assault has been a priority for me throughout my life.&nbsp; It is why I wrote and championed the original Violence Against Women Act (VAWA), a law that has transformed how we respond to sexual assault and which I count as one of my proudest legislative accomplishments.&nbsp; I am proud to have recently signed into law the reauthorization of VAWA, which expands prevention efforts and protections for survivors of sexual assault and other forms of gender-based violence. &nbsp;The law will provide increased resources and training so that our law enforcement and our judicial systems are better able to appropriately handle these cases.&nbsp; It&nbsp;includes a new focus on addressing technology-facilitated abuse and establishes a Federal civil cause of action for victims of non-consensual distribution of intimate images.&nbsp; The&nbsp;Act will strengthen rape prevention and education efforts, support rape crisis centers, improve the training of sexual assault forensic examiners, reduce the backlog of untested DNA kits, and broaden access to legal services for all survivors.&nbsp; It will also expand recognition of the special criminal jurisdiction of Tribal courts to cover non-Native perpetrators of sexual assault, sex trafficking, child abuse, and stalking.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This month, we honor the bravery and leadership of survivors by rededicating ourselves to eliminating sexual violence.&nbsp; It will require care and commitment from each of us to realize an America where everyone is free from the threat and impact of sexual violence.</p>



<p>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month.  I urge all Americans to support sexual assault survivors including when survivors reach out and disclose abuse.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Child Abuse Prevention Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-national-child-abuse-prevention-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every child deserves to live in a safe and loving household; yet, for hundreds of thousands of children across our Nation, abuse and neglect are a tragic reality.&#160; During National Child Abuse Prevention Month, our country stands as one to condemn and combat child abuse in all of its forms &#8212; including physical, emotional, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every child deserves to live in a safe and loving household; yet, for hundreds of thousands of children across our Nation, abuse and neglect are a tragic reality.&nbsp; During National Child Abuse Prevention Month, our country stands as one to condemn and combat child abuse in all of its forms &#8212; including physical, emotional, and sexual abuse, as well as online sexual exploitation; we raise awareness about the risk factors that can lead to child abuse and neglect; and we highlight the importance of supporting families to prevent child maltreatment.&nbsp; As a Nation, we must work together to prevent and address child abuse and ensure that every child can grow up in a safe environment and live a happy, prosperous life.</p>



<p><strong>   </strong>  Child abuse crosses all socioeconomic and educational levels, religions, and ethnic and cultural backgrounds.  We know that abuse and neglect negatively impact every aspect and stage of a child&#8217;s life.  Child abuse impacts the ability of students to succeed in school and often hinders their ability to forge healthy relationships with their loved ones and peers.  It is associated with involvement in the juvenile justice system, especially for girls who have experienced sexual abuse.  One of the most important tools to break the cycle and eliminate the tragedy of child abuse and neglect is prevention.  This requires that we support and uplift our communities, families, and individuals so that our children can be raised in safe, loving, and healthy environments.  For those children and adolescents who do experience abuse, it is important to ensure access to trauma-informed services and healing.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In order to help prevent child abuse and neglect, my Administration is committed to providing high-quality and equitable support to all families that need it.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan provided cash assistance to millions of working families and expanded the Child Tax Credit &#8212; which lifted millions of children and families out of poverty.&nbsp; It supplied critical funding to support State and community child abuse prevention and response efforts and authorized an additional $250 million for community-based child abuse prevention programs. &nbsp;This additional funding has allowed communities to address the complex structural issues that contribute to families becoming involved in the child welfare system.&nbsp; At a&nbsp;time when families are experiencing elevated hardships, especially vulnerable families that have been disproportionately affected by COVID-19, this extra support is more important than ever. &nbsp;Also, I was proud to sign into law a bill to help sustain the Crime Victims Fund, which provides assistance for child advocacy centers and other programs to address child abuse.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was raised to believe that one of the greatest sins is the abuse of power, and there is no greater abuse of power than the abuse of a child. &nbsp;National Child Abuse Prevention Month is an opportunity to take bold action to better support parents and caregivers with access to resources to cope during challenging times.&nbsp; It is also a time to identify and take the necessary steps to address inequities experienced by those who have been historically underserved and adversely affected by continuous poverty and inequality.&nbsp; Reducing child poverty is critical to&nbsp;reducing the disproportional representation of low-income children and families &#8212; especially communities of color &#8212; in&nbsp;the child welfare system and foster care.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our Nation is also witnessing a cynical and dangerous campaign waged by some elected leaders who are attempting to weaponize the child welfare system against families just because they love and affirm their transgender children. &nbsp;These leaders have sought to direct child abuse investigations into families simply because they have provided access to affirming care for their children. &nbsp;These discriminatory actions threaten to hurt our Nation&#8217;s children and must stop.&nbsp; Affirming a transgender child&#8217;s identity is one of the best things that a parent, teacher, or doctor can do to keep children from harm. &nbsp;My Administration will continue to take actions to keep transgender children and their families safe. &nbsp;That is why the Department of Health and Human Services recently released new guidance to State child welfare agencies on how they can support and affirm LGBTQI+ children who are in foster care.</p>



<p>     During National Child Abuse Prevention Month and throughout the year, I call upon everyone to stand together against child abuse and neglect and show our appreciation of the hardworking child-welfare workforce and allies who are steadfast in their commitment to strengthening families, protecting children, and combating systemic inequities.  For more information on how professionals and communities are supporting families and to learn strategies to advance equity in child abuse prevention programs, please view the 2021/2022 Prevention Resource Guide, available at childwelfare.gov.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Child Abuse Prevention Month.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this month by joining together as a Nation to promote the safety and well-being of all children and families and to recognize the child-welfare workforce and allies who work tirelessly to protect our children. &nbsp;And we honor the strength and resilience of adult survivors of child abuse.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Cancer Control Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/national-cancer-control-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[    Since the Congress passed the landmark National Cancer Act in 1971, our Nation has made tremendous strides in preventing, detecting, and treating cancer.  But nearly all families &#8211;including my own and that of the Vice President&#8217;s &#8212; still know the pain a cancer diagnosis brings.  Despite our Nation&#8217;s progress over the last 50 years, cancer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>    Since the Congress passed the landmark National Cancer Act in 1971, our Nation has made tremendous strides in preventing, detecting, and treating cancer.  But nearly all families &#8211;including my own and that of the Vice President&#8217;s &#8212; still know the pain a cancer diagnosis brings.  Despite our Nation&#8217;s progress over the last 50 years, cancer in its many forms is still the second leading cause of death in the United States, with more than 600,000 deaths and nearly 1.9 million new cancer diagnoses each year.  A cancer diagnosis remains a crushing blow to those diagnosed, as well as their loved ones.  In the name of all those we have lost and for all those still fighting, I believe we can end cancer as we know it.  <br><br>     During National Cancer Control Month, we renew our commitments to improve cancer prevention, promote early detection, enhance treatment, and support the needs of cancer patients, survivors, and caregivers.  We recognize that while the fight against cancer is often personal, the desire to make cancer more preventable, detectable, and treatable is one that has the potential to unite us as a Nation, inspiring us to stand together and work together.  <br><br>     In 2016, as Vice President, I led the Cancer Moonshot to accelerate our progress against cancer and take advantage of 21st century science and technology &#8212; an effort that has catalyzed change across the cancer community.  As President, I have reignited the Cancer Moonshot and set ambitious new goals to reduce the death rate from cancer by 50 percent over the next 25 years and to improve the experience of people and their families living with and surviving cancer.  We are creating the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA-H), with the singular purpose of expediting breakthroughs in the prevention, detection, and treatment of cancer and other deadly diseases.  <br><br>     As part of a recommitment to the Cancer Moonshot, the First Lady and I announced a call to action on cancer screening and early detection.  Our goal is to drive progress on potentially life-saving screenings that so many Americans have missed as a result of the pandemic and to help ensure that everyone in the United States benefits equitably from the technology we have to detect, diagnose, and treat cancer.  We urge every American to get back on track with their recommended screenings, and we implore the public and private sectors to increase access to early detection for individuals and communities.  To learn more about which cancer screenings are appropriate for you, talk to your healthcare provider, visit <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/cancer/dcpc/prevention/screening.htm">cdc.gov/cancerscreening</a> or <a href="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/screening/screening-tests">cancer.gov/screeningtests</a>, or call 1-800-4-CANCER. <br><br>     We also encourage Americans to take the proven steps to lower their risk for many forms of cancer.  Experts agree that reducing tobacco use, eating healthily, engaging in regular physical activity and exercise, limiting alcohol consumption, and reducing exposure to the sun when it is at its peak can help reduce the risk of a cancer diagnosis.  Given that cigarette smoking is responsible for 30 percent of all cancer deaths, helping people quit smoking and limiting exposure to secondhand smoke can save lives.  Resources are available at <a href="http://www.smokefree.gov/">SmokeFree.gov</a>, by calling 1-800-QUIT-NOW, or by texting QUITNOW to 333888. <br><br>     Access to health coverage is critical to the fight against cancer, and we were proud to expand access to quality, affordable coverage through the American Rescue Plan.  Most health insurance plans are required to cover recommended cancer screenings with no out-of-pocket costs.  But for millions of Americans, the care they need is not within reach.  That is why I am committed to reducing prescription drug costs and health insurance premiums for millions of Americans and closing the Medicaid coverage gap in States that refuse to expand Medicaid.  This would allow millions more of our fellow Americans to access cancer screenings and tobacco cessation services.  <br><br>     We also thank the doctors, nurses, researchers, caregivers, and advocates who are dedicated to finding treatments and cures and reducing the pain and burden of cancer.  Our Nation&#8217;s health care workers continued to provide care and support to cancer patients and their loved ones, even as a global pandemic made their jobs more difficult and demanding, and our Nation is forever grateful.  <br><br>    During Cancer Control Month, we reaffirm our national commitment to meet the scourge of cancer with urgency and with all the tools and talent we can bring to bear.  For survivors and caregivers who carry the physical and mental scars of cancer treatment and recovery, for those who we have lost, and for those who we can save &#8212; let us end cancer as we know it. <br><br>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Cancer Control Month.  I encourage citizens, government agencies, private businesses, nonprofit organizations, and other interested groups to join in activities that will increase awareness of what Americans can do to prevent, detect, treat, and control cancer.<br><br>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Donate Life Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-national-donate-life-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, more than 100,000 men, women, and children in the United States need a life-saving organ transplant.  In many cases, an organ donation provides another chance to live a full life.  For those waiting for that gift of life &#8212; the uncertainty can be excruciating, exacting a physical and emotional toll on the potential recipient and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, more than 100,000 men, women, and children in the United States need a life-saving organ transplant.  In many cases, an organ donation provides another chance to live a full life.  For those waiting for that gift of life &#8212; the uncertainty can be excruciating, exacting a physical and emotional toll on the potential recipient and their loved ones.  During National Donate Life Month, we give thanks to the families and friends of donors who have supported their loved one&#8217;s decision to save lives by donating; we show our appreciation for the professionals who serve the transplantation community; and we encourage Americans who can to become organ, eye, tissue, marrow, and blood donors.  In so doing, we honor those who have given this most extraordinary of gifts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, because of the charity and generosity of the American people, our Nation&#8217;s transplant experts performed more than 41,000 organ transplants &#8212; a record number. &nbsp;We saw organ donations from deceased donors set an annual record for the 11th consecutive year. &nbsp;Living donor transplants, which decreased significantly in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic, increased with over 6,500 living donor transplants performed.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Despite our progress, our Nation continues to face a critical shortage of organ donors, and the number of people in need of a transplant is high, with 17 people dying every day while waiting for a transplant.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s transplant waitlist also includes more than 1,900 children under the age of 18 awaiting the gift of life.&nbsp; That is why during National Donate Life Month, we also recognize National Pediatric Transplant Week&nbsp;from April 24-30, a period dedicated to ending the pediatric transplant waiting list.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Waitlist data shows that people of color make up nearly 60&nbsp;percent of individuals awaiting an organ transplant. &nbsp;To increase access to transplantation for everyone, we recommit to promoting greater diversity in organ donation, as we continue to advance health equity for all communities, including those that have gone underserved, across our Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every year, nearly 18,000 people in America are diagnosed with life-threatening blood cancers or other diseases for which a blood stem cell transplant may be their best or only hope for a cure.&nbsp; Approximately 70 percent of these individuals need donors from outside their families. &nbsp;Although nearly 23 million adults in the United States are currently registered as blood stem cell donors, we need more registrants to help the many individuals who still have difficulty finding a suitably matched donor.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During National Donate Life Month, we thank the millions of&nbsp;individuals across America who are living or registered organ donors.&nbsp; We recognize and commend the researchers, advocates, volunteers, and medical professionals working to reduce the number of people awaiting vital organ transplants.&nbsp; Our Nation applauds the therapeutic innovations that have decreased rates of organ rejection and have extended the lifespan of transplanted organs.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; While transplantation continues to increase substantially and meet the needs of many people with organ failure, we must continue our efforts to shorten the waiting list and encourage organ donation. &nbsp;If you have not signed up as an organ donor, we&nbsp;can use your help.&nbsp; I encourage every American to help people in&nbsp;need by visiting <a href="https://www.organdonor.gov/sign-up">organdonor.gov</a> for organ, eye, and tissue donation, and <a href="https://bloodstemcell.hrsa.gov/">bloodstemcell.hrsa.gov</a> for marrow and blood donation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the&nbsp;United States of America, by the authority vested in me by the&nbsp;Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Donate Life Month.&nbsp; I call upon every person who can to share the gift of life and hope by becoming organ, eye, tissue, marrow, and blood donors.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this</p>



<p>thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
