<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 19:59:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Regional Appointments for&#160;HHS</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/president-biden-announces-key-regional-appointments-for-hhs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51732</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS): Ala Stanford, HHS Regional Director, Region 3 Antrell Tyson, HHS Regional Director, Region 4 Janine Boyd, HHS Regional Director, Region 5 These regional appointees will be critical to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS):</p>



<ul><li>Ala Stanford, HHS Regional Director, Region 3</li><li>Antrell Tyson, HHS Regional Director, Region 4</li><li>Janine Boyd, HHS Regional Director, Region 5</li></ul>



<p>These regional appointees will be critical to the President’s efforts to rebuild communities most impacted by the pandemic, the economic recovery, and climate change. They bring deep expertise in their issue areas as well as critical relationships with federal, state, tribal, and local leaders. And, consistent with the President’s commitment to building an administration that looks like America, these regional appointees represent the diversity of America and the communities they serve.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES (HHS)</u></strong><br>Regional Directors lead HHS’s 10 Regional Offices that directly serve state and local organizations. Regional Directors ensure the Department maintains close contact with state, local, and tribal partners and addresses the needs of communities and individuals served through HHS programs and policies.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ala Stanford, HHS Regional Director, Region 3</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Ala Stanford, a practicing physician for over 20 years, is board certified by the American Board of Surgery in both pediatric and adult general surgery and a health care advocate. She is the Founder of The Black Doctors COVID19 Consortium (BDCC). The consortium was formed in response to the disproportionate number of African Americans being diagnosed and dying from coronavirus in Philadelphia, PA and the lack of swift intervention to mitigate disease spread. The mission of the consortium is to educate, provide advocacy and barrier free coronavirus testing and coronavirus vaccination in an effort to decrease the morbidity and mortality associated with the disease. Her research in basic science, clinical research, and public health have been published in peer reviewed medical journals. Stanford also serves as a medical correspondent for local and national news outlets. She is the former director of the Center for Minority Health and Health Disparities of Temple University School of Medicine, and serves on the CDC Philadelphia Department of Public Health COVID19 Vaccine Advisory Committee. Stanford has received many accolades, notably being named a 2021 Top 10 CNN Hero and 2021 George H.W. Bush Points of Light Award recipient.</p>



<p>Region 3 serves Delaware, the District of Columbia, Maryland, Pennsylvania, Virginia, and West Virginia.</p>



<p><strong><u>Antrell Tyson, HHS Regional Director, Region 4</u></strong></p>



<p>Antrell Tyson previously served as the Director of Business Services and Policy for the city of Atlanta&#8217;s Workforce Development Agency. In this role, Tyson re-established the city&#8217;s federally-funded work-based training programs to help buld a highly skilled and responsive workforce. Additionally, Tyson served as the agency&#8217;s top legal advisor to ensure the agency&#8217;s compliance with local, state, and federal laws and regulations. Tyson previously served as the District Director for Representative Lucy McBath (D-GA-06). As the Congresswoman&#8217;s top District advisor, Tyson oversaw the daily operations of the district office. Tyson also helped to advance many of the Congresswoman&#8217;s policy priorities, including expanding access to affordable healthcare, lowering prescription drug costs, and decreasing maternal mortality rates.</p>



<p>Tyson laid a strong foundation as a public policy professional while working on and off Capitol Hill in Washington, D.C. He has served as Counsel for a Member of Congress and a U.S. Senate committee, as well as Assistant General Counsel for the National Association of Broadcasters. Tyson holds a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science from Colgate University, and a Juris Doctor from the T.C. Williams School of Law at the University of Richmond. He is a native of Decatur, Georgia, and resides in Atlanta with his wife Laurie and their son Dorian.</p>



<p>Region 4 serves Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Tennessee.</p>



<p><strong><u>Janine Boyd, HHS Regional Director, Region 5</u></strong></p>



<p>Janine R. Boyd is a pediatric speech and language pathologist turned advocate and state legislator. With almost two decades of experience in health and human services advocacy and policy as a government affairs professional, Boyd has been actively involved in Ohio’s state budget process and identifying federal opportunities on behalf of programs that serve&nbsp;the&nbsp;most vulnerable citizens. Through her experience with the&nbsp;state&nbsp;legislative process, Boyd has been an advocate for change in Columbus and has developed strong working relationships with agency directors, statewide elected officials, and lawmakers from all backgrounds and political parties. As a former Cleveland Heights council member, Boyd worked to establish a mentoring and juvenile diversion program and catalyzed the expansion of human rights laws to increase protections for members of the LGBT+ community.</p>



<p>In Ohio’s Legislature, Boyd served as Ranking Minority Member on the House Health Committee, as well as the Committee on Community and Family Advancement, among other committees. Boyd co-founded the first statewide Black Maternal Health Caucus and sits on the board of the Ohio Children&#8217;s Trust Fund.&nbsp;Boyd has also been a servant leader in her community, as&nbsp;a trustee on the&nbsp;board for the Heights Emergency Food Center and for Beaumont Catholic High School, her alma mater. She follows the longtime public service example set by her mother, Barbara Boyd.</p>



<p>Region 5 serves Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio, and Wisconsin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE:     Bridget A. Brink, of Michigan, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Ukraine. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>    Bridget A. Brink, of Michigan, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary to the Vice President Kirsten&#160;Allen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/statement-from-press-secretary-to-the-vice-president-kirsten-allen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 16:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Harris tested positive for COVID-19 on rapid and PCR tests. She has exhibited no symptoms, will isolate and continue to work from the Vice President’s residence. She has not been a close contact to the President or First Lady due to their respective recent travel schedules. She will follow CDC guidelines and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Harris tested positive for COVID-19 on rapid and PCR tests. She has exhibited no symptoms, will isolate and continue to work from the Vice President’s residence. She has not been a close contact to the President or First Lady due to their respective recent travel schedules. She will follow CDC guidelines and the advice of her physicians. The Vice President will return to the White House when she tests negative. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Bilateral Virtual Meeting Between President Joe&#160;Biden and President Andrés Manuel López&#160;Obrador</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-bilateral-virtual-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-president-andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 13:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, April 29, President Joe Biden will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador virtually. In this virtual event, the two leaders will discuss their vision for the Ninth Summit of the Americas and how North America can lead on priority initiatives for the region. They also plan to discuss cooperation on migration, joint&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, April 29, President Joe Biden will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador virtually. In this virtual event, the two leaders will discuss their vision for the Ninth Summit of the Americas and how North America can lead on priority initiatives for the region. They also plan to discuss cooperation on migration, joint development efforts in Central America, competitiveness and economic growth, security, energy, and economic cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Expands Second Chance Opportunities for Formerly Incarcerated&#160;Persons</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-expands-second-chance-opportunities-for-formerly-incarcerated-persons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America must offer meaningful opportunities for redemption and rehabilitation to empower those who have been incarcerated to become productive, law-abiding, members of society, and reduce crime and make our communities safer. Leaders on both sides of the aisle recognize that second chance opportunities offer people who have made mistakes and served their time a path&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America must offer meaningful opportunities for redemption and rehabilitation to empower those who have been incarcerated to become productive, law-abiding, members of society, and reduce crime and make our communities safer. Leaders on both sides of the aisle recognize that second chance opportunities offer people who have made mistakes and served their time a path to make meaningful contributions to their communities and reduce recidivism. In doing so, we can break the cycle of crime, and allow law enforcement to focus their time and resources on the most pressing threats to public safety.<br><br>Embodying the President’s belief that America is a nation of second chances, today the President granted pardons to three people and <a>commuted</a>&nbsp;the sentences of 75 people, all of whom have made efforts to rehabilitate themselves, including through educational and vocational training or drug treatment in prison.<br><br>Advancing successful reentry outcomes makes our communities safer, disrupts cycles of economic hardship, and strengthens our economy. Improving reentry is also key part of the comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">strategy</a><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> </a>President Biden announced last June to tackle gun crime and violence. And, since President Biden took office, our economy has added a record 7.9 million jobs and the unemployment rate has fallen to 3.6 percent. At the same time, many industries are facing workforce shortages to meet growing demand as their businesses flourish. America is in a prime position to offer opportunities for meaningful employment to the more than 600,000 people that leave prison every year—for whom securing stable employment is among the most significant challenges.<br><br>Today, during Second Chance Month, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing a comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Incarceration-to-Employment-Strategy.pdf">strategy&nbsp;</a>that expands Incarceration to Employment opportunities, as well as the following concrete policy actions as part of a whole-of-government effort to advance employment, bolster reentry, empower formerly incarcerated persons, and strengthen our communities and our economy:<br><br><strong>Investing in Job Training and Intensive Reentry in Federal Prisons</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Launching Historic DOJ-DOL Partnership.</strong> Today, the Department of Justice and the Department of Labor are announcing a first-of-its-kind collaboration to invest $145 million over FY22-FY23 to provide job skills training and individualized employment and reentry plans for people incarcerated in Bureau of Prisons (BOP) facilities, and to provide pathways for a seamless transition to employment and reentry support upon release. This landmark initiative is part of the Department of Justice’s implementation of the First Step Act, and it will be the first time the Department of Labor will bring its job training and reentry support and expertise to federal prisoners.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanding Federal Job Opportunities and Loan Programs</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing New Workforce Grant Funding.</strong> The Department of Labor has announced solicitations for grants totaling $140 million to advance job opportunities:<br><ul><li><a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/ETA/grants/pdfs/FOA-ETA-22-03_.pdf"><strong>Growth Opportunities</strong></a> is a new $85 million program that will provide education and training, paid work experience, mentorship, and leadership development to justice-involved youth and young adults.<br></li><li><a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/ETA/grants/pdfs/FOA-ETA-22-04%20.pdf"><strong>Pathway Home</strong></a> will fund $55 million for job training, pre-apprenticeship programs, digital literacy training, and pre-release and post-release career counseling for justice-involved adults.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Access to Business Capital.</strong> This week, the Small Business Administration (SBA) will publish <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2020/12/14/2020-26446/regulatory-reform-initiative-streamlining-and-modernizing-the-7a-microloan-and-504-loan-programs-to?msclkid=08f00f42c0ee11ecae5d0207f5e651a9">changes</a> to remove barriers to eligibility based on irrelevant criminal history records for its 7(a), Microloan, and 504 loan programs. SBA is also developing other ways to reduce restrictions in its programs. The SBA recently <a href="https://www.sba.gov/article/2022/mar/30/biden-harris-administration-expands-sba-pilot-program-targeting-access-capital-underserved">announced</a> the elimination of criminal record restrictions to access its Community Advantage loans, a critical program that provides loans to low-income borrowers and those from underserved communities. These actions build on SBA’s February 2021 expansion of eligibility for the Paycheck Protection Program by removing restrictions for entrepreneurs with certain prior criminal convictions or other involvement in the justice system.</li><li><strong>Expanding Access to Federal Employment. </strong>This week, the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) will publish <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/public-inspection/2022-08975/fair-chance-to-compete-for-jobs">proposed regulations</a> that remove barriers to federal employment for formerly incarcerated individuals under the bipartisan Fair Chance to Compete for Jobs Act. Once enacted, these regulations will expand the positions covered by the federal government’s “ban the box” policy, which delays inquiries into an applicant’s criminal history a conditional offer has been made. The regulations also create new procedures that outline due process and accountability steps for hiring officials who are alleged to have violated the “ban the box” procedures.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Leveraging Historic Investments in Infrastructure to Promote Hiring of Formerly Incarcerated Persons. </strong>The Department of Transportation is expanding access to jobs for formerly incarcerated persons and historically marginalized populations in bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act grant programs, including the <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/RAISEgrants">RAISE Grants</a>, <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/grants/infra-grants-program">INFRA Grants</a>, and the <a href="https://www.maritime.dot.gov/PIDPgrants">Port Infrastructure Development Program</a>.</li><li><strong>Promoting Best Practices with Federal Construction Industry Contractors. </strong>Given the landmark level of funding available under the bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to the construction industry and provisions in those grant programs aimed at expanding access to project jobs for formerly incarcerated persons, it is critical that federal contractors and subcontractors comply with the law. This is why the Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contracting and Compliance Programs (OFCCP) issued <a href="https://content.govdelivery.com/accounts/USDOLOFCCP/bulletins/3136722">new guidance</a> to federal contractors and subcontractors that underscores its earlier <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/directives/2013-02">directive</a> that criminal background check policies, which may have a disparate impact on protected classes, may violate existing nondiscrimination obligations. &nbsp;OFCCP also developed compliance assistance materials for contractors including a <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/compliance-assistance/outreach/webinars">webinar</a>, <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/faqs/construction-compliance">Construction Compliance FAQs</a>,&nbsp;and a <a href="https://ofccptraining.dol.gov/catalog/construction-compliance-review-contractors">training</a>. OFCCP has also <a href="https://content.govdelivery.com/accounts/USDOLOFCCP/bulletins/2ef6204">released</a> a new memorandum identifying 400 federal contractors and subcontractors who have been neutrally selected to undergo a full compliance review of their hiring practices to ensure people with arrest and conviction records are not being discriminated against.</li><li><strong>Expanding Second Chance Visiting Fellowship Program.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Justice’s Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA) <a href="https://www.ojp.gov/blog/second-chance-fellows-john-bae-and-angel-sanchez">brought on two new Second Chance Fellows&nbsp;</a>who were formerly incarcerated to help develop reentry policy. For the first time, one of those Fellows will work with the Department of Education (ED) on educational policy for carceral settings and upon reentry.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Promoting Best Practices for Hiring Across the Federal Government</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing Interactive Training and Technical Assistance for Job Seekers.</strong> The Office of Personnel Management has published <a href="https://chcoc.gov/content/second-chance-month">detailed guidance</a> for applicants with arrest and conviction records who are interested in federal employment. To further support them, OPM is hosting interactive sessions between federal agencies’ Human Resources practitioners and applicants with arrest and conviction records.</li><li><strong>Leveraging Existing Hiring Authorities for Agencies.</strong> OPM will host a <a href="https://secondchance.eventbrite.com">training webinar</a> on April 28 to assist federal hiring officials, human resource and DEIA practitioners, and supervisors with leveraging existing federal hiring authorities to recruit and hire formerly incarcerated persons into the federal government.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Veterans</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expediting the Restoration of Benefits</strong>. In partnership with the Social Security Administration and the Bureau of Prisons, the Department of Veterans Affairs’ Veterans Benefits Administration <a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5780">announced</a> a new effort to automate information-sharing among these agencies to accelerate benefit restoration and reduce the administrative burden for veterans.</li><li><strong>Conducting Outreach to Incarcerated Veterans.&nbsp;</strong> The VA <a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5780">announced</a> new efforts to increase the number of state prisons and jails that use its Veterans Reentry Search Service, which helps identify veterans in their custody and connect them with reentry services.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanding Access to Health Care and Housing</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Access to Health Care. </strong>The Department of Health and Human Services is <a href="https://www.cms.gov/files/document/cms-4199-p.pdf">proposing</a> to establish a Special Enrollment Period (SEP) of six months post-release for Medicare for people who missed an enrollment period while incarcerated, which would reduce potential gaps in coverage and late enrollment penalties.</li><li><strong>Expanding Access to Housing.</strong> The Department of Housing and Urban Development announced that it has <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/Main/documents/Memo_on_Criminal_Records.pdf">initiated a 6-month comprehensive review</a> of its existing regulations and guidance to identify how HUD programs can increase their inclusivity of people with arrest and conviction records.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Developing and Amplifying Educational Opportunities</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Second Chance Pell.</strong> ED will select 73 additional schools to <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-expansion-second-chance-pell-program-and-actions-help-incarcerated-individuals-resume-educational-journeys-and-reduce-recidivism">expand</a> its Second Chance Pell Initiative. The expansion of the program into these schools will ultimately provide access to thousands of additional students. First established in 2015 by the Obama-Biden Administration, the Second Chance Pell Initiative provides Pell Grants to incarcerated individuals to participate in postsecondary education programs. This expansion of sites will help the Department to prepare for full expansion of Pell Grant eligibility to incarcerated students in July 2023.</li><li><strong>Providing a Pathway Out of Loan Default. </strong>ED will also announce <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-expansion-second-chance-pell-program-and-actions-help-incarcerated-individuals-resume-educational-journeys-and-reduce-recidivism">changes</a> to policies to help incarcerated individuals get out of loan default to access Pell Grants. In the short term, incarcerated persons who have defaulted will get a “fresh start.” Like other defaulted borrowers, incarcerated borrowers with defaulted loans will reenter repayment in good standing when the student loan payment pause ends. ED is also announcing a longer-term fix that will take place after “fresh start” is implemented: it will allow incarcerated persons to consolidate their loans to get out of default. Incarcerated persons interested in enrolling in Second Chance Pell were twice as likely as the broader population to be turned away because of defaulted loans. This change will now allow incarcerated persons the same opportunity to get out of default as non-incarcerated persons.</li><li><strong>Investing in Digital Literacy.</strong> The Department of Commerce’s <a href="https://broadbandusa.ntia.doc.gov/resources/grant-programs/digital-equity-programs">Digital Equity Planning Grant</a>, funded by the bipartisan Infrastructure and Investment Jobs Act, will provide $60 million to states and Puerto Rico to invest in digital literacy and equity programs for underserved communities,&nbsp; including incarcerated and formerly incarcerated persons.</li><li><strong>Publishing New Guidance on Correctional and Reentry Education Resources.</strong> ED published <a href="https://cte.ed.gov/yadiversion/">guidance</a> to states and localities on how to divert young adults from the juvenile and criminal justice system. ED also published new <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ovae/pi/AdultEd/take-charge-your-future.pdf">guidance</a> for incarcerated persons seeking educational opportunities, summarizing the resources available to support them.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Job Seekers and Establishing Best Practices for Employers</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Tax Credits and Free Bonding Programs for Employers. </strong>DOL developed <a href="https://reo.workforcegps.org/resources/2022/04/06/17/28/Reentry-Employment-Opportunities-Recognizes-April-as-Second-Chance-Month">new resources</a> for justice-involved job seekers, reentry service providers, and employers to learn about existing federal reentry employment incentives including the <a href="https://bonds4jobs.com/">Federal Bonding Program</a> and the <a href="https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-self-employed/work-opportunity-tax-credit">Work Opportunity Tax Credit</a>.</li><li><strong>Resources for Employers, Job Seekers, and Employees.</strong> The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission’s new <a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/arrestandconviction">landing page</a> centralizes existing resources on the use of arrest and conviction records in employment decisions, and other technical assistance documents for employers and job seekers.</li><li><strong>Supporting Reentry 2030.</strong> DOJ’s Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA  partnered with the Council of State Governments (CSG) to launch the <a href="https://bja.ojp.gov/events/advancing-successful-reintegration-every-person-reentry-2030-national-launch#:~:text=Reentry%202030%20is%20a%20partnership,towards%20their%20Reentry%202030%20goals.">national Reentry 2030 campaign</a>, which will work with state leaders to set public reentry goals to achieve better economic mobility and outcomes for persons exiting prison, parole or probation by 2030.</li><li><strong>Promoting Resources for Second Chance Month. </strong>The National Reentry Resource Center (NRRC) is <a href="https://nationalreentryresourcecenter.org/second-chance-month-april-2022-calendar">hosting a series</a> of live training and technical assistance events for Second Chance Act grantees as well as the public in honor of Second Chance Month.</li><li><strong>Reentry Toolkit. </strong>The <a href="https://nationalreentryresourcecenter.org">National Reentry Resource Center</a> launched the Bureau of Justice Assistance’s <a href="https://nationalreentryresourcecenter.org/resources/toolkits/reentry">Reentry Toolkit</a> for local reentry coalition leaders and community leaders to allow assessment of existing reentry efforts and opportunities to strengthen outcomes for incarcerated persons in their communities. The NRRC will also continue to host its searchable database of reentry resources.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clemency Recipient List</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/clemency-recipient-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is granting clemency to 78 individuals, consisting of three pardons and 75 commutations. President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is pardoning the following three individuals: Abraham W. Bolden, Sr. – Chicago, IllinoisAbraham Bolden is an 86-year-old former U.S. Secret Service agent and was the first African American to serve on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is granting clemency to 78 individuals, consisting of three pardons and 75 commutations.<br><br>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is pardoning the following three individuals:<br><br><strong>Abraham W. Bolden, Sr.</strong> – Chicago, Illinois<br>Abraham Bolden is an 86-year-old former U.S. Secret Service agent and was the first African American to serve on a presidential detail.  In 1964, Mr. Bolden was charged with offenses related to attempting to sell a copy of a Secret Service file.  His first trial resulted in a hung jury, and following his conviction at a second trial, even though key witnesses against him admitted to lying at the prosecutor’s request, Mr. Bolden was denied a new trial and ultimately served several years in federal custody.  He has steadfastly maintained his innocence, arguing that he was targeted for prosecution in retaliation for exposing unprofessional and racist behavior within the U.S. Secret Service.  Mr. Bolden has received numerous honors and awards for his ongoing work to speak out against the racism he faced in the Secret Service in the 1960s, and his courage in challenging injustice.  Mr. Bolden has also been recognized for his many contributions to his community following his release from prison.<br><br><strong>Betty Jo Bogans</strong> – Houston, Texas<br>Betty Jo Bogans is a 51-year-old woman who was convicted in 1998 of possession with intent to distribute crack cocaine in the Southern District of Texas after attempting to transport drugs for her boyfriend and his accomplice, neither of whom were detained or arrested.  At the time of her conviction, Ms. Bogans was a single mother with no prior record, who accepted responsibility for her limited role in the offense.  Because of the harsh penalties in place at the time she was convicted, Ms. Bogan received a seven-year sentence.  In the nearly two decades since her release from custody, Ms. Bogans has held consistent employment, even while undergoing treatment for cancer, and has focused on raising her son.   <br><br><strong>Dexter Eugene Jackson</strong> – Athens, Georgia<br>Dexter Jackson is a 52-year-old man who was convicted in 2002 for using his business to facilitate the distribution of marijuana in the Northern District of Georgia.  Mr. Jackson was not personally involved in trafficking marijuana, but allowed marijuana distributors to use his pool hall to facilitate drug transactions.  He accepted full responsibility for his actions at the time he was charged, and pled guilty.  Since his release from custody, Mr. Jackson has converted his business into a cell-phone repair service and hired local high school students through a program that seeks to provide young adults with work experience.  Mr. Jackson has also worked to build and renovate homes in a community that lacks quality affordable housing.<br><br>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is commuting the sentences of the following 75 individuals:<br><br><strong>Sergio Acosta</strong> – Montgomery, Alabama<br><strong>Offense:</strong> Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Kentucky). <br><strong>Sentence:</strong> 97 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 23, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kathy Marie Albrecht</strong> – Jamestown, North Dakota<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a controlled substance (District of North Dakota).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 150 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (November 6, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Maria Isabel Arreola</strong> – San Bernardino, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>:<br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine (Eastern District of Texas).<br>2. Conspiracy to distribute cocaine hydrochloride (Middle District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 121 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 24, 2016).<br>2. 130 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (November 17, 2016).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run concurrently.<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year terms of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Roberto Barrio </strong>– South Gate, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute cocaine base and cocaine powder; interstate travel in aid of racketeering enterprise (four counts); use of a telephone to facilitate the distribution of cocaine base and cocaine powder (two counts) (Western District of Oklahoma).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (October 23, 2000).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kelvin Beaufort</strong> – Charlotte, North Carolina<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute cocaine and cocaine base (Western District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 324 months of imprisonment, 20-year term of supervised release (December 10, 2007); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, 20-year term of supervised release (January 20, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 20-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brandon Todd Berry </strong>– Sikeston, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of a substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (October 19, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Sharon Louise Boatright</strong> – Richardson, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 190 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (December 16, 2013); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (July 15, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Terry Booty</strong> – Morgan City, Louisiana  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine (Eastern District of Louisiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $10,000 fine (November 13, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $10,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Ramola Kaye Brown</strong> – Huntsville, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute five kilograms or more of cocaine and less than 50 kilograms of marijuana (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 145 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (September 15, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Julian Burford </strong>– Bedford, Ohio<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute cocaine (Northern District of Ohio).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (September 17, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mark Richard Burton</strong> – Odessa, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and/or 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence: </strong>121 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $15,000 fine (March 16, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Nickolas Cano</strong> – Amarillo, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine and aiding and abetting (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (September 5, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Ruben Lopez Cazares</strong> – Chula Vista, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute controlled substance (District of Nebraska).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 300 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 7, 2007); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (January 12, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Jose Luis Colunga </strong>– Juniata, Nebraska<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possession with intent to distribute 1,000 kilograms or more of marijuana (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (July 13, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on October 26, 2023, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Paul Hernandez Contreras</strong> – Perris, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possession with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine and a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of cocaine (District of Colorado).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 108 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 8, 2019).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Karen Cox</strong> – Salt Lake City, Utah  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 121 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $900 community restitution (June 16, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 60-month term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $900 community restitution.<br><br><strong>Lori Jean Cross</strong> – North Richland Hills, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (September 12, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mario Cruz</strong> – Grand Rapids, Michigan<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute an unspecified quantity of cocaine and heroin (Western District of Michigan).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 121 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 23, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Christopher Dancy </strong>– Prince George, Virginia<br><strong>Offense: </strong>Conspiracy to distribute cocaine hydrochloride (Eastern District of Virginia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 336 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 27, 2009); amended to 288 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 19, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Catalina Davis</strong> – San Antonio, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute methamphetamine; aiding and abetting the possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 6, 2014); amended to 151 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 31, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stacie Demers</strong> – Constable, New York<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute marijuana; aiding and abetting the possession with intent to distribute marijuana (Northern District of New York).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (October 26, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Deborah Ann Dodd</strong> – Forney, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectible amount of methamphetamine or 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Eastern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 19, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Manuel Ruben Duran-Pimentel</strong> – Miami, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to import controlled substances; laundering of monetary instruments (District of Puerto Rico).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 151 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (April 20, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Nova Neal Finau</strong> – Fort Worth, Texas<br><strong>Offense: </strong>Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (March 31, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tina Marie Finazzo</strong> – Las Vegas, Nevada<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine (District of Hawaii).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 172 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 16, 2012); amended to 168 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 19, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David C. Frazier</strong> – St. Louis, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute cocaine; possession with intent to distribute a mixture containing cocaine; maintaining a drug involved premises (Eastern District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 144 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 21, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Julio Garza </strong>– Edinberg, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>:  Possession with intent to distribute 10 kilograms of cocaine (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (May 13, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Odell Givens</strong> – Certe, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute a controlled substance; possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (three counts) (Northern District of Illinois).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 186 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 14, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Dianna Gonzalez-Agosto</strong> – Altura de Rio G, Puerto Rico<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute at least 3.5 kilograms but less than 5 kilograms of cocaine within a protected location (District of Puerto Rico).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 87 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (July 14, 2020).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Virgil Goodman, Jr. </strong>– Lexington, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession of methamphetamine with intent to distribute (Western District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 262 months of imprisonment, six-year term of supervised release (June 30, 2005).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the six-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Christopher Gunter</strong> – Columbia, South Carolina  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute 50 grams or more of cocaine base, 5 kilograms or more of cocaine, and 100 kilograms or more of marijuana; possession with intent to distribute a quantity of marijuana and a quantity of MDMA (District of South Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (September 25, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rachel Lynn Hanson </strong>– Richton Park, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession of an unspecified quantity of cocaine with intent to distribute (Western District of Michigan).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 151 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 4, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stephanie Hernandez</strong> – Dallas, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (April 21, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brandon Jermaine Huguley</strong> – Chattanooga, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 280 grams or more of cocaine base (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 235 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 20, 2012); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 22, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David Charles Jenkins</strong> – Beaumont, Texas<br><strong>Offense:</strong><br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine base; possession with intent to distribute cocaine base (Western District of Louisiana).<br>2. Violation of supervised release (Eastern District of Texas).<br>3. Production of counterfeit access devices (Eastern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 151 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (November 28, 2011); amended to 121 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (February 9, 2018).<br>2. 24 months of imprisonment (January 5, 2012).<br>3. 24 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $2,516 restitution (April 29, 2015).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight and three-year terms of supervised release, and the unpaid remainders, if any, of the $5,000 fine and $2,516 restitution.<br><br><strong>Douglas Dean Johnson</strong> – Dickens, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to manufacture and distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and possess and distribute pseudoephedrine following a felony drug conviction; travel in interstate commerce and aid and abet travel in interstate commerce with the intent to promote and facilitate a business enterprise involving the manufacture and distribution of controlled substances (Northern District of Iowa).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (December 8, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Gregory Jones </strong>– Philadelphia, Pennsylvania  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute five kilograms or more of cocaine; attempted possession with the intent to distribute five or more kilograms of cocaine and aiding and abetting (East District of Pennsylvania).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 216 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,500 fine (March 30, 2012).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,500 fine.<br><br><strong>Stephan George Jones</strong> – Rosebud, South Dakota<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute a controlled substance (District of South Dakota).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $1,000 fine (April 11, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $1,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Terri Kelly </strong>– Rialto, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams of methamphetamine (Eastern District of Kentucky).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (November 30, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tellas Levallas Kennedy </strong>– Glennville, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a quantity of cocaine hydrochloride (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $4,800 fine (September 30, 2013); amended to 168 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $4,800 fine (October 22, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and $4,800 fine.<br><br><strong>Vincent Edward Kennedy </strong>– Surfside Beach, South Carolina<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine; money laundering (District of South Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 180 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 26, 2014); amended to 145 months of imprisonment 10-year term of supervised release (June 29, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brittany Krambeck </strong>– Fort Worth, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Maintaining drug involved premises; structuring transactions to evade reporting requirements (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 220 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (October 29, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2024, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Carry Le </strong>– Duluth, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 1,000 or more marijuana plants (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 4, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David Lee </strong>– Philadelphia, Pennsylvania<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute more than one kilogram of heroin and to distribute or manufacture in or near a school zone; distribution and possession of heroin with intent to distribute (seven counts); use of communication facility (Eastern District of Pennsylvania).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 300 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $1,500 fine (October 1, 2007); amended to 243 months of imprisonment,10-year term of supervised release, $1,500 fine (June 24, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and $1,500 fine.<br><br><strong>Rosamaria Lucero </strong>– New Braunfels, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance, aiding and abetting (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 13, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Paul A. Lupercio </strong>– Blue Springs, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 1,000 kilograms or more of marijuana and five kilograms or more of cocaine (Western District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (May 8, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Angelica Marquez </strong>– Apple Valley, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute more than 50 grams of methamphetamine (District of Kansas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 117 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (April 23, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Eddie Mateus </strong>– New York, New York<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute heroin and cocaine (Southern District of New York).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stephanie McMurphy </strong>– Adel, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of methamphetamine within 1,000 feet of a school (Middle District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 102 months of imprisonment, six-year term of supervised release (October 22, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the six-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Byron James Miller</strong> – St. Louis, Missouri<br><strong>Offense:</strong><br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute crack cocaine; possession with intent to distribute in excess of 500 grams of cocaine (Eastern District of Missouri).<br>2. Possession with intent to distribute heroin; possession of heroin in a federal prison (District of Central Illinois).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: <br>1. 292 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 6, 1997); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (December 17, 2019).<br>2. 210 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 5, 1999).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the consecutive eight and three-year terms of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Bethel Cheyenne Mooneyham </strong>– Spencer, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to manufacture and distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 13, 2011).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Colleen Mossberger </strong>– Crest Hill, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of methamphetamine (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 5, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Quang Nguyen </strong>– Houston, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 1,000 or more marijuana plants (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 30, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rickey Wayne Norton </strong>– Augusta, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $40,000 fine (October 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $40,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Shannon Ann Norton </strong>– Augusta, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $40,000 fine (October 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $40,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Thomas Perkins </strong>– Louisville, Kentucky<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute in excess of 5 kilograms or more of cocaine hydrochloride (mixture) and 50 grams or more of cocaine base (mixture) (Southern District of Indiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (December 22, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Aaron Ponce </strong>– Odessa, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a controlled substance, 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (July 11, 2013).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rose Trujillo Rangel </strong>– Waco, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute cocaine, a schedule II-narcotic-drug-controlled substance (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (April 14, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $5,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Alejandro Reyna</strong> – Brownsville, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Importation of more than 50 grams of methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (January 16, 2014); amended to 180 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (February 26, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Fermin Serna</strong> – Rio Grande City, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute in excess of 1,000 kilograms of marijuana, a schedule I controlled substance (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (November 9, 2007).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mackie Shivers</strong> – Ft. Lauderdale, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 5 kilograms or more of cocaine; possession with intent to distribute 5 kilograms or more of cocaine (Southern District of Florida).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (April 10, 2001).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kirstie Marie Smith Israel</strong> – Albertville, Alabama<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine (Northern District of Alabama).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 97 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (August 23, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tony Lee Stanfield</strong> – Villa Rica, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Western District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (November 2, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Cleola Sullivan</strong> – Tallahassee, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute cocaine base and 5 kilograms or more of cocaine; possess with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of cocaine (Northern District of Florida).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 13, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Charles Arnold Thomas </strong>– Inglewood, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>:<br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 100 grams or more of phencyclidine, or one kilogram or more of a mixture containing a detectable amount of phencyclidine (Southern District of Texas).<br>2. Possession of a prohibited item by a prison inmate (Eastern District of Arkansas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 4, 2011).<br>2. Seven months of imprisonment (April 25, 2018).<br>Prison sentences in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Edwin G. Tierney </strong>– Council Bluffs, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute methamphetamine (District of Nebraska).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (November 8, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Jesse Alan Trimue</strong> – Burton, Michigan<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute 5 grams of actual methamphetamine and 50 grams or more of methamphetamine mixture, a schedule II-controlled substance (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (June 6, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Daniel Valencia</strong> – Maylene, Alabama<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Importation of a quantity of 50 grams or more of methamphetamine and 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 135 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (April 24, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Martin R. Vandemerwe</strong> – Price, Utah<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (District of Utah).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 20 years of imprisonment; five-year term of supervised release (September 23, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>James Darrell Walker</strong> – Lubbock, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of and possession with intent to distribute cocaine base (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 327 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 21, 2006); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 9, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Cindy Noella Williams</strong> – Casper, Wyoming<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $800 restitution (October 10, 2018); amended to 102 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release; $800 restitution (November 4, 2019).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $800 restitution.<br><br><strong>Cynthia Lynn Yeley-Davis</strong> – Mills, Wyoming<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $1,000 fine (December 17, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $1,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Andrea Zavala</strong> – Waterloo, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute at least 50 grams of a mixture or substance containing methamphetamine and 5 grams of actual methamphetamine (Northern District of Iowa).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 108 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 7, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Courtney Donnell Zeno </strong>– Warner Robins, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of cocaine base (five counts); possession with intent to distribute cocaine base; forfeiture (Western District of Louisiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (August 31, 2010); amended to 240 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (February 7, 2013).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David L. Zouck </strong>– Buffalo, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of methamphetamine; distribution of five grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Western District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 132 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 30, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Clemency and Second Chance&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-clemency-and-second-chance-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America is a nation of laws and second chances, redemption, and rehabilitation. Elected officials on both sides of the aisle, faith leaders, civil rights advocates, and law enforcement leaders agree that our criminal justice system can and should reflect these core values that enable safer and stronger communities. During Second Chance Month, I am using&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America is a nation of laws and second chances, redemption, and rehabilitation. Elected officials on both sides of the aisle, faith leaders, civil rights advocates, and law enforcement leaders agree that our criminal justice system can and should reflect these core values that enable safer and stronger communities. During Second Chance Month, I am using my authority under the Constitution to uphold those values by <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/clemency-recipient-list/">pardoning and commuting</a> the sentences of fellow Americans.</p>



<p>Today, I am pardoning three people who have demonstrated their commitment to rehabilitation and are striving every day to give back and contribute to their communities. I am also commuting the sentences of 75 people who are serving long sentences for non-violent drug offenses, many of whom have been serving on home confinement during the COVID-pandemic—and many of whom would have received a lower sentence if they were charged with the same offense today, thanks to the bipartisan First Step Act. &nbsp;</p>



<p>My Administration is also announcing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-expands-second-chance-opportunities-for-formerly-incarcerated-persons/">new steps</a> today to support those re-entering society after incarceration. These actions include: a new collaboration between the U.S. Department of Justice and the U.S. Department of Labor to provide job training; new grants for workforce development programs; greater opportunities to serve in federal government; expanded access to capital for people with convictions trying to start a small business; improved reentry services for veterans; and more support for health care, housing, and educational opportunities.  </p>



<p>As I laid out in my comprehensive strategy to reduce gun crime, helping those who served their time return to their families and become contributing members of their communities is one of the most effective ways to reduce recidivism and decrease crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While today’s announcement marks important progress, my Administration will continue to review clemency petitions and deliver reforms that advance equity and justice, provide second chances, and enhance the wellbeing and safety of all Americans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Increases Access to COVID-&#8288;19 Treatments and Boosts Patient and Provider&#160;Awareness</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-administration-increases-access-to-covid-19-treatments-and-boosts-patient-and-provider-awareness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 response, there are now more tools than ever before to protect people from the virus, including highly-effective treatments. Over the past 15 months, the Administration has pulled levers across the federal government and deployed resources Congress provided to expedite the development, production, and procurement of COVID-19 treatments. As a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 response, there are now more tools than ever before to protect people from the virus, including highly-effective treatments. Over the past 15 months, the Administration has pulled levers across the federal government and deployed resources Congress provided to expedite the development, production, and procurement of COVID-19 treatments. As a result, the U.S. now has several treatments available that can help keep people out of the hospital and save lives.<br><br>One of the most effective available treatments is Pfizer’s oral antiviral pill, Paxlovid, which has been shown to reduce the risk of hospitalization or death by about 90 percent. The U.S. has committed to purchase 20 million treatment courses—more than any other country in the world. Although Paxlovid was initially in short supply after Food and Drug Administration (FDA) authorization, the Administration has worked with Pfizer to accelerate the delivery of these pills, and they are now in ample supply. The President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/covidplan/">National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan</a> lays out a roadmap for ensuring that these pills, along with other treatments, are available for any American who needs one.<br><br>Since December 2021, the Administration has distributed COVID-19 oral antivirals directly to states, Tribes, territories, and community health centers for free. States and territories play an important role in distributing these treatments to health care providers, pharmacies, and other locations, and any doctor can prescribe treatments. In March, as supply began to ramp up, the President announced the Test-to-Treat initiative to help make it easier for people at high risk of severe disease to quickly access oral antiviral treatments. The Test-to-Treat initiative creates additional locations where people can get a COVID-19 test, a visit with a medical provider, and, if needed, free oral antiviral pills—all in one visit.<br><br>To date, the Administration has worked with pharmacies, long-term care facilities, community health centers, and other health care settings to establish more than 2,200 Test-to-Treat sites around the country, including sites specifically for military families and veterans. As a result, usage of oral antivirals has more than doubled over the last several weeks.<br><br>Today, the Administration is announcing new actions to make these treatments even easier to access and to make sure health care providers and patients know about their safety, efficacy, and availability. These actions will help strengthen and further build the infrastructure to ensure that lifesaving treatments for COVID-19 are quickly distributed around the country, widely available, and easy to access. At the same time, ensuring that this remains the case—and securing more and even better treatments—will require additional funding from Congress.<br><br>Today’s actions include:<br><br><strong>Nearly doubling the number of places oral antivirals are available in the coming weeks. </strong>Right now, oral antivirals are available in about 20,000 locations across the country—including pharmacies, community health centers, hospitals, urgent care centers, and Veterans Affairs clinics, and Department of Defense Medical Treatment Facilities. Now that the United States has ample supply of these treatments, the Administration is making it easier for pharmacies to order antivirals from the federal government. Starting this week, the Administration will allow all pharmacy partners in the federal antiviral pharmacy program—tens of thousands of pharmacy locations nationwide—to order free oral antiviral treatments directly from the federal government. Pharmacies will also continue to be able to receive treatments from state and territorial health departments and through the Test-to-Treat initiative. For many Americans, pharmacies are the most common and convenient place to pick up their prescriptions and receive other forms of health care. Opening ordering to all of these pharmacies will dramatically expand the number of local pharmacies with oral antivirals in stock for patients in their community. The Administration expects that oral antivirals will soon be available in more than 30,000 locations. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will work with pharmacy partners to increase availability even further to up to 40,000 sites over the coming weeks—bringing these treatments closer to more Americans.<br><br><strong>Launching a new effort to stand up federally-supported Test-to-Treat sites. </strong>Building on the current 2,200 Test-to-Treat sites in pharmacies and other clinical settings, the federal government will work with states and jurisdictions to establish additional Test-to-Treat locations with federal support. These sites will co-locate testing, an assessment from a medical provider, and oral antiviral treatments in one convenient stop—launching in partnership with state, Tribal, and territorial governments, and with support and coordination from HHS and the Federal Emergency Management Agency. These sites will launch in select communities in the coming weeks and, as more data comes in, the Administration will determine how federally-supported sites can best be expanded and scaled if needed during any potential future surge in cases. These sites will be targeted to meet demand and increase equitable access to lifesaving COVID-19 treatments and will function in direct collaboration with state and local health agencies. The Administration will also continue working with existing Test-to-Treat pharmacy partners to improve the patient experience, including through telehealth options.<br><br><strong>Supporting medical providers with more guidance and tools to understand and prescribe treatments. </strong>It is critical that health care providers stay informed about the latest information on effective COVID-19 treatments—including their benefits, contraindications, drug-to-drug interactions, and other side effects—so that they are in a position to quickly prescribe one of these treatments where appropriate. The Administration has been working for months with health care providers around the country to inform them about new treatments, with weekly webinars with state and territorial health officials, health care and medical organizations, as well as biweekly clinical webinars with health care providers, including those who specialize in treating high-risk patients. The Administration will continue to engage the clinical community to broaden awareness and understanding of these treatments and to make sure that health care providers are counseling their patients about these effective treatments, prescribing them when appropriate, and helping patients identify where their prescription can be filled. This includes providing toolkits and resources to help doctors assess whether treatments are appropriate for their patients and additional guidance and outreach to every state, pharmacy chain, and major medical association to increase awareness around eligibility, accessibility, contraindications and prescribing considerations for COVID-19 treatments. To that end, just yesterday, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) issued a <a href="https://emergency.cdc.gov/han/2022/pdf/CDC_HAN_463.pdf">Health Alert Network health advisory</a> to its extensive network of public health officials to provide additional information about the efficacy and availability of these treatments. Building on its ongoing work with electronic health record companies to develop and disseminate information about COVID-19 treatments to providers, the Administration is also calling on these companies to incorporate information about oral antivirals directly into their health records interface. This would make it easier to prompt doctors with information about treatments and locations when interacting with a patient—helping to better integrate the prescription of oral antivirals to patients that need them into doctors’ everyday practice.<br><br><strong>Communicating to the American people that safe, effective treatments are widely available. </strong>Now that the Administration has made treatments widely available and there are tens of thousands of sites around the country where they can be dispensed, the Administration will ramp up its public awareness and education efforts on COVID-19 treatments. The Administration’s efforts will focus on making sure that people know that COVID-19 oral antiviral treatments must be taken within the first five days of symptom onset and understand their role in reducing the risk of severe disease and death from COVID-19. These efforts build on steps that the Administration has taken in recent weeks to help people access treatments, including the launch of COVID.gov, creating shareable infographics with clear test-and-treat messages, promoting test-and-treat messages on social media, launching the <a href="https://covid-19-test-to-treat-locator-dhhs.hub.arcgis.com/">Test-to-Treat locator</a>, and standing up a call center (800-232-0233) to provide help in English, Spanish, and more than 150 other languages.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan call with South African National Security Advisor Sydney&#160;Mufamadi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-call-with-south-african-national-security-advisor-sydney-mufamadi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with South African National Security Advisor Sydney Mufamadi. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Mufamadi reaffirmed President Biden and President Ramaphosa’s commitment to strengthen the U.S-South Africa bilateral relationship. Mr. Sullivan pledged support to the people and government of South Africa in response to the deadly floods in Kwa Zulu&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with South African National Security Advisor Sydney Mufamadi. Mr. Sullivan and Mr. Mufamadi reaffirmed President Biden and President Ramaphosa’s commitment to strengthen the U.S-South Africa bilateral relationship. Mr. Sullivan pledged support to the people and government of South Africa in response to the deadly floods in Kwa Zulu Natal. He also emphasized the United States’ continued readiness to work closely with South Africa to address the crisis in Ukraine; enhance our partnership on trade and investment, health systems and health security, and climate change; and support counterterrorism and regional security efforts. They highlighted the need for an immediate end to Russia’s aggression in Ukraine, and shared views on addressing the impact on supply chains, commodity prices, and food security in Africa.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-national-security-advisor-dr-eyal-hulata-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 02:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following President Biden’s fruitful conversation with Israeli Prime Minister Bennett on April 24, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with his Israeli counterpart, National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata, to discuss a range of regional and global security issues.  Mr. Sullivan emphasized that the United States is attuned to Israel’s concerns about threats to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Following President Biden’s fruitful conversation with Israeli Prime Minister Bennett on April 24, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with his Israeli counterpart, National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata, to discuss a range of regional and global security issues.  Mr. Sullivan emphasized that the United States is attuned to Israel’s concerns about threats to its security, including first-and-foremost from Iran and Iranian-backed proxies.  They agreed to further enhance the ongoing coordination through the U.S.-Israel Strategic Consultative Group and strengthen security and diplomatic cooperation wherever possible with other regional partners.  They also discussed Israel’s relationships with key Indo-Pacific countries.  Sullivan and Hulata continued their discussions regarding Russia’s war on Ukraine and the need to continue supporting our Ukrainian partners.  They committed to continue their close coordination on the range of security issues of importance to both the United States and Israel, and they look forward to President Biden’s visit to Israel in the coming months.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
