<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:10:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Measures on Cuba</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-measures-on-cuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The United States stands with the brave Cubans who have taken to the streets to oppose 62 years of repression under a communist regime.” – President Biden The world watched on July 11 as tens of thousands of Cuban citizens marched in cities across Cuba to demand freedom from both the pandemic and from the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>“The United States stands with the brave Cubans who have taken to the streets to oppose 62 years of repression under a communist regime.” </em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><em>– President Biden</em></p>



<p>The world watched on July 11 as tens of thousands of Cuban citizens marched in cities across Cuba to demand freedom from both the pandemic and from the decades of repression and economic suffering to which they have been subjected by Cuba&#8217;s authoritarian regime. The United States stands with the Cuban people, and therefore addressing the moment and the ongoing situation in Cuba is a top priority for the Biden-Harris Administration. At President Biden’s direction, the United States is actively pursuing measures that will both support the Cuban people and hold the Cuban regime accountable.  </p>



<p><strong>Holding the Cuban Regime Accountable</strong><br>On July 22, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) sanctioned one Cuban individual and one Cuban entity for serious human rights abuse, pursuant to Executive Order 13818, which builds upon and implements the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act and targets perpetrators of serious human rights abuse and corruption around the world. This action targets the Cuban Minister of Defense and the Brigada Especial Nacional del Ministerio del Interior of the Cuban Ministry of the Interior for their role in facilitating the repression of peaceful, pro-democratic protests in Cuba that began on July 11.</p>



<p><strong>Engaging the International Community</strong><br>The Administration remains deeply concerned about the welfare of the hundreds of protestors who have been unjustly detained and disappeared simply for demanding their most fundamental rights.  The President continues to call for the swift release of those peaceful protestors who have been unjustly detained. The Administration is also actively engaged with the Organization of American States (OAS), the United Nations, and our international partners to collectively condemn the violence and repression upon the Cuban people for demanding freedom.<br><br><strong>Ensuring Cuban Citizens Have Internet Access</strong><br>The Administration is actively collaborating with the private sector to identify creative ways to ensure that the Cuban people have safe and secure access to the free flow of information on the Internet. The President continues to call on Cuba’s leaders to reinstate and to maintain access to all Internet and telecommunications services for all people within its border, and condemns the use of partial or complete Internet shutdowns and network restrictions imposed by the Cuban Government, which restricts the exercise of human rights and disrupts access to essential services. The intentional blocking of access to the Internet should be strongly condemned by the international community.<br><br><strong>Listening to Cuban American Leaders</strong><br>The Administration has been consistent in its belief that Cuban-Americans are the best ambassadors for freedom and prosperity in Cuba. The Administration will continue to meet with Cuban American leaders and stakeholders as they work to help elevate the voices of demonstrators in Cuba, and provide their recommendations for how the U.S. government can help.<br><br><strong>Reviewing the Remittances Policy</strong><br>The Administration is focused on letting families support one another, by maximizing the flow of remittance payments to the Cuban people. This is a complex issue that requires a measured and thoughtful approach in coordination with experts that will help to inform the Administration’s policy.  The Administration’s guiding principle is ensuring that funds, to the greatest extent possible, get to the Cuban people without a portion of the proceeds being siphoned off by the regime. The President remains concerned that remittances do not reach their intended recipients, including some of the most vulnerable populations on the island, and instead are being used as a stopgap to treat their government&#8217;s failures. <br><br><strong>Restaffing U.S. Embassy Havana</strong><br>The Administration is working to enhance our ability to provide Consular services to the Cuban people given their dire circumstances under an oppressive authoritarian regime. The re-staffing of our Embassy in Havana will serve to enhance our diplomatic, civil society, and Consular service engagement all of which are part of our demonstrated effort to support the Cuban people and their desire for freedom. The Administration is also mindful of the fact that USG personnel have suffered grave injuries while posted to Cuba. Before augmenting our staff in Havana we must do our utmost to ensure that they can safely and securely serve in Cuba.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/22/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-46/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:09 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&#160; Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Fauci will present on the effectiveness of the vaccines and cases among the vaccinated, and I will discuss our work to get more people vaccinated and help states curb&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:09 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Fauci will present on the effectiveness of the vaccines and cases among the vaccinated, and I will discuss our work to get more people vaccinated and help states curb the spread of the virus.&nbsp; And Dr. Murthy will talk about the on-the-ground work we’re supporting in communities to get more people vaccinated.&nbsp; And then we’ll open it up for questions.<br><br>Over to Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp; Yesterday, CDC reported 46,318 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is at about 37,700 cases per day, and this represents an increase of 53 percent from the prior seven-day average.&nbsp; The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 35,000 per day &#8212; an increase of about 32 percent from the previous seven-day period.&nbsp; And the seven-day average of daily deaths has also increased to 237 per day &#8212; and increase of about 19 percent from the previous seven-day period.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I want to speak about our need to come together against a common enemy &#8212; SARS-CoV-2 and the Delta variant.&nbsp; The Delta variant is spreading with incredible efficiency and now represents more than 83 percent of the virus circulating in the United States.&nbsp; Compared to the virus we had circulating initially in the United States at the start of the pandemic, the Delta variant is more aggressive and much more transmissible than previously circulating strains.&nbsp; It is one of the most infectious respiratory viruses we know of and that I have seen in my 20-year career.&nbsp;<br><br>We recognize that some of you are still thinking about whether you will get vaccinated.&nbsp; Maybe you&#8217;re seeing your local officials stepping forward publicly to get vaccinated, or maybe you&#8217;re watching on local news that your community hospitals are getting full.&nbsp; Or scarier still, maybe COVID-19 sickness has tragically hit you or your community closer to home.<br><br>If you are still on the fence, if you still have questions about the vaccines, we welcome them.&nbsp; My request to you is this: Ask your questions.&nbsp; Talk to your healthcare provider.&nbsp; Talk to your pharmacist.&nbsp; Talk to your friends and neighbors who have gotten vaccinated and get your questions answered so that you feel comfortable and informed in making this critical decision.&nbsp; And, please, continue to do the things that we know work to protect you and your family until you are fully vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>If you are not vaccinated, please take the Delta variant seriously.&nbsp; This virus has no incentive to let up, and it remains in search of the next vulnerable person to infect.<br><br>Please consider getting vaccinated and take precautions until you do.&nbsp; And if you&#8217;ve already had COVID infection, CDC guidance strongly recommends that you get vaccinated.&nbsp; It gives you longer-lasting and more robust protection with the breadth and depth of coverage needed to conquer the variants currently circulating in this country.&nbsp;<br><br>To those of you who&#8217;ve already gotten vaccinated: I know you&#8217;re watching the rise in cases and have questions about what it means for you.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re probably worried about two things: whether you will still get COVID despite being vaccinated and which activities are safe.&nbsp;<br><br>Let&#8217;s start with the first concern.&nbsp;&nbsp; Being fully vaccinated gives you a high degree of protection against infection and an even a higher degree of protection against severe illness, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; That is what these vaccines were designed for and what the clinical trials studied, and the vaccines generally do their job quite well.<br><br>These vaccines are some of the most effective that we have in modern medicine.&nbsp; And the good news is that, current scientific evidence shows that our current vaccines are working as they did in clinical trials, even against the Delta variant.<br><br>Importantly, our data showed that infections are much less common in vaccinated people compared to unvaccinated, and most illness in vaccinated individuals is asymptomatic or mild.&nbsp; The most important public health step is to increase the vaccination coverage in all communities in the U.S. and globally.&nbsp;<br><br>There are places in this country where cases are high and cases caused by the Delta variant are also really high, and many of these areas have low vaccine coverage.&nbsp; In areas with high vaccine coverage and low rates of disease transmission, the chances of you coming in close contact with someone who is infectious is relatively low.<br><br>In contrast, in areas with low vaccine coverage and high transmission, there is a much higher chance of you coming in close contact with one or many persons who are infectious and that, in those cases, the greatest risk is for those who are not fully vaccinated.<br><br>Whether you are vaccinated or not, please know we, together, are not out of the woods yet and you will want to make thoughtful decisions to protect your health and the health of your family and your community.&nbsp; We are yet at another pivotal moment in this pandemic, with cases rising again and some hospitals reaching their capacity in some areas.&nbsp; We need to come together as one nation, unified in our resolve to protect the health of ourselves, our children, our community, our country, and our future with the tools we have available.<br><br>With that, I will turn it over to Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; What I&#8217;d like to address for the next few minutes is the phenomenon that many have been speaking about lately, and that is the occurrence of infection after full vaccination.&nbsp;<br><br>So, let&#8217;s just give a bit of a background on the first slide.&nbsp; What do we mean by that?&nbsp; That is the detection of SARS-CoV-2 equal to or 14 days after completion after all recommended doses of what would be an FDA EUA-authorized vaccines.<br><br>It&#8217;s important to remember, as I&#8217;ll get to in a moment, that infections after vaccination are expected.&nbsp; No vaccine is 100 percent effective.&nbsp; However, even if a vaccine does not completely protect against infection, it usually, if it&#8217;s successful, protects against serious disease.&nbsp; And that’s what I&#8217;d like to spend a moment on.<br><br>If I could have the next slide.<br><br>This is a slide that I put together several years ago in trying to describe the situation with vaccines against the standard childhood and adult diseases, as well as the difficulty we were having with developing vaccines against HIV.<br><br>And when you think about vaccines being successful or unsuccessful &#8212; i.e. a failure &#8212; you really have to look at it in multiple subsets.&nbsp; For example, one element of a successful vaccine &#8212; in one in which there&#8217;s no illness, but there&#8217;s no replication of the virus, no dissemination of the virus, and clearance of the virus.&nbsp; That is something that is an unusual feat for a vaccine to give truly what we call &#8220;sterilizing immunity.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then, there&#8217;s is also, within the framework of a successful vaccine, one in which there&#8217;s no clinical illness, but there is replication of the virus.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t disseminate throughout the body.&nbsp; It stays at the level of entry &#8212; be that the upper airway, the GI tract, or what have you.<br><br>Another element of a successful vaccine is one in which there might be mild illness that really does not interfere with the function of a person; that has replication; mild &#8212; very mild dissemination, but ultimately the virus is cleared.&nbsp;<br><br>You have a failure of a vaccine when, actually, you get frank disease.&nbsp; In other words, you haven&#8217;t prevented the disease caused by the virus or the pathogen in question.&nbsp; In this place, you get substantial replication; you get substantial dissemination; and unless you have a lethal virus that kills the patient, ultimately the virus is cleared from the body.&nbsp;<br><br>So what we&#8217;re talking about when we talk about infection after vaccination, which is clearly being discussed now in the context of the Delta variant &#8212; by no means does that mean that you&#8217;re dealing with an unsuccessful vaccine.&nbsp; The success of the vaccine is based on the prevention of illness.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s just look at that very briefly.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>These are the data that I&#8217;ve shown you multiple times about the efficacy of the Pfizer BioNTech and the Moderna: 95 and 94 percent respectively.&nbsp; Note: It is not 100 percent effective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The same holds true for the J&amp;J, which, in the United States, is 72 percent effective against clinically recognizable disease &#8212; not 100 percent effective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, if you go to the last slide, what we&#8217;re really dealing with is effectiveness against serious disease leading to hospitalization and, in some cases, death.</p>



<p>And since the Delta variant is, as Dr. Walensky said, now 83 percent in this country, it&#8217;s the one we&#8217;re dealing with.&nbsp; So even though we are seeing infections after vaccination &#8212; referred commonly to as &#8220;breakthrough infections&#8221; &#8212; the effectiveness against severe disease is still substantial, which is, yet again, another argument which all of us say continually, &#8220;Get vaccinated.&nbsp; It offers good protection against disease.&#8221;</p>



<p>With that, we&#8217;ll go back to Jeff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you both, Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; It is clear that we&#8217;re experiencing what many other countries are experiencing: increased case counts driven by the more transmissible Delta variant.<br><br>We are concerned with the rise in cases among the unvaccinated, but we are also clear that we are in a very different situation than we were earlier this year for three reasons.</p>



<p>First and foremost, as Dr. Fauci just showed, our vaccines work.&nbsp; Fully vaccinated individuals have a high degree of protection against severe illness, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; While we will see some cases among those who are vaccinated, as to be expected with any vaccine, these cases are generally mild and oftentimes asymptomatic, which is just more proof that the vaccines work.&nbsp; In fact, unvaccinated individuals account for virtually all &#8212; 97 percent &#8212; of the COVID hospitalizations and deaths in the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, we have fully vaccinated 162 million Americans, including 80 percent of those most vulnerable &#8212; individuals 65 years and older.&nbsp; As a result, we have fundamentally changed the course of this pandemic.&nbsp; The threat is now predominantly only to the unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>The data is clear: The case increases are concentrated in communities with low vaccination rates.&nbsp; In fact, the counties with the highest case rates have significantly lower vaccination rates than counties with lower case rates.&nbsp; This week, just three states &#8212; Florida, Texas, and Missouri; three states with lower vaccination rates &#8212; accounted for 40 percent of all cases nationwide.&nbsp; For the second week in a row, one in five of all cases occurring in Florida alone.&nbsp; And within communities, these cases are primarily among unvaccinated people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The third reason we&#8217;re in a different situation than earlier in the year is that we&#8217;re continuing to make more progress by increasing the number of vaccinated Americans.&nbsp; Importantly, states with the highest case rates are actually seeing their vaccination rates go up.&nbsp; In fact, in the past week, the five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, [Missouri, and] Nevada &#8212; had a higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a very positive trend.&nbsp; For the second week in a row, states with lower vaccination and higher case rates are seeing their vaccination rates grow faster than the national average.&nbsp; People in these states are feeling the impact of being unvaccinated and responding with action.&nbsp; And across the country, in the past 10 days, more than 5.2 million Americans have gotten a shot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, each day, hundreds of thousands of Americans are choosing to protect themselves, their kids, and their neighbors by getting their first shot.&nbsp; And just as importantly, hundreds of thousands more are getting their second shot on the way to being fully vaccinated.&nbsp; These Americans are stepping up and doing their part.&nbsp; Each shot matters.&nbsp; Each additional person fully vaccinated is a step closer to putting this pandemic behind us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re making continued progress in our fight against the virus.&nbsp; And today, we&#8217;re announcing additional resources to get more shots in arms and combat surges, particularly in rural communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President said last night, unvaccinated Americans know and trust people in their own communities to help get them accurate information about vaccines and help answer their questions.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we are announcing that we were sending $100 million to rural health clinics to support vaccine education and outreach efforts in these communities where we are generally seeing low vaccine uptake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This funding, made possible by the American Rescue Plan, will provide nearly 2,000 rural health clinics the resources they need to better reach unvaccinated Americans in their communities with information about COVID-19 and the vaccines and answers to their questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we work to get more shots in arms, we&#8217;re also doubling down on our efforts to detect, prevent, and respond to outbreaks caused by the Delta variant.&nbsp; Testing and building testing capacity is a key part of our surge response because we know quickly detecting cases allows us to help prevent outbreaks and contain the virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last week, we announced $400 million in American Rescue Plan funding for 1,540 small rural hospitals for COVID-19 to increase testing capacity in rural America.&nbsp; And today, as part of our efforts to reach more vulnerable individuals, we&#8217;re making an additional $1.6 billion investment in American Rescue Plan funding to bolster testing and mitigation measures in high-risk congregate settings, including homeless shelters, mental health and substance abuse treatment centers, domestic violence shelters, and prison systems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These resources will help local health officials and communities identify potential outbreaks before they happen and prevent the further spread of COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our COVID-19 Surge Response Teams are also working with governors and local public health officials to identify specific needs on the ground and provide federal resources and support to fight outbreaks due to the spread of the Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are now providing CDC&#8217;s technical expertise, including on genetic sequencing, data analysis, and outbreak response to Missouri, Illinois, and Colorado.<br><br>FEMA will be deploying mobile vaccination clinics in North Carolina.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, HHS Secretary Becerra is traveling to Nevada, where we have deployed federal resources and 100 personnel from FEMA and HHS to support local health officials as they work to mitigate the spread of Delta and increase vaccinations.&nbsp;<br><br>In closing, our whole-of-government response continues to do everything we can to get more Americans fully vaccinated and protected from the virus, and help states and communities curb the spread of the Delta variant.</p>



<p>As the President said last night, it&#8217;s up to each and every single American to do their own part.&nbsp; We know everyone&#8217;s vaccination journey is different.&nbsp; We are ready to get more Americans vaccinated whenever, wherever they&#8217;re ready.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, please, if you are unvaccinated, consider vaccination today.&nbsp; It&#8217;s free, it&#8217;s available, it&#8217;s easy, it works, and it&#8217;s never, never been more important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to Dr. Murthy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, thank you so much, Jeff.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s great to be with all of you again today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll start just by acknowledging the obvious &#8212; what we&#8217;re all seeing in the numbers &#8212; that it is troubling to see this rise in COVID cases, and it&#8217;s another reminder that we&#8217;re not out in the woods yet.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s important, also, that we not lose sight of how far we&#8217;ve come.</p>



<p>Cases are down dramatically from their January peak when we were averaging 200,000-plus cases a day.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gotten more than 161 million people fully vaccinated, which means they have a high degree of protection against COVID-19.&nbsp; And every day, hundreds of thousands of people are still choosing to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That is all good news.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One fact that has been proven time and time again during this past year is that vaccines save lives.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why 99.5 percent of COVID-19 deaths and 97 percent of possible hospitalizations are among the unvaccinated.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also why nearly every death from COVID-19 is a preventable tragedy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to share a few updates about how we&#8217;re continuing to support people in making their decisions about the vaccine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, we are ramping up our work with trusted messengers in key communities.&nbsp; This summer, we&#8217;ve seen people in every community stepping up to get their loved ones and neighbors vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been really encouraging.&nbsp; And these groups include faith communities from the group Choose Healthy Life, which has worked with powerful networks of 48 Black churches in five cities to test and vaccinate people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It also includes the American Muslim and Multifaith Women&#8217;s Empowerment Council, which has engaged their communities through phone banking, text banking, social media, and door-to-door canvassing.</p>



<p>Healthcare professionals have also been stepping up, have more conversations with your patients.&nbsp;<br><br>And earlier this summer, the Alpha Chapter of the Chi Eta Phi sorority, a service organization made up of nurses, had more than 1,145 conversations about vaccinations at barber shops, grocery stores, and throughout their communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also continuing to work with the student COVID-19 Community Corps, where students participate in calls to learn best practices and hear from their peers about how they can talk about vaccines with their friends and family and community members.<br><br>And we&#8217;re working with platforms like Twitch to answer user questions about the vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But very importantly, we&#8217;re also increasingly asking vaccinated people to help get their family and friends vaccinated.&nbsp; And the importance of this last item &#8212; family and friends talking to family and friends &#8212; is underscored by recent data, which found that one out of five adults who were unsure about the vaccine in January have now been vaccinated.&nbsp; And when asked what changed their mind, it was talking to family, friends, and their doctors, and seeing that people they knew had been safely vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>So we need to keep having these conversations, reminding people that vaccination is still the best way to keep our family and friends safe from the worst outcomes of COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second way that we&#8217;re gaining ground against the virus is by addressing health misinformation.&nbsp; Last week, I issued a Surgeon General&#8217;s Advisory to call the nation&#8217;s attention to the threat of health misinformation.&nbsp; Since then, we&#8217;ve continued to emphasize what individuals can do to stop health misinformation in its tracks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That includes asking everyone to raise their own bar for sharing health information by checking to make sure that it&#8217;s backed by credible, scientific sources.&nbsp; As we say in the advisory, “If you are not sure, don&#8217;t share.”&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to say that on social media, in a video PSA that we&#8217;ve created and released, and in conversations we&#8217;re convening with people around the country.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also mobilizing other stakeholders to address misinformation &#8212; from technology companies and healthcare professionals, to researchers and community-based organizations.&nbsp; In fact, right after this briefing, my office will be hosting a conversation with community organizations around the country to discuss the steps that they can take to stop the spread of health misinformation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the bottom line: Misinformation is a threat to our health, and the speed, scale, and sophistication with which it is spreading is unprecedented.&nbsp; I will not hesitate to say that and to call for greater accountability and action to address health misinformation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A word about equity, though.&nbsp; We recognize that equity must be at the center of our work to confront health misinformation and here&#8217;s why: because unequal access to the healthcare system, education, and technology means that some people have more limited access to accurate information than others.&nbsp; And when those people instead encounter health misinformation, it can worsen their health outcomes, which exacerbates health inequities in what becomes a vicious cycle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ultimately, while the threat of the Delta variant is here, while climbing infection rates are what we&#8217;re seeing day to day, primarily among the unvaccinated, it is more important than ever before that we not let our guard down.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m asking everyone to please talk to your family and friends about getting vaccinated because you could be saving their life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s the people-powered movement that we&#8217;ve got to expand in our country.&nbsp; We made great progress thanks to the hard work of millions of people across this country.&nbsp; We should not forget that.&nbsp; And we should be proud of it, but we have more work to do to end this pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I look forward to taking your &#8212; some of your questions.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll turn it back to you, Jeff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Doctor.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s open it up for a few questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe we&#8217;re having trouble hearing the questions, if the questions have begun.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, we&#8217;re taking a minute to sort through this technical issue.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, we can hear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; This question is for Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Last night, President Biden indicated that the vaccine may be approved for children under 12 as soon as August, September, or October.&nbsp; Is there anything you can share about what led to that timeframe, and what any preliminary data shows so far for children who are participating in clinical trials?&nbsp; And one more quick thing on this: Do you anticipate approval will be for all children under 12 at once or likely be separated by age groups?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; So, maybe I&#8217;ll just say that we&#8217;re looking at the clinical trial data now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re waiting for the clinical trial data to come in.&nbsp; The approval of the data and the authorization will be a regulatory FDA decision.&nbsp; So, after we have seen the clinical trial data &#8212; I have not seen them myself &#8212; after we will see them, then they will go to the FDA for their regulatory process of authorization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, anything to add there?&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re having trouble hearing Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, Jeff, we were on mute.&nbsp; No, just to underscore what Dr. Walensky said, and that is that the clinical trials that are in progress are doing an age de-escalation; that relates the second part of the questioner’s question.&nbsp; So they&#8217;ll do 12 to 9 years old, 9 to 6, 6 to 2, and then 6 months to 2 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The data are being collected right now.&nbsp; Ultimately, as Dr. Walensky correctly said, this will be a regulatory decision based on the data that&#8217;s accumulated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just reiterate what we&#8217;ve talked about before, which is the FDA is the gold standard for vaccine review and approval.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll run an independent and rigorous scientific process.&nbsp; And when that process is complete, the American people can rest assured that the FDA maintained those world-class standards throughout this period.<br><br>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s try Sabrina again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; Just wanted to make sure that you can hear me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:  Yes. <br><br>Q     All right, thank you so much.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Thank you.<br><br>Q     Perhaps it&#8217;s a question for Dr. Fauci, who talked about how effective the vaccines are at preventing severe illness.  I&#8217;m curious if we know more about what the risk of breakthrough cases resulting in<br>long COVID is?  And given how recently people have been vaccinated, how long might it take to start identifying trends among possible long-haul patients who&#8217;ve been vaccinated?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:  Well, that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a &#8212; an object of a very intensive study right now following individuals with various levels of seriousness of disease as to what the incidence and prevalence will be of long COVID.  We don&#8217;t have enough information right now to give you an accurate number of what that incidence is, but that&#8217;s something that is being very actively followed right now. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Elizabeth Weise at USA Today.<br><br>Q     Great.  Thanks so much for taking my call.  This is a question for Dr. Walensky.  I&#8217;ve been talking to epidemiologists, and one of their concerns is that the CDC’s masking policy lacked teeth, so most people just took it to mean they didn&#8217;t need to wear a mask at all.  San Francisco is now contemplating requiring proof of vaccination to get into bars and restaurants.  Other people have suggested that masking regulations change if cases go above 5 per 100,000.  Are there any thoughts in the works of either clarifying or changing CDC’s masking policy?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:  Thank you, Elizabeth.  You know, as we have said consistently, the greatest risk right now is to those who are unvaccinated.  And we have consistently and repeatedly said, “If you are unvaccinated, you need to be wearing a mask to protect yourself and others around you.”  And we need more people to get vaccinated to stop this pandemic. <br><br>So, overall, the CDC recommendations haven&#8217;t changed.  Fully vaccinated people are protected from severe illness.  And we&#8217;ve always said that communities and individuals need to make the decisions that are right for them based on what&#8217;s going on in their local areas. <br><br>So, if you&#8217;re in an area that has a high case rate and low rates of vaccination where Delta cases are rising, you should certainly be wearing a mask if you are unvaccinated.  If you are vaccinated, you get exceptional protection from the vaccines.  But you have the opportunity to make the personal choice to add extra layers of protection if you so choose.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Michael Shear at New York Times.<br><br>Q     Hi, can you hear me?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Yes.<br><br>Q     Okay, thanks.  This is for Jeff probably.  One specific and one general question.  The specific question is: There was this report overnight about the White House discussing masks &#8212; discussing mask mandates in light of L.A. County&#8217;s decision and the rise of the Delta variant.  Can you, you know, tell us whether that report is correct?  Is the White House, in fact, having high-level discussions about that?<br><br>And then, on a broader level, I wonder if you could sort of reflect on the moment that we&#8217;re in compared to where we were just two weeks &#8212; two or so weeks ago, you know, when the President welcomed the &#8212; sort of the world back to normal with a Fourth of July party on the White House lawn and it felt like we were going in a very different direction.  You know, how &#8212; the President said yesterday wa- &#8212; he was frustrated by all of this.  How &#8212; you know, how much of a different place are we in?  And what is all this portend for everybody going back to school and work in the fall?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  So, on masking, I think you just heard a &#8212; a very strong summary from Dr. Walensky, and that&#8217;s where we are.  We will follow the science, and public health guidance is made by Dr. Walensky and her team at the CDC. <br><br>So, we will continue to follow the science and follow CDC on mask guidance &#8212; or mask re- &#8212; mask recommendations.  I think the President captured it well last night, and it&#8217;s consistent with his message on July 4th.  We&#8217;ve made significant progress with 162 million people fully vaccinated.  And fully vaccinated people have a high degree of protection, even against the more transmissible Delta variant. <br><br>If you are not vaccinated &#8212; as the President spoke to unvaccinated people last night and back on July 4th &#8212; you need to get vaccinated or you do not have a high degree of protection for yourself, for your friends, and for your family and your community. <br><br>So, you know, we&#8217;ve made significant progress.  We’re in a very different place than we were several months ago by getting 162 million people vaccinated, but we have a lot more work to do.  And unvaccinated people need to roll up their sleeves as soon as possible and begin their vaccination routine.<br><br>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Time for a couple more questions.  Let&#8217;s go to Kaitlan, CNN. <br><br>Q     Thanks so much.  Dr. Walensky, I just want to circle back on this just so we have complete clarity.  Is the CDC considering right now changing its mask guidance for people who are fully vaccinated?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:  We are always looking at the data as the data come in.  Our ma- &#8212; our guidance has been clear since &#8212; since we put it out several months ago, and that is: If you are unvaccinated, you should continue to wear a mask and protect yourself against others around you.  And more importantly, you should go and get vaccinated to get better layers of protection. <br><br>We have always said that communities &#8212; local communities have to look at what is going on locally, as we have very heterogenous country right now.  In areas that have a high amount of disease and low amounts of vaccination, that, you know &#8212; if you&#8217;re unvaccinated, you should absolutely be wearing a mask.  If you&#8217;re vaccinated, you have exceptional levels of protection from the vaccine, and you may choose to add an extra layer of protection by putting on your mask, and that’s a very individual choice.  That has been consistent with our CDC guidance since we put it out.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Last &#8212; let me do one more question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Let’s go to Tamara Keith at NPR. <br><br>Q     Thank you so much for taking my question; it’s two questions, but I’ll make it quick.  A lot of people who&#8217;ve gotten the J&amp;J vaccine are wondering if they can or should get an mRNA booster.  I know it&#8217;s not recommended at this time, but are you recommending against it?  Or should patients and their doctors make a decision about that? <br><br>Also, wanted to get an update: In early June, you announced a plan to share 80 million doses globally by the end of June.  It’s middle of late July.  What has stopped you from meeting that goal? <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Okay, why don&#8217;t we start with the J&amp;J vaccine booster question, Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:  Yes, thank you, Jeff.  The J&amp;J vaccine &#8212; the data that I showed on the efficacy slide &#8212; was one of the slides I showed &#8212; is a very effective vaccine.  There is no reason to believe right now that people who have taken the J&amp;J vaccine are in need of a booster dose of any sort.  There are no data to indicate that that is the case.  Back to you, Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  On the global front, as you know, we &#8212; the President has committed to sharing 580 million doses of vaccine to the world.  Half a billion doses of Pfizer being donated to those hundred or so countries most in need.  This is, by far, the largest-ever donation of COVID-19 vaccines by a single country. <br><br>We shared the 80 million by the end of June, and they have now shipped.  So they have &#8212; they’re in the air or they’ve arrived in the recipient country.  And we’ll continue to share tens of millions of doses across the summer months, beyond the 80 million.<br><br>Thank you for joining, and we look forward to seeing everybody at the next briefing.  Thank you.</p>



<p>11:44 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_22July2021_for-transcript-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_22July2021_for-transcript-1.pdf </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on Continuing Crackdown in Cuba</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-continuing-crackdown-in-cuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 17:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I unequivocally condemn the mass detentions and sham trials that are unjustly sentencing to prison those who dared to speak out in an effort to intimidate and threaten the Cuban people into silence. The Cuban people have the same right to freedom of expression and peaceful assembly as all people. The United States stands with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I unequivocally condemn the mass detentions and sham trials that are unjustly sentencing to prison those who dared to speak out in an effort to intimidate and threaten the Cuban people into silence. The Cuban people have the same right to freedom of expression and peaceful assembly as all people. The United States stands with the brave Cubans who have taken to the streets to oppose 62 years of repression under a communist regime.<br> <br>Today, my Administration is imposing new sanctions targeting elements of the Cuban regime responsible for this crackdown—the head of the Cuban military and the division of the Cuban Ministry of the Interior driving the crackdown—to hold them accountable for their actions. This is just the beginning–the United States will continue to sanction individuals responsible for oppression of the Cuban people.<br> <br>As we hold the Cuban regime accountable, our support for the Cuban people is unwavering and we are making sure Cuban Americans are a vital partner in our efforts to provide relief to suffering people on the Island. We are working with civil society organizations and the private sector to provide internet access to the Cuban people that circumvents the regime’s censorship efforts. We are reviewing our remittance policy to determine how we can maximize support to the Cuban people. And we are committed to restaffing our embassy in Havana to provide consular services to Cubans and enhance our ability to engage with civil society, while ensuring the safety of U.S. diplomats serving in Cuba.<br> <br>Advancing human dignity and freedom is a top priority for my Administration, and we will work closely with our partners throughout the region, including the Organization of American States, to pressure the regime to immediately release wrongfully detained political prisoners, restore internet access, and allow the Cuban people to enjoy their fundamental rights.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How the Build Back Better Plan Will Create a Better Future for Young Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/fact-sheet-how-the-build-back-better-plan-will-create-a-better-future-for-young-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Although there has been a strong economic recovery under President Biden, young adults have now lived through two historic economic downturns. In 2008, many young workers without a college degree lost their jobs. In 2020, at the height of the pandemic, the highest proportion of young adults between the ages of 18 and 29 were&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Although there has been a <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/PAYEMS%20https:/fred.stlouisfed.org/series/GDP">strong economic</a> recovery under President Biden, young adults have now lived through two historic economic downturns. In 2008, many young workers <a href="https://www.bls.gov/opub/ted/2009/mar/wk5/art03.htm?view_full">without a college degree lost their jobs</a>. In 2020, at the height of the pandemic, the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2020/09/04/a-majority-of-young-adults-in-the-u-s-live-with-their-parents-for-the-first-time-since-the-great-depression/">highest proportion of young adults between the ages of 18 and 29 were living at home with their parents</a> since the Great Depression and unemployment for young adults reached a <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/young-workers-covid-recession/">peak of 24.4 percent</a>, and was even higher for young adults of color. The <a>economic events of the past 15 years have made the </a><a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/young-workers-covid-recession/">path to the middle class difficult</a> for many young Americans.</p>



<p>Young adults are facing additional challenges on their path to economic security, including barriers to home ownership, unaffordable or hard to find child care, and the existential threat of climate change. Home ownership <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/millennials/reports/emerging-millennial-wealth-gap/homeownership-and-living-arrangements-among-millennials-new-sources-of-wealth-inequality-and-what-to-do-about-it/">rates are at a historic low for young adults</a>. Child care for two children costs <a href="https://www.childcareaware.org/millennial-map/">at least 50 percent of the median millennial&#8217;s salary</a> in 47 states, as well as in the District of Columbia. And the climate crisis poses <a href="https://climate.nasa.gov/effects/">an urgent threat</a> to our environment, our health, our communities, our national security, and our economy.</p>



<p>President Biden&#8217;s Build Back Better plan is a once-in-a-generation investment that responds to the historic challenges facing the country, including young Americans. President Biden knows that it is not enough to restore us to where we were prior to the pandemic – we need to build back better. That means making it easier for American families to break into the middle class, and easier to stay in the middle class.&nbsp; It means reducing the cost of things that working people depend on. And, he knows that, in order to secure a brighter, more equitable future, we need to support young adults, many of whom are dealing with the long-term consequences of two economic downturns.</p>



<p><strong>Education and Workforce Opportunities</strong></p>



<p>Thirteen years of school is <a href="https://cew.georgetown.edu/cew-reports/americas-divided-recovery/">no longer enough</a> to be prepared for the jobs of today&#8217;s economy. At the same time, the cost of education beyond high school has become unaffordable for too many students across the country. The <a href="https://www.nasfaa.org/issue_brief_double_pell">value of Pell Grants</a> over the last nearly 50 years has fallen from covering more than 75 percent of the cost of a four-year degree at a public university to under 30 percent, forcing millions of low-income students to take on debt. Additionally, as more young Americans rejoin the workforce or seek out new opportunities in a changing economy, <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/building-americas-job-skills-with-effective-workforce-programs-a-training-strategy-to-raise-wages-and-increase-work-opportunities/">there is a greater need for skills development opportunities</a> for workers of all kinds that lead to high-quality jobs. To expand education and workforce opportunities, the Build Back Better plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Ensure that postsecondary education is accessible and affordable for young adults, and that students who enroll are ultimately successful: </strong>Millennials have grown up in and graduated into an economy <a href="https://cew.georgetown.edu/cew-reports/americas-divided-recovery/">where the majority of jobs created between 2010 and 2016 require some education beyond high school</a>. Because of this, they are the <a href="https://youngamericans.berkeley.edu/2020/01/29/college-attainment/">most educated generation</a>, but have faced challenges along the way. While more young adults from <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/pdf/Indicator_CPA/coe_cpa_2018_05.pdf">low-income backgrounds are enrolling in college,</a> the Pell Grant has not kept up with the increase in cost. This has contributed to an increasing reliance on debt. The Build Back Better plan makes an education beyond high school more affordable and accessible by providing two years of free community college and by making college more affordable for low- and middle-income students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs), Tribal Colleges and Universities (TCUs), and institutions such as Hispanic-serving institutions, Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions, and other minority-serving institutions (MSIs). This is bolstered by increasing the maximum Pell Grant by nearly $1,500 to help all eligible low-income students pay for a two- or four-year degree. Finally, President Biden recognizes that access is not enough &#8211; students need support to obtain a credential or degree. The Build Back Better plan invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at community colleges and institutions that serve students from our most disadvantaged communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Build the capacity of the existing workforce development systems:</strong> The United States has underinvested in the workforce development system for decades. In 2018, for example, we spent <a href="https://data.oecd.org/socialexp/public-spending-on-labour-markets.htm">less than one quarter</a> of the average that other advanced economies spend on workforce and labor market programs as a share of GDP. This lack of investment <a href="https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/sites/default/files/page/files/20161220_active_labor_market_policies_issue_brief_cea.pdf">impacts</a> all of us: better educated workers create spillover effects for other workers and lack of employment has negative social impacts on communities. President Biden is calling on Congress significantly increase investments in American workforce development infrastructure and worker protection. This includes registered apprenticeships and pre-apprenticeships, creating one to two million new registered apprenticeships slots, and strengthening the pipeline for more women and people of color to access these opportunities through successful pre-apprenticeship programs such as the Women in Apprenticeships in Non-Traditional Occupations. &nbsp;It also invests in sector-based training programs, which are comprehensive training programs that include wraparound services, paired with high-quality training and effective partnerships between educational institutions, unions, and employers &#8212; guaranteeing placement in a good quality, in-demand job. The sector-based training investments will provide millions of workers &#8211;particularly young workers, women and workers of color &#8211;with pathways into high job-quality sectors including, clean energy, manufacturing and infrastructure. This will ensure these underserved groups have greater access to new infrastructure jobs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Help for Young Adults Who Care for Their Families</strong></p>



<p>The hope of a middle-class life has gotten further and further out of reach for too many American families, as the costs of raising children – from child care to <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/women/news/2021/02/05/495504/quick-facts-paid-family-medical-leave/">taking leave time</a> to care for a child or family member – have grown. The cost of child care is now <a href="https://www.epi.org/child-care-costs-in-the-united-states/">more than in-state tuition at public four-year colleges</a> in over half of the country. Difficulty in finding high-quality, affordable child care and lack of access to preschools leads some parents to drop out of the labor force entirely, some to reduce their work hours, and others to turn down a promotion. When a parent drops out of the workforce, reduces work hours, or takes a lower-paying job early in their careers, they can suffer lifetime consequences on earnings, savings, and retirement. Similarly, high costs and increasing shortages of care for disabled and elderly people leave many to rely on unpaid caregiving – <a href="https://press.aarp.org/2020-5-14-Caregiving-in-the-US-Report">nearly a quarter of millennials are providing care for a family member</a>. To help young adults care for their families, the Build Back Better plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Create free universal pre-K: </strong>President Biden is calling for a national partnership with states to offer free, high-quality, accessible, and inclusive preschool to all three-and four-year-olds, benefitting five million children and saving the average family $13,000 when fully implemented. This historic investment in America’s future will prioritize high-need areas and enable communities and families to choose the settings that work best for them, including schools, child care centers, family child care providers, Head Start, and other community-based providers. The President’s plan will also ensure that all publicly-funded preschool is high-quality, with low student-to-teacher ratios, developmentally appropriate curriculum, and supportive classroom environments that are inclusive for all students.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Guarantee access to high-quality, affordable child care for low- and middle-income families and offer universal free preschool to all three- and four-year old children.</strong>&nbsp; Families will pay only a portion of their income based on a sliding scale. For the most hard-pressed working families, child care costs for their young children would be fully covered, and families earning up to 1.5 times their state’s median income will pay no more than 7 percent of their income for all children under age five. When fully implemented, this plan will save the average family $14,800 each year, help parents better manage work and care, and produce lifetime benefits for children. &nbsp;The President’s plan would also make permanent the dramatic expansion of the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit (CDCTC) enacted in the American Rescue Plan. With this expanded credit, families can receive up to half of what they spend on child care for children under age 13, up to a total of $4,000 for one child or $8,000 for two or more children.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Create a national comprehensive paid family and medical leave program</strong>. The program will ensure workers receive partial wage replacement to take time to bond with a new child, care for a seriously ill loved one, deal with a loved one’s military deployment, find safety from sexual assault, stalking, or domestic violence, heal from their own serious illness, or take time to deal with the death of a loved one. It will guarantee 12 weeks of paid parental, family, and personal illness/safe leave by year 10 of the program, and also ensure workers get three days of bereavement leave per year starting in year one. The program will provide workers up to $4,000 a month, with a minimum of two-thirds of average weekly wages replaced, rising to 80 percent for the lowest wage workers. Additionally, the plan has an inclusive definition of family, ensuring workers can care for and be cared by a loved one who is not related by blood.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Significantly expand the Child Tax Credit and deliver it monthly</strong>. The Build Back Better proposal would extend the Child Tax Credit (CTC) expansion first enacted in the American Rescue Plan from $2,000 to $3,000 per child six years-old and above, and to $3,600 per child under six. Parents can use this tax credit on everything from diapers to putting more food on the table to paying the rent or mortgage. For a family with two parents who earn a combined $100,000 per year and have two children under six, the Child Tax Credit expansion means the family’s credit would go from $4,000 total to $7,200 total, an additional $3,200 per year in tax relief. For a family with two parents who earn a combined $24,000 per year and have two children under six, the expansion means even more; they would see roughly an additional $4,400 in tax relief because the full credit was not previously available to them. The Build Back Better proposal makes the credit fully refundable on a permanent basis, so that low-income families—the families that need the credit the most—can benefit from the full tax credit. An <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/american-rescue-plan-act-includes-critical-expansions-of-child-tax-credit-and">estimated 66 million children</a> (90 percent) are already poised to benefit from the expanded tax credit, including over 9 million Black children and over 17 million Latino children.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Housing Affordability and Access</strong></p>



<p>Homeownership remains stubbornly out of reach for young Americans due to interrelated issues of rising costs and scarcity of supply. Millennial renters <a href="https://www.apartmentlist.com/research/millennial-homeownership-2021">report</a> declining optimism about the prospect of homeownership and cite affordability as their greatest concern. But even for the majority of millennials who aspire to own a home, high rental costs, plus other expenses that many carry, make it difficult to save up money to buy a home. A recent <a href="https://www.apartmentlist.com/research/millennial-homeownership-2021">survey</a> of millennial renters showed that 63% of renters planning to buy a home had no down payment savings. Whether they seek to own a home or not, a lack of housing supply drives up housing costs for young renters and homeowners alike. To help renters and homeowners, the Build Back Better plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Expand access to federal subsidies that will enable the construction or rehabilitation of more than 1 million affordable rental housing units.</strong> President Biden’s Build Back Better Plan would bolster funding for successful housing subsidy programs to produce and preserve housing that is affordable for very- and extremely-low income renters. This includes investments in the HOME Investment Partnerships program, the Housing Trust Fund, and the Capital Magnet Fund. The President is also proposing authorizing $2 billion in new project-based rental assistance agreements for the first time in more than 20 years to help even more working families access affordable housing. Together, these investments will produce, preserve, and retrofit more than a million affordable rental housing units in big cities and small towns across the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Build and rehabilitate more than 500,000 homes for low- and middle-income homebuyers.</strong> President Biden is calling on Congress to take immediate steps to spur the construction and rehabilitation of homes for underserved communities. Specifically, he is calling on Congress to pass the innovative, bipartisan Neighborhood Homes Investment Act (NHIA). Offering $20 billion worth of NHIA tax credits over the next five years will result in approximately 500,000 homes built or rehabilitated, creating a pathway for more families to buy a home and start building wealth.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Incentivize the removal of exclusionary zoning and harmful land use policies</strong>. For decades, exclusionary zoning laws – like minimum lot sizes, mandatory parking requirements, and prohibitions on multifamily housing – have inflated housing and construction costs and locked families out of areas with more opportunities. President Biden’s plan seeks to help jurisdictions reduce barriers to producing affordable housing and expand housing choices for people with low or moderate incomes. The Build Back Better Plan will create an incentive program that awards flexible and attractive funding to jurisdictions that take concrete steps to reduce barriers to affordable housing production.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Climate Crisis</strong></p>



<p>The climate crisis is one of the greatest threats America and the global community face. And it is this younger generation that will inherit the worst impacts of this crisis. That is why on Day 1, President Biden mobilized the whole of government to tackle the climate crisis, rejoined the landmark Paris Agreement, and set an ambitious and achievable goal of cutting emissions by 50-52% below 2005 levels by 2030. To meet this goal, this Build Back Better plan will make once-in-a-generation investments in clean energy and infrastructure that can help tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice in communities across the country. To address the climate crisis for young Americans, the Build Back Better plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in clean energy manufacturing right here in America. </strong>The plan will provide tax cuts for businesses and consumers to deploy clean energy technology like renewables, battery storage, and electric vehicles. These along with investments for retooling factories and growing supply chains will spur demand for more domestic manufacturing. This will not only grow our capacity to build these technologies here in America, but also create millions of good-quality jobs when paired with strong labor standards and a free and fair choice to join a union and bargain collectively. When paired with an Energy Efficiency and Clean Electricity Standard (EECES), it will help get America on track to meet the goal of 100 percent carbon pollution-free electricity by 2035 and zero net emissions economy-wide by 2050.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Create a new Civilian Climate Corps. </strong>In 1933 President Roosevelt established the Civilian Conservation Corps, a popular New Deal program that transformed the American landscape and put unemployed Americans back to work. During the 9 years of the program’s existence, more than three million young men ages 18-28 served for up to two years earning $30 per month – the equivalent of $600 per month in today’s economy – in addition to meals and lodging. Today there is an opportunity to put a new generation of climate, conservation, and resilience workers to work – paid a living wage and provided a pathway to public service or good-paying union jobs. The plan will enlist a new, diverse generation of Americans to work conserving our public lands and waters, bolstering community resilience, and advancing environmental justice – all while maximizing the creation of accessible training opportunities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in Clean Energy and Energy Efficiency Block Grants to spur thousands of local projects</strong>. This includes installing community solar in disadvantaged communities, replacing street lights with LED bulbs manufactured in America, and making upgrades to a community center to cut its electricity bills—that prioritize worker empowerment and advance environmental justice.&nbsp; These block grants will support states and local governments that are stepping up to lead on climate—by implementing policy measures that accelerate progress toward clean energy goals</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden After Marine One Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-after-marine-one-arrival-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 14:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn (July 21, 2021) THE PRESIDENT:&#160; We answered enough questions today.&#160; The only reason I&#8217;m stopping: I feel badly you&#8217;re here this hour of the night.&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, can you clarify what you said about no &#8212; that there&#8217;s no &#8212; no one in the Democratic Party is anti-police?&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I didn&#8217;t say that.&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 21, 2021)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We answered enough questions today.&nbsp; The only reason I&#8217;m stopping: I feel badly you&#8217;re here this hour of the night.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, can you clarify what you said about no &#8212; that there&#8217;s no &#8212; no one in the Democratic Party is anti-police?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t say that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know that you said you don&#8217;t want to defund the police &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I said that that &#8212; that is not the Democratic Party&#8217;s position.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m the Democratic Party; I am President.&nbsp; So is the Speaker of the House and so is the –- the Majority Leader.&nbsp; We are not the defunding the police.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And are there people who &#8212; in the Democratic Party, who want to defund the police?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Are there people in the Republican Party who think we&#8217;re sucking the blood out of kids?<br>&nbsp;<br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Air Force One Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 13:42:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cincinnati/Northern Kentucky International Airport Cincinnati, Ohio (July 21, 2021) 10:15 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I can’t see you, but I know you’re there.&#160; Thank you for your patience today.&#160; I know it’s a long day for you.&#160; I really mean it.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you. I was just talking to one of the people who asked&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cincinnati/Northern Kentucky International Airport <br>Cincinnati, Ohio<br> <br>(July 21, 2021)</p>



<p>10:15 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I can’t see you, but I know you’re there.&nbsp; Thank you for your patience today.&nbsp; I know it’s a long day for you.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>I was just talking to one of the people who asked the question (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, the debt limit: Mitch McConnell said today that Republicans won’t vote to raise the debt limit, and Democrats will have to include it in reconciliation.&nbsp; What’s your response?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I was hoping that wouldn’t be the case.&nbsp; You know, for the last four years, they&#8217;ve just extended the debt limit.&nbsp; The reason for the significant debt is because of their &#8212; their debt, their tax limit &#8212; excuse me, their tax cut.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are going to be a couple of very difficult decisions that are going to have to be made to get through the end of the year.&nbsp; And one of them is the debt limit and extending the debt.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I don’t have an answer for you, but it’s &#8212; I hope we can get by it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what do you think of the Republicans and Fox News changing their tune on the vaccine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, rather than be critical of it, I thank them for it.&nbsp; I think it’s a matter of &#8212; first of all, in truth, I don&#8217;t know how many of them believed what they were saying.&nbsp; They may have really believed it &#8212; the things that they&#8217;ve been saying.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; but I think once the realization occurred that this virus is only killing primarily those people who had not been vaccinated, I think it was sort of, as we Catholics say, a bit of an &#8220;epiphany&#8221; for them.&nbsp; You know, it was a &#8212; like a &#8212; you know, conversion on the way to Damascus or something.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>But I think it became real, and I &#8212; I’m glad they had the courage to say what they said.&nbsp; And hopefully it will have some impact.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any comment on the Nord Stream deal, sir?&nbsp; The fact that there’s a deal that Nord Stream 2 is going to move forward.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, I can.&nbsp; Nord Stream is 99 percent finished.&nbsp; The idea that anything that was going to be said or done was going to stop it was not possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I had, as you know, very, very fruitful discussions with Angela Merkel, and her &#8212; she is working with the German government on a commitment that suggests that if, in fact, Russia takes pains to deliberately inflict pain on Ukraine or other countries, they will respond.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what do you say to Americans who have done everything right?&nbsp; They’ve gotten fully vaccinated and they still contract COVID &#8212; a &#8220;breakthrough case,&#8221; as it’s called.&nbsp; What do say to them?<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I say to them: There are very, very, very, very, very, very few people &#8212; number one.&nbsp; Those that it happened to, I don’t &#8212; it may be possible &#8212; I know of none where they’re hospitalized, in ICU, and/or passed away.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, at a minimum, I can say that even if they did contract it &#8212; which I’m sorry they did &#8212; it’s such a tiny percentage, and it is not life-threatening.<br>&nbsp;<br>Guys, we got to get on the plane or they’re going to leave us all.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, one more question on January 6th.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; January 6th is &#8212; look, guys.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned that no matter what happens now, the result is going to be perceived as partisan?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, because I think the American public, as I said tonight &#8212; you can’t not understand what happened and still be partisan and try to cover it up.&nbsp; But nobody really believes it wasn’t an insurrection.&nbsp; I mean, you know it.&nbsp; You can see it on the looks on their faces.&nbsp; They know it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>10:20 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in a CNN Town Hall with Don Lemon</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-in-a-cnn-town-hall-with-don-lemon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mount St. Joseph UniversityCincinnati, Ohio (July 21, 2021) 8:01 P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; How you doing, pal?&#160; Good to see you.&#160;&#160;MR. LEMON:&#160; Good to see you.&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good to see you.&#160;MR. LEMON:&#160; How you been?&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;MR. LEMON:&#160; It’s good to see you.&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It’s good to be back.&#160;MR. LEMON:&#160; Yeah, you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Mount St. Joseph University<br>Cincinnati, Ohio</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 21, 2021)</p>



<p>8:01 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; How you doing, pal?&nbsp; Good to see you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Good to see you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good to see you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; How you been?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; It’s good to see you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s good to be back.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah, you as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, listen, I&#8217;m going to get to the audience.&nbsp; And I know you don’t want to sit down, right?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; You’d rather stand here and talk to these guys.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to go out in the audience.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; We’re going to get to the audience questions in just a moment.&nbsp; But I have a couple questions I want to ask you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Because you know the pandemic is a big concern for everyone, really, around the world &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sure is.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; &#8212; especially around America.&nbsp; New cases are up three &#8212; you know, three times since last month.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; The pandemic is a big concern.&nbsp; Hospitalizations, death rising.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you said last month that this &#8212; that the virus is in retreat.&nbsp; Do you still feel that way?&nbsp; Is that still the case?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, the virus &#8212; look, here&#8217;s the &#8212; it’s real simple: We have a pandemic for those who haven&#8217;t gotten a vaccination.&nbsp; It’s that basic, that simple.&nbsp; Ten thousand people have recently died; 9,950 of them, thereabouts, are people who hadn&#8217;t been vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There’s a simple, basic proposition: If you&#8217;re vaccinated, you&#8217;re not going to be hospitalized, you&#8217;re not going to be in an ICU unit, and you&#8217;re not going to die.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s gigantically important that you act like &#8212; we all act like Americans that care about our &#8212; our fellow Americans.&nbsp; To get &#8212; there&#8217;s legitimate questions people can ask &#8212; that they worry about getting vaccinated &#8212; but the questions should be asked, answered, and people should get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is not a pandemic.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made sure that since I got in office, we &#8212; we&#8217;ve inoculated over 160 million people; 85 percent of people over the age of 50.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It’s frustrating.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; But what do you say to people who are worried about a new round of restrictions and mask mandates and so forth?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m saying &#8212; look &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; it’s a little bit like when I got elected.&nbsp; You know, the &#8212; this pandemic was out of control.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve lost more people in the United States &#8212; over 630-some-thousand people than in every major war we&#8217;ve ever fought, in the United States of America.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s come to a screeching halt for those who’ve been vaccinated.&nbsp; It really has.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; This is overwhelming evidence to sustain that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, what I say to people who are worried about a new pandemic is: Get vaccinated.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re vaccinated, even if you do catch the “virus,” quote, unquote &#8212; like people talk about it in normal terms &#8212; you&#8217;re in overwhelm- &#8212; not many people do.&nbsp; If you do, you&#8217;re not likely to get sick.&nbsp; You&#8217;re probably going to be symptomless.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not going to be in a position where you &#8212; where your life is in danger.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it&#8217;s really, kind of, basic.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s get to the questions, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I want to introduce you to Andrea Granieri.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a community resource director for a charter school.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a Democrat currently running for her local school board.<br>&nbsp;<br>Andrea, welcome.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; God love you.&nbsp; The most important, thankless job in the world: being on a school board.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, here in Hamilton County, the vaccination rate remains at about 50 percent &#8212; and you talked about the virus that&#8217;s spreading.&nbsp; Masks are seen less and less.&nbsp; And, as you know, children under age 12 still are not eligible to be vaccinated.&nbsp; Schools are working with all of this information as they think about reopening next month.&nbsp; As a school employee and as a parent to children under age 12, what &#8212; I&#8217;m really concerned.&nbsp; What is your message to those parents, educators, and school districts?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I understand your concern.&nbsp; I really do.&nbsp; My children are grown now, but my grandchildren &#8212; and I have one who’s only one-and-a-half years old.&nbsp; So, you know, I understand &#8212; number one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My message is that one of the reasons why &#8212; you remember the criticism I got initially, saying, “Teachers should get vaccination, get in line first.”&nbsp; The vast majority of teachers are vaccinated, number one.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, the CDC is going to say that what we should do is, everyone over the age of &#8212; under the age of 12 should probably be wearing a mask in school.&nbsp; That&#8217;s probably what&#8217;s going to happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Secondly, those over the age of 12 who are able to get vaccinated &#8212; if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you shouldn&#8217;t wear a mask.&nbsp; If you aren&#8217;t vaccinated, you should be wearing a mask.<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s going to get a little bit tight in terms of, “Well, are mom or dad being honest that, you know, Johnny did or did not get vaccinated?”&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to raise questions.&nbsp; But I think what&#8217;s going to happen is you&#8217;re going to see this work out in ways that people are going to know in the community.&nbsp; Everybody knows in the community whether or not Johnny really did get the vaccination when he&#8217;s 15 or 17 years old.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so it&#8217;s going to &#8212; I think it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s a matter of community responsibility, and I think you&#8217;re going to see it work through.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Well, let me ask &#8212; let me follow up on her question, asking: When will children under 12 be able to get vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Soon, I believe.&nbsp; Now, look, one of the things that I committed to do when I got elected &#8212; I said &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; How soon is “soon,” Mr. President?&nbsp; Not to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; and let me he- &#8212; let me finish the question &#8212; the answer.&nbsp; “Soon” in the sense that I do not tell any scientists what they should do.&nbsp; I do not interfere. (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And so they are doing &#8212; they are doing the examinations now &#8212; the testing now, and making the decision now.&nbsp; When they are ready, when they&#8217;ve done all the scientific need to be done to determine children at ages 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 and 8, they, in fact, are &#8212; all have different makeups.&nbsp; They&#8217;re developing.&nbsp; They&#8217;re trying to figure out whether or not there&#8217;s a vaccination that would affect one child that’s at such and such an age and not another child.&nbsp; That&#8217;s underway.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Just like the other question, there&#8217;s a logical &#8212; and I&#8217;ve heard you speak about it because you always &#8212; I&#8217;m not being solicitous, but you &#8212; you&#8217;re always straight up about what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the question is whether or not we should be in a position where you are &#8212; why can&#8217;t the &#8212; the &#8212; the experts say, “We know that this virus is, in fact &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be…”&nbsp;&#8212; or, excuse me &#8212; “We know why all the drugs approved are not temporarily approved, but permanently approved.”&nbsp; That&#8217;s underway too.&nbsp; I expect that to occur quickly.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Well, that means &#8212; you mean for the FDA?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; For the FDA.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, what do you &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The Federal Drug Administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; You said that you&#8217;re talking to scientists, though, but what &#8212; what are they telling you, Mr. President?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What they&#8217;re telling me is, “Let us decide, based on scientific data, in how we proceed.&nbsp; Do it the way we would ordinarily do it.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, for example, everybody talks about how, you know, this virus came &#8212; this &#8212; this &#8212; the drugs that are designed to kill the virus came along so quickly.&nbsp; They’ve been working on it for two decades.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing quick about this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been over two decades.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So people said, “I&#8217;m not taking a drug that was approved so quickly.”&nbsp; It&#8217;s been two decades.&nbsp; The truth is we haven&#8217;t said it enough to people to allay their feals [sic].&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing &#8212; their fears.&nbsp; This is nothing that just happened yesterday and they said, “Well, let&#8217;s take a shot on this.”&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a process.&nbsp; Usually the process takes the better part of a year or more to get some of these things decided.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the expectation &#8212; they&#8217;re not promising me any specific date &#8212; but my expectation, talking to the group of scientists we put together &#8212; over 20 of them, plus others in the field &#8212; is that sometime maybe in the beginning of the school year &#8212; at the end of August, beginning of September, October &#8212; they’ll get a final approval saying the FDA said, “No, this is it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good.”<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, one last thing.&nbsp; I &#8212; we don&#8217;t talk enough to you about this, I don&#8217;t think.&nbsp; One last thing that’s really important is: We&#8217;re not in a position where we think that any virus &#8212; including the Delta virus, which is much more transmissible and more deadly in terms of non &#8212; unvaccinated people &#8212;&nbsp;the vi- &#8212; the various shots that people are getting now cover that.&nbsp; They&#8217;re &#8212; you&#8217;re okay.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not going to &#8212; you&#8217;re not going to get COVID if you have these vaccinations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I want to stay on the subject.&nbsp; I want to get to Dr. Nicole Baldwin.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a pediatrician and a Republican.<br>&nbsp;<br>Dr. Baldwin, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Doc, how are you?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question, Mr. President.&nbsp; I am a pediatrician who utilizes social media to educate about health.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m very concerned about the rise in misinformation from the anti-vaccine community that is eroding trust in lifesaving vaccines.&nbsp; Spread of this misinformation and declining vaccination rates could leave Americans vulnerable to vaccine-preventable diseases in the future.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, what I want to know is: What is the White House doing to combat medical misinformation and to restore America&#8217;s faith in science?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What we&#8217;re doing is, number one, to restore America&#8217;s faith in science is listen to the scientists.&nbsp; (Applause begins.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I mean, literally listen to the scientists, and not interfere, not rush anything.&nbsp; Just make &#8212; let the scientists proceed, because they desperately want to get this right &#8212; number one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, you may have heard &#8212; I never get myself in trouble, as you know, politically &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; but you may have heard that I was critical of some of the things that are on Facebook, and it was that I was attacking Facebook.&nbsp; I wasn’t attacking Facebook.&nbsp; There was a report out saying that for that &#8212; something like 45 percent of the overwhelming disinformation on Facebook comes from 12 individuals.&nbsp; I said: They&#8217;re killing people &#8212; those 12 individuals; that misinformation is going to kill people.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s like telling your kid, “I tell you what…”&nbsp;&#8212; four years old &#8212; “…when you see a red light, cross the street.”&nbsp; I mean, come on.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, what we&#8217;re trying to do is use every avenue we can &#8212; public, private, government, non-government &#8212; to try to get the facts out, what they really are.&nbsp; And one of the things, Doc, that’s happening, that I&#8217;m feeling better about &#8212; I&#8217;m not being a wise guy now.&nbsp; You know, you &#8212; one of those other networks is not a big fan of mine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp; One you talk about a lot.<br>&nbsp;<br>But if you noticed, as they say in that southern part of my state, “They&#8217;ve had an altar call,” some of those guys.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; All of a sudden, they&#8217;re out there saying, “Let&#8217;s get vaccinated.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get vaccinated.”&nbsp; The very people who before this were saying &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>So that &#8212; but that &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t make fun.&nbsp; That&#8217;s good.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good.&nbsp; We just have to keep telling the truth.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why &#8212; for example, my wife just flew to Alaska today to do an event in Alaska about making sure people understand and get vaccinated, talking about COVID, et cetera.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So it’s &#8212; you know.&nbsp; And, by the way, there’s pockets.&nbsp; If you notice, there&#8217;s about &#8212; what? &#8212; four or five states that have close to 45 percent or whatever.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t hold me to the exact number.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Lower than that, even.&nbsp; In my home state of Louisiana, it’s 36 percent, and I think there are other southern states.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, but I mean, out of all the cases &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; all the cases, a very overwhelming majority of those cases are in four or five states.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just not &#8212; there&#8217;s nothing political about this.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no blue or red.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Well, let’s bring in Christian Oliver.&nbsp; He’s a Democrat.&nbsp; He works for the insurance industry.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Christian, what&#8217;s your question?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, so, my wife Stephanie and I are newlyweds, as of this past Saturday.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’d brag if I were you too.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>As they say when they look at me and my wife: “You married up, kid.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>We require all of our guests and vendors to be vaccinated to ensure safety.&nbsp; We are African American, and in many of our communities, people are against the vaccine.&nbsp; A reason that stood out the most in regards to our guests is that they don&#8217;t see the vaccine as being as safe as the CDC put it &#8212; puts it out to be.&nbsp; How are you working toward convincing those in these communities that the vaccine is safe?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s really an important question because, in the African American community, there is less of an uptake of the vaccination.&nbsp; Number one, there&#8217;s a reason for that: You know, you go back just to even World War Two.&nbsp; African Americans were used as experimental; they were almost like guinea pigs in terms of ex- &#8212; they were &#8212; anyway.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And your mom and dad remember that, or your grandparents remember that.&nbsp; And so there&#8217;s a reason for people to think that, “I don&#8217;t know, I&#8217;m not sure I trust.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure I trust this.”&nbsp; Plus, a lot of disinformation on top of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One of the things that we&#8217;re doing is what I&#8217;ve done &#8212; “we’ve” done, excuse me &#8212; my team has done &#8212; is we’ve provided the ability to put in African American communities the vaccine and those who are, in fact, able to administer the vaccine, and people who are respected in the community, in the vacc- &#8212; in those areas, particularly in areas where you have public health commu- &#8212; public health centers, where you, in fact, have people who are the folks who are really at the low end of the economic scale, don&#8217;t have much access to anything.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;ve taken literally mobile vans and people to the communities, to the hardest-hit communities, and it’s beginning to have some impact.&nbsp; But we have to talk about it more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, I was just with &#8212; I get in trouble because my wife is a Philly girl and a Philly fan, an Eagles fan.&nbsp; I just hosted the Tampa Bay Buccaneers.&nbsp; And &#8212; and there&#8217;s a guy &#8212; there&#8217;s a quarterback there.&nbsp; What&#8217;s his name, man?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Anyway, all kidding aside, you know, what we&#8217;re doing is getting people of consequence, who are respected in the community &#8212; whether they’re athletes, whether or not they are entertainers, whether they&#8217;re just well respected.&nbsp; And, by the way, one of the things I&#8217;ve gotten able to get done: I&#8217;ve get &#8212; I have overwhelming support from the African American clergy that I sort of come from, and my so- &#8212; support.&nbsp; They are opening up their churches for &#8212; as vaccination centers.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Can I ask you something, Mr. President?&nbsp; Because, you know &#8212; and, by the way, you got &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if you heard that you got applause when you corrected the “I” for “we.”&nbsp; And we&#8217;re talking about “we,” and I think that’s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, it is “we.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; &#8212; a commendable attribute to have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But even with my own family &#8212; I was just able to get with them.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t seen my mom in a year and a half, except for two weeks ago.&nbsp; I hadn’t seen my family for two years since the last time they visited me two summers ago.&nbsp; But even within my own family &#8212; here I am on television every night &#8212; there is ambivalence, there&#8217;s misinformation, and there&#8217;s also mistrust in the system.&nbsp; How do you fix that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; you&#8217;re going to &#8212; this is going to seem like a non-answer to start with.&nbsp; One of the things I said when I ran for office &#8212; it’s not Democrat or Republican again &#8212; is we got to restore faith in government.&nbsp; You got to get people to a point where they trust government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I made a commitment that when I made a mistake, I’d tell you I&#8217;ve made mistakes.&nbsp; And when I think I got it right, I&#8217;ll say it.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll take responsibility for what I do and say.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Part of it is just generally &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I don’t mean that &#8212; part of it is, generally, raising confidence in elected officials.&nbsp; Raising confidence.&nbsp; And I know this is going to sound like a non-answer to you, but part of this is that, you know &#8212; you know because you&#8217;re one of the most informed journalists in the country.&nbsp; You know the criticism I got when I said I&#8217;m going to unite the country.&nbsp; They said, “You can’t unite the country.”&nbsp; Well, if we can’t unite the country, we can never get some of these problems solved.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that goes to trust.&nbsp; Why can&#8217;t you unite the country?&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t there a willingness to trust?&nbsp; Government trust is really at a &#8212; was at an incredibly low ebb.&nbsp; It’s coming up some.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So with regard to your family in particular.&nbsp; Part of it is not just that they see you on television and trust you; the people who seem to have the most impact are the &#8212; are, you know, that &#8212; for that 17-year-old kid, the kid that he or she plays ball with.&nbsp; “You got the vaccination?&nbsp; Are you okay?&nbsp; I mean, you seem…”&nbsp; “No, it works.”&nbsp; Or you, you know &#8212; or the mom and dad, or the neighbor, or when you go to church, or when you&#8217;re &#8212; no, I really mean it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are trusted interlocutors.&nbsp; Think of the people &#8212; if your kid wanted to find out whether or not there were &#8212; there&#8217;s a man on the moon, or whatever &#8212; you know, something, or, you know, whether those aliens are here or not &#8212; you know, who are the people they talk to beyond the kids who love talking about it?&nbsp; They go to people they respect, and they say, “What do you think?”<br>&nbsp;<br>And so they should be asking other people &#8212; the people there &#8212; everything from their teachers to their ministers to the priest, to people that they trust.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Well, part of it is that &#8212; don&#8217;t you think part of it is that young people, especially those who are 30 &#8212; maybe 30, 40 and under, they feel like they&#8217;re invincible; they haven&#8217;t faced mortality.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t it amazing we’re saying “40 or younger”?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s hard to say, isn&#8217;t it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; It is.&nbsp; But for them, you know, at first, the va- &#8212; at first, the virus wasn’t affecting them as much.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; And so they may feel that they’re invincible.&nbsp; And now that this Delta variant is affecting them, maybe they’ll have a “come to Jesus” of some sort.&nbsp; I’m &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, by the way, I think that is &#8212; that&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; And, look, think about this:&nbsp; This is the worst health crisis in 100 years.&nbsp; As I said, more people have died than all our major wars combined.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If I told you that or you had told me that two years ago, I’d say, “Come on.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not going to happen in America.”&nbsp; But it happened.&nbsp; It happened.&nbsp; And people are unfortunately &#8212; some more slowly than others &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, by the way, remember when I first got elected, the issue was, well, I said I was going to do a million shots a week, and people said, “Biden can’t do that” or “Biden team can&#8217;t do that.”&nbsp; And it was 2 million.&nbsp; We had trouble getting enough people &#8212; and people who wanted to get vaccinated.&nbsp; We’re opening up stadiums.&nbsp; We&#8217;re getting 100,000 people coming through.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the vast majority of the American people said, “I understand.&nbsp; I want to get this vaccination.”&nbsp; But now, when the &#8212; when it’s phased off, either “I&#8217;m invincible, I&#8217;m young, I&#8217;m not going to get sick, it won’t happen to me” &#8212; or whatever the reason &#8212; now they’re looking around and they’re saying, “Whoa, boy.&nbsp; In the community I live in, there’s very few people who have gotten the vaccination.&nbsp; This COVID is much more transmissible; it&#8217;s really rising.&nbsp; I better get some…”<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think it&#8217;s gradually changing.&nbsp; And you got a great dog there, kid.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; (Off-mic.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; By the way, that is Danielle Lippi.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a student here at the university, and she&#8217;s a Republican.&nbsp; She&#8217;s got a question for you.&nbsp; Go ahead, Danielle.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; But your dog is a Democrat &#8212; I can tell.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; I’m teasing.&nbsp; I’m teasing.&nbsp; I’m a big dog person.&nbsp; I’m sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Her name is Wonder.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my question is: The economy is picking up significantly as it reopens from the pandemic.&nbsp; Are you concerned about the higher inflation prices, especially as we see gasoline, automotive, and food prices increase rapidly?&nbsp; What is your administration doing to help prevent the economy from overheating, such as the poor and middle class are not hurt by the higher prices of goods in the long run?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; First of all, the good news is the economy is picking up significantly.&nbsp; It&#8217;s rational, when you think about it.&nbsp; The cost of an automobile bill, it&#8217;s kind of back to what it was before the pandemic.&nbsp; We compare what the prices were for the last year in the pandemic, and they are up.&nbsp; They’re up because, in fact, there was not much to call for.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, automobiles: You know, you had the rental car companies selling off their entire stock.&nbsp; You found yourself in the same way with automobile dealers.&nbsp; And all of a sudden, now it&#8217;s coming back, and we&#8217;re going to grow at 7 percent &#8212; is expected.&nbsp; We created more jobs in the first six months of my &#8212; our administration than any time in American history.&nbsp; No President has ever &#8212; no administration has ever created as many jobs.&nbsp; And all of a sudden, people are saying &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I don’t say it &#8212; but it goes to the legitimate question being asked about the concern about inflation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The vast majority of the experts, including Wall Street, are suggesting that it&#8217;s highly unlikely that it’s going to be long-term inflation that’s going to get out of hand.&nbsp; There will be near-term inflation because everything is now trying to be picked back up.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way, that’s one of the reasons why I also signed an executive order dealing with the whole idea of competition &#8212; you know, the idea that we&#8217;re in a situation where there are so many companies who are keeping people out of the competition.&nbsp; For example, you have over 600,000 people out there signing &#8212; 6 million people signing a &#8212; I better check the number &#8212; of &#8212; signing non-compete agreements.&nbsp; Not because they have any sta- &#8212; any secret, but because they were working for one fast food restaurant, and they&#8217;re told they can&#8217;t get 10 cents more going across town going to the other fast food restaurant.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; To keep wages down.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so what&#8217;s happening now is, all of a sudden, people are having choices.&nbsp; You know, I always thought the free market system was not only that there&#8217;s competition among companies, but, guess what?&nbsp; Companies should have to compete for workers.&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; Maybe even pay more money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; So, you seem pretty confident that inflation is temporary.&nbsp; But if you’re pumping all of this money into the economy, couldn’t that add to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, look, here’s the deal: Moody’s, today,&nbsp;went out &#8212; a Wall Street firm, not some liberal think tank &#8212; said if we passed the other two things I’m trying to get done, we will, in fact, reduce inflation.&nbsp; Reduce inflation.&nbsp; Reduce inflation &#8212; because we’re going to be providing good opportunities and jobs for people who, in fact, are going to be reinvesting that money back into all the things we&#8217;re talking about, driving down prices, not raising prices.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, it is &#8212; I sincerely mean this: Prices are up now, and they&#8217;re up in &#8212; for example, you’re in a position where you&#8217;re trying to build a house, trying to find two-by-fours and lumber.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; People stopped working cutting lumber.&nbsp; They stopped doing it because they &#8212; the unemployment was so down.&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, all of a sudden, there&#8217;s this need because people are coming back.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; Instead of paying 10 cents, you&#8217;re paying 20.&nbsp; But you understand what I’m saying.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It relates to what, in fact, is now needed because we&#8217;re growing.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know anybody, including Larry Summers &#8212; who&#8217;s a friend of mine &#8212; who&#8217;s worried about inflation, is suggesting that there&#8217;s any long-term march here if we do the things we&#8217;re going to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, if we get this build on that I’ve been &#8212; put together a long time ago &#8212; and, by the way, I want to say, I&#8217;m in his territory.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s &#8212; Portman is a good man.&nbsp; Portman is a congressman from this area.&nbsp; I talked to him before I got &#8212; and I really mean it.&nbsp; He&#8217;s a decent, honorable man, and he and I are working on trying to get this &#8212; this infrastructure bill passed.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; But you&#8217;re &#8212; you&#8217;re talking about Senator Rob Portman of Ohio?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; No, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I thought that (inaudible).&nbsp; I apologize.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah, but &#8212; no, since you &#8212; you mention that infrastructure, the bipartisan infrastructure deal failed the procedural vote today.&nbsp; Right?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; But &#8212; no &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; In the Senate today.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah, it did.&nbsp; But that’s irrelevant.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Go on.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the Senate, negotiators say that they need more time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, then &#8212; but they’re expected to vote again on Monday, but how much time do you think that they need to get this done?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Until Monday.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Look &#8212; no, I&#8217;m not being facetious.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not being facetious.&nbsp; You had up to 20 Republicans sign a letter saying, “We think we need this deal.&nbsp; We think we need this deal.”&nbsp; And so I think there&#8217;ll be &#8212; by the way, the reason we&#8217;re talking this way: We need 60 votes to get something moving.&nbsp; And what&#8217;s going to happen is, I believe &#8212; because I take my Republican colleagues at my &#8212; at their word when you shake.&nbsp; I come from a tradition in the Senate: You shake your hand.&nbsp; That&#8217;s it.&nbsp; You keep your word.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I found Rob Portman does that.&nbsp; I found that &#8212; you know, your governor is a good man.&nbsp; You shake his hand, it&#8217;s done.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I really mean that.&nbsp; I’m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not being falsely complimentary.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Do you think it’s going to move forward in the Senate on Monday?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I do.&nbsp; Here’s what I think:&nbsp; What happens is, the vote on Monday is a motion to be able to proceed to this issue.&nbsp; Then they&#8217;re going to debate the issue of the elements &#8212; the individual elements of this plan to sake [sic] sure we&#8217;re going to fix that damn bridge of yours going into Kentucky. (Applause.)&nbsp; No, I’m serious.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; We’re going to talk about that bridge in just a moment.&nbsp; We asked (inaudible) about that bridge.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; But I think it’s going to get done.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You may find in the amendments that take place on the detail &#8212; the detail of whether or not &#8212; and I&#8217;m the guy that wrote this bill to begin with, and so I&#8217;ve had to compromise to make changes in the bill.&nbsp; When I say “I,” I campaigned on this.&nbsp; I mean, everybody thought I was a little nuts when I talked about there are three reasons why I was running: one, to restore the soul of this country and bring back some decency; two, to build back the middle class because they&#8217;ve been getting really knocked around a long time.&nbsp; They’re the backbone that unite the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the big issues was dealing with infrastructure.&nbsp;&nbsp; Remember, the last four years we had “Infrastructure Week” every week.&nbsp; We didn&#8217;t do a thing.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s necessary.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I really mean it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to not only increase job opportunities, it’s going to increase commerce.&nbsp; It’s going to &#8212; it&#8217;s a good thing, and I think we&#8217;re going to get it done.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; A lot of this stuff you&#8217;re going need &#8212; you need bipartisan support.&nbsp; So, let&#8217;s &#8212; let&#8217;s talk about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our next question comes from Cindy Peebles.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a financial executive and a Democrat.&nbsp; Go ahead, Cindy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, Mr. President.&nbsp; I am dismayed at how often Democratic plans for stabilizing the economy or shoring up new strains of the virus are held hostage by the utopian need to gain bipartisan support.&nbsp; It appears, at every turn, the Democratic plan is weakened and still secures zero Republican votes.&nbsp; Sometimes the opposition is just wrong, and working to get them to agree with you is fruitless.&nbsp; Why is the strategy to abandon the need for bipartisanship not the right answer?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, I may be the wrong guy to talk to because I spent a lot of time as a Senator and Vice President, and I’m going to say something outrageous: I don’t know you’ll find any Republican I&#8217;ve ever worked with who says I ever broke my word, didn&#8217;t do exactly what I said I would do and keep my word.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I was able to get an awful lot of compromises put together to do really good things, to change things.&nbsp; And I still believe that&#8217;s possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>But the well has been so poisoned over the last four years.&nbsp; And even now, there&#8217;s still this lingering effort.&nbsp; A lot of my Republican friends &#8212; and I&#8217;m not talking about Portman; I&#8217;m not talking about your governor &#8212; a lot of my Republican friends say, “Joe, I &#8212; I know you&#8217;re right, but if I do this, I&#8217;ll get primaried and I&#8217;ll lose my primary.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be in trouble.”<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think that&#8217;s all beginning to move.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t mean overnight.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not playing out some panacea here.&nbsp; But I think people are figuring out that if we want to &#8212; I&#8217;ve always found you get rewarded for doing what you think at the time is the right thing, and people really believe you believe it&#8217;s the right thing to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And so I think you&#8217;re seeing it coming together.&nbsp; And, by the way, the compromises are &#8212; you know, are real &#8212; compromise within my own party between the far left and the center and some of the folks who are more conservative.&nbsp; That&#8217;s coming together.&nbsp; They said that would never happen, but if you notice, it has happened.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s talk a little bit more about bipartisanship.&nbsp; You know, the Republicans removed all their picks today for the January 6 committee &#8212; the select committee.&nbsp; Nancy Pelosi rejected two of them.<br>&nbsp;<br>The first thing I want to ask you is, what&#8217;s your reaction to that? &nbsp;But number two, if Republicans and Democrats can&#8217;t come together &#8212; right? &#8212; to investigate the biggest attack on our Capitol in 200 years, what makes you think that they can come together on anything?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; These people.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, I mean it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not being facetious.&nbsp; Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t care if you think I&#8217;m Satan reincarnated.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; The fact is, you can&#8217;t look at that television and say, “Nothing happened on the 6th.”&nbsp; You can&#8217;t listen to people who say this was a “peaceful march.”&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; Think of the things being said.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ve been through the other end of this when the Democrats, 35 years ago, were way off to the other side.&nbsp; Think about it.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; But what you can do, though &#8212; what they can do is try to change the narrative and say, “Well, why wasn&#8217;t Nancy Pelosi prepared?&nbsp; Why weren&#8217;t the Democrats prepared for that to happen?”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, no, they can say that, and you can make honest judgments about it.&nbsp; I have &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, I sometimes get myself in trouble for what I’m about to say &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; not that I ever get in trouble.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; As you&#8217;ve heard me say before: No one ever doubts I mean what I say; the problem is I sometimes say all that I mean.&nbsp; And &#8212; (laughter).<br>&nbsp;<br>But all kidding aside, I have faith in the American people &#8212; I really do &#8212; to ultimately get to the right place.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way, many times Republicans are in the right place.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t mean that the Repub- &#8212; that it’s always the Democratic point of view.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But some of the stuff &#8212; I mean, QAnon:&nbsp;The idea that the Democrats or that Biden is hiding people and sucking the blood of children and &#8212; no, I’m serious.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, you may not like me, and that&#8217;s your right.&nbsp; Look, it&#8217;s a simple thing.&nbsp; You can walk out and say, “I just don’t like the way that guy wears his tie.&nbsp; I’m voting against him.”&nbsp; You have a right to do that.&nbsp; You have a right to do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>But the kinds of things that are being said of late, I think you&#8217;re beginning to see some of the &#8212; and both &#8212; and by Democrats as well &#8212; sort of the venom get &#8212; sort of &#8212; sort of leak out a lot of it.&nbsp; We got to get beyond this.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What do you say to your grandchildren or you children about what’s happening?&nbsp; Do you ever remember a time like this before, in the entire history, whether you’re Democrat or Republican?<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not who we are.&nbsp; And I’ll say one last thing &#8212; and you’re going to &#8212; I’ve had a lot of experience internationally.&nbsp; And I mean that &#8212; not good or bad, just I have; I’ve chaired the Foreign Relations Committee.&nbsp; I’ve been deeply involved.&nbsp; I did national security for the &#8212; our last &#8212; the &#8212; the &#8212; the administration with Barack.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, folks, the rest of the world is wondering about us.&nbsp; Those of you who travel abroad &#8212; not a joke, not a joke &#8212; you ask &#8212; you know, when I went to this G7, all the major democracies &#8212; I walked in &#8212; and I know a lot of them because of my role in the past.&nbsp; And they walk in and I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And they go &#8212; I’m serious, heads of state &#8212; I give you my word as a Biden &#8212; said, “Are you really back?&nbsp; I mean, how can I &#8212; we believe you, Joe, but will the country ever get it together?”<br>&nbsp;<br>I talked to Xi &#8212; Xi Jinping in China, who I know well.&nbsp; We don’t agree on a lot of things.&nbsp; He’s a bright and really tough guy.&nbsp; He truly believes that the 21st century will be determined by oligarchs, by &#8212; and I’m not &#8212; not a joke.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Democracies cannot function in the 21st century &#8212; the argument is &#8212; because things are moving so rapidly &#8212; so, so rapidly that you can’t pull together a nation that is divided to get a consensus on acting quickly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, autocrats &#8212; autocracies &#8212; I had a long meeting with Putin, and I continued &#8212; I know him well.&nbsp; These guys actually are betting &#8212; betting &#8212; I’m not joking &#8212; on autocracies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Democracy has to stand up and demonstrate it can get something done.&nbsp; It’s not just important that we are &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I really mean it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Mr. President, we’re just getting started.&nbsp; We got a lot to talk about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; No, no, no.&nbsp; You’re good.&nbsp; We’re going to take a quick break, and we’re going to come back with more questions for the President of the United States right after this.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>(Commercial break begins.)<br>&nbsp;<br>(Commercial break ends.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Welcome back, everyone.&nbsp; We are live at a CNN Town Hall in Cincinnati, Ohio, with the President of the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Straight to the audience for a question.&nbsp; This is John Lanni.&nbsp; He is the owner and co-founder of a restaurant group with 39 restaurants across the country, Mr. President.&nbsp; He is a Republican.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>John.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hey, John.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question tonight.&nbsp; We employ hundreds of hard-working team members throughout the state of Ohio and across the country.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re looking to hire more every day as we try to restart our restaurant business.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The entire industry, amongst other industries, continue to struggle to find employees.&nbsp; How do you and the Biden administration plan to incentivize those that haven&#8217;t returned to work yet?&nbsp; Hiring is our top priority right now.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, two things.&nbsp; One, if you notice, we kept you open.&nbsp; We spent billions of dollars to make sure restaurants could stay open.&nbsp; And &#8212; and a lot of people who now &#8212; who work as waiters and waitresses decided that they don&#8217;t want to do that anymore because there&#8217;s other opportunities and higher wages, because there&#8217;s a lot of openings now in jobs.&nbsp; And people are beginning to move &#8212; beginning to move.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s some evidence that maintaining the ability to continue not &#8212; to not have your &#8212; have to pay your rent so you don&#8217;t get thrown out, and being able to provide for unemployment insurance, has kept people from going back to work.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no &#8212; not much distinction between not going back to work in a restaurant and not going back to work at a &#8212; at a factory.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So people are looking to change opportunities, change what they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My &#8212; my deceased wife&#8217;s father-in-law was a restauranteur up in &#8212; up in Syracuse, New York.&nbsp; And, by the way, he tried to con- &#8212; he had a &#8212; had a restaurant that was in a town called Auburn, about 20,000 people, which was at a flagship 24-hour-a-day restaurant that &#8212; and he offered it to me, which I would have been making five times what I would in law school to try to keep me in Syracuse.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I spent too many times at home hearing a &#8212; in his home, hearing a phone call: “The cook didn’t come in?&nbsp; He&#8217;s in a fight with his wife?&nbsp; What &#8212; what&#8217;s going on?”<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Exactly.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So I would &#8212; God love you doing what you do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s tough.<br>&nbsp;<br>But all kidding aside, I think it really is a matter of people deciding now that they have opportunities to do other things.&nbsp; And there is a shortage of employees.&nbsp; People are looking to make more money and to bargain.&nbsp; And so I think your business and the tourist business is really going to be in a &#8212; in a bind for a little while.&nbsp; And one of the things &#8212; we&#8217;re ending all those things that are the things keeping people back from going back to work, et cetera.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;ll be interesting to see what happens, but my gut tells me &#8212; my gut tells me that part of it relates to &#8212; you know, you can make a good salary as a waiter or waitress.&nbsp; One of my sister-in-laws is &#8212; of five sisters &#8212; makes a very good salary.&nbsp; She works in Atlantic City.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where she&#8217;s &#8212; she&#8217;s from.&nbsp; But it is &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of people who &#8212; who are looking to change their &#8212; their occupation, I think.&nbsp; But I could be wrong.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Well, let me ask you, because he&#8217;s &#8212; John is looking to hire people.&nbsp; He&#8217;s got 39 restaurants across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Is there anything you can do to help him out?&nbsp; I mean, he&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s got to get people in.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, John &#8212; first of all, I &#8212; you know, the thing we did to help John and the Johns out is provide billions of dollars to make sure they could stay open.&nbsp; Number one.&nbsp; So you all contributed to making sure John could stay in business.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we should.&nbsp; We should have done that, as we did for other industries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But secondly, John, my guess is that people being $7, $8 an hour, plus tips, that &#8212; that&#8217;s &#8212; I think, John, you&#8217;re going to be finding &#8212; (applause) &#8212; 15 bucks an hour or more now.&nbsp; You know what I mean?&nbsp; But you may pay that already.&nbsp; You may pay that already.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Well, let me &#8212; let me ask you, because everywhere I go, there isn’t pretty much a shop in my town, a restaurant or whatever, where there isn’t a “for hire” sign.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We were trying to check into the hotel; they couldn&#8217;t get the rooms cleaned fast enough because they can&#8217;t find staff.&nbsp; You mentioned something &#8212; you said, “We&#8217;re going to end the things that may be keeping people back.”&nbsp; You think that&#8217;s the unemployment benefits expanded?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, that was the argument it was.&nbsp; I &#8212; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it did much.&nbsp; But the point is, it&#8217;s argued that because the extended unemployment benefits kept people &#8211;they&#8217;d rather stay home and not work &#8212; than go to work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; You don&#8217;t think it hurt?&nbsp; Did that?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I see no evidence it had any serious impact on it.&nbsp; But you can argue &#8212; let&#8217;s assume it did.&nbsp; It&#8217;s coming to an end, so it&#8217;s not like we&#8217;re in a situation where &#8212; if that was it and it ends, then we&#8217;re going to see John is going to have no problem.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I think is happening, folks, is, look, if you make less than fift- &#8212; and I&#8217;m not saying, John, your folks make less than 15 &#8212; you had good restaurants; that means their tips are good, people make a lot more than just what the &#8212; what the minimum wage &#8212; what the wage is being paid on with the &#8212; put tips on top of it.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, folks, look, here&#8217;s the deal.&nbsp; Think about it: You know, if you have an &#8212; we &#8212; for example, I want to be able to &#8212; one of my programs is to make sure that we have four more years of school that’s free &#8212; two years for three-year-olds and four-year-olds, because it&#8217;s demonstrated that that &#8212; (applause) &#8212; increases significantly success, and community college.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, those folks are not likely to want to go and be waiters.&nbsp; There’s nothing wrong being a waiter or waitress.&nbsp; My family has been engaged in that business.&nbsp; But the folks is &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, lastly, if you make less than 15 bucks an hour working 40 hours a week, you&#8217;re living below the poverty level.&nbsp; You’re living below the poverty level.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; I want to continue on and talk about &#8212; this has to do with infrastructure, because you got applause when you mentioned the bridge earlier &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; By the way, your congressman wants that bridge too.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Todd Michael is here.&nbsp; He&#8217;s a union electrician and a Democrat.&nbsp; He has a question about something that a lot of people in Cincinnati are concerned about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Todd, take it away.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As Mr. Lemon said, you have already touched on the subject of my question.&nbsp; The two most recent presidents &#8212; past presidents &#8212; had both campaigned using this region&#8217;s Interstate 75 Bridge &#8212; the Brent Spence Bridge that crosses the Iowa River &#8212; as backdrops with a promise of an infrastructure bill that would help with the replacement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden, is it possible to bring Congress together to pass an infrastructure bill that builds a bridge that does not just benefit this region, but the entire I-75 corridor, from Michigan all the way to Florida?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The answer is absolutely, positively yes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m not just saying that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not just saying that.&nbsp; And if you take a look at Ohio and Kentucky combined, there&#8217;s well over &#8212; there&#8217;s thousands of bridges that need repair.&nbsp; Thousands.&nbsp; Thousands of bridges.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we should be looking at it this way: It increases commerce, number one.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; They’re good-paying union jobs.&nbsp; Union.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Union jobs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; and &#8212; and, by the way, can you ever think of a time &#8212; those of you who are economists, who are &#8212; who teach here, economics &#8212; can you think of any time when the middle class did better, the wealthy didn&#8217;t do really well?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not being facetious now.&nbsp; I’m being deadly earnest.&nbsp; Can you think of any time that&#8217;s occurred when the middle class does better?&nbsp; I&#8217;m tired of trickle down.&nbsp; I come from the corporate state of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way, I think you should be able to go out and make a billion dollars or a hundred million dollars if you have the capacity to do it.&nbsp; But I ask one thing: Pay your fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Just pay your fair share.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; And if you know anything about me, check it out: We have more corporations registered in Delaware than all the rest of America combined.&nbsp; Combined.&nbsp; Combined.&nbsp; I represented it for 36 years.&nbsp; I’ve never seen a time when we have the middle class growing that the wealthy didn’t do very, very, very well.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So, that’s what we have to do: Build it out and up, not just down.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So that people like our next guest &#8212; who just graduated from law school, by the way &#8212; his name is Cory Marcum.&nbsp; He’s a graduate from the University of Cincinnati Law School.&nbsp; And he &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He’s a graduate, huh?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Excuse me, he’s heading to law school &#8212; I’m wrong &#8212; in the fall.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; So, Cory, good luck in law school.&nbsp; And what’s your question?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Your first year &#8212; you wish you had already graduated.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; I &#8212; me too.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; So, my question is: Last week, regarding the GOP’s efforts to restrict voting rights, you said those efforts were, quote, “the most dangerous threat to voting and the integrity of free and fair elections in our history,” end quote.&nbsp; While you have condemned these attacks, you and congressional members of your party have done little to actually stop these assaults.&nbsp; If these efforts are really the most dangerous in our history, isn’t it logical to get rid of the filibuster so we can protect our democracy and secure the right to vote?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I stand by what I said.&nbsp; Never before has there been an attempt by state legislatures to take over the ability to determine who won.&nbsp; Not count the votes &#8212; determine who won.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have election officials across the board that they’re deciding to push out of the way.&nbsp; And if, in fact, tomorrow &#8212; let’s say we’re running last time and we’re &#8212; these laws had been in effect that are &#8212; these changes.&nbsp; In Georgia, the Georgia legislature &#8212; you know, Biden won by multiple thousand votes; they could say, “We don’t think it was legit.”&nbsp; And the state legislature votes, “We’re going send electors up to Congress to vote for Trump, not Biden.”&nbsp; That’s never, ever, ever, ever, ever, ever, ever, ever been tried before.&nbsp; This is Jim Crow on steroids what we’re talking about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, it takes &#8212; to go to your second point, I’ve been saying for a long, long time: The abuse of the filibuster is pretty overwhelming.&nbsp; When I got to the United States Senate at a time when we had guys like Jim Eastland and Strom Thurmond and Robert F. Byrd and a whole range of people who were very, very, very, very, very, very conservative on race, to say the least &#8212; even then, if you were to filibuster, you had to stand on the floor and hold the floor.&nbsp; And that’s why Strom, I think, set the record at 24 straight hours or something.&nbsp; Don’t hold me to the number.&nbsp; But, you know, so you had to take &#8212; there were significantly fewer filibusters in those days.&nbsp; In the middle of the civil rights movement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; But let me &#8212; let me talk to you about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, let me finish my answer, because I’ll tell you what I’d do.&nbsp; I would go back to that where you have to maintain the floor.&nbsp; You have to stand there and talk and hold the floor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You can’t just say that now.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; I understand that.&nbsp; But what difference is that if you hold the floor for, you know, a day or a year?&nbsp; What difference does it make?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here’s the thing for me: You talked about people &#8212; and this is important for people who look like me.&nbsp; My grandmother would sit around when I was a kid, fifth grade &#8212; (applause) &#8212; had a fifth-grade education.&nbsp; I learned that she couldn&#8217;t read when I was doing my homework.&nbsp; And she would tell me stories about people asking her to count the number of jellybeans in the jar or the soap.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so why is protecting the filibuster &#8212; is that more important than protecting voting rights, especially for people who fought and died for that?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; It’s not.&nbsp; I want to see the United States Congress, the United States Senate, pass S.1 and S.4, the John Lewis Act, and get it on my desk so I can sign it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But here&#8217;s the deal: What I also want to do &#8212; I want to make sure we bring along not just all the Democrats; we bring along Republicans, who I know know better.&nbsp; They know better than this.<br>&nbsp;<br>And what I don&#8217;t want to do is get wrapped up, right now, in the argument of whether or not this is all about the filibuster or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, the American public, you can&#8217;t stop them from voting.&nbsp; You tried last time.&nbsp; More people voted last time than any time in American history, in the middle of the worst pandemic in American history.&nbsp; More people did.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And they showed up.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to show up again.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to do it again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I want to do is I&#8217;m trying to bring the country together.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want the debate to only be about whether or not we have a filibuster or exceptions to the filibuster or the &#8212; going back to the way the filibuster had to be used before.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; But isn&#8217;t that the only way you&#8217;re going to get it done right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I don&#8217;t believe that.&nbsp; I think we can get it done.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; If you &#8212; if you &#8212; you agree with the former president; he has called &#8212; as you call him, your “old boss” &#8212; that it’s “a relic of Jim Crow.”<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It is.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; If it’s a relic of Jim Crow, it’s been used to fight against civil rights legislation historically, why protect it?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no reason to protect it other than you&#8217;re going to throw the entire Congress into chaos and nothing will get done.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Nothing at all will get done.&nbsp; And there’s a lot at stake.&nbsp; The most important one is the right to vote.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the single most important one.&nbsp; And your vote counted, and counted by someone who honestly counts it.<br>&nbsp;<br>But it goes beyond that.&nbsp; For example, wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; wouldn&#8217;t my friends on the other side love to have a debate about the filibuster instead of passing the recovery act?&nbsp; Or wouldn&#8217;t they love doing it instead of being in a position where we provide for &#8212; how many of you have children under the age of 17?&nbsp; Raise your hand.&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; You’re getting a lot of money in a monthly check now, aren&#8217;t you?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>No, you deserve &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, no, no, I really mean it.&nbsp; Republicans used to fight for it as well.&nbsp; It&#8217;s called the Child Tax Credit.&nbsp; If you have a child under the age of seven, you get 300 bucks a month &#8212; 350 bucks a month.&nbsp; If you have a child under &#8212; between 7 and 17, you get a total of 200 bucks a month.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; It’s cutting child poverty in half.&nbsp; In half.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Mr. President, I want to talk about something else that affects people a lot, and to children as well.&nbsp; The next question &#8212; and it&#8217;s about gun violence.&nbsp; This is from a paralegal and she&#8217;s an advocate.&nbsp; Her name is Andrea Solis Canto.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a Democrat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Andrea, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I used to be a public defender, kid.&nbsp; Thanks for what you&#8217;re doing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, gun violence has been on the rise across the country, and as a recent student and young professional living in Over-the-Rhine, I’ve seen this firsthand.&nbsp; Gun violence has taken the lives of so many young students and young people.&nbsp; I’m tired, and I want to see change that’s going to make our cities, like Cincinnati, safer.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, how will you address gun violence, from a federal point of view, to actually bring about change and make our local cities safer?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Now, I’m not being a wise guy.&nbsp; There’s no reason you should &#8212; have you seen my gun violence legislation I’ve introduced?&nbsp; As you know &#8212; because you’re so involved &#8212; actually, crime is down; gun violence and murder rates are up.&nbsp; Guns.&nbsp; I’m the only guy that ever got passed legislation, when I was a senator, that made sure we eliminated assault weapons.&nbsp; The idea you need a weapon that can have the ability to fire 20, 30, 40, 50, 120 shots from that weapon &#8212; whether it’s a &#8212; whether it’s a 9-millimeter pistol or whether it’s a rifle &#8212; is ridiculous.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m continuing to push to eliminate the sale of those things, but I’m not likely to get that done in the near term.&nbsp; So here’s what I’ve done: The people who, in fact, are using those weapons are acquiring them illegally &#8212; illegally.&nbsp; And so what happens is, I’ve gotten ATF &#8212; Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms &#8212; I have them increase their budget and increase their capacity, along with the Justice Department, to go after the gun shops that are not abiding by the law of doing background checks.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; For real.&nbsp; That&#8217;s number one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two &#8212; number two, we’re in a position where you &#8212; most of the cities &#8212; and I don&#8217;t know enough &#8212; I think you&#8217;ve had a lot of gun violence here in Cincinnati.&nbsp; I think it was up to &#8212; what? &#8212; how many &#8212; how many how dead?&nbsp; Five hundred over a period.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t hold me to the number &#8212; whatever it was.&nbsp; But my point is, all across the country.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not because the gun shops in the cities are selling these guns.&nbsp; They are either shadow gun dealers and/or gun shops that are not abiding by the law.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;re going to do major investigations and shut those guys down and put some of them in jail and &#8212; for what they&#8217;re doing: selling these weapons.&nbsp; There&#8217;s also a thing called “ghost guns” that are being sold now and being used.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so &#8212; but in addition to that, what we have to do is we have to deal with a larger problem of the whole issue of law enforcement, generally.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a situation where, as much as we need to pass the Floyd Act and all that &#8212; but here&#8217;s the deal: Cops are having real trouble.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not all bad guys; there’s a lot of good guys.&nbsp; We need more policemen, not fewer policemen.&nbsp; But we need them involved in community policing.&nbsp; Community policing.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And when we did that, violent crime went down.&nbsp; All the criticism about the original crime bill &#8212; well, guess what?&nbsp; Crime went down until we stopped doing community policing.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s about getting &#8212; we have availability now of over billion &#8212; lots of money for cops to be able to hire psychologists, psychiatrists, as well as social workers to be engaged in the process.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Mr. President, we&#8217;re going to put a period, maybe a comma right here because we have more to come.&nbsp; We got to take a quick break.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ll be right back.&nbsp; More from President Joe Biden right after this.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>(Commercial break begins.)<br>&nbsp;<br>(Commercial break ends.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Welcome back to our CNN Town Hall with the President of the United States, Joe Biden.&nbsp; I just &#8212; I said we were going to put a comma on it because I want to continue this conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You said that you need &#8212; we need more police, right?&nbsp; Your words.&nbsp; So then, how do you respond to Republicans who try to paint you and your party as anti-police?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They’re lying.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, look, never once &#8212; we have to change police conduct.&nbsp; We have to have rules where things are open.&nbsp; We have to have rules where you can be able to determine what the background &#8212; how many times a cop has violated the rules and be able to have access to what&#8217;s going on in police departments, or the Justice Department can get involved in whether or not they have to change their pattern and practices.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ve always said that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; But what about defunding the police though?&nbsp; Because there&#8217;s a “Defund the Police.”<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I’ve never &#8212; never, never said defunding the police.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, I don&#8217;t know any community, particularly the communities that are in the most need and the poorest and the most at risk, that don&#8217;t want police.&nbsp; They want police, though, to look at them as equals.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; They want police to treat them in a way.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want police abusing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And what happened was we got in the position where &#8212; we used to have community policing where the cop &#8212; my deceased son was the attorney general of the state of Delaware.&nbsp; And what we did when that original bill got passed was he would go down in the tough neighborhoods in my &#8212; in my state &#8212; in my city of Wilmington, which is overwhelming a minority city, and he&#8217;d go where the &#8212; everybody can tell me where the best basketball is played in a playground here in this city.&nbsp; You know where it is; you know who the best ballplayers are; you know where they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;d go down and sit there on the bench with his son, my &#8212; my grandson, who&#8217;s now 16, when he was 5 and 6 years old, and let them know he was there.&nbsp; He&#8217;d go over and knock on the window of the local cop, who was sitting there by himself in a squad car.&nbsp; I’d say, “Get out of the car.&nbsp; Meet people.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Because what used to happen was cops used to &#8212; when first community policing came about &#8212; they’d go in and they knew who the minister was in the church, they knew who owned the local liquor store, the local drugstore, the local grocery store.&nbsp; And they&#8217;d walk in and say, “Look, I&#8217;m Joe Biden, and I&#8217;m going to be in this beat.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s my cell number.&nbsp; You have a problem, call me.&nbsp; Here’s my cell number.”<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; You said it&#8217;s tough right now.&nbsp; You said police are up against &#8212; well, they&#8217;re up against the narrative that, you know, the country is anti-police, Democrats are anti-police, Joe Biden is anti-police.&nbsp; And then you have &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They aren&#8217;t saying Joe Biden is anti-police.&nbsp; Cops are not saying that about Joe Biden.&nbsp; They know me, period.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Go on.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re not saying.&nbsp; Republicans are saying it on the far &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; anyway, it doesn’t matter.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; No, you can &#8212; no, I want you to talk about this, because &#8212; I mean &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, look &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; &#8212; it&#8217;s an important narrative.&nbsp; There is no more important issue, I think, right now than safety.&nbsp; You can rebuild a home.&nbsp; You can, you know, get a lot of things back.&nbsp; But, Mr. President, you cannot get back a life.&nbsp; And it &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s exactly right.&nbsp; That’s exactly right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And if police aren’t doing their jobs, that increases &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay &#8212; no, if police aren’t doing their job, they should be held accountable.&nbsp; They should be fired if they’re not doing their job.&nbsp; They should &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I have no &#8212; I make no excuses for that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We should have, for example, the George Floyd Act, where chokeholds are against the law, where a whole lot of things that are laid out in that legislation.&nbsp; And, by the way, I grew up in a neighborhood where you became a cop, a firefighter, or a priest.&nbsp; I wasn’t qualified for any one of them, so here I am.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But all kidding aside &#8212; I&#8217;m not joking &#8212; the guys that grew up in Scranton and Claymont, Delaware &#8212; a steel town &#8212; that’s what we did.&nbsp; That’s what they did.&nbsp; It’s what my friends did.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And here’s the point: The point is that they &#8212; it doesn’t justify maltreating the public.&nbsp; You have no right to do that.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; But now what&#8217;s happening is, because they’ve become &#8212; it’s become so tough across the spectrum, we&#8217;ve actually cut down on a number of police, unrelated to anybody asking for it.&nbsp; The towns and cities aren’t spending as much money on it.&nbsp; There is not as much federal money to hire police.&nbsp; And now, what&#8217;s happening is police are not wanting to be a cop.&nbsp; Raise your hand if you want to be a cop now.&nbsp; What do you think, huh?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So what we got to do is we got to give them the help they need to be better at their job.&nbsp; The idea that you have someone sitting on a ledge, saying they&#8217;re going to jump off a ledge, and you call the cop, and sending a guy or a woman who’s a law enforcement officer, has a criminal justice degree, when you could send with him or her &#8212; you could send with them a psychologist or a social worker, or somebody who can talk to them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yes!<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I mean it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m serious.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Mr. President, I want to get to more questions now.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to bring in Lynne Miller.&nbsp; She&#8217;s an attorney and a Democrat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Lynne, what&#8217;s your question?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, the opioid crisis continues, and in this part of the country, it remains a huge problem.&nbsp; While the over-prescription of opioids is part of that problem, the drugs available in the black market are a growing issue as many of these contain fentanyl.&nbsp; That took the life of our son.&nbsp; How can your administration combat the issue of illegal opiates, many of which our young people buy online?&nbsp; Someone should bear responsibility for delivering death through the mail.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They should bear responsibility.&nbsp; You may or may not be aware: Even in the period when I was out of office, I was railing against the fact that drug companies were selling on the open market.&nbsp; There was one case &#8212; what’s really got me was you had two drugstores in small town in West Virginia having something like prescription for 4,000 pills.&nbsp; And it was obviously drug trafficking.&nbsp; That’s what was going on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So what we did was &#8212; what they did was, they went after it.&nbsp; They just settled with Johnson &amp; &#8212; some of the drug companies who make opioids for twenty-si- &#8212; was it $26 billion or 27.&nbsp; Today, if I&#8217;m not mistaken, the settlement took place.<br>&nbsp;<br>But here&#8217;s the deal: In addition to that, you have the Chinese sending fentanyl to Mexico, in large part, that&#8217;s being mixed with opioids and/or heroin and other drugs, which is a dead-set killer of people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, what we have to do &#8212; I&#8217;ve had this encounter with China, and we&#8217;re going to continue it.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve also increased the number of DEA agents &#8212; what we&#8217;re doing at the border &#8212; and how we&#8217;re going to deal with ex- &#8212; the intercepting that drug trade.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to that, the Justice Department is moving on dealing with the whole opioid issue by increasing significantly the number &#8212; the number of people in Justice Department working on this issue.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s much more to say about it, but it is incredibly, incredibly dangerous.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Mr. President, I believe there&#8217;s no better way to speak about this than &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible) &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; &#8212; from experience.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s probably a family in this room who hasn&#8217;t been affected by addiction.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve been very open about your son Hunter&#8217;s problems with addiction.&nbsp; This is personal for you.&nbsp; And listen, I&#8217;ve dealt with it in &#8212; within my own family.&nbsp; Every family deals with it.&nbsp; But this is personal for you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m so damn proud of my son.&nbsp; My son just wrote a book about how he overcame being addicted.&nbsp; And he did it, and he&#8217;s doing it, and he is in good shape, thank God.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here&#8217;s the thing: We don&#8217;t have nearly enough people involved in mental health and drug addiction services &#8212; number one.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Number one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two &#8212; number two, we shouldn&#8217;t be sending people to jail for use; we should be sending them to mandatory rehabilitation.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Mandatory rehabilitation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number three, when people are in fact in jail, they should be getting &#8212; if that’s not the main crime, but they also did &#8212; they should be getting treatment while they are in jail.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Fourth, when people get out of jail &#8212; whether it&#8217;s for drug addiction or any other crime &#8212; if they&#8217;ve served their time, they should have full access to everything from Pell Grants, to public housing, to &#8212; to the like.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way &#8212; and, by the way, folks, it’s not just the right thing to do; it’s the smart thing for us to do. Because what happens?&nbsp; Years ago, there was a guy named Arlen Specter from Pennsylvania.&nbsp; He and I introduced legislation that was a second chance.&nbsp; It would &#8212; meant that, right now, when you get out of jail in most prisons in the states around the country &#8212; what happens? &#8212; you get a bus ticket and 25 bucks.&nbsp; You end up under the bridge, just like you did before.&nbsp; You&#8217;re almost &#8212; almost guaranteed to get back in &#8212; in whatever &#8212; whatever your problem was before.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, they should have access to drug treatment.&nbsp; They should have access to housing.&nbsp; They should have access to whatever they qualify based on their income.&nbsp; And we should, in prisons as well, be training people differently.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the mi- &#8212; the big thing here is: We have to deal with the idea of addiction by providing for what we all know &#8212; it’s a disease of the brain.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s a disease of the brain and has to be treated as such.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s &#8212; I think addiction and mental health issues have to be dealt with, just as if you break your arm and go to the doctor.&nbsp; We should be able to talk.&nbsp; There should be &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I agree.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; &#8212; there shouldn&#8217;t be a stigma about it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to bring in now Madeena Nolan.&nbsp; Madeena Nolan is a writer and editor.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a Democrat.<br>&nbsp;<br>Madeena, what&#8217;s your question?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hi, Madeena.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good evening, Mr. President.&nbsp; Vice President Harris said to Guatemalans, “Don&#8217;t come.”&nbsp; Recently, you have indicated you are in favor of refugees coming to this country.&nbsp; Could you please explain your administration&#8217;s basic stance on immigration?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; They should not come.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we&#8217;re trying to set up is, in the countries like in &#8212; and particularly in the Northern Triangle &#8212; Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, et cetera &#8212; we are setting up in those countries: If you seek asylum in the United States, you can seek it from the country, from your &#8212; in place.&nbsp; You can seek it from an American embassy.&nbsp; You can go in and seek and see whether or not you qualify.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve significantly increased the number of officers who can hear cases as to whether or not you qualify under the law for being here as a refugee.&nbsp; That is &#8212; that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve done.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thirdly, we have enabled a move, significantly, to change the number &#8212; there were thousands of people in &#8212; in custody with the Border Patrol.&nbsp; It’s now cut by 90 percent, where there &#8212; it’s considerably down.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I &#8212; what I do say is: The one place you may heard that I&#8217;m talking about more immigrants coming in are those folks from Afghanistan who helped the American soldiers, who will be &#8212; they and their family will be victimized very badly as a consequence of what happens if they&#8217;re left behind.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re providing for them to be able to see whether they qualify to meet this special requirement to be able to come to the United States as a refugee and as, ultimately, earning citizenship here.&nbsp; It seems to me it&#8217;s the only decent thing that we can do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the meantime, we&#8217;re going to send people to American bases, where they&#8217;re not going to be able to leave the base while their cases are being determined &#8212; whether they qualify &#8212; and also other bases.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; I want to talk to you about DACA.&nbsp; I got two questions on immigration.&nbsp; They&#8217;re quick questions I want to ask you about.&nbsp; Because just last week, there was a federal judge who ruled the program unlawful, blocked it from accepting new applications.&nbsp; What do you say to DREAMers who are really worried about their futures here in the United States?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not letting this go.&nbsp; Look, guys, let&#8217;s just put it &#8212; (applause) &#8212; let&#8217;s just put this &#8212; you know, we talk about DREAMers sort of generically.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s think about it now, what it really means: You&#8217;re five years old.&nbsp; You&#8217;re nine years old.&nbsp; Your mom or your dad says, “I&#8217;m going to take you across the Rio Grande and we’re going to illegally going to go into the United States.”&nbsp; What are you supposed to say?&nbsp; “Not me.&nbsp; That’s against the law”?&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8211;no, I&#8217;m being &#8212; I&#8217;m being deadly earnest.&nbsp; What can a kid say?&nbsp; What could they do?&nbsp; They come here with really no choice.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re here, and they&#8217;re good, good people.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve done well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Ten thousand of them were first-line workers.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; These are kids who&#8217;ve done well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, what we&#8217;re going to do is, first of all, appeal the case &#8212; number one.&nbsp; But number two, we&#8217;re going to make sure that &#8212; a number of my Republican colleagues say they support the right of DREAMers to come.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s call the question.&nbsp; They should be able to stay in the United States of America when a child comes (inaudible).&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Mr. President, you&#8217;ve been the big guy for six months now in the White House.&nbsp; Can you take us behind the scenes &#8212; something that was extraordinary or unusual that happened that stands out to you?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; “Mr. President, you didn’t close the door.&nbsp; Mr. President, what the hell are you going out at this time for?”&nbsp; You know.&nbsp; (Laughter.) You know, it’s &#8212; it&#8217;s a wonderful honor.&nbsp; As you can tell, I hope I have very good manners, but I&#8217;m not very hung up on protocol.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I &#8212; and the Secret Service is wonderful.&nbsp; And because things are so &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and because things are so crazy out there, it is very hard to get comfortable like I would ordinarily be.&nbsp; For example, I think all of the &#8212; all the help that&#8217;s there, providing meals and all the rest &#8212; I think they love us.&nbsp; We can say, “Don&#8217;t come in for breakfast.&nbsp; We can get our own breakfast.”&nbsp; Because I like to walk out in my robe and go in.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, no, I’m not &#8212; you think I&#8217;m joking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not.&nbsp; You know what I mean?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so it&#8217;s just a &#8212; you know, the only place I have felt like what the office connotes is when I went to Europe and watched the rest of the heads of state react to me &#8212; not me, because I&#8217;m the President of the United States of America &#8212; the United States of America.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And here&#8217;s what happened: It&#8217;s the first time I ever felt like &#8212; you always hear say “leader of the free world.”&nbsp; Well, I realize, when I&#8217;m sitting across from Putin, who I know, he knows who I am; I know who he is.&nbsp; He knows I mean what I say and can do what I say.&nbsp; He understands.&nbsp; It doesn’t mean he will do it or not do it.&nbsp; But the point is it&#8217;s the first time I&#8217;ve ever felt the notion that I am in the office that is the leader of the free world.&nbsp; And we must be the leader of the free world.&nbsp; If we don&#8217;t do it, nobody good is likely to do it or has the capacity to do it.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I genuinely mean it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it&#8217;s the thing, Don, that is the only time &#8212; and, by the way, the first time I walked downstairs and they played “Hail to the Chief,” I wondered, “Where is he?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, you think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not kidding.&nbsp; You know, I mean &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great tune, isn’t it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s a great tune, but I &#8212; you know, you feel a little self-conscious.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But you think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I am &#8212; I am not at all self-conscious about the power that goes with the office as it relates to resolving issues.&nbsp; These are issues that I&#8217;ve dealt with my whole life.&nbsp; Whether I&#8217;m good or bad, I have more experience coming to the office than anyone who&#8217;s ever held that office.&nbsp; I have done &#8212; I&#8217;ve &#8212; I&#8217;ve been deeply steeped in foreign policy, the justice system, the econo- &#8212; not that I&#8217;m right.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t mean that.&nbsp; But nothing has come before me where I&#8217;ve gone, “Oh, my God, I never &#8212; I never thought…”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, what the difference is &#8212; I used to kid Barack &#8212; he&#8217;s a good friend &#8212; President Obama.&nbsp; And, you know, at one point, I&#8217;d always be the &#8212; I was always the last guy in the room, for real.&nbsp; On every important decision, I got to give my advice.&nbsp; I’d give it all away, but I&#8217;d be the last guy before I walked out.&nbsp; And one day, he thanked me.&nbsp; And I said, “Mr. President, here&#8217;s the deal: I should be paying you, not you me, because I get to give the advice, and then I get to leave.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; The one thing that is real, that is different &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; and I feel comfortable with it &#8212; but is you&#8217;re the last guy in the room.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You decide, “Is the decision I&#8217;m about to make, will that cause war?&nbsp; Will that cause conflict?&nbsp; The decision I&#8217;m about to make, is that going to hurt people?&nbsp; Is it going to help people?”&nbsp; That&#8217;s the part that is different.<br>&nbsp;<br>But the living conditions, I mean, it&#8217;s such a great, great honor to live in the White House.&nbsp; But, quite frankly &#8212; I kid the Vice President &#8212; like, one day, Barack came over to NAVOBS &#8212; it’s called Naval Operations [sic] &#8212; the Vice President&#8217;s Residence &#8212; which is on about, I guess, 80, 90 acres.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a beautiful, beautiful spot.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a fence around the whole property.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; I bet you miss that, don’t you?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And Barack came over and he said, “This is great.”&nbsp; And I said, “I’ll tell you…”&nbsp; And I said, “Trade you only if the power goes with it.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the point is that, there, it was totally different.&nbsp; You could walk out in your shorts &#8212; with a short-sleeve shirt on, and you can walk around and there wasn’t anybody there.&nbsp; You can&#8217;t walk out anywhere now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not complaining.&nbsp; I&#8217;m trying to answer your question as honestly as I can.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I just &#8212; it&#8217;s the greatest honor, I think, could ever be bestowed on an American that a majority of American citizens said, “I want you to lead the country.”&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a great honor &#8212; a great honor when you have presidents and prime ministers and the rest of the world saying, “You know, what does the United States think?”&nbsp; You&#8217;re the leader of the free world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I was able to go to the G7 and change their mind about a whole range of things.&nbsp; They never once had included China in any criticism on what was going on.&nbsp; They&#8217;re very reluctant to be able to be in a position &#8212; you and I have talked about this &#8212; about whether or not they&#8217;re going to do business with China in a way that, you know, pushes America aside.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All of a sudden, if you notice, we&#8217;re getting a great deal &#8212; not because of me, but because of the administration I put together.&nbsp; And America is back; traditional America is more back.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re willing to follow us, I think.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, Mr. President &#8212; Mr. President, here&#8217;s the deal.&nbsp; Mr. President, here&#8217;s the deal: I&#8217;m the last guy that gets to ask you questions tonight.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Uh-oh.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And then I get to leave.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thanks, man.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; I appreciate it.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. LEMON:&nbsp; We’re so glad that you guys are here and that you got to ask questions to the President of the United States.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you to our audience, for everyone, for being here taking questions.&nbsp; Of course, thank you to the President of the United States.&nbsp; And we want to thank Mount St. Joseph University right here in Cincinnati, Ohio &#8212; right? &#8212; (applause) &#8212; for housing us.<br>&nbsp;<br>9:19 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the Second White House Eviction Prevention Convening</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/21/readout-of-the-second-white-house-eviction-prevention-convening/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 23:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House hosted a second virtual convening to help cities quickly deliver emergency rental assistance and develop plans to prevent evictions. The convening highlighted actions taken by cities since the first summit on June 30th and is part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s broader efforts to ensure state and local governments disburse the more&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House hosted a second virtual convening to help cities quickly deliver emergency rental assistance and develop plans to prevent evictions. The convening highlighted actions taken by cities since the first summit on June 30<sup>th</sup> and is part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/">broader efforts</a> to ensure state and local governments disburse the more than $46 billion dollars in Emergency Rental Assistance (ERA) made available to them to assist households in need. Today, Treasury released <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0284">new data</a> on the ERA program, which showed that more than $1.5 billion in assistance was delivered to eligible households in the month of June—more than what was provided in the previous three reporting periods combined. The number of households served in June grew by about 85 percent over the previous month and nearly tripled since April.</p>



<p>White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling opened today’s convening, reaffirming the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to do everything it can to make sure cities and states provide relief to renters and landlords as the CDC’s eviction moratorium comes to an end on July 31st. Sperling stressed that the Administration has provided new flexibilities to get emergency rental assistance out and that this is the time for state and local officials to step up and not hide behind being overly cautious or conservative. Officials from the Department of Treasury then shared best practices and responded to frequently asked questions about the ERA program and updated guidance. Speakers from across the country discussed case studies and best practices on topics such as culturally and linguistically relevant outreach and ways to improve the delivery of rental assistance programs. The convening also featured panels focused on how mayors, judges, and philanthropy can champion local efforts to prevent evictions, as well as strategies for community and landlord engagement.</p>



<p>Today’s convening builds upon the June 30<sup>th</sup> <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/readout-of-the-white-house-eviction-prevention-summit/">White House Eviction Prevention Summit</a> which brought together teams from 46 cities to commit to take swift action to prevent evictions in their jurisdictions.</p>



<p>Public officials speaking at the second convening included:</p>



<ul><li>Mayor Tom Barrett, City of Milwaukee</li><li>Mayor Greg Fischer, City of Louisville</li><li>Judge Brendan Murphy, Chief Magistrate, Cobb County (GA)</li><li>Judge Rachel L. Bell, Presiding Judge, General Sessions Court, Division VII, Davidson County (TN)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki Aboard Air Force One En Route Cincinnati, OH</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/21/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-cincinnati-oh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 22:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24701</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3:40 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Welcome to our trip to Cincinnati, Ohio &#8212; also known as the birthplace of my husband.&#160; So, a special place in my heart.&#160;A couple of announcements for you at the top:&#160;Today, Treasury released new data on the Emergency Rental Assistance Program, which showed that more than $1.5 billion in assistance was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>3:40 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Welcome to our trip to Cincinnati, Ohio &#8212; also known as the birthplace of my husband.&nbsp; So, a special place in my heart.<br>&nbsp;<br>A couple of announcements for you at the top:<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, Treasury released new data on the Emergency Rental Assistance Program, which showed that more than $1.5 billion in assistance was delivered to eligible households in the month of June &#8212; more than what was provided in the previous three reporting periods combined.&nbsp; The number of households served in June grew by about 85 percent over the previous month and nearly tripled since April.<br>&nbsp;<br>The data demonstrates that the administration has heard from states and localities over the past months that ERA is helping develop a new national infrastructure for rental assistance and eviction prevention that did not previously exist.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that also today, as a part of this effort, the White House is hosting a second virtual convening on eviction prevention with over 2,000 participants from cities and states across the country, including the 46 cities that were the focus of the first summit on January 30th.&nbsp; That is virtual; everyone can tune in.<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, on August 25th, the President and members of his national security team and across the administration will hold a meeting with private sector leaders to discuss how we work together to collectively improve the nation&#8217;s cybersecurity.&nbsp; So that is a continuation of his effort to work in close partnership with the private sector.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, I also wanted to note that, according to a new report from Moody&#8217;s this morning, the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and Build Back Better agenda will add almost 2 million jobs per year, on average, across the whole decade while accelerating America&#8217;s path to full employment and increasing labor force participation.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Moody&#8217;s report also confirms that the &#8212; what the President said on Monday: that these sorts of investments in making our economy more productive will keep prices stable and decrease inflationary pressure.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, where should we start?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions off the top, on the debt limit.&nbsp; Mitch McConnell said today that Democrats should basically pass a hike in the debt limit on their own; that Republicans would not vote for that.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House response?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And does the White House believe that Democrats should pass a standalone debt limit hike and sort of leave it up to Republicans?&nbsp; Or would you be open to including it in a reconciliation bill, or eliminating the debt limit altogether?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we expect Congress to act in a timely manner to raise or suspend the debt ceiling as they did three times on a broad bipartisan basis during the last administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you all know, raising or suspending the debt ceiling does not authorize new spending; it merely allows Treasury to meet obligations that Congresses have already approved.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that Republicans raised the debt ceiling throughout the Trump administration, including after putting exorbitant deficit and debt &#8212; debt-hoaking [sic] tax breaks &#8212; debt-hiking &#8212; sorry &#8212; tax breaks for the wealthiest Americans and big corporations on the country&#8217;s credit card.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what we expect them to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;To follow up on a part that Alex just asked about at the end: Would the administration be open to, whether now or in the coming weeks and months, talking about fully eliminating the debt ceiling so that we don&#8217;t have these crises &#8212; crisis moments every so often?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not making a projection of that.&nbsp; We are fully expecting Congress will raise the debt ceiling as they have numerous times over the last couple of years.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you want it to continue to exist?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick question on travel restrictions.&nbsp; The airlines have been lobbying the administration to ease travel restrictions on European travel.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the status of those conversations?&nbsp; Are you moving closer to that point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are ongoing discussions between the working groups and, of course, updates and briefings with our health and medical experts about when it is safe to do that.&nbsp; We will be guided by the science.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have any prediction of what the timeline looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said a few days ago that he would have something more to say within a few days on the travel restrictions.&nbsp; Can you at least give us a sense of the timing for when you think there may be some easing or loosening?&nbsp; Or is it &#8212; is the upsurge in Delta variants, in cases involving Delta, pushing that off?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He gets regular updates from his COVID team; that&#8217;s what he was referring to.&nbsp; But he is going to be guided by their recommendations on when we should ease travel restrictions, which are based on a range of criteria.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on Nord Stream.&nbsp; So, today there&#8217;s been announcements about an agreement reached with Germany.&nbsp; There were lots of signals about this already last week.&nbsp; There&#8217;s widespread criticism of this among Republican lawmakers who feel that the administration isn&#8217;t actually acting on the laws that they have passed &#8212; that have been passed by Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Are you &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what way?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because of the waiving of the sanctions.&nbsp; But then there are other sanctions or other laws that haven&#8217;t &#8212; where sanctions haven&#8217;t been fully implemented.&nbsp; Are you concerned that you may be sending a wrong signal to Russia about this pipeline?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say on part of your question: We&#8217;re committed to following the law and continuing to examine entities that have engaged in potentially-sanctioning behavior, as would be abiding by the law.&nbsp; That has not changed.<br>&nbsp;<br>This announcement today follows, of course, the meeting the President had with Chancellor Merkel last week, where they said that they would be asking their teams to look at practical measures we could take together to address what our root issues are here, which we have voiced many times in the past.<br>&nbsp;<br>So even though the pipeline was 90 percent built when the President took office, what our objective is, is to prevent or reduce the geopolitical impact that it was going to have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I know these have been announced; I think a lot of you are following them.&nbsp; But for the purpose of the full context, these measures, in our view, represent a significant impact by Germany, supported by the United States, to push back against the Kremlin&#8217;s harmful activities and to advance a more secure and sustainable energy future for Ukraine and other frontline NATO and EU countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, yes, it was 90 percent built.&nbsp; We feel confident about the impact of these measures.&nbsp; And, of course, we&#8217;ll continue to abide by the law, which includes using sanction authority as needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say how much U.S. money will flow into this billion-dollar Green Fund for Ukraine energy independence?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question, Andrea.&nbsp; Let me &#8212; it&#8217;s really a State Department announcement that we&#8217;re making today.&nbsp; I’ll see if there&#8217;s more details I can get back to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quickly, I have a follow-up on Nord Stream.&nbsp; Is the Zelenskyy visit a part of that deal in terms of, you know, giving them a visit as part of the concessions to Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; They&#8217;re unrelated.&nbsp; We have long been in touch with the Ukrainians about scheduling a visit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one other thing on the borders, please.&nbsp; The reports today that DHS has extended the restrictions on the Canadian and the Mexican border: Can you give any explanation as to why, especially given the recent announcement from Canada about vaccinated travelers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We rely on the health &#8212; the guidance of our health and medical experts, not on the actions of other countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the White House &#8212; is there concern, though, about repercussions about, like, easing restrictions at one border and not the other?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We created these working groups so that we could have an open line of communication about what the criteria looked like, what measures needed to be met.&nbsp; Those are ongoing, and, of course, we are continuing to be briefed internally as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you say something about infrastructure and, sort of, the progress on the Hill and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you know, the Republicans, potentially this group of 10 or 11 lawmakers, supporting a vote next week to move forward on the bill? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, kind of related to that, on reconciliation: It seems like the Democrats in the Senate are still a far way off from a real agreement on that.&nbsp; Would you be concerned if that gets pushed later into August, into September, and this whole process continues to drag on?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the President is enormously grateful to the work of Republican senators who have poured so much good work &#8212; and Democratic senators, of course &#8212; and vision into the bipartisan infrastructure deal; is eager to deliver these economic benefits that Americans in red states and blue states have deserved for so long.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we certainly &#8212; we were encouraged to see the comments of Senator Romney this morning, and we understand this is a legislative process, and it&#8217;s ongoing.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the reconciliation process, of course, we&#8217;re working in close coordination with Leader Schumer.&nbsp; We are grateful to his efforts.&nbsp; He has conveyed his interest in moving this forward in July, and we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re looking forward to supporting that effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the infrastructure, what &#8212; to the Republicans&#8217; criticism about the shell bill vote that&#8217;s being held today: Essentially, what is the harm in waiting until Monday, like the GOP negotiators on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework wish to do?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first note that this is just a vote on a motion to proceed, so a motion to debate.&nbsp; This is not a vote on a final package.&nbsp; And this is the same procedure that the Senate used as it related to the AAPI Hate Crimes bill and as it related to a number of pieces of legislation already this Congress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it is par for the course and normal operations up there on the Senate side.&nbsp; This is merely a motion to proceed, and certainly we were encouraged, again, by Senator Romney&#8217;s comments this morning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And sticking with some Congress news here, the select committee for January 6: The White House statement that was released just before we took off &#8212; among the things that was listed in this statement was that they&#8217;re confident in Speaker Pelosi&#8217;s ability to proceed with an investigation that is full, investigative, and transparent.&nbsp; The word &#8220;bipartisan&#8221; was not included in there.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering, is the White House disappointed that Speaker Pelosi&#8217;s investigation, as it will proceed, will be technically bipartisan because of Liz Cheney&#8217;s involvement, but not truly bipartisan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, we stated at the time our disappointment that there wasn&#8217;t bipartisan support for a select committee when there was an opportunity to vote for that.&nbsp; And we also have long stated our support for Speaker Pelosi in getting to the bottom of what happened on January 6 &#8212; a dark day in our democracy &#8212; and we support her efforts for moving forward on that initiative.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Jen, are you concerned that no matter what product comes from Speaker Pelosi&#8217;s investigation or Leader McCarthy&#8217;s separate investigation &#8212; that no matter what comes of it, the result is always going to be perceived as partisan, based on what happened today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think many Americans across the country, regardless of their political affiliation, look at the events of January 6 as a dark day in our democracy.&nbsp; The President strongly supports taking steps to get to the bottom of what happened so we can prevent it from happening in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the visit to Ohio today, the White House put out a comprehensive list of what it says it&#8217;s going to be doing for the people of Ohio, but notable in the absence in that list was anything about fentanyl, the opioid epidemic.&nbsp; Has that been deprioritized?&nbsp; Where &#8212; is it still a priority?&nbsp; And what do you say to the people of Ohio and the country with &#8212; there&#8217;s still a plateau and tens of thousands of people dying?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely, it&#8217;s a top priority, and there&#8217;s no question it is an issue that has impacted people across Ohio and continues to.&nbsp; Any health expert will tell you that the most important thing we could do is make sure people have access to healthcare coverage.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the President has taken a number of steps to ensure more people have access to, including opening up the Special Enrollment Period, including pushing for tax cuts to incentivize more people to get access to healthcare.&nbsp; That is the best way, but certainly this remains a priority and will continue to be and he may even talk about it today in the town hall.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see what questions come up.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another question on behalf of the radio pool: Are you encouraged by the shift in messaging by Republicans and Fox News now overtly talking positively about vaccines?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to designate it around one individual or one network or one social media platform.&nbsp; I will say that our view is that we are at war with the virus; we are not at war with a social media platform or with a network.&nbsp; And so anyone who goes out there and shares accurate information about the effectiveness of the vaccine, about the fact that it can save lives, is a positive step in our view, and hopefully it continues.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I ask you another question on inflation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The signs seem to be &#8212; there was a &#8212; there was a hope, I think, that the prices would peak over the summer months.&nbsp; Now it looks like that may continue and slip into the fall.&nbsp; Are you concerned by this sort of sustained, you know, increase in prices and this sort of &#8212; like the fact that it&#8217;s not coming down, or there are no indications yet?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we take inflation very seriously.&nbsp; Obviously, it&#8217;s the purview of the Federal Reserve, and I would point you to their projections about inflation coming down in 2022.&nbsp; That&#8217;s also in line with a number of outside economists.&nbsp; But we do take it incredibly seriously.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that there are a number of impacts, including the economy turning back on; steps that we&#8217;re taking in addition to getting more money in the hands of the American people, including the Child Tax Credit that just started going out a few weeks ago, to make sure they have extra assistance in this time, even as we&#8217;re seeing prices go back up, some to pre-pandemic levels.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also working to get important initiatives across the finish line.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would, again, return to where I started, which was the Moody&#8217;s analysis that conveyed that this would help address inflation in the future by providing more supply out there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A COVID question, Jen.&nbsp; If Axios hadn’t learned about the positive case at the White House, would the White House have informed the public about it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me give you a little bit of an update here.&nbsp; One moment.&nbsp; I just want to do this completely accurately.&nbsp; Sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And sort of related to that, just &#8212; you know, is &#8212; are there any discussions happening within the White House about potentially, you know, direct- &#8212; or encouraging, if not requiring, mask wearing again on the White House grounds or anything like that?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen &#8212; I think people are, on the Hill and at the White House, are wearing masks a little bit more today than they might have been a week ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say on that: We abide by public health guidance by the CDC.&nbsp; The CDC guidelines currently are: If you are vaccinated, you do not need to wear a mask.&nbsp; If you are not vaccinated, you should wear a mask.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the guidelines we continue to give to members of the White House staff.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, if individuals decide to wear masks for whatever reason, we support that, and that&#8217;s their personal choice &#8212; and individuals do for a variety of reasons.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let me just give you a little bit of an update to some of the questions that were asked yesterday.&nbsp; There are approximately 2,000 people on the White House campus each day.&nbsp; So, statistically speaking, COVID cases among vaccinated people will occur, just like they occur across the country.&nbsp; They have occurred; they will continue to occur.&nbsp; We&#8217;re prepared for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as the instance yesterday shows, cases in vaccinated individuals are typically mild or asymptomatic.&nbsp; There&#8217;s &#8212; this is more &#8212; this is one more reminder of the efficacy of the COVID-19 vaccines against severe illness or hospitalization.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because of our commitment to transparency, what we&#8217;re going to be providing are up- &#8212; moving forward &#8212; are updates on any White House official who tests positive for COVID-19 that the White House medical unit deems as having had close contact with the President, Vice President, First Lady, or Second Gentleman.&nbsp; That will up to &#8212; be up to the White House medical unit, based on the criteria of the CDC.&nbsp; And this criteria, again, is up to the CDC.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At no point has the President been required to change his behavior or self-quarantine due to a close contact with an individual who tested positive for COVID.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that, today, an email from our COVID-19 operations protocol team has been sent to White House staff informing them of the official policy that if you are in close contact with a principal and test positive for COVID-19, your case will be disclosed to press, along with any other relevant details, and that we will share the name of the staffer if that individual agrees to do so.&nbsp; Of course, we respect their privacy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, that is our policy moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask one follow-up on that?&nbsp; For July 4th, anyone coming to the White House lawn who was not vaccinated was asked to wear a mask.&nbsp; Should we take that policy to mean that the athletes who were unmasked at the White House yesterday were all vaccinated?&nbsp; Was that confirmed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The policy that we continue to convey with public events is the CDC policy: If you are vaccinated, you don&#8217;t need to wear a mask.&nbsp; If you are not vaccinated, you should wear a mask.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that the same for outdoors, though?&nbsp; You&#8217;re saying, outdoors, if you are unvaccinated, you need to be wearing a mask if you&#8217;re at the White House?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is &#8212; we &#8212; our guidelines are not different from what CDC guidelines are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What guidance is the First Lady following as she heads to Tokyo for the Olympics?&nbsp; And is there still confidence that she&#8217;ll be kept safe, as we&#8217;re seeing some breakout infections?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah &#8212; so, I would say: One, we have consulted. &nbsp;The First Lady is on her way &#8212; proceeding to Tokyo &#8212; and that has been done in consultation with, of course, our White House medical unit, with staff about what protocols she and the delegation should abide by.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that while she is leading this delegation &#8212; because it was important to the President and the First Lady that we cheer on our athletes and show support for the United States at the highest level &#8212; it is a delegation of two, and usually it is a much larger delegation.&nbsp; They will have limited public interaction, and they will be taking every precaution throughout the course of their trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say another word about this cybersecurity meeting that you&#8217;re hosting &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; or that the President will host on August 25th?&nbsp; Can you say what private-sector leaders are going to be participating, and whether &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re not quite there yet.&nbsp; Yeah,<br>I mean, it&#8217;s more than a month away.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I understand.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you &#8212; you know, you&#8217;ve had a focal point on ransomware.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;ve been having regular meetings on ransomware.&nbsp; Is that going to be a big focus for that meeting &#8212; ransomware?&nbsp; Or is it, you know, cybersecurity writ large?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re not quite there on the agenda for the meeting.&nbsp; What I would note is that the President felt it was important to use the White House as a forum for bringing together private sector leaders to have a discussion about both how we can work together and also what best practices are, which is including them taking &#8212; hardening their own cybersecurity protections and also what the U.S. government can do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, as you know, there have been ongoing considerations, from a policy perspective, of what we can stake [sic] &#8212; take &#8212; what steps we can take.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you also know from covering this closely, ransomware attacks have increased over the last 18 months.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question it&#8217;s a big issue and factor for private sector companies.&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s no question it will be a part of the agenda at this meeting, but in terms of what the day looks like, we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the Milwaukee Bucks come to the White House?&nbsp; Has the President invited them?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He did tweet about them today &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I saw (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; congratulating them.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we will invite them to the White House.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a scheduled meeting quite yet.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;re celebrating on their own today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About Iraq, if I may: When the Prime Minister comes to the White House, should we expect announcements regarding U.S. troops or maybe a timeline, anything?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ah- &#8212; quite ahead of the meeting.&nbsp; Obviously, it&#8217;s an important meeting to discuss our relationship with Iraq and with the Prime Minister, and certainly our presence on the ground and their role moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the State Department officials who were briefing earlier on the Nord Stream deal made the point that getting this issue off the table with Ukraine will allow a broader discussion of security issues with Ukraine.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a lot of interest, of course, in terms of supporting Ukraine vis-à-vis Russia and its aggression.&nbsp; Are you &#8212; are there any new initiatives that you can talk about in terms of bolstering Ukraine security or the security of the Eastern Flank allies?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a couple of things that were in the package that, I think, will benefit Ukraine, so let me highlight some of those.&nbsp; Germany will help to preserve gas transit revenues for Ukraine and buy time for Ukraine to eliminate its dependence on Russian gas and transit fees, as it has long sought to do, including with U.S. support.&nbsp; Germany will do this by committing to appoint a special envoy to use all its available leverage to negotiate an extension to Ukraine&#8217;s gas transit agreement with Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s no question that the impact, in what we&#8217;re trying to address here, is the impact on the Eastern Flank countries of this pipeline.&nbsp; And so that is part of our effort as we, you know, work to finalize the deal announced today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I mean, the President of Ukraine will be coming here to visit with the President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; at the White House.&nbsp; What &#8212; you know, what is your vision at this point &#8212; I realize it&#8217;s still a month off &#8212; but for that meeting?&nbsp; I mean, what do you hope to get out of that meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re in a position to preview it quite yet.&nbsp; We will, as I &#8212; as we get closer to the meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should the Ukrainians feel a little disappointed about the Nord Stream final decision going through? &nbsp;And they’ve been kind of bracing for it since May, when the U.S. said they would waive sanctions.&nbsp; But given the announcement today of Volodymyr Zelenskyy&#8217;s visit later, based on the decision that&#8217;s coming, do they have a right to feel a little disappointed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think, again, part of the objective here, as the President said last week, was to work to address the geopolitical impact of this pipeline &#8212; a pipeline that was 90 percent built when the President took office.&nbsp; And Ukraine and the impact on their energy security is certainly part of that, and there are initiatives in this that help to address that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just something quickly on &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the statement that came in from the bipartisan group of lawmakers working on the infrastructure deal: They say that they&#8217;ve made significant progress and are close to a final agreement.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you were aware of that before you came back here, or if there&#8217;s anything else, sort of, on the progress here beyond what you said before.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That certainly is a positive sign.&nbsp; I will check more on that and see if there&#8217;s more to report from our end.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve been encouraged and grateful &#8212; encouraged by the progress and grateful to the work of both the Democrats and Republicans involved.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there going to be ice cream in Cincinnati?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Graeter&#8217;s ice cream?&nbsp; Raspberry chip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don’t think so, but we&#8217;ll have to &#8212; I don’t know.<br>&nbsp;<br>(Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now I really want &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;s aware of it.<br>&nbsp;<br>4:03 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White House Releases Policy for Contacts with Agencies and Departments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/21/white-house-releases-policy-for-contacts-with-agencies-and-departments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House sent the Senate and House Judiciary Committees our policy on contacts between the White House and agencies and departments, and the Department of Justice formally updated their policy on contacts with the White House. These policies reaffirm President Biden’s commitment to restoring faith in institutions of government and the independent role of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House sent the Senate and House Judiciary Committees our policy on contacts between the White House and agencies and departments, and the Department of Justice formally updated their policy on contacts with the White House. These policies reaffirm President Biden’s commitment to restoring faith in institutions of government and the independent role of the Department of Justice in law enforcement matters.</p>



<p>Read the White House’s policy here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/White-House-Policy-for-Contacts-with-Agencies-and-Departments.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/White-House-Policy-for-Contacts-with-Agencies-and-Departments.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
