<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 14:34:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces Additional Actions in Response to Vice President Harris’s Call to Action on Maternal&#160;Health</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/13/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-additional-actions-in-response-to-vice-president-harriss-call-to-action-on-maternal-health/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 14:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris to Host First-Ever Meeting with Cabinet Officials on Maternal Health On Wednesday, April 13, 2022, during Black Maternal Health Week, Vice President Kamala Harris will convene a meeting with Cabinet Secretaries and agency leaders to discuss the Administration’s whole-of-government approach to addressing maternal mortality and morbidity. The Vice President will convene leaders&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris to Host First-Ever Meeting with Cabinet Officials on Maternal Health</em></p>



<p>On Wednesday, April 13, 2022, during Black Maternal Health Week, Vice President Kamala Harris will convene a meeting with Cabinet Secretaries and agency leaders to discuss the Administration’s whole-of-government approach to addressing maternal mortality and morbidity. The Vice President will convene leaders across the federal government – including agencies that may not have historically taken a leading role addressing the maternal health crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>In December 2021, Vice President Harris convened the first-ever federal Maternal Health Day of Action, where she announced a historic Call to Action to improve health outcomes for parents and infants in the United States. This resulted in the Administration’s announcement of <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=bdad8be2d8&amp;e=60572324a0">private sector</a> and <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=dd8d87202c&amp;e=60572324a0">public sector</a> investments. Ahead of the meeting with Cabinet officials, the Administration is following up with additional actions to address maternal health, and to combat the systemic inequities that lead to worse maternal outcomes for Black, Native American, and rural women.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>New Announcements:</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>11 Additional States and D.C. Ask to Extend Medicaid and CHIP Coverage to a Full Year After Pregnancy under American Rescue Plan: </strong>The American Rescue Plan is working to make Medicaid and CHIP coverage for 12 months after pregnancy a reality for people across the country.&nbsp;The Vice President called on states to expand their postpartum coverage during her Call to Action in December.<ul><li>The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) has approved Louisiana, Virginia, New Jersey, and Illinois’ extension of Medicaid and CHIP coverage for 12 months after pregnancy on or before April 1, 2022. CMS is also working with another eleven states and the District of Columbia to extend postpartum coverage for a full year after pregnancy, including: California, Indiana, Kentucky, Maine, Michigan, Minnesota, Oregon, New Mexico, South Carolina, Tennessee, and West Virginia.&nbsp; In addition, a number of other states have announced that they are working to extend Medicaid and CHIP coverage to 12 months after pregnancy, and CMS looks forward to working with those states.</li><li>In order to receive federal funds and to ensure consistency with federal standards, including those set by the American Rescue Plan, states must go through a formal process run by CMS. Medicaid covers more than 40 percent of births in the United States, and extending this coverage will bring the peace of mind of health coverage to parents and children during the vulnerable post-partum period.&nbsp;</li><li>Based on HHS estimates, approximately 720,000 people would benefit if all states were to adopt the American Rescue Plan’s new option to extend post-partum Medicaid and CHIP coverage for a full 12 months.</li></ul></li><li><strong>“Birthing-Friendly” Hospital Designation: </strong>CMS is proposing the “Birthing-Friendly” hospital designation to drive improvements in maternal health outcomes and maternal health equity. The “Birthing-Friendly” hospital designation would assist consumers in choosing hospitals that have demonstrated a commitment to maternal health. The Administration announced this new designation during the White House Maternal Health Day of Action Summit.<ul><li>Initially, the designation would be awarded to hospitals based on attestation that the hospital has participated in maternity care quality improvement collaboratives and implemented best practices that advance health care quality, safety, and equity for pregnant and post-partum patients.</li><li>Data will be submitted by hospitals for the first time in May 2022, and CMS will post data for October to December 2021 in fall 2022. Criteria for the designation may be expanded in the future.</li></ul></li><li><strong>Engaging the Health Care Industry to Improve Health Outcomes: </strong>In Summer 2022, CMS will convene health care industry stakeholders – including health care facilities, insurance companies, state officials and providers – to focus on industry commitments to improve health outcomes experienced by pregnant and postpartum people. CMS and experts will share best practices and commitments and request that health care industry leaders make commitments to advance maternal health.</li><li><strong>Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting (MIECHV) Programs:</strong> The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), through the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), announced approximately $16 million to strengthen Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting (MIECHV) Programs through seven awards supporting eight states.<ul><li>These awards will advance data and technology innovations to support positive maternal and child health outcomes in states and communities, and focus on addressing health disparities.</li></ul></li><li><strong>State Maternal Health Innovation and Implementation (State MHI) Program:</strong> State MHI supports state-level development and implementation of proven strategies to improve maternal health and address maternal health disparities. The new funding, $9 million, will continue to build state capacity to deliver high-quality maternity care services and provide training for maternal care clinicians. It also adds a component to enhance the quality of state-level maternal health data through better collection, reporting and analysis.&nbsp;The program will fund up to nine cooperative agreements, and each will receive up to $1 million over five years.</li><li><strong>Maternal Health Best Practices: </strong>HHS, through the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), is also, on telehealth.hhs.gov, posting a new Maternal Health Best Practice Guide for providers to incorporate telehealth for prenatal and postpartum care, and monitoring within high-risk pregnancy. Through remote patient monitoring, screening and treatment for postpartum depression, and lactation consulting, maternal telehealth can help reduce barriers to access to critical care for mothers before, during and after a pregnancy.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Previous Actions Announced since the Vice President’s Call to Action in December</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Investing in Doulas:</strong> HHS <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=4a82af5246&amp;e=60572324a0">announced</a> the availability of $4.5 million for hiring, training, certifying, and compensating community-based doulas in areas with high rates of adverse maternal and infant health outcomes, doubling the number of Healthy Start doula programs nationwide.</li><li><strong>Title X</strong>: HHS <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=014e3bb105&amp;e=60572324a0">restored</a> access to Title X family planning services nationwide to fill service gaps caused by more than a quarter of Title X providers withdrawing from the program over the past two and a half years in response to the previous administration’s Title X rule. HHS awarded $256.6 million in grant funding to support 76 grantees to deliver equitable, affordable, client-centered, and high-quality family planning services.</li><li><strong>FY23 Budget Request</strong>: The President’s budget includes $470  million to: reduce maternal mortality and morbidity rates; expand maternal health initiatives in rural communities; implement implicit bias training for healthcare providers; create pregnancy medical home demonstration projects; and address the highest rates of perinatal health disparities, including by supporting the perinatal health workforce.</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Additional Background</span></strong></p>



<ul><li>As Vice President, Kamala Harris has worked closely with President Biden and other leaders in the Administration to improve outcomes for Black women and their families.<ul><li>The White House released a Presidential Proclamation to mark Black Maternal Health Week in <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=1dc908d34d&amp;e=60572324a0">2021</a> and <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=ce11247eb4&amp;e=60572324a0">2022</a>.</li><li>In December 2021, the Vice President led a <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=eb284fc1e0&amp;e=60572324a0">Maternal Health Day of Action Summit</a>, noting the urgent need to address this crisis.<ul><li>At the Summit, the Vice President <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=9726cc666b&amp;e=60572324a0">announced</a> guidance to help states provide 12 months of continuous postpartum coverage through their Medicaid programs, up from 60 days; a new HHS report showing the impact of state extensions of Medicaid postpartum coverage to 12 months; and CMS’s plan to propose the establishment of a “Birthing-Friendly” hospital designation. She also <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=a49560e7f1&amp;e=60572324a0">announced</a>&nbsp;that more than 20 companies and nonprofits have pledged to invest over $150 million and take other critical actions to address the maternal health crisis.</li></ul></li><li>In April 2021, the Vice President hosted a roundtable on Black Maternal Health with Domestic Policy Advisor Ambassador Susan Rice. She was joined by women who shared their experiences with complications from pregnancy, childbirth, and postpartum as well as their work in advocacy and research, highlighting the disparities that Black women face in maternal health.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li>The Omnibus spending bill passed in March and signed by the President includes both the Maternal Health Quality Improvement Act and an expansion of the Rural Maternal and Obstetric Modernization of Services (Rural MOMS) program.&nbsp;<ul><li>These foundational bills authorize and improve programs to address the maternal mortality crisis in this country and build on current funding at the Centers for Disease Control &amp; Prevention (CDC) and Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) to reduce maternal morbidity and mortality.</li></ul></li><li>Last fall, the Administration released the first-ever <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=dc85326b3a&amp;e=60572324a0">National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality</a>, which includes its vision to strengthen health care and&nbsp; women’ health, including through addressing the maternal mortality crisis in the United States and abroad.</li><li>As a Senator, Vice President Harris was a champion on the issue of maternal health. She brought racial disparities in maternal mortality, particularly for Black women, to the forefront legislatively, increasing awareness among her colleagues and leading to a broader discussion of racial disparities across other health issues.<ul><li>She convened roundtables, lifted up local organizations that are focused on the issue, and ensured that initiatives on maternal health included references to racial disparities and relevant solutions.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p>She introduced several bills in the Senate specifically targeted to addressing racial disparities in maternal mortality, including the Maternal CARE Act and the Black Maternal Health Momnibus Act.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency With Respect to Specified Harmful Foreign Activities of the Government of the Russian&#160;Federation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/13/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-specified-harmful-foreign-activities-of-the-government-o/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 14:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50992</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1662(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1662(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date. &nbsp;In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation declared in Executive Order 14024 of April 15, 2021, which was expanded in scope in Executive Order 14066 of March 8, 2022, and with respect to which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 14039 of August 20, 2021, Executive Order 14068 of March 11, 2022, and Executive Order 14071 of April 6, 2022, is to continue in effect beyond April 15, 2022.</p>



<p>Specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation &#8212; in particular, efforts to undermine the conduct of free and fair democratic elections and democratic institutions in the United States and its allies and partners; to engage in and facilitate malicious cyber-enabled activities against the United States and its allies and partners; to foster and use transnational corruption to influence foreign governments; to pursue extraterritorial activities targeting dissidents or journalists; to undermine security in countries and regions important to United States national security; and to violate well-established principles of international law, including respect for the territorial integrity of states &#8212; continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States. &nbsp;Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024 with respect to specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation Of The National Emergency With Respect To Specified Harmful Foreign Activities Of The Government Of The Russian&#160;Federation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/13/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-specified-harmful-foreign-activities-of-the-government-of-the-russian-federation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 13:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 15, 2021, by Executive Order 14024, I declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 15, 2021, by Executive Order 14024, I declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation. &nbsp;On March 8, 2022, I issued Executive Order 14066 to expand the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024. &nbsp;On August 20, 2021, March 11, 2022, and April 6, 2022, I issued Executive Orders 14039, 14068, and 14071, respectively, to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024.</p>



<p>Specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation &#8212; in particular, efforts to undermine the conduct of free and fair democratic elections and democratic institutions in the United States and its allies and partners; to engage in and facilitate malicious cyber-enabled activities against the United States and its allies and partners; to foster and use transnational corruption to influence foreign governments; to pursue extraterritorial activities targeting dissidents or journalists; to undermine security in countries and regions important to United States national security; and to violate well-established principles of international law, including respect for the territorial integrity of states &#8212; continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States. &nbsp;For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024, which was expanded in scope by Executive Order 14066, and with respect to which additional steps were taken in Executive Orders 14039, 14068, and 14071, must continue in effect beyond April 15, 2022.</p>



<p>Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;14024.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; April 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Impact of Texas Border&#160;Delays</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/13/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-impact-of-texas-border-delays/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Governor Abbott’s unnecessary and redundant inspections of trucks transiting ports of entry between Texas and Mexico are causing significant disruptions to the food and automobile supply chains, delaying manufacturing, impacting jobs, and raising prices for families in Texas and across the country. Local businesses and trade associations are calling on Governor Abbott to reverse this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Governor Abbott’s unnecessary and redundant inspections of trucks transiting ports of entry between Texas and Mexico are causing significant disruptions to the food and automobile supply chains, delaying manufacturing, impacting jobs, and raising prices for families in Texas and across the country. Local businesses and trade associations are calling on Governor Abbott to reverse this decision because trucks are facing lengthy delays exceeding 5 hours at some border crossings and commercial traffic has dropped by as much as 60 percent.  The continuous flow of legitimate trade and travel and CBP’s ability to do its job should not be obstructed. Governor Abbott’s actions are impacting people’s jobs, and the livelihoods of hardworking American families. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Sixteenth Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/13/president-biden-names-sixteenth-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 12:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50984</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing five new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country —&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing five new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.<br><br>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.<br><br>For example, the slate includes:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>A nominee who would be the first Asian American judge to ever serve on the Seventh Circuit.</li><li>A nominee who would be the first Hispanic judge to ever serve on the Ninth Circuit from Washington State.</li><li>A nominee who would be the first Hispanic woman to ever serve as a federal judge in the state of Illinois.</li><li>A nominee who would be would be the only judge of color currently serving on the U.S. District Court for the District of Delaware, and the second African American judge to ever serve on the District of Delaware.</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s sixteenth round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his fourth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 90.</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies. And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Circuit Court</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Judge John Z. Lee: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit</strong><br><br>Judge John Z. Lee has served as a U.S. District Court Judge for the Northern District of Illinois since 2012. From 1999 to 2012, Judge Lee was an associate and then partner at Freeborn &amp; Peters LLP in Chicago. From 1996 to 1999, Judge Lee was an associate at Grippo &amp; Elden LLC, and from 1994 to 1996, he was an associate at Mayer Brown LLP. Mr. Lee served as a trial attorney in the Environmental and Natural Resources Division of the U.S. Department of Justice from 1992 to 1994.<br><br>Judge Lee received his A.B., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from Harvard College in 1989, and his J.D. from Harvard Law School, <em>cum laude</em>, in 1992.<br><br><strong>Judge Salvador Mendoza, Jr.: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit<br></strong><br>Judge Salvador Mendoza, Jr. has served as a U.S. District Court Judge for the Eastern District of Washington since 2014. Judge Mendoza previously served as a Washington State Superior Court Judge from 2013 to 2014. From 1999 to 2013, Judge Mendoza was a solo practitioner then president of a small law firm in Eastern Washington, and also served as a judge pro tempore on various local courts. From 1998 to 1999, Judge Mendoza served as a Deputy Prosecuting Attorney for the Franklin County Prosecuting Attorney’s Office, and from 1997 to 1998, he was an Assistant Attorney General in the Office of the Washington State Attorney General.<br><br>Judge Mendoza received his J.D. from the University of California, Los Angeles School of Law in 1997, and his B.A. from the University of Washington in 1994.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>District Court</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Judge Stephen Henley Locher: Nominee for the United States District Court for the Southern District of Iowa<br></strong><br>Judge Stephen Henley Locher has served as a U.S. Magistrate Judge for the Southern District of Iowa since 2021. Judge Locher was previously a partner at Belin McCormick, P.C., in Des Moines, Iowa from 2013 to 2021. From 2008 to 2013, Judge Locher was an Assistant U.S. Attorney in the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of Iowa. From 2004 to 2008, Judge Locher was an associate at Goldberg Kohn in Chicago. Judge Locher served as a law clerk for Judge John R. Gibson on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Eighth Circuit from 2003 to 2004.<br><br>Judge Locher received his J.D. from Harvard Law School in 2003, and his B.A. from the University of Notre Dame, <em>magna cum laude</em>, in 2000.<br><br><strong>Nancy L. Maldonado: Nominee for the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois<br></strong><br>Nancy L. Maldonado is a partner at Miner, Barnhill &amp; Galland, P.C. in Chicago, Illinois. Ms. Maldonado joined the firm as an associate in 2003 and was elevated to partner in 2010. Ms. Maldonado previously served as a law clerk for Judge Rubén Castillo on the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of Illinois from 2001 to 2003.<br><br>Ms. Maldonado received her J.D. from Columbia Law School in 2001, and her A.B., <em>cum laude</em>, from Harvard College in 1997.<br><br><strong>Gregory B. Williams: Nominee for the United States District Court for the District of Delaware</strong><br><br>Gregory B. Williams is a partner in the Wilmington, Delaware office of Fox Rothschild LLP. He joined the firm in 1995 as an associate and was elevated to partner in 2003. Mr. Williams has served as a special master in complex civil cases for the District of Delaware since 2020. From 1986 to 1992, Mr. Williams served in the U.S. Army Reserve.<br><br>Mr. Williams received his J.D. from Villanova University School of Law in 1995 and both his B.A. and B.S. from Millersville University of Pennsylvania in 1990.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with President Maia Sandu of&#160;Moldova</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/12/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-president-maia-sandu-of-moldova/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 23:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50978</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with President Maia Sandu of Moldova. Mr. Sullivan expressed appreciation for Moldova’s generosity in welcoming individuals fleeing Russian aggression in neighboring Ukraine. He underscored the U.S. commitment to help Moldova and the region manage the effects of Russia’s brutal war, including $100 million announced earlier this month to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with President Maia Sandu of Moldova. Mr. Sullivan expressed appreciation for Moldova’s generosity in welcoming individuals fleeing Russian aggression in neighboring Ukraine. He underscored the U.S. commitment to help Moldova and the region manage the effects of Russia’s brutal war, including $100 million announced earlier this month to help Moldova meet the needs of refugees as well as additional financial assistance to multilateral institutions supporting Moldova. He expressed strong support for President Sandu’s efforts to build a more democratic and prosperous county. He thanked her for sharing Moldova’s experience countering corruption at last year’s Summit for Democracy and noted continued U.S. support for these reform efforts, including through the recently announced European Democratic Resilience Initiative. Mr. Sullivan and President Sandu welcomed the opportunity to further strengthen bilateral cooperation at the U.S.-Moldova Strategic Dialogue, which will be held in Washington next week.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/12/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Des Moines International AirportDes Moines, Iowa 5:23 P.M. CDT&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, what made you use the word “genocide” today?&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, have you seen enough evidence to declare genocide in Ukraine, sir?&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Yes, I called it genocide.&#160; It has become clearer and clearer that Putin is just trying to wipe out the idea of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Des Moines International Airport<br>Des Moines, Iowa</p>



<p>5:23 P.M. CDT<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what made you use the word “genocide” today?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, have you seen enough evidence to declare genocide in Ukraine, sir?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, I called it genocide.&nbsp; It has become clearer and clearer that Putin is just trying to wipe out the idea of even being &#8212; being able to be Ukrainian.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the amount &#8212; the evidence is mounting.&nbsp; It’s different than it was last week.&nbsp; The &#8212; more evidence is coming out of the &#8212; literally, the horrible things that the Russians have done in Ukraine.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to only learn more and more about the devastation.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ll let the lawyers decide internationally whether or not it qualifies, but it sure seems that way to me.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>5:23 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Administration&#8217;s Historic Commitment to Worker Organizing and&#160;Empowerment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/12/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-administrations-historic-commitment-to-worker-organizing-and-empowerment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 23:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sheet Metal Workers Local 19 JATCPhiladelphia, Pennsylvania THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Can we please give it up for William?&#160; (Applause.)&#160; You know, I was &#8212; I was backstage listening to you, William.&#160; And when I listened to you &#8212; we had a minute to talk earlier &#8212; and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Sheet Metal Workers Local 19 JATC<br><em>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Can we please give it up for William?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I was &#8212; I was backstage listening to you, William.&nbsp; And when I listened to you &#8212; we had a minute to talk earlier &#8212; and I know that you represent the future of the American labor movement.&nbsp; And in that movement, we are strong.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Well, good afternoon, Philadelphia.&nbsp; It’s good to be back.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s good to be back, and it’s good to be here at the Sheet Metal Workers Local 19.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I love being in the house of labor.&nbsp;<br><br>And I will tell you &#8212; I think we all know, William had it exactly right &#8212; being here &#8212; Marty Walsh talked about it &#8212; being here &#8212; well, it’s being with family.&nbsp; It feels like being with family because it is being with family.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to recognize and thank my friend, Liz Shuler, the President of the AFL-CIO, who traveled down with me on Air Force Two.&nbsp; As you all know well, Liz is a fighter.&nbsp; She goes to work<br>every day for the working people of our nation, and she is an essential partner to our administration.<br><br>I know Joe Sellers is here because we were hanging out earlier &#8212; I want to thank him &#8212; the General President of the Sheet Metal Workers International, who got his start right here at Local 19.<br><br>And I know Sean O&#8217;Brien is here, the new General President of the Teamsters.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you each for your tremendous leadership.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Also here with us here are a number of elected officials &#8212; true champions of the labor movement, people I have worked with for years &#8212; leaders like Senator Bob Casey.&nbsp; Thank you, Bob, always.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Congresswoman Mary Gay Scanlon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There she is.&nbsp; And Congressman Dwight Evans.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I want to thank you, Governor, for the warm welcome at the tarmac this morning when I arrived.&nbsp; And thank you for your work.<br><br>And, Mayor Jim Kenney, thank you as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, of course, joining us today, a great, great leader &#8212; before he had the title of “Secretary,” because he’s just been a leader in every position he’s had &#8212; but our Secretary of Labor, Mahrty &#8212; Marty &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; Marty Walsh.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>SECRETARY WALSH:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Mahty!<br><br>You know, over the past year, Secretary Walsh and I have been traveling the country.&nbsp; We’ve been visiting job sites and training facilities and union halls.&nbsp;<br><br>And we’ve actually been on a bit of a traveling roadshow, I should say.&nbsp; And I couldn’t tell you &#8212; I’ve seen Secretary Walsh &#8212; I heard him say this earlier &#8212; but I’ve seen you, Secretary, when the cameras are on, when the sec- &#8212; when the cameras are off.&nbsp; And you are always fighting for the working people of our nation.&nbsp; I thank you for that.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And some of you may have met the Secretary for the first time, but you probably know from hearing him speak: Secretary Walsh &#8212; he grew up in a union household, in a family and in a community that believed in the power of solidarity.<br><br>And, you know, he and I get on quite well.&nbsp; We really do enjoy each other’s company.&nbsp; We’ve developed a real friendship.&nbsp; And, you know, some people might look at us and say, “Well, what could they possibly have in common?”&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I grew up on the other side of the country.&nbsp; But I was raised &#8212; and he and I were raised with the same values.<br><br>My parents met while they were marching for civil rights.&nbsp; They taught me that people can make a difference and that when we use our collective voice, whether at a protest or a picket line, we can drive great change.<br><br>And that belief in the power of solidarity has guided me, him, and all of us our entire lives.&nbsp; And it guides our administration.<br><br>President Joe Biden and I are determined to lead the most pro-union administration in America’s history.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Because you see, we are clear and we know, each and every day in ways big and small, unions change lives.&nbsp; Unions negotiate better wages and safer working conditions for millions of workers around our country.&nbsp;<br><br>And let’s be clear: Even if you are not a member of a union, you thank unions for every benefit that you receive.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank unions for the five-day workweek, for the weekend, for sick leave.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We should all &#8212; anyone who works in America &#8212; know that you have benefited from the hard work, from the fight of the leaders in this movement.&nbsp; Our labor leaders, our unions train people to take on good jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But as you have heard, it’s so much more than a training of a skill.&nbsp; It provides community.&nbsp; It provides home.&nbsp; It provides a place that remembers that nobody should be made to fight alone.&nbsp; It is so fundamental in terms of the approach, which says that we all know we are stronger when we stand together.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That is at the heart of the spirit behind this movement.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Unions create stronger communities.&nbsp; They bring people together.&nbsp; And they, of course, protect workers from things like harassment and discrimination.&nbsp; And they give workers a voice.&nbsp; Put simply, unions move our nation forward.&nbsp; And the American people know it.&nbsp; The American people know that when unions win, workers win, families win, communities win.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; When unions win, America wins &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as evidenced by the fact that, today, unions have their highest approval rating since 1965.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>People know what we’re talking about.&nbsp; They know what we’re talking about.&nbsp; They know, today, as a matter of fact, about half of all non-union workers say they would join a union if given a chance.&nbsp; That is almost 60 million people in our country, nearly 20 percent of our nation.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; Think about it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then that, of course, has to prompt the question: “Well, what’s stopping them?”&nbsp; And we know that part of the answer &#8212; a big part of the answer is that, for decades, powerful forces in our country have been hard at work building barriers to stop workers from organizing.&nbsp; And we all know that we’ve got to then take it on with a powerful counterforce, which is why our administration is working even harder to tear those barriers down.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As Secretary Walsh mentioned, as partners, he and I lead the White House Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment.&nbsp; Last year, our task force proposed nearly 70 actions the executive branch of our government can take to protect and expand the rights of workers to organize and collectively bargain.&nbsp; And the President &#8212; our President, Joe Biden &#8212; accepted every single one.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, as everyone here knows, we also made an historic investment in our nation’s infrastructure.&nbsp; With your help, we passed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br>It will put thousands of union workers, carpenters, and pipefitters, and plumbers, and, yes, sheet metal workers,<br>to work across the country.<br><br>In fact, last week, I met &#8212; in my office in D.C., I met with some longtime friends from the California Building Trades.&nbsp; And one of the leaders told me there that thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, workers will soon be upgrading &#8212; not only in California, but around the country &#8212; for example, the H-VAC systems in local schools.&nbsp; Well, let’s think about what that means.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>As the pandemic &#8212; it, of course, only highlighted the importance of clean air in our schools where our babies, where the children of our nation go to get an education, to reach their God-given capacity.&nbsp; And we know then the connection between these issues because we know that when students breathe clean air, they are healthier, they concentrate better, they learn more.&nbsp; Well, who’s going to do the job of help making that possible?&nbsp; These folks.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, it invests billions of dollars in our nation&#8217;s schools so that we make it safer for our children.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All these issues are connected.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we are fighting not only to create jobs, but to protect our workers.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, as has been mentioned and Liz talked about it, summer, of course, is coming.&nbsp; And the late &#8212; the last, actually, eight years, you all might know, have been the hottest on record.&nbsp; The last eight years have been the hottest on record.&nbsp; And many of the jobs that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law created will require workers to work outdoors, outside, to build back up our nation’s infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that means, during the summer months in particular, they will be working outside in the heat, building bridges, replacing lead pipes, laying broadband wire so that our students can have the benefit of being able to have that resource, knowing that, unlike for some of us, the thing of Encyclopedia Britannica is a thing of a long time ago &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and now the kids need to be online to help get their homework done.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Broadband wire &#8212; why do we care about that?&nbsp; We’re going to lay it across the country because we know that our seniors might need the benefit of telemedicine if it’s too far to get to a hospital.&nbsp; Our small business owners need access to high-speed broadband to run those small businesses that are part of what fuels America’s economy.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But all that work, so much of it will be done by highly skilled workers outside.&nbsp; So it’s a real issue.<br><br>And then, there are other jobs created by the Infrastructure Law that will require workers to be indoors &#8212;<br>in steel mills and on factory floors &#8212; where temperatures can climb high enough to give workers heatstroke.<br><br>And as many of you know then, this high heat is dangerous and can be dangerous when it is there, in their workplace &#8212; even deadly.<br><br>And every year, thousands of workers suffer heat-related<br>injury and illnesses.&nbsp; The danger posed by extreme heat has been ignored and overlooked for far too long.&nbsp; And that danger is only increasing.<br><br>Because as we know, climate change has become a climate crisis.&nbsp; By 2030, this very city can expect 25 days a year with heat and humidity that will make it feel like 105 degrees or hotter.&nbsp; Think about that.<br><br>So, let’s be clear: Heat is a workplace safety issue.&nbsp; It turns out outdoor heat, indoor heat presents a workplace safety issue.&nbsp; And employers are responsible for protecting their workers in the workplace from the dangers of heat, including<br>in farm fields, in delivery vans, and in nursing homes &#8212; (applause) &#8212; everywhere that has workers.<br><br>So, our administration is fighting to make sure<br>every workplace is protected.<br><br>Now, I’m making an obvious point clear.&nbsp; Some people who don’t understand need to understand that the workplace to get the jobs done that’ll make life easier for most people in our country, that workplace is not necessarily an office with air conditioning.&nbsp; But it is a workplace nonetheless where highly skilled workers work.&nbsp; And that is how we are approaching this issue.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, I know you heard, when I served in the United States Senate with Bob Casey, I introduced a bill to create a federal heat standard to protect workers.&nbsp; We named it after a farmworker who lost his life after picking grapes for 10 hours in 105-degree heat.<br><br>And I’m proud that last fall, OSHA &#8212; the Occupational Safety and Health Administration &#8212; took the first step toward creating such a standard.&nbsp; But we cannot wait for that rule to be finalized to protect our workers.<br><br>So, today, OSHA is initiating what’s named a National Emphasis Program on heat.&nbsp; And for the first time, OSHA will begin &#8212; for the first time, OSHA will begin nationwide workplace heat inspections &#8212; (applause) &#8212; targeting over 70 high-risk industries.&nbsp;<br><br>Because we’re going to put these values in place.&nbsp; We’re going to put these rules in place.&nbsp; And we’re going to monitor to make sure that the workers aren’t out there without us making sure that they are receiving all of the protections that they are entitled to receive.&nbsp; And we’re not going to stop there.&nbsp;<br><br>As all of you know, it is not how you start a job; it is how you finish it.&nbsp; And so our administration is going to continue this fight until every worker is protected, by using every tool at our disposal to mitigate the danger posed by extreme heat.<br><br>Philadelphia: For myself, for President Biden, and I know for so many of you, this is what it all comes down to &#8212; dignity.&nbsp; The dignity of work.&nbsp; Understanding all work requires a skill.&nbsp; And this work is highly skilled.&nbsp; And it is critical that if we are to strengthen ourselves as a nation, we must strengthen the rights of workers and we must collectively recognize their value and the dignity of that work.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Every worker deserves a safe and a healthy workplace.&nbsp; Every worker deserves a job with good wages and fair benefits.&nbsp; Every worker in America deserves the choice to join a union.&nbsp; And the President and I will always stand with you to defend these sacred principles.&nbsp;<br><br>Our administration will do everything in our power to ensure the workers of our nation can succeed and&nbsp;can thrive.&nbsp; Because when workers succeed and thrive, so does our nation.&nbsp;<br><br>I thank you all very much.&nbsp; And please take care.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Lowering Energy Costs for Working&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/12/remarks-by-president-biden-on-lowering-energy-costs-for-working-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[POET Bioprocessing – MenloMenlo, Iowa 3:17 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you very, very much.&#160; Now, as I was campaigning here in Iowa and made that commitment &#8212; I don’t think anybody heard, but we’re back.&#160; We’re back. And I &#8212; my name is Jon- &#8212; Joe Biden.&#160; I work for Congresswoman Axne.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; There&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">POET Bioprocessing – Menlo<br>Menlo, Iowa</p>



<p>3:17 P.M. CDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very, very much.&nbsp; Now, as I was campaigning here in Iowa and made that commitment &#8212; I don’t think anybody heard, but we’re back.&nbsp; We’re back.</p>



<p>And I &#8212; my name is Jon- &#8212; Joe Biden.&nbsp; I work for Congresswoman Axne.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; There she is.&nbsp; I learned a long time ago, when she says, “I have a…” I just say yes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I say yes right off the bat.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I tell you what: She is one hell of a champion for you.&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp; You ask anyone.&nbsp; If you ever come to Washington, walk into the Congress and say, “You know anybody from Iowa?” &#8212; the first thing they’ll say &#8212; they’ll mention her name.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyway, Cindy, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for your friendship.</p>



<p>To start, I’d like to say a few words about the mass shooting in a New York City subway this morning that you’ve all read and heard about.</p>



<p>Jill and I &#8212; my wife Jill and I are praying for those that are injured and all those touched by that trauma.</p>



<p>And we’re grateful for all the first responders who jumped into action, including civilians &#8212; civilians who didn’t hesitate to help their fellow passengers and tried to shield them.</p>



<p>My team has been in touch with Mayor Adams and New York’s police commissioner.&nbsp; And the Department of Justice and the FBI are working closely with the NYPD on the ground.</p>



<p>We’re going to continue to stay in close contact with New York authorities and &#8212; as we learn more about this situation over the coming hours and days.</p>



<p>And something could have broken between now and the last hour.&nbsp; I haven’t heard the news.&nbsp; I haven’t spoken to anybody but my staff.&nbsp; But we’re not letting up on it until we find out and we find the &#8212; the perpetrator.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, to the reason I’m here today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank you, Rachel.&nbsp; And thank you, Congresswoman Axne.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you hear about progress we’re making in Iowa on everything from biofuels to bridges, you can thank Cindy.&nbsp; That’s what you &#8212; no, I’m not joking.&nbsp; I am not joking.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There is no fence at the White House high enough to keep her out.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>All kidding aside, Cindy, you’re doing one heck of a job.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to say a special hello to someone who really wanted to be here today.&nbsp; And you think I’m kidding.&nbsp; He started &#8212; he’s the guy that brought me to the first biofuel plant in Iowa years ago.&nbsp; Your former governor and my Secretary of Agriculture, Tom Vilsack.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unfortunately, he couldn’t be here today.&nbsp; He went to a press event in Washington, and like two thirds of the people who went, I think they got COVID.&nbsp; He’s doing fine.&nbsp; I spoke to him.&nbsp; But he couldn’t be here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I’m here today to talk about the work we’re doing to lower costs for American families and put rural America at the center of our efforts to build a future that’s made in America.&nbsp; And that’s not hyperbole; it’s about being made in America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A lot of that has &#8212; has to do with this industry.&nbsp; I just had a chance to see the work you do here &#8212; and turn more than 40 million bushels of local corn into 130 million gallons of ethanol a year.&nbsp; That’s a lot of gallons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We want to see facilities like this all over the Midwest, and here’s why: First, it supports farms.&nbsp; It supports farmers and the farm economy.&nbsp; You know, everybody thinks Delaware is a big industrial state, a banking state &#8212; and DuPont.&nbsp; We have a $4 billion industry &#8212; it’s called agriculture &#8212; in Delaware.&nbsp; And it’s mostly &#8212; we have more chickens in Delaware &#8212; broilers &#8212; chickens than you have in the entire Midwest, I think.</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, it is a big industry in Delaware.&nbsp; And my state &#8212; everybody thinks is a &#8212; is a industrial state.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very rural state.&nbsp; The largest city outside of the main city of Wilmington, Delaware, is a couple hun- &#8212; almost 150,000 people &#8212; is 20,000 people.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a rural state.&nbsp; And so, we understand about getting rural communities engaged and being able to make a &#8212; to be able to make it generally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all &#8212; all that corn in the silos is from farmers within 60 miles of here.&nbsp; Knowing you have a buyer gives farmers something they don&#8217;t often have: peace of mind, certitude about where that product can be sold and you get a fair price for it.</p>



<p>Second, it creates good-paying jobs.&nbsp; It’s estimated there are over 400,000 jobs directly and indirectly supported by this industry nationwide.&nbsp; There’s a lot of people.&nbsp; That’s a lot.&nbsp; And a lot of paychecks &#8212; and good, decent paychecks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, it reduces our reliance on foreign oil.&nbsp; By adding this fuel to our gasoline &#8212; (applause) &#8212; 10 percent or 15 percent, even more &#8212; it stretches the supply.</p>



<p>And fourth, it gives you a choice at the pump.&nbsp; When you have a choice, you have competition; when you have competition, you have better prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in addition to all of that, you get less harm to the environment, lower greenhouse gas emissions, and you get even byproducts like grain here which does &#8212; goes into animal feed and which helps cattle producers and lowers their costs.</p>



<p>This is an industry with a tremendous future.</p>



<p>I’ve set a goal of zero-carbon for aviation sector, for example, by 2050.&nbsp; I’ve spoken with the leading heads of all major airlines.&nbsp; It’s going to require billions of gallons of sustainable aviation fuel.&nbsp; And you simply can’t get to net zero by 2050 without biofuels.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Aviation &#8212; aviation isn’t a case where you blend in a little bit of biofuel.&nbsp; It’s where &#8212; it’s called “drop in” &#8212; meaning 100 percent biofuel.</p>



<p>You don’t need to take my word for it.&nbsp; Take the word of the CEO of American Airlines who said, “Sustainable aviation fuel is the cornerstone of our strategy.”&nbsp; End of quote.&nbsp; And the CEO of United Airlines, who called the first biofuel-powered flight “a significant milestone for our efforts to decarbonize our industry.”</p>



<p>To bring that future within reach, I proposed a sustainable aviation fuel tax [credit] that we brought together &#8212; the governments, the agencies, aircraft manufacturers, airlines, fuel producers, airports &#8212; to advance cleaner and more sustainable fuels for American aviation.&nbsp; That’s how we’re going to get there.&nbsp; And we can.</p>



<p>We’re on the cusp of so many significant things that are going to happen in this country &#8212; not just in the fuel side, but in the next 10 years.&nbsp; Your children are going to see more change in the next 10 years than we’ve seen in the last 40 years.&nbsp; That’s how rapidly technology is changing.</p>



<p>So this industry has a role to play in a sustainable energy future.</p>



<p>But I’m here today because homegrown biofuels have a role to play right now &#8212; right now &#8212; as we work to get &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as we work to get prices under control to reduce the costs for families.</p>



<p>Look, I grew up in a family &#8212; not a joke &#8212; where if the price of a gallon of gasoline went up, it was a conversation at our kitchen table.&nbsp; It mattered.&nbsp; It mattered with my mom and dad.&nbsp; It made a difference.&nbsp; We felt it.</p>



<p>Putin’s invasion of Ukraine has driven up gas prices and food prices all over the world.&nbsp; The two-est [sic] largest grain producers in the world, China and &#8212; excuse me &#8212; Ukraine and Russia, are not going what they usually do, so everything is going up.</p>



<p>We saw it in today’s inflation data: Seventy percent of the increase in prices in March came from Putin’s price hike in gasoline.</p>



<p>We need to address this challenge with an urgency that it demands.&nbsp; That’s why I’ve called on Congress to move immediately to lower the cost of families’ utility bills, prescription drug bills, and more, while lowering the deficit to reduce inflationary pressures.&nbsp; And that’s what we’ve done &#8212; we’ve lowered the deficit by $300 billion so far.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it’s expected &#8212;</p>



<p>So, folks, we can do these things without raising a penny in tax on anybody in this &#8212; in this hall &#8212; hall.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;In this giant barn.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Look, it’s going to make a big difference for families.&nbsp; You know, and it’s the most impactful way that Congress can address inflation right now.</p>



<p>But even as we work with Congress, I’m not going to wait</p>



<p>to take action to help American families.&nbsp; I’m doing everything within my power, by executive orders, to bring down the prices and address the Putin price hike.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, we’ve already made progress since the March inflation data was collected.</p>



<p>Your family budget, your ability to fill up your tank &#8212; none of it should hinge on whether a dictator declares war and commits genocide a half a world away.</p>



<p>To help deal with this Putin price hike, I’ve authorized the release of 1 million barrels per day for the next six months from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</p>



<p>This is by far the largest release of our national reserve in history.&nbsp; It’s a wartime bridge to increase oil supply as we work with U.S produc- &#8212; oil producers to ramp up their production this year.</p>



<p>I coordinated release with partners and allies around the world.&nbsp; I’ve spent hours and hours with my counterparts around the world, trying to get them in on the deal.</p>



<p>And shortly after I made the announcement, over 30 countries agreed to release another 60 million additional barrels out on the market.</p>



<p>Over 240 million barrels over the next six months is a bridge to be able to make sure we are going to be able to keep prices down.</p>



<p>This is the largest collective reserve release in history.&nbsp; Hundreds of hours of meetings with key allies, keeping them together, is paying off.&nbsp; Putin is &#8212; was counting on the division the NATO, the division of the European Union, the division of the world.</p>



<p>Well, we spent a lot of time, but they’re all following, every single one &#8212; including, in Asia, South Korea and Japan; Australia &#8212; all of them.</p>



<p>Nations coming together to help deny Putin the ability</p>



<p>to weaponize his energy resources against American families and families in Europe and around the world.</p>



<p>And, by the way, we’re also cutting off access to technology for him.&nbsp; Without American techno- &#8212; look at the number of major American companies, on their own, not of my urging &#8212; over 600 of them, from Exxon to McDonald’s &#8212; have left Russia &#8212; left Russia.&nbsp; He has a burning Tundra, literally.&nbsp; It’s burning.&nbsp; The permafrost is burning.&nbsp; He’s got a problem.&nbsp; And he’s caused &#8212; we’re not going to let him cause that problem to spread to the rest of the world.</p>



<p>And that helped stop the run-up of oil prices that have begun to bring prices down a little bit as a result of countries acting together to release these reserves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Americans should be seeing the savings.&nbsp; And we’re not just learning and leaning on our reserves or our allies and partners to help bring down gas prices and to power the nation.&nbsp; We’re leaning on you, our farmers, our biofuel refiners.</p>



<p>Today, I’m announcing that the Environmental &#8212; and I don’t think it’s much of an announcement; it’s already broken out pretty much the last 24 hours &#8212; but the Environmental Protection Agency is planning to issue an emergency waiver to allow E15 gasoline that uses more ethanol from homegrown crops to be sold across the United States this summer in order to increase fuel supply.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, I feel like &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; I feel like, as a minister and I feel like I’m preaching to the choir here.&nbsp; But here’s what it means: E15 is about 10 cents a gallon cheaper than E10, and some gas stations offer an even bigger discount than that.</p>



<p>But many of the gas stations that sell it here in Iowa, Illinois, Minnesota, Wisconsin, Pennsylvania are required to stop selling it in the summer.</p>



<p>But with this waiver, on June 1, you’re not going to show up at your local gas station and see a bag over the pump that has the cheapest gas.&nbsp; You’re going to be able to keep filling up with E15.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it’s going to solve a whole problem.</p>



<p>But it’s not going to solve all our problems, but it’s going to help some people.&nbsp; And I’m committed to doing whatever I can to help.&nbsp; Even if it’s an extra buck or two in the pockets when they fill up, it’ll make a difference in people’s lives.</p>



<p>And even though E15 is only available in a few thousand pumps today, we’re investing more than $100 million to build biofuel infrastructure of the future &#8212; things like blend pump &#8212; blender pumps, the gas pumps that can handle higher blends of bio-ethanol and diesel fuel.</p>



<p>Of course, there’s more we need to do to bring down the prices for American families.</p>



<p>I’m also working to address food prices.&nbsp; Because right now, farmers aren’t getting a fair deal and &#8212; nationwide &#8212; and neither are families at the grocery store.</p>



<p>Back in July, I signed an executive order to promote competition, to help level the playing field for many family farmers and ranchers, because, as many of you here know better than anyone &#8212; that four big companies control more than half the market for beef, pork, and poultry, giving ranchers very few choices about who to sell to get their product.&nbsp; These big conglomerates drive down prices they pay farmers, and even as they drive up prices at the grocery store.</p>



<p>So we’re investing up to $1 billion of the American Rescue funds for new and expanded meat and poultry processing capacity throughout this country.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And this is something that I’ve talked about with Brent Johnson, who is here today.</p>



<p>We’re going to invest in innovative new products and processors, small businesses, independent businesses &#8212; the lifeblood of our economy.&nbsp; It’s going to give farmers and ranchers more options to shore up a weak point in our food supply chain and bring down prices for American families.</p>



<p>I’ve said it before and I say it again: I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; But without capitalism &#8212; without competition, it isn’t capitalism, it’s exploitation.&nbsp; Exploitation.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And bringing down the historic economic progress, reducing costs for families also requires investing in infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My introducer is going to drive home 50 miles.&nbsp; I got make sure of the thousands of bridges in this state and around the country that aren’t safe &#8212; I hope you’re not going over some of them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that starts with roads and bridges.&nbsp; It really does.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Cindy has pointed out, Iowa has more bridges than any other state in the nation that are classified as “structurally deficient.”&nbsp; Four thousand five hundred are in “poor condition.”</p>



<p>And here is reason why Cindy’s work on the Infrastructure Law was so important: About two thirds of the bridges in need of repair in this country are considered “off system” because they are not directly on the interstate highway system.</p>



<p>And back in January, I was supposed to speak in Pittsburgh, which I did, at a steel mill.&nbsp; But on the way there, a bridge collapsed in the city.&nbsp; That’s what most people don’t realize: It’s called the “City of Bridges.”&nbsp; There’s more bridges in Pittsburgh than any other city in America.&nbsp; And it was &#8212; and that morning I got there, it collapsed.&nbsp; We went straight to the site.&nbsp; It &#8212; the bridge had been rated in “poor condition” for the last 10 years.</p>



<p>Thank God nobody died.&nbsp; It was about, I’m guessing, maybe 300 yards across a little bit of a valley and a shallow creek.&nbsp; And the steepest part, from the bridge to this creek, was probably about 8 or 10 stories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it was a snow day.&nbsp; And that bridge &#8212; if it weren’t a snow day &#8212; would have had, at the moment it went down, school buses with hundreds of kids going across that bridge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This stuff matters.&nbsp; I mean, it really matters.</p>



<p>I was telling Cindy, back in &#8212; I was in a small town in Western Pennsylvania, and they needed a bridge &#8212; or the bridge was only as far as from the length of &#8212; half the length of this &#8212; this room.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; The fire station was on one side and this town was on the other, but because they couldn’t take the firetrucks across that bridge because they were afraid it would collapse, they had to go &#8212; if I’m not mistaken, it was either 10 or 11 miles &#8212; 5 and a half miles up and 5 and a half miles back &#8212; to get there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they had a fire, and they couldn’t get there in time.&nbsp; Just across &#8212; they could see it.&nbsp; It was literally maybe 500 yards away, and they couldn&#8217;t do anything about it.</p>



<p>These bridges are essential for small towns &#8212; in my state and your towns &#8212; and rural areas, for farmers to get their products to market, and for small businesses to be able to serve their customers.</p>



<p>These are bridges that, when they’re closed, <s>shifts</s> [shuts] off delivery and routes to schools and routes home.&nbsp; It takes a lot longer.</p>



<p>They create longer delays for first responders when every second counts.&nbsp; And you all &#8212; Cindy can cite it for you &#8212; the statistics are: You get in an accident in a rural area, you have about a 40 percent greater chance of being se- &#8212; dying than you do if you’re &#8212; it happens in the city.&nbsp; It just simply takes longer to get to the hospital, longer to get to the doc.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill, we included $27.5 billion for smaller bridges, including dedicated funding for off-system bridges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, look, we used to be rated the number one infrastructure &#8212; had the number one in- &#8212; infrastructure in the world.&nbsp; We’re now number eight &#8212; the United States of America.&nbsp; The United States of America.</p>



<p>And, folks, here in Iowa, our Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is delivering $93 million for those bridges just this year.&nbsp; Ninety-three million.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And at least $14 million for off-system bridges this year.</p>



<p>Look, this investment is going to help connect entire towns and regions to new opportunities.&nbsp; We’ve gone from waiting for “Infrastructure Week,”&nbsp;and now you’ve got infrastructure &#8212; infrastructure decade.&nbsp; Ten years.&nbsp; Ten years.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we owe it to you, Cindy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, it’s going to help workers get jobs &#8212; good-paying jobs, products get to market, reduce costs for families.</p>



<p>With this investment, we’re sending the message to America’s small communities and the people who call your &#8212; call you home &#8212; this home: You matter.&nbsp; You matter.&nbsp; We see you.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And we’re building back with you.&nbsp; We’re making sure you’re not left out or left behind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re also investing in universal, affordable high-speed Internet.&nbsp; I was surprised at this number, I have to tell you: Sixteen percent of Iowa households don’t have an Internet sub- &#8212; subscription.</p>



<p>In some places, there’s no high-speed Internet infrastructure at all.&nbsp; Zero in this state.&nbsp; And the law will make high-speed Internet affordable and available everywhere in Iowa.</p>



<p>And think of what that will make possible &#8212; from telemedicine to precision agriculture, to small businesses that want to be able to sell in bigger markets.</p>



<p>In the 21st century in America, no parent ever should have to pull into McDonald’s or a fast-food chain to literally hook up to the Internet in their car so their kid could do their homework over &#8212; on the line &#8212; online.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; The United States of America.&nbsp; We’re the guys that came up with all of this stuff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our Infrastructure Law invests in clean water and wastewater systems, including a major investment in the Lewr- &#8212; Lewis &amp; Clark Rural Water system, to bring clean, reliable drinking water to more than 350,000 people in South Dakota to Minnesota, to northwest Iowa.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It matters.&nbsp; It matters to their health.&nbsp; It matters to their convenience.&nbsp; It matters across the board.</p>



<p>We’re investing in ports and waterways, including over $700 million for the Lock and Dam project 25 on the Mississippi.</p>



<p>And you say, “What does that have to do with me?”&nbsp; It has a lot to do with you all.&nbsp; Because nearly every bushel of soybean and corn that is transported on that river from Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri, Wisconsin goes through these locks.&nbsp; And they were built in 1930 &#8212; 1930s.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Barges often need to be split into smaller groups to make it through, taking hours and sometimes greater delays.</p>



<p>With new, modern locks, we’re going to help farmers get their products to market faster and more efficiently, lower costs, and keep American agriculture globally competitive.</p>



<p>Folks, the list goes on.</p>



<p>I’m starting to bore myself here.&nbsp; But this is important stuff, I think.&nbsp; I think.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, members of my administration and I will be visiting rural America in over 25 states over the next three weeks to talk about how we can do even more to create jobs and opportunity, to make sure that the investments we’re making</p>



<p>reach rural communities &#8212; buy from rural businesses, create jobs here at home &#8212; giving young people the opportunity to make a living and raise a family in the place where they were raised and where they want to stay.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I won’t ask the people &#8212; I know no woman is over 50 years of age here, but the men are over 50.&nbsp; How many times have you had a son or daughter, niece or nephew, say, “I don’t want to move, but I have to.&nbsp; There’s no job here.&nbsp; I don’t have a chance here”?&nbsp; We’re changing that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me close with this: When I was running for office, I heard it a thousand times, “We’re going to build an economy around you, the communities who feed and fuel our nation.”&nbsp; Well, we are.&nbsp; We are.&nbsp; We’re going to deal in people and places that have been left out and left behind for a long time.&nbsp; We’re making progress.</p>



<p>Over the course of my presidency, our recovery has now created 7.9 million jobs in almost 17 mo- &#8212; 14 months.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; More jobs created over the first 14 months of any President in American history.</p>



<p>And by 20- &#8212; in 2021, our economy created more jobs in rural America than occurred in the last 15 years.</p>



<p>So, I’m more optimistic about America today than I’ve been in my whole life.&nbsp; And I &#8212; my doc &#8212; I had an aneurism when I was much younger, and I was put in the hospital; I was a senator.&nbsp; And he started to explain to me what an aneurism was.&nbsp; I said, “I don’t need to know.”&nbsp; He said, “I just &#8212; we’re going to just take the top of your head off and do something with it.”&nbsp; And I said, “No, you do your job, I’ll do mine.&nbsp; And I’ll be the patient.”&nbsp; And after it was all over, he said, “You know what your problem is, Senator?”&nbsp; I was senator.&nbsp; And I said, “No.”&nbsp; He said, “You’re a congenital optimist.”&nbsp; And I am, because I’m an American.&nbsp; That’s why I’m optimistic.&nbsp; Because I see a future that’s within our grasp &#8212; no hyperbole.</p>



<p>We’re the only nation on Earth &#8212; this is not pure chauvinism; this is the truth &#8212; we’re the only nation on Earth, if you think about it, that’s come out of every major crisis stronger than when we went in.&nbsp; We just didn’t build back to where we were, we came out stronger.&nbsp; Stronger.&nbsp; Literally, every major crisis we faced, we turned into an opportunity.&nbsp; And that’s exactly what we’re going to do today.</p>



<p>So, to all of you, I can’t thank you enough for your &#8212; all the work you put in, all the faith you have in your state, in your community, in your country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I just want to say God bless you all.&nbsp; And every time I’d walk out of my Grandpa Finnegan’s house up in Scranton &#8212; which died when coal died; it’s coming back.&nbsp; Every time you’d walk out door, he’d yell, “Joey, keep the faith.”&nbsp; And then one of my &#8212; either my grandmother or my aunt would yell, “No, Joey, spread it.”&nbsp; Let’s go spread the faith.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>3:42 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/12/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 21:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Des Moines, Iowa 1:24 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Okay, welcome to our trip to Iowa.&#160; Two items for you at the top.&#160; One, you may have seen this, but we put out a readout of the President’s call with Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom and about his&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Des Moines, Iowa</p>



<p>1:24 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, welcome to our trip to Iowa.&nbsp; Two items for you at the top.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, you may have seen this, but we put out a readout of the President’s call with Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom and about his recent visit &#8212; the Prime Minister’s recent visit to Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the readout, just to highlight a few points: “The leaders affirmed their commitment to continue providing security and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine in the face of ongoing atrocities by Russia.&nbsp; They also welcomed ongoing cooperation with allies and partners to impose severe costs on Russia for its unprovoked and unjustified war.”</p>



<p>Also wanted to highlight part of the reason &#8212; a big part of the reason we’re going to Iowa today: Today, the President is announcing &#8212; sorry, dramatic windup &#8212; new steps to achieve the goal of reducing &#8212; of building real energy independence in the long term by reducing our reliance on fossil fuels, by increasing fuel supplies, offering more consumer choices, and reducing gasoline prices for Americans.&nbsp; And, of course, doing that on a day where we&#8217;ve seen that energy prices is about 70 percent of the headline CPA &#8212; CPI data.&nbsp; So, we know we need to do everything possible to reduce costs for the American people.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s going to announce that the EPA Administrator is planning to allow E15 gasoline &#8212; gasoline that uses a 15 percent ethanol blend &#8212; to be sold this summer.&nbsp; This is the latest step in expanding Americans’ access to affordable fuel supply and bringing relief to Americans suffering from Putin’s price hike at the pump.</p>



<p>To make E15 available in the summer, the EPA is planning to issue a national emergency waiver.&nbsp; Without this action, E15 cannot be used in most of the country from June 1st to September 15th, and the EPA plans to take final action to issue the emergency waiver closer to June 1st.&nbsp;</p>



<p>E15 is currently offered at 2,300 gas stations in the country, many of them in the Midwest, where it can serve as an important and more affordable source of fuel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At current prices, E15 can save a family 10 cents per gallon of gas on average, and many stores sell E15 at an even greater discount.</p>



<p>With that, (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, is the United States participating in an investigation into whether chemical weapons were used in Mariupol?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’ve nothing to confirm at this time.&nbsp; Of course, we are going to contribute in every way we can to getting to the bottom of it, but we don&#8217;t have anyone on the ground as a part of that at this point in time, as you well know.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any updates.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did you see the comments from President Putin out in eastern Russia in which he seemed to be very defensive and said the military operation will continue?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That &#8212; I have not seen those comments, but that is certainly in lined &#8212; in line with our expectations and what we&#8217;ve seen over the course of the last several days, which is a repositioning, not a total withdrawal.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And while we can certainly applaud the Ukrainians for their bravery and courage in essentially winning the Battle of Kyiv, we know that the brutality and the intention of taking over, militarily, portions of Ukraine, parts of the country &#8212; a sovereign country &#8212; we expect that to continue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you just mentioned that 70 percent of the CPI increase was gasoline related.&nbsp; We saw prices go up for housing, men’s clothing, airfare &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Food.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; food &#8212; you know, transportation, and all sorts of things.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering if &#8212; what in this report has the White House convinced that inflation isn&#8217;t being embedded into the economy going forward?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that the projections con- &#8211;from the Federal Reserve and other outside economists continue to be that inflation will moderate by year end.&nbsp; But we are not going to wait for that.&nbsp; And that is one of the reasons that the President is going to continue to take steps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One step he’s taking, of course, today, which is to lower the cost of gasoline by &#8212; by announcing the EPA waivers that E15 can be available at 2,300 gas stations across the country.</p>



<p>But beyond that, he’s obviously taken steps to release a historic amount from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; And we’ve continued to advocate for actions Congress can take to lower costs for Americans.</p>



<p>And if you look at how all of those costs impact Americans, we know that big, big costs &#8212; our childcare, healthcare, eldercare &#8212; these are all areas where the President has proposed a plan to reduce costs, and certainly it’s reminder of the importance of moving forward with that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the fuel waivers, the EPA’s own guidance says specifically that these waivers aren’t supposed to be used for relieving high gas prices.&nbsp; Some critics are also pointing to the fact that you’re declaring an emergency in June; we’re sitting in April right now.&nbsp; Can you kind of talk through why we’re taking some unprecedented steps or using some unprecedented justifications for this waiver?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we’ve seen gas prices go up anywhere from 80 cents to a dollar since the &#8212; since President Putin invaded Ukraine.&nbsp; And that is certainly having a significant impact on the pocketbooks of Americans across the country.</p>



<p>And so, there are a range of reasons to take this step &#8212; and, of course, that the EPA is taking this step.&nbsp; But certainly, the fact that, right now, without this step, 2,3000 gas stations would essentially have a cover over the E15 gas pumps, not allowing people to utilize gas that is less expensive and not allowing additional supply to get into the marketplace.</p>



<p>So, at this moment where, obviously, we have a foreign dictator invading another country, we want to give ourselves additional flexibility and also do whatever we can do reduce costs for the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you mentioned the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; There’s been some reporting that Michael Barr is a leading candidate for the nomination that Sarah Bloom Raskin had before.&nbsp; Can you confirm whether or not that’s true in terms of if he’s being considered, and also, kind of, give a sense of timeline for when you guys expect to make that announcement?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to confirm and no guidance to offer other than to reiterate that the President has every intention of nominating an eminently qualified person to fill this important role in the Federal Reserve.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the last one on Ukraine.&nbsp; There seems to be a new offensive mounting &#8212; that Russia is mounting towards eastern Ukraine.&nbsp; Specifically, I’m wondering if you have a sense of &#8212; well, what you expect to happen there and what you’re worried about, what you’re looking at in terms of that situation.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So on the ground &#8212; and I know my colleagues at the Department of Defense did a backgrounder today as well &#8212; but all indications are that Russia will seek to surround and overwhelm Ukrainian forces in that region.&nbsp; We expect Russia will continue to launch air and missile strikes across the rest of the country to cause military and economic damage and to cause terror, because Russia’s goal in the end is to weaken Ukraine as much as possible.</p>



<p>We also expect that this stage of the conflict could last a long time.&nbsp; And we should have no illusions that Russia will adjust its brutal tactics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, of course, what our focus is on is continuing to provide a range of security assistance.&nbsp; We essentially look at and review the requests made by Ukrainian leaders.&nbsp; And last week, they had a call with our Chairman of the Joint Chiefs and our National Security Advisor &#8212; a two-hour call &#8212; where they went through items on that list.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think this was already &#8212; this was also provided by the Defense Department, but let me reiterate: We’re also &#8212; as we’re looking to continue to expedite delivery &#8212; we’ve committed $1.7 billion, as you all know &#8212; we’re working to provide the Ukrainians with artillery systems that they have recently requested in conversations between our governments.&nbsp; And we’re working to provide them with artillery from U.S. stocks but also to facilitate the transfer from other allies and partners as well, as we did with the S-300 and the backfill of the Patriot battery system.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake had said over the weekend that some of those additional &#8212; some of that additional military aid might need trainings from Western &#8212; do you have any sense of how that’s going to work, where that training would happen, and who would be involved?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is what we&#8217;re discussing and still working through.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I want to ask about the subway shooting &#8212; the subway attack in New York.&nbsp; What more can you tell us about what the White House&#8217;s contact has been with New York City and New York state officials?&nbsp; Has the President spoken to the mayor or the governor?&nbsp; What kind of assistance has the White House offered?&nbsp; What has New York City asked for?&nbsp; And do you know why the NYPD has already said that, at this time, this isn&#8217;t being investigated as terror?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the investigation is going to happen and be overseen by local New York authorities.&nbsp;&nbsp; The New York Police Department Counterterrorism Unit is working with the JTF- &#8212; TF [JTTF], the FBI, and the ATF to investigate.&nbsp; So, certainly, we would assist in every appropriate way through those channels.</p>



<p>As we noted earlier this morning, not only has the President been briefed on latest developments, but White House senior staff are in touch with Mayor Adams, with poli- &#8212; with the police commissioner, and we&#8217;ve offered any assistance we can provide.</p>



<p>I just spoke again with the President about this earlier on the plane, and he reiterated that that is his &#8212; his request of his team.&nbsp; Anything they need, anything they want, we are here to help them and provide that to them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He has not yet had a call.&nbsp; If that happens today, I will provide that information to all of you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know why they’ve said that this is not, at this time, being investigated as terror; if this investigation is so preliminary, why they’ve ruled that out?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would point you to them.&nbsp; They&#8217;re overseeing the investigation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think we might hear from the President specifically on this &#8212; on this matter today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have a prediction of that at this point in time, but if there are updates to provide from our end, I&#8217;ll let you all know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a follow-up on the use of possible chemical weapons or poisonous gas in Russia?&nbsp; What would our response be if that is verified?&nbsp; How &#8212; and how long might it take to verify that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to speculate about hypotheticals.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have confirmation of the use, and so I&#8217;m not going to speculate on hypotheticals at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will note that it is difficult to get the data and information that you need in cases like this.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have &#8212; we don&#8217;t have a team on the ground, obviously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that we did have credical [sic] &#8212; credible information before today that Russia may use a variety of riot control agents, including tear gas mixed with chemical agents, that would cause stronger symptoms in order to weaken and incapacitate entrenched Ukrainian fighters and civilians as part of its aggressive campaign to take Mariupol.</p>



<p>We shared that information with the Ukrainians at the time.&nbsp; And of course, we’ll continue to share up-to-date intelligence-gathering information.</p>



<p>But at this point in time, we have no confirmation, so I’m not going to get ahead of that process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more about China.&nbsp; I understand there&#8217;s advice to &#8212; going out to Americans &#8212; a recommendation not to travel to China right now because of zero-COVID policies and the possibility of parents being separated from their children, which we know is happening, obviously, now in China.&nbsp; Do we have any evidence or any talk of that happening to American citizens right now who are in China?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would point you to the State Department.&nbsp; They provide that type of guidance and information to the American people, wherever they are in the world.&nbsp; They do it out of an abundance of caution and to make sure they&#8217;re as transparent as possible about what they&#8217;re seeing on the ground in countries.</p>



<p>And I believe it was specific to Shanghai, not all of China &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; I believe.</p>



<p><a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back on CPI: I think you said yesterday you don&#8217;t expect most people to dive beyond headline inflation.&nbsp; So how concerned is the White House that people are going to see that 8.5 percent sort of roll back their spending and then drive us into a recession?&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would also say that core CPI did go down this month.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to over-crank that, but that is certainly also data we look at.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we noted that &#8212; our expectation about headline CPI &#8211;so that the American people, through all of you and whatever way you chose to report it, would understand we expected it to be elevated because of Putin’s invasion; because of the impact on energy prices, which they&#8217;re certainly experiencing every day.</p>



<p>So, I don&#8217;t have a projection on consumer spending at this point in time.&nbsp; Obviously, that data is taken by economists, but we wanted to provide as much information as we could assess about what we thought the data would show based on what people are already experiencing when they go to the gas pumps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, back on the shooting, I’m wondering if you guys have an assessment of how successful these DOJ strike forces have been.&nbsp; Specifically, do we have a number of how many illegally transferred guns they’ve taken off the streets in those five major metro areas?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s a great question.&nbsp; I can see if we can get an update from the Department of Justice, who obviously oversees the strike forces, in terms of what their successes have been.&nbsp; I know we’ve provided updates a little bit in the past, but I don’t have that information in front of me, so let me get that to you after the bri- &#8212; after (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine, please.&nbsp; The administration has said many times that it would help Ukraine investigate war crimes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you maybe detail how is that happening without having presence on the ground?&nbsp; And is it maybe a plan at some stage to send U.S. personnel to collect &#8212; for example, to collect evidence and to assist Ukrainian forces?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have any updates on that last particular part of your question.&nbsp; What I can tell you is that there are a couple of ways that historically we have participated in investigations, and we certainly would in this case.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Some of that is intel gathering and sharing that with our partners and allies around the world who are also contributing to investigations.&nbsp; Some of that is through those diplomatic channels, of course.&nbsp; Some of that is reporting of, frankly, the media and reporters who are in Ukraine, on the ground, who can sometimes not gather the type of data necessarily I’m talking about, but often do provide pictures and visuals.&nbsp; And then there is, of course, a range of means we have to work to gather information.&nbsp; But I can’t detail more of it from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a last one, on the French election.&nbsp; I know you won’t comment on the outcome, but is the administration monitoring the process for Russian interference?&nbsp; And have you seen signs of it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have an assessment of it, but I think we&#8217;ve seen the Russians’ interference in elections throughout the course of recent history and before then, whether it&#8217;s here or in Europe.&nbsp; So, certainly, we anticipate that that could be possible.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any confirmation of it at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the President&#8217;s position on whether Iowa should have the first-in-the-nation presidential contest in ’24?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is a process being overseen by the DNC that will play out over the course of the coming days.&nbsp; And we certainly respect and support that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the French election, is there a concern within the White House that if President Macron is not reelected, that it could, sort of, become an issue in the &#8212; in the bid to keep European, sort of, unity and cross-Atlantic unity in the face of the Russian invasion of Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, unity is obviously very important to us.&nbsp; Maybe the most used word in our description of our efforts and our strategy here.&nbsp; But, as you know, the runoff election is not for a week and a half, so we&#8217;re just not going to get ahead of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On COVID, Jen, Philadelphia is the first major city to reinstate an indoor mask mandate with this current surge.&nbsp; Do you guys expect other cities to follow suit?&nbsp; What would it take for the White House to reinstate a mask mandate on campus as well?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It would take the CDC recommending that.&nbsp; I would remind you that what &#8212; every state and city is going to make evaluations and their own assessments on what they need to do to keep communities safe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we are guided by is the CDC guidance, which has red, green, yellow, and even impact &#8212; yellow-green, I should say.&nbsp; It even impacts where the President wears masks, where we wear masks.&nbsp; And obviously, if we go to an area where it’s recommended, we will continue to do that.</p>



<p>So, you know, right now, there are of course requirements in transit, but the President won&#8217;t be wearing a mask &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Philadelphia taking this step prematurely, in the White House’s view?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s been our view that cities and local communities can take and should take steps that they feel will keep their community safe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you one more about ethanol?&nbsp; This is a &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t an emergency suspension, but this is something the Trump administration did.&nbsp; They allowed year-round sales of E15.&nbsp; It was overturned by federal court.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m just wondering &#8212; you know, the politics of this, this is something that was also supported by several Midwestern Republican senators in the Senate.&nbsp; So is there any fear that the Democratic base might be a little bit disillusioned by doing something that has been supported by Republicans and was done by the Trump administration, even given the circumstances with rising gas prices?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think our view is that people &#8212; the American people are going to put gas in their tanks, in their cars across the country, including across the Midwest where many of these 2,300 pumps are, where &#8212; that have E15 &#8212; the E15 gasoline option.&nbsp; And if they can pay 10 cents less a gallon, then they’ll appreciate that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure they&#8217;re looking at that through a political lens.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on inflation, Jen.&nbsp; Given the consistently high numbers we keep seeing and Shanghai being in lockdown, zero-COVID, Russia’s war &#8212; I know you&#8217;re saying that the Fed is anticipating, end of year, things will ease, but how certain can we really be, given the uncertainties and these lo- &#8212; you know, COVID-zero and Russia’s war?&nbsp; It could last longer, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And would the Pres- &#8212; and would the President &#8212; obviously, the Fed is a sep- &#8212; is separate, but would he then want to not see an increase in interest rates, an increase in what the Fed is already planning for the rest of the year?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the Fed, as you noted, is independent.&nbsp; And they have predicted or conveyed publicly that they intend to recalibrate.&nbsp; We support that pivot, and we support their independence and their, you know, ability to make decisions about interest rates and other policies around inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I will say though is that how the American people experience inflation is rising costs &#8212; right? &#8212; in a variety of areas.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; They experience it at the gas pump.&nbsp; They experience it when they go to the grocery store.&nbsp; They experience it when things cost more, whether it’s childcare or taking care of their grandparents.&nbsp; That’s why we have been so aggressive in pushing for the President’s agenda that would lower those costs &#8212; because they would have such a huge impact on the American people, and we feel that’s a solution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If Republicans have an alternative to it, we welcome that.&nbsp; But that is a way we could cut costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But otherwise, to go back to your original question, we certainly respect the independence of the Federal Reserve and support their publicly stated intention of recalibrating.</p>



<p>1:43 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
