<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:48:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in Roundtable Discussion With State&#160;Legislators</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-roundtable-discussion-with-state-legislators/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57536</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orange County Convention CenterOrlando, Florida THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I want to thank the Florida State legislators for joining us this afternoon for a discussion about one of the, I think, most pressing issues facing our country today, which revrol- &#8212; revolves around the point that every woman in America should be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Orange County Convention Center<br><em>Orlando, Florida</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I want to thank the Florida State legislators for joining us this afternoon for a discussion about one of the, I think, most pressing issues facing our country today, which revrol- &#8212; revolves around the point that every woman in America should be free to make decisions, some of the most intimate decisions a woman can make, about their own bodies and their life.<br><br>And we are having this conversation in the context of a Supreme Court that took a constitutional right, that had been recognized, from the women of America.<br><br>We&#8217;re having this conversation in the context of states and so-called leaders of states, such as some in Florida, who are seeking to restrict a woman&#8217;s right to make decisions about her own body at a state level.<br><br>And I think that we collectively agree, as do most Americans, that there are certain things the government should just not interfere with.&nbsp; And one of them is what should be the right of every American to make the most intimate decisions about what I like to call “heart and home.”<br><br>So that&#8217;s the context in which we are having this conversation.&nbsp; I think many of us also agree that this is not an issue that requires any particular person to change their faith or their belief system.&nbsp; It is simply that we should agree that in a democracy, in America, the government should not interfere with certain decisions.&nbsp; Let the woman make that decision with her doctor, her loved ones, her pastor, her priest, her rabbi.&nbsp; But the government should not be doing that.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So that&#8217;s the cons- &#8212; that&#8217;s the issue.&nbsp; That is also a constitutional issue.&nbsp; And &#8212; and we know that this fight to stand up for these rights is occurring and will occur on a national level, but certainly is also happening at a state level.&nbsp; And so I applaud the leaders who are here.&nbsp;<br><br>When the President and I think about our responsibilities, it is certainly to do the work I&#8217;ve done my entire career, which is to fight for the safety, health, and wellbeing of the women of America.&nbsp; And that, of course, includes the women of Florida.<br><br>And so we&#8217;re here to have that conversation and &#8212; and also to recognize that this is not happening in a vacuum.&nbsp; I look at a state like Florida, and it is from the same so-called leaders that these restrictions are being imposed on women that there are also restrictions on voting rights.&nbsp; There are also restrictions on the rights that members of our LGBTQ+ community should have, to live and love freely.<br><br>And so this is the environment in which &#8212; in which we work.&nbsp; And we will together do what we can to stand together for the people of America and each state, and also to build the coalitions between all of the communities that are directly impacted, with the knowledge that the whole country has something at stake when we are looking at these laws.<br><br>So with that, I thank you all.&nbsp; And I want to, in particular, thank Secretary of Health and Human Services, Xavier Becerra, for his leadership &#8212; longstanding leadership &#8212; and also through the agency he runs.<br><br>And so I will invite you, Secretary Becerra, if you can begin the discussion, and then we&#8217;ll go around the table.<br><br>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; Madam Vice President, I will begin by saying, first, thank you for coming to Florida.&nbsp; Thank you for inviting me to come, because we know that there are champions here for access to healthcare everywhere in America.&nbsp; But certainly here in Florida, we know folks are fighting &#8212; the leaders in the medical community, leaders in our legislative community, and we want to say thank you for that.<br><br>And we, at HHS, hope to put in action the instructions you and the President have given us to try to make sure we preserve that access to care, that we continue to protect those rights that Americans did know for some 50 years, and that we do it in a way that continues to move our country forward instead of moving backwards.<br><br>I think most of us have always known America as a place where the best days are ahead, and that requires us to believe in that.&nbsp; And so I&#8217;m thrilled to be able to speak to folks here in Florida about the actions that you and the President have asked HHS to take on.<br><br>And so thank you very much for the invitation.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Secretary.&nbsp; And with that, we will go around the table.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d invite Dr. Schickler to my right to offer a few words about your perspective as the chief medical officer of Planned Parenthood of <s>Southeast </s>[Southwest] and Central Florida.<br><br>(Press departs.)<br><br>END</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By Vice President Harris At Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority’s 70th&#160;Boule</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-alpha-kappa-alpha-sororitys-70th-boule/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orange County Convention CenterOrlando, Florida 11:48 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning, sorors!  (Applause.)  (Laughs.)  Oh, my goodness.  Oh.  Good morning, good morning, good morning.  (Applause.) Please have a seat.  We have so much to talk about.  (Laughter.)  Oh, my goodness.  What a sight my eyes do behold.  (Applause.) It is so good to be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Orange County Convention Center<br><em>Orlando, Florida</em></em></p>



<p>11:48 A.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning, sorors!  (Applause.)  (Laughs.)  Oh, my goodness.  Oh.  Good morning, good morning, good morning.  (Applause.)<br></p>



<p>Please have a seat.  We have so much to talk about.  (Laughter.)  Oh, my goodness.  What a sight my eyes do behold.  (Applause.)<br><br>It is so good to be here.  I can’t even explain how this feels.  I can’t even explain how this feels.  (Applause.)<br><br>To our Supreme Basileus, Dr. Glenda Glover &#8212; (applause); members of the Directorate; former Supreme Basilei; and all who serve Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated &#8212; (applause) &#8212; good morning to everyone.  Good morning.<br> <br>Dr. Glover, you have been a tremendous friend to me, and sister, over so many years, and a phenomenal leader of our sisterhood.  So I want to thank you in front of everyone &#8212; (applause) &#8212; for all that you have done and for your commitment, your enduring commitment to exemplify excellence.<br> <br>I also want to thank our International President, Danette Anthony Reed, as you guide us into the next chapter of our sorority.  (Applause.)  I’m so excited to walk with you on this journey.<br> <br>And what an amazing sight to look out and to see so many of our sorority sisters under one roof at the same time.  (Applause.)  I look out at all of you and, of course, I see family.<br> <br>In fact, our sorority, some of you may know, has been a part of my life since I was a little girl.  You see, my aunt, Christine Simmons, joined Alpha Kappa Alpha at Howard University in the year 1950.  And so &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  We know!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Yes, you know.  And &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and when I was a teenager, she was basileus of Alpha Nu Omega chapter in Oakland, California.  (Applause.)  And when I graduated high school, there, of course, was no question that I would attend Howard University.  And I was determined, from a young girl, to join Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated.  (Applause.)  And, of course, this sisterhood remains a key part of who I am today.<br> <br>In fact, when Auntie Chris was basileus, I’ll never forget: She hosted one of our revered founders, Miss Norma E. Boyd.  And Miss Boyd was in her late 80s at the time, and we had a reception for her.  And she was then signing of her book, “A Love That Equals My Labors.”  And she signed a copy: “To Kamala, with love, Norma E. Boyd.”  And I will tell you, I proudly display the signed copy of that book in my West Wing office in the White House.  (Applause.)  Yes, I do.  The legacy lives on.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>And last month, I’ll tell you &#8212; and I see some of them here &#8212; I was so proud to host my line sisters, the 38 Jewels of Iridescent Splendor &#8212; (applause) &#8212; at my home in the official residence of the Vice President of the United States.  (Applause.)<br> <br>All of that being just one of the thousands of stories of how enduring and lifelong and through the generations our sisterhood is.<br><br>Our sorority, along with all the Divine Nine organizations, was founded to create lasting bonds of community.<br> <br>All of our founders were acutely aware we needed to build networks of support for young Black men and women who attend college in America.<br> <br>AKA, of course, was the first sorority created to meet this call.  (Applause.)<br> <br>As we all remember, Ethel Hedgemon Lyle led the effort to found our sisterhood &#8212; and in the face of terrible challenges.<br> <br>Just think: In the year 1908, when our soro- &#8212; sorority was founded, 89 Black people were lynched across the country.  Just think: At the time of the founding of our sorority, American life was deeply segregated.<br> <br>When Miss Lyle attended Howard, less than a quarter of the students were women.  And yet, despite all of this, and perhaps because of it, she believed in the power of sisterhood and in the power of service to create desperately needed social and legal change &#8212; beliefs that guide us all to today.<br><br>Our legacy is service to all mankind, and our work in Mississippi alone over the last 87 years is a perfect example.<br> <br>During the Great Depression, our sorors provided free medical care to poor Black women in the Mississippi Delta.  (Applause.)  And generations later, many of you here ran vaccination drives in those same communities during the COVID pandemic.  (Applause.)  It’s but one example of so many.<br> <br>You know, recently I was reminded of another example of our longstanding, enduring commitment to service when I was a member of the United States Senate.<br> <br>So across the street from the United States Senate &#8212; and my office is in the Hart building, it’s called &#8212; sits the Library of Congress.  And I would visit the Library of Congress from time to time.  And one time I visited, and the librarian was very proud to show me an old photograph from the year 1950 of President Truman.<br><br>He was meeting with representatives from the National Pan-Hellenic Council, which included a member of our sorority, to talk about ending employment discrimination in America.<br> <br>And fast-forward to today, there are recent photographs &#8212; very recent &#8212; of the Divine Nine presidents at the White House while they met with me in the Ceremonial Office of the Vice President of the United States.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And these photographs are a testament, then, to how members of the Divine Nine have always made sure Black voices are in the rooms where decisions are being made &#8212; (applause) &#8212; how our advocacy has been the history of moving the highest levels of government into action, and how we will always fight for what our communities need and for the best of who we are as a nation.<br> <br>In the year 2020, our sorority proved this yet again.  Our sorority registered more than 250,000 people to vote.  (Applause.)  Our sorority teamed up with our Divine Nine sisters and strolled to the polls &#8212; (laughter and applause) &#8212; indeed &#8212; and with the entire Divine Nine to combat voter suppression.  And I will never forget how, during those long days, you turned out for almost every rally and campaign event.<br> <br>In fact, at one of my events, my &#8212; I was in a hold room in the back, and some folks who were working the event came, and they said, “Ma’am, there are a bunch of ladies out there wearing pink and green” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; “and they’d like to see you.”  (Laughs.)  And of course I said, “Well, you bring them in immediately.  Those are my sorors!”  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, in 2020, just as a most recent example, you not only showed up for President Biden and me, you showed up for America.  (Applause.)  And together, we were joined in our fight for progress, which is part of our legacy.<br> <br>Together, we said we must fight to address the current challenges we face as a nation and that we are prepared to lead on issues like the Black maternal health crisis in our country.  (Applause.)  Because we know Black women are three times as likely to die from pregnancy-related causes, and we know women in rural America are more than one and a half times more likely to die.<br> <br>So, after the election, the President and I and all of us elevated the issue of maternal health to a national priority, building on the work that we did together over the years.<br> <br>In fact, for the first time, we hosted the women most impacted &#8212; Black women, rural women, Native women &#8212; to the White House to discuss &#8212; get this &#8212; at the White House to discuss the importance of doulas &#8212; (applause); to discuss and speak up and out about the issues of fibroids &#8212; (applause); post-partum depression; and the barriers to care for women of color and rural women.  (Applause.)  Because we’re not going to be quiet when we know there is a role and a need for us to serve.<br><br>And through the work we have done together, we’ve dedicated resources to hire and train doulas.  We have done the work of funding research to address the biggest contributors to maternal mortality, and to advance and speak about the need to advance culturally competent care.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Through the work that we did together on this issue, we have now got to the point where we have encouraged &#8212; in a positive way &#8212; encouraged states &#8212; urged them, cajoled them to understand that Medicaid postpartum coverage should not just be 2 months, it should be 12 months.  (Applause.)  Because the women who require and count on Medicaid coverage require that, after giving birth to a human being &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; that their needs are recognized for beyond just the first 2 months.  And this will benefit over a quarter million women as of today.  (Applause.)<br><br>Together, we all said we must help our children reach their God-given potential.  And so our administration extend &#8212; extended the Child Tax Credit, which lifted up nearly 40 percent of Black children in America out of poverty just last year alone.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We recognized working people are struggling and, in particular, when it comes to covering the cost of their basic needs, including the cost of raising a child.  So we passed a tax cut to give working families a tax cut of up to $8,000 a year, which gives folks more room in their budgets to buy food, medication, and school supplies for their children.<br> <br>We’ve been traveling the country.  Many of you have joined me in different places in our country to talk about the longstanding, very serious problem of lead pipes, where our babies are being forced to drink toxic water, having well documented, then, health consequences, including consequences to their ability to learn.<br><br>So, together, we did the work to remove lead pipes.  We are in the process of doing that to ensure that no child has to drink water poisoned with lead, and to make sure that we, again, are doing everything we can, understanding our children &#8212; God has given them so much capacity, but we here, on Earth, must do our part to make sure they are protected and can live in an environment that allows them to thrive.<br><br>Which is why, together, we have also addressed the issue of high-speed Internet.  Because I know there are a whole lot of folks here right now who know what that pandemic meant to your child’s ability to learn and go to school &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and what that required in terms of you having access and being able to afford high-speed Internet.<br><br>I travel the country.  I can’t tell you how many parents I met who would have to go and &#8212; and drive the kids to the local fast-food restaurant or library to have access to the public Wi-Fi there.  The kids would be in the back seat of the car, trying to do their homework.<br><br>We know what an education means in terms of what it allows for the future of one’s ability to grow and succeed.  However, so many of the children in our country will be impaired in that ability if they don’t have the basic tools, like access to high-speed Internet.<br><br>So we’ve invested billions of dollars to provide what we know needs to be access to high-speed Internet &#8212; (applause) &#8212; across the country, including subsidies for low-income and working families so that they can afford it, even if they have access.<br> <br>We have talked about the fact that so many of our children and, therefore, their families and their parents, are in need &#8212; in dire need of support when it comes to those children who have disabilities &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and what we need to do to ensure that the families have resources they need.  So we are fighting together for home health care work, that it is affordable. <br><br>We are fighting to say that if we want to have a nation that can compete around this world &#8212; Dr. Glover talked about it &#8212; I have been traveling all of this world as Vice President.  I have met with, I’m told, at least 80 prime ministers and presidents, talking with them about the challenges that face our world.<br>    <br>One of the common themes, everyone knows, is you invest in the children of a nation, you are investing in the future of a nation.  (Applause.)  And when we invest in the education of the children of a nation, we are doing the best &#8212; (applause) &#8212; in terms of ensuring certain outcomes.<br> <br>So, together, for example, we all said: Let&#8217;s support some of the most excellent academic institutions in the United States of America, which are referred to as HBCUs.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And so, under Dr. Glover’s leadership, our sorority raised millions of dollars for HBCUs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and our administration invested an historic $5.8 billion in our HBCUs.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And as a point of personal privilege, as the first Vice President to be a graduate of an HBCU, I&#8217;m particularly proud of that fact.  (Laughs.) (Applause.) <br> <br>So, as we move forward, we know that there is more work to do.  And that means to ensure that we have invested in the success of all of the people of our nation.  And, Dr. Glover, again, I want to thank you for being the Vice Chair of the White House HBCU Initiative, which we can ensure will lead to its success.  (Applause.) <br> <br>So, Sorors, together, we said that our country must build more wealth and opportunity for all communities.  That is part of what we fight for. <br> <br>And our administration then invested billions of dollars in minority and women entrepreneurs, knowing there is nothing more important than building the wealth for most Americans, and that means investing in home ownership.  This is something the sorority has worked on through the years.<br> <br>We know, historically, that one of the impediments to economic health, growth, and wealth for the Black community has been biases in the system that allows for homeownership.  And that continues to today. <br> <br>So I&#8217;ve met with many of the leaders here and around the country to talk about the fact that one of the remaining issues in terms of the bias and the system is the bias in home appraisals.  (Applause.)  You (inaudible).  Right?  You&#8217;ve heard the stories. <br> <br>The stories of how a Black family wants to sell their home or learn the value of their home because maybe it is then the assets of that home that will be the basis of sending their child off to college or helping their child grow a business.  And then the appraisers come in and the family knows, &#8220;No, that sounds like a low estimate of the value of our home.&#8221; <br> <br>And there are stories, which I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ve all heard, about that family then having &#8212; friends of the family and other family who are white and inviting them to come in and put up their family pictures &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and the Black family takes down their own, leaves the house for a couple of days and the appraiser comes in and, lo and behold, the same house appraises for a higher amount.<br> <br>So, one of the issues we&#8217;ve been dealing with is speaking that truth and dealing with it around what we need to do to eliminate racial bias in home appraisals, understanding when we have an economic agenda, the value of a home for so many of our families is the greatest source of their wealth and intergenerational wealth.  (Applause.) <br> <br>So, moving forward, that is part of the work that we have done so that we can make sure that folks can realize the full and actual value of their home.<br> <br>When we look at then where we are, we also know that, together, we said, &#8220;Police reform is long overdue.&#8221;  We cannot stop having that discussion.  (Applause.)  And President Biden issued an executive order to increase accountability in policing, including a ban on chokeholds in federal law enforcement.  (Applause.)  And there is still more work to do.<br> <br>And last but not least: Together, we said we needed better representation on the federal courts.  (Applause.)  You know where I&#8217;m going.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>So, first, I will tell you and share with you, we have appointed the most diverse group of judges in the history of the United States &#8212; (applause) &#8212; including, of course, the first Black woman appointed to the United States Supreme Court: Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And I was so proud to be a part of that process.  And when we look at where she sits and think about our founders and think about everything that is the spirit behind who we are and why we serve, it&#8217;s such a perfect example of what makes all that work worthwhile. <br> <br>So, I say all of this and I went through that list of accomplishments because all of this was possible because of your work.  And I just want to remind you of that.  Because this is a group of leaders that is so invested in fighting for the best of our country. <br> <br>This is a group of leaders who know the power of service and the need in the power of service to create needed social and legal change.  And so all of that to say: Thank you, Sorors.  Thank you. <br> <br>Because this is the progress that you fought for.  And I’ve not had a chance before today to thank you all in one place for what you have done for the lives of people you may not ever meet and people who may never know your name.  This progress is what you stood in line for. <br> <br>And so I&#8217;m also here to say: We must do it again this November.  (Applause.)  Because there is still more work to do.  To have a strong workforce, we have to do more to support working parents.  We must continue the fight to make sure that parents don’t have to pay more than 7 percent of their income in childcare.  That’s the work we still have yet to complete.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We cannot let up our fight to lower the cost of home healthcare, including eldercare.  And we must continue the fight to lower the cost of prescription drugs, including insulin &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so that it is no more than $35 a month and not causing people to look at bankruptcy just to take care of their basic health needs.<br> <br>There is more work to do.  If we want as a nation to keep our communities safe from gun violence, well, we must demand that Congress has the courage to repeal the liability shield that protects gun manufacturers, and we must demand they have the courage to renew the assault weapons ban.  (Applause.) <br> <br>We have lost too many precious lives.  I attended the funeral in Buffalo of an 86-year-old grandmother.  And you know her story, and if not, I will share with you.  She was going to the grocery store after having left her husband who she’d been caring for, who’s in a nursing home.  She was just going to buy some groceries.  A matriarch of a family. <br> <br>So, in Buffalo. In Uvalde, those babies and their teachers.  In Highland Park, I went there within 24 hours of that massacre that was supposed to be a parade route.  And in communities and cities across our country.<br> <br>Listen, as we applaud &#8212; and we must applaud &#8212; our President, Joe Biden, for signing the first federal gun safety bill in 30 years &#8212; (applause) &#8212; he signed it. <br> <br>And there is still more work to do to see it through, especially when, in America today, while Black people are 13 percent of America’s population, Black people are 62 percent of gun homicide victims. <br> <br>This is our issue.  This is our issue in terms of our leadership on this issue of the need for reasonable gun safety laws.  It is an issue on which we lead because we know we have so much at stake as leaders in our country.  When young Black men are 18 times more likely to be victims of gun homicides, we will lead on this issue. <br> <br>And we have more work to do.  (Applause.) <br> <br>But I’m here to, obviously, speak a little truth &#8212; a lot of truth.  And so, in that spirit, the road to get there, to see it through, it’s not going to be easy.  It’s never been easy.<br> <br>And there are, as there have always been, forces that stand in our way.  Forces that oppose even the most &#8212; on this issue of gun safety &#8212; even the most commonsense gun safety proposals.  Forces that include extremist so-called leaders who, instead of expanding rights, work to restrict rights; these so-called leaders who, after we fought and marched &#8212; members of our sorority being among the greatest leaders, fought for the right to vote &#8212; these so-called leaders, right here in this state and in other places in the country, making it more difficult for people to vote!  (Applause.) <br> <br>So-called leaders: In neighboring states, making it even illegal to give folks food and water as they’re standing in line to vote.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And we know what we need to do.  One of the things we need to do is pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act and the Freedom to Vote Act.  (Applause.)  So-called leaders.<br> <br>So-called leaders who are in the process of criminalizing doctors and punishing women who want to make health decisions for themselves.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So we know what we need to do.  We need to continue to fight for a woman’s right to make the most intimate, personal decisions for herself, with her doctor, with her pastor, with her priest, with her loved ones, but not her government telling her what she’s supposed to do.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, all of this to say that we have a legacy of fighting for social and legal change in our country.  And when we have done that, everyone has benefitted.  When we have fought for social and legal change, it has never been about fighting against something, it’s about fighting for something for the benefit of all mankind.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And so much of what we have fought for is on the line again.  And so we know what we need to do.<br> <br>In particular &#8212; because I’m going to leave you with a couple specifics &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; we need two additional United States senators to protect voting rights.  (Applause.)  We need two additional United States senators to protect a woman’s right to make decisions about her own body.  (Applause.)  And we need to elect people who will defend these rights up and down the ballot &#8212; from district attorneys to state attorneys general to local sheriffs to governors.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And to make this happen, let us do what we do best: We build coalitions.  We know how to do that.  We got the meanest, baddest phone trees in the world.  (Laughter.)  We know how to network.  We are fueled in the deeply held belief that we all have so much more in common than what separates us. <br> <br>So let’s do the kind of work that we have done, because we do it so well, and continue to activate and organize our communities.  Let’s continue to be on the frontlines of the greatest movement for progress in our country.<br> <br>And I’ll close with this: Our soror, the great Coretta Scott King, once said that freedom must be earned and won in each generation.<br> <br>I look out at this group, and I see among the folks here a young woman who is still making her way through college, sitting next to a woman who has served her community in pink and green with pride for over 75 years.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Ours is an intergenerational sisterhood.  (Applause.)  And we live with that knowledge, with the knowledge that we stand on great and broad soldiers, like Norma E. Boyd.  We live knowing that we are their legacy, that we learn from each other, that we teach each other, and that we have always been about fighting for the best of our country.<br> <br>Because the women of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated have always been unburdened by what has been, unburdened by what society may say we can or cannot be.<br> <br>And through our sisterhood, we teach that there is no barrier we cannot break and there is no obstacle we cannot overcome.<br> <br>We are built for leadership.  And every day, we see it through.  We strive.  And we do.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so, I celebrate the many.  And today, I’ll honor the first: Alpha Kappa Alpha.  Thank you all very much.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  Thank you. <br> </p>



<p>END                 12:25 P.M. EDT</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Twenty-Third Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/president-biden-names-twenty-third-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing the nominations of four new federal judicial nominees, his intent to nominate a fifth federal judicial nominee, and three nominees for local courts in the District of Columbia—all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing the nominations of four new federal judicial nominees, his intent to nominate a fifth federal judicial nominee, and three nominees for local courts in the District of Columbia—all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, if confirmed, this slate would include:</p>



<ul><li>The first Black woman to serve on the U.S. District Court for the District of Oregon</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s twenty-third round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his tenth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 123.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies. And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p><strong><u>District Court – Press Bios</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Matthew L. Garcia: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of New Mexico</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Matthew L. Garcia has served in the Office of New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham as Chief of Staff from 2020 to 2022 and General Counsel from 2019 to 2020. From 2012 to 2018, he was a partner at Garcia Ives Nowara in Albuquerque, New Mexico, and from 2009 to 2012, he was a partner at Bach &amp; Garcia in Albuquerque, New Mexico. Mr. Garcia had his own solo practice from 2008 to 2009. From 2006-2008 Mr. Garcia was an associate at Freedman Boyd Daniels Hollander Goldberg &amp; Ives in Albuquerque, New Mexico. Mr. Garcia received his J.D. from the University of New Mexico School of Law in 2005, an M.P.P. from Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government in 2003, and a B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from the University of New Mexico in 1999.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Lindsay C. Jenkins: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois—<em>Intent to Nominate</em></u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Lindsay C. Jenkins is a partner at Cooley LLP in Chicago, Illinois, where she has worked since 2021. She previously served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of Illinois from 2006 to 2021. Ms. Jenkins was previously an associate at Jones Day from 2004 to 2006. She served as a law clerk for Judge Solomon Oliver, Jr. on the United States District Court for the Northern District of Ohio from 2002 to 2004. Ms. Jenkins received her J.D., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Cleveland-Marshall College of Law at Cleveland State University, in 2002 and her B.A. from Miami University of Ohio in 1998.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Justice Adrienne C. Nelson: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of Oregon</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Justice Adrienne C. Nelson has served as an Associate Justice on the Oregon Supreme Court since 2018. From 2006 to 2018, Justice Nelson served as a trial judge on the Multnomah County Circuit Court. Justice Nelson worked as a senior attorney for Portland State University from 2004 to 2006, and she was in private practice at Bennett, Hartman, Morris &amp; Kaplan from 2004 to 2006. From 1996 to 1999, Justice Nelson was a public defender with Multnomah Defenders, Inc. Justice Nelson received her J.D. from the University of Texas School of Law at Austin in 1993 and her B.A., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from the University of Arkansas at Fayetteville in 1989.</p>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong><u>Judge Andrew G. Schopler: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Southern District of California</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Andrew G. Schopler has served as a United States Magistrate Judge for the Southern District of California since 2016.&nbsp;From 2004 to 2016, Judge Schopler was an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of California. He worked at Rudolf and Maher in Chapel Hill, North Carolina from 1998 to 2004 He was a solo practitioner from 1997 to 1998.&nbsp;Judge Schopler received his J.D. from Harvard Law School in 1997 and his B.A., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Dartmouth College in 1994. He has served in the United States Army Reserve and California Army National Guard since 2014.</p>



<ol type="1" start="5"><li><strong><u>Judge James Edward Simmons Jr: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Southern District of California</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge James Edward Simmons Jr. has been a judge on the California Superior Court since 2017. He is currently the Supervising Judge of the North County Branch of the San Diego Superior Court. From 2006 to 2017, he was a Deputy District Attorney in the San Diego District Attorney’s Office. In 2005, Judge Simmons was a Deputy City Attorney in the San Diego City Attorney’s Office. Judge Simmons received his J.D from Golden Gate University School of Law in 2004 and B.A. from the University of California, Berkeley in 2001.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>D.C. Court of Appeals</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Vijay Shanker: Candidate for D.C Court of Appeals</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Vijay Shanker is the Deputy Chief of the Appellate Section in the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice, where he has worked since 2005. He was previously Counselor and Acting Deputy Chief of Staff to the Assistant Attorney General for the Criminal Division and Senior Litigation Counsel in the Criminal Division’s Fraud Section at the Department of Justice. Mr. Shanker was an associate at Mayer Brown from 2004 to 2005 and at Covington &amp; Burling from 1999 to 2000 and 2001 to 2004. He served as a law clerk for Judge Chester J. Straub on the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit from 2000 to 2001. Mr. Shanker received his J.D., Order of the Coif, from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1999 and his B.A., <em>cum laude</em>, from Duke University in 1994.</p>



<p><strong><u>D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Laura Crane: Candidate for D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Laura Cranehas served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia since 2014. Before joining the United States Attorney’s Office, Ms. Crane was a senior associate at WilmerHale in Washington, D.C. from 2013 to 2014 and a litigation associate at Cravath, Swaine, and Moore in New York City from 2010 to 2012. She served as a law clerk for the Judge James E. Boasberg on the United States District Court for the District of Columbia from 2012 to 2013. Ms. Crane received her J.D., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from the Washington University School of Law om 2009 and her B.A., <em>magna cum laude,</em> from Duke University in 2003.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Veronica Sanchez: Candidate for the D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Veronica Sanchez is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia, a role she has held since 2009. Ms. Sanchez was a trial attorney in the Antitrust Division of the United States Department of Justice from 2002 to 2009. She served as a law clerk for Judge Melvin Brunetti on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2001 to 2002 and for Judge Edward C. Reed on the United States District Court for the District of Nevada from 1999 to 2001. Ms. Sanchez received her J.D. from the UCLA School of Law in 1999 and her B.A. from Duke University in 1996</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement From Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on Texas Attorney General’s Lawsuit in the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of&#160;Texas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-texas-attorney-general-ken-paxtons-u-s-district-court-for-the-northern-district-of-texas-lawsuit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 19:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is yet another example of an extreme and radical Republican elected official. It is unthinkable that this public official would sue to block women from receiving life-saving care in emergency rooms, a right protected under U.S. law. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This is yet another example of an extreme and radical Republican elected official. It is unthinkable that this public official would sue to block women from receiving life-saving care in emergency rooms, a right protected under U.S. law.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Council of Governors&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/readout-of-council-of-governors-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 18:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Wednesday, July 13, senior officials from the White House, Department of Defense, and Department of Homeland Security participated in the 25th plenary meeting of the Council of Governors and the second plenary meeting under the Biden-Harris Administration to discuss homeland defense and security priorities. Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas, Deputy Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Wednesday, July 13, senior officials from the White House, Department of Defense, and Department of Homeland Security participated in the 25<sup>th</sup> plenary meeting of the Council of Governors and the second plenary meeting under the Biden-Harris Administration to discuss homeland defense and security priorities. Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro N. Mayorkas, Deputy Secretary of Defense Dr. Kath Hicks, Assistant to the President Julie Chavez Rodriguez, and Special Assistant to the President Caitlin Durkovich provided opening remarks along with the Co-Chairs of the Council of Governors, Ohio Governor Mike DeWine and Minnesota Governor Tim Walz. The Council of Governors members received updates on cybersecurity, disaster preparedness, workforce development, and support for military families.  The Council also received an overview of the National Defense Strategy from Assistant Secretary Melissa Dalton, an update on preparedness for the 2022 disaster season from FEMA Administrator Criswell, and information on the strategic guidelines for the Department of Defense Fiscal year 2024 program from Under Secretary of Defense McCord.  Finally, Director Aylward provided an overview of the progress made on the 50<sup>th</sup> Anniversary Vietnam War commemoration efforts. </p>



<p><br>Participants from the Council of Governors included:</p>



<ul><li>Governor Tim Walz (MN), Co-Chair of the Council of Governors</li><li>Governor Mike DeWine (OH), Co-Chair of the Council of Governors</li><li>Governor John Carney (DE)</li><li>Governor John Bel Edwards (LA)</li><li>Governor Gretchen Whitmer (MI)</li><li>Governor Kate Brown (OR)</li><li>Governor Spencer Cox (UT)</li><li>Governor Phil Scott (VT)</li><li>Governor Mark Gordon (WY)</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Israeli Presidential Medal of Honor&#160;Reception</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/14/remarks-by-president-biden-at-israeli-presidential-medal-of-honor-reception/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 17:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President&#8217;s Residence GardenJerusalem, Israel 6:08 P.M. IDT&#160; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; President Herzog, it&#8217;s wonderful to be with you again and an honor to be with so many familiar faces out in this garden. You know, if anyone should understand my inclination to enthusiasm, you should be.  With a &#8212; with a grandfather who thought Sinn Féin&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">President&#8217;s Residence Garden<br>Jerusalem, Israel</p>



<p>6:08 P.M. IDT&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; President Herzog, it&#8217;s wonderful to be with you again and an honor to be with so many familiar faces out in this garden.</p>



<p>You know, if anyone should understand my inclination to enthusiasm, you should be.  With a &#8212; with a grandfather who thought Sinn Féin was the future of Ireland, you should understand that.  (Laughter.)</p>



<p>You all think I&#8217;m kidding; I&#8217;m not.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; A great day for the Irish.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve known many of you for a long time.&nbsp; And all of you, you know that my love for Israel is deep rooted.&nbsp; I was raised, as we say and you say, by a righteous Christian &#8212; my dad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’ve had the honor &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to say these words &#8212; for over 50 years &#8212; it can&#8217;t be that long &#8212; but for over 50 years in the federal government to helping build the relationship.&nbsp; Fifty years ago, we never had this audience before.&nbsp; We would not have this audience out here.&nbsp; We have so many people represented, representing so many different nations and faiths as well.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s important.</p>



<p>But, you know, seeing Israel thrive, seeing the wildest dreams of Israel&#8217;s founding fathers and mothers grow into a reality that Israel children enjoy today, to me is close to miraculous.&nbsp; You&#8217;re always &#8212; there&#8217;s a &#8212; we use, in the Catholic Church, a hymn that&#8217;s based on one of the Psalms.&nbsp; And it says, &#8220;May He raise you up on eagle&#8217;s wings and bear you on the breath of dawn.&nbsp; Until we meet again, may God hold you in the palm of his hand.&#8221;</p>



<p>Well, every time I&#8217;ve come over these years, thank God, God seems to be holding us in the palm of his hand, because we get stronger, not weaker.&nbsp; And to me, it&#8217;s pretty miraculous.</p>



<p>The Torah tells a story of the prophet who described the ancient Israeli &#8212; Israe- &#8212; Israelis as the people that &#8220;dwell alone&#8221; &#8212; in the Torah portion that will be read in services across the United States this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I know, President Herzog, that your uncle also wrote a book with that title.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; But as I look out on these proud, strong Israelis in the audience, at the nation that made the desert bloom and built the Iron Dome, I see people who are growing more secure, more integrated, more confident, and more &#8212; have greater relations with their neighbors; a nation that has forged peace before and can do it again; and a nation that will never dwell alone.&nbsp; Because as long as we’re the United States, you will never, ever be alone.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you know, there&#8217;s still so much more work to be done.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why America&#8217;s commitment to Israel’s security remains ironclad.&nbsp; Today and in the future, that commitment is not about me or any other American president.&nbsp; It springs from the deep affinity and enduring connection between our peoples.&nbsp; And it is our responsibility as leaders to nurture that bond, to ensure that it grows stronger, deeper, and broader as we navigate the challenges ahead &#8212; and they will continue to be profound and they will change.</p>



<p>And as a leader, I can say without hesitation that being known as a friend of Israel and receiving this award today is among the greatest honors of my career.&nbsp; And I mean that from the bottom of my heart. (Applause.)&nbsp; In fact &#8212;<br><br>And thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Since I know that you and I share a connection, as I said, to Ireland, I hope you forgive me for ending by quoting an Irish poet, Seamus Heaney.&nbsp; And he wrote &#8212; in “The Cure at Troy,” he said: “History says, Don’t hope on this side of the grave.&nbsp; But then, once in a lifetime, that longed-for tidal wave of justice rises up, and hope and history rhyme.”<br><br>I truly believe that we&#8217;re at one of those moments, if we get lucky and work hard, where we can make hope and history rhyme.<br><br>Israel and the United States are both places built on hope, grit, and determination.&nbsp; And I believe, together, we will stay always true to our founding values and that we can help make hope and history rhyme once more.&nbsp; But this time &#8212; this time, in one of the most dysfunctional, in the past, regions of the world where you, again, will be fully integrated and be one of the leaders.<br><br>So, Mr. President, it&#8217;s an incredible honor.&nbsp; And, as some of you heard me say, if my mother were here, she’d say, “Joey, hush up and let the man get on with his job.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>So, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; So, Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (Speaks Hebrew.)<br><br>President of the State of Israel, Isaac Herzog, will bestow the Presidential Medal of Honor upon the President of the United States of America, Joe Biden.<br><br>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; So, the Honorable President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., in recognition of the strong support for Israel you have consistently demonstrated, and the depth of the friendship our nations share, I wish to present you with the highest honor bestowed by an Israeli President, the Presidential Medal of Honor.&nbsp; This tradition was instituted by the late president and your good friend, Shimon Peres.<br><br>The accompanying certificate reads, and I begin with quoting the Bible:&nbsp; (Speaks Hebrew.)&nbsp; “With Him are wisdom and strength.&nbsp; He has counsel and understanding.”</p>



<p>The Presidential Medal of Honor is hereby awarded to the Honorable President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States of America for his true friendship with the State of Israel, the people of Israel, and the Jewish people; his uncompromising, decades-long commitment to Israel&#8217;s security; his contributions to deepening, strengthening, and enhancing the strong and unwavering alliance between Israel and the United States of America; and his struggle against anti-Israeli and antisemitic hatred around the world.”<br><br>(The Medal of Honor is presented.)&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; What a great honor.&nbsp; Thank you very, very much.<br><br>PRESIDENT HERZOG:&nbsp; A pleasure.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p> 6:14 P.M. IDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Yair Lapid of the State of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-yair-lapid-of-the-state-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 17:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Waldorf AstoriaJerusalem, Israel 2:34 P.M. IDT  PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&#160; Mr. President, in March, 1965, on Dr. Martin Luther King&#8217;s famous march from Selma to Montgomery, walking beside him in the front row was a Jewish rabbi &#8212; Rabbi Abraham Joshua Heschel.&#160; When he returned home this &#8212; that day, Rabbi Heschel wrote in his diary,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Waldorf Astoria<br>Jerusalem, Israel</p>



<p>2:34 P.M. IDT </p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; Mr. President, in March, 1965, on Dr. Martin Luther King&#8217;s famous march from Selma to Montgomery, walking beside him in the front row was a Jewish rabbi &#8212; Rabbi Abraham Joshua Heschel.&nbsp; When he returned home this &#8212; that day, Rabbi Heschel wrote in his diary, “Today, I felt my legs were praying.”<br><br>In the State of Israel, Mr. President, our legs pray every single day.&nbsp; Nothing is &#8212; in our lives is taken for granted.&nbsp; My father was a Jewish child in the Budapest ghetto, hiding from those who tried to kill him.<br><br>The fact that I am standing here today did not happen by itself.&nbsp; We learned the lesson, Mr. President: At all times, Israel must be strong, free, and safe, with a powerful army that can defend our citizens.<br><br>Be it Joshua crossing the Jordan River or Dr. King crossing the Alabama River, the principle is the same: If you want your independence, your hands must defend you and your legs must pray for you.&nbsp; You must march fearlessly towards the river.&nbsp;<br><br>This past year, with Russia&#8217;s unjustified invasion of Ukraine, with the Iranian nuclear threat becoming more dangerous, and with the threats of terrorism worldwide, we were all reminded of something: In order to protect freedom, sometimes force must be used.&nbsp; Nobody wants that, but neither can we shy away from it, on the side of terrorists and people who will not hesitate to exploit any weakness, people who do not &#8212; who do not play by the rules.<br><br>Those of us who were fortunate enough to be born free people sometimes do not understand the intensity of the hatred behind the attack on democracy.<br><br>What we &#8212; did we do to them?&nbsp; What makes them crash planes into skyscrapers in New York and fire rockets at kindergartens in the city of Sderot?&nbsp; The answer is fear.<br><br>What scares them the most is that their citizens, their people can see us, can see our quality of life &#8212; the dynamism and creativity of our economy, the rights of women and the LGBTQ community, freedom of religion, freedom of speech.&nbsp;<br><br>Our way of life is what threatens them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s what makes the Iranian regime develop is &#8212; its nuclear program, Hezbollah aim its missiles at us, and terrorist organizations worldwide send suicide bombers.&nbsp; They want to destroy the only Jewish state in the world.&nbsp; That &#8212; we will never let that happen.&nbsp;<br><br>Words will not stop them, Mr. President.&nbsp; Diplomacy will not stop them.&nbsp; The only thing that will stop Iran is knowing that the &#8212; if they continue to develop their nuclear program, the free world will use force.&nbsp; The only way to stop them is to put a credible military threat on the table.<br><br>You have said many times, Mr. President, that big countries do not bluff.&nbsp; I completely agree.&nbsp; It should not be a bluff but the real thing.&nbsp; The Iranian regime must know that if they continue to deceive the world, they will pay a heavy price.&nbsp;<br><br>Here in the Middle East, we have an alternative now.&nbsp; It is growing and gaining power.&nbsp; We are creating an alliance of moderate countries that believe in peace, that believe that our children deserve the opportunity to live a better life.<br><br>From here, from Jerusalem &#8212; the eternal capital of the State of Israel &#8212; you will travel to Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; Your visit to Saudi Arabia is important for Israel and for the entire region, for our security and for the future and prosp- &#8212; prosperity of the Middle East.</p>



<p>We send with you, to all the nations of the region &#8212; including, of course, the Palestinians &#8212; a message of peace.&nbsp;<br><br>Israel wants peace and believes in peace.&nbsp; We will never yield an inch of our security.&nbsp; We are obligated to be cautious at every step.&nbsp; But to any country, any nation that wants peace and normalization with us, we say, “<em>Ahlan wa sahlan</em>. <em>Shalom</em>.&nbsp; Welcome.”<br><br>Mr. President, you will meet with the leaders of Saudi Arabia, Qatar, Kuwait, Oman, and Iraq.&nbsp; I would like you to pass them all a message from us:<br><br>Our hand is outstretched for peace.&nbsp; We are ready to share our technology and experience, ready for our people to meet and learn about one another, ready for our scientists to collaborate and our businesses to cooperate.<br><br>The Book of Psalms says all of this in one verse.&nbsp; Chapter 29 reads, “(Speaks Hebrew.)&nbsp; The Lord will give strength to His people.&nbsp; The Lord will bless His people with peace.”<br><br>If we are strong, if we are determined, if the world understands that we will not hesitate to defend ourselves and our values, peace can come.<br><br>Mr. President, our relationship runs deep.&nbsp; It crosses party lines.&nbsp; It connects not only our governments but also our peoples.<br><br>This friendship is one of the cornerstones of Israel&#8217;s national security.&nbsp; It is moving, and it is certainly not taken for granted.<br><br>Throughout all your years in public service, you were one of the chief architects of this relationship.&nbsp; For that, you have the everlasting gratitude of the people of Zion.<br><br>Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Prime Minister.&nbsp; An eloquent statement.<br><br>I&#8217;m honored to be back here in the capital of Israel.</p>



<p>As I said yesterday, I’ve met every Prime Minister</p>



<p>since Golda Meir, and it was a pleasure to be able to spend some time with you today and to get to know you better.</p>



<p>Mr. Prime Minister, a deep love and respect for Israel has only taken a deeper hold of my heart and my gut since I first visited here back in 1973 as a young senator.<br><br></p>



<p>I’m returning for my 10th visit as Pres- &#8212; this time, as President of the United States.&nbsp; But I’ve never forgotten</p>



<p>what Prime Minister Meir told me when I was a brand new junior senator from the state of Delaware.&nbsp; It was just weeks before the Yom Kippur War, and she could see on my face that I was worried.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we stood before the press taking questions and pictures, she looked at me, and without press hearing, she said, “Don’t look so worried, Senator.&nbsp; Israel has a secret weapon.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I looked at her as I turned my head, and she was tell- &#8212; I just looked at her and she said, &#8220;We have nowhere else to go.”&nbsp; I&#8217;ll never forget what she told me.&nbsp; That was nearly 50 years ago.&nbsp; Fifty years ago, the threats then were real.&nbsp; And the threats to Israel remain real today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The scourge of antisemitism still marches around the world, and we must never forget the horrors which an unchecked hatred can lead.</p>



<p>And that’s why I immediately &#8212; when I returned, I wanted to visit Yad Vashem &#8212; when I landed yesterday &#8212; to bear witness, to remember, to renew our vow of: never &#8212; never again.</p>



<p>At the same time, the Israeli &#8212; the Israel of today is not the Israel of 50 years ago.</p>



<p>You’ve cultivated new resources, capabilities, new relationships, including a growing integration with neighbors in the region.</p>



<p>You have new tools that keep Israel strong and secure.&nbsp; You have an ironclad commitment from the United States of America to Israel’s security.&nbsp; An ironclad commitment.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll make sure that Israel can defend itself by itself.</p>



<p>When I was Vice President under President Obama, we passed a record-setting agreement for Israel’s security &#8212; $38 billion over a 10-year period.</p>



<p>And I was proud that, last year, we also provided an additional $1 billion to replenish Israel’s Iron Dome supplies, making 2022 the largest single year of military assistance that Israel has ever received.</p>



<p>Yesterday, I viewed some of Israel’s Iron Dome technology, as well as the very promising new Iron Beam technology &#8212; a laser-enabled missile defense system.&nbsp; These technologies and advancements are critical.&nbsp; They&#8217;re critical because every rocket that is intercepted is a potential life &#8212; perhaps more &#8212; that has been saved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as we move forward together, partners in both security and in innovation, the United States and Israel defense sectors will cooperate in new high-energy laser weapons systems that can defend Israel &#8212; Israeli lives, as well as the lives of American service members.</p>



<p>Israel and the United States also stand together to defend the fundamental values and underwrite global security, prosperity, and freedom, not just for us but for many around the world.</p>



<p>And Putin’s assault on Ukraine is a challenge to the peace and stability everywhere in the world.&nbsp; Putin’s war must be a strategic failure, and the free world must sustain our resolve to help Ukraine defend its democracy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States will continue to support Ukraine and the Ukrainian people who have been devastated and displaced by the Russian violence.</p>



<p>Today, you and I also discussed America’s commitment to ensuring Iran never obtains a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a vital security interest to both Israel and the United States and, I would add, for the rest of the world as well.</p>



<p>I continue to believe that diplomacy is the best way to achieve this outcome.</p>



<p>And we’ll continue to work with Israel to counter other threats from Iran throughout the region, including its support for terrorism and the ballistic missile program that continues, and the proliferation of weapons to terrorists and proxies like Hezbollah.</p>



<p>We’ll also continue building on the Abraham Accords, which I strongly support, because they deepen &#8212; they deepen Israel’s integration into the broader region and establish lasting ties for business, cooperation, and tourism.</p>



<p>We’ve just completed the first leaders’ summit among Israel, India, the United States, and the United Arab Emirates</p>



<p>to deepen the economic ties between the Middle East and the Indo-Pacific, to create new partnerships to tackle global challenges, like food insecurity and clean energy technology.</p>



<p>Regional integration is also the goal of the historic Negev Forum, which took place here in Israel this past March.</p>



<p>Israel’s integration in the region, Israel’s peace with its neighbors &#8212; these are essential goals.</p>



<p>Tomorrow I’ll be the first American President to fly from Israel directly to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; That represents important progress.</p>



<p>And when I see the Saudi leadership tomorrow, I’ll be carrying a direct message &#8212; a message of peace and extraordinary opportunities that a more stable and integrated region could bring to the region and, quite frankly, the whole world.</p>



<p>As we work together toward greater integration &#8212; greater integration, we’ll also continue to work for &#8212; toward a lasting negotiated peace between the State of Israel and the Palestinian people.</p>



<p>Israel must remain an independent, democratic, Jewish state &#8212; the ultimate guarantee and guarantor of security of the Jewish people not only in Israel but the entire world.&nbsp; I believe that to my core.</p>



<p>And the best way to achieve that remains a two-state solution for two people, both of whom have deep and ancient roots in this land, living side-by-side in peace and security.&nbsp; Both states fully respecting the equal rights of their citizens;&nbsp;both people enjoying equal measures of freedom.</p>



<p>And any more that takes us further from that outcome &#8212; I believe &#8212; anything is detrimental to the long-term security of Israel.</p>



<p>Prime Minister Lapid, Israel and the United States are natural partners because we share the same values.&nbsp; Our people share the same innovative spirit, the same determination to preserve and persevere through every single challenge.</p>



<p>That’s why we’re launching a new High-Level Strategic Dialogue on Technology that’s going to help Israel and the United States harness critical and emerging technologies and apply them to issues that matter most to our mutual futures.</p>



<p>So thank you, Mr. <s>President</s> [Prime Minister], for welcoming me back, for fostering the enduring bonds, and continuing them, that link the people of Israel and the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s what this visit is about: affirming those ties that stretch back to just 11 minutes &#8212; 11 minutes after Israel declared statehood, when the United States became the first country in the world to recognize Israel.&nbsp; And I assure you, it will be the last country in the world ever to walk away from Israel.<br><br>Ties that have grown deeper and broader with each passing year and now encompass a 21st-century partnership, one grounded on ageless values and looking squarely at the future.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re here to stay, Mr. President &#8212; Mr. Prime Minister.&nbsp; Like it or not, we’re with you.&nbsp; There’s no way out.<br><br>I want to thank you very, very much for your hospitality.&nbsp; And I mean it from the bottom of my heart that your security, the security &#8212; the &#8212; is going to determine the security of Jewish people around the world for the rest of the world.&nbsp; It’s critical.&nbsp; And we’re in it with you.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Mr. President.&nbsp; And before we move on to the &#8212; a question, there was a technical change on the stage.</p>



<p>(An adjustment is made to the onstage technical equipment.)</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; These guys work awful hard.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; Yes, we&#8217;re just standing here.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; We will now be taking questions from the press.&nbsp; The first one to ask a question to Ms. Gili Cohen from Channel 11, Israeli television.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I want to ask: Will you set a deadline for the nuclear talks or define a certain stage when you will say there is no more opportunity to revive the nuclear deal?&nbsp; And what will happen afterwards?<br><br>And another question, sir.&nbsp; You’ll visit, tomorrow, East Jerusalem, and you won&#8217;t be accompanied by an Israeli official.&nbsp; Does this represent a change in your administration&#8217;s view regarding the recognition of Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and if East Jerusalem is part of it?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; The answer to your last question is no.<br><br>With regard to your first question, we&#8217;ve laid out for the people &#8212; for the leadership of Iran what we&#8217;re willing to accept in order to get back in the JCPOA.&nbsp; We&#8217;re waiting for their response.&nbsp; When that recur- &#8212; when that will come, I&#8217;m not certain.&nbsp; But we are not going to wait forever.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Mr. President, do you want to &#8212;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; The question was for the President.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Mr. President, do you want to call on the next question?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I was given a list here.&nbsp; Steve Holland of Reuters.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; There is some opposition back home to your meeting with Saudi leaders this week.&nbsp; What will you say to Saudi leaders, specifically to Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, about the Khashoggi murder and other human rights practices?<br><br>And if I may, Prime Minister Lapid, how close are you to an agreement with Saudi Arabia to gain overflight rights?&nbsp; And should we expect that soon?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; With regard to the question you asked me, my views on Khashoggi have &#8212; they’ve been absolutely, positively clear.&nbsp; And I have never been quiet about talking about human rights.<br><br>The question that I&#8217;m &#8212; the reason I&#8217;m going to Saudi Arabia, though, is much broader.&nbsp; It’s to promote U.S. interests &#8212; promote U.S. interests in a way that I think we have an opportunity to reassert what I think we made a mistake of walking away from: our influence in the Middle East.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to be meeting with nine other heads of state.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just &#8212; it happens to be in Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; And so, there are so many issues at stake that I want to make clear that we can continue to lead in the region and not create a vacuum, a vacuum that is filled by China and/or Russia, against the interests of both Israel and the United States and many other countries.<br><br>And so the purpose of the visit is to &#8212; is to coordinate with nine heads of state what are in U.S. interests and I believe in Israel&#8217;s interests as well.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you don&#8217;t expect to bring up human rights?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s let the Prime Minister &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I will bring up &#8212; I always bring up human rights.&nbsp; I always bring up human rights.&nbsp; But my position on Khashoggi has been so clear.&nbsp; If anyone doesn&#8217;t understand it in Saudi Arabia and everywhere else, then they haven&#8217;t been around for a while.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; About the overflights of Saudi Arabia, of course, as I was saying in my speech, we are all for promoting normalizations with every country in the region that it is possible.&nbsp; But since the President is going to Saudi Arabia, and he &#8212; there will be a finalization of the issues over there, I will let the President finalize this when he&#8217;s in Jeddah.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, Prime Minister.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m optimistic.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br><br></p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; And the next question will come from Ms. Tal&nbsp; Schneider from Times of Israel.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, hello.&nbsp; Thank you for being in Jerusalem.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good to see you.<br><br>Israelis have been waiting to hear developments on the Visa Waiver Program.&nbsp; We know that there are hurdles but &#8212; to get there.&nbsp; But can you set a deadline after which Israelis will be granted with a waiver to enter the U.S.?&nbsp; Will you bring this issue with the opposition leader, Netanyahu, when you meet him today?<br><br>And another question for our prime minister: There is a discussion about regional defense cooperation that includes Israel and the Saudis, but we hear that there are technical difficulties as well as other reservations from the Saudis with respect to defense system, which means it&#8217;s mostly about Israel sharing its intelligence, its intel.&nbsp; How do you see the cooperation moving along with those problems?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; With regard to your question to me, we are working very, very, very hard to eliminate the lack of precision in the applications, many times, for the visa program.&nbsp; It is my hope and expectation that in the next several months, we&#8217;ll have it worked out.</p>



<p><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; And jumping on the subject, and we urge the Israeli opposition to become &#8212; to be more responsible and help with the legislation needed to finalize this.<br><br>As for your question, it is no secret that we&#8217;re doing our best, with our American friends, to work on a regional security architecture.&nbsp; So this was no secret.&nbsp; The details of this apparently are, so I&#8217;m not going to go into details on this.&nbsp;<br><br>But we are working with everybody we can in order to promote regional security, especially facing Iran&#8217;s regime and the terror policy they bring to the table.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; The next person to ask a question, I guess &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; is Nadia.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Nadia Bilbassy of Al Arabiya Television.&nbsp; Allow me to press you a little bit on Iran, if I may.</p>



<p><br>You visited the &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; No, I’m not going to allow that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; We got to &#8212; we got to walk off.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; You are &#8212; you are visiting the Middle East here in Israel and then you go into Saudi Arabia where you meeting with King Salman and other GCC leaders.<br><br>You know in advance, before you come here, their position, their concern, their fear about Iran nuclear program and Iran&#8217;s support for proxies in the region.<br><br>Tangibly, what are you offering them to assuage their fear and concern, practically?&nbsp; Is this anything that you&#8217;re offering them to make them feel comfortable that the United States are on the same page with them?<br><br>And if I may, Mr. Prime Minister, what are the differences and the similarities between you and President Biden regarding Iran?&nbsp; Do you see eye to eye on all the issues?&nbsp; You alluded to some differences just now.<br><br>And, if I may, I wanted you to confirm to us today your position in supporting the two-state solution as a caretaker Prime Minister and if should you be elected as the next prime minister of Israel.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; With regard to Iran and convincing the Saudis and others that we’re &#8212; mean what we say is we mean what we say.&nbsp; They have an opportunity to accept this agreement that’s been laid down.&nbsp; If they don&#8217;t, we made it absolutely clear: We will not &#8212; let me say it again &#8212; we will not allow Iran to acquire a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p><br>PRIME MINISTER LAPID:&nbsp; Well, with regards to the question about Iran, we have an open discussion about what is the best way to deal with it.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a light between us in terms of &#8212; these are all means to an end.<br><br>We cannot allow Iran to become nuclear.&nbsp; Israel asserts the right to act freely on the subject.&nbsp; But we are, of course, discussing everything with our greatest ally, which is the United States.<br><br>About the two-state solution, I haven&#8217;t changed my position.&nbsp; A two-state solution is a guarantee for a strong democratic state of Israel with a Jewish majority.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; This concludes the signing ceremony and the press conference.&nbsp; Please remain seated until the leaders have left the room.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you all so much.<br><br>2:59 P.M. IDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Herzog of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-herzog-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:48:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met with President Isaac Herzog of Israel today ahead of the Israeli Medal of Honor ceremony this evening. The leaders discussed several issues including the United States’ ironclad support for Israel’s security, their commitment to working together to counter Iran’s destabilizing activities, and efforts to promote regional integration to widen the circle of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met with President Isaac Herzog of Israel today ahead of the Israeli Medal of Honor ceremony this evening. The leaders discussed several issues including the United States’ ironclad support for Israel’s security, their commitment to working together to counter Iran’s destabilizing activities, and efforts to promote regional integration to widen the circle of peace. President Biden and President Herzog reaffirmed the deep bonds and enduring friendship between our two nations and our people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves North Dakota Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/14/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-north-dakota-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of North Dakota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and flooding during the period of April 22 to May 25, 2022. Federal funding is available&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of North Dakota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement State, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and flooding during the period of April 22 to May 25, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to State, tribal, eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm and flooding in the counties of Adams, Barnes, Billings, Bottineau,&nbsp; Burke, Cavalier, Dickey, Divide, Dunn, Foster, Golden Valley, Grand Forks, Grant, Griggs, Hettinger, Kidder, LaMoure, Logan, McHenry, McIntosh, McKenzie, McLean, Mountrail, Nelson, Oliver, Pembina, Ramsey, Ransom, Renville, Richland, Rolette, Sargent, Steele, Stutsman, Towner, Traill, Walsh, Ward, Wells, and Williams.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Alana B. Kuhn as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the State and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Minnesota Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/14/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-minnesota-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 16:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57458</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Minnesota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, and flooding during the period of April 22 to June 15, 2022. Federal funding is available to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Minnesota and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms, straight-line winds, and flooding during the period of April 22 to June 15, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms, straight-line winds, and flooding in the counties of Beltrami, Clearwater, Cook, Kittson, Koochiching, Lake, Lake of the Woods, Mahnomen, Marshall, Norman, Pennington, Polk, Red Lake, Roseau, and St. Louis and the Bois Forte Band of Chippewa, Leech Lake Band of Ojibwe, Red Lake Nation, and the White Earth Nation.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures in all areas within the state.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Brian F. Schiller as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp;FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
