<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:32:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Addressing the Long-Term Effects of&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/05/memorandum-on-addressing-the-long-term-effects-of-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES SUBJECT:      Addressing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19  By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows: Section 1.  Policy.  My Administration has made combating the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES</p>



<p>SUBJECT:      Addressing the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19 </p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, it is hereby ordered as follows:<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1</span>.  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Policy</span>.  My Administration has made combating the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic, and guiding the Nation through the worst public health crisis in more than a century, our top priority.  When I came into office, COVID-19 was wreaking havoc on our country &#8212; closing our businesses, keeping our kids out of school, and forcing us into isolation.  Today, America has the tools to protect against COVID-19 and to dramatically decrease its risks.  We move towards a future in which COVID-19 does not disrupt our daily lives and is something we prevent, protect against, and treat.<br><br>As we chart the path forward, we remember the more than 950,000 people in the United States lost to COVID-19.  They were beloved parents, grandparents, children, siblings, spouses, neighbors, and friends.  More than 200,000 children in the United States have lost a parent or caregiver to the disease.  Each soul is irreplaceable, and the families and communities left behind are still reeling from profound loss.  Many families and communities have already received support from Federal programs that help with the loss they have experienced.  As we move forward, we commit to ensuring that families and communities can access these support programs and connect to resources they may need to help with their healing, health, and well-being.<br><br>At the same time, many of our family members, neighbors, and friends continue to experience negative long-term effects of COVID-19.  Many individuals report debilitating, long-lasting effects of having been infected with COVID-19, often called &#8220;long COVID.&#8221;  These symptoms can happen to anyone who has had COVID-19 &#8212; including individuals across ages, races, genders, and ethnicities; individuals with or without disabilities; individuals with or without underlying health conditions; and individuals whether or not they had initial symptoms.  Individuals experiencing long COVID report experiencing new or recurrent symptoms, which can include anxiety and depression, fatigue, shortness of breath, difficulty concentrating, heart palpitations, disordered sleep, chest and joint pain, headaches, and other symptoms.  These symptoms can persist long after the acute COVID-19 infection has resolved.  Even young people and otherwise healthy people have reported long COVID symptoms that last for many months.  These symptoms may be affecting individuals&#8217; ability to work, conduct daily activities, engage in educational activities, and participate in their communities.  Our world-class research and public health organizations have begun the difficult work of understanding these new conditions, their causes, and potential prevention and treatment options.  Our health care and support programs are working to help meet the needs of individuals experiencing the lasting effects of COVID-19.  To organize the Federal Government&#8217;s response, executive departments and agencies (agencies) must work together to use the expertise, resources, and benefit programs of the Federal Government to ensure that we are accelerating scientific progress and providing individuals with the support and services they need.<br><br>In addition, the American public is grappling with a mental health crisis exacerbated by the pandemic. Too many have felt the effects of social isolation, sickness, economic insecurity, increased caregiver burdens, and grief.  My Administration has made significant investments in mental health as well as substance use disorder prevention, treatment, and recovery support for the American public, including by expanding access to community-based behavioral health services.  We are committed to advancing these behavioral health efforts in order to better identify the effects of the pandemic on mental health, substance use, and well-being, and to take steps to address these effects for the people we serve.<br><br>Our Nation can continue to protect the public &#8212; and spare countless families from the deepest pain imaginable &#8212; if everybody does their part.  Today, we have numerous tools to protect ourselves and our loved ones from COVID-19 &#8212; from vaccines to tests, treatments, masks, and more.  My Administration recognizes the toll of this pandemic on the American public and commits to redoubling our efforts to support the American people in addressing the long-term effects of COVID-19 on their lives and on society.<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec</span>. <span style="text-decoration: underline">2</span>.  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Organizing the Government-Wide Response to the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19</span>.  (a)  The Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) shall coordinate the Government-wide response to the long-term effects of COVID-19.  My Administration will harness the full potential of the Federal Government, in coordination with public- and private-sector partners, to mount a full and effective response.  The Secretary shall report on the coordination efforts to the Coordinator of the COVID-19 Response and Counselor to the President and to the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy.<br><br>     (b)  The heads of agencies shall assist and provide information to the Secretary, consistent with applicable law, as may be necessary to carry out the Secretary&#8217;s duties described in subsection (a) of this section.<br><br>     (c)  In performing the duties described in subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall seek information from relevant nongovernmental experts, organizations, and stakeholders, including individuals affected directly by the long-term effects of COVID-19.  The Secretary shall consider using all available legal authorities, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to assist in gathering relevant information, including a waiver under 42 U.S.C. 247d(f).<br><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec</span>. <span style="text-decoration: underline">3</span>.  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Report on the Long-Term Effects of COVID-19</span>.  The Secretary, supported within the Department of Health and Human Services by the Assistant Secretary for Health and the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall publish a public report within 120 days of the date of this memorandum outlining services and mechanisms of support across agencies to assist the American public in the face of the far-reaching and long-term effects of COVID-19.  The report shall outline Federal Government services to support individuals experiencing long COVID, individuals and families experiencing a loss due to COVID-19, and all those grappling with mental health and substance use issues in the wake of this pandemic.  The report shall also specifically address the long-term effects of COVID-19 on underserved communities and efforts to address disparities in availability and adoption of services and support for such communities.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec</span>. <span style="text-decoration: underline">4</span>.  <span style="text-decoration: underline">National Research Action Plan on Long COVID</span>.  (a)  Coordinated efforts across the public and private sectors are needed to advance progress in prevention, diagnosis, treatment, and provision of services for individuals experiencing long COVID.  The Secretary, supported by the Assistant Secretary for Health and in collaboration with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Energy, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall coordinate a Government-wide effort to develop the first-ever interagency national research agenda on long COVID, to be reflected in a National Research Action Plan.  The National Research Action Plan will build on ongoing efforts across the Federal Government, including the landmark RECOVER Initiative implemented by the National Institutes of Health.  The Secretary shall release the jointly developed National Research Action Plan within 120 days of the date of this memorandum.<br><br>     (b)  The National Research Action Plan shall build upon existing research efforts and include strategies to:<br><br>          (i)     help measure and characterize long COVID in both children and adults, including with respect to its frequency, severity, duration, risk factors, and trends over time;<br><br>          (ii)    support the development of estimates on prevalence and incidence of long COVID disaggregated by demographic groups and symptoms;<br><br>          (iii)   better understand the epidemiology, course of illness, risk factors, and vaccine effectiveness in prevention of long COVID;<br><br>          (iv)    advance our understanding of the health and socioeconomic burdens on individuals affected by long COVID, including among different race and ethnicity groups, pregnant people, and those with underlying disabilities;<br><br>          (v)     foster development of new treatments and care models for long COVID based on a better understanding of the pathophysiological mechanisms of the SARS-CoV-2 virus;<br><br>          (vi)    inform decisions related to high-quality support, services, and interventions for long COVID;<br><br>          (vii)   improve data-sharing between agencies and academic and industry researchers about long COVID, to the extent permitted by law; and<br><br>          (viii)  specifically account for the pandemic&#8217;s effect on underserved communities and rural populations.<br><br>Sec. 5.  General Provisions.  (a)  Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br><br>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br><br>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br><br>     (b)  This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br><br>     (c)  This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.<br><br>     (d)  The Secretary is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.<br><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Accelerates Whole-of-Government Effort to Prevent, Detect, and Treat Long&#160;COVID</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/05/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-accelerates-whole-of-government-effort-to-prevent-detect-and-treat-long-covid/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. has made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID-19. Today, Americans have the tools they need to protect against and treat the virus. At the same time, millions of individuals continue to experience prolonged illness from COVID-19, known as “Long COVID.” Many report debilitating, lasting symptoms that can persist long after the acute&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The U.S. has made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID-19. Today, Americans have the tools they need to protect against and treat the virus. At the same time, millions of individuals continue to experience prolonged illness from COVID-19, known as “Long COVID.” Many report debilitating, lasting symptoms that can persist long after the acute COVID-19 infection has resolved, and can manifest in anyone who has had COVID-19. These symptoms often look like those associated with other chronic medical conditions.</p>



<p>The Administration has mobilized to advance our nation’s understanding of Long COVID and its associated conditions, promote high-quality care for patients, and help individuals access supportive services—especially for those from communities disproportionately affected by the pandemic. The President’s National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan makes clear that we are committed to accelerating these efforts, with additional support and resources from Congress.</p>



<p>Today, President Biden issued a Presidential Memorandum directing the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to coordinate a new effort across the federal government to develop and issue the first-ever interagency national research action plan on Long COVID. The effort will advance progress in prevention, diagnosis, treatment, and provision of services, supports, and interventions for individuals experiencing Long COVID and associated conditions. The Presidential Memorandum also directs HHS to issue a report outlining services and supports across federal agencies to assist people experiencing Long COVID, individuals who are dealing with a COVID-related loss, and people who are experiencing mental health and substance use issues related to the pandemic. This report will specifically address the long-term effects of COVID-19 on high-risk communities and efforts to address disparities in access to services and supports.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement builds on the Administration’s ongoing work to implement the recommendations of the <a href="https://www.minorityhealth.hhs.gov/healthequitytaskforce/">Presidential COVID-19 Health Equity Task Force</a>. It also builds on a number of additional actions the Administration is taking to support the millions of Americans experiencing Long COVID and their families by delivering high-quality care and expanding access to services and supports, as well as actions to advance efforts to detect, prevent, and treat Long COVID.</p>



<p>These actions include:</p>



<p><strong>Delivering high-quality care for individuals experiencing Long COVID: </strong>As a complex condition that can affect multiple organ systems, Long COVID may require care and coordination across multiple medical specialties. The Administration recognizes that the COVID-19 pandemic has resulted in new members of the disability community and has had a tremendous impact on people with disabilities. The Administration will continue to center the voices of patients in this work and is advancing efforts to deliver high-quality, high-value care to people experiencing Long COVID—especially communities hardest-hit by COVID-19. In collaboration with patients, payers, and providers across the care continuum, the Administration will accelerate and disseminate clinical support and best practices to promote coordinated, integrated care models and expand access to high-quality care in communities across the country.</p>



<ul><li>Launching Centers of Excellence and promoting evidence-based care models: Through the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), the President’s Fiscal Year 2023 (FY23) budget will invest in a multi-year initiative, beginning with $20 million in FY23, to investigate how health care systems can best organize and deliver care for people with Long COVID, provide telementoring and expert consultation for primary care practices, and advance the development of multispecialty clinics to provide complex care. This work would fund institutions across the country that bring together leading researchers and care providers across the full care continuum – including hospitals, health centers, long-term care services and supports, and other providers – and promote the implementation of new evidence into care, especially for disproportionately affected populations. As information emerges on effective Long COVID treatments and care, AHRQ in partnership with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), Food and Drug Administration (FDA), Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA), and National Institutes of Health (NIH)—in collaboration with clinical leaders, professional societies, and the national academies—will build on existing <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/clinical-care/post-covid-index.html">interim clinical guidance</a> to get providers and patients the care information they need.</li><li>Expanding and strengthening Long COVID clinics: Across the country, 18 Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facilities have already established Long COVID care programs, consolidating multidisciplinary clinical expertise in locations veterans know and trust. The VA will expand on the success of these programs by establishing additional Long COVID programs and robust referral and follow-up systems across its facilities. These programs, and others established by hospitals and health systems across the country, are serving as a source of rapid learning and long-term research on best practices and new therapies, along with the broader provider, patient, and scientific community. The Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health (OASH) will launch the Health+ project to gain insights into the experiences and patient journeys of people living with Long COVID and associated conditions, to help inform high-quality care and contribute to standardized best practices at Long COVID clinics.</li><li>Promoting provider education and clinical support: The Administration will continue to work with providers to advance our recognition and understanding of Long COVID and associated conditions, including by sharing culturally competent information and resources through platforms like the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) Medicare Learning Network and Indian Health Service (IHS) provider education and partnerships with academic institutions. The Administration will also launch targeted clinician and medical coder education on the <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/icd/icd10cm.htm">ICD-10-CM</a> code (U09.9) effective last year to support diagnosis, billing, and tracking of Long COVID. To further support equitable access to high-quality care in communities hard-hit by the pandemic, the Administration, through the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), will continue to build sustainable telementoring programs and networks in rural and medically underserved communities. HHS will additionally convene experts across the country to provide recommendations to our nation’s providers on best practices in the identification and management of the mental and behavioral health disorders associated with Long COVID. &nbsp;</li><li>: The Administration is working to make Long COVID care as accessible as possible. CMS has clarified that, under the American Rescue Plan (ARP) requirement that state Medicaid and Children&#8217;s Health Insurance Program (CHIP) programs cover treatments for COVID-19, states must also cover treatments and therapies for Long COVID. Additionally, the essential health benefits (EHB) provided by the Affordable Care Act (ACA) generally provide coverage for the diagnosis and treatment of COVID-19, including Long COVID, though coverage and cost-sharing details vary by plan. CMS has also expanded Medicare coverage for pulmonary rehabilitation services for Long COVID care beginning in the <a href="https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/fact-sheets/calendar-year-cy-2022-medicare-physician-fee-schedule-final-rule">2022 Physician Fee Schedule</a>. Moving forward, the Administration will continue to assess opportunities to enhance access to care for Long COVID and its associated symptoms through Medicare, Medicaid, insurance marketplace coverage, and other options. The Office of Personnel Management (OPM) will also increase awareness of Long COVID among Federal Employee Health Benefit (FEHB) Program carriers—serving over 8.2 million federal employees, retirees, and their families—and call on them to closely monitor care for individuals with Long COVID. OPM will additionally enhance enrollee education on plans’ coverage of the assessment and treatment of Long COVID and associated symptoms such as respiratory illness and chronic fatigue.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Making services and supports available for individuals experiencing Long COVID:</strong> The Administration continues to work to understand Long COVID and its impact across populations, including how it interacts with other medical and physical conditions. Individuals with Long COVID may need help doing things they did by themselves in the past, or may need accommodations in their daily activities based on changes in their abilities<a>. </a>In addition to the Long COVID guidance <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-marks-anniversary-of-americans-with-disabilities-act-and-announces-resources-to-support-individuals-with-long-covid/">package</a> released during the 31st anniversary of the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), the Administration is raising awareness of Long COVID as a potential cause of disability, and strengthening services and supports available for individuals experiencing Long COVID.</p>



<ul><li>Raising awareness of Long COVID as a potential cause of disability: To protect individuals with Long COVID from discrimination, HHS and the Department of Justice (DOJ) have released <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/civil-rights/for-providers/civil-rights-covid19/guidance-long-covid-disability/index.html">guidance</a> explaining that some individuals with Long COVID may have a disability under civil rights laws, including the ADA, Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act, and Section 1557 of the Affordable Care Act. The Department of Education (ED) also released a <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/ocr-factsheet-504-20210726.pdf">resource</a> to support children, students, educators, schools, service providers, and families—providing information about Long COVID as a disability and about schools’ and public agencies’ responsibilities for the provision of services and reasonable modifications to children and students for whom Long COVID is a cause of a disability. The Administration for Community Living (ACL) and the HHS Office for Civil Rights (OCR) are continuing to disseminate resources to help people with Long COVID understand if they have a disability, educate people on their rights, and to inform organizations of their obligations.</li><li>Translating research into inclusive disability policy: Through the Social Security Administration’s close collaboration with research agencies and other entities, the Administration will continue to clarify and update policy guidance as the science develops to support inclusive disability policy and claims adjudication processes through the Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) and Supplemental Security Insurance (SSI) programs for individuals experiencing Long COVID. This includes building on its <a href="https://secure.ssa.gov/apps10/reference.nsf/links/04162021020344PM">Emergency Message on Evaluating Cases with COVID-19</a> and continuing to be responsive to findings from the medical and scientific communities about the types of evidence that can help establish impairments and identify functional limitations linked to Long COVID, when appropriate. Additionally, ACL and the Department of Labor (DOL) continue to elevate experiences of individuals with disability due to Long COVID, including on return-to-work.</li><li>Connecting people with the resources they need: The Administration will help connect people with Long COVID to information, resources, and service and support options. This includes incorporating multilingual information and support into the <a href="https://wwwn.cdc.gov/dcs/ContactUs/Form">CDC-INFO call center</a>, <a href="https://acl.gov/DIAL">Disability Information and Access Line (DIAL)</a>, and call centers run by CMS—which together receive over 3 million calls each month—and providing Long COVID-specific trainings for customer service representatives. Through ACL’s DIAL and <a href="https://eldercare.acl.gov/Public/Index.aspx">Eldercare Locator</a>, the Administration will also continue to connect older adults and individuals with disabilities to critical local services, such as transportation to receive care. IHS will additionally train business office and benefit administrator staff to assist Tribal communities in navigating Long COVID. SAMHSA will additionally collaborate with stakeholders to advance our understanding of the mental health effects of COVID-19 and promote high-quality mental and behavioral health care services for those who need it.</li><li>Strengthening support for workers experiencing Long COVID: The <a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/wysk/what-you-should-know-about-covid-19-and-ada-rehabilitation-act-and-other-eeo-laws#N">Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</a> (EEOC) and DOL recently released guidance on access to equitable employment opportunities for people experiencing the impact of COVID-19 and the symptoms of Long COVID. To protect workers experiencing Long COVID, DOL, in coordination with the EEOC, will continue supporting enforcement of the ADA, and other federal disability related nondiscrimination requirements for all workers. DOL’s <a href="https://askjan.org">Job Accommodation Network</a> (JAN) also helps individuals with Long COVID remain in or return to their jobs. This includes both resources to empower workers to request and negotiate accommodations, as well as resources for employers on effective accommodation strategies. Additionally, through the legal networks funded by ACL, the Administration will continue to support legal assistance related to Long COVID to older adults and people with disabilities.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing the nation’s understanding of Long COVID:</strong>&nbsp;Robust data and information are essential to our fight against the COVID-19 pandemic and its long-term effects. The Administration will support and accelerate research to understand, prevent, diagnose, treat, advance non-discrimination for, and otherwise support individuals with Long COVID. This includes efforts to better identify and characterize Long COVID – including with respect to its frequency, severity, duration, and risk factors; account for its impact on hard-hit and high-risk populations; and better understand its symptoms—including anxiety and depression, fatigue, shortness of breath, difficulty concentrating, heart palpitations, disordered sleep, chest and joint pain, and headache. These symptoms may look like those associated with other chronic medical conditions—including dysautonomia, myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome (ME/CFS), and mast cell activation syndrome (MCAS). In collaboration with patients, academia, providers, and other stakeholders, the Administration will continue to take critical steps to advance our scientific understanding in order to prevent, detect, and treat Long COVID.</p>



<ul><li>Launching the first-ever <em>National Research Action Plan on Long COVID</em>: Today, President Biden issued a Presidential Memorandum directing the Secretary of Health and Human Services to coordinate a new effort across the federal government to develop and issue the first-ever interagency national research action plan on Long COVID. The effort will advance progress in prevention, diagnosis, treatment, and provision of services, supports, and interventions for individuals experiencing Long COVID. This effort, building on the landmark <a href="https://recovercovid.org/">Researching COVID to Enhance Recovery</a> (RECOVER) Initiative and other initiatives across the federal government, will advance our understanding of Long COVID, foster the development of new treatments and care models, and inform services, support, and interventions for individuals experiencing Long COVID.</li><li>: Last year, the NIH launched its $1.15 billion RECOVER Initiative to advance our understanding of and ability to predict, treat, and prevent Long COVID. To help catalyze progress, the Administration will accelerate the enrollment of approximately 40,000 individuals with and without Long COVID into RECOVER’s longitudinal observational arm—in addition to advancing RECOVER’s pathobiology studies, EHR studies, and clinical trials. Equity remains at the center of the Administration’s COVID-19 response efforts, and RECOVER will focus on enrolling individuals across all ages, races, ethnicities, and socioeconomic statuses—including pregnant people, individuals with disabilities, and those from the communities hardest hit by the pandemic. RECOVER will also continue to bolster its patient-centered approach, leveraging its National Community Engagement Group—comprised of patient representatives across its pathobiology task forces and executive, steering, and oversight committees—to enable patients to shape research design and execution, listen for community feedback, and learn from patients’ first-hand experience.</li><li>Making further investments to advance Long COVID research and surveillance: Building on the $50 million CDC has already invested, the President’s FY23 budget has requested $25 million to answer key questions on the characteristics, risk factors, underlying mechanisms, and health impacts of Long COVID—through clinician engagement, electronic health data analyses, and grant funding. This includes through the <a href="https://www.covidinspire.org/">Innovative Support for Patients with SARS-CoV-2 Infections Registry (INSPIRE) study</a> by CDC, which will follow nearly 6,000 individuals nationwide for up to 18 months, and other dedicated research in Tribal and other hard-hit, high-risk communities.</li><li>Leveraging the power of federal data: With its robust, national health care databases, the U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) offers a wealth of information on the risks and burdens of COVID-19. Using data from over 600,000 individuals with COVID-19, the VA will continue advancing its work to assess the different health impacts of COVID-19 over time. This includes building on its already published analyses relying on EHR data on <a href="https://doi.org/10.1681/ASN.2021060734">kidney</a>, <a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41591-022-01689-3">cardiovascular</a>, and <a href="https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj-2021-068993">mental health</a> outcomes in people who have gotten COVID-19, through a national study surveying infected Veterans and uninfected controls about persistent symptoms. Additionally, the Department of Defense (DOD) has launched theEpidemiology, Immunology, and Clinical Characteristics of Emerging Infectious Diseases with Pandemic Potential (EPICC) study of Military Health System beneficiaries to help determine effects of COVID-19 and define clinical strategies to address them. This foundational study will not only support our military medical readiness but also our broader understanding of the disease.</li><li>Identifying workplace interventions that help keep individuals connected: To inform the development of inclusive disability policies and benefits, the DOL is scaling its work to identify early intervention strategies for workers who experience injuries or illnesses, including Long COVID, when working. DOL is expanding beyond its initial pilot study—to Kansas, Kentucky, Minnesota, Ohio, and Vermont—to help workers find alternatives as they decide whether to stay at or return to work following an illness like Long COVID.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Implementation of the Australia – United Kingdom – United&#160;States Partnership&#160;(AUKUS)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/05/fact-sheet-implementation-of-the-australia-united-kingdom-united-states-partnership-aukus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Prime Minister Scott Morrison of Australia, Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom, and President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States reviewed progress in implementing the Australia – United Kingdom – United States (AUKUS) partnership. The leaders reaffirmed their commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific, and more broadly to an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Prime Minister Scott Morrison of Australia, Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom, and President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States reviewed progress in implementing the Australia – United Kingdom – United States (AUKUS) partnership. The leaders reaffirmed their commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific, and more broadly to an international system that respects human rights, the rule of law, and the peaceful resolution of disputes free from coercion – a commitment whose importance has only grown in response to Russia’s unprovoked, unjustified, and unlawful invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Implementation of the AUKUS partnership has now begun. It has two related lines of effort.</p>



<ul><li>Submarines. AUKUS will provide Australia with a conventionally armed, nuclear powered submarine capability at the earliest possible date,&nbsp;while upholding the highest non‑proliferation standards.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Advanced capabilities. AUKUS will develop and provide joint&nbsp;advanced military capabilities to promote security and stability in the Indo-Pacific region.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Senior-Level Meetings</u></strong></p>



<p>Since AUKUS was announced on September 15, 2021, the three countries have held multiple high-level meetings.</p>



<ul><li>Senior Officials Group. On March 10, 2022, National Security Advisors from the three allies met virtually to review AUKUS progress and provide direction to the trilateral partnership going forward.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Joint Steering Groups. The three countries have held multiple Joint Steering Group meetings for each of the two AUKUS lines of effort, including in-person sessions in Canberra, London, and Washington, D.C.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Working Groups. Seventeen trilateral working groups have been established (nine relating to conventionally-armed nuclear-powered submarines, and eight relating to other advanced military capabilities); each has met multiple times.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Australia’s Future Conventionally-Armed Nuclear-Powered Submarine Capability</u></strong></p>



<p>When AUKUS was announced in September 2021, Prime Minister Morrison, Prime Minister Johnson, and President Joe Biden agreed to determine, by March 2023, the optimal pathway for an Australian conventionally-armed, nuclear-powered submarine capability. AUKUS partners have taken important steps toward implementation.</p>



<ul><li>Information exchange. The Exchange of Naval Nuclear Propulsion Information Agreement (ENNPIA) entered into force on February 8, 2022, enabling AUKUS partners to share naval nuclear propulsion information trilaterally.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Nuclear stewardship. For several weeks in February, combined teams from Australia, the United Kingdom and the United States visited multiple sites in Australia to baseline its nuclear stewardship, infrastructure, workforce, and industrial capabilities and requirements. On February 28, findings were considered by the Joint Steering Group on submarines. The Joint Steering Group will use this information as it develops the optimal pathway for Australia to acquire nuclear-powered submarines.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Australia workforce. Initial steps are underway to ensure Australia has a workforce with the necessary skills, training, and qualifications to build, operate, and sustain a conventionally-armed nuclear-powered submarine capability. For example, a cohort of Australian personnel have commenced higher-education and training opportunities in nuclear science and engineering.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>New submarine base. Prime Minister Morrison announced, on March 7, Australia’s plan to establish a future submarine base on the east coast of Australia to support the basing and disposition of future nuclear-powered submarines. This new facility will operate in conjunction with Australia’s existing submarine base in Western Australia.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Nuclear Powered Submarine Construction Yard: The Australian Government is taking initial steps to secure additional land on which to build the Nuclear-Powered Submarine Construction Yard, including land adjacent to the existing Osborne North Shipyard in South Australia.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Non-proliferation. Since the announcement of AUKUS, our nations have been engaging proactively with the International Atomic Energy Agency on the non-proliferation aspects of our partnership.  Following the initiation of technical consultations with the IAEA, IAEA Director General Rafael Mariano Grossi <a href="https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/statements/iaea-director-generals-introductory-statement-to-the-board-of-governors-7-march-2022" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reported</a> to the IAEA Board of Governors on March 7 that Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States “are committed to ensuring the highest non-proliferation and safeguards standards are met.” </li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Advanced Capabilities</u></strong></p>



<p>AUKUS partners have made strong progress in the four advanced capabilities that the President and Prime Ministers identified in September 2021, and have recently initiated work in four additional areas. As we mature trilateral lines of effort within these and other critical defense and security capabilities, we will seek to engage allies and close partnersas appropriate.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Undersea capabilities. Through the AUKUS Undersea Robotics Autonomous Systems (AURAS) project, our nations are collaborating on autonomous underwater vehicles, which will be a significant force multiplier for our maritime forces. Initial trials and experimentation of this capability are planned for 2023.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Quantum technologies. The AUKUS Quantum Arrangement (AQuA) will accelerate investments to deliver generation-after-next quantum capabilities.&nbsp;&nbsp;It will have an initial focus on quantum technologies for positioning, navigation, and timing.&nbsp;&nbsp;Together, we will integrate emerging&nbsp;quantum technologies in trials and experimentation over the next three years.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Artificial intelligence and autonomy.&nbsp;Trilateral cooperation on artificial intelligence (AI) and autonomy will provide critical enablers for future force capabilities, improving the speed and precision of decision-making processes to maintain a capability edge and defend against AI-enabled threats. Early work is focused on accelerating adoption, and improving the resilience of, autonomous and AI-enabled systems in contested environments.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Advanced Cyber. In light of the importance of the cyber domain to advanced capabilities, we are focusing our efforts on strengthening cyber capabilities, including protecting critical communications and operations systems.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Hypersonic and counter-hypersonic capabilities.&nbsp;The AUKUS partners will work together to accelerate development of advanced hypersonic and counter-hypersonic capabilities.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Electronic warfare.&nbsp;&nbsp;The electromagnetic spectrum is increasingly contested.&nbsp;&nbsp;The three countries will work together to share understanding of tools, techniques, and technology to enable our forces to operate in contested and degraded environments.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Innovation. Our work on innovation aims to accelerate our respective defense innovation enterprises and learn from one another, including ways to more rapidly integrate commercial technologies to solve warfighting needs.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Information sharing. We will expand and accelerate sharing of sensitive information, including as a first priority enabling workstreams that underpin our work on agreed areas of advanced capabilities.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AUKUS Leaders’ Level&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/05/aukus-leaders-level-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the&#160;leaders of the Australia-UK-US (AUKUS) partnership – Prime Minister Scott Morrison of Australia, Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom, and President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States – assessed progress under AUKUS. We reaffirmed&#160;our commitment to AUKUS and to&#160;a free and open Indo-Pacific. In light of Russia’s unprovoked, unjustified, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the&nbsp;leaders of the Australia-UK-US (AUKUS) partnership – Prime Minister Scott Morrison of Australia, Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom, and President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States – assessed progress under AUKUS.</p>



<p>We reaffirmed&nbsp;our commitment to AUKUS and to&nbsp;a free and open Indo-Pacific. In light of Russia’s unprovoked, unjustified, and unlawful invasion of Ukraine,&nbsp;we reiterated our&nbsp;unwavering commitment to&nbsp;an international system&nbsp;that respects human rights, the rule of law,&nbsp;and&nbsp;the peaceful resolution of disputes free from coercion.</p>



<p>We are pleased with the progress in our trilateral program for Australia to establish a&nbsp;conventionally armed, nuclear‑powered&nbsp;submarine&nbsp;capability. We are fully committed to establishing a robust approach to sharing naval propulsion technology with Australia that strengthens the global non-proliferation regime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also committed today to commence new trilateral cooperation on&nbsp;hypersonics and counter-hypersonics, and electronic warfare capabilities, as well as to expand information sharing and to deepen cooperation on&nbsp;defense innovation. These initiatives will add to our existing efforts to deepen cooperation on cyber capabilities, artificial intelligence, quantum technologies, and additional undersea capabilities. As our work progresses on these and other critical defense and security capabilities, we will seek opportunities to engage allies and close partners.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Administration’s Proposed Rule to Fix “Family Glitch” and Lower Healthcare&#160;Costs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/05/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-administrations-proposed-rule-to-fix-family-glitch-and-lower-healthcare-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 12:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50558</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 5:42 P.M. EDT MR. MUNOZ:&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Happy Monday.&#160; Thank you for joining us on this call about tomorrow’s announcement around the President, Vice President, and former President Obama’s event around the Affordable Care Act.&#160;&#160; We will be providing a factsheet very soon that will also be embargoed until 5:00 a.m.&#160; A reminder&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>5:42 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Happy Monday.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us on this call about tomorrow’s announcement around the President, Vice President, and former President Obama’s event around the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will be providing a factsheet very soon that will also be embargoed until 5:00 a.m.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A reminder this call is attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I will kick it to [senior administration official] to discuss tomorrow’s announcement.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us this afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris believe that healthcare is a right, not a privilege.&nbsp; So, I want to discuss today three things: First, a regulation that will be released by the Department of the Treasury tomorrow to strengthen the Affordable Care Act; second, the tremendous progress we’ve made in helping people get affordable, high-quality healthcare; and third, an executive order that the President will sign tomorrow that will direct agencies to continue their efforts in making coverage more affordable and accessible for American families.</p>



<p>So, to start, tomorrow Treasury will release a proposed rule that will help hundreds of thousands more Americans get coverage under the Affordable Care Act.</p>



<p>Under the ACA, people who do not have access to affordable health insurance through their jobs may qualify for financial help to buy coverage under the ACA.</p>



<p>For single people, “affordable” means coverage that costs less than about 10 percent of their income.</p>



<p>But for spouses and kids that are offered coverage through a family member’s job, under current rules, they’re treated as having affordable coverage no matter what the actual cost of that coverage is for them.&nbsp; So that could mean that families would have to pay 25 or 30 percent of income to get coverage through their employer, and they can’t get financial help under the ACA, under today’s rule.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the rules that Treasury is releasing tomorrow will propose to change that.&nbsp; Under Treasury’s new proposed rules, family members who have to pay more than 10 percent of income for coverage will be able to get financial help under the ACA.</p>



<p>As a result, 200,000 uninsured people are expected to gain coverage, and nearly a million more are expected to see lower premiums every day.</p>



<p>To borrow a phrase, this rule is a big deal.&nbsp; We’re excited about it.&nbsp; And we think it (inaudible) significant administrative action to improve implementation of the ACA that’s been taken since the law was first enacted.</p>



<p>Second, I want to highlight that tomorrow’s rule builds on the remarkable progress that we have already made as an administration in bringing affordable coverage to folks.</p>



<p>Enrollment in coverage through the ACA is at an all-time high, and the uninsured rate is near historic lows.</p>



<p>One of the very first things we did in this administration was open a special enrollment period to get people coverage. &nbsp;President Biden had been in his seat for less than a month when HHS opened the doors to HealthCare.gov to ultimately help about 2 million people get (inaudible).</p>



<p>This winter, we ran the most successful open enrollment period under the ACA ever: 14.5 million people buying an ACA Marketplace plan; another 1 million signed up for coverage through a related program called the “Basic Health Plan” &#8212; a really tremendous open enrollment period that brought millions of people into coverage.</p>



<p>In addition, 19 million people are today covered through the Medicaid expansion, and Medicaid enrollment totals nearly 80 million people.</p>



<p>More people than ever before have the security and peace of mind that comes with affordable health insurance.</p>



<p>And the American Rescue Plan is a major contributor to this success.&nbsp; We’ve made coverage much more affordable for everyone buying through the ACA.&nbsp; And the President was proud to sign that legislation.</p>



<p>This also reflects the tireless work of agencies to expand their outreach and their enrollment assistance, including quadrupling the amount of in-person staff available to provide outreach assistan- &#8212; enrollment assistance in communities across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ACA is facilitating the expansion of Medicaid in Missouri and Oklahoma, which brought another half a million people into eligibility for coverage.</p>



<p>In short, this administration has been working since our first hours in office to get more Americans healthcare, and we’re still at it.</p>



<p>We are incredibly proud of what we’re getting done, but there is more to do.&nbsp; And so, tomorrow, the President will also sign an executive order that directs agencies to continue their efforts to strengthen access to affordable, high-quality healthcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The executive order will highlight a number of areas:</p>



<ul><li>Making it easier for people to enroll in and keep their coverage.</li><li>Helping people better understand their coverage options so they can pick the one that’s best for them.</li><li>Strengthening and improving the generosity of benefits and improving access to healthcare providers.</li><li>Improving the comprehensiveness of coverage and protecting Americans from low-quality health insurance.</li><li>Continuing to make health coverage more accessible and affordable by expanding eligibility and lowering costs for Americans with ACA, Medicare, or Medicaid coverage.</li><li>Connecting people to healthcare services by improving access to providers and improving linkages between the healthcare system and our communities to help Americans with health-related needs.</li><li>And finally, taking steps to help reduce the burden of medical debt that far too many Americans experience.</li></ul>



<p>And so that’s a sort of a brief summary of the executive order that the President will sign tomorrow.&nbsp; So I think, with that, I’m happy to take questions about this package of announcements.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And for those that joined a little bit late, we will be sending out an embargoed factsheet soon, and this is attributable to “senior administration officials.”</p>



<p>Please “raise your hand” if you have any question related to tomorrow’s announcement.</p>



<p>First, let’s go to Joyce Frieden at MedPage Today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; Regarding the Treasury rule, I&#8217;m wondering how much fixing this family glitch is going to cost and how it will be paid for.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t speak to that directly.&nbsp; Treasury is in charge of interpreting the provisions of 36B of the Affordable Care Act, which is the part of the law that provides financial assistance to people.&nbsp; 36B tax credits are an entitlement just like anything else in the tax code, and Treasury is interpreting their regulations to propose making this change.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Tami at CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much for holding this call.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; One is: How quickly do you think that people in the family glitch will be able to get coverage?&nbsp; How long will this take?</p>



<p>And then also, can you be a little bit more specific on what types of things the executive order might result in?&nbsp; What types of changes?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; On the first question, Treasury is proposing that the bona fide interpretation of affordability would take effect beginning January 1st, 2023, so people would be able to get financial assistance through the ACA&nbsp;starting at &#8212; during the next open enrollment period.</p>



<p>And as to the executive order, I think I&#8217;m not in a position tonight to preview more than what I have today.&nbsp; We will be sending out a factsheet that, broadly, the President is directing agencies to do everything in their power to make coverage more affordable and accessible.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Amy Lotven at Inside Health Policy.</p>



<p>Amy, you’re still muted.&nbsp; All right, we’ll try you later, Amy.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s go to Tom Howell with The Washington Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for doing the call.&nbsp; I just want to know about the bigger subsidies in the ACA.&nbsp; Does the President plan to address that?&nbsp; I believe they expire at the end of the year, but his Build Back Better Agenda would extend them.&nbsp; Does he plan to pressure lawmakers over that to get that part of the agenda passed?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;m not going to comment on any potential negotiations with Congress.&nbsp; But, as you know, the Build Back Better Act includes significant coverage policy, including extending the financial assistance under the ARP.&nbsp; (Inaudible) policies have widespread support, and we look forward to getting it done.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let&#8217;s go back to you, Amy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, yes.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m actually really wondering &#8212; it sounds like the affordability threshold will still apply to the families, but they&#8217;ll only &#8212; that they&#8217;ll be able to access the credit if they&#8217;re over the threshold.&nbsp; I just &#8212; is that right?&nbsp; So, you&#8217;re not fully &#8212; so, the rule doesn’t fully separate the families from the worker?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, under the rule, coverage for the family will be &#8212; the affordability of coverage for the family will be affected.&nbsp; So, if coverage for the family as a whole costs more than about 10 percent of household income, then the non-employee family members will be eligible for financial assistance in the marketplace.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Any more questions?&nbsp; All right, a couple more.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s go to Selena at NPR.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing the call.&nbsp; I just have a question about the number of people who might be affected.&nbsp; I was looking at an analysis from KFF on the so-called “family glitch” that estimated 5.1 million people nationally fall into the family glitch.&nbsp; The numbers that you mentioned at the top of the call &#8212; you said 200,000 people are expected to gain coverage, and a million &#8212; or I forget &#8212; I might have missed that number &#8212; would pay a lower cost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m just wondering if you can explain, like, something behind your estimate of who might be impacted here.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp; So there won&#8217;t be any official estimates from the administration coming out tomorrow.&nbsp; But to give you some context on sort of what&#8217;s out there: You&#8217;re right that there are estimates that there were &#8212; that there are about 10 million people who are affected in some way by the family glitch.&nbsp; And so all of those people will have a new option under these proposed rules.</p>



<p>Some of them may choose to stay in the coverage that they’re in today because they find it more convenient to have their whole family in a single health plan.&nbsp; And so, some of the 5 million people who were affected and get this new option will nonetheless choose to stay in the type of coverage that they have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But others, and the people for whom this is the greatest hardship, will change their current &#8212; you know, whatever they&#8217;re doing right now.&nbsp; So, as a result, about 200,000 uninsured people are expected to gain coverage for the first time because they don&#8217;t &#8212; they have no coverage at all, say because it&#8217;s just too expensive for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And another of that million people, you know, they switch from the coverage that they have today into more affordable Marketplace coverage.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Brett Samuels with The Hill.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I just had a quick question about former President Obama being part of the event tomorrow.&nbsp; I was just hoping you could speak to kind of what role he&#8217;ll play in this event and sort of the significance of having him, you know, at the White House for the signings of these orders.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to preview there.&nbsp; I think you’ll hear more from the President about that tomorrow afternoon.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; And, Brett, Jen spoke to this in the briefing today, so there&#8217;s a little bit more detail there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t think we have any more questions.&nbsp; So, with that, thank you, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; As a reminder. we will provide a factsheet shortly tonight.&nbsp; This and the factsheet are embargoed until 5:00 a.m.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you have any other questions, please reach out to me.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>5:58 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Harris Administration Proposes Rule to Fix “Family Glitch” and Lower Health Care&#160;Costs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/05/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-proposes-rule-to-fix-family-glitch-and-lower-health-care-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden Announces Proposal to Take Most Significant Administrative Action to Improve Implementation of the ACA Since its Enactment President Biden and Vice President Harris believe that health care is a right, not a privilege. They promised to protect and build on the Affordable Care Act (ACA), lowering costs and expanding coverage so that every&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>President Biden Announces Proposal to Take Most Significant Administrative Action to Improve Implementation of the ACA Since its Enactment</em></p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris believe that health care is a right, not a privilege. They promised to protect and build on the Affordable Care Act (ACA), lowering costs and expanding coverage so that every American has the peace of mind that health insurance brings.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration continues to deliver on that promise. Thanks to the landmark American Rescue Plan, ACA premiums are at an all-time low, while enrollment is at an all-time high. Four out of five Americans can find quality coverage for under $10 a month, and families are saving an average of $2,400 on their annual premiums—$200 in savings every month back to families. The Administration has lowered costs and increased enrollment to a record high of 14.5 million Americans—including nearly 6 million who newly gained coverage. With the addition of Missouri and Oklahoma, two states that expanded Medicaid last year, nearly 19 million low-income Americans are enrolled in the ACA’s Medicaid expansion coverage, adding up to a record nearly 80 million children, pregnant women, seniors, people with disabilities, and other low-income Americans covered by Medicaid.<br><br><strong><u>PROPOSING TO FIX THE “FAMILY GLITCH”</u></strong><br><br><strong>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is proposing a rule to strengthen the ACA by fixing the “family glitch,” which would save hundreds of thousands of families hundreds of dollars a month.</strong><br><br>Under the ACA, people who do not have access to “affordable” health insurance through their jobs may qualify for a premium tax credit to purchase affordable, high-quality coverage on the ACA’s health insurance marketplaces. Current regulations define employer-based health insurance as “affordable” if the coverage solely for the employee, and not for family members, is affordable, making family members ineligible for a premium tax credit even though they need it to afford high-quality coverage through the Marketplace.  For family members of an employee offered health coverage through an employer, the cost of that family coverage can sometimes be very expensive and make health insurance out of reach. The “family glitch” affects about 5 million people and has made it impossible for many families to use the premium tax credit to purchase an affordable, high-quality Marketplace plan.<br><br>The Treasury Department and the Internal Revenue Service are proposing to eliminate the “family glitch.” Should today’s proposed rule be finalized, family members of workers who are offered affordable self-only coverage but unaffordable family coverage may qualify for premium tax credits to buy ACA coverage. Should the proposed change be made, it’s estimated that 200,000 uninsured people would gain coverage, and nearly 1 million Americans would see their coverage become more affordable. Many families would be able to save hundreds of dollars a month thanks to lower premiums. This proposed rule would amount to the most significant administrative action to improve implementation of the ACA since its enactment.<br><br><strong><u>EXECUTIVE ORDER CONTINUING TO STRENGTHEN AMERICANS’ ACCESS TO AFFORDABLE, QUALITY HEALTH COVERAGE</u></strong><br><br>Last January, President Biden signed an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/28/executive-order-on-strengthening-medicaid-and-the-affordable-care-act/">Executive Order</a> directing federal agencies to take action to strengthen Medicaid and the Affordable Care Act. Today, President Biden is building on that directive with a new Executive Order directing federal agencies to continue doing everything in their power to expand affordable, quality health coverage. This includes:</p>



<ul><li>Making it easier for people to enroll in and keep their coverage.<br></li><li>Helping people better understand their coverage options so they can pick the best one for them.<br></li><li>Strengthening and improving the generosity of benefits and improving access to health care providers.<br></li><li>Improving the comprehensiveness of coverage and protecting Americans from low-quality coverage.<br></li><li>Continuing to make health coverage more accessible and affordable by expanding eligibility and lowering costs for Americans with ACA, Medicare, or Medicaid coverage.<br></li><li>Connecting people to health care services by improving access to health care providers and linkages between the health care system and communities to help Americans with health-related needs.<br></li><li>Taking steps to help reduce the burden of medical debt that far too many Americans experience.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>ADDITIONAL EFFORTS TO STRENGTHEN THE ACA AND MEDICAID</u></strong><br><br>These latest actions build on months of work to strengthen the ACA and Medicaid by lowering costs and expanding coverage.</p>



<ul><li><strong><em>Lowered premiums and out of pocket costs for millions of Americans.</em></strong> As the biggest expansion of affordable health care since the ACA, the American Rescue Plan (ARP) included enhanced subsidies that lowered premiums for 9 million Americans by an average of $50 per month per person. The enhanced subsidies helped <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/documents/18cd655222dc3de64866b269143731ce/aca-briefing-book-aspe-03-2022.pdf">expand</a> the availability of free and low-cost health plans to millions of consumers with nearly half of existing consumers able to enroll in a silver level plan with no premium and 70 percent of existing able to enroll in a low-premium silver plan. In addition, the Administration lowered the cap on total out-of-pocket costs by $400 in 2022.<br></li><li><strong><em>Made it easier to sign up for affordable coverage, including opening a Special Enrollment Period in 2021.</em></strong> In addition to opening a Special Enrollment Period last year, which enabled nearly 3 million Americans to newly sign up for coverage under the ACA, the Administration extended HealthCare.gov’s Open Enrollment period by one month, giving people more time to sign up for coverage The Administration operated the most successful Open Enrollment Period in history last year, with a historic 14.5 million Americans signing up for ACA coverage and another million people signing up for the Basic Health Program, an alternative coverage program created by the ACA.&nbsp; The Administration also eliminated unnecessary paperwork and increased outreach, quadrupling the number of trained Navigators to help Americans sign up for coverage on HealthCare.gov. These efforts helped reach communities that have historically been left behind, with the HealthCare.gov enrollment rate increasing by 26 percent for Hispanic Americans and 35 percent for Black Americans.<br></li><li><strong><em>Facilitated the expansion of Medicaid in Missouri and Oklahoma. </em></strong>The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) helped Missouri and Oklahoma become the 38<sup>th</sup> and 39<sup>th</sup> states to expand Medicaid, which will cover nearly half a million more low-income Americans in those two states. Missouri and Oklahoma are also taking advantage of the ARP’s financial incentive to expand Medicaid, which is <a href="https://www.medicaid.gov/state-resource-center/downloads/allstatecall-20210330.pdf">expected</a> to provide an extra $968 million and $500 million in federal dollars to these states, respectively.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong><em>Expanded and strengthened access to home care for millions of older Americans and people with disabilities.</em></strong> The ARP provided states with increased Medicaid funding to help expand access to home care services, furthering the Administration’s commitment to ensuring people can get the care they need in their homes and communities.&nbsp; The additional Medicaid funding will also help states strengthen their home- and community-based services programs by investing in the home care workforce and other innovations to improve the delivery of care.<br></li><li><strong><em>Provided new options to help people experiencing a behavioral health crisis.</em></strong> Thanks to the ARP, states can now receive enhanced Medicaid funding to establish mobile crisis intervention services teams to help provide services to Medicaid beneficiaries experiencing a behavioral health crisis.&nbsp; This new option is a key component in the Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-announce-strategy-to-address-our-national-mental-health-crisis-as-part-of-unity-agenda-in-his-first-state-of-the-union/">strategy</a> to address the Nation’s mental health crisis by ensuring that Medicaid beneficiaries experiencing a behavioral health crisis can get connected to the care they need.<br></li><li><strong><em>Tackled the maternal health crisis.</em></strong> Medicaid covers more than 40 percent of births in the United States. Thanks to the ARP and the Vice President’s leadership, the Biden-Harris Administration partnered with Illinois, New Jersey, Virginia, and Louisiana to make sure new moms can keep their Medicaid coverage for a year after they deliver. Another 9 states are in the process of seeking CMS approval to expand postpartum coverage to their states as well. Based on HHS estimates, more than 83,000 beneficiaries across five states will benefit from this extended post-partum coverage during the critical first year after delivery.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki and National Security Advisor Jake&#160;Sullivan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/04/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:06 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Okay.  We have a return guest: Jake Sullivan, our National Security Advisor, who will give some brief remarks, take some questions.  And then we will do a briefing from there. With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to Jake. MR. SULLIVAN:  Hi, everyone.  I hope you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:06 P.M. EDT<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Okay.  We have a return guest: Jake Sullivan, our National Security Advisor, who will give some brief remarks, take some questions.  And then we will do a briefing from there.<br> <br>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to Jake.<br> <br>MR. SULLIVAN:  Hi, everyone.  I hope you guys are doing well.<br> <br>With apologies to Jen and to you, my remarks are not going to be so brief because I have a number of points I want to get through before opening it to questions.<br> <br>First, you heard the President today condemn in powerful terms the atrocities committed by Russian forces retreating from Bucha and other towns in Ukraine.  The images that we see are tragic, they&#8217;re shocking, but unfortunately, they&#8217;re not surprising.<br> <br>We released information even before Russia’s invasion showing that Russia would engage in acts of brutality against civilians, included it tar- &#8212; including targeted killings of dissidents and others they deemed a threat to their occupation.  And as the horrific images that have emerged from Bucha have shown, that’s exactly what they have done.<br> <br>We had already concluded that Russia committed war crimes in Ukraine, and the information from Bucha appears to show further evidence of war crimes.  And as the President said, we will work with the world to ensure there is full accountability for these crimes.  We are also working intensively with our European allies on further sanctions to raise the pressure and raise the cost on Putin and on Russia.<br> <br>Today, I&#8217;d like to take a step back and talk about where we are and where we think we are going.<br> <br>Russia launched its invasion of Ukraine more than a month ago.  When Russia started this war, its initial aims were to seize the capital of Kyiv, replace the Zelenskyy government, and take control of much &#8212; if not all &#8212; of Ukraine.  Russia believed that it could accomplish these objectives swiftly and efficiently.<br> <br>But Russia did not account for the strength of the Ukrainian military and the Ukrainian people, or the amount or effectiveness of military assistance provided by the United States and its allies and partners.<br> <br>The Ukrainian people, backed resolutely by the United States and other nations, have held firm.  Kyiv and other cities still stand.<br> <br>The Ukrainian military has performed exceptionally well.  And many Ukrainian civilians have joined local militias in addition to using nonviolent means to resist.<br> <br>Vladimir Putin also believed that the West would not hold together in support of Ukraine.  Russia was surprised that President Biden and the United States were so effective in rallying the world to prepare for and respond to the invasion. <br> <br>And after President Biden reinforced and reinvigorated Western unity at a series of summits in Brussels just 11 days ago, the Russians have now realized that the West will not break.<br> <br>At this juncture, we believe that Russia is revising its war aims.  Russia is repositioning its forces to concentrate its offensive operations in eastern and parts of southern Ukraine, rather than target most of the territory.  All indications are that Russia will seek to surround and overwhelm Ukrainian forces in eastern Ukraine.<br> <br>We anticipate that Russian commanders are now executing their redeployment from northern Ukraine to the region around the Donbas in eastern Ukraine.<br> <br>Russian forces are already well on their way of retreating from Kyiv to Belarus as Russia likely prepares to deploy dozens of additional battalion tactical groups, constituting tens of thousands of soldiers, to the frontline in Ukraine’s east.<br> <br>We assess Russia will focus on defeating the Ukrainian forces in the broader Luhansk and Donetsk provinces, which encompasses significantly more territory than Russian proxies already controlled before the new invasion began in late February.<br> <br>Russia could then use any tactical successes it achieves to propagate a narrative of progress and mask or un- &#8212; or try to discount or downplay prior military failures.<br> <br>In order to protect any territory it seizes in the east, we expect that Russia could potentially extend its force proje- &#8212; projection and presence even deeper into Ukraine, beyond Luhansk and Donetsk provinces.  At least that is their intention and their plan.<br> <br>In the south, we also expect that Russian military forces will do what they can to try to hold the city of Kherson, to enable their control of the waterflow to Crimea, and try to block Mykolaiv so that Ukrainian forces cannot proceed to retake Kherson.<br> <br>In the north, Russia will likely keep pressure on Kharkiv.<br> <br>During this renewed ground offensive in eastern Ukraine, Mas- &#8212; Moscow will likely continue to launch air and missile strikes across the rest of the country to cause military and economic damage &#8212; and, frankly, to cause terror, including against cities like Kyiv, Odesa, Kharkiv, and Lviv.<br> <br>Russia’s goal, in the end, is to weaken Ukraine as much as possible.<br> <br>Russia still has forces available to outnumber Ukraine’s, and Russia is now concentrating its military power on fewer lines of attack.<br> <br>But this does not mean that Russia will succeed in the east.  So far, Russia’s military has struggled to achieve its war aims, while Ukraine’s military has done an extraordinary and courageous job demonstrating its will to fight and putting its considerable capabilities to use.<br> <br>The next stage of this conflict may very well be protracted.  We should be under no illusions that Russia will adjust its tactics, which have included and will likely continue to include wanton and brazen attacks on civilian targets.<br> <br>And while Moscow may be interested now in using military pressure to find a political settlement, if this offensive in the east proves to gain some traction, Russia could regenerate forces for additional goals, including trying to gain control of yet more territory within Ukraine. <br> <br>Now, as the images from Bucha so powerfully reinforce, now is not the time for complacency.  The Ukrainians are defending their homeland courageously, and the United States will continue to back them with military assistance, humanitarian aid, and economic support.<br> <br>We know that military assistance is having a critical impact on this conflict.  Ukrainians are effectively defending themselves with U.S.-produced air defense systems and anti-tank systems, such as Stingers and Javelins, as well as radar systems that give the Ukrainians early warning and target data, and multiple other types of arms and munitions.<br> <br>The administration is working around the clock to fulfill Ukraine’s main security assistance requests &#8212; delivering weapons from U.S. stocks where they are available and facilitating the delivery of weapons by Allies where Allied systems better suit Ukraine’s needs.  This is happening at what the Pentagon has described at an &#8220;unprecedented pace.&#8221;<br> <br>Last Friday, we announced an additional $300 million in security assistance, bringing the U.S. commitment to $1.65 billion in weapons and ammunition since Russia’s invasion and $2.3 billion since the beginning of the administration.<br> <br>The latest package includes laser-guided rocket systems, Puma unmanned aerial systems, armored High-Mobility Multipurpose Wheeled Vehicles, and more. <br> <br>Material is arriving every day, including today, from the United States and our Allies and partners.  And we will have further announcements of additional military assistance in the coming days.<br> <br>We are working with the Ukrainians, as I said, to identify solutions to their priority requests.  In some cases, that means sourcing systems from other countries because the U.S. either doesn’t have the system or doesn’t have a version that could effectively be integrated into the fight.  Sorts of systems like this include longer-range anti-aircraft systems, artillery systems, and coastal defense systems.<br> <br>So, let’s take coastal defense systems as an example.  President Biden went to Brussels to talk to key Allies 11 days ago about how to get coastal defense systems to Ukraine, because there is not, at the moment, a good U.S. option. <br> <br>Last week, the UK announced at the close of its donor conference that coastal defense systems would be provided to the Ukrainians.  It is a good example how, working with Allies and partners, we are successfully responding to Ukraine&#8217;s requests. <br> <br>We expect additional new capabilities to be delivered in the near future.  We can’t always advertise what is being delivered out of deference to our Allies and partners or for operational sensitivities, but we are moving with speed and efficiency to deliver.<br> <br>Let me close with this: Even as Russia acknowledges the failure of its initial plans and shifts its goals, three elements of this war remain constant.<br> <br>First, Russia will continue to use its military to try to conquer and occupy sovereign Ukrainian territory.<br> <br>Second, the Ukrainian military and people will continue to effectively and bravely defend their homeland.<br> <br>And third, the United States will stand by them for as long as it takes.<br> <br>Russia has tried to subjugate the whole of Ukraine, and it has failed.  Now it will attempt to bring parts of the country under its rule.  It may succeed in taking some territory through sheer force and brutality.<br> <br>But no matter what happens over the coming weeks, it is clear that Russia will never be welcomed by the Ukrainian people.  Instead, its gains will be temporary, as the brave Ukrainian people resist Russian occupation and carry on their fight for an independent, sovereign nation that they so richly deserve.<br> <br>And with that, I&#8217;d be happy to take your questions.<br> <br>Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Jake, can I ask you about the President&#8217;s call for a war crimes trial for Vladimir Putin?  What are the mechanics of how the President sees that playing out?  Would it be at the International Criminal Court or at some other tribunal?<br> <br>MR. SULLIVAN:  So, we have to consult with our allies and partners on what makes most sense as a mechanism moving forward.  Obviously, the ICC is one venue where war crimes have been tried in the past, but there have been other examples in other conflicts of other mechanisms being set up.<br> <br>So, there is work to be done to work out the specifics of that.  And between now and then, every day, what we are focused on is continuing to apply pressure to the Russian economy and provide weapons to the Ukrainian people to be able to defend themselves.<br> <br>Q    Other &#8212;<br> <br>MR. SULLIVAN:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Sorry, forgive me.  Other forums for this might include something that the U.N. General &#8212; the U.N. Security Council might adopt.  Is that what you&#8217;re suggesting &#8212; that you would go to the Security Council?<br> <br>MR. SULLIVAN:  Well, obviously, with Russia as a permanent member of the U.N. Security Council, it would be difficult to imagine that they would not attempt to exercise their veto to block something.</p>



<p>But there have been creative solutions to the question of accountability in the past, and I&#8217;m not going to prejudge what solution would be applied here or what forum or venue would be applied here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I will say is what the President said this morning: There has to be accountability for these war crimes.&nbsp; That accountability has to be felt at every level of the Russian system, and the United States will work with the international community to ensure that accountability is applied at the appropriate time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President was careful to say he does not see this as genocide.&nbsp; Many Ukrainians believe that it is because their nation, their people are being attacked.&nbsp; Where is the line, in your view?&nbsp; And how have you counseled the President between “genocide” and “war crimes”?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So this is something we, of course, continue to monitor every day.&nbsp; Based on what we have seen so far, we have seen atrocities, we have seen war crimes.&nbsp; We have not yet seen a level of systematic deprivation of life of the Ukrainian people to rise to the level of genocide.&nbsp; But, again, that&#8217;s something we will continue to monitor.<br>&nbsp;<br>There is not a mechanical formula for this.&nbsp; There is a process that we have run just recently at the State Department to ultimately determine that the killing &#8212; the mass killing of Rohingya in Burma constituted genocide.&nbsp; That was a lengthy process based on an amassing of evidence over a considerab- &#8212; a considerable period of time and involving, frankly, mass death, the mass incarceration of a significant portion of the Rohingya population.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we will look to a series of indicators along those lines to ultimately make a determination in Ukraine.&nbsp; But as the President said today, we have not arrived at that conclusion yet.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I just have three quick questions.&nbsp; When you say the next stage will be “protracted,” do you mean years?&nbsp; I mean, Russia has been in Crimea and Donbas since 2014.&nbsp; What &#8212; what&#8217;s “protracted”?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we can&#8217;t predict, but I would just say that, so far, this conflict has lasted a little more than five weeks.&nbsp; And yet, in that time, we&#8217;ve seen an enormous amount of killing and death and, also, an enormous amount of bravery and success on the part of the Ukrainian forces.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I&#8217;m saying when I say “protracted” is that it may not be just a matter of a few more weeks before all is said and done.&nbsp; That first, quote, unquote, “phase” of the conflict, of &#8212; the Russians put it, was measured in weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>This next phase could be measured in months or longer.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the beginning, the consensus seemed to be: Russia was unstoppable; we just had to make the price as high as possible for them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Then the new thinking is: Maybe Ukraine can actually win.&nbsp; Do you agree with that?&nbsp; And what would winning look like?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we believe that our job is to support the Ukrainians.&nbsp; They will set the military objectives.&nbsp; They will set the objectives at the bargaining table.&nbsp; And I am quite certain they are going to set those objectives at success, and we are going to give them every tool we can to help them achieve that success.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we are not going to define the outcome of this for the Ukrainians.&nbsp; That is up for them to define and us to support them in.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to do.&nbsp; And we do have confidence in the bravery, skill, and capacity of the Ukrainian armed forces and the resilience of the Ukrainian people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just have one &#8212; one quick thing on chemical weapons.&nbsp; The President and other allies have promised consequences without saying what they would be.&nbsp; The last time Russia used chemical weapons, there were sanctions but not very stiff ones.&nbsp; Are you ready to define consequences?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m going to say the same thing I&#8217;ve said from this podium that the President has said from a podium down the hall in this same building, which is that Russia will pay a severe price.&nbsp; We have communicated to them directly.&nbsp; We have coordinated with our allies and partners.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to go further in terms of the specifics here today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, two questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration initially did not call this “war crimes,” and eventually, though, they did after they &#8212; what they saw on the ground.&nbsp; Do you think that&#8217;s going to be the case with calling it a genocide?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, so, first, it&#8217;s not just that we sit around and debate terms and then, ultimately, decide to apply a term based against static circumstances.&nbsp; We watch as things unfold.&nbsp; We gather evidence.&nbsp; We continue to develop facts.&nbsp; And as we gathered evidence and as we got the facts together, we ultimately came to the conclusion that war crimes were committed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, in fact, I would say, on this front, President Biden was a leader.&nbsp; He went out and said Putin is a war criminal.&nbsp; And many of you raised your eyebrows at that; many people out in the public raised their eyebrows at that.&nbsp; And now you see the scenes coming out of Bucha today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, he&#8217;s not going to hesitate to call a spade a spade, to call it like he sees it, and neither is the U.S. government.<br>&nbsp;<br>So as the facts develop, could we see ourselves reaching a different conclusion on that question?&nbsp; Of course we could.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s going to be based on evidence and facts as we gather it along the way.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And two more quick ones for you.&nbsp; On the sanctions that the President was talking about today, should we expect those this week, or what&#8217;s the timing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; You can expect further sanctions announcements this week.&nbsp; And we are coordinating with our allies and partners on what the exact parameters of that will be.&nbsp; But, yes, this week, we will have additional economic pressure elements to announce.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And my last question, quickly.&nbsp; You keep using the word “retreat” instead of “reposition.”&nbsp; How much is that in part due to the spring conditions, the muddy conditions that are on the ground in Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The reason I use the phrase “retreat” is just kind of quite simple common sense.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not some fancy technical military term.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a term that all of us understand, which is, if you run pell-mell for an objective and you get stopped, and then you start to get beaten back, and then you withdraw, you pull out &#8212; that&#8217;s what I would call a retreat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what happened to the Russians in Kyiv: They attacked Kyiv.&nbsp; They failed.&nbsp; They started to get beaten backwards by the Russian &#8212; by the Ukrainian military.&nbsp; And they ultimately retreated back across the border into Belarus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, with those forces, as I said in my opening comments, they are not intending to stand pat.&nbsp; They are going to reposition those forces to go after a different objective &#8212; a scaled-down objective, but nonetheless a dangerous and disturbing objective, which is to conquer an occupied territory in eastern Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And now it&#8217;s our job to help the Ukrainian people have the tools they need to be able to stymie that objective.&nbsp; That is what we&#8217;re intent on doing at this time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, I know you&#8217;re not willing to call it a genocide, but does the U.S. government have information that you can &#8212; that you can use to independently corroborate Ukraine&#8217;s allegations about atrocities in Bucha?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we have &#8212; obviously got access to a lot of the information that you all have.&nbsp; We also have information that the Ukrainians have provided us directly.&nbsp; And we will also work with fact finders &#8212; independent fact finders as we go forward to get to a level of documentation that allows us to help build very strong dossiers of evidence for war crimes prosecutions.&nbsp; And that is what we intend to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, on the question of the genocide determination: Obviously, we will continue on a daily basis to have consultations with the Ukrainians to reach determinations.&nbsp; And if at some point we reach the judgment that there, in fact, has been a level of atrocity, a level of killing, a level of intentional activity that rises to meet our definition of genocide, we&#8217;ll call it for what it is.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have never hesitated to call out the Russians for what they have done in Ukraine, and we will not start now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And sorry &#8212; sorry, one quick question on France, Jake.&nbsp; They are &#8212; they have suggested that, you know, a hefty EU-wide tariff should be imposed, as opposed to a blanket ban on Russian energy imports into the EU.&nbsp; Does the U.S. support that?&nbsp; And will that be part of what you&#8217;re planning to do next in terms of sanctions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We are having conversations, as I stand here at this podium, with senior officials in the main European capitals, as well as in Brussels, on the full range of sanctions options, including sanctions options or pressure options that relate to energy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to negotiate that out at this podium.&nbsp; We want to make sure that we&#8217;re able to pull together a consensus along with the rest of the European Union.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, the Kremlin is denying the images out of Bucha, saying that they don&#8217;t show any kind of apparent execution.&nbsp; What is the U.S. doing to try and expose Russia&#8217;s actions to its own citizens?&nbsp; I mean, what can we do to sort of fight this information war?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, I would note that the Kremlin is working overtime to close down the information space inside of Russia, which is not exactly the action of a strong and confident government that feels really good about the story that it would be telling if it were allowing independent news sources to come in.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, we are, of course, supporting, through a variety of means, the provision of information about these atrocities and about the entire effort by the Russians to unjustly and unlawfully invade a sovereign neighboring country not just to the Russian people, but to people everywhere.&nbsp; We will continue to do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to be clear: Is it your sense that the atrocities that we&#8217;re seeing in Bucha are based on orders coming from Putin or his senior military officials?&nbsp; Or is there a chance here that this is sort of Russian forces acting on their own?&nbsp; And is there even a distinction?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get into the specific intelligence related to Bucha at this point.&nbsp; But what I will say, as I said at the outset, is that even before the invasion happened, we shared information with the public, with the press, including from this podium, that Russia was intending as a matter of policy &#8212; not as a matter of one guy in a unit in a suburb of Kyiv, but as a matter of policy in this war &#8212; to kill dissidents, to kill those who caused problems for the occupation, and to impose a reign of terror across occupied territories within Ukraine.&nbsp; That is what we are seeing play out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, no, we do not believe that this is just a random accident or the rogue act of a particular individual.&nbsp; We believe that this was part of the plan.&nbsp; We declared it from this podium as part of the plan, and now we are seeing it play out in real life, in living color, in these terrible, tragic images we are seeing come from Bucha.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, I know you don’t want to talk about possible venues for a war trial &#8212; war crimes trial, but can you talk a little bit about the evidence-gathering aspect of it?&nbsp; That’s going to be crucial to combatting disinformation and what Russians will say &#8212; that “Ukrainian rebels are fighting us. &nbsp;That was legitimate warfare what happened.&#8221;&nbsp; That could be a tactic they’re taking.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So can you walk us through the evidence-gathering?&nbsp; Who’s doing it?&nbsp; Are there people on the ground gathering evidence?&nbsp; How long does that take to, sort of, build a case?&nbsp; And what does that look like?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I will directly answer your question, but I also think it is important for our team at the State Department, which will take the lead on this, including our Global War Crimes Coordinator, to give you a fully elaborate answer to this question, in technical detail, so that everybody understands exactly how this process works.<br>&nbsp;<br>But with that being said, there are four main sources of information that we will develop in an effort to help build the case for war crimes.<br>&nbsp;<br>The first is the information we and our allies and partners gather, including through intelligence sources.&nbsp; And we, actually, within our intelligence community, had previously stood up a team to be able to document and analyze war crimes and worked closely with the State Department in doing so.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also coordinating with key allies and partners who have their own capacities.<br>&nbsp;<br>The second is what the Ukrainians themselves will do on the ground to develop this case, to document the forensics of these tragic and senseless killings in this particular instance and in other instances across Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>The third is international organizations, including the United Nations, but others as well &#8212; prominent international non-governmental organizations with real credibility and expertise in this area.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the fourth is all of you.&nbsp; Because part of building this case is relying upon the global independent media, who has images, interviews, documentation.&nbsp; And when you put all of those four sources together, you can build, we believe, a package that can stand up to the relentless disinformation we are likely to see and have already started seeing from Russia, and that, ultimately, the truth will withstand the assault on the truth that we can expect to come from Moscow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On former President Trump, he&#8217;s having Save America rallies where he&#8217;s decrying the Biden administration, decrying the response that you all in the White House have been giving to this war in Ukraine.&nbsp; He said if he was in here in office, he would do it better; it wouldn&#8217;t happen under him.&nbsp; What is your response to the former President, Donald J. Trump, saying these things about the current administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a response to the former President.&nbsp; We are focused on getting the job done, getting the support to the Ukrainian people that they need, applying unprecedented pressure to the Russian economy, and building a form of Western unity that no one could reasonably have expected and that we have sustained through the early weeks of the war and will sustain for the period ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;ll leave the commentary on what the former President said to others.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; To follow up on what you said about Ukraine setting terms for any potential resolution, President Zelenskyy said on “Face the Nation” that with regard to any potential peace agreement, the important thing in this agreement are security guarantees.&nbsp; But he also said the U.S. has not recei- &#8212; has not provided any yet.&nbsp; Is the U.S. considering that?&nbsp; And what would that look like?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we are in regular contact &#8212; and by “regular,” I mean near daily contact.&nbsp; I personally am in near daily contact with my counterpart in the Ukrainian government.&nbsp; And we are talking constantly about how we can support a negotiated solution that defends Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp; And we have told them that we are prepared to do our part to support that, including by ensuring that Ukraine has the means to defend itself in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to get into the specifics of what those negotiations are because I believe it&#8217;s very important that they have a protected space to be able to be carried out.&nbsp; But you can rest assured that the United States is actively working in consultation with Ukrainians to support their efforts at the peace table.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, a question on the sanctions.&nbsp; You just said that you&#8217;re under no illusions that Russia will adjust its target.&nbsp; So what function will an additional sanctions package have when you announce it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I would say two things about sanctions.&nbsp; One is that sanctions are intended to impose costs so that Russia cannot carry on these grotesque acts without paying a severe price for it.&nbsp; The other is to have an effect on Russia&#8217;s behavior over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But as President Biden has made clear repeatedly, we don&#8217;t expect that that shift in behavior will be caused by sanctions overnight or in a week.&nbsp; It will take time to grind down the elements of Russian power within the Russian economy, to hit their industrial base hard, to hit the sources of revenue that have propped up this war and have propped up the klepto- &#8212; kleptocracy in Russia.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to take some time to play out.<br>&nbsp;<br>But there&#8217;s no better time than now to be working at that so that the costs end up setting in and that ends up sharpening Russia&#8217;s choices.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, sanctions are not alone going to solve any of these problems, but they are a critical tool in ultimately producing a better outcome to this conflict than would otherwise be produced.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have the revelations about Bucha prompted the administration and its allies to reconsider what kind of military assistance it&#8217;s providing to Ukraine?&nbsp; Are tanks now part of, you know, potential transfers that could be provided to the Ukrainian military?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m not going to get into certain specific systems because, as I said at the outset, there are operational sensitivities and the sensitivities of our allies and partners for why we wouldn&#8217;t speak about a particular capability like tanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I will say this: Even before Bucha, the United States was working with Ukrainians on every item on its priority list and how we could go ahead and ensure that that could be provided to them.&nbsp; The only capability that we have discussed with them where there has been a difference in perspective that has been played out in living color and in this podium many times over has been the question of direct facilitation from a U.S. airbase in Germany into contested airspace over Ukraine &#8212; the MiG-29s.<br>&nbsp;<br>Otherwise, before Bucha, we were working with them on a wide range of capabilities, including some capabilities that people here were writing we weren&#8217;t prepared to provide.&nbsp; That wasn&#8217;t right.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, it&#8217;s hard for me to correct the record in every case because, for very good reasons, some of these systems we cannot advertise, we cannot talk to you all about it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I want to make clear, as I said at the outset, is the extent and depth of effort to acquire and transfer a variety of advanced weapons capabilities is extraordinary, it is unprecedented, and it has been ongoing from well before the terrible images came out this week.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on the International Criminal Court: Is one of the reasons why the U.S. is considering alternate venues is because the U.S. is not a signatory?&nbsp; And does that undercut the U.S. push to hold Putin accountable with a war crimes trial of some kind when the U.S. is not a signatory of the International Criminal Court?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The U.S. has in the past been able to collaborate with the International Criminal Court in other contexts, despite not being a signatory.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s a variety of reasons one might consider alternative venues as well, beyond the specific relationship between the U.S. and the ICC.<br>&nbsp;<br>Most importantly, this is not a decision the United States is going to make by itself.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to make the call out of Washington for the appropriate venue for accountability; that is going to be done in consultation with allies and with partners around the world.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want to prejudge those conversations that are ongoing.<br>&nbsp;<br>And what I can communicate is the very real, sustained, and committed proposition that the United States has that we are going to ensure that there is accountability.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yeah.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just take one more.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; The U.S. had rejected Poland’s plan for a peacekeeping force to protect civilians.&nbsp; Is that something that&#8217;s being reconsidered, given what we&#8217;ve seen of these atrocities?&nbsp; And is there any talk among the Allies to do some sort of force to help protect the civilian population?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t quite accept the premise of the question.&nbsp; There &#8212; there had been various peacekeeping proposals floated; none of them have ever been given full shape or been kind of formally put forward and suggested should actually be implemented.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we continue to consult with our Allies and partners, including Poland, on what makes sense going forward.&nbsp; We have not yet seen a proposal that actually has been fleshed out that could be operationalized.<br>&nbsp;<br>The one thing that the United States has made clear throughout this is that it is not our intention to send U.S. soldiers to fight Russian soldiers in Ukraine.&nbsp; But in terms of the supply of capabilities, in terms of other steps to support the Ukrainians and to do our best to protect civilians in Ukraine, we continue to look at every possible option, including in consultation with our partners on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ll &#8212; I’ll leave it at that.&nbsp; Thank you, guys.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Jake, so much for joining us.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Come again, please.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He will, I’m sure.&nbsp; He’s probably our most frequent guest.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you get &#8212; I probably owe him something for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, a couple of items for all of you at the top.&nbsp; Today, Vice President Harris and administration officials announced the Biden-Harris Action Plan for Building Better School Infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>By leveraging funds from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the American Rescue Plan, this action plan will activate the entire federal government to support students’ health and learning, from upgraded HVAC systems to electric school buses, from on-site solar energy installations to safe routes to school.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also wanted to note, in light of the President&#8217;s event on trucking, a couple of details or facts for all of you.&nbsp; 2021 was the best year for trucking growth &#8212; jobs growth since 1994.&nbsp; And December 2021 through February of 2022 was the best three-month stretch for long-distance truck hiring since the 1990s.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks to the efforts of the Department of Transportation, we doubled the issuance of Commercial Driver&#8217;s License issuances in January and February of 2022, compared to the prior January and February of 2021.<br>&nbsp;<br>And over 100 employers &#8212; including Domino&#8217;s, Frito-Lay, and UPS &#8212; launched registered apprenticeship programs in the past 90 days.&nbsp; This could result in more than ten thou- &#8212; 10,000 additional apprentices &#8212; apprenticeships nationwide, which, of course, get more people &#8212; more truckers trained, more trucks on the road, more goods moving around and onto shelves across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also wanted to note &#8212; I think you all saw this, but just to confirm for all of you: Tomorrow, the President and Vice President will be joined by former President Obama to highlight how the Affordable Care Act continues to lower healthcare costs for American families.&nbsp; This will be the first time former President Obama returns to the White House since leaving office.<br>&nbsp;<br>Since we&#8217;ve taken office &#8212; since we&#8217;ve entered &#8212; the President &#8212; since President Biden has entered office, we&#8217;ve taken big steps to reduce healthcare costs and expand access to healthcare for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>And how President Biden and former President Obama both see the Affordable Care Act is an example &#8212; a shining example of how government can work for the American people.&nbsp; Not only did it ensure that millions of people had access to affordable healthcare, but it has been an opportunity to build on that and make changes and make improvements over the course of time, which, of course, is what they will talk about tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>But even since the President took office, through the American Rescue Plan, we lowered premiums for 9 million Americans &#8212; the biggest expansion of affordable healthcare since the ACA.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made affordable health coverage more accessible during the pandemic through the opening of the special enrollment period, which enabled nearly 3 million Americans to have access &#8212; to newly sign up for coverage under the ACA.<br>&nbsp;<br>And President Biden has overseen the most successful open enrollment period in history last year, with a historic 14.5 million Americans signing up for the &#8212; for ACA coverage and another million people signing up for the basic healthcare program.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, tomorrow, they&#8217;ll announce more steps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll also note, as they did every week when President &#8211;former President Obama was president and President Biden was vice president &#8212; that&#8217;s a mouthful &#8212; they will have lunch tomorrow as well, as they used to do on a weekly basis.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note they continue to talk regularly.&nbsp; They are real friends, not just Washington friends, and so I&#8217;m sure they will talk about events in the world as well as their families and personal lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;ll try to get around the room as best as I can.&nbsp; But, Chris, why don&#8217;t you kick us off?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, one question on Title 42.&nbsp; Some Republican attorneys general are suing the administration over the plan to lift it.&nbsp; What is the administration&#8217;s response?&nbsp; And is the administration concerned that this would end up blocking the push to lift the order?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, on the lawsuit itself, I&#8217;d of course refer you to the Department of Justice; they would be overseeing any steps there.<br>&nbsp;<br>But broadly speaking, I think it&#8217;s important to note for any critics in any lawsuits that Title 42 is a public health directive; it&#8217;s not an immigration/migration enforcement measure.&nbsp; And the decision on when to lift Title 42 was made by the CDC.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our objective from here &#8212; and this is why we have the implementation period over the next several weeks &#8212; continues to be to ensure we are increasing our resources, surging personnel and resources to the border, improving border processing, implementing COVID-19 mitigation measures, and continuing to work with other countries in the Western Hemisphere to manage migration and address root causes.<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is, again, a healthcare measure &#8212; a health measure determination and not one on immigration policy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Let me ask you the question I was going to ask Jake, which is that: As part of this new effort to ramp up sanctions, is the administration going to be ramping up pressure on China and India to abide by existing sanctions?&nbsp; And what does that look like?&nbsp; I know Daleep Singh was just in India.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to intensify some criticism of them and others who haven’t done so?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well &#8212; well, certainly our expectation and our public and private message is &#8212; will continue to be that every country should abide by the sanctions that we have announced and that we are implementing around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you noted &#8212; so let me start with India, if that&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; As you noted, Daleep Singh, our Deputy National Security Advisor, was just there.&nbsp; I would note that, you know, just given some of the reporting, energy payments are not sanctioned; that&#8217;s a decision made by each individual country.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been very clear that each country is going to make their own choices, even as we have made the decision and other countries have made the decision to ban energy imports.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What &#8212; what Daleep did make clear to his counterparts during this visit was that we don&#8217;t believe it&#8217;s in India&#8217;s interest to accelerate or increase imports of Russian energy and other commodities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Right now, just to give everybody the full scope of it, India&#8217;s imports of Russian energy represent only 1 to 2 percent of their total energy imports.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, while he al- &#8212; he explained both the mechanisms of our sanctions and reiterated that any country or entity should be abiding by those, we also made clear that we&#8217;d be happy to be a partner in reducing their reliance or even their small percentage of &#8212; of reliance on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to China &#8212; I know that Jake spoke to this the last time he was here &#8212; our assessment hasn&#8217;t changed on that front, but we continue to convey the same expectations of abiding by sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on COVID funding, there are reports that the Republicans and Democrats in the Senate are nearing a deal on a $10 billion package that doesn&#8217;t include global aid.&nbsp; Is a package of that size, and that doesn&#8217;t include global vaccine assistance, something that President Biden could sign into law?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that we are encouraged by the strong progress that Congress is making in finalizing a deal &#8212; not yet final, but finalizing a deal &#8212; to fund some of our most very urgent COVID response needs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would remind everyone that what we had requested was $22.5 billion, not $10 billion, in order to achieve a number of objectives &#8212; including securing enough booster shots for the general population; purchasing more monoclonal antibodies and Evusheld for the immune- &#8212; immunocompromised; maintaining our testing capacity; getting shots in arms abroad, to go to your question; and funding for variant-specific vaccines if needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this does not &#8212; will, obviously, not meet all of those &#8212; all of those needs &#8212; dire needs in this country.&nbsp; And certainly, our objective would continue be &#8212; to be to press for funding for international &#8212; support for international &#8212; for ensuring we continue to be the arsenal of vaccines in the world, regardless of what this final package looks like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d note that the reason that&#8217;s so important is not just because of the need to have vaccine doses, it&#8217;s because we need to &#8212; a lot of &#8212; there are countries around the world who are refusing our vaccine dose- &#8212; doses because they don&#8217;t have the mechanisms, the know-how, and the capacity to be able to distribute those doses.&nbsp; So that funding that we&#8217;ve been requesting and we&#8217;ll continue to press for would be accounting for that as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I &#8212; can I note one more last thing?&nbsp; Sorry, I&#8217;ve got a lot on this.&nbsp; Is &#8212; I would also note that as you&#8217;re watching Congress and the Senate, there are a wide number of Republicans who have called for funding for and called for ensuring that we continue to be the arsenal of vaccine distribution around the world &#8212; they don&#8217;t use that exact phrase, but basically that&#8217;s the basics &#8212; including Senator Graham, who said, &#8220;I support the effort&#8221; &#8212; just in June of last year &#8212; &#8220;of the Biden Administration to donate vaccines to at-risk populations throughout the world.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Senator Portman said that &#8212; that he is &#8220;pleased&#8221; that legislation &#8212; this is last summer &#8212; that has passed the committee at the time would help ensure that &#8212; that domestic supply is part of our &#8212; what we&#8217;re doing in domestic supply &#8212; excess domestic supply is part of our global vaccination strategy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Senator McConnell said it would be &#8220;terribly unfortunate&#8221; if a supplemental COVID-19 funding package did not include international vaccines.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I&#8217;m not going to prejudge where all they &#8212; they will all be on this or future legislation.&nbsp; I would just note that if we want to continue to be providing to the world, we need money.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a case we will continue to make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ukraine&#8217;s Prosecutor General just suggested that there&#8217;s more gruesome evidence of the aftermath of Russia&#8217;s occupation around Kyiv, saying that the worst situation may, in fact, be in Borodyanka.&nbsp; I apologize if I don&#8217;t pronounce that correctly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But do you have a sense of how widespread this may be in the Kyiv region?&nbsp; I mean, I know Jake just said that you&#8217;re going to continue to see these kinds of brazen attacks, but what more can you tell us about some of these other areas that we may be hearing about?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a new or additional assessment.&nbsp; This is something we will continue to gather information on, and Jake, obviously, outlined a number of ways we will do that &#8212; both by intel gathering, working with our partners and allies around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would also note, Mary &#8212; to go back to your earlier question &#8212; that the fact that we&#8217;re seeing these horrific images from Bucha around the wor- &#8212; you know, now around the world, thanks to all of your broadcasts and many global broadcasters &#8212; I mean, we have access.&nbsp; There&#8217;s access to this area.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not access to a lot of the areas around Mariupol and other areas of Ukraine where we have not even begun to see the impact of the atrocities and the impact of what, as Jake said, President Putin and the Russians made clear they were intending to do from the outset of the war.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, while I don&#8217;t have additional assessment, I would just note that, you know, we should brace ourselves for what we may see as we gain greater access and learn more about what atrocities they have implemented.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The U.S. ambassador to the U.N. says that tomorrow she&#8217;s going to go to New York and seek Russia&#8217;s suspension from Human Rights Council.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that at the direction of the President?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; The President does not believe &#8212; he believes it&#8217;s ludicrous for Russia to be a member of the Human Rights Council.&nbsp; And certainly, the ambassador spoke to this today and while she was on her overseas trip, and she will continue to make the case in her role when she returns to New York.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not seek to permanently expel them?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; From the Human Rights Council?<br>&nbsp;<br>I would point &#8212; I would point you to our U.N. ambassador on what specific steps, but obviously removing them would be the next appropriate step in the process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; So, President Biden is talking about putting Putin on a wartime trial.&nbsp; Does he expect Putin to turn himself in to stand trial?&nbsp; Or does he think somebody&#8217;s going to have to go into Russia and arrest him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, without getting into the mechanisms &#8212; which, I know, were the good questions everybody was asking our National Security Advisor &#8212; there is precedent in the past of how this process can work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re not going to prejudge what the process would work or &#8212; or what steps would be taken through &#8212; through an international legal process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, that&#8217;s not quite where we&#8217;re at right now, Peter, and I can&#8217;t give you a sense of the mechanisms of &#8212; of, if convicted, what would happen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>A question about college sports.&nbsp; In some places like the Ivy League, now there are biological males competing against women.&nbsp; Does the White House think that is fair?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would note that we&#8217;re not the governing body for the NCAA or any other system out there that &#8212; I believe you&#8217;re probably referring to the case over &#8212; in swimming in the NCAA.<br>&nbsp;<br>We understand how important sports are to student athletes across the country.&nbsp; But the NCAA obviously makes &#8212; puts these policies in place.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I would say, Peter, if we look at this broadly, is that we celebrated International Transgender Day of Visibility last week with a slate of new actions to ensure we are continuing &#8212; we continue to protect the dignity and identity of all Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>And at a moment where we&#8217;re looking at and we&#8217;re seeing increased mental health issues related to young people, especially LGBTQ+ young people, we&#8217;re providing additional funding and resources to address this issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we hope all leaders can focus on those important issues and the impact on many of these young people who are impacted across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, what about this new law in Florida?&nbsp; At what age does the White House think that students should be taught about sexual orientation and gender identity?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first of all, Peter, we have spoken to the &#8220;Don&#8217;t Say Gay&#8221; bill in the past &#8212; I believe is what you&#8217;re referring to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;&#8212; and made clear that as we look at this &#8212; this law, what we think it&#8217;s a reflection of is politicians in Florida propagating misinformed, hateful policies that do absolutely nothing to address the real issues.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department of Education is well positioned and ready to evaluate what to do next, and when &#8212; and its implementation &#8212; whether its implementation violates federal civil rights law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would note that parents across the country are looking to, you know, national, state, and district leaders to support our nation&#8217;s students, to ensure that kids are treated equally in schools.&nbsp; And that is certainly not &#8212; this is not a reflection of that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, just the last one.&nbsp; So if you guys oppose this law that bans classroom instruction about sexual orientation and gender identity in K through 3, does the White House support that kind of classroom instruction before kindergarten?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Do you have examples of schools in Florida that are teaching kindergarteners about sex education?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m just asking for the President&#8217;s opinion about this law.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that&#8217;s a &#8212; I think that&#8217;s a relevant question, because I think this is a politically charged, harsh law that is putting parents and LGBTQ+ kids in a very difficult, heartbreaking circumstance.&nbsp; And so, I actually think that&#8217;s a pretty relevant question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Ukraine atrocities, Jake referenced some of the images that all our news organizations have been gathering.&nbsp; Is the administration able to gather other and document other cases that you have assembled that we may not be aware of, in terms of this collection of data on war crimes, rapes, murders &#8212; things like that &#8212; that we have not yet seen?&nbsp; Is there more data that &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the ground, you mean?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve seen, Kelly, that the EU announced their intention to send a team there, which obviously hasn&#8217;t happened yet.&nbsp; But that was an announcement made earlier today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, through intel gathering, we likely do have access to different types of information.&nbsp; We have declassified a range of information over the course of time, which I would expect we continue to do &#8212; we will continue to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Right now, I can&#8217;t give you an assessment of what we may know that you don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; But I would just say and reiterate what Jake said, which is we&#8217;re going to use every tool at our disposal we can &#8212; some of that is through intel channels; some of that is, of course, working with our counterparts around the world &#8212; to gather as much data and information as we can.<br>&nbsp;<br>It is difficult &#8212; to go back to an earlier question &#8212; given that we need access, or even our European friends and partners need access, to gather.&nbsp; But &#8212; but it is vital, it is important, and we are going to do everything we can to support those efforts from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if the Russians are able to take some territory in the east and have greater stability of their control there, would it ever be the U.S. position that that could be a stable outcome?&nbsp; Or is maintaining the current map of Ukrainian sovereignty what the West would want?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s going to be up to the Ukrainians and Ukrainian leaders to determine what the diplomatic path forward looks like here &#8212; what discussions, what negotiations they are comfortable with.<br>&nbsp;<br>What our objective is and what tool we can &#8212; we feel we can most be effective at, I should say, is supporting them and strengthening their hand in these negotiations.&nbsp; And that includes not just the economic support, the military support.&nbsp; I would note, over the course of the last couple of days, the Department of Defense announced an additional package beyond what was announced just a few weeks ago.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to continue to do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>But in terms of the negotiations and what they would be comfortable with, we&#8217;re here to support them, and we&#8217;re not going to predetermine that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just last week, you said that the U.S. is sending protective gear to Ukraine &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to help shield Ukrainians from chemical weapons use.&nbsp; Have those deliveries been made, or have they started?&nbsp; Is there any timeline specifically for those deliveries?&nbsp; Because Jake did mention that deliveries have started.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I can check for you a status of that.&nbsp; We try to do it in an expedited manner.&nbsp; And we still have means of getting equipment of &#8212; a range of equipment to people who need it on the ground.&nbsp; And I can check if that equipment has been delivered, or is in process &#8212; I guess you’re asking.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have a quick question on Elon Musk and him picking up a 9 percent stake in Twitter, which makes him the largest shareholder in the company.&nbsp; Obviously, the White House uses Twitter quite extensively, and Musk has been very critical of President Biden.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if there is perhaps any recalibration of the use of the platform or to what extent, you know, the White House is using Twitter, going forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s a decision of a private sector leader.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any specific comment on it.&nbsp; But I expect we will continue to use Twitter, as you all will as well, I would expect.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could elaborate a little bit more on President Biden and former President Obama and their relationship and how often and how they communicate. And you had mentioned that they are real friends and not just Washington friends.&nbsp; But given that they only live a few miles apart, why is this the first time that the former President has been invited to the White House?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, I have known them both for some time.&nbsp; And I have watched &#8212; I watched their friendship grow over the course of the period of time when the President was vice president and when the former President was president.<br>&nbsp;<br>And why I noted that at the top is because I think people who didn&#8217;t have the seat I had may just think that it&#8217;s like inviting any former President to the White House.&nbsp; And it certainly is not that.&nbsp; They talk on the phone; they do that on a regular basis.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you the number of times they&#8217;ve had conversations, but I would note they consult on a range of issues, but also about their families and things happening in their personal lives.&nbsp; And, you know, it&#8217;s not a relationship of obligation.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one where they developed a deep and close friendship through the course of their time serving together, and that has continued.<br>&nbsp;<br>And tomorrow is, of course, exactly the right time to have the former President come here, given this is one of the proudest accomplishments that they worked on together, they shared together.&nbsp; And it is emblematic of their shared view and belief that government can work for people, and it can work for the American people.&nbsp; And this is an example of building on a success from more than 10 years ago and making it better over time.<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; and I suspect that former President Obama will be back when there is a portrait unveiling and perhaps for other &#8212; other engagements here as well in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Karen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Can you tell us how the President or if he &#8212; the President has engaged with lawmakers in the last couple of days on the COVID funding deal?&nbsp; And has he talked to any Republicans on this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you an outline or a detail of people he&#8217;s spoken to.&nbsp; I will note that it&#8217;s rare that I am in the Oval Office on any given day where he doesn&#8217;t just pick up the phone and call a member of Congress, often a Republican &#8212; at least when I&#8217;m in there &#8212; to talk to them about a range of priorities.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is clearly a huge focus for the President because of the dire need we have at this moment to get this funding through and the fact that we are already at a point where we have had to halt, delay a range of programs and purchases that we feel are imperative.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that on the global side, you know, we are &#8212; we already need to stop plans to expla- &#8212; expand the global vaccination initiative to more countries.&nbsp; We’ll also have to immediately scale back our global efforts to provide lifesaving tools &#8212; this is a little bit of what I mentioned earlier &#8212; like oxygen systems, antiviral pills &#8212; things that can cut death rates by 90 percent for the unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would also note that, even as we&#8217;re very encouraged by the progress, we&#8217;re going to need more &#8212; because our objective here is going to continue to be &#8212; to be ahead of the process and be ahead in planning to make sure we can have funding for antivirals, the vaccines needed for people for many months to come.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to be clear: So, he has been talking on this specific issue (inaudible) &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s been engaged with a range of members about a range of issues.&nbsp; This is a huge priority.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to get into the details of what those calls look like.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I just wanted to clarify what I was asking Jake there, because it sounded like, at the end, he was leaving open the possibility of U.S. boots on the ground to protect civilians in Ukraine or to protect the supply chain.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think that was his intention.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Because he did say, in terms of the supply chain or civilians, that you&#8217;re discussing all possibilities with allies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212; nothing has changed about the President&#8217;s view about boots on the ground.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the jobs report came out on Friday.&nbsp; Inflation is at 7.9 percent.&nbsp; It shows average hourly wages went up 5.6 percent.&nbsp; I wonder what the level of concern is for the President and the White House that people will stop spending because the stuff they want is more expensive and that leads us to a recession.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say on the latter part of your question that what we know is that the economy is strong, our recovery has been strong.&nbsp; And that continues to be &#8212; while we, of course, are monitoring progress and where we have concern &#8212; including rising costs and, obviously, the need to continue to address inflation &#8212; that continues to be our assessment, which is &#8212; which is even as there are challenges we need to continue to address, it means that we have a strong basis that we are building from.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would remind you also that the unemployment rate is 3.6 percent.&nbsp; And the President created more jobs last year than any president in American history.&nbsp; So those fundamentals are also backed up by data.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, what we&#8217;re trying to do &#8212; as you know from following this closely, there are a couple of areas that are impacting rising costs more than others &#8212; right? &#8212; including the price of gas, including the price of automobiles and the impacts on the car industry of the lack of &#8212; the chip shortages.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, what we&#8217;re also trying to do is take steps to address each area where we see rising costs.&nbsp; And obviously, the President&#8217;s announcement on Thursday to do a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, where we&#8217;ve seen already a small reduction in the price of gas and the price of oil come down by several dollars, is an effort to bring down costs that are impacting people&#8217;s checkbook, pocketbooks &#8212; checkbook, et cetera.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you&#8217;re not concerned about if consumers stop spending?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We, of course, continue to assess, but I don&#8217;t have any projection of that at this point in time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, one thing on the wealth tax.&nbsp; Elon Musk tweeted out last week that Tesla and SpaceX would &#8220;have died&#8221; if such attacks existed in 2008, after the Great Recession.&nbsp; With the push for EVs and space exploration, what&#8217;s the White House level of concern that that a wealth tax could stifle innovation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that, you know, right now, America&#8217;s teachers and firefighters pay a higher tax rate than billionaires.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t even think Elon Musk probably thinks that&#8217;s fair.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know who thinks that&#8217;s fair.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not fair, and that should not be the case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, what this proposal does and why the President supports it, in his view, is it fixes that.&nbsp; And this would close an unfair tax loophole and promote economic growth by encouraging productivity, enhancing investments.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, really, what it does &#8212; to get into the nitty gritty of it &#8212; is, you know, right now, the super wealthy &#8212; billionaires &#8212; I think everyone considers them super wealthy &#8212; are able to access the value of their assets, even if they never sell them, in order to finance lavish consumption.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And right now, billionaires with unrealized gains borrow against their assets during li- &#8212; their life at ultra-low interest rates.&nbsp; And when &#8212; when they die, they get a step-up in basis and no tax is paid on the appreciation of their asset.&nbsp; In other words, their income is never taxed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s not fair.&nbsp; And I think what the President is trying to do and what many senators and others support is closing that.&nbsp; Why that should impact a lack of innovation, I think there should be more explanation on.&nbsp; This is trying to make the system more fair.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, sorry, Weijia.&nbsp; I’ll come back to you.&nbsp; Go ahead, in the middle.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; It seemed U.S. senators have written President Biden, urging him to designate Cameroon for TPS.&nbsp; Is that something he&#8217;s willing to do?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; an assessment is made by a process led by the Department of Homeland Security, so I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that at this point in time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on his approval rating: When he came into office last year, he was around 60 percent and even more, and now he&#8217;s around 40 percent and sometimes less.&nbsp; Who does he blame now: Putin, Trump, you &#8212; the communication team?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, does he blame me?&nbsp; Oh, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I hope not.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, I think that the President recognizes that the country is still grappling with a number of challenges that impact people and their everyday lives, whether that is a continuing fight with a pandemic that has been going on for several years or the fact that costs are going up.&nbsp; Some of those are a result of the actions of President Putin &#8212; yes, as it relates to gas prices &#8212; but others are related to impacts of COVID-19 and impacts on the supply chain.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, what our focus is and his focus continues to be: on solutions to address these challenges, and keeping our heads down and trying to continue to deliver for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Weijia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Shifting to Russian billionaires because, today, the DOJ announced the seizure of that &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; huge, $90 million yacht.&nbsp; Is there any evidence that zoning in on Putin’s close allies in this way &#8212; seizing their assets &#8212; is having an impact on his calculations?&nbsp; And if not, what is the end goal here to try to apply pressure to Putin himself?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s not the only approach we&#8217;re taking &#8212; right, Weijia? &#8212; but it is one of the steps that we have &#8212; our national security team determined from the beginning would hopefully be effective on putting necessary pressure on. That includes significant consequences we have implemented on the Russian economy, but it also includes going after people who are in the inner circle and are close, where their actions have warranted that, including Russian oligarchs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But it is not our &#8212; our expectation is not that one component is going to lead to a direct change.&nbsp; These are just a range of pressure points, and we&#8217;re going to lu- &#8212; use all of them that we possibly can.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the hope that this particular action will take?&nbsp; What &#8212; because we&#8217;re seeing so many images of yachts around the world being seized, other assets being seized.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, it&#8217;s one of several actions we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; And I think if you look at the totality of it and the pool of the actions, the Russian economy has been on a downward spiral.&nbsp; There are businesses &#8212; private sector businesses around the world have pulled their &#8212; their business and their investments out of Russia.&nbsp; They&#8217;re isolated from the world.&nbsp; The oligarchs are isolated from the world.&nbsp; All of these are meant to be consequences and meant to, of course, impact the calculation over the longer term.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one quick one &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the President&#8217;s announcement last week about the<br>strategic supply of oil.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you know, the crude prices came down &#8212; we saw that almost right away &#8212; but how long do you expect that Band-Aid will hold if OPEC does not also agree to ramp up production, which it has not so far?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s how you should look at it.&nbsp; It was intentionally done as a million barrels a day over the course of six months because we knew there needed to be, kind of, a gap filled for that period of time, where our expectation and hope is that there could be greater production by the oil companies over that course of time.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are also steps &#8212; as you&#8217;ve seen, this as a coordinated release around the world, and there was an announcement last Friday about that as well &#8212; by other countries to help fill the gap that we see from Russia and from the fact that their oil is not contributing as much as it had historically onto the global marketplace.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, oil prices are global &#8212; I mean, it&#8217;s a global marketplace.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re already seeing, as you said, a reduction, but this is meant to be a six-month effort to kind of bridge the gap in many ways for that period of time and ramp up production in a range of ways.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yes, you referenced OPEC Plus, but also other countries last Friday announced their plans and their intentions to release more oil to help meet the supply needs on the market.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re intending to do here, and we&#8217;re going to continue to look at many ways to achieve that objective.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Iran, over the weekend, said that a deal was close.&nbsp; We heard something different from U.S. officials only days before that.&nbsp; So, what is the current assessment of that deal?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our assessment is that the onus for concluding this deal is squarely on Iran.&nbsp; Together with our European allies, the United States has negotiated the roadmap for a mutual return to compliance through the Vienna talks.&nbsp; The President will reenter the deal if it&#8217;s in our national security interests.&nbsp; And both ourselves and our allies are prepared to conclude a strong agreement if Iran is prepared to do the same.<br>&nbsp;<br>What we&#8217;ve seen, however, is that Iran has raised a number of issues that has nothing to do with the mutual compliance under the nuclear deal.&nbsp; And that is where our focus and our objective is.&nbsp; So, we would encourage Iran to focus on the deal negotiated in Vienna, rather than seeking to open issues outside the Vienna context or casting blame, of course, on others for a pause in the talks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the White House making a &#8212; any push this week &#8212; last-minute push &#8212; to get another Republican or two to support Judge Jackson?<br>&nbsp;<br>And secondly, if you could reflect on what Senator Graham said about if Republicans were in control, that she wouldn&#8217;t get a hearing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me say on the first part that our view continues to be that Judge Jackson&#8217;s credentials, her record warrant bipartisan support.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen some of that to date.&nbsp; But certainly, we&#8217;re going to continue to work the phones up until the last moment here.&nbsp; But I can&#8217;t make a prediction for you on what the end result of that will be.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say on Senator Graham&#8217;s comments, I think the best questions are probably posed to Senator Graham.&nbsp; I would remind you all that he has previously voted for Judge Jackson when her record and her credentials were exactly the same as they are today.&nbsp; So, it seems like there&#8217;s more questions that could be posed to him.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a follow-up on the Senate Supreme Court confirmation hearing: Republicans have said that they wanted to &#8212; that this would be a respectful and fair process, and it&#8217;s been very contentious.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Given Senator Graham&#8217;s comments, what do you think is the nature of the Supreme Court as we look ahead for the future, not just this Supreme Court nominee but for future nominations, given the contentious comments from Senator Graham?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, I think that our view continues to be that qualified nominees, those who meet every objective bar of qualification of backgrounds should be considered and treated with fairness as they go through the process.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how President Biden is going to continue to &#8212; to operate.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how we would expect every member of the Senate to continue to operate.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, obviously, his comments are disappointing, but our focus needs to continue to be on supporting Judge Jackson and her path to the Supreme Court.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask two questions &#8212; one about refugees and one about the Supreme Court.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On refugees, the 100,000 number that the President put out when you all were in Europe &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; can you talk about how you arrived at that number and what preparations are being made at this point to accept those refugees?&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t seen the State Department really put out a lot of detail yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I expect we&#8217;ll have more soon.&nbsp; And I think the understandable questions are kind of the prioritization and how the process will work and what the models will be &#8212; all very good questions.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re just working through the final pieces of the policy process at this point in time.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the number, it doesn&#8217;t mean we will &#8212; we will reach that number.&nbsp; As you know, while there have been a startling number of refugees &#8212; individuals who have been kicked out of their homes because of the Russian invasion of Ukraine &#8212; the vast majority of them want to stay in neighboring countries.&nbsp; And that continues to be our expectation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is just an effort for us to play a role, beyond the historic amount of humanitarian assistance and support we&#8217;re providing to neighboring countries, to ensure that we can find a pathway for those who want to come to the United States to come here too.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re still finalizing the policy details, and hopefully we&#8217;ll have more soon on that for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask one more on the Supreme Court.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden was asked last week about Justice Clarence Thomas.&nbsp; I believe he said something &#8212; or he said it was up to the Justice Department or the January 6th Committee on whether Justice Clarence Thomas would recuse himself from any of those cases &#8212; those being the January 6th cases.<br>&nbsp;<br>Judicial ethics mean that the Supreme Court Justice generally makes his own decision on recusals.&nbsp; Does the President still agree with the view of the Justice Department or January 6th Committee should decide?&nbsp; Has he taken a position at this point on whether Justice Thomas should recuse himself?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;That&#8217;s a decision up to the Supreme Court.&nbsp;&nbsp;We don&#8217;t have any additional position from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They were friends from the time they were on Foreign Relations Committee together.<br>&nbsp;<br>So in terms of &#8212; Japan has the largest number of U.S. troops.&nbsp; Is there some way that they could be involved, as a country that also went through war, with this current situation in Russia?&nbsp; And do you know if they&#8217;ve been included in some of these discussions going forward?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know that they have been included and a part of the conversations, including during President Biden&#8217;s recent trip to Europe, and that our partnership and friendship with Japan continues as we discuss how to help support Ukraine through the invasion &#8212; Russia&#8217;s invasion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I believe you&#8217;re running out of time.&nbsp; Maybe just a couple more?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, we&#8217;re going to do one or two more.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Amid the Ukraine crisis, we know the United States and Russia are still working together on Afghanistan issues.&nbsp; Actually, last Thursday, March 31st, there was a meeting in China where the U.S., China, and Russia delegations went over this issue.&nbsp; Can you describe the working relations between U.S. and Russia on this meeting?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s China&#8217;s role on it?&nbsp; Do you worry China might take advantage of the tension between the U.S. and Russia right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; China &#8212; and just to make sure I&#8217;m unpacking your question: What you&#8217;re asking about &#8212; you&#8217;re asking about a meeting on Afghanistan between Russian, U.S., and Afg- &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, Chinese officials?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point you to the State Department.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to get more details on it and see.&nbsp; I would note that Russia and China are both members of the P5+1.&nbsp; And obviously, we&#8217;re continuing to pursue a diplomatic deal there as well.&nbsp; So, there are other examples of us working, even as we are horrified by the atrocities in Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, last one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Moments ago, you said that it was &#8220;ludicrous&#8221; that Russia would be allowed to sit on the U.N. Human Rights Council.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if the President wants to see China remain on that Human Rights Council as well, given that his administration has already made a determination that China is engaged in genocide against the Uyghur people.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our focus right now on the international stage on this question is on Russia, given the invasion of Ukraine and given what we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; the photos from Bucha, others that we may see in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we will continue to press publicly and privately where we have concerns about human rights violations, including as it relates to China.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks so much, everyone.</p>



<p>4:14 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on Public School&#160;Infrastructure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/04/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-public-school-infrastructure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 23:09:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thomas Elementary SchoolWashington, D.C. 5:18 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you all.&#160; Thank you. &#160;Please, have a seat.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, Ms. Trina.&#160; (Laughter.) I am so happy to be surrounded by our young leaders.&#160; I am telling you, this is &#8212; a highlight of being Vice President is to be around all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Thomas Elementary School<br>Washington, D.C.</em></p>



<p>5:18 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;Please, have a seat.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, Ms. Trina.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>I am so happy to be surrounded by our young leaders.&nbsp; I am telling you, this is &#8212; a highlight of being Vice President is to be around all of our young leaders.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so happy to be with you all today, and I&#8217;m so proud of you.<br><br>Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br><br>It is good to be here at Thomas Elementary and to be introduced, of course, by a graduate of Thomas Elementary.<br><br>And today we are joined, as you know, by extraordinary leaders: our Secretary of Energy, Jennifer Granholm; our Administration&#8217;s National Climate Advisor, Gina McCarthy; and our Secretary of Education, Miguel Cardona, who began his career as an elementary school teacher.<br><br>And we are also joined, of course, by the Chancellor of<br>D.C. Public Schools, Lewis Ferebee, and by a number of labor leaders and advocates for the future of our country: “they” being the children of our nation.<br><br>All &#8212; all of you are truly indispensable as partners to our administration.&nbsp; And I bring you greetings on behalf of the President, Joe Biden.<br><br>So, it is an honor to share the stage with so many of you and with so many extraordinary young leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I will tell you that when I look out at who&#8217;s here and I spent some time quickly with the principals who are here, the teachers who are here, I just love our teachers.&nbsp; I love our educators.&nbsp; I love our principals.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I really do.&nbsp; I really do.<br><br>And I will tell you: My first-grade teacher &#8212; my first-grade teacher attended my law school graduation.&nbsp; Mrs. Frances Wilson &#8212; God rest her soul &#8212; attended my law school graduation.&nbsp; There are many things that have contributed to me being here at this very moment as Vice President, and that is one of them.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I thank you all &#8212; the educators &#8212; for what you do every day, because I know this work is personal to you.&nbsp; And you are raising and helping to raise, along with the parents and the community, the future of our nation.<br><br>And over the past two years, you have faced incredible challenges, in particular.&nbsp; You have responded with incredible resilience and strength.&nbsp; I was talking with Madam Principal earlier, and we toured through the school.&nbsp; What dedication this has required, in particular these last two years, doing everything that you can in your power to ensure that your students have been learning and growing.&nbsp; And you have continued to fight to ensure all schools receive the resources they need &#8212; in the midst of all of that and before.&nbsp;<br><br>And we might not be here today making these exciting announcements were it not for your longstanding advocacy.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President and I are deeply grateful for all you have done and all you continue to do.<br><br>So, about a year ago &#8212; I was talking to the Secretary of Education &#8212; about a year ago, we took a trip to Connecticut, and I met a young student by the name of Galya, and she was five years old. &nbsp;<br><br>And from the moment I walked into her classroom,<br>she was glued by my side.&nbsp; And she was something.&nbsp; She was absolutely something.&nbsp; Charming, energetic, intelligent.<br><br>At one point, I bent down and I said to her, &#8220;Galya, you can be anything you want to be.&#8221;<br><br>And she looked me in my eyes, and she said, &#8220;Well, I want to be everything.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Yes, she did.&nbsp; She &#8212; and she &#8212; and she will be.&nbsp; And she will be.&nbsp;<br><br>And that ambition, that aspiration is extraordinary.&nbsp; And it is not uncommon.<br><br>In every classroom, in every school, in every community<br>of our nation, there are young people like Galya, like these young leaders behind me who see so much, who are so smart, who have such bright and creative ideas, and who will be the future of our nation and are currently leaders in their own right.<br><br>These young people who dream of becoming scientists and doctors and engineers and teachers.&nbsp; Young people filled with so much passion and purpose.<br><br>And our future will be determined, I know that, by these young leaders.<br><br>And our nation, therefore, has an obligation to ensure nothing limits their ability to learn, to grow, and to thrive.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, today, our administration is releasing the Biden-Harris Action Plan for Building Better School Infrastructure.&nbsp; This Plan contains a number of initiatives that will improve the learning environment for public school children across our nation.&nbsp; And today, I’ll provide a few examples.&nbsp;<br><br>For decades, our country has chronically underinvested in our public schools.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And far too many of our school districts have gone without important repairs and upgrades to buildings and to classrooms.&nbsp; For example, upgrades to heating, to ventilation, and air conditioning systems, known as HVAC systems, which was highlighted, as we know, during the course of the height of the pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>In schools with outdated HVAC systems, classrooms are often<br>too cold in the winter and too hot in the spring and approaching the summer.&nbsp; And, of course, that harms our students and their ability to concentrate and perform all year round.&nbsp; And it threatens the health and wellbeing of students, of teachers, of staff, and administrators.<br><br>One school, for example, in St. Paul, Minnesota, that I&#8217;ve been told about had to pass out wet towels and water bottles in the days before summer break because classroom temperatures were pushing 100 degrees.&nbsp; A dozen students had to be sent to the nurse&#8217;s office.<br><br>Schools with inadequate HVAC systems are also more likely to have poor indoor air quality.&nbsp; Studies have shown that breathing such air, day in and day out, can of course trigger allergies and asthma attacks.<br><br>And we know that schools in low-income and minority districts are more likely to have dangerous indoor air quality. This is just simply unacceptable.&nbsp; Unacceptable.<br><br>Today, the Department of Energy, therefore, is launching a $500 million grant program, funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, to enable public schools to invest in energy upgrades.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And these grants will be &#8212; can be and will be used on a number of the issues that we have just discussed, such as improving school HVAC systems, similar to what happened right here at Thomas Elementary with the help of Mayor Muriel Bowser and the Representative who is here &#8212; Eleanor Holmes Norton, who&#8217;s here and has been a leader for so long.&nbsp;<br><br>I &#8212; I cannot thank you enough for all that you do.&nbsp; I just &#8212; want to just take a point of personal privilege, if I may.&nbsp; And if we can just &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Eleanor Holmes Norton has been fighting for the children of D.C. for as long as I can remember.&nbsp; I looked up to you in your role of leadership when I was a student here at Howard University.&nbsp; And so many of us look to you always as a voice of conscience for what our country deserves and what the children and the people of Washington, D.C., deserve.&nbsp; Thank you so very much.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so glad to see you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And these Department of Energy grants can also be used to install energy-efficient windows, solar panels, and better insulation.&nbsp; And they will, of course, prioritize undeserved [sic] &#8212; underserved, excuse me, districts.&nbsp;<br><br>These grants will also save schools money.&nbsp; In most school districts, the second-largest yearly expense after salaries is the energy bill.&nbsp; These grants will help schools reduce their energy costs significantly &#8212; savings that can be reinvested in the school to hire more teachers, to make long-needed repairs, or to invest in new technology to support learning.&nbsp;<br><br>And at the same time, these projects will create good-paying union jobs for electricians and carpenters and painters and more.&nbsp;<br><br>Every public school in the country is eligible to apply for these grants, and I encourage them to do so.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, we know that the school day does not start when students set foot on school grounds.&nbsp; It starts when they get on the school bus or on their bicycle or when they lace up their shoes and walk out the door.&nbsp; And that is why our administration is working to ensure students are safe and healthy when they are on their way to and from school.<br><br>For example, through the Department of Transportation&#8217;s Safe Routes to Schools, we are providing funding for schools to invest in safer walking and biking routes.&nbsp; And &#8212; (applause) &#8211;and, again, because our theory of the case &#8212; and I don&#8217;t have to tell anyone here: Their school day starts from the time they wake up, which &#8212; don&#8217;t have me started about what that means in terms of all of the responsibilities that we have as a society to understand that if we want to care for, protect, and support the children of our nation, we must do that in the context in the families in which they are being raised and address the needs of that family as well to be able to provide the best that we can for those young people.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And for those students who take the school bus, we are investing in a program that is especially close to my heart. &nbsp;Yellow school buses are our nation&#8217;s largest form of mass transit.&nbsp; Yellow school buses.&nbsp; Every day, millions of children ride on diesel school buses, breathing toxic fumes that can harm their health.&nbsp;<br><br>When I was senator, I introduced the first bill to electrify our nation&#8217;s school buses.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m proud that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests $5 billion dollars in the EPA’s Clean School Bus program to help school districts electrify their fleet of buses.&nbsp;<br><br>To all students &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to all the students who are watching today: You are the leaders of today and tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>And as we take on the challenges of the future &#8212; and I&#8217;m looking at our students &#8212; we need your help.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; We need your ideas.&nbsp; We need your intelligence.&nbsp; We need your ambition.&nbsp; And I want you to always have ambition.&nbsp; And we need your aspiration.&nbsp; All right?&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>And in that way, our world &#8212; our nation and our world will be all that it can be.&nbsp; And I will make this promise to our young leaders: that we will continue to fight to ensure that you have every opportunity to not only succeed, but to thrive.&nbsp;<br><br>We are counting on you.&nbsp; And when I look at you, each one of you, I know our future is bright.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>END &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 5:31 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden Marking 54 Years Since Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.’s&#160;Assassination</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/04/statement-by-president-biden-marking-54-years-since-dr-martin-luther-king-jr-s-assassination/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 22:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50526</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few years ago, I visited the National Civil Rights Museum in Memphis, which is the site of the Lorraine Motel. I stood on its balcony, where Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. last stood before a hateful gunman took away his last breath fifty-four years ago today. The motel balcony leads back into Dr. King’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>A few years ago, I visited the National Civil Rights Museum in Memphis, which is the site of the Lorraine Motel. I stood on its balcony, where Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. last stood before a hateful gunman took away his last breath fifty-four years ago today.</p>



<p>The motel balcony leads back into Dr. King’s room, preserved just as it was on that day.&nbsp; The bed is unmade.&nbsp;Coffee cups are on the table.&nbsp; There is a restless spirit in that room – of a dream deferred, of unfinished business. The night before, Dr. King preached from the pulpit of Mason Temple and delivered what would be his final sermon, <em>“Let us move on in these powerful days, these days of challenge, to make America what it ought to be.”</em><br>&nbsp;<br>Fifty-four years later, his charge remains as vital as it was that night. A charge to make real the promise of America for all Americans – a promise that holds we are all created equally and deserve to be treated equally throughout our lives. As a nation, we have never fully lived up to that promise, but we have never fully walked away from it either.</p>



<p>And in this past year, we have made great strides forward by putting racial equity at the center of our work: to beat COVID-19, rebuild our economy, tackle the climate crisis, and root out systemic racism from our nation’s laws, policies, and institutions. But whether it’s delivering racial justice, safeguarding the sacred right to vote, or giving hate no safe harbor, we know that challenges remain.</p>



<p>As we look ahead, on this day of remembrance, let us pray for Dr. King and his family. Let us redouble our efforts to deliver the promise of America that he gave his life for.</p>



<p>Let us move on in these powerful days to come.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Trucking Action Plan to Strengthen Our Nation’s Supply&#160;Chains</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/04/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-trucking-action-plan-to-strengthen-our-nations-supply-chains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 21:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 2:08 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I think she can do anything she wants, don’t you?&#160; Well, hello, everyone.&#160; It’s an honor to welcome you to the White House out on the lawn here.&#160; I heard that helicopter going by.&#160; I was hoping the helo wasn’t going to land.&#160; (Laughter.) Maria, thanks for sharing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Lawn</em></p>



<p>2:08 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think she can do anything she wants, don’t you?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, hello, everyone.&nbsp; It’s an honor to welcome you to the White House out on the lawn here.&nbsp; I heard that helicopter going by.&nbsp; I was hoping the helo wasn’t going to land.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Maria, thanks for sharing your story.</p>



<p>And my buddy, Patrick Murphy, former Assistant Secretary &#8212; Secretary of the Army as well as a former congressman.  And the boy stays in shape, man.  Huh?  Look at him.  (Laughter.)  I tell you &#8212;</p>



<p>CHAIR MURPHY:&nbsp; I’m trying to (inaudible) you, sir.&nbsp; I (inaudible) you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I tell you what, man, I &#8212; and I want to thank you for being here, man.&nbsp; Nobody worked harder as a congressman or Acting Secretary of the Army to connect veterans to opportunity, and that’s what it’s all &#8212; been all about for you.</p>



<p>And I want to thank another veteran who knows a thing or two about laying the foundation for good jobs and the transportation sector: Secretary Buttigieg.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I &#8212; he says, “Go Navy.”&nbsp; He says, “Go Army.”&nbsp; I used to say, “Go Navy,” but then my son got a Bronze Star in the Army and I decided I couldn’t say it anymore.&nbsp; So I just say, “Go American forces.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to recognize &#8212; he couldn’t be here today, but Marty Walsh, the Secretary of the &#8212; of Labor.&nbsp; And he’s doing an outstanding job helping to lead this effort alongside Pete &#8212; Secretary Buttigieg.</p>



<p>And, you know, I want to welcome members of Congress who are here today as well.&nbsp; Tammy, how are you, Tammy?&nbsp; Good to see you.&nbsp; Tammy Baldwin, by the way.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, Congressman Pete DeFazio.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Laura Underwood &#8212; where’s Laura?&nbsp; There she is, right there &#8212; right in front.&nbsp; Good to see you, Laura.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I want to particularly shout out to the new President of the Teamsters, Sean O’Brien.&nbsp; Stand up, man; I want them to see you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As &#8212; as they say in parts of Wilmington, Delaware, “These guys brung me to the dance” 35 years ago &#8212; 40 years ago.</p>



<p>And also, I want to say a quick hi to a pal.&nbsp; And you’ve been a pal.&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; thank you for being here and getting things done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, in addition to all that, there’s an outfit called &#8212; you’ve probably heard of them &#8212; the United Mine Workers.&nbsp; Yeah, well, you know, they got the president here too.&nbsp; Mr. President, where are you?&nbsp; Where is he sitting?&nbsp; He was here.&nbsp; A lot of truckers in the United Mine Workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At any rate, folks, I spend a lot of time talking about the economy and the record-breaking economic comeback we’re &#8212; experienced because of all of you sitting out there in those chairs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I want to talk with people who are &#8212; who are making the comeback possible &#8212; people like Maria, who you just heard from, and her son Roman who’s going there pretty soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all those truck drivers and their families that are here today, I want to thank you all to &#8212; you keep &#8212; what you’re doing to keep America moving, because that’s literally what you’re doing, especially these last two years helping carry the nation, literally, on your backs.</p>



<p>You learned, on Friday, the economy created 431,000 jobs in March.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; A record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the course of my presidency, the economy has now created 7.9 million jobs.&nbsp; More jobs in the first 14 months than any President ever &#8212; (applause) &#8212; in large part of all of you.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>Unemployment is at 3.6 percent, down from 6.4 when we took office.&nbsp; The fastest decline in unemployment at the start of any presidential term ever recorded.</p>



<p>And after a long stretch, Americans are back to work.&nbsp; Americans are back to work.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>An economy has gone from being on the mend to being on the move.&nbsp; And the economy we’re building &#8212; we’re building a strong economy, one where hardworking Americans can live with dignity, support their families, build a better life, and a better life for their children as well.</p>



<p>All of you here today are people our economy should be built around because you all &#8212; you all are the people who literally make it run.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; You literally make it run.</p>



<p>I have nothing against investment bankers.&nbsp; They could all retire and nothing much would change.&nbsp; You all quit, everything comes to a halt.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; Come to a literal halt.</p>



<p>During the pandemic, a lot of Americans have been introduced to a term you all know well &#8212; and Pete used it: supply chains.&nbsp; A simple term.&nbsp; A supply chain is a journey &#8212; the journey of a product to get to a customer’s doorstep.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it is.</p>



<p>And during the pandemic, those chains were interrupted.&nbsp; Factory closures around the world &#8212; not just in the United States, around the world &#8212; caused backups and delays because of COVID.</p>



<p>At the same time, because of the strength and speed of our recovery, Americans had more money in their pockets than they had in a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the pandemic, they wanted to spend that money not on restaurants or vacations, which are now coming back as well, but on hard goods.</p>



<p>They wanted home improvements, televisions, and automobiles &#8212; things that had to be transported.&nbsp; The very products that slow down by disruptions of the supply chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Demand was high.&nbsp; Supply was interrupted.&nbsp; And the recipe for higher prices and long delays &#8212; that’s exactly what we saw not only here, but all around the world.</p>



<p>So, we knew we needed every tool at our disposal to address the problem.&nbsp; And the best way to do it was to invest in people who make the supply chain run.&nbsp; Trucking moves about 70 percent &#8212; about 70 percent of all the goods in this country.&nbsp; Seventy percent.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And truck drivers are facing real challenges.&nbsp; The average driver waits four and a half hours for their truck to be loaded and unloaded during an eleven-hour shift &#8212; and 40 percent of their day.&nbsp; And often, they don’t get paid for that wait time.</p>



<p>Back in 1978, the average truck driver&#8217;s pay was $34 &#8212; was $34 an hour in today’s dollars.&nbsp; Last year, it was $25 an hour, nearly a 30 percent decline.&nbsp; In this iconic American industry, it’s getting harder and harder to raise a family with dignity and pride that you deserve.&nbsp; And it’s no surprise so many drivers left their jobs.</p>



<p>The workforce is getting older &#8212; not that I am, but they are.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I used to drive a truck; it&#8217;s a long story.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>It’s getting har- &#8212; and I thought I was going to get to drive one of these suckers today, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; anyway, it&#8217;s another story, too.</p>



<p>But, look, it&#8217;s getting harder and harder to recruit new drivers, particularly women and people of color, to an industry that this nation and our economy desperately needs at full strength.</p>



<p>The good news is that since I took office, we’ve begun to turn things around.&nbsp; In fact &#8212; and 2021 was the best year for trucking employment since 1994.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There are now 35,000 more trucking jobs than there were before the pandemic.</p>



<p>But we all know that we need to move faster getting more people working in this industry, in jobs they can rely on and raise a family on.</p>



<p>That’s why last December we brought together industry and labor to tackle the problem facing drivers, and we listened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when we heard that there were long wait times in many states for people wanting to get their commercial driver’s licenses &#8212; their CDLs &#8212; we took action.&nbsp; We provided technical assistance as well as $57 million in federal funds to help states issue these CDLs faster.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’m proud to report: Because of Pete and others, so far in 2022, we’re issuing CDLs at double the rate of last year &#8212; 120,000 in January and February alone.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also know that the key ingredient to getting and keeping more drivers was increasing training programs like the registered apprenticeships approved by the Department of Labor &#8212; programs that allow aspiring drivers to learn while &#8212; earn while they learn, while making this essential job more attractive for potential drivers regardless of age, background, and gender.</p>



<p>The program has proven to be &#8212; improve safety and better working conditions and better pay and benefits.</p>



<p>Typically, it takes about eight months to create a registered apprenticeship program.&nbsp; But because of Pete and others and this Department of Labor, we were able to cut the red tape.&nbsp; And now it takes as little as two days.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>As a result, in the last 90 days, 100 major employers have launched new registered apprenticeship programs &#8212; UPS, Domino’s, Pepsi, Albertsons, and more; along with the trade associations, like the American Trucking Association, the National Minority Trucking Association, the Food Industry Association, and others.</p>



<p>What that all adds up to is a strong foundation for the work ahead: a pipeline of hardworking men and women from all backgrounds, highly trained and highly motivated to get behind the wheel, including a whole lot of veterans, thanks to the veterans trucking initiative known as “Taskforce Movement” by Patrick Murphy &#8212; led by Patrick Murphy.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, I&#8217;d say, parenthetically: If you can handle a tank, if you can handle an armored personnel carrier, you sure in hell can handle one of these suckers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And an awful lot of well-known people also.</p>



<p>The idea &#8212; I remember &#8212; I&#8217;m going to just digress for one second.&nbsp; I &#8212; I got a commercial license because my dad used to run an automobile agency.&nbsp; And I used to have to go up to the body shop up in Philadelphia from Wilmington. &nbsp;And when they&#8217;d order a trailer or a cab, I&#8217;d just &#8212; they’d sell the cab.&nbsp; And so, I had to have a licensed to be able to drive it up and back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, during the truckers strike years later, when I was a young senator, I was &#8212; there was a guy who ran steel from Deemer Steel out to Ohio.&nbsp; And so, I decided to ride out with him to see what it was like in the strike.&nbsp; And I was driving, going through Shiloh, Ohio, and &#8212; and we &#8212; he was &#8212; his handle was “Big 10”.&nbsp; And I remember every &#8212; all the trucks stops were being blockaded at the time during the strike.</p>



<p>And he &#8212; he called, and he said, “Big 10 wanting to come in.”&nbsp; I forget exactly how he said it.&nbsp; And the &#8212; and the only woman truck driver I ever knew I met that day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She said, “This is Big Mama.&nbsp; No room.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Swear to God, true story.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Swear to God.&nbsp; He said, “I’ve got a United States senator driving my truck.”&nbsp; She said, “I got the damn president in mine.&nbsp; So what?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’ll never forget that.&nbsp; I was a very powerful guy.</p>



<p>Anyway &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; that was the first woman trucker I met.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But look, the Labor and &#8212; Labor and Transportation Departments are working closely with industry to tackle issues facing women in trucking, recruit and retrain more women drivers so we can draw more Americans to work with increased wages, reduced wait times, and improved safety, and so much more.</p>



<p>Folks, there’s a heck of a lot more we have to do.&nbsp;&nbsp; A lot more we have to do.&nbsp; Secretary Buttigieg laid out some of the steps we’re taking to make these jobs more attractive for more Americans.&nbsp; And it’s all centered around listening to you, the drivers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, you’ve got to keep it &#8212; we’ve got to keep it going.&nbsp; We’re building a better economy around American manufacturing and American supply chains.&nbsp; And thanks to the Infrastructure Law &#8212; and it wasn’t my law; it was a bipartisan &#8212; one of the few great bipartisan things we&#8217;ve done this year &#8212; we’re making the largest investment in American roads and bridges since, literally, the creation of the Interstate Highway System.&nbsp; And that means a bright future for American trucking.</p>



<p>This &#8212; this country will be counting on you more than it ever has.&nbsp; So we should be able to &#8212; you should be able to count on us to keep investing in you and your families.&nbsp; That’s exactly what we’re going to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m looking forward to all of the progress we’re going to make together.&nbsp; And I want to thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you for being here.&nbsp; Thank you for what you do.&nbsp; Thank your families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And may God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>   2:20 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
