<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 16:41:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the Death Of Abe&#160;Shinzo</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/08/a-proclamation-on-the-death-of-abe-shinzo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 16:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56970</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The longest serving Prime Minister in Japan&#8217;s history, Abe Shinzo was a proud servant of the Japanese people and a faithful friend to the United States.  He worked with American Presidents of both parties to deepen the Alliance between our nations and advance a common vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific. Even in the moment&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The longest serving Prime Minister in Japan&#8217;s history, Abe Shinzo was a proud servant of the Japanese people and a faithful friend to the United States.  He worked with American Presidents of both parties to deepen the Alliance between our nations and advance a common vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific. Even in the moment he was attacked and killed, he was engaged in the work of democracy, to which he dedicated his life.  </p>



<p>As a mark of respect for the memory of Abe Shinzo, former Prime Minister of Japan, by the authority vested in me as President of the United States by the&nbsp;Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States of America, I&nbsp;hereby order that the flag of&nbsp;the United&nbsp;States shall be flown at half-staff at the White&nbsp;House and upon all public buildings and grounds, at all military posts and naval stations, and on all naval vessels of&nbsp;the Federal Government in the District of Columbia and throughout the United&nbsp;States and its Territories and possessions until sunset, July 10, 2022. &nbsp;I also direct that the flag shall be flown at&nbsp;half-staff for the same length of time at all United&nbsp;States embassies, legations, consular offices, and other facilities abroad, including all military facilities and naval vessels and&nbsp;stations.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-seventh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Biden on the June&#160;Jobs Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-june-jobs-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 13:41:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we learned that our private sector has recovered all of the jobs lost during the pandemic, and added jobs on top of that. This has been the fastest and strongest jobs recovery in American history, and it would not have been possible without the decisive action my Administration took last year to fix a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we learned that our private sector has recovered all of the jobs lost during the pandemic, and added jobs on top of that. This has been the fastest and strongest jobs recovery in American history, and it would not have been possible without the decisive action my Administration took last year to fix a broken COVID response, and pass the American Rescue Plan to get our economy back on track.</p>



<p>In the second quarter of this year, we created more jobs than in any quarter under any of my predecessors in the nearly 40 years before the pandemic. We have more Americans working in the private sector today than any day during Donald Trump’s Presidency – more people than any time in our history.</p>



<p>The historic strength of our job market is one reason our economy is uniquely well positioned to tackle a range of global economic challenges – from global inflation to the economic fallout from Putin’s war. No country is better positioned than America to bring down inflation, without giving up all of the economic gains we have made over the last 18 months.</p>



<p>Of course, having added a record number of new jobs, and achieved historically low levels of unemployment, additional job growth from this strong position will be slower. That is not a bad thing, because our economy should move to stable growth for the years ahead.</p>



<p>The best way to achieve that goal is for Congress to pass legislation that lowers costs for families – from prescription drugs to utility costs – while reducing the federal budget deficit, in addition to passing the Bipartisan Innovation Act.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Killing of Former Japanese Prime Minister Abe&#160;Shinzo</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-killing-of-former-japanese-prime-minister-abe-shinzo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56949</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am stunned, outraged, and deeply saddened by the news that my friend Abe Shinzo, former Prime Minister of Japan, was shot and killed while campaigning. This is a tragedy for Japan and for all who knew him. I had the privilege to work closely with Prime Minister Abe. As Vice President, I visited him in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I am stunned, outraged, and deeply saddened by the news that my friend Abe Shinzo, former Prime Minister of Japan, was shot and killed while campaigning. This is a tragedy for Japan and for all who knew him. I had the privilege to work closely with Prime Minister Abe. As Vice President, I visited him in Tokyo and welcomed him to Washington. He was a champion of the Alliance between our nations and the friendship between our people. The longest serving Japanese Prime Minister, his vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific will endure. Above all, he cared deeply about the Japanese people and dedicated his life to their service. Even at the moment he was attacked, he was engaged in the work of democracy. While there are many details that we do not yet know, we know that violent attacks are never acceptable and that gun violence always leaves a deep scar on the communities that are affected by it. The United States stands with Japan in this moment of grief. I send my deepest condolences to his family. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Sign Executive Order Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care&#160;Services</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-sign-executive-order-protecting-access-to-reproductive-health-care-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two weeks ago, the Supreme Court issued a decision that overturned Roe v. Wade and eliminated a woman’s Constitutional right to choose.&#160; This decision expressly took away a right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to make her own reproductive health care decisions, free from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Two weeks ago, the Supreme Court issued a decision that overturned <em>Roe v. Wade </em>and eliminated a woman’s Constitutional right to choose.&nbsp; This decision expressly took away a right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to make her own reproductive health care decisions, free from government interference.&nbsp; Fundamental rights – to privacy, autonomy, freedom, and equality – have been denied to millions of women across the country, with grave implications for their health, lives, and wellbeing. This ruling will disproportionately affect women of color, low-income women, and rural women.<br><br>President Biden has made clear that the only way to secure a woman’s right to choose is for Congress to restore the protections of&nbsp;<em>Roe</em>&nbsp;as federal law. Until then, he has committed to doing everything in his power to defend reproductive rights and protect access to safe and legal abortion.<br><br>Today, President Biden will sign an Executive Order Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care Services. This Executive Order builds on the actions his Administration has already taken to defend reproductive rights by:</p>



<ul><li>Safeguarding access to reproductive health care services, including abortion and contraception;<br></li><li>Protecting the privacy of patients and their access to accurate information;<br></li><li>Promoting the safety and security of patients, providers, and clinics; and<br></li><li>Coordinating the implementation of Federal efforts to protect reproductive rights and access to health care.</li></ul>



<p><strong>SAFEGUARDING ACCESS TO REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH CARE SERVICES</strong><br><br>The President has directed the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to take the following actions and submit a report to him within 30 days on efforts to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect Access to Medication Abortion.</strong>&nbsp; HHS will take additional action to protect and expand access to abortion care, including access to medication that the FDA approved as safe and effective over twenty years ago. These actions will build on the steps the Secretary of HHS has already taken at the President’s direction following the decision to ensure that medication abortion is as widely accessible as possible.<br></li><li><strong>Ensure Emergency Medical Care.</strong>&nbsp; HHS will take steps to ensure all patients – including pregnant women and those experiencing pregnancy loss – have access to the full rights and protections for emergency medical care afforded under the law, including by considering updates to current guidance that clarify physician responsibilities and protections under the Emergency Medical Treatment and Labor Act (EMTALA).&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Protect Access to Contraception.</strong>&nbsp; HHS will take additional actions to expand access to the full range of reproductive health services, including family planning services and providers, such as access to emergency contraception and long-acting reversible contraception like intrauterine devices (IUDs). &nbsp;In all fifty states and the District of Columbia, the Affordable Care Act guarantees coverage of women’s preventive services, including free birth control and contraceptive counseling, for individuals and covered dependents. The Secretary of HHS has already directed the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to take every legally available step to ensure patient access to family planning care and to protect family planning providers.<br></li><li><strong>Launch Outreach and Public Education Efforts.&nbsp; </strong>HHS will increase outreach and public education efforts regarding access to reproductive health care services—including abortion—to ensure that Americans have access to reliable and accurate information about their rights and access to care.<br></li><li><strong>Convene Volunteer Lawyers.</strong>&nbsp; The Attorney General and the White House Counsel will convene private pro bono attorneys, bar associations, and public interest organizations to encourage robust legal representation of patients, providers, and third parties lawfully seeking or offering reproductive health care services throughout the country.&nbsp; Such representation could include protecting the right to travel out of state to seek medical care. Immediately following the Supreme Court decision, the President announced his Administration’s position that Americans must remain free to travel safely to another state to seek the care they need, as <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/attorney-general-merrick-b-garland-statement-supreme-court-ruling-dobbs-v-jackson-women-s">the Attorney General made clear in his statement</a>, and his commitment to fighting any attack by a state or local official who attempts to interfere with women exercising this right.</li></ul>



<p><strong>PROTECTING PATIENT PRIVACY AND ACCESS TO ACCURATE INFORMATION</strong><br><br>The President’s Executive Order takes additional steps to protect patient privacy, including by addressing the transfer and sales of sensitive health-related data, combatting digital surveillance related to reproductive health care services, and protecting people seeking reproductive health care from inaccurate information, fraudulent schemes, or deceptive practices.&nbsp; The Executive Order will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect Consumers from Privacy Violations and Fraudulent and Deceptive Practices.</strong>&nbsp; The President has asked the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission to consider taking steps to protect consumers’ privacy when seeking information about and provision of reproductive health care services.&nbsp; The President also has directed the Secretary of HHS, in consultation with the Attorney General and Chair of the FTC, to consider options to address deceptive or fraudulent practices, including online, and protect access to accurate information.</li><li><strong>Protect Sensitive Health Information.</strong>&nbsp; HHS will consider additional actions, including under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA), to better protect sensitive information related to reproductive health care. The Secretary of HHS has already directed the HHS Office for Civil Rights to take initial steps to ensure patient privacy and nondiscrimination of patients, as well as providers who provide reproductive health care, including by:<br><ul><li>Issuing <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/privacy/guidance/phi-reproductive-health/index.html">new guidance</a> to address how the HIPAA Privacy Rule protects the privacy of individuals’ protected health information, including information related to reproductive health care. The guidance helps ensure doctors and other medical providers and health plans know that, with limited exceptions, they are not required – and in many cases, are not permitted – to disclose patients’ private information, including to law enforcement.&nbsp;<br></li><li>Issuing <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/privacy/guidance/cell-phone-hipaa/index.html">a how-to guide</a> for consumers on steps they can take to make sure they’re protecting their personal data on mobile apps.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>PROMOTING SAFETY AND SECURITY</strong><br><br>The Executive Order addresses the heightened risk related to seeking and providing reproductive health care and will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect Patients, Providers, and Clinics.</strong>&nbsp; The Administration will ensure the safety of patients, providers, and third parties, and to protect the security of other entities that are providing, dispensing, or delivering reproductive health care services.&nbsp; This charge includes efforts to protect mobile clinics, which have been deployed to borders to offer care for out-of-state patients.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>COORDINATING IMPLEMENTATION EFFORTS</strong><br><br>To ensure the Federal government takes a swift and coordinated approach to addressing reproductive rights and protecting access to reproductive health care, the President’s Executive Order will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Establish an Interagency Task Force.</strong>&nbsp; The President has directed HHS and the White House Gender Policy Council to establish and lead an interagency Task Force on Reproductive Health Care Access, responsible for coordinating Federal interagency policymaking and program development.&nbsp; This Task Force will also include the Attorney General.&nbsp; In addition, the Attorney General will provide technical assistance to states affording legal protection to out-of-state patients as well as providers who offer legal reproductive health care.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>EXECUTIVE ORDER BUILDS ON ADMINISTRATION’S ACTIONS TO PROTECT ACCESS TO REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH CARE</strong><br><br>In addition to the actions announced today, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken the following steps to protect access to reproductive health care and defend reproductive rights in the wake of the Supreme Court decision in <em>Dobbs</em>.&nbsp; On the day of the decision, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-supreme-court-decision-to-overturn-roe-v-wade/">the President strongly denounced the decision</a> as an affront to women’s fundamental rights and the right to choose In addition to action mentioned above, the Biden-Harris Administration is:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting Providers and Clinics.&nbsp; </strong>The Secretary of HHS directed all HHS agencies to ensure that all HHS-funded providers and clinics have appropriate training and resources to handle family planning needs, and <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/06/30/hhs-announces-new-grants-to-bolster-family-planner-provider-training.html">announced nearly $3 million in new funding</a> to bolster training and technical assistance for the nationwide network of Title X family planning providers.<br></li><li><strong>Promoting Access to Accurate Information.</strong>&nbsp; On the day of the Supreme Court’s decision, HHS launched <a href="https://reproductiverights.gov/">ReproductiveRights.gov</a>, which provides timely and accurate information about reproductive rights and access to reproductive health care.&nbsp; This includes know-your-rights information for patients and providers and promoting awareness of and access to family planning services, as well as guidance for <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/ocr/complaints/index.html">how to file a patient privacy or nondiscrimination complaint</a> with its Office for Civil Rights.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Providing Leave</strong><strong> for Federal Workers Traveling for Medical Care.&nbsp; </strong>The Office of Personnel Management <a href="https://www.opm.gov/policy-data-oversight/pay-leave/leave-administration/fact-sheets/sick-leave-faqs.pdf">issued guidance</a> affirming that paid sick leave can be taken to cover absences for travel to obtain reproductive health care.<br></li><li><strong>Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care Services for Service members, DoD Civilians, and Military Families.</strong>&nbsp; The Department of Defense (DoD) issued a memo to the Force, DoD civilians and military families on ensuring access to essential women’s health care services. The memo reiterates that the Department will continue to provide seamless access to reproductive healthcare for military and civilian patients, as permitted by federal law.&nbsp; Military providers will continue to fulfill their duty to care for Service members, military dependents and civilian personnel who require pregnancy termination in the cases of rape, incest, or to protect the life of the mother.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>For up-to-date information on your right to access reproductive health care, visit </em><a href="http://www.reproductiverights.gov"><em>www.reproductiverights.gov<br><br></em></a>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/07/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3:41 P.M.&#160;EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &#160;Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; I&#8217;m sorry it took me a couple more &#8212; less [more] than a two-minute warning; more like a five-minute warning.&#160; You guys would appreciate it: I bumped into Simone Biles and I thought I&#8217;d say hello to her.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I think you guys would have done the same.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>3:41 P.M.&nbsp;EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &nbsp;Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry it took me a couple more &#8212; <s>less</s> [more] than a two-minute warning; more like a five-minute warning.&nbsp; You guys would appreciate it: I bumped into Simone Biles and I thought I&#8217;d say hello to her.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I think you guys would have done the same.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can she come out here?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; She&#8217;s &#8212; I believe she&#8217;s on the White House North Lawn doing some interviews.&nbsp;<br><br>Anyway, good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; It’s good to see everyone.&nbsp; Happy Thursday.&nbsp; Okay, I &#8212; I do have a couple of things that I want to share with all of you.<br><br>So this week has been marked by honoring service to our nation through Presidential Medals of Honor and Freedom.&nbsp; And I think some of you may have been in the room on Tuesday and today.&nbsp; I don’t think there was a dry eye in the room.&nbsp; It was just such a beautiful, impactful, powerful moment.&nbsp;<br><br>But on Tuesday &#8212; just to recap just a little bit: On Tuesday, the President bestowed our nation’s highest military honor to four Vietnam veterans &#8212; recognition that was very, very long overdue.<br><br>And today, as we all just saw &#8212; some of you may have &#8212; may have been in the room &#8212; we saw 17 individuals spanning different backgrounds, careers, contributions to the United States receive the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the highest &#8212; the nation’s highest civilian honor.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden has long said that America can be defined by one word, and that is “possibilities.”&nbsp; These Americans demonstrate the power of possibilities and embody the soul of the nation: hard work, perseverance, and faith. <br><br>Today, the Department of Transportation announced nearly $1 billion in funding from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to 85 airports across the United States to modernize their terminals.<br><br>For example, in Orlando, we’re &#8212; we are investing $50 million to construct four new gates, increasing capacity and providing ADA-compliant facilities.&nbsp;<br><br>At Pittsburgh International Airport, we’re investing $20 million in building a new terminal, which will include improved security screening and baggage inspection systems.&nbsp;<br><br>And when all is said and done, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will pour $5 billion into similar terminal projects and $25 billion total to airport-related infrastructure across the country.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So investing in terminals is not something the federal government typically takes on; usually it’s local airports and owners and airlines who tend to do that.&nbsp; But thanks to the President’s Infrastructure Law, we are able to step up and make these kinds of investments that will benefit traveling Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>Finally &#8212; lastly, Senator Mitch McConnell is holding hostage the bipartisan package &#8212; a bipartisan package &#8212; the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which would make more in America and strengthen our competitive edge with China.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s doing all &#8212; all of this &#8212; he&#8217;s putting this in hostage, this bipartisan law, to protect the Big Pharma’s profit.&nbsp;<br><br>It is outrageous.&nbsp; And here’s the thing: We must do both and we can do both.&nbsp;<br><br>I remind &#8212; I remind you and all others that &#8212; when Leader Mitch McConnell himself agreed last fall that bipartisan negotiations shouldn’t be paused for other priorities, saying, and I quote, “Republicans have been negotiating in bipartisan good faith to meet the real infrastructure needs of our nation.&nbsp; The President cannot let congressional Democrats hold a bipartisan bill hostage over a separate and partisan process.”<br><br>I want to be clear here, though: Negotians [sic] have been &#8212; negotians [sic] have been productive, and in recent weeks, negotiators made progress in key issues of the Bipartisan Innovation Act.&nbsp;<br><br>So we are ready to finish up this process, negoti- &#8212; of negotiating and pass this bill.&nbsp; It&#8217;s now or never to do this.&nbsp; Other countries aren&#8217;t waiting.&nbsp; They are offering tax incentives for companies to invest in new manufacturing lines.&nbsp; Companies are currently making their investment decision.&nbsp;<br><br>And here&#8217;s the bottom line: We got to get this done.&nbsp; We can do both.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I say to Mitch McConnell: Let&#8217;s get this done.&nbsp;<br><br>All right, with that, Aamer, what&#8217;s your question &#8212; your first question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; With Prime Minister Johnson&#8217;s resignation today &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t like to get into other country&#8217;s politics, but more substantively, what does this mean going forward?&nbsp; Big ally.&nbsp; You basically have a caretaker, lame-duck Prime Minister now.&nbsp; But this is a very difficult time in Europe, obviously.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s efforts to keep Europe paddling or rowing the same way on Ukraine is top of mind now.&nbsp; Is there any concern that this becomes a little bit more difficult when you have a big partner like Prime Minister Johnson in the position he&#8217;s in?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: Our alliance with the United Kingdom continues to be strong.&nbsp; Our special relationship with the people in the country will continue to endure.&nbsp; None of that changes.&nbsp;<br><br>And I will mi- &#8212; I will remind you: A week ago &#8212; just a week ago today, when the President was in NATO &#8212; in Madrid for a historic NATO Summit, as you heard him speak at the press conference and you saw what happened, you saw a reassurance, a reaffirmation of NATO countries saying, again, what they are going to continue to do: continue to support Ukraine in their effort to defend their democracy against Putin’s brutal war.</p>



<p>And so that is not going to change.&nbsp; And not only that, you saw an &#8212; a potential expanding of NATO, with two additional countries, which is incredibly important &#8212; something that the President has worked very hard on these last several months, who has also led on this effort.</p>



<p>You saw other alliances make a commitment to increase their security assistance.&nbsp; And so, all of that &#8212; what you’re seeing currently today, because of the leadership of this President, is a more &#8212; a more unified NATO.&nbsp; And I don’t think that changes at &#8212; at all.</p>



<p>And you saw him at the G7, in Germany, where you saw him with the &#8212; you know, the G7 leaders &#8212; the same.&nbsp; You saw a &#8212; a committed &#8212; a committed alliance amongst &#8212; amongst friends, amongst other countries on everything that they’re going to work on together to push American’s intr- &#8212; America’s interest, and also what &#8212; the interest of other countries as we look at the global challenges ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Just one more on &#8212; now that Brittney Griner has pleaded guilty, what is the next steps that the administration is contemplating?&nbsp; Does the President support Bill Richardson going over to Moscow to try to fashion her release?</p>



<p>And would the &#8212; would the administration entertain a trade of Russian detainees in American custody for Mrs. Griner, particularly the arms dealer, Viktor Bout?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just to be clear &#8212; so I&#8217;ve said this before, but I want to state it again: We believe that the Russian Federation is holding &#8212; is wrongfully detai- &#8212; has wrongfully detained Brittney Griner.&nbsp; And she is in intolerable circumstances right now.&nbsp; And we are going to do everything that we can.</p>



<p>The President has this top of mind to make sure that we get Brittney home safely and also Paul Whelan.&nbsp; That is an important &#8212; important priority of the President.</p>



<p>And he &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve been clear from day one: When it comes to U.S. nationals who are being held abroad, who are being held wrongfully &#8212; detained wrongfully, who are being held hostage, we are going to do everything that we can, use every means that we have to bring them home.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to lay out exactly the steps that we&#8217;re going to take, as you can imagine why.&nbsp; We want to make sure that we do this safely.</p>



<p>As you know, the President wrote a letter to Brittney Griner.&nbsp; He spoke to her wife yesterday.&nbsp; And so, Secretary Blinken &#8212; just on the letter, because I know people were asking me; I think people saw this already &#8212; the letter was delivered to her.&nbsp; He tweeted: U.S. Embassy in Moscow “officials again attended Brittney Griner’s trial today and delivered to her a letter from President Biden.&nbsp; We will not relent until Brittney, Paul Whelan, and all &#8212; and all other wrongfully detained Americans are reunited with their loved ones.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is the focus of the Secretary of State, that&#8217;s the focus of the pres- &#8212; national &#8212; national security team, and his focus as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a follow on that, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I didn’t &#8212; oh, it was April?&nbsp; I’ll come back to you, April.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that note, Paul Whelan&#8217;s family says that they have not heard directly from President Biden.&nbsp; Does the President have plans to call the Whelan family as well?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have a call right now to announce or to preview for you today.</p>



<p>Look, we can&#8217;t even begin to imagine what his family is going through.&nbsp; I know these are devastating times for them, and they have been &#8212; they have been working very hard to get their &#8212; their brother home.&nbsp; This is &#8212; I&#8217;m talking about Elizabeth Whelan and her brother &#8212; and his brother, David Whelan.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll list out a couple of things that we have done as far as communicating with the family, which I think is very important to share.</p>



<p>So, yesterday, White House staff joined the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs on a call with Elizabeth Whelan.&nbsp; And Secretary Blinken and National Security Advisor Sullivan have also called her to offer support and reaffirm the President&#8217;s commitment to bringing Paul home.</p>



<p>The SPEHA office has a biweekly phone call with &#8212; with Elizabeth Whelan to provide updates and pass information on pro- &#8212; on progress in securing Paul&#8217;s release and to secure he is well supported while he remains in prison.</p>



<p>Department of State representatives in D.C. and at Embassy Moscow have regular phone calls with Paul Whelan.&nbsp; Consular officials last visited him on June 17th, so just a few weeks ago, and they hold regular calls with the Whelan family on the case to address any concerns that the family or Paul have raised regarding his treatment.</p>



<p>Again, this is some &#8212; this is a situation &#8212; these cases &#8212; the President is getting regularly updated.&nbsp; This is at top of mind.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a call to preview for you, but we have been in regular contact with his family.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just quickly: Griner’s guilty plea &#8212; what kind of impact does this have on the negotiations to try to bring her home?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It will have no impact on &#8212; on any of the negotiations.&nbsp; The President, the national security team, the State Department, the Special Envoy that I just spoke about &#8212; we&#8217;re going to do everything that we can to bring home Brittney Griner safely and to also make sure that we bring Paul Whelan back home as well.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Can you share any more about what the President conveyed in his letter to Brittney Griner?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the President, as you know, was deeply moved, as you can imagine &#8212; I know some of you read her letter as well &#8212; was deeply moved by &#8212; by her handwritten note.&nbsp; He wanted her to know and to reassure her that we are doing &#8212; that he is doing everything that he can to bring her home.</p>



<p>You know, in her letter, she talked about what July 4th meant &#8212; means for her this year and what freedom means for her this year, and that is touching.</p>



<p>And so, again, we are going to do &#8212; he is going to do everything that he can to make sure she gets home safely.&nbsp; This is top of mind.&nbsp;<br><br>And he had a &#8212; you know, a very &#8212; I would say, a very deep &#8212; and he sees it as an important conversation with &#8212; with her wife, as well, yesterday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just to follow up on some of the reaction from Paul Whelan&#8217;s family.&nbsp; Some of the members of his family are asking sort of what does it take for their family to get a call with the President.&nbsp; You saw Trevor Reed’s family protest outside of the White House.&nbsp; They had a meeting with the President.&nbsp; We saw the family of Brittney Griner criticize the Biden administration, saying that they may not be doing enough when it comes to her case, and then get a phone call with the President.&nbsp; How can this administration assure the Whelan family that their pleas are being heard and taken seriously?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean &#8212; so, look, I just laid out all of the things, all of the &#8212; kind of all of the conversations that we have been having for &#8212; with the Whelan family.<br><br>Look, again, we cannot &#8212; I cannot imagine what they&#8217;re going through right now.&nbsp; We understand this is a very tough moment in time, and it has been, especially for him, for these past several years.<br><br>But we want to assure them &#8212; the Whelans and the Griner family and all other U.S. nationals’ families who are &#8212; U.S. nationals who are being detained, wrongfully detained, or held hostage abroad &#8212; that this President is doing everything that he can to make sure that they come home safely.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to use any &#8212; every means that we have.&nbsp; Clearly, we cannot negotiate in public.&nbsp; That is not something that we&#8217;re going to do.&nbsp; But we are committed to making sure they all get home safely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just a quick follow-up on Boris Johnson.&nbsp; Has the President had a chance to speak to him since he announced his decision?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a call to read out for you.&nbsp; As I mentioned just moments ago, he saw Boris Johnson in Madrid, at NATO, most recently and also at the G7 in Germany.&nbsp; And I think you guys were all there.&nbsp; They had a pretty friendly and close interaction.&nbsp; And they have, you know, reaffirmed their commitment to, you know, agenda that matters to both &#8212; to both the United Kingdom and to the United States.&nbsp; And we believe our alliance with the United Kingdom will continue to be strong.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he plan to speak to him, Karine?&nbsp; Before he leaves &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick question on Roe.&nbsp; We did see the President meet a bunch of governors earlier this week.&nbsp; And if you can talk a little bit about sort of the events, including meetings or speeches, that the President is planning, you know, to give or attend or be a part of in the coming days that involve him talking about reproductive rights.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this: The President is not done speaking on how he&#8217;s going to continue to fight for women&#8217;s freedoms and women&#8217;s rights, especially after this extreme decision that we saw come down on Roe by the Supreme Court.&nbsp; He is committed to this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of this President.&nbsp;<br><br>I could assure you, you will hear more from him.&nbsp; I’m just not going to give a timeline from here.<br><br>But look, here&#8217;s the thing: The President has been very clear he&#8217;s going to do everything that he can, that he has the legal authority to do from here in the &#8212; from the executive side.&nbsp; But we believe and he believes that the way that Roe goes into law or gets codi- &#8212; codified is if Congress acts.&nbsp; Right? We have to make sure that we get Congress to act.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to call on that to make sure that that happens.<br><br>And, you know, this is &#8212; this is such a critical time, as we see Republicans trying to take away those rights, as we see Republicans talking about a national ban.&nbsp; This is &#8212; this is what&#8217;s happening on the other side.&nbsp; And so, we have to continue to use our political capital, if you will, to fight as hard as we can and to make sure we do the work that we need to have pro-choice congressional members in Congress.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So on that point, Karine, we understand the White House was working on an executive order.&nbsp; Is that still happening?&nbsp; Is the White House continuing to work on an executive order, or has the White House dropped that plan?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;ll say this: The President is going to do everything in his legal authority to continue to fight for freedom and for &#8212; for rights &#8212; women&#8217;s rights, in particular, as we&#8217;re speaking about Roe.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of him.&nbsp; But I assure you, you will hear from him in a short order.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we could expect an executive order?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; In a short order.&nbsp; He will &#8212; he will speak to this himself.&nbsp; I’m not going to get ahead of the President.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; To what extent has Brittney Griner’s public profile and kind of the posture and push around her shifted the administration’s strategy as it pertains to her case specifically?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I will say this, Phil: We&#8217;ve been working on this for months.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been working with her and &#8212; and having conversations with her family and the people who love her for some time.&nbsp;<br><br>Secretary Blinken &#8212; I have mentioned his regular contact with the family and friends.&nbsp; National Security Advisor Sullivan most recently spoke to &#8212; to the family twice in the past, I would say, 10 days.&nbsp; This has been top of mind for the national security team, for the State Department.<br><br>And again, not just &#8212; not just Brittney Griner &#8212; which is top of mind for him; clearly, he just wrote her a letter and spoke to <s>his</s> [her] wife yesterday &#8212; but for all U.S. nationals that are being held abroad, detained &#8212; wrongfully detained and held hostage.&nbsp;<br><br>This is something that this administration has been working on since last year to make sure that we do everything that we can to bring &#8212; to bring folks home.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On a different topic.&nbsp; Oil prices have dropped pretty significantly.&nbsp; At the pump, they’ve started to fall as well.&nbsp; Do you believe that the drop is durable?&nbsp; Do you believe that this is sustainable, that we have turned a corner?&nbsp; Or should Americans expect that it might pop back up again?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, what we believe is the lower &#8212; the lower gas prices that we&#8217;re seeing, the prices starting to come down is a good thing.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; It&#8217;s a cooldown, if you will.<br><br>But we believe that more work still remains and that we need to do more work.&nbsp; The President believes that.&nbsp; Part of that is retailers need to pass on their lower cost to consumers.&nbsp; Wholesale gas prices are down by $1 per gallon.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard me talk about this over the past month. But retail gas prices have only come down by about 20 cents over the same period.&nbsp; So, more work needs to be done.<br><br>You know, you &#8212; I&#8217;ve heard this phrase, “Don&#8217;t &#8212; we can&#8217;t sit on our laurels,” if you will.&nbsp; We got to continue to do the work.&nbsp;<br><br>And one of the things that the President will continue to call on is this gas holiday tax &#8212; this 90-day suspension of &#8212; on the federal gas tax, which we think is an easy thing to do.&nbsp; There are pieces of legislation right now in the House, in Congress, that can be easily picked up and passed.&nbsp;<br><br>And so that&#8217;s what the President is calling &#8212; calling for Congress to do.&nbsp; We think it will have an important effect on American families and give them that little bit of breathing room that you hear the President talk about.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more quick one.&nbsp; Does the President &#8212; there seems to be a view on Capitol Hill that August is the deadline for the reconciliation package.&nbsp; Does the President view the month of July as the be-all, end-all as it pertains to that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, I&#8217;m not going to go into negotiations or negotiate from public, as you hear us say often.&nbsp; What I will say is that independent economists have shown that this would fight inflation as we&#8217;re talking about high gas prices, as we&#8217;re talking about inflation for the long haul, and protect Americans’ finances in the short term.<br><br>So, we think this is something that is going to help Americans, American families, and we&#8217;re going to continue to have the negotiations.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to have the conversations to make sure we deliver for the American public.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So no deadline from here?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here.&nbsp; I’m not going to give a deadline from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Mike.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I could ask about two administration officials.&nbsp; First of all, given the revelations that my colleagues wrote about regarding the actions of the IRS over the last several years, does the President retain the confidence &#8212; does the &#8212; does the IRS Commissioner have the President&#8217;s confidence?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: We don&#8217;t comment on enforcement actions taken by the IRS.&nbsp; So just the first thing &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; I &#8212; no, I know.&nbsp; I’m &#8212; I just want to &#8212; since you gave me the opportunity, Michael, I want to take it.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So any &#8212; any questions on that I would refer &#8212; refer you to the IRS.&nbsp; That&#8217;s for anyone who has any questions on that.<br><br>As you know, the IRS Commissioner &#8212; his term is up in November.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any updates on that.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to anything more besides, you know, we would refer you to the IRS on that specific thing.&nbsp;<br><br>And he is going to be up in November.&nbsp; So I will leave it there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; but, between now and November, the President still is confident that he&#8217;s able to fairly and, you know, without bias, you know, do the things that a &#8212; that the IRS does objectively?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, again, I&#8217;m going to say that he is up in November.&nbsp; He is a commissioner.&nbsp; He does &#8212; he is the Commissioner of the IRS, part of the administration.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to leave it at that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then on the Director of the Secret Service who just announced resignation today &#8212; obviously, the Secret Service has been in the news of late, given the &#8212; some of the testimony in front of the January 6th Committee as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do &#8212; is there any relationship between the Director’s departure now and the timing of some of those revelations from the committee?&nbsp; Did the White House know about his intention to retire before &#8212; before the &#8212; that testimony last week, I guess?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, Michael, I would say that there&#8217;s no relations at all.&nbsp; This has been in talks for several months &#8212; I &#8212; for his &#8212; his retirement &#8212; I believe, since April &#8212; so before the January 6th hearing.&nbsp;<br><br>And for &#8212; as I &#8212; as I know, he is headed to the private sector.&nbsp; So it is not connected at all.&nbsp; This has been in talks for some time now &#8212; his &#8212; his retirement.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Actually, I&#8217;m going to go &#8212; I know, April, I said I was going to come to you on, I think, Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Was that your &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and on something else.&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Brittney Griner: I talked to Cherelle Griner last night.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And now this morning&#8217;s decision.&nbsp; And we understand that, according to sources close the case, it was Brittney’s decision and it was an informed decision that was discussed over several weeks to make this decision to plead guilty.&nbsp; Was the White House ever in any understanding that this was going to be the case this morning?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on &#8212; I cannot speak about her case in public.&nbsp; I cannot speak about the process of her decision.&nbsp; That is something that she should speak to, which sounds like she has spoken to you about that.&nbsp;<br><br>But we from &#8212; from &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, (inaudible) with the case.&nbsp; But she talked about &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, got it.&nbsp; Un- &#8212; understood.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; not wanting to watch this morning.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Understood.&nbsp; But we cannot do that from here.&nbsp; It is &#8212; it is a personal matter.&nbsp; It is a &#8212; it is a legal matter that we cannot speak to from &#8212; from here, or the podium.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say that &#8212; I think I was just asked about if this verdict &#8212; her verdict will change anything that we&#8217;re doing: It will not.&nbsp;<br><br>We will continue to make this a top priority, in making sure that we bring her home safely.&nbsp; That is a commitment that we have made to her, to her family, and also to other U.S. nationals as we&#8217;re trying to bring them back home.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the hope that this guilty plea will be viewed favorably by the Russians to help her come home sooner or her sentencing be less?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, April, I appreciate the question.&nbsp; I cannot &#8212; that was a legal advice, clearly, that Brittney received from her &#8212; from her lawyers.&nbsp; I cannot speak to why the decision was made.&nbsp; I cannot speak to the minds of the Russian Federation.&nbsp;<br><br>I &#8212; that is not for me to do.&nbsp; What I can say is what we&#8217;re going to do here &#8212; here.&nbsp; And what the President wants to do is making sure that we bring home these U.S. nationals who are wrongfully being held abroad and also held hostage.&nbsp; It is important that we get them home safely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mrs. Griner says she wants to come for a face to face that the President offered.&nbsp; Any dates yet?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And two other questions on two other subjects really fast.&nbsp; As you talked about and as we&#8217;re still reeling and trying to figure out still what happens after Roe v. Wade in the states, et cetera &#8212; after the overturn of Roe v. Wade: In October, a case is supposed to be before the Supreme Court on affirmative action when it comes to education admittance &#8212; admittance on race.&nbsp; And there is a thought that it could be overturned with the way this Court has been overturning longstanding action cases.</p>



<p>What is the White House&#8217;s thought on this?&nbsp; And is there a plan?&nbsp; Are you preparing for this, as many law organizations are preparing amicus briefs, friend of court briefs in favor of keeping these admittance &#8212; racial admittance procedures?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, April, the President has been very clear about these extreme decisions that the Supreme Court has been making &#8212; not just on Roe, but EPA and other decisions that have come down most recently.&nbsp; This is another one that you&#8217;re talking about, in October.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, the President has been also clear &#8212; is that we have to take action.&nbsp; We &#8212; that, you know, Americans have to make sure that they take their voices to the ballot box.&nbsp; That is the way that we are going to be able to &#8212; to fight back in a way that&#8217;s effective, in a way that&#8217;s going to make a difference.<br><br>We have Republicans who are doing extremes.&nbsp; The President calls them “Ultra-MAGA.”&nbsp; They are a part of the Ultra-MAGA wing who are trying to take away the rights of the American people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what they&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we have to do everything that we can.&nbsp; American public has to do everything that they can to make sure that their voices are heard at the ballot box.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the President is going to continue to speak to, and that&#8217;s what the President is asking for people to do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question, on the Secret Service Director.&nbsp; Is equity and inclusion still a part of the President&#8217;s hiring practices when he looks at that spot?&nbsp; Because you have never had a Black man or someone of another color, I guess, be the head of that organization.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the &#8212; of the process.&nbsp; But as you know, this is a President that prides on making sure that we have equity, that we have inclusion.&nbsp; You see that up and down his administration.&nbsp; He wants to make sure that we have an administration that looks like America.&nbsp; And so that is a priority for him.&nbsp;<br><br>I cannot speak to that particular vacancy &#8212; potential vacancy.&nbsp; That is something that &#8212; a decision has not been made, and so I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Tam.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; Back when the President did sort of the small signing ceremony for the gun legislation, he said that he was going to do a bigger ceremony later.&nbsp; Is that still in the books?&nbsp; And can you give any sort of a preview of his message?&nbsp; A lot has happened since he signed that bill, and outside advocates are pushing him to go even further.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And he wants to go further.&nbsp; I mean, he has said that.&nbsp; He has been very clear on saying that as much as he welcomed the bipartisan gun reform legislation that he signed into law right before he left for Europe, he had said we need to do more.&nbsp; He has been very clear on that.&nbsp;<br><br>You got to remember, this is a President that led on the effort of making sure &#8212; on banning assault weapons back in 1994, which sunset 10 years later.&nbsp; That &#8212; it was a priority for him then, and it continues to be a priority for him now.<br><br>If you think about what we have seen over the last several weeks &#8212; you think about Buffalo, you think about Uvalde, you think about Highland Park &#8212; you think about the same story that they have over and over again, which is a weapon of war being unleashed on our &#8212; in our communities.&nbsp;<br><br>And how &#8212; and it&#8217;s not just those communities.&nbsp; You think about Parkland, you think about Orlando, Las Vegas, Sandy Hook.&nbsp; It&#8217;s assault rifles.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, you &#8212; it has &#8212; it &#8212; and you think about what it&#8217;s done to families and communities.&nbsp; These are assault rifles that, you know &#8212; that bodies are too mutilated for families to even recognize, that they have to do a DNA test.<br><br>That should not be happening in our streets.&nbsp; It should not be happening in our streets.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the President believes that we need to ban assault weapons.&nbsp; This is something that he has talked about, again, for years.&nbsp; It is something that he wants to see happen.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to continue to call on.&nbsp;<br><br>On your first question on if we&#8217;re going to have an event: Yes, we will have an event.&nbsp; You will hear from us soon on when that will be.&nbsp; But, yes, he is &#8212; that is going to happen at some point.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yesterday, he &#8212; in his remarks in Ohio, it sounded like a midterm message.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, just a little bit.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It was fun.&nbsp; It was fun.&nbsp; It was great.&nbsp; It was great to see.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are we going to see more of that?&nbsp; What is your sense of how much travel will be ramping up for the President, if at all?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; yeah, we don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this &#8212; at this time.&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, you know, this is something that the President &#8212; you&#8217;ve heard him say this himself: He wants to get out there.&nbsp; He &#8212; you know, you see him out there with &#8212; with the American people, and it is a lively time.&nbsp; It is a &#8212; it is definitely an exciting time to see him, and they get excited.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s able to push his message or talk about his message, his platform directly to the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you think about &#8212; yesterday, it was about pensions; it was about union pensions.&nbsp; It’s about how we&#8217;re &#8212; what &#8212; the work that the American Rescue Plan has done to make sure that we protect those pensions.&nbsp; And so that is such an important message for the American people to hear.&nbsp; And not just in Ohio, in many other country &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, and many other states across the country is going to be affected by the American Rescue Plan as well when it relates to union pensions and other items as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Since you started the briefing talking about McConnell holding the Bipartisan Infrastructure &#8212; sorry &#8212; Innovation Act hostage, has the President reached out directly to any Senate Republicans to convince them and make the case for why they should support this bill?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; we don&#8217;t have any calls to read out.&nbsp; As you know, his Office of Leg Affairs is in constant communication, and not just his Office of Leg Affairs; we have other departments, offices in the White House that are constantly talking to congressional leaders and staff on issues that &#8212; on these types of legislations that we believe are important to the American public.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to read out.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I figured you would say that, but what is the path forward if you know that there is Republicans that support this bill but you need to get 10 of them to go ahead with you over the objections of McConnell?&nbsp; Like, what are you doing?&nbsp; And are you confident that there are actually 10 who would do that?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, we have seen and I said at top: We have seen progress.&nbsp; We wanted to make that clear, even though you heard me call out Mitch McConnell.&nbsp; We have seen some progress.&nbsp; What I was calling out is the hypocrisy that we have seen from Leader &#8212; from Leader McConnell on this.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, you know, the President and bipartisan members of Congress, you know, they &#8212; who share &#8212; who share the same goal, and we understand that.&nbsp; It is to reach a final agreement that meets our economic and national security objectives.&nbsp; And we want to do this by this summer.&nbsp; We feel confident in that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to work to make that happen.&nbsp;<br><br>We know companies are making decisions now on where to invest this year.&nbsp; So the time is now to act.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I said if it doesn&#8217;t happen now, it won&#8217;t.&nbsp; So we are going to do everything we can to make sure that we make this happen.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one follow-up to Michael&#8217;s question on the IRS commissioner.&nbsp; You noted that his term is up in November.&nbsp; Are you insinuating that you won&#8217;t renominate him?&nbsp; And if so, why not fire him now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; That is a decision for the President to make, and I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of that decision.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Peter.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Why do you think it is the 88 percent of people in this country polled by Monmouth think the country is on the wrong track?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: The President understands what the American people are going through.&nbsp; He understands that gas prices are high because of Putin’s tax hike, because of the war that Putin &#8212; the brutal war that Putin has taken on in Ukraine, and their brave fight to fight for their democracy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing here.&nbsp; And also the food insecurity &#8212; the food cost has skyrocketed.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s why the President has done everything that he can to blunt those high prices.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he&#8217;s tapped into the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; We saw a historic amount of barrels coming out a day &#8212; 1 million a day.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why he is doing the bio- &#8212; the home- &#8212; homegrown biofuels &#8212; the ethanol 15 &#8212; making that available this summer, which is not normally available this summer, so that we can try and bring down those costs.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why he&#8217;s going to continue to work to make sure we lower those costs.&nbsp;<br><br>Look &#8212; but, again, we understand what the American people are feeling.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing everything that we can.&nbsp; We have a plan.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s the thing: We have a plan.&nbsp; Republicans do not have a plan.&nbsp; What they want to do is take away rights from the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But do you think it&#8217;s possible that your plan just is not popular with the American people right now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s that our plan is not popular with the American people.&nbsp; We know that the American people are feeling the high costs.&nbsp; We understand what they are feeling.&nbsp; Because &#8212; because when you look at inflation; when we look at where we are economically &#8212; and we are in a strong &#8212; we are stronger economically than we have been in history; when you look at the unemployment numbers of 3.6 percent; when you look at the jobs numbers &#8212; more than 8.7 million of new jobs created &#8212; that is important.&nbsp;<br><br>But we understand that gas prices are high, and we understand that food costs are high.&nbsp; And that is because of a once &#8212; once-in-a-generation pandemic and also Putin&#8217;s war.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s just the facts.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So if you think that the &#8212; your plan is popular with the American people, is it just that the plans are not being communicated properly, and is that why the Communications Director is leaving?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, that&#8217;s where you were going with this question.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Oh, that&#8217;s very slick there of you, Peter.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, why is she really leaving?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean &#8212; well, she said why she is leaving.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, let me just say something.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, but &#8212; is it &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Wait.&nbsp; Wait.&nbsp; No, no, no, no.&nbsp; You&#8217;re asking me &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is it a coincidence that at a time that a historic number of people think the country is on the wrong track, somebody who has been a part of Biden world for as long as just about anybody here says that she is leaving?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, first, let me just say I explained that we understand what the American public is feeling.&nbsp; The President is doing everything in his power to lower costs, to blunt gas prices, as he has been doing.&nbsp;<br><br>And we have &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Then why make a change?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; we have done that.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I just want to speak about Kate for a second because I think this is really important.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve known Kate since 2007.&nbsp; She is a friend and she is a colleague.&nbsp; She is exceptionally talented, and she will be greatly missed.<br><br>Her smart skills and hard work helped get the President elected and has helped us accomplish so much since we&#8217;ve been here.&nbsp;<br><br>And like I said, on a personal note, she&#8217;s a good friend and a colleague, and we&#8217;re going to miss her.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, you&#8217;re asking me &#8212; basically, you&#8217;re asking me her leaving and what does that mean &#8212; right? &#8212; to the administration?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I don&#8217;t think her leaving will have&nbsp;&nbsp; effect on what we&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp; Because, look, she leaves behind a talented team and communications department, and the President will name a new communications director.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing new here.&nbsp; These things happen.&nbsp;<br><br>And I do want to call out a data by Brookings showing that turnover in this administration is below the historical average, going back to Reagan.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what we&#8217;re seeing here is not unusual.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re seeing here is &#8212; is normal.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re going to continue to do is we&#8217;re going to communicate with the American people in a truthful way, and we&#8217;re going to do that every day.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just a different topic.&nbsp; The largest labor union in the country, the National Education Association, had been proposing a resolution for future contracts to replace the word “mother” with “birthing parent.”&nbsp; What does the President think about proposals like that one?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re not the NEA.&nbsp; And I would refer you to their team about that particular sp- &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Vice President just spoke at that conference, though.&nbsp; The First Lady is a teacher.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President says he&#8217;s the most pro-labor &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; She&#8217;s a member of &#8212; she’s &#8212; she’s &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; President ever.&nbsp; Does he &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; support proposals like that one?&nbsp; Does he think that is a &#8212; an important priority for &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And the First Lady is a proud member of the NEA.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak about a &#8212; an organization&#8217;s policy or change of policy.&nbsp; I am not their spokesperson.&nbsp; That’s not something that I&#8217;m going to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Yes, the Vice President was there on Tuesday.&nbsp; She spoke at NEA.&nbsp; And when they did &#8212; when they did regular order &#8212; when they did their regular business, she left.&nbsp; So she was also not part of that discussion.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, this is a policy change.&nbsp; That is not something that I can speak to.&nbsp; I refer you to NEA.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So I have a question on the federal district judge appointment in Kentucky.&nbsp; So, earlier today, Governor Andy Beshear said that it&#8217;s been plenty of time for the administration to tell his office whether, you know, the White House is rescinding the appointment of Chad Meredith.&nbsp; I guess, what&#8217;s your reaction to that?&nbsp; And why haven&#8217;t you rescinded that appointment yet?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You &#8212; I believe your colleague asked me this question last week, or &#8212; gosh, not even last week; a couple days ago.&nbsp; Every &#8212; every day feels like long days.&nbsp;<br><br>But look &#8212; and I said this on Tuesday, and I&#8217;ll said this &#8212; I&#8217;ll say this to you, which is, like, we do not comment on vacancies.&nbsp; This is a vacancy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not something that we&#8217;re going to comment on.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t comment on executive branch or judicial vacancy.&nbsp;<br><br>We have not made a nomination yet.&nbsp; And so, one of the things that we are very proud of, which you hear us talk about, is like &#8212; is that we have more federal judges &#8212; we have done more federal judges during this administration than any of the last three presidency.<br><br>It includes making sure that we do history-making first to help our judiciary represent the diversity of America, and we&#8217;re going to continue to do that.<br><br>I’m &#8212; I just &#8212; is not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to speak to an open vacancy.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The Veterans Affairs currently doesn&#8217;t offer any abortion services in any exceptions.&nbsp; But VA Secretary McDonough has told Congress &#8212; he told them in April that the VA has statutory authority to provide abortion services, that the law permits it.&nbsp; So does the President agree with the VA Secretary that the department can take this action?<br><br>MR. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the administration and the VA are committed to providing healthcare to veterans, and the VA continues to offer reproductive healthcare services to their veterans as well.<br><br>As you note, current regulation doesn&#8217;t allow for the VA to provide abortions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to review, we&#8217;re going to continue to explore every possible option to protect women&#8217;s rights and access to reproductive health.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, we&#8217;re going to continue to review.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given that &#8212; that it’s based on regulation, though, I mean, is the President considering at all any kind of executive action to direct the VA, given that its regulation (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have anything specifically on the VA.&nbsp; We have talked about the President reviewing executive actio- &#8212; actions.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of what those actions are going to be.<br><br>But like I said, you know, we&#8217;re going to continue to review and look at our options here.&nbsp; And, you know, the President is going to continue &#8212; he did use his executive authority when the decision came down, within hours of the decision that came down &#8212; the Roe being striked down.&nbsp;<br><br>And so those authorities we believed were &#8212; were impactful for the moment, when you’re talking about providing safe medication, FDA-approved medication so women can make decisions on their healthcare &#8212; medication, which is what majority of women use when they are looking to make that decision on an abortion, which is a very personal decision.&nbsp; And also, women who have to travel as well, making sure that DOJ protect their rights.&nbsp;<br><br>And we think that those are incredibly impactful, incredibly important.&nbsp; And like I said, the President is going to continue to look at all his options.<br><br>Let me come back here, okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; (Inaudible)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, you’ve mentioned a few times in this briefing the importance of electing candidates that are supportive of access to abortion.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if the President feels that that is the Democrats’ best path forward at this point in getting some sort of legislation passed that would legalize abortion access &#8212; that it really is up to what happens this November and nothing can really get done before then.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak to any political election process and what strategy we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; What I can say is the President has been very clear he is going to do everything that he can to protect freedoms and rights for women and the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>As we know, the Supreme Court, as we saw what Clarence Thomas wrote, they&#8217;re going to go further.&nbsp; And that is something we should really listen to and pay close attention to.&nbsp; And it is going to happen.&nbsp; This is something that the President has said.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, what I would say is: He&#8217;s been very clear.&nbsp; We need &#8212; we need Congress to act.&nbsp; We need to codify Roe, make that the law of the land.&nbsp; That is the best way &#8212; the best way we&#8217;re going to protect rights and freedoms.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and if it doesn&#8217;t happen in Congress, he has &#8212; he has asked the American public to take their voices to the ballot box to make sure to do what you just asked me &#8212; to make sure that we have pro-choice members in Congress.<br><br>All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see you tomorrow.</p>



<p>4:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden on the Retirement of United&#160;States Secret Service Director Jim&#160;Murray</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/07/statement-from-president-joe-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-on-the-retirement-of-united-states-secret-service-director-jim-murray/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 19:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56933</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Director Jim Murray has led a long and distinguished career in federal and military service for three decades, including the last three years as Director of the United States Secret Service. Jim embodies the meaning of service over self, and protected the families of U.S. Presidents like they were part of his own. We are incredibly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Director Jim Murray has led a long and distinguished career in federal and military service for three decades, including the last three years as Director of the United States Secret Service. Jim embodies the meaning of service over self, and protected the families of U.S. Presidents like they were part of his own. We are incredibly grateful for his service to our country and our family.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden Administration Announces Nearly $1B in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Funding Improving Airport Terminals across&#160;U.S.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/07/biden-administration-announces-nearly-1b-in-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-funding-improving-airport-terminals-across-u-s/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 13:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Projects will increase airport capacity, energy efficiency and accessibility Funding going to communities small, medium and large across country WASHINGTON – The U.S. Department of Transportation’s Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) will award nearly $1 billion from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding to 85 airports across the country to improve terminals of all sizes. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>Projects will increase airport capacity, energy efficiency and accessibility</em></p>



<p><em>Funding going to communities small, medium and large across country</em></p>



<p><strong>WASHINGTON</strong> – The U.S. Department of Transportation’s Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) will award nearly $1 billion from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding to 85 airports across the country to improve terminals of all sizes. The grants expand capacity at our nation’s airport terminals, increase energy efficiency, promote competition and provide greater accessibility for individuals with disabilities. Building better airport terminals will improve customer experiences, move goods through the economy more efficiently to lower prices and enhance U.S. competitiveness.</p>



<p>Two grants will also be awarded to build and improve new air traffic control towers.</p>



<p>“Americans deserve modern airports that meet the needs of their families and growing passenger demand. Funded through President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, today’s grants will improve airport terminals while also creating good jobs in communities across the country,”<strong> said U.S. Transportation Secretary Pete Buttigieg.</strong></p>



<p>View a <a href="https://www.faa.gov/bil/airport-terminals">data visualization of the airports</a> receiving grants and how the funds will be invested.</p>



<p>“The work that goes in to build safer, more accessible and sustainable terminals will provide opportunities for people across the nation. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is a critical investment not only in our nation’s infrastructure, but an investment in the future of our country’s workforce,” <strong>said FAA Deputy Administrator A. Bradley Mims.</strong></p>



<p>Historically, the FAA has invested in runways, traffic-control towers and back-of-house infrastructure. Thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, there is dedicated funding to support modernizing airport terminals across the country.</p>



<p>70 grants contain an element that will <strong><u>expand terminal capacity</u></strong>. Among them are:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Pittsburgh International Airport (Pittsburgh, Pa.)</strong>: $20 million to construct a new 700,000-square-foot landside terminal adjacent to the existing airside terminal and includes an improved passenger security screening checkpoint and checked baggage inspection system, baggage handling equipment, U.S. Customs and Border Protection area, and associated public spaces and support functions to serve passengers and meet the operational needs of the airport.</li><li><strong>Chattanooga Metropolitan Airport (Chattanooga, Tenn.): </strong>$5 million for phase one of a terminal expansion project that will expand its second level by nearly 27,000 square feet to allow for two new gates, one expanded gate, a new set of restrooms, and additional passenger queuing, hold room and circulation space. This phase will also reorient the TSA Checkpoint to allow for an additional screening lane and expand the terminal rotunda sufficient to provide adequate passenger queuing space. The project will increase terminal capacity, improve ADA accessibility, increase energy efficiency, promote airline competition, and create jobs.</li><li><strong>Huntsville Intl-Carl T Jones Field (Huntsville, Ala.)</strong>: $10 million to replace aging elevators, escalators, and mechanical equipment; adding one elevator and three escalators; constructing new terminal and concourse restrooms, family restrooms, nursing rooms, and a Service Animal Relief Area; expanding terminal public areas; and ticket counter modifications. The project will provide more amenities for passengers, increase capacity, achieve ADA compliance, improve energy efficiency, improve accessibility, and create construction jobs.</li><li><strong>Orlando International Airport (Orlando, Fla.):</strong> $50 million to construct four gates capable of serving either four wide body or eight narrow body aircraft. The project increases capacity, provides ADA-compliant facilities, achieves LEED (Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design) certification and provides for increased competition.</li></ul>



<p>76 grants contain an element that will <strong><u>increase terminal sustainability</u></strong>. Among them are:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport (Texas)</strong>: $35 million to construct a zero-carbon electrical central utility plant to assist the airport in achieving its goal of net-zero carbon emissions by 2030. Phase 1 will construct the facility and cover two of five terminals.</li><li><strong>Boise Airport (Boise, Ida.):</strong> $960,000 to install energy efficient boilers to support Boise&#8217;s clean energy goal. The funds will also be used to replace aging skylight infrastructure with new skylights that will be more energy efficient.</li><li><strong>Seattle-Tacoma International Airport (Seattle, Wash.):</strong> $10 million for Phase 3 of a restroom modernization that will be ADA compliant and include energy efficient lighting, low flow fixtures and refillable water bottle stations and service animal relief areas.</li><li><strong>Bishop International Airport (Flint, Mich.):</strong> $3.5 million to replace the terminal roof, which has failed in many places. It will be replaced with energy efficient materials, including improved insulation. This will result in decreased heating and cooling needs and reduce energy consumption.</li></ul>



<p>47 grants contain an element that will go <strong>to improving airport access to historically disadvantaged populations and rural airports.</strong> Among them are:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Dexter Regional Airport (Dexter, Maine)</strong>: $760,000 to build a new 800 square foot terminal building replacing the existing 50-year-old 200 square foot terminal building. It includes the reconstruction of the access road. The existing terminal building is beyond its useful life and does not meet current standards or needs for a basic general aviation terminal building. It does not meet ADA requirements and energy efficiencies. The new terminal building will enhance and meet all these needs and requirements. This project provides access to improved terminal facilities for a disadvantage population area in this rural part of Maine.</li><li><strong>Washington Municipal Airport (AWG) Washington, Iowa</strong>: $129,675 to install a solar power system and associated electrical efficiency enhancements for the general aviation terminal.</li><li><strong>Chamberlain Municipal Airport (Chamberlain, S.D.):</strong> $855,000 to construct a new general aviation terminal. This project will replace an existing annex to a Fixed Base Operator (FBO) building that is currently being used as a general aviation terminal. The existing facility does not meet ADA requirement and does not meet the needs of the airport.</li><li><strong>Fillmore County Airport (Preston, Minn.):</strong> $950,000 to replace an existing facility that was constructed in the 1981 that is in poor condition and does not meet ADA requirements.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>73 grants contain an element that <strong><u>provide greater access to individuals with disabilities</u></strong>. Among them are:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Phoenix-Mesa Gateway Airport (Phoenix, Az.):</strong> $14.4 million to expand and update existing temporary terminal space with a permanent five-gate ADA compliant facility.</li><li><strong>Minneapolis-St. Paul International Airport (Minneapolis, Minn.):</strong> $7.1 million to replace five passenger boarding bridges and relocate one passenger boarding bridge. This project will modify walkways, ramps, and slopes to better utilize space and meet ADA requirements. The new boarding bridges will also be more energy efficient.</li><li><strong>Austin Bergstrom International Airport (Austin, Texas)</strong>: $15 million to complete Phase 2, which includes needed capacity expansion immediately and infill for future expansion for the medium hub on the cusp of large hub. In addition to capacity, the project improves access with hearing loops, wayfinding, and multi-lingual assistance, plus assistive care restrooms and ADA compliance throughout. LEED Silver goal projects include energy efficient systems, glass tinting, and sustainable energy construction.</li></ul>



<p>Two grants are awarded to airports to <strong><u>build new air traffic control towers</u></strong>. Those airports are:</p>



<ul><li><strong>General Wayne A. Downing Peoria International Airport (Peoria, Ill.)</strong>: $15 million to construct a new air traffic control tower. The existing tower is 63 years old, in poor condition, and does not meet ADA standards. The new tower will meet all current building codes including ADA, and will utilize modern, energy efficient HVAC systems and lighting.</li><li><strong>Asheville Regional Airport (Asheville, N</strong><strong>.C.):</strong> $15 million to construct a new air traffic control tower. This project replaces an existing 61-year-old air traffic control tower with a new, expanded facility. It is also an enabling project for the expansion and renovation of the existing terminal building. The project will enable increased terminal capacity, replace aging and obsolete infrastructure, improve airfield safety, upgrade the facility to ADA standards, and increase energy efficiency.</li></ul>



<p>One grant will increase <strong><u>multimodal transportation access</u></strong>. That grant goes to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Gainesville Regional Airport (Gainesville, Fla.):</strong> $1.67 million to improve a multi-modal ground transport facility. This project consists of multi-modal ground transport facility improvements, including lighted, accessible, covered walkways to the commercial airline terminal, a covered passenger waiting area, accessible restrooms, and queuing lanes for taxis and city busses arriving and departing the terminal. The project will reduce curbside congestion, increase ADA accessibility, improve accessibility for historically disadvantaged populations, and provide construction jobs.</li></ul>



<p>Today’s funding is from the <a href="https://www.faa.gov/bil/airport-terminals">Airport Terminal Program</a>, one of three aviation programs created by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The law provides $1 billion annually for five years for Airport Terminal grants. Learn more at <a href="http://www.faa.gov/bil">faa.gov/bil</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/bipartisan-infrastructure-law/">President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</a>, also known as the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act, makes a historic investment in our nation’s infrastructure and competitiveness. It will rebuild America’s roads, bridges and rails, upgrade and expand public transit, modernize the nation’s ports and airports, improve safety, tackle the climate crisis, advance environmental justice and invest in communities that have too often been left behind. It will drive the creation of good-paying union jobs and grow the economy sustainably and equitably to help everyone get ahead for decades to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the American Rescue Plan&#8217;s Special Financial Assistance&#160;Program</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/06/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-american-rescue-plans-special-financial-assistance-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 22:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3:19 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, Cleveland!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; (The orchestra concludes playing “Hail to the Chief.”) Thank you to the orchestra.&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; (Applause.) Well, let me start off by saying &#8212; I’d get in trouble with my mother, were she here, if I didn’t say, “Excuse my back&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>3:19 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, Cleveland!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The orchestra concludes playing “Hail to the Chief.”)</p>



<p>Thank you to the orchestra.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Well, let me start off by saying &#8212; I’d get in trouble with my mother, were she here, if I didn’t say, “Excuse my back when I’m speaking.”&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; Number one.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You have my &#8212; (laughs) &#8212;</p>



<p>Hello, Cleveland!&nbsp; Before I begin, though, I want to make one serious comment about the shooting and the death of Jayland Walker.&nbsp; The Justice Department’s Civil Rights Division; the FBI Field Office in Akron, Ohio; and the local U.S. Attorney’s Office are closely monitoring and reviewing what happened.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The FBI continues to coordinate with state and local partners to provide resources and specialized skill.&nbsp; If the evidence reveals potential violations of federal criminal statutes, the Justice Department will take the appropriate action.&nbsp; And I just want you to know what’s going to happen.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And now &#8212; now for today’s program.&nbsp; Thank you, Bill, for that introduction and for the welcome on behalf of the Ironworkers Local 17 here in Cleveland.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ironworkers were with me the first time I ran, as a 29-year-old kid, for the Senate.&nbsp; And you’re all crazy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>I remember you got a guy named Tommy Schranck who was the president of a Local in Delaware.&nbsp; And he said, “Let’s go out and meet some of the guys and women.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>We went out to a buil- &#8212; a construction site.&nbsp; We went up a makeshift elevator.&nbsp; We went up 13 floors.&nbsp; They’re sitting on 18-inch beams, eating their lunch.&nbsp; I’m thinking to myself, “My God, these guys are supporting me.”&nbsp; But they’re the guys I grew up with.</p>



<p>You know, the people you heard speak earlier today &#8212; and I apologize, I’m going to repeat some of what they said.&nbsp; But, you know, we all come from the neighborhood.&nbsp; We all come from &#8212; no, I mean it.&nbsp; I &#8212; I was born in Scranton, Pennsylvania, which was a union town, mostly coalmine union town &#8212; a lot more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My great-grandfather was a &#8212; worked in the mines, was a mining engineer.&nbsp; And everybody &#8212; everybody there &#8212; there was only one word you heard most often in my family.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Most important word wasn’t “unions,” it was “dignity.”&nbsp; “Dignity.”&nbsp; Everyone is entitled to be treated with dignity.</p>



<p>My dad &#8212; (applause) &#8212; then we moved to a little town &#8212; when coal died, we moved to a town called Claymont, Delaware, just across the line in &#8212; from Pennsylvania, where the Delaware River bends.</p>



<p>And, you know, you used to have over 6,000 &#8212; 6,000 steelworkers &#8212; were steel.&nbsp; It’s all gone now.&nbsp; All of it, gone.&nbsp; Used to be a company town, literally.&nbsp; The hills were all company stores, company &#8212; company buildings.&nbsp; But it’s gone.&nbsp; And the union movement began to just crumble in Delaware and in Claymont.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And my dad never belonged to a union, but I say this at the front end: My dad was a salesperson.&nbsp; And he came down from Scranton when coal died.&nbsp; He wasn’t a coalminer, but he worked in sales up there.</p>



<p>And I’ll never forget: We lived in a &#8212; we lived in a three-bedroom, split-level home, like a lot of suburban areas developing in the early ‘50s and mid-‘50s.&nbsp; And there were, I think, 38, 40 homes.&nbsp; And they were &#8212; and we had four kids in the family and a grandpop living with us and mom and dad.</p>



<p>And the walls were thin.&nbsp; And my dad &#8212; one night, I could tell he was really restless.&nbsp; I could hear him and sort of a &#8212; not banging, but leaning up against the wall in the room &#8212; my room.</p>



<p>Next morning, I asked my &#8212; my dad had an expression.&nbsp; He said, “Joey, you never complain and never explain.&nbsp; Just get up.&nbsp; Just get up.”</p>



<p>And I was wondering what was wrong.&nbsp; And I asked my mom.&nbsp; She said, “The company says no pensions.&nbsp; No pensions.”</p>



<p>And so, you know, a lot of you come from families like mine &#8212; a lot of the people who stood behind me.&nbsp; Richie Neal from the state of Massachusetts &#8212; (applause) &#8212; he is, as my uncle would say &#8212; Richie is &#8212; he is union from belt buckle to shoe sole, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And &#8212; but all the folks you heard speak today care about it, because we know what it’s like to be deprived of your dignity.&nbsp; We know what it’s like to have a father or a mother have to put their head down when they know they can’t afford a thing for their kid that they need, whether it’s a prescription or whether it’s just plain being able to go off to school.</p>



<p>And the point I want to make is this: We all understand this.&nbsp; And when I ran for office this time &#8212; and I’ve been a union supporter for my whole career.&nbsp; But I made a promise.&nbsp; I mean it sincerely, and Marty knows this.&nbsp; I guaranteed, when the &#8212; you know, when the Fair Labor Standards Act was passed and &#8212; back in the ‘30s &#8212; and Roosevelt came along, it didn’t say unions were okay.&nbsp; It says we should “encourage” unions.&nbsp; Encourage unions.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Because when unions do well, everybody does well.&nbsp; Everybody does well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>So here’s the deal.&nbsp; The deal is quite simple.&nbsp; When I ran, I was criticized for the basis upon which I ran.&nbsp; I said I’m running for three reasons. One, to restore the soul of America &#8212; the decency and honor of this country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And, two, to rebuild the backbone of the country.&nbsp; The backbone of the country are the working women and men, the middle class.&nbsp; And, you know, there’s a middle class for one reason: American unions.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s the only reason there&#8217;s a middle class.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>And when the middle class does well, everybody does well &#8212; people have a way up, and the wealthy still do very well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, folks, the third reason I ran was to unify the country &#8212; to unify it.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been the harder part of it right now.&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; Because we’ve become so divided &#8212; so divided in this.&nbsp; But one thing we were divided on when we ran &#8212; and, you know, I want to thank Mayor Bibb for the passport into the city.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>But we &#8212; we were divided on the question we&#8217;re celebrating today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, how about actually having a union guy as Secretary of Labor?&nbsp; Isn&#8217;t that something?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, Marty.</p>



<p>And I know we have a fantastic Secretary of Housing and Urban Development: Cleveland&#8217;s own Marcia Fudge.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; She&#8217;s &#8212; she wished she was going to be here.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m also honored to be here with Senator Sherrod Brown, a great champion of working folks.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; He really is.&nbsp; He really is.</p>



<p>And thank you also for the incredible Democratic members of Congress here.&nbsp; Marcy Kaptur &#8212; God love you, Marcy.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You are the best.&nbsp; She does it all &#8212; unions and foreign policy.&nbsp; And for- &#8212; and you think I&#8217;m joking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; She really knows more about foreign policy.&nbsp; She&#8217;s forgotten more than most members of Congress know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And, Shontel Brown, just remember me when you&#8217;re president, okay?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; All right?&nbsp; Congratulations.</p>



<p>Look, and Richie Neal is not only a strong, strong union supporter and been a great supporter of this legislation, but he&#8217;s chairman of the most powerful committee in the United States Congress, the House Ways and Means Committee &#8212; the guys with the money.&nbsp; The guys with money.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s led on labored issue &#8212; labor issues for decades.</p>



<p>You know, while they couldn&#8217;t be here, I also want to thank Senator Tim Ryan &#8212; future Senator Tim Ryan &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and Senator Patty Murray of the state of Washington for their incredible work on this legislation.</p>



<p>With everyone&#8217;s leadership and with their votes and, most of all, with the unrelenting commitment of labor and all of you, this historic day is made possible.&nbsp; And it really is historic.</p>



<p>This was $90 billion, okay?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But it&#8217;s small in comparison to the bailouts of businesses and major corporations and banks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, I&#8217;m here today to talk about the issue that affects every single American and their retirement.&nbsp; People around the country wake up every day wondering whether they&#8217;ve saved enough to provide for themselves and their families before they stop working &#8212; work at a job that provides basic dignity, a good middle-class job you can raise a family on, a job that provides a dignified retirement and will give you peace of mind.</p>



<p>Think of all the people &#8212; and many of you went to bed at night putting your head on the pillow and saying, “Am I going to be all right?&nbsp; Is my family going to be all right?&nbsp; Is my wife or my husband or my child, are they going to be okay?”</p>



<p>It&#8217;s a dignified retirement with your spouse in the home in your community you worked and lived for your whole life.&nbsp; But the reality is for so many people: The goalposts keep moving.&nbsp; Unfor- &#8212; that’s probably Trump calling me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I hear &#8212; I hear that sound there.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, this happens to people who need it most: working people in this country.&nbsp; A lot of politicians like to talk about how they&#8217;re going to do something about it.&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m here today to say we&#8217;ve done something about it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve kept their promise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I campaigned to restore the backbone of this country &#8212; the middle class and unions &#8212; because I know this: The middle class built American unions, built the middle class today.&nbsp; I&#8217;m keeping the promise &#8212; one of the most significant achievement union workers and retirees have received in over 50 years.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>For years and years, union workers have been driving trucks from factories to stores, bagging your groceries, constructing the buildings, bridges, roads we need, and so much more.&nbsp; The ironworkers, bricklayers, carpenters, laborers, plumbers, truck drivers, musicians, I might add.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Food workers and so much more.</p>



<p>And with each paycheck you earn, their employers put money into their pension plans.&nbsp; These workers work hard today to secure a retirement tomorrow.&nbsp; That’s what it’s all about.</p>



<p>Now, a lot of businesses aren’t able or willing to run their own pension plans.&nbsp; And in some industries, workers are employed by several different employers over the course of a year or longer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, we see that in transportation, construction, and entertainment.&nbsp; So working with the union that represents their employees, businesses in the same industry often come together to form what’s called multi-employer union &#8212; and I know you know this, but people listening to this on television may not know this &#8212; pension plans that serve 11 million Americans across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to make sure these pensions are managed responsibly and to protect the participating workers and retirees, the federal government oversees and insures the plans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we’ve seen the risk of millions of workers face as they watch their hard-earned pensions turn into broken promises.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We saw it before the pandemic and the economic crisis that followed.&nbsp; Millions of retirees were at risk of losing their retirement security, through no fault of their own, based on conditions and unrelenting attacks on unions that were taking place.</p>



<p>Two hundred multiemployer pension plans for 2 to 3 million workers and retirees were going insolvent.&nbsp; What that means is to those 2 or 3 million workers &#8212; they faced painful cuts to the benefits they counted on and for the dignified security of retirement.</p>



<p>You just heard from Bill what it’s like to work 30, 40, 50 years &#8212; working hard every day, doing everything to provide for your family; track every dollar of that paycheck for groceries, the mortgage, and, hopefully, for a family vacation maybe one day; knowing when it’s time to retire, your pension you earned will be there; knowing that together with your Social Security benefits, that pension will continue a good middle-class life for you in retirement.&nbsp; For some, just &#8212; my dad used to say, “Just a little peace of mind.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But for folks at home, imagine losing 50 or 60 percent of that pension through absolutely no fault of your own.&nbsp; Imagine what it does financially and emotionally, what it does to your dignity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Also here is Davey Grubbs, a retired Teamsters truck driver from North Carolina who faced nearly 70 percent cut in his pension.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now also joining me today is Rita Lewis.&nbsp; Where are you, Rita?&nbsp; Rita is here somewhere, I&#8217;m told.&nbsp; She stepped out.&nbsp; I don’t blame her.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You know, she&#8217;s Butch’s widow.&nbsp; And their anniversary is coming up in a couple of days.&nbsp; Childhood sweethearts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Butch was a ballplayer drafted by the Pittsburgh Pirates out of high school, but he enlisted in the United States Army instead.&nbsp; Special Forces Army Ranger.&nbsp; Served in Vietnam.&nbsp; Earned, like my son, the Bronze Star.&nbsp; My son did not earn the Purple Heart, but &#8212; and the Purple Heart.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Came back home to Rita, settled in Cincinnati.&nbsp; Became a trucker represented by the Teamsters, and then president of his local.&nbsp; Known as an honorable, honest, and decent labor leader.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Butch faced severe cuts in his pension, and he became a fierce advocate for protecting the pensions of his fellow workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Butch died more than 16 years &#8212; 6 years ago.&nbsp; And Rita has carried on his legacy ever since.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with the &#8212; with &#8212; and with the Democrats in Congress, I might add, and Marty Walsh’s leadership, we brought the Butch &#8212; he &#8212; we fought for the Butch Lewis Act to protect pensions for millions of workers and retirees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a candidate for President, I argued for its passage and promised, when it passed, I would sign it.&nbsp; And that’s the promise I&#8217;ve kept when I &#8212; I included the Butch Lewis Act in the American Rescue Plan. (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, multi-employer plans will remain solvent for decades to come at least until &#8212; guaranteed until 2051.&nbsp; These retirees &#8212; those retirees who lost their benefits will have them restored retroactively.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We turned a promised broken into a promised kept.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It matters to workers.&nbsp; It matters to their families.&nbsp; It matters to the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You all remember what the economy was like when I was elected: a country in a pandemic with no real plans how to get out of it &#8212; millions of people out of their jobs, families in cars &#8212; remember? &#8212; backed up for literally miles, waiting for a box of food to be put in their trunk.&nbsp; Just a &#8212; a box of food to be put in their trunk because they didn’t have enough to eat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The previous administration lost more jobs on its watch than any administration since Herbert Hoover<a></a> &#8212; that’s a fact &#8212; all based on failed trickle-down economics that benefitted the wealthiest Americans and hit the middle class and working people the hardest.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we came in with a fundamentally different economic vision: an economy that grows from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; It’s good for everyone, because when the middle class does well, the poor have a ladder up and the wealthy still do very well.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And that’s why we designed the American Rescue Plan based on &#8212; based on the belief that a recovery should help all Americans prosper, a belief that working &#8212; building power and unions are good for workers and for the economy, a plan that led to the most jobs created in the first period of a presidency than any time in over &#8212; in all American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And we’ve seen in the past how economic crisis can leave so many Americans in tough straits for years, sometimes for the rest of their lives.&nbsp; Economists call it the “scarring effect” &#8212; the lasting bad effects of economic hardship, including folks unemployed for a long time.</p>



<p>Remember, when we started this, a lot of people were equally as qualified, but they’d been unemployed for 8, 10, 12 months; they wouldn’t even be considered.&nbsp; Two people put in an application &#8212; the person may be more qualified but unemployed &#8212; out of &#8212; out of work for longer.&nbsp; It’s called the “scarring effect” &#8212; people not able to get back to work.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; But we changed that.&nbsp; And young people who faced a weak labor market &#8212; they’re back.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Losing a big part of your income late in life, that’s a scar, though, that doesn’t heal.&nbsp; Well, not this time.&nbsp; Long-term unemployment and youth unemployment dropped at a record pace.&nbsp; With today’s actions, millions of workers will have the dignified retirement they earned and they deserve.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, folks, let’s be honest: I’d love to tell you, everyone, that &#8212; here that this policy that honors hard work and ensures dignified retirement was universally supported, regardless of political party.&nbsp; But this is an important point and this really matters: Unfortunately, that’s not the case.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not one single Republican &#8212; not &#8212; no, this is &#8212; I mean, this is what I’m talking about.  Not one single solitary Republican voted for the Butch Lewis Act or this legislation.<br><br>AUDIENCE:  Booo &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And, folks &#8212; and, folks, I can tell you, those of us in the &#8212; were &#8212; I was in the Congress a long time, and the people are still in the Congress &#8212; there’s ones who wanted to, but they’re afraid to &#8212; afraid to &#8212; because the Trumpers would literally take them out.  Not a joke.  That’s how bad it’s gotten.  We’ve got to change it.  We’ve got to change it.<br><br>In fact, when this bill was moving through Congress, Republicans called it &#8212; called these pensions, quote, “rat holes.”  That was their &#8212; no, that was their phrase on the floor &#8212; “rat holes.”</p>



<p>Who do they think they are?  Who do they think you are, for God’s sake?  And my predecessor had the chance to act, but he didn’t have the commitment to you or the courage to stand up to his own party to get things done, dismissing and ignoring the forgotten people he promised to help.  Remember how he was going to help working-class folks? </p>



<p>But tax cut for the wealthiest Americans &#8212; he had no trouble passing that.&nbsp; They passed a $2 trillion tax cut, not a penny of which was paid for.&nbsp; Increased the debt by $2 trillion.&nbsp; The vast majority of people making the top 1 percent of income, the biggest corporations and their &#8212; their biggest cheerleaders of that two thou- &#8212; $2 trillion tax cut.&nbsp; Again, disproportionately benefitted the wealthiest &#8212; the wealthiest Americans.<br><br>Protecting a system in which, for example, the 55 of the largest Fortune 500 companies in America paid zero in taxes.&nbsp; Zero.</p>



<p><br>They made &#8212; they made $40 billion.&nbsp; Didn’t pay a single penny.<br><br>The party that choose to make life more comfortable for the already comfortable disparage and oppose retirement security for working people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now, when Republicans actually do offer a plan &#8212; and they finally &#8212; we &#8212; you know, I’m not joking.&nbsp; Ask yourself this question: What is the Republican platform going into this campaign?<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; I’m not &#8212; I’m being deadly earnest.&nbsp; I’m not trying to be poli- &#8212; just &#8212; just a fact.<br><br>Well, they have a guy who is the &#8212; Rick Scott from Florida, who heads up the Republican Campaign Committee.&nbsp; He put out the plan.&nbsp; What does that plan do?&nbsp; It makes the tax system less fair by giving &#8212; wanting to tax everybody making under $100,000 significantly more, on average &#8212; a lot more money.&nbsp; It actually raises taxes on those working families because he thinks you don’t pay enough in taxes already.<br><br>No, no.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I can &#8212; I should have brought along the actual copy of the plan, but go online and get &#8212; no, for real.&nbsp; It’s been published.&nbsp; They published it.&nbsp; They think we’re freeloaders.<br><br>But he’s not &#8212; but he’s got a problem with a tax code that allows billionaires &#8212; none at all, no problem &#8212; trillion and billionaires in America &#8212; there’s 789 or thereabouts.&nbsp; You know what their average federal income tax they pay?&nbsp; Eight percent.<br><br>Every one of you have a job pays more than 8 percent &#8212; every single one of you.&nbsp; If you’re a cop, a teacher, a firefighter, union worker, you probably pay two to three times that.&nbsp; Now, after refusing to protect your pension, they’re going after your Social Security.<br><br>Look, I would have thought, had I not seen it on paper and heard them talk about it, that I was making this up.&nbsp; Not a joke.<br><br><br></p>



<p>His big idea is put Social Security on the chopping block every five years.&nbsp; That is: Every five years, Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid have to be reauthorized or they go out of existence.</p>



<p>Social Security you paid in from the day you started working.&nbsp; It’s your other pension.&nbsp; You paid into it every single paycheck.&nbsp; You earned it.&nbsp; It’s your money, just like your pension.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he adds in Medicare and Medicaid for the chopping block every five years.&nbsp; Unless Congress explicitly votes to extend those programs, they go away.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know how they work the rules in the Senate.&nbsp; The ability to slow this up and keep that from happening is real.</p>



<p>You know how hard it is to get anything done in Congress.&nbsp; Imagine what it would mean if Republicans had their way.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the ultra-MAGA Republicans &#8212; Congress is deciding every five years whether the &#8212; your promise of your hard-earned Medicare and Social Security would be continued or discontinued or slashed.&nbsp; It’s shameful.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Rick Scott is not alone.&nbsp; Senator Lindsey Graham of South Carolina is talking &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, he has a proposal to cut Social Security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by the way, I might note, parenthetically: As President &#8212; the first year I was President, I cut the federal deficit by $350 billion.&nbsp; And do you know how much I cut it this year?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Cut &#8212; cut this year &#8212; by the end of September, I will have cut the federal budget by $1 trillion 400 billion &#8212; cut the deficit.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when they start talking about you being big spenders, just point them to that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here’s the point: Republicans are talking about privatizing social security &#8212; privatizing social sec- &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I &#8212; this is not a jo- &#8212; I mean, you know, we used to hear this stuff and think they didn’t mean it, but they’ve written it down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The senator from Wisconsin, Ron Johnson, promised again that if they regain power, they’re going to get rid of the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What does that mean?&nbsp; It means that if any of you who have a preexisting condition will automatically lose insurance.&nbsp; Because the insurance companies are able to &#8212; right now, because of the Affordable Care Act, no one can be denied insurance because they have a preexisting condition.&nbsp; It’s the only thing that &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; no.&nbsp; And by the &#8212; we’re talking 90 million people with preexisting conditions gone.&nbsp; Gone.</p>



<p>They tried to do it about 17 times last &#8212; under Trump.&nbsp; We were able to stop them.</p>



<p>But, folks, this is a different world.&nbsp; I don’t know where they live.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I’m not joking.&nbsp; That’s why elections have consequences, and that’s why they matter, and that’s why what we’re doing here is so important.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: We’ve made incredible cogress [sic] on the &#8212; progress on the economy from where we were a year and half ago.&nbsp; We got a long way to go because of inflation and because of the &#8212; I call it “the Putin tax increase” &#8212; “Putin” because of gasoline and all that grain he’s keeping from being able to get to the market.</p>



<p>Now I’m fighting like hell to lower costs on the things that you talk about around your kitchen table.&nbsp; My dad used to say, “At the end of the day, it’s just, when you sit at that table, do you have enough money to pay for everything you need?”&nbsp; Not a lot over.&nbsp; Do you have enough money to pay for everything you need?</p>



<p><a>While Republicans do nothing <s>to</s> [but] obstruct our efforts to lower your gas taxes </a>&#8212; I’ve proposed that and I’ve asked the Congress to eliminate the federal gas tax for the next &#8212; as long as this crisis goes on; to lower food prices, lower healthcare costs; hopefully soon, lower your prescription drug costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, you’ve got a &#8212; you got a Republican leader in the United States Senate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I was able to work out something with Intel.&nbsp; They’re going to provide for over 7,000 jobs in this state, out of Columbus &#8212; (applause) &#8212; making computer chips.</p>



<p><a>Well, there’s another bill that, if we get it passed &#8212; and my guys are working like hell to pass it &#8212; it’ll create another $100 <s>million</s> [billion] in investments in Ohio, creating more jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>But do you know what?&nbsp; You know what the Republican leader is saying?&nbsp; If, in fact, we pass the law that says Medicare can negotiate drug prices like they can for the military; if, in fact, we pass the plan that says we’re going to raise taxes on multi-millionaires so they start paying their fair share, then he’s going to block the passage of the legislation that will provide for another $100 billion invested in this state.</p>



<p>Folks, this is not right.&nbsp; This is not right.&nbsp; And that’s why this election is going to be so darn important.&nbsp; The key is that we just have to remember who built this country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I know I remember.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, I’ll be awarding the highest honor that can be given to a civilian, the Presidential Medal of Freedom, to our dear friend the late Rich Trumka, who fought so damn hard to protect &#8212; (applause) &#8212; for the protection of these pensions.&nbsp; He once said unions &#8212; quote, “We do America’s work.”&nbsp; Unions do America’s work.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Fourth of July, let’s remember who &#8212; who is the backbone of this country.&nbsp; It’s you, the American worker.&nbsp; I promised you I would be the most pro-labor, pro-union, pro-worker&nbsp;President in our history.&nbsp; And there’s another promise I am going to be keeping as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; So, let me tell you something: There’s no other place I want to be than right here with the workers in this room and the workers that built America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I see you, I hear you, and I’ll always have your back.&nbsp; I promise.&nbsp; God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>3:47 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House and President of the Senate providing notice of the President’s intent to rescind the designation of Afghanistan as a Major Non-NATO&#160;Ally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-and-president-of-the-senate-providing-notice-of-the-presidents-intent-to-rescind-the-designation-of-afghanistan-as-a-major-non-nato-ally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 22:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) In accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k), I am providing notice of my intent to rescind the designation of Afghanistan as a Major Non‑NATO Ally. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Sincerely, &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>In accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k), I am providing notice of my intent to rescind the designation of Afghanistan as a Major Non‑NATO Ally.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Fifteenth Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/06/president-biden-announces-fifteenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 21:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56895</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 3.1 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula on July 17 and 22 Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Kendamil baby formula from England to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of over 3.1 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula on July 17 and 22</em></p>



<p><br>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Kendamil baby formula from England to New York, NY via flights on July 17 and 22 respectively. These two deliveries will include in total approximately 200,000 pounds of Kendamil EU Classic First Infant Milk Stage 1 and Kendamil EU Organic First Infant Milk Stage 1, the equivalent of approximately 3.1 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available at Target stores. Parents and Pediatricians can learn more about Kendamil infant formula at <a href="https://us.kendamil.com">https://us.kendamil.com</a>  and compare its nutritional content per 100kcal with other leading formula brands at <a href="https://us.kendamil.com/pages/compare-kendamil">https://us.kendamil.com/pages/compare-kendamil</a>.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Kendamil can export additional infant formula into the U.S., including&nbsp;Kendamil EU Classic First Infant Milk Stage 1 and Kendamil EU Organic First Infant Milk Stage 1. Kendamil plans to export approximately 58 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market over the next 6 months.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By July 10, Operation Fly Formula will have transported more than 43 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents to the U.S.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img width="483" height="483" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-56896" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg 483w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/07/BABY-FORM.jpg?resize=1200,1200 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 483px) 100vw, 483px" /></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
