<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:39:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Captive Nations Week, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/16/a-proclamation-on-captive-nations-week-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From the founding of our Nation to today, through the crucibles of war and the struggle of successive generations, America has strived to uphold the ideals of freedom and democracy upon which our country was built and expand the ability of people around the world to freely exercise their rights.&#160; As the world&#8217;s longest-standing democracy,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>From the founding of our Nation to today, through the crucibles of war and the struggle of successive generations, America has strived to uphold the ideals of freedom and democracy upon which our country was built and expand the ability of people around the world to freely exercise their rights.&nbsp; As the world&#8217;s longest-standing democracy, we carry a special responsibility to lead at home and abroad, not only by the example of our power, but by the power of our example &#8212; to prove to ourselves and to the world that democracy can deliver for all people.&nbsp; Though much has changed in the world since President Eisenhower issued the first Captive Nations Proclamation in 1959, its call for liberty and opportunity still ring true.&nbsp; During Captive Nations Week, we recommit ourselves to those principles which form the foundation of our Nation, and to amplify the voices of courageous individuals around the world who are striving to advance the principles of human rights, justice, and the rule of law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, far too many people are subject to routine abuses of power, as oppressive governments detain, harass, or commit acts of violence against dissenting voices; disseminate disinformation and propaganda; undermine democratic systems; and otherwise violate the public trust.&nbsp; These abuses are not new &#8212; but they remain as stern a threat to human rights and freedom as they have ever been.</p>



<p>No nation or person of conscience can ignore the voices of those crying out for liberty.&nbsp; We hear Belarusians peacefully calling for democratic elections, and the courageous people of Hong Kong demanding the autonomy and liberty promised by Beijing under the Sino-British Joint Declaration and Hong Kong&#8217;s Basic Law.&nbsp; We hear millions of Uyghurs and other ethnic and religious minorities in Xinjiang, China, who have been unjustly interned and subject to surveillance and forced labor.&nbsp; We hear the determination of those rejecting military rule in Burma, resisting dictatorship in Venezuela, taking to streets in Cuba to demand freedom in the face of brutal state repression, and pressing for free and fair elections in Nicaragua &#8212; as well as the Crimean Tatars, ethnic Ukrainians, and other ethnic and religious minorities who suffer repression for opposing Russia&#8217;s illegal occupation of Crimea.</p>



<p>The American creed, which defines our Nation, proclaims that all people are created equal, and deserve to be treated equally, with dignity and respect, throughout their lives.&nbsp; We stand in solidarity with the brave human rights activists and pro-democracy advocates around the world who risk their lives for the rights of others. &nbsp;We are committed to ensuring that all those who are oppressed across the globe &#8212; including people with disabilities, women and girls, members of the LGBTQI+ community, indigenous populations, and racial and ethnic minorities &#8212; are heard, respected, and protected.</p>



<p>During Captive Nations Week, we recommit ourselves to the timeless, vital work of advancing freedom and justice for all. &nbsp;</p>



<p>We do that by forging a more equitable and inclusive society, by solving problems and helping to ease the burdens people face, and by fulfilling our role as a global leader for human rights and fundamental freedoms of expression, association, peaceful assembly, and religion or belief.&nbsp; Together with our allies and partners, we must continue to strengthen democratic institutions, defend independent civil society and media freedom, promote free and fair elections, protect human rights online, insist on accountability for those who commit abuses and foster cultures of corruption, and push back against authoritarianism around the world.</p>



<p>The Congress, by joint resolution approved July 17, 1959 (73 Stat. 212), has authorized and requested the President to issue a proclamation designating the third week of July of each year as &#8220;Captive Nations Week.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim July 18 through July 24, 2021, as Captive Nations Week.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to reaffirm our commitment to championing those around the world who strive for liberty and justice for all.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this sixteenth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-jacinda-ardern-of-new-zealand/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 01:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24131</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today spoke by phone with Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand. They discussed our interest in maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific region, and President Biden underscored the enduring U.S. commitment to the region. The leaders discussed our close partnership on a range of issues, including efforts to support the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today spoke by phone with Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand. They discussed our interest in maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific region, and President Biden underscored the enduring U.S. commitment to the region. The leaders discussed our close partnership on a range of issues, including efforts to support the global economic recovery and to end the COVID-19 pandemic. President Biden commended Prime Minister Ardern for her steadfast and effective leadership throughout the pandemic. President Biden expressed U.S. support for the Christchurch Call to Action. They also discussed our cooperation on and engagement with Pacific Island nations. President Biden also thanked Prime Minister Ardern for hosting the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Virtual Leaders’ Retreat on July 16, and they agreed on the importance of multilateral institutions and economic cooperation throughout the region.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and Chancellor Merkel of the Federal Republic of Germany in Press Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/15/remarks-by-president-biden-and-chancellor-merkel-of-the-federal-republic-of-germany-in-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 5:16 P.M. EDT&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN: Thank you all. Please have a seat. Today, it&#8217;s been my great honor &#8212; and I mean that &#8212; to welcome a dear friend back to the White House.&#160;And before I say anything else, Chancellor Merkel, I want to express to you and to the people of Germany my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>5:16 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Thank you all. Please have a seat. Today, it&#8217;s been my great honor &#8212; and I mean that &#8212; to welcome a dear friend back to the White House.<br>&nbsp;<br>And before I say anything else, Chancellor Merkel, I want to express to you and to the people of Germany my sincere condolences and the condolences of the American people for the devastating loss of life and the destruction due to the flooding over the past 24 hours in Germany and neighboring countries. It&#8217;s a tragedy, and our heart goes out &#8212; our hearts go out to the families who&#8217;ve lost loved ones.<br>&nbsp;<br>Chancellor Merkel has been here frequently over the past 16 years. Matter of fact, she knows the Oval Office as well as I do. But all kidding aside, through &#8212; though this administration &#8212; she&#8217;s been there for four years &#8212; for four Presidents.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I want to take a moment to acknowledge the historic nature of her chancellorship. First woman chancellor in German history. The first chancellor from the former East Germany. And now, the second largest &#8212; longest-serving chancellor since Helmut Kohl. Here&#8217;s an exemplary life of groundbreaking service to Germany and, I might add &#8212; and I mean it from the bottom of my heart &#8212; to the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>On behalf of the United States, thank you, Angela, for your career of strong, principled leadership. And thank you for speaking out for what is right and for never failing to defend human dignity.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to thank you for your continued support for the longstanding goal of a Europe whole, free, and at peace. You&#8217;ve been a stalwart champion of the Transatlantic Alliance, the Atlantic Partnership.<br>&nbsp;<br>Under your chancellorship, the friendship and cooperation between Germany and the United States has grown stronger and stronger.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m looking forward to celebrating more at our dinner this evening, but today was very much a working visit. Chancellor Merkel and I covered a wide range of issues where Germany and United States are working to advance a shared agenda. We discussed, together with our fellow major democracies at the G7, Germany and the United States have responsibilities to lead with our values, as do the other members of NATO.<br>&nbsp;<br>And today, I&#8217;ve &#8212; I&#8217;ve confided that in our new Washington Declaration, which we&#8217;ve codified &#8212; a document affirming our commitment to the democratic principles that are the heart &#8212; that are at the heart of both of our nations, and how we will apply them to meet the biggest challenges of today and tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Both our nations &#8212; both our nations understand the imperative of proving that democracies can deliver the needs of our people in the second quarter of the 21st century. We will stand up for democratic principles and universal rights when we see China or any other country working to undermine free and open societies.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are united &#8212; united in our commitment to addressing democratic backsliding, corruption, phony populism in the European Union or among candidates for the EU membership or anywhere we find it in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>We agree on the importance of further integrating the Western Balkans into the European &#8212; into European institutions and in our continued support for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine, as well as the continued importance of reforms in the support of their Euro-Atlantic aspirations.<br>&nbsp;<br>We stand together and will continue to stand together to defend our Eastern Flank allies at NATO against Russian aggression. And while I rere- &#8212; while I reiterated my concerns about Nord Stream 2, Chancellor Merkel and I are absolutely united in our conviction that Russia must not be allowed to use energy as a weapon to coerce or threaten its neighbors.<br>&nbsp;<br>And today, we&#8217;re launching a climate and energy partnership to support energy security and the development of sustainable energy, sustainable energy technologies, and emerging &#8212; and emerging economies, including in Central Europe and Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>To unite our efforts to upend and &#8212; on our global climate ambitions that we have to up-the-ante, what happened is we talked about when Paris Accord was set, we thought we had established just how serious it was, but things have gotten much more dire since even that date. And to unite our efforts to update and to up-the-ante on global climate &#8212; on global climate ambitions.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also thank Chancellor Merkel for the dedication and the sacrifice of German troops who have served side by side along with U.S. forces in Afghanistan for almost 20 years.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we reaffirmed our shared commitment to continuing to counter terrorist threats where we find them, including in the Sahel in Africa.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we &#8212; when we think about the future, the future we want for the world, there is no issue &#8212; there&#8217;s no issue set at all that I believe we find anything other than the certainty that a commitment that &#8212; between the United States and Germany doesn&#8217;t benefit whatever the problem or the concern is.<br>&nbsp;<br>We need to fight COVID-19 pandemic everywhere, to strengthen global health security for tomorrow so we&#8217;re ready for the next pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>We need to make sure that the rules of the road governing the use of emerging technologies advance freedom, not authoritarianism and repression.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we need to promote a sustainable and inclusive economic recovery that enhances the prosperity and opportunity for all.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so much more.<br>&nbsp;<br>This just &#8212; this isn&#8217;t just the work of governments, the work is the work of our peoples, sharing their innovation and insights, joining together to amplify our collective impact.<br>&nbsp;<br>So today, we&#8217;re launching a Futures Forum between our two countries, which will bring together top experts across business, academia, civil society, and more to collaborate as we shape our shared future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Madam Chancellor, I know that the partnership between Germany and United States will continue to grow stronger on the foundation that you have helped to build. But on a personal note, I must tell you, I&#8217;ll miss seeing you at our summits. I truly will.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you again, Angela, for making the journey, for our productive meeting today, and for your friendship.<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR MERKEL: (As interpreted.) Mr. President, dear Joe, first of all, I would like to thank you most warmly for the condolences and the empathy you expressed as regards the victims to the floodings in Germany.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would like to ask for your understanding that I need to address this matter with a few words because, in North Rhine-Westphalia and Rhineland-Palatinate, the day is already drawing to a close &#8212; a day that is characterized by fear, by despair, by suffering. And hundreds of thousands of people, all of a sudden, were faced with catastrophe. Their houses were literally death traps. Small rivers turned into flooded, devastating rivers.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I must say that my empathy and my heart goes out to all of those who, in this catastrophe, lost their loved ones or who are still worrying about the fate of people still missing.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I include Belgium, Luxembourg, and the Netherlands who’ve also suffered from floodings.<br>&nbsp;<br>The rescuers, first responders are doing their utmost to help people. I must say that I&#8217;m very much feeling with those who&#8217;ve suffered, and I know that millions of people in Germany feel the same.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Minister-Presidents Ms. Dreyer and Mr. Laschet, Minister-Presidents of Rhineland-Palatinate and North Rhine-Westphalia, respectively, and also the ministers who were responsible here &#8212; I talked to them, and I would like to send out a message to the people that we will not leave them alone with their suffering and that we&#8217;re trying our utmost to help them in their distress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Mr. President, dear Joe, thank you for the invitation. Thank you for making it possible to talk to you. It&#8217;s my first visit since 2019, and I&#8217;m so much &#8212; so happy about the personal exchange we have seen again today that we&#8217;re not only partners and allies, but we&#8217;re very close friends. And thank you for the very friendly exchange that we had this afternoon.<br>&nbsp;<br>We all share the same values. We all share the same determination to tackle the challenges of our times, to master them. And I&#8217;m deeply convinced that simply committing to these values is certainly not sufficient. We are living at a crucial moment in time where we are facing new challenges, and these challenges need to be translated into practical policies.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I&#8217;m very grateful that we have this opportunity to work on foundations. And we lay down those foundations in the Washington Declaration, and also how we see the road ahead, and also measures. And I think that this Futures Forum will deal with those issues. Our societies will discuss together what sort of solutions they think appropriate, and I think such structures are very important.<br>&nbsp;<br>There is a very large degree of common ground, as has come out of our talks. We are convinced, both of us, that overcoming this pandemic is only possible if as many people as possible are vaccinated in our countries, and many wish to do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have to also support the rest of the world with vaccines. We work together with COVAX. And I&#8217;m very grateful to the United States that, under your leadership, dear Joe, the U.S. has committed itself very clearly and unequivocally to multilateralism, be it on climate, be it on reform of the World Health Organization, and support also to WTO.<br>&nbsp;<br>Germany and the United States have agreed to provide vaccine doses to poorer countries; we work within COVAX, as I said.<br>&nbsp;<br>We talked about the challenge of climate change. And I am very happy that the United States are now back again with us in the Paris Climate Agreement and for Glasgow. That provides us with a totally different basis in order to work among the parties to the treaty better &#8212; in a much better and much more efficient way for climate.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we see countries that are (inaudible) by floodings, by wildfires, and by storms in an increasing manner, and that shows that there is a dramatic increase in such unusual weather phenomena and we have to contend with this.<br>&nbsp;<br>Germany and the United States have now forged an Energy and Climate Partnership. I think it&#8217;s a very important message that we&#8217;re sending here. We want to build on future-oriented technologies &#8212; green hydrogen, for example; renewables; electromobility. We&#8217;re in competition with others on this planet, and we would like to be successful together. And Germany is very much looking forward to cooperating in this respect.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I support the President in what he proposed as a global infrastructure project, which we agreed on on the G7 summit. Next year, as you probably know, we will have the chairmanship of the &#8212; the presidency of the G7, and we will bring this project forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>We talked about Russia and Ukraine and, in this context, also about Nord Stream 2. We&#8217;ve come to different assessments as to what this project entails. But let me say very clearly: Our idea is and remains that Ukraine remains a transit country for natural gas; that Ukraine, just as any other country in the world, has a right to territorial sovereignty, which is why we&#8217;ve become engaged and continue to be engaged in the Minsk Process.<br>&nbsp;<br>We will be actively acting should Russia not respect this right of Ukraine that it has as a transit country. So Nord Stream 2 is an additional project and certainly not a project to replace any kind of transit through Ukraine. Anything else would obviously create a lot of tension. And we&#8217;re also talking about how we can actually make this very clear together.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also talked about other priorities in our foreign policy. For example, our relationship with China. We are countries who stand up for free, democratic societies &#8212; stand up for those rights &#8212; civic rights for those who live in these societies. So, wherever human rights are not guaranteed, we will make our voices heard and make clear that we don&#8217;t agree with this. We are also for territorial integrity of all countries of the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also talked about the many facets of cooperation and also of competition with China, be it in the economic area, be it on climate protection, be it in the military sector and on security.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, obviously, there are a lot of challenges ahead. On the nuclear agreement with Iran, JCPOA &#8212; we think that everything ought to be done in order to bring this to a successful conclusion. But I think that is something that is also &#8212; the ball very much here is also in the Iranian camp.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, over many, many years, we&#8217;ve served together in Afghanistan. We&#8217;ve been able to contain, to a certain degree, terrorist dangers. But, unfortunately, we have not been able to build a nation as we would like it to look.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, still, I would hold, it was a good partnership &#8212; has been a good partnership with the United States all throughout this experience. Also very good contacts between our soldiers. I know our soldiers greatly appreciated that.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also talked about Sahel &#8212; the Sahel zone where terrorism is on the rampage. And obviously, for us in Europe, this is a great challenge. We&#8217;re very &#8212; and also for the countries on the ground &#8212; we’re very grateful to the United States for their mission in order to contain and push back against these terrorist advances.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also have drawn up a German &#8212; we&#8217;ve also agreed on a German-American dialogue between our business communities, because we have considerable trade links and we wish to build on this. And obviously, the economy and economic ties are of prime importance.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it was a very, very good exchange. We&#8217;re close partners. I would like this to remain even after I have left office. And I think, with this visit, we probably paved the way to make it possible to also create formats where we can exchange, because the world will continue to be a place that is full of challenges.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you very much for making it possible for us to tackle those together. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Thank you very much. We&#8217;re each going to take two questions. And I&#8217;m going to begin by recognizing Steve Portnoy and congratulate you on your new role as president of the White House Correspondents Association.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, sir.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: My sympathies.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: No, but thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; I appreciate that, sir. On behalf of the press corps, thank you, and we&#8217;re looking forward to the day we can have even more reporters all the way to the back of the room. So, thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; I have a couple of questions for you. Also a question for the Chancellor. But, Mr. President, with respect to Latin America and the developments there in the last week-plus &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; what are the circumstances under which you would send American troops to Haiti? That&#8217;s the first question.<br>&nbsp;<br>The second question is: When it comes to Cuba, what is your current thinking on American sanctions toward Cuba and the embargo? And today, your Press Secretary said that communism is a “failed ideology.” I assume that&#8217;s your view. I was wondering if you could also give us your view on socialism.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, for the Chancellor, the question is: Madam, the President said that you know the Oval Office as well as he does. I&#8217;m wondering if you could reflect on your exchanges with American Presidents over the last 16 years and, particularly, contrast the current President with his most immediate predecessor.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: In two minutes or less. (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, I know why they elected you president. (Laughter.) Well, let me start off by answering the question relative to Haiti and Cuba. And communism is a failed system &#8212; a universally failed system. And I don&#8217;t see socialism as a very useful substitute, but that&#8217;s another story.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to whether the circumstances in which we would send military troops to Haiti: We &#8212; we’re only sending American Marines to our embassy to make sure that they are secure and nothing is out of whack at all. But the idea of sending American forces into Haiti is not on the agenda at this moment, number one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, with regard to Cuba: Cuba is a &#8212; unfortunately, a failed state and repressing their citizens. There are a number of things that we would consider doing to help the people of Cuba, but it would require a different circumstance or a guarantee that they would not be taken advantage of by the government &#8212; for example, the ability to send remittances to &#8212; back to Cuba. I would not do that now because the fact is it’s highly likely that the regime would confiscate those remittances or big chunks of it.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to the need COVID on &#8212; I mean &#8212; excuse me &#8212; they have a COVID problem on &#8212; in Cuba. I&#8217;d be prepared to give significant amounts of vaccine if, in fact, I was assured an international organization would administer those vaccines and do it in a way that average citizens would have access to those vaccines.<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of the things that you did not ask but we&#8217;re considering is &#8212; they&#8217;ve cut off access to the Internet. We&#8217;re considering whether we have the technological ability to reinstate that access.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think I&#8217;ve answered your questions. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR MERKEL: (As interpreted.) Allow me, if I may, to elaborate on three different points. Any German chancellor has a vested interest to talk &#8212; and that’s in &#8212; very much in the vested interest of Germany to work and talk together with any American President.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ve always had contacts, and we &#8212; you’ve been able to &#8212; it was, I think, very transparent, and today it was a very friendly exchange.<br>&nbsp;<br>Oh, sorry. I have to call on Mr. Kynast and his German question.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; (As interpreted.) Thank you very much, Madam Chancellor, Mr. President. Allow me, if I may, to ask a question as regards Nord Stream 2. Madam Chancellor, you just said that you would act actively should Russia be in breach of its commitments &#8212; so, for example, interrupt gas transit through Ukraine. What do you mean in concrete terms? Will Germany then switch off Nord Stream 2 from the German side? And what sort of legal grounds would you be, sort of, claiming?<br>&nbsp;<br>Mr. President, you have fought so many years &#8212; the U.S. has fought so many years against Nord Stream 2. Now, there will be only a few days left until this pipeline comes into operation. Why &#8212; will you allow it to go ahead, to put it in operation, or will the people who operate the system actually have to contend with sanctions on the horizon?<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR MERKEL: Well, Mr. Kynast, as the Chancellor, you know that we&#8217;ve worked a lot &#8212; not only Germany incidentally, but the whole of the European Commission &#8212; for talking to Russia and Ukraine, negotiating a treaty that ensures until 2023 the gas contract and, after that, gas deliveries must be possible as well. That is what I&#8217;ve heard at least. Let me be very careful here in my wording.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then should that not go ahead, we have a number of instruments at our disposal, which are not necessarily on the German side, but on the European side. For example, sanctions and as regards Crimea and breach of the Minsk treaty has shown that we have these sanctions &#8212; these instruments at our disposal.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have possibilities to react. We are in contact with our European friends on this. But at the &#8212; at the point in time of which I hope we will never have to take those decisions, you will then see what we do.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: My view on Nord Stream 2 has been known for some time. Good friends can disagree. And &#8212; but by the time I became President, it was 90 percent completed. And imposing sanctions did not seem to make any sense. It made more sense to work with the Chancellor on finding out how she’d proceed based on whether or not Russia tried to, essentially, blackmail Ukraine in some way.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, the Chancellor and I have asked our teams to look at practical measures we could take together, and whether or not Europe energy security, Ukraine security are actually strengthened or weakened based on Russian actions. And so this is a &#8212; we&#8217;ll see. We&#8217;ll see.<br>&nbsp;<br>Ms. Leonard of Bloomberg.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President. I have two questions for you, and then some for Chancellor Merkel as well. Your administration, tomorrow, is issuing a business advisory for Hong Kong. I was wondering if you can explain why you think that is necessary.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, secondly, on your Build Back Better agenda, have you spoken to Senators Manchin and Sinema about the $3.5 trillion framework, and are you confident that they&#8217;ll be on board at that level? And if they demand that you lose some components, will you be able to keep progressives on board?<br>&nbsp;<br>(As interpreted.) I wanted to ask you whether you have a feeling that, after the talk with President Biden, he better understands your viewpoint as regards to China or whether the situation is still tense, whether there is still decoupling. And secondly, whether you think that the United States has contributed enough to vaccinate the rest of the world, or do you think it’s only &#8212; is it appropriate for children in the United States being vaccinated &#8212; children below the age of 12, while adults in other countries have no chance to get vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: That’s all? (Laughter.) I thought I said we’d take two questions, but I guess that translated to we&#8217;d take two questions or more from each person called on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me talk about the business advisory. The situation in Hong Kong is deteriorating. And the Chinese government is not keeping its commitment that it made how it would deal with &#8212; with Hong Kong.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so it is more of an advisory as to what may happen in &#8212; on Hong Kong. It&#8217;s as simple as that and as complicated as that.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to “Am I confident?” &#8212; I&#8217;m supremely confident that everything is going to work out perfectly in terms &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; look, I understand why the press, among others, is skeptical that I can actually get this deal done on infrastructure and on human infrastructure. And I&#8217;ve watched and listened, and the press declared my initiative dead at least 10 times so far.<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t think it’s dead. I think it’s still alive. I still have confidence we&#8217;re going to be able to get what I proposed and what I&#8217;ve agreed to in the bipartisan agreement on infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ve gotten &#8212; we&#8217;ve each committed &#8212; I trust the members of &#8212; the Republican senators who have made the commitments relative to how we should proceed and what would be included in the package for infrastructure. And they’re men and women of honor, and I expect they would keep their commitment.<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to the further issue of what&#8217;s going on and what will confuse the listening audience &#8212; but reconciliation &#8212; that is the mechanism by which you have to get every single Democrat to agree to proceed on matters like what I announced today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today &#8212; I don&#8217;t know whether you have any children; it&#8217;s none of my business whether you do, but if you do, you&#8217;re going to get &#8212; if you&#8217;re making less than $150,000 &#8212; you&#8217;re going to get a significant stipend that is a tax cut. If you have a child under the age of seven years old, you&#8217;re going to get &#8212; in your bank account today, you&#8217;re going to get a payment of one &#8212; 12 months divided &#8212; $3,600 &#8212; $3,700 for that child divided by 12 every month, just like a Social Security check.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s expected to reduce pov- &#8212; child poverty by over 40 percent. And it could be a significant, significant game-changer.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have mechanisms to pay for both these mechanisms. And there may be some last-minute discussion as to who &#8212; what mechanism is used to pay for each of these items, both the infrastructure package and the human infrastructure package. But I believe we will get it done. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR MERKEL: (As interpreted.) We talked about China, and there is a lot of common understanding that China, in many areas, is our competitor; that trade with China needs to rest on the assumption that we have a level playing field so that we all play by the same rules, have the same standards. That, incidentally, was also the driving force behind the EU-China Agreement on trade that they abide by the core labor norms of ILO.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are convinced of our needing to be technological leaders for our two countries in many, many areas. Obviously, it&#8217;s legitimate for China wishing to do this as well, but, for example, we will cooperate in many technological state-of-the-art technologies &#8212; for example, CHIPS. I think the act that the President launched is fundamental in this respect and crucial.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we want to trade together at a time of digitalization where security issues loom very large in our agenda &#8212; as we ought to have an exchange on this; we ought to talk about this; we ought to talk about norms, standards that govern the Internet; whether we can agree on common norms. I think, particularly as regards to the relationship of us with China, we ought to coordinate our efforts. We do that in the European Union, and we should do it with the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then there are interests, obviously &#8212; sometimes divergent interests, but sometimes common interests. But we also have, obviously, areas where American companies compete with European companies, and we have to accept that. But I think, basically, the rules as to how we deal with China ought to rest and do rest on our shared values.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think, on the pandemic, we are obviously of the opinion that the pandemic &#8212; we can only master the pandemic if each and every one is vaccinated. We are trying to boost production. We are trying also to get as many people in our country vaccinated as possible &#8212; which obviously opens us up to criticism of those countries who has yet have not had the chance, which is why we invested a lot of money in COVAX, which is why we encourage our companies to increase their production of vaccines.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, in Africa, we are trying to help Africans to upskill people so that they, too, can have their own production sites. We&#8217;re going to do this, but, de facto, there is an imbalance; I agree.<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; but we&#8217;re overcoming. We&#8217;re putting our all into that and also together in overcoming that imbalance.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m sorry. I call on Ms. Schaeuble from Der Tagesspiegel newspaper. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Very short one for each of you. Mr. President, my question &#8212; my first question touches an issue that worries a lot of people in the U.S. and in Germany. Can you explain to us why there still is a travel ban for people coming from Germany or other states of the European Union, while people from Turkey, where the number of new cases are seven times as high, can come?<br>&nbsp;<br>You all have repeatedly said that you&#8217;re following scientific data. What is the main argument for not lifting that travel ban for the Schengen region?<br>&nbsp;<br>And, Chancellor Merkel &#8212; (as interpreted) &#8212; you talked to the business companies here. You heard their concerns. You heard their headaches. Some have threatened that they&#8217;re going to shift business away from the United States. What was your main argument to work for a lifting of the travel ban? And have you had success with this?<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: We brought in the head of our &#8212; our COVID team because the Chancellor brought that subject up. It’s in the process of (inaudible) how soon we can lift the ban &#8212; it&#8217;s in process now. &nbsp;And I&#8217;ll be able to answer that question to you within the next several days &#8212; what is likely to happen. I&#8217;m waiting to hear from our folks in our &#8212; our COVID team as to when that should be done. And the Chancellor did raise it. (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR MERKEL: (As interpreted.) I did raise the issue, yes, and got the same answer that the President gave you just now. The COVID team is evaluating the matter. We had an exchange on &#8212; in both areas.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Delta variant actually being on the increase, that is, again, a new challenge to both of us. And obviously, before such a decision, one has to reflect, and it has to be a sustainable decision. It is certainly not sensible to have to take it back after only a few days. So I&#8217;m &#8212; have every confidence in the American COVID team.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN: Having been here many times, if we don&#8217;t leave right now, we&#8217;re going to miss dinner. Chancellor and I have a dinner with some &#8212; a number of folks, and very shortly.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you for your attention. And thank you for your &#8212; for your questions. Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR MERKEL: Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>5:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with Dr. Angela Merkel, Chancellor of the Federal Republic of Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/statement-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-dr-angela-merkel-chancellor-of-the-federal-republic-of-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 23:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24119</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris hosted Chancellor Angela Merkel of Germany for breakfast at her residence today to convey her appreciation for the close friendship and shared values between Germany and the United States. Vice President Harris and Chancellor Merkel had a candid and wide-ranging discussion about current and future geopolitical threats and challenges. They agreed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris hosted Chancellor Angela Merkel of Germany for breakfast at her residence today to convey her appreciation for the close friendship and shared values between Germany and the United States. Vice President Harris and Chancellor Merkel had a candid and wide-ranging discussion about current and future geopolitical threats and challenges. They agreed on the urgent need to invest in democratic institutions anchored in the rule of law and grounded in the fundamental rights and dignity of all people. They expressed their shared desire to strengthen the transatlantic partnership and continue robust cooperation in areas such as pandemic response and recovery, global health, and the environment. The Vice President thanked Chancellor Merkel for Germany’s contributions to global vaccination efforts and its leadership in combatting climate change. They discussed the need for concrete actions to create norms around emerging technology, and for more coordinated international efforts to address the root causes of migration. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"> ###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and Surgeon General Dr. Vivek H. Murthy, July 15, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/15/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-surgeon-general-dr-vivek-h-murthy-july-15-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 22:12:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24113</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:05 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI: Hi, everyone. We have another special guest today. Doesn’t sing as well as our guest from yesterday &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but very knowledgeable.&#160;SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Definitely don’t ask me to sing.&#160;MS. PSAKI: (Laughs.) Today, we have a special guest, Surgeon General Vivek Murthy. The Surgeon&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:05 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Hi, everyone. We have another special guest today. Doesn’t sing as well as our guest from yesterday &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but very knowledgeable.<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Definitely don’t ask me to sing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: (Laughs.) Today, we have a special guest, Surgeon General Vivek Murthy. The Surgeon General has been one of our leading voices on public health in the administration, in particular around the COVID-19 response.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, he published an advisory on health misinformation as an urgent public health crisis, and he is here to talk more about this issue and take a few of your questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, I will turn it over.<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Hello, everyone. How are you?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Good, thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: It’s nice to see you all today. And thank you, Jen, for that very kind introduction.<br>&nbsp;<br>As all of you know, we’ve come a long way in our fight against COVID-19, and we’ve come a long way thanks to the efforts of many, many people across communities in the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>But right now, we are seeing COVID deaths markedly down from their peak in January. We have 160 million people who have been fully vaccinated. And hundreds of thousands of people each day are choosing to get vaccinated. That is all good news.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we are not out of the woods yet. Millions of Americans are still not protected against COVID-19, and we are seeing more infections among those who are unvaccinated. And that’s why I want to talk to you today about one of the biggest obstacles that’s preventing us from ending this pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, I issued a Surgeon General’s Advisory on the dangers of health misinformation. Surgeon General Advisories are reserved for urgent public health threats. And while those threats have often been related to what we eat, drink, and smoke, today we live in a world where misinformation poses an imminent and insidious threat to our nation’s health.<br>&nbsp;<br>Health misinformation is false, inaccurate, or misleading information about health, according to the best evidence at the time. And while it often appears innocuous on social media apps and retail sites or search engines, the truth is that misinformation takes away our freedom to make informed decisions about our health and the health of our loved ones.<br>&nbsp;<br>During the COVID-19 pandemic, health misinformation has led people to resist wearing masks in high-risk settings. It’s led them to turn down proven treatments and to choose not to get vaccinated. This has led to avoidable illnesses and death. Simply put, health [mis]information has cost us lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, health misinformation didn’t start with COVID-19. What’s different now though is the speed and scale at which health misinformation is spreading. Modern technology companies have enabled misinformation to poison our information environment with little accountability to their users. They’ve allowed people who intentionally spread misinformation &#8212; what we call “disinformation” &#8212; to have extraordinary reach.<br>&nbsp;<br>They’ve designed product features, such as “Like” buttons, that reward us for sharing emotionally-charged content, not accurate content. And their algorithms tend to give us more of what we click on, pulling us deeper and deeper into a well of misinformation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, we need an all-of-society approach to fight misinformation. And that’s why this advisory that I issued today has recommendations for everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, we include recommendations for individuals and families. We ask people to raise the bar for sharing health information by checking sources before they share, to ensure that information is backed by credible, scientific sources. As we say in the advisory, “If you’re not sure, don’t share.”<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, we’re asking health organizations to proactively address misinformation with their patients. Today, the American Academy of Pediatrics is announcing an educational campaign to help parents navigate online health information. I’m encouraged to see this commitment. And, again, this is just the beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third, we’re asking educational institutions to help improve health information literacy.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re asking researchers and foundations as well to help us learn more about how health [mis]information spreads and how to stop it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, the Rockefeller Foundation is announcing a $13.5 million commitment to counter health misinformation. The Digital Public Library of America is announcing that they will convene a set of librarians, scholars, journalists, and civic leaders to confront health misinformation together.<br>&nbsp;<br>Fourth, we’re saying we expect more from our technology companies. We’re asking them to operate with greater transparency and accountability. We’re asking them to monitor misinformation more closely. We’re asking them to consistently take action against misinformation super-spreaders on their platforms.<br>&nbsp;<br>Fifth, we’re also asking news organizations to proactively address the public’s questions without inadvertently giving a platform to health misinformation that can harm their audiences.<br>&nbsp;<br>And sixth, we know that government can play an important role too by investing in research, by bringing individuals and organizations together to address misinformation, and by supporting groups that are working on this issue.<br>&nbsp;<br>On a personal note, it’s painful for me to know that nearly every death we are seeing now from COVID-19 could have been prevented. I say that as someone who has lost 10 family members to COVID and who wishes each and every day that they had had the opportunity to get vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>I say that also as a concerned father of two young children who aren’t yet eligible for the vaccine, but I know that our kids are depending on all of us to get vaccinated to shield them from this virus.<br>&nbsp;<br>Every week, I talk to doctors and nurses across our country who are burning out as they care for more and more patients with COVID-19 who never got vaccinated &#8212; all too often because they were misled by misinformation.<br>&nbsp;<br>We must confront misinformation as a nation. Every one of us has the power and the responsibility to make a difference in this fight. Lives are depending on it.<br>&nbsp;<br>You can read the full advisory at SurgeonGeneral.gov/HealthMisinformation.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I hope that you will see it as I do &#8212; as a starting point from which we can build a healthier information environment, safeguard our nation against future threats, and ultimately, empower people to lead healthier lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks so much for your time. And I’ll turn it to Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Andrea.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Andrea Shalal with Reuters. I wanted to ask you whether you see any evidence at all that the misinformation or disinformation that you’re seeing comes from any nefarious sources. Are you seeing some structures behind the scenes that point to who or what might be behind them? We’ve seen Russian disinformation in the past. We’ve seen, kind of, that hybrid warfare. Are you seeing any indication that there could be nation states behind this disinformation?<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Well, Andrea, thank you for the question. The misinformation that we&#8217;re seeing comes from multiple sources. Yes, there is disinformation that is coming from bad actors. But what is also important to point out is that much of the misinformation that is circulating online is often coming from individuals who don&#8217;t have bad intentions, but who are unintentionally sharing information that they think might be helpful.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s why, in this advisory, we make it very clear that among the things we&#8217;re asking individuals to do is to pause before they share, to check sources. And if they&#8217;re not sure if a source is credible, to not share. You know, one of the things we have said, again, is that when it comes to misinformation, not sharing is caring &#8212; unlike what many of our moms taught us earlier in life. (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you very much. Surgeon General, is misinformation the number one reason why people are not getting vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Well, Kaitlan, it&#8217;s one of several reasons why people are not getting vaccinated, but it&#8217;s a very important one because what we know from polls, Kaitlan, is that two thirds of people who are not vaccinated either believe common myths about the COVID-19 vaccine or think some of those myths might be true. Myths like, “You can get COVID from the vaccine,” which is absolutely not true. So we know that it&#8217;s not the only driver that&#8217;s leading people not to be vaccinated, but it is a very important one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; And do you personally believe that public figures and public companies that are helping spread misinformation about the vaccine should be held accountable?<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Well, I think in a moment like this when we see misinformation literally costing us our loved ones, costing us lives, all of us have to ask: How we can be more accountable and responsible for the information that we share?<br>&nbsp;<br>And those of us who may have larger platforms, I think bear a greater responsibility to think about that. But the bottom line is all of us have an important role here to play, and technology companies have a particularly important role.<br>&nbsp;<br>We know that the dramatic increase in the speed &#8212; speed and scale of spreading misinformation has, in part, been enabled by these platforms. So that&#8217;s why in this advisory today, we are asking them to step up. We know they have taken some steps to address misinformation, but much, much more has to be done. And we can&#8217;t wait longer for them to take aggressive action because it&#8217;s costing people their lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead in the middle, and then Rachel. And then, unfortunately, he has to go. Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; So, the reality is a lot of the health misinformation you were citing came from this lectern last year. I mean, what do you think the best approach is to counter or deal with misinformation that comes from public officials &#8212; people in position of authority?<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Well, what I would say is that when it comes to determining what is accurate, in terms of health information, science has to guide us. And the good news is that we have credible science individuals in our country. We have doctors and nurses in communities. We have public health departments and the CDC. We have medical schools, nursing schools, and healthcare institutions.<br>&nbsp;<br>These should be our sources of credibility when it comes to evaluating whether information is true or not. I think one of the greatest roles that public leaders can play is to point to scientists and to credible sources and have them speak directly to the public.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll note for you that that’s one thing that this administration has done is work hard to put science, scientists, and healthcare professionals in front of cameras to &#8212; having to speak directly to the public. That&#8217;s what we have to do more of.<br>&nbsp;<br>The problem right now is that the voices of these credible health professionals are getting drowned out, and that&#8217;s one of the reasons we are asking technology companies to help lift up the voices of credible health authorities. It&#8217;s also why they have to do more to reduce the misinformation that&#8217;s out there so that the true voices of experts can shine through.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead, Rachel.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you so much for taking my question. So are there specific elected leaders that you believe are part of the problem with pushing this misinformation?<br>&nbsp;<br>And we had an ABC News-Washington Post poll that showed that 93 percent of Democrats say they&#8217;re vaccinated or will be vaccinated, but only 49 percent of Republicans say the same. So, how do you break through to the people who may be trusting some of these elected leaders that are pushing, maybe, some of this misinformation more than they actually trust members of your administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Well, thanks, Rachel. You know, I think about this as I &#8212; as I think about doctoring, and as I think about my approach to patients, which is: I recognize that each patient that I was blessed to care for is an individual, you know, regardless of what their political affiliation or their past may be. They&#8217;re an individual and I &#8212; my goal was to understand what their needs and desires were, what their values were, and then to help them improve their health.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have to take a similar approach here when it comes to reaching people with information about COVID-19 and the vaccine. We&#8217;ve got to recognize that sometimes the most trusted voices are not the ones that had the most followers on social media or are the ones that have the most, you know, name recognition. Sometimes the most trusted sources are a mother or father or a faith leader or a local doctor or a nurse, and that&#8217;s why, to reach people with accurate information, what we have to do is partner with those local trusted voices.<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s why, in this advisory, one of the things that we point out an important role for government is to support local organizations, including healthcare professionals, so that they can get out there and speak directly to people and share that information.<br>&nbsp;<br>These public health efforts move at the speed of trust, and we have to recognize where trust is &#8212; you know, where those relationships are &#8212; invest in them, support them, so that people can ultimately get the information they need to improve their health.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Thank you so much for joining us.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Jen, I have a follow-up for &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; the Surgeon General on &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: I think he has to go, unfortunately. Thank you so much.<br>&nbsp;<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: Thank you so much, Jen. Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Okay, I think we’re getting ready to start the briefing. I think everybody has a lot of questions. So why don’t you &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; (Inaudible.) You never &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: We &#8212; we are going to proceed with the briefing, and then we’re happy to take lots of questions in the room.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay. So, unemployment claims, which you all saw the data come out this morning &#8212; today’s data on new unemployment claims is further proof that the President’s economic plan is working.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today marked another new pandemic low in initial unemployment claims &#8212; the lowest level since March of 2020. And the four-week average of new claims continued to decline, dropping to its lowest level in 16 months &#8212; down 55 percent since when President Biden took office.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is evidence of the strengthening labor market we’re seeing across the economy: Unemployment is down, wages are up, and three million new jobs have been created in five months &#8212; the fastest rate in U.S. history.<br>&nbsp;<br>We just gave you a few headlines over here, just in case you haven’t read all of your own coverage. (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And because of the President’s Rescue Plan and his work curbing the pandemic, the United States is expected to return to full employment by next year instead of 2024, which was the projection when the President first took office.<br>&nbsp;<br>Another piece of news today: We heard the President, of course, announce today that $15 billion in Child Tax Credit payments were distributed to tens of millions of families, covering 60 million children. Working families will receive these payments on the 15th of every single month for the next year thanks to the American Rescue Plan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Eighty-six percent of American families will receive their payment by direct deposit. It will show up in their bank accounts as “Child CTC.” Others will receive their check in the mail today or in the next few days.<br>&nbsp;<br>And just as a reminder: The American Rescue Plan is providing the largest-ever Child Tax Credit. And this is a historic increase that will provide middle-class families with critical tax relief. And many project it will help cut the child poverty rate in half.<br>&nbsp;<br>I have a little update for all of you on ransomware, as well as vaccines. And then we&#8217;ll get to your questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>In April, the President directed agencies to take aggressive action to counter the ransomware threat at home and abroad. We have coordinated these efforts, regularly convening an interagency task force that drives coordinated whole-of-government action to counter ransomware. Participation spans the whole government including law enforcement, the intelligence community, center risk management agencies, regulators, and other national security agencies.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, as a part of our ongoing ransomware efforts, the Department of Homeland Security, Department of Justice, Treasury, and State announced new resources and initiatives to protect American businesses and communities from ransomware attacks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Those include: The Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Justice launched StopRansomware.gov, a coordinated, federal government, one-stop resource for public- and private-sector organizations to reduce their risk of ransomware attacks.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department of Treasury announced a FinCEN exchange on ransomware to discuss efforts by the public and private sectors to increase targeted information sharing and analysis, and pursue criminal actors and networks that engage in such attacks.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the Department of State announced it will offer up to $10 million in rewards for information leading to the identification or location of any person engaged in state-sponsored, malicious cyber activities.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a part of our ongoing efforts and our ongoing work of our interagency process that is a new &#8212; a newer initiative in this administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, last night, Haiti received 500,000 doses of COVID-19 Moderna vaccines donated by the United States through the COVAX facility. And we will send a significant amount of additional doses to Haiti soon, in consultation with local health authorities.<br>&nbsp;<br>The embassy in Haiti has worked closely with Haitian health &#8212; the heal- &#8212; Haitian Health Ministry, Pan American Health Organization, and UNICEF to ensure that these vaccines arrive safely and securely, and that they are also distributed equitably and without interference to the people who need them most.<br>&nbsp;<br>We remain, of course, a partner of the Haitian people in building a more stable and secure Haiti, including in its fight against COVID-19.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Alex.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. Can you talk a little bit more about this request for tech companies to be more aggressive in policing misinformation? Has the administration been in touch with any of these companies and are there any actions that the federal government can take to ensure their cooperation, because we&#8217;ve seen, from the start, there&#8217;s not a lot of action on some of these platforms.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure. Well, first, we are in regular touch with these social media platforms, and those engagements typically happen through members of our senior staff, but also members of our COVID-19 team, given, as Dr. Murthy conveyed, this is a big issue of misinformation, specifically on the pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of actions, Alex, that we have taken &#8212; or we&#8217;re working to take, I should say &#8212; from the federal government: We&#8217;ve increased disinformation research and tracking within the Surgeon General&#8217;s office. We&#8217;re flagging problematic posts for Facebook that spread disinformation. We&#8217;re working with doctors and medical professionals to connect &#8212; to connect medical experts with popular &#8212; with popular &#8212; who are popular with their audiences with &#8212; with accurate information and boost trusted content. So we&#8217;re helping get trusted content out there.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also created the COVID-19 &#8212; the COVID Community Corps to get factual information into the hands of local messengers, and we&#8217;re also investing, as you all have seen in the President&#8217;s, the Vice President’s, and Dr. Fauci’s time in meeting with influencers who also have large reaches to a lot of these target audiences who can spread and share accurate information.<br>&nbsp;<br>You saw an example of that yesterday. I believe that video will be out Fri- &#8212; tomorrow. I think that was your question, Steve, yesterday; I did a full follow-up there.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are also proposed changes that we have made to social media platforms, including Facebook, and those specifically are four key steps.<br>&nbsp;<br>One, that they measure and publicly share the impact of misinformation on their platform. Facebook should provide, publicly and transparently, data on the reach of COVID-19 &#8212; COVID vaccine misinformation. Not just engagement, but the reach of the misinformation and the audience that it&#8217;s reaching.<br>&nbsp;<br>That will help us ensure we&#8217;re getting accurate information to people. This should be provided not just to researchers, but to the public so that the public knows and understands what is accurate and inaccurate.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, that we have recommended &#8212; proposed that they create a robust enforcement strategy that bridges their properties and provides transparency about the rules. So, about &#8212; I think this was a question asked before &#8212; there&#8217;s about 12 people who are producing 65 percent of anti-vaccine misinformation on social media platforms. All of them remain active on Facebook, despite some even being banned on other platforms, including Facebook &#8212; ones that Facebook owns.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third, it&#8217;s important to take faster action against harmful posts. As you all know, information travels quite quickly on social media platforms; sometimes it&#8217;s not accurate. And Facebook needs to move more quickly to remove harmful, violative posts &#8212; posts that will be within their policies for removal often remain up for days. That&#8217;s too long. The information spreads too quickly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, we have proposed they promote quality information sources in their feed algorithm. Facebook has repeatedly shown that they have the levers to promote quality information. We&#8217;ve seen them effectively do this in their algorithm over low-quality information and they&#8217;ve chosen not to use it in this case. And that’s certainly an area that would have an impact.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, these are certainly the proposals. We engage with them regularly and they certainly understand what our asks are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; And then, one of the problems with vaccines right now is that they become politicized. You guys &#8212; the White House has obviously made the calculation that it&#8217;s important to be more aggressive in confronting this information, but is there at all a concern that that could backfire and further contribute to politicization? And is there anything that you can do to prevent that at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, you&#8217;re abs- &#8212; you&#8217;re absolutely right, I should say, Alex, in that we have to be very careful and we are mindful of being quite careful of not politicizing the effectiveness of vaccines, the fact that they can save lives &#8212; young people, old people, middle-of-the-road people.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s important for us &#8212; we&#8217;ve made a calculation to push back on misinformation. You&#8217;re right. But that&#8217;s one of the reasons, as Dr. Murthy was conveying, we have empowered, engaged, funded local voices, because they are often the most trusted voices &#8212; doctors, medical experts, clergy &#8212; you know, people who are members of &#8212; civic leaders in communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s where we are putting most of our resources, even as we are working to combat misinformation that&#8217;s traveling online or traveling, unfortunately, out of the mouth of elected officials from time to time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Just want to follow up on the ransomware &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; questions. So the President told us last week that there&#8217;s this meeting tomorrow of the U.S.-Russian working group on ransomware. Can you say a little bit more about that meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: I think it was actually yesterday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; It was? Okay. And can you give us any kind of a further readout of what decisions were made, if any? Last week, the President also said that it made sense to potentially go after servers that were being used in these ransomware attacks. Has the administration made any decisions about whether to proceed with that kind of action?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: So I would say that the meeting, which I believe was yesterday &#8212; I will double confirm for you, Andrea, and for others &#8212; but, is part of ongoing engagement that has been occurring at the expert level since the President met with President Putin.<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s been ongoing. No one meeting is necessarily decisive; it&#8217;s about having a continued discussion about our expectations and steps that need to be taken to address ransomware attacks, cyberattacks, and what the capacities are on information of course that we have.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of specific actions, the President, of course, reserves the right and the option to respond in a time and a manner of his choosing should he believe actions warrant. But I&#8217;m not going to preview that from the podium today or probably any day.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; So a senior administration official had told us in the aftermath of that conversation that we should expect action within days and weeks, and some of it would be visible, some of it would not be visible. I understand you can&#8217;t share a lot of information, but can you say whether any action has in fact been taken that perhaps is not visible to us?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: There&#8217;s nothing more I can preview or detail for you from here. I certainly understand the interest.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; The President has designated $10 billion for testing in schools, but we&#8217;ve seen some states, like Idaho and Iowa &#8212; they say they don’t even want the money. So is that a mistake? And who should be held responsible if children in those schools get sick?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, certainly, we&#8217;ve always said from the beginning that local school districts are going to make decisions about how to use the funding and resources available, but also how they&#8217;re going to apply the mitigation measures that have been laid out by the CDC. And certainly we would expect that members of their local community, parents, others who care about the health and wellbeing of their children would voice their concern if they have it. But it&#8217;s always worked that way in terms of local school districts implementing policies.<br>&nbsp;<br>The role of the CDC is to provide public health information. Our role from the federal government was to secure funding to ensure schools that need resources &#8212; they don&#8217;t all need resources &#8212; but have access to those funds should they need it. Many have used it, many have applied it, and many schools will be opening as a result of that funding.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Is there a concern, though, about not being able to even track an outbreak if there is one because of the lack of testing, possibly?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, we certainly &#8212; the CDC certainly does track where there is a rise in cases. As you see, they put out publicly available data. I expect they would continue to do that. But I would point you to them for more information on how they would track.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Can I just ask one quick follow-up on inflation: We heard from the Fed Chair, Jerome Powell; he&#8217;s testifying on Capitol Hill this week. He noted that inflation has notably increased but he believes that it will remain elevated in the coming months before moderating.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve heard from Republicans who say the administration is sort of flooding the economy with cash. Even Democrats like Senator Joe Manchin &#8212; I talked to him yesterday &#8212; he says that he has concerns about inflation. Is the White House underestimating the impact of all of this government spending that it will have on inflation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, our experts believe &#8212; and the data shows and the Federal Reserve Chair, who operates independently, conveyed, yesterday &#8212; that most of the price increases we are seeing are expected to be temporary due to the consequences of restarting an economy shut down during the pandemic. And we&#8217;re seeing that in certain industries more than others as prices go back to where they were pre-pandemic. And that certainly was an ex- &#8212; we had an expectation that would be an impact.<br>&nbsp;<br>So areas like spike in car prices due to supply chain challenges on the &#8212; on the restart or a spike in hotel room costs as the hospitality industry gets going &#8212; these are &#8212; a number of these are transitory or they&#8217;re impacted by other factors, including supply chain issues, which we’re working with Democrats and Republicans to help address through the CHIPS legislation.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I want to be clear: We take &#8212; we understand the threat that inflation poses. We will be vigilant as responses are needed &#8212; are needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to legislation: We&#8217;re continuing to advocate for the way to keep prices in our economy down is to increase the supply of goods that consumers want to buy and keep the costs of producing and getting them to market lower. That&#8217;s exactly what the President&#8217;s Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and the Build Back Better plans will do.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would also remind you all, it&#8217;s an eight-year investment in better roads, bridges, and transit systems. So this is not an immediate influx in the next few months of funding; it&#8217;s over the course of several years because this is a long-term issue.<br>&nbsp;<br>And it will also &#8212; if, as we &#8212; as we work to pass the Build Back Better reconciliation package, increase the availability of childcare, more workers will enter the workforce, increasing our output, and helping to keep prices down.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we are quite mindful of it. We do monitor it. I would also note the Federal Reserve, who’s independent, has also projected that the inflation numbers will come down to about 2.2 next year from where they&#8217;re projecting for this year, which is something we also watch closely.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Can I follow up on that, Jen?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Is the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Are you confident that the government is going to be able to find the parents who qualify for the Child Tax Credit but are outside of the tax system?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, we have a &#8212; as you&#8217;ve seen as we&#8217;ve implemented a number of our programs to date, we have a means &#8212; a number of means of trying to identify individuals who are eligible for these programs. Some of it is by promotion in communities for individuals who may not have had to pay taxes or may not be in the system.<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly we will be vigilant and do everything we can to reach every single person who&#8217;s eligible, get out the word to communities that they are &#8212; that they are maybe people who are eligible, even if they don&#8217;t make enough money to pay taxes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; So what are the other avenues, specifically, that you&#8217;re using to find these parents?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think you&#8217;ve seen us use a number of avenues in the past few months where there were not individuals &#8212; as it related to our $1,400 checks that we put out just a few months ago. We put out a website where people could go if they had not paid taxes because they did not make enough money to pay taxes.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also, of course, work with local communities to get out and make sure &#8212; get the word out and make sure people know they are eligible. Again, I would think &#8212; I think that, starting today, the vast majority &#8212; vast, vast majority of people who are eligible, of course, will get their checks direct &#8212; through direct deposit and through direct checks. So, we&#8217;re talking about a small percentage of individuals who we would be looking to find. And, of course, we will be vigilant about doing everything we can to find them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; And one follow-up on that: Will the President accept a spending bill that does not extend the tax credit for four years like he wants?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, there&#8217;s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: There are a range of details I know you are all eager to see and to have, and there&#8217;s been reporting about it. We will certainly leave it to Leader Schumer and Democrats on the Hill to put out all of the specific details.<br>&nbsp;<br>But the President certainly understands that there could be changes, even to his original proposal and even from here as the final negotiations continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; So, he would accept that? Sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here, Kaitlan, but we&#8217;ll look to see what the final package looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President has advocated for an extension of the Child Tax Credit because he thinks it is a benefit that helps working families. That&#8217;s why he&#8217;s proposed it in multiple packages, and we&#8217;ll look to see the final details.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Weijia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, Jen. I know you said this is moving, but some Democrats have expressed they believe the Child Tax Credit should be permanent. Does President Biden agree with that or does he think the four-year extension is adequate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, as you know, Weijia, he put in his proposal a five-year extension. He certainly understands that there was going to be &#8212; and there was &#8212; a range of views. Some wanted it shorter. Some wanted it longer. Some didn&#8217;t want it at all. That&#8217;s part of the negotiations and the discussion.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think one of the calculations here that senators and Congress have to work through is what components can be worked through that you can pay for in the package. That&#8217;s a factor as it relates to &#8212; certainly to the Child Tax Credit, which, as I understand, costs about a billion dollars a year.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ll let them work out the length of it, and we look forward to seeing the de- &#8212; the final details made public in the coming days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; On the bipartisan bills &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Some Republicans have just said that &#8212; that they&#8217;re not prepared to vote on something that is not written yet. They just expressed this on the Hill. As Senator Romney said, it would be a dereliction of duty to vote, even procedurally, on something that has not been written. Does the President agree with Senator Schumer&#8217;s timeline to hold a vote before all the language is finalized?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I think it&#8217;s important to remember that there was an agreement that many senators were a part of &#8212; Democrat and Republican &#8212; on the framework that is the basis of this piece of legislation &#8212; right? &#8212; that they agreed to. The President certainly expects that everyone will stay true to their commitment, as &#8212; as he will.<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, the President believes that his most important role he can play is to continue to advocate for the key components of what&#8217;s in this package, why it&#8217;s important for people to support it in Congress, and why the American people should be excited about investments in roads and railways and bridges and investments in making sure we&#8217;re addressing our climate crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>He will leave the mechanics and the timeline up to Leader Schumer.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you, Jen. Now that you&#8217;ve had a few days to think about it, does this White House still think the protests in Cuba are happening because people are upset about a rise in COVID cases there or is there some thought, maybe, given to the possibility that they&#8217;re protesting because they are sick of communism?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, Peter, first, I would say: Communism is a failed ideology, and we certainly believe that. It has failed the people of Cuba. They deserve freedom. They deserve a government that supports them, whether that is making sure they have health and medical supplies, access to vaccines, or whether they have economic opportunity and prosperity.<br>&nbsp;<br>And instead, this has been a government &#8212; an authoritarian communist regime &#8212; that has repressed its people and has failed the people of Cuba. Hence, we&#8217;re seeing them in the streets.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would note that the ideology of the government, which has failed, has led to a fail- &#8212; a lack of access to economic opportunity, to medical supplies, to COVID vaccines. So all of those pieces are true.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; And there are protesters now in this country who are chanting, as these protests in Cuba are going on, &#8220;Where is Biden?&#8221; So, where is he? What is he doing to protect these people who are rising up against the leaders of this failed experiment?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, he is certainly advocating for and speaking out, as we put out a statement &#8212; multiple statements &#8212; maybe one of you will ask him a question about Cuba today. I will &#8212; I will leave it to all of you to determine that.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, one, he has made clear that he stands with the Cuban people and their call for freedom from both the pandemic and from decades of repression and economic suffering to which they&#8217;ve been subjected by Cuba&#8217;s authoritarian regime.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s an ongoing review of our own policies. And as we look at those policies, one of the big factors is ensuring we are not doing anything to pad the pockets of a corrupt authoritarian regime. And that is certainly a factor as he&#8217;s considering, but we&#8217;re looking closely at how we can help in a humanitarian way, how we can help support the voices of the Cuban people, and there&#8217;s an ongoing policy review in that regard.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; We&#8217;d be happy to ask him about it later if he calls on us. (Laughter.) But one more &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Anyone can ask anything they want. But go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; One more for you: Why is the Secretary of State Blinken trying to address human rights in the U.S. by inviting experts &#8212; U.N. experts from Cuba and China here?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I would say that the Secretary put out an extensive statement on why he is holding &#8212; why he believes that we need to play a role in lifting up and pushing countries to do better on human rights, on ending systemic racism in their countries. Certainly, human rights is always going to be a priority for the Biden administration and for this State Department.<br>&nbsp;<br>As the Secretary said in his statement, he believes responsible nations must not shrink from scrutiny of their human rights record. Rather, they should acknowledge it with the intent to improve it, and also push and lift up and put a &#8212; shine a light on other countries that need to do better. And that is the role we&#8217;re playing here from the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; But you just rattled off all these problems with Cuba. They&#8217;ve got dissenters disappearing down there. In China, they&#8217;ve got a million religious minorities in internment camps. Why are they going to come here and tell us how to improve our country?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: I certainly don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s the format of the event. But lifting up and elevating human rights; systemic racism; the &#8212; the steps that have been taken &#8212; the poor treatment of Uyghurs, as I think you&#8217;re referencing here &#8212; in China; and pushing other countries with a spotlight on them to do better is certainly a role we can play from the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Can I ask about South Africa very quickly?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; There have been days of looting and unrest there in South Africa. They&#8217;ve now destroyed hundreds of businesses. At least 117 people there have been killed. Does the White House have any reaction to what&#8217;s taking place there? And what, if any, role does the U.S. government have here to help try to quell the situation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: We certainly track and watch closely and certainly have concerns about unrest that we see in the streets in South Africa.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the specific actions, I think the State Department is probably best equipped, but I&#8217;m happy to talk to our national security team if there&#8217;s anything specifically we can convey from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Let me follow up. Yesterday, I asked you about Afghanistan. Is there anything more you can tell us about those Special Immigrant Visas as they relate to the Afghan interpreters, translators, engineers, and others?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure. Let me try to provide a little bit more detail on how the process works, which I &#8212; you have all understandably been asking about.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as I&#8217;ve noted in the past, our immediate focus is on interested and eligible Afghan nationals and their families who have supported the United States and our partners in Afghanistan and are in the application pipeline &#8212; so translators, interpreters, others, their family members who are in the process.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are approximately 20,000 Afghans who have applied. So, those are the individual interpreters or translators; that does not include their family members. And about half that have completed the necessary paperwork to move forward in the process.<br>&nbsp;<br>I believe, also, the State Department is going to do a more thorough briefing, but I&#8217;ll just go through as many details as I can from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Once individuals &#8212; this is how the process works &#8212; once individuals are approved through the security vetting process &#8212; which their paperwork conclusion does not conclude it; there&#8217;s another vetting process they would conclude &#8212; they may be eligible under humanitarian parole.<br>&nbsp;<br>Under that parole, a lot &#8212; a large portion of that group could be relocated directly to a military base in the United States where they would receive medical checkups.<br>&nbsp;<br>Those who have not yet completed their background checks would first be relocated from Afghanistan to either a U.S. military base overseas or to third countries, where they will be safely housed until their visa processing is complete and they can be transferred to the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note we are not considering any location or place for the third-party countries that would not be safe, would not treat them with respect, and not &#8212; would not ensure that they are treated humanely through the journey of their process.<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, on our vetting process &#8212; this is a thorough process. There are some of these individuals who have completed their paperwork and are in through the vetting process. Their family members may not be in the same stage of the vetting process, so that may have an impact too of the timeline and how &#8212; not the timeline, but of, kind of, how they&#8217;re moved and where they are moved to.<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; and the third par- &#8212; the third-country move would be temporary until they finalize their paperwork and security vetting process is complete.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that is a little bit more detail on the process. Hopefully, that helps.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Alex.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; President &#8212; former-President Bush yesterday, in an interview, criticized the withdrawal, and he said he&#8217;s very concerned about the Afghan women. So what is the U.S. going to do to ensure the safety of those women in Afghanistan after we leave?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I would say that the President agrees that we need to ensure we are continuing to support &#8212; through humanitarian programs, through security programs &#8212; the women of Afghanistan. And we certainly respect the right of the former President to voice his view on &#8212; on Afghanistan and the President&#8217;s decision.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s not a secret that President Biden and President Bush haven&#8217;t seen eye to eye on matters relating to the use of military force. So, we respect his right to voice his opinion; we just disagree.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that while we continue to provide security and humanitarian assistance, we also intend to have a diplomatic presence on the ground to continue to be a source and resource for individuals in Afghanistan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; And, just secondly, Senator Manchin is quite upset about some of the climate provisions in the 3.5 trillion package. Is the White House reaching out to him? Is it &#8212; is the White House prepared to move off of some of that &#8212; lessen the &#8212; some of the provisions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, we, of course, are in touch with Senator Manchin, I can assure you, as we are in touch with a number of senators who will be &#8212; who have been pivotal partners and will continue to be moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think there was &#8212; one of the concerns I think I saw expressed &#8212; but tell me if this is what you were asking about &#8212; is fossil fuels. Is that the specific piece?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: So, while of course the pa- &#8212; the plan and the package will go a long way in addressing the climate crisis &#8212; and that is a huge priority to the President, ensuring that these tax credits are in the reconciliation bill, which is something that did not make it into the bipartisan deal, is something the President has advocated for. And we&#8217;re eager, of course, to pivot to a clean energy future.<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t intend to do so just by &#8212; just by banning fossil fuels or leaving any working community behind. And what we&#8217;d certainly convey to any concerned individuals is that President Biden has formed an interagency working group to mobilize federal investments to support hard-hit coal, oil, and gas, and power plant communities across the country. That working group has already identified 30 billion in existing federal resources that could be accessed by communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t want to lose &#8212; leave communities behind. We still think we can move forward in addressing our climate crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Steve.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; A follow-up to that &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: First day of your presidency. Congratulations, I think?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you very much. No, it’s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s &#8220;congratulations&#8221;; it seems hard to make. Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; “Thank you” when it’s over. (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>I wanted to ask a follow-up to Alex&#8217;s question, and that is: How does the President see his role in the negotiation on the reconciliation bill? Is he an intermediary between some of the more liberal elements of his party and Senator Manchin? Is he a closer? Is he directly involved in this? He went up to Capitol Hill yesterday. What&#8217;s he going to be doing in the weeks ahead?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: He&#8217;s going to be available for whatever is needed to get these bills across the finish line. And a lot of the discussions are happening, certainly, at a staff level. As you all know, we have a number of very experienced individuals here who have gotten a lot of bills across the finish line: Steve Ricchetti, Ron Klain, Louisa Terrell, and many beyond them. They are playing a big role &#8212; Brian Deese &#8212; in discussing and having conversations with members.<br>&nbsp;<br>A lot of the discussions, though, are primarily between the Democratic members themselves about what the final package and the final details look like. Leader Schumer and his team will put out the final details on &#8212; on the timeline that works for them.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I will tell you: The President is available. He&#8217;s ready. He&#8217;ll pick up the phone. He&#8217;ll host people. He&#8217;ll have snacks, drinks &#8212; whatever is needed in order to get these bills across the finish line. And I think leaders in Congress certainly know that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Oh, go ahead, Brian.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thanks. Thank you very much. Two questions. One, to follow up on inflation. Inflation surged to 5.4 percent in June &#8212; its the largest jump since 2008. You all say it&#8217;s temporary, but today Axios is reporting the JPMorgan Chase CEO is saying, “I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s only temporary,” and that it&#8217;s a little worse than the Fed predicts. Now, there&#8217;s a disparity there. How are you going to address what they think may be permanent?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, I would say, first, that many outside experts, including the Federal Reserve &#8212; even if JPMorgan or Jamie Dimon or whomever it is disagrees &#8212; have projected that the &#8212; that the rise of inflation is transitory and have projected a lowering of inflation next year.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also have seen in the data that some of the issues &#8212; and I outlined this a little bit earlier, like the spike in car prices, which we know has a bigger issue &#8212; has another issue involved in it, which is the supply chain issues which we&#8217;re trying to separately address &#8212; or hotels and some of the &#8212; of the industries that &#8212; related to travel that have seen increases because the economy is turning back on.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we certainly will refer to economic experts out there, the Federal Reserve, and many others who have projected the transitory nature of this, as well as what we see as a number of the factors that are leading to the impact currently.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; The second question is about Jeff Flake. Earlier this week, he was nominated to the President to go to Turkey as our envoy. That ambassadorship is &#8212; that&#8217;s a problematic area. What is it exactly in the former senator&#8217;s background that gives this administration confidence that he can carry out his task there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, he&#8217;s a former member of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee &#8212; someone who played an important role in discussing, debating, and &#8212; and working on a range of foreign policy issues as &#8212; in his role as a former U.S. senator. So that is a pretty good basis.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay. Francesca, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. I have a foreign policy question.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Just to stay on inflation for a moment: What is the White House&#8217;s message to average Americans, including those who are limited income, though, who are experiencing higher prices right now for food and clothing and other goods and services. You mentioned that it’s expected to die down next year, but what is your message to them in the meantime? Is it simply just to wait it out?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: That&#8217;s certainly not what I&#8217;ve ever said, but I will say our message is that we understand the threat that inflation poses. We will be vigilant about any responses needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s important for Americans to know and understand that these impacts are temporary and some of these price increases are a result of the economy turning back on. And experts will tell you that &#8212; whether it&#8217;s the hotel industry or the airline industry going back to pre-pandemic prices.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll also note that the President has taken a number of steps, including ensuring that the vast majority of the American people were getting $1,400 checks, getting the Child Tax Credit out to people&#8217;s bank accounts today, because he knows that Americans need a little extra help &#8212; still need a little extra help as the economy turns back on. So he&#8217;s committed to helping working people, and it&#8217;s also important for people understand the transitory nature of inflation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; And can you provide a status update on investigative assistance for Haiti? And also, when can the public expect the administration to make a determination on whether it&#8217;s changing its policy towards Cuba?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure. I don&#8217;t have anything for you on the timeline on Cuba policy. I will note that we certainly look at the policy through the prism of how we can most help the Cuban people &#8212; the people who have been out in the streets looking to have their voices heard in these protests.<br>&nbsp;<br>And even as we look at individual components of policies that would be under consideration &#8212; including, say, remittances &#8212; there are a range of factors. There are a number, of course, of people who have called for a return for allowing remit- &#8212; remittances to go from family members to individuals in Cuba.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the flip side of that, or one of the challenges is: the prevention or our desire to prevent remittances or any funding going in the hands or the pockets of leaders in Cuba.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, these are challenging issues. There&#8217;s an ongoing review. I don&#8217;t have a timeline to preview for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of Haiti &#8212; let me see. I do think I have a little bit of an update for you. Let me see what I have for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve provided a couple of updates of what we&#8217;ve provided. So, I &#8212; just in case you don&#8217;t have this. The FBI is providing investigative assistance to the Haitian authorities at the request of the government of Haiti. They remain committed to working alongside our international partners to administer justice. That was a specific ask.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re also continuing to provide ongoing security assistance and &#8212; and consultations, as they have also requested. We&#8217;re still working with leaders in Haiti to refine their requests, and that review is ongoing. We&#8217;re in regular touch. And as we have additional components to provide, we&#8217;ll share that with all of you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; I think we have to wrap.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Okay. Let&#8217;s &#8212; go ahead. One more. One more.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. I &#8212; two quick ones. So, first &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Uh &#8212; yeah, I know. I &#8212; we’re wrapping. It&#8217;s like a last one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; &#8212; Senate and House &#8212; Senate and House Democrats say that they want to put citizenship halfway into the reconciliation package. Is the White House supportive of that strategy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Okay. And then &#8212; can I squeeze in my last one &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; since that was so fast?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure. That was an easy one. Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Okay, so the &#8212; Florida’s governor and some FEC commissioner in Miami, representatives are calling on Biden to greenlight a plan that would allow the deployment of higher altitude communication balloons to beam Internet into Cuba. Is this something the administration plans to do? And if not, why not?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Well, the lack of Internet access, as you know, which is why you&#8217;re asking, is a huge issue in Cuba and one that is very challenging for the people of Cuba so they can gain access to accurate information, they can correspond with family members and others.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are certainly looking at that to see what can be done to address, but in terms of that specific proposal, I don&#8217;t have an assessment of that. I can see if there&#8217;s more specifics on it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Okay. Thanks, everyone. Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:53 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/fact-sheet-u-s-germany-climate-and-energy-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 22:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden and Chancellor Merkel today at the White House launched the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership. As part of our ongoing work together on addressing the threat of climate change, this Partnership will strengthen climate ambition and deepen our collaboration on the policies and sustainable technologies needed to accelerate the global net-zero future. Both&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden and Chancellor Merkel today at the White House launched the U.S.-Germany Climate and Energy Partnership. As part of our ongoing work together on addressing the threat of climate change, this Partnership will strengthen climate ambition and deepen our collaboration on the policies and sustainable technologies needed to accelerate the global net-zero future. Both countries are committed to achieving the goals of the Paris Agreement and taking decisive action this decade to keep a 1.5-degree Celsius temperature limit within reach. We share the goals of leading the world to develop the innovative tools urgently needed to accelerate global climate action and achieve net-zero greenhouse gas emissions in their economies by 2050 at the latest. The United States and Germany will invest in a sustainable economy that drives inclusive growth, supports communities, and creates good jobs and a healthy environment on both sides of the Atlantic and beyond.<br><br>The Climate and Energy Partnership will be co-chaired from the U.S. side by the Special Presidential Envoy for Climate and the Secretary of Energy, and from the German side by the Minister for Economic Affairs and Energy and the Minister for the Environment, Nature Conservation and Nuclear Safety, with participation from the U.S. Department of State, Germany’s Ministry of Foreign Affairs, and other agencies or ministries as appropriate.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States and Germany intend the Partnership to include three key areas of cooperation:&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Climate Action: The United States and Germany will push to raise global climate ambition and work bilaterally and multilaterally to accelerate reaching a net-zero future. </strong>We will develop actionable roadmaps and policies for near-term and long-term reduction of emissions to keep a 1.5-degree Celsius limit in sight; coordinate on climate and trade agendas; mobilize finance for sustainable development; advance sectoral decarbonization and address short-lived climate pollutants; and coordinate on common interests in multilateral fora including the Conference of the Parties of the UN Framework Convention on Climate Change, and the climate tracks in the G20, and G7.<br><br><strong>Transformational Energy Technologies: The United States and Germany will collaborate on developing and deploying critical energy technologies.&nbsp; </strong>We will advance renewable energy technologies and grid integration of variable renewable energy including through energy storage; collaborate on sustainable hydrogen technologies; cooperate on efficiency measures across the building and industrial sectors; increase the adoption of electric vehicles; promote technology commercialization from research institutions to industry; advance reliable and resilient energy systems and supply chains; cooperate on advanced sustainable energy systems while promoting inclusivity, supporting communities, and strengthening the workforce; and coordinate in multilateral energy fora including the energy tracks in the G20 and G7, Mission Innovation, Clean Energy Ministerial, International Energy Agency, and IRENA.<br><br><strong>Energy Transitions in Emerging Economies: The United States and Germany will collaborate to accelerate sustainable energy in emerging economies critical to tackling the climate crisis and preventing the use of energy as a coercive tool.&nbsp; </strong>We will mobilize investment in Central and Eastern Europe, including by supporting Ukraine’s energy transformation, energy efficiency, and energy security; mobilize investment in sustainable energy in major and growing emitters around the world such as those in South and Southeast Asia; develop energy policy and regulations for increased adoption of renewables and sustainable fuel alternatives like sustainable hydrogen; and pursue technology and technical assistance collaboration with major emerging economies to speed decisive action to curb emissions this decade and enable swift net-zero transitions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Washington Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/washington-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 22:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President of the United States and the Chancellor of Germany affirm their commitment to close bilateral cooperation in promoting peace, security, and prosperity around the world. The foundation of our relationship is a shared commitment to democratic principles, values, and institutions.&#160;Together, we will uphold the rule of law, promote transparency and good governance,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President of the United States and the Chancellor of Germany affirm their commitment to close bilateral cooperation in promoting peace, security, and prosperity around the world.</p>



<p><strong>The foundation of our relationship is a shared commitment to </strong><strong>democratic principles, values, and institutions.</strong>&nbsp;Together, we will uphold the rule of law, promote transparency and good governance, and support civil society and independent media. We will defend the rights and dignity of all individuals, and counter injustice and inequality wherever it occurs. We uphold the universal values at the heart of the United Nations Charter and stand together in our commitment to promote respect for human rights everywhere, including by rejecting and responding in concert to violations of human rights. We must act now to demonstrate that democracy delivers for our people at home and that democratic leadership delivers for the world.</p>



<p><strong>We commit ourselves to defending an open world.</strong> Across the globe, all nations must be free to determine their political futures free from foreign interference, coercion, or domination by outside powers. As two nations whose economies depend on the free transit of goods around the world, we affirm the critical importance of the freedoms of navigation and overflight and other lawful uses of the sea, consistent with international law. This vision is unachievable in a world carved into competing spheres of influence and we will resist attempts to create them, be it through attempts at territorial annexation, control of digital infrastructure, transnational repression, or weaponized energy flows.</p>



<p><strong>More than three decades after German reunification, we will continue to work tirelessly for a Europe that is whole, free, and at peace.</strong> Where outside powers present barriers to the realization of this vision, we will join together to collectively strengthen our defense, cultivate our resilience, and enhance our solidarity. NATO will remain the cornerstone of this effort, and our commitment to Article 5 is ironclad. We underscore the need to build upon our alliances and partnerships for the challenges that lie ahead – including cyber threats, energy security, disinformation, corruption, democratic backsliding, and interference in our elections.</p>



<p><strong>We will work together to ensure that the rules, norms, and standards that govern emerging technologies are channeled toward freedom rather than repression. </strong>As technology reshapes our citizens’ lives, our national economies, and our geopolitical environments, it must reflect our core democratic values. We will deepen cooperation between our scientists, engineers, and mathematicians to ensure that the major innovations of this century advance democratic governance, rather than authoritarianism. States need to protect the rights of citizens, and we will resist the use and spread of surveillance technologies to improperly restrict the exercise of human rights.</p>



<p><strong>We recognize our responsibility to lead in the development of global solutions to shared challenges.&nbsp;</strong>Our citizens’ lives are subject to disruption by a range of international forces that demand a collective response. We are committed to taking urgent action to address the climate crisis, including by launching the Climate and Energy Partnership to deepen collaboration on the policies and energy technologies needed to accelerate the global net-zero transition. We will work to strengthen global health and health security, including resilience against future pandemics. We will work tirelessly toward a sustainable global economic recovery, constructed on a fair, inclusive, sustainable, rules-based global economy for the 21st century. With shared strength and ingenuity, we will innovate novel solutions to these novel challenges – and work together bilaterally, as well as in the G7 and G20, to ensure the multilateral system, including the UN system, can meet the demands of our time.</p>



<p>Since the end of World War II, countless people from all walks of life – including business and science, civilian and in uniform, civil society organizations, think tanks and academic networks – have strengthened and deepened the bond between our two nations. As a lasting demonstration of our bilateral relationship and our commitment to the above principles, we are launching a U.S.-German Futures Forum that will fully utilize the expertise and innovative power of our societies and recommend solutions to jointly shape our future. To facilitate cooperation on crucial economic issues, we will also establish a U.S.-German Economic Dialogue.<br><br><strong>Joseph R. Biden, Jr.</strong><br><strong>Angela Merkel</strong><br>July 15, 2021</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-25/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 19:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Richard Trumka Jr., of Maryland, to be a Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission for a term of seven years from October 27, 2021, vice Robert S. Adler. &#160; &#160; &#160;Alvin Harlyn Warren, of New Mexico, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Richard Trumka Jr., of Maryland, to be a Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission for a term of seven years from October 27, 2021, vice Robert S. Adler.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Alvin Harlyn Warren, of New Mexico, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for National and Community Service for a term expiring October 6, 2023, vice Hyepin Christine Im, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;James A. Diossa, of Rhode Island, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation for a term expiring October 3, 2024, vice Harvey M. Tettlebaum, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Terrence Keith Wright, of Delaware, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation for a term expiring May 29, 2025, vice John J. Faso, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Rahul Gupta, of West Virginia, to be Director of National Drug Control Policy, vice James W. Carroll Jr.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jeffry Lane Flake, of Arizona, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Turkey.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kent Doyle Logsdon, of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Moldova.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Atul Atmaram Gawande, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Alma L. Golden.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Gabriel Camarillo, of Texas, to be Under Secretary of the Army, vice James E. McPherson.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Chester John Culver, of Iowa, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation, vice Charles A. Stones.</p>



<p>     Alan F. Estevez, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, vice Mira Radielovic Ricardel, resigned.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden to Mark the Day That Tens of Millions of Families Will Get Their First Monthly Child Tax Credit Relief Payments Thanks to the American Rescue Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/15/remarks-by-president-biden-to-mark-the-day-that-tens-of-millions-of-families-will-get-their-first-monthly-child-tax-credit-relief-payments-thanks-to-the-american-rescue-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 19:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 12:27 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Well, for you &#8212; anybody under the age of 13 &#8212; this has got to be boring, boring, boring for you.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Right?&#160; Well, I’ll tell you what, we have to work something out here so that when this is over, your parents, your uncles,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>12:27 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, for you &#8212; anybody under the age of 13 &#8212; this has got to be boring, boring, boring for you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Well, I’ll tell you what, we have to work something out here so that when this is over, your parents, your uncles, your aunts &#8212; whoever you’re with &#8212; they owe you some ice cream or something for this.&nbsp; You know?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Folks, it’s a pleasure to be here.&nbsp; I’m going to take a sip here.&nbsp; (Drinks water.)&nbsp; And this &#8212; I believe this is actually a historic day &#8212; a historic day in the sense that we continue to build an economy that respects and recognizes the dignity of working-class families and middle-class families.&nbsp; It&#8217;s historic and it&#8217;s our effort to make another giant step toward ending child poverty in America.&nbsp; I think this will be one of the things that the Vice President and I will be most proud of when our terms are up.<br><br>Beginning this morning, nearly all working families &#8212; that is people making under $150,000 as families or an individual making under $120,000 &#8212; $125,000 who have children, are raising children in America, they’re going to receive their first monthly &#8212; first monthly tax cut payment.&nbsp; That payment &#8212; that payment from the expanded Child Tax Credit that we signed into law as part of my &#8212; our American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s one of the largest-ever single tax cuts for families with children, and it&#8217;s a reflection of our belief that the people of this country who need a tax cut aren&#8217;t the folks at the top.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve got plenty of tax cuts.&nbsp; They’re doing just fine.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s the people in the middle, the folks who are struggling, who are just looking for a little bit of &#8212; my dad would say, “a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; A little bit of breathing room.<br><br>This has the potential to reduce child poverty in the same way that the Social Security reduced poverty for the elderly.&nbsp; And by the way, you think of monthly payments &#8212; you get a Social Security check &#8212; those who you know get Social Security, they get it monthly.&nbsp; Well, this will be &#8212; unless you want it in one lump sum, this would be a monthly payment for childcare &#8212; for &#8212; excuse me, for your children, a tax cut.&nbsp;<br><br>And here&#8217;s how the tax credit works: For every child under the age of six, a parent will get $3,600 a year.&nbsp; For every child 6 to 17, they&#8217;ll get $3,000 per year.&nbsp; For example, a middle-class family with two young children would expect to receive $7,200 a year to help raise their children.&nbsp; This will be the &#8212; they&#8217;ll get the first half of this $3,600 starting today.&nbsp; Today.&nbsp; Today.&nbsp; And it’ll be paid out at $600 a month between now, July, and December.&nbsp; And then they’re going to get the rest of the payment next spring around Tax Day.<br><br>Now, if you file taxes electronically, you can go to your bank account today &#8212; today &#8212; and you&#8217;ll see a payment that says “Child CTC.”&nbsp; Let me say that again: payments of $300 for each child under the age of 6, $250 for each child between the ages of 6 and 17 on a monthly basis between now &#8212; between July and December.&nbsp;<br><br>If you don’t file electronic- &#8212; your taxes electronically, as you did last year, you can expect to receive a check in the mail beginning today or a few days from now.&nbsp; And you’ll get this payment on the 15th of every month for the rest of this year.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you’re not required to file taxes at all in the past &#8212; you haven’t filed because you didn’t owe any taxes, then you can go to: ChildTaxCredit.gov.&nbsp; Let me say it again: ChildTaxCredit.gov.&nbsp; And you will give you &#8212; they’ll give you clear information and a link to help you sign up for the first time.&nbsp; This can be lifechanging for so many families.&nbsp;<br><br>Because of the way the tax credit was structured before the American Rescue Plan, more than 26 million children from the hardest-pressed working families didn’t get any full payment for the Child Credit &#8212; for childcare &#8212; for Child Tax Credit.&nbsp; Half of all Black and Hispanic children in America never received the full tax credit.&nbsp; We’ve changed all that.<br><br>In technical terms, we’ve made this tax cut fully refundable.&nbsp; In plain English, it means instead of families who need help the most getting the le- &#8212; getting the least, the hard-working &#8212; the hard-working families will get this on a month- &#8212; full monthly basis.&nbsp;<br><br>Ninety-seven percent of the children receiving this credit come from working families.&nbsp; And the other 3 percent includes kids being raised by retired grandparents or by someone with a serious disability.<br><br>And by the way, this credit doesn’t start to phase out until a couple is making $150,000 or a single parent is making <s>$112,000</s> [$112,500].&nbsp; It begins to phase out then.&nbsp; This is a middle-class tax cut.&nbsp; When I came up &#8212; when I decided I wanted this in the legislation, I referred to it in the way it really is: It’s a middle-class tax cut.&nbsp; It’s just like the wealthy get tax cuts for a lot of things, this is a tax cut for your children &#8212; having children.<br><br>And this can make it possible for a hardworking parent to say to his or her child, “Honey, we get &#8212; you can get your new braces now.&nbsp; We can get you a tutor to help you in that math class you’re having trouble with.&nbsp; We can get you the sports equipment you need to sign up to &#8212; for your first team you’re going to play on.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>People have written me to tell me they’ll use the money to buy their kids new shoes, to send them to summer camp, to cover afterschool care when school starts up again.&nbsp;<br><br>You know &#8212; and to give you a sense of how transformative this is:&nbsp;This would be the largest-ever one-year decrease in child poverty in the history of the United States of America &#8212; as we begin now. &nbsp;Historic reductions in child poverty among white, Black, and Latinos, and AAPI communities. &nbsp;It’s not even close. &nbsp;The benefits will be felt for years.<br><br>Studies have shown &#8212; (a baby cries) &#8212; that tax relief that helps children &#8212; that’s okay, don’t worry about it.&nbsp; It’s okay to let him cry, or her, whichever &#8212; that helps children and can lead to better health, better school performance, and better future earnings.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, research from Columbia University in New York found that for each dollar this tax cut costs, it returns eight dollars in benefit down the line.&nbsp; Eight dollars would have to be spent other ways.&nbsp; It’s a gigantic help.&nbsp; It’s an eight to one return.&nbsp;<br><br>Your head, your heart, and your budget all lead to the same place.&nbsp; This is the right thing to do, and it’s the smart thing to do.<br><br>Today, these tax cut payments are arriving automatically.&nbsp; But it didn’t happen automatically &#8212; the result of the work that people who did this, advocating for this for a long, long time.&nbsp; And we finally got it passed in my American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to particularly thank those who have been fighting for this for years: Congresswoman Rosa DeLauro from Connecticut.&nbsp; She has been a champion for this issue.&nbsp; Congressman Richie Neal and &#8212; and Torres.&nbsp; And Senators Bennet, Brown, and Booker.&nbsp; And Ron Wyden.&nbsp;<br><br>You’ll probably hear from our Republican friends &#8212; all who voted against this &#8212; but they’ll tout the success as it helps working families in their states and their districts.&nbsp; But in the coming days, we’re also going to hear from them saying, “I want to now extend this tax…”&nbsp; It’s only for one year now.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s all I could get it for, for the first time.&nbsp; And so, I want to extend it into the future now.&nbsp; I have another piece of legislation that will be voted on soon, saying we’re going to continue this.<br><br>To the people who say we can’t afford to give the middle class a break, I say: We can afford it by making people at the top and the big corporations &#8212; over 50 of which paid no taxes last year at all &#8212; to finally just &#8212; just start paying their fair share.&nbsp; I’m not going to gouge them.&nbsp; Just pay their fair share.&nbsp; Because people who are working hard and paying taxes deserve a break.<br><br>That’s why &#8212; excuse me for all these terms I’m using, but my Build Back Better agenda, which still needs to be voted on in the Congress, keeps this tax cut for working families in place for years to come.&nbsp; We shouldn’t let taxes go up on working families.&nbsp; We shouldn’t let child poverty continue to stain the conscience or drag down our economy.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I say to my colleagues in Congress: This tax cut for working families is something we should extend, not end, next year.<br><br>And I say to all of you watching: Make sure your family, friends, and community know about this tax cut.&nbsp; Send to them, as I said, ChildTaxCredit.gov to learn more about the difference this is going to make in their lives.<br><br>Let me close with this: I signed the American Rescue Plan less than two months after taking office on January 20th.&nbsp; Four months later, we’ve implemented the fir- &#8212; we’ve implemented the first-ever automatic monthly payment for any major tax credit ever, as the Vice President was talking about, beyond Social Security, which was a long time ago.<br><br>This groundbreaking effort is similar to what we did in our &#8212; what I called our “war-time effort” to vaccinate Americans against COVID-19, to mobilize the whole country.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re proving &#8212; we’re proving that democracy can deliver for people, and deliver in a timely way &#8212; saving lives, improving lives, helping fuel a recordsetting recovery, giving working families a fighting chance again.&nbsp;<br><br>I received an email today from a mother in Washington State.&nbsp; She’s a young teacher who had just received her payment.&nbsp; She wrote, and I’m quoting, “My family has been living hand to mouth to put me through school so I can follow my passion of molding young minds…&nbsp; This first CTC payment has come at the exact moment when we need it most.&nbsp; These payments may seem small to some, but they are lifechanging for my family, for us.”&nbsp;<br><br>Millions of children and their families &#8212; starting today, their lives are about to change for the better.&nbsp; And our country will be better off for it as well.&nbsp;<br><br>This is a really good day.&nbsp; And parents are going to be able to tell your kids when they’re 25-years-old that you were there the day this happened; we talked about it.&nbsp; We are showing once again that there’s nothing beyond the capacity &#8212; our capacity as Americans to get done when we do it together.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I want to thank you.&nbsp; God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; And kids, thank you for being so polite while I was speaking.&nbsp; You’re very, very nice.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>See you all.&nbsp; Bye bye.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>12:39 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How the Build Back Better Framework Will Support Women’s Employment and Strengthen Family Economic Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/15/fact-sheet-how-the-build-back-better-framework-will-support-womens-employment-and-strengthen-family-economic-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite the progress our nation has made over the last four months, there remain two million fewer women in the workforce than there were before the pandemic struck – taking a toll on our economy and on millions of families across the country. Thirty years of progress in women’s labor force participation has been eroded;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Despite the progress our nation has made over the last four months, there remain two million fewer women in the workforce than there were before the pandemic struck – taking a toll on our economy and on millions of families across the country. Thirty years of progress in women’s labor force participation has been eroded; millions of women are still struggling to return to the workforce.&nbsp;And while the pandemic has exacerbated this reality, many of the challenges facing women aren’t new. Historically, women have typically held jobs with lower wages and fewer benefits and protections. Women of color are even more likely to work in jobs that have lower wages and few benefits and protections.<br><br>Our economic recovery depends on addressing longstanding discrimination and barriers that have hampered women—including women of color—from fully participating in the labor force. One economist finds the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2021/05/11/perspectives/biden-build-back-better/index.html">President’s plan</a>, and especially its investments in the care economy, would increase labor force participation by almost a full percentage point—with even greater gains for women—and boost the economy’s real GDP growth by 10 to 15 basis points in the long-term. Increasing women’s labor force participation is also critical to supporting America’s working families, including the over 4 in 10 mothers – disproportionately women of color – who are sole or primary breadwinners for their families, contributing significantly to their families’ total earnings.<br><br>When women are better off, we’re all better off. The Build Back Better Agenda rests on our commitment to ensuring every American is given a fair shot to get ahead in this country. It will strengthen our families, our communities, and our nation by making bold and necessary investments in women’s employment and ensure a broad and deep recovery – one on which the success of the entire U.S. economy rests. Our economy cannot reach its full potential when half of the population is forced to leave their jobs, cut back on their hours, or unable to access good jobs. These issues are not simply women’s issues. They are issues that affect all families, our economy’s stability and growth, and our nation’s competitiveness.<br><br><strong><u>Supporting Women’s Caregiving Needs</u></strong></p>



<p>Too many American women struggle with the high costs of raising children, caring for a sick family member, providing long-term care for people with disabilities or older adults, and addressing the myriad other caregiving challenges. Although professional care is costly for families, caregivers themselves &#8211; <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat18.htm">disproportionately women of color &#8211;</a> remain some of the <a href="https://equitablegrowth.org/working-papers/the-wages-of-care/">most underpaid workers</a> in the country, often having to rely on public income supports to get by. And, many American women fill the gap in professional caregiving options by providing unpaid care to their loved ones, often causing them to reduce working hours, choose lower-paying jobs, or leave the labor force entirely.<br><br>In&nbsp;part&nbsp;due to the <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w18702">lack of family friendly policies</a>, the United States has fallen behind its competitors in the share of women in the labor force. The United States is one of the only countries in the world that does not guarantee paid leave &#8212; <a href="https://www.bls.gov/ncs/ebs/benefits/2020/employee-benefits-in-the-united-states-march-2020.pdf">95 percent of the lowest wage workers</a>, who tend to be <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/meet-the-low-wage-workforce/#:~:text=Low-wage%20workers%20comprise%20a%20substantial%20share%20of%20the,the%20most%20likely%20to%20be%20raising%20children%20%2843%25%29.">predominately&nbsp;women&nbsp;</a>and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nationalpartnership.org/our-work/resources/economic-justice/paid-leave/paid-family-and-medical-leave-racial-justice-issue-and-opportunity.pdf">workers of color</a>, lack any access to paid family leave. Only 57 percent of children under six years old have parents who report there are good choices for child care where they live. And, <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/system/files/pdf/265126/LTSSOlAmRB.pdf">high costs</a> and increasing <a href="https://books.google.com/books?id=AtYpDwAAQBAJ&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;source=gbs_ViewAPI#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false">shortages</a> of care for disabled and elderly people leave many to rely on unpaid caregiving – more than one in six adult women are unpaid eldercare providers. <a href="https://www.aarp.org/content/dam/aarp/livable-communities/old-learn/health/metlife-study-of-caregiving-costs-to-working-caregivers-2011-aarp.pdf">One study</a> estimates that women who leave the labor force early to care for elderly parents lose $330,000 [1]&nbsp;in lifetime wages and Social Security benefits.<br><br>Research shows <a href="http://oro.open.ac.uk/50547/1/care_economy_en.pdf">investments in the care economy</a> would increase employment, especially for women, reducing the gender employment divide. Not only would this support women’s economic security, it would lead to a more robust and equitable economy. The President’s Build Back Better plan:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Creates a National Comprehensive Paid Family and Medical Leave Program</strong>.&nbsp;The program will ensure workers receive partial wage replacement to take time to bond with a new child; care for a seriously ill loved one; deal with a loved one’s military deployment; find safety from sexual assault, stalking, or domestic violence; heal from their own serious illness; or take time to deal with the death of a loved one. This program guarantees twelve weeks of annual paid parental, family, and personal illness/safe leave, and also ensures workers get three days of bereavement leave per year. The program will provide workers up to $4,000 a month, with a minimum of two-thirds of average weekly wages replaced, rising to 80 percent for the lowest wage workers. In California, one study&nbsp;found that the state’s paid leave law increased new mothers’ likelihood of working a year after the birth of their child by <a href="https://equitablegrowth.org/factsheet-what-does-the-research-say-about-the-economics-of-paid-leave/">18 percentage points</a>. In addition <a href="https://journals.lww.com/greenjournal/Citation/2021/04000/Association_Between_Rhode_Island_s_Paid_Family.26.aspx?context=LatestArticles">recent</a> <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32134836/">research</a> shows that in the short term, paid family leave policies are associated with positive health outcomes including <a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w25902">better maternal physical health</a>, infant mortality, improved infant attachment and childhood development. Paid family leave encourages men and women to take <a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1002/pam.21894">time off</a>. This is crucial in an economy in which <a href="https://www.thirdway.org/report/the-fatherhood-bonus-and-the-motherhood-penalty-parenthood-and-the-gender-gap-in-pay">fatherhood increases men’s wages</a> and motherhood decreases women’s (by four percent per child), exacerbating the gender wage gap.<br></li><li><strong>Guarantees access to high-quality, affordable child care for low- and middle-income families and offers universal free preschool to all three- and four-year old children</strong><strong>.</strong>&nbsp;President Biden’s Build Back Better plan offers free, high-quality preschool to all three- and four-year old children, fully covers the cost of high-quality child care for young children for the most hard-pressed working families, and ensures that families earning up to 1.5 times their state’s median income will pay no more than 7 percent of their income for all children under age five. This is estimated to increase labor force participation of these parents, and especially women, by up to 20 percent. The President’s plan would also make permanent the dramatic expansion of the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit (CDCTC) enacted in the American Rescue Plan. With this expanded credit, families can receive up to half of what they spend on child care for children under age 13, up to a total of $4,000 for one child or $8,000 for two or more children. In addition to reducing the cost of child care and freeing up money for other spending, child care and preschool programs also increase mothers’ incomes, as mothers continue working and earn more over time.<br></li><li><strong>Expands Access to Long-Term Care Services under Medicaid. </strong>In addition to caring for children, families feel the financial burden of caring for aging relatives and family members with disabilities, and there is a financial strain for people with disabilities living independently to ensure that they are getting care in their homes. At the same time, hundreds of thousands of people who need better care are unable to access it, even though they qualify under Medicaid. Aging relatives and people with disabilities deserve high-quality care that meets their unique needs and personal choices. President Biden is calling on Congress to put $400 billion toward expanding access to quality, affordable home- or community-based care. One <a href="https://scholar.harvard.edu/files/kshen/files/caregivers.pdf">recent study</a> finds that for every 2.4 to 3 women whose parent receives formal home care through Medicaid, one additional daughter works full-time.<br></li><li><strong>Boosts compensation of child care and home care workers.</strong> About nine in ten care workers are women, and nearly <a href="https://nwlc.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ChildCareWorkersFS.pdf">five in ten</a> child care workers are women of color. As of 2020, the median <a href="https://www.bls.gov/ooh/personal-care-and-service/childcare-workers.htm">child care worker</a> made $12.24 per hour and the median <a href="https://www.bls.gov/ooh/healthcare/home-health-aides-and-personal-care-aides.htm">home health and personal care aide</a> made $13.02 an hour. On average, child care workers make <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/child-care-workers-arent-paid-enough-to-make-ends-meet/">23 percent below</a> workers who do not work in child care. The President’s plan would ensure child care and preschool teachers are paid at least $15 an hour and comparable to kindergarten teachers if they have similar credentials. The President’s plan to expand HCBS under Medicaid will support well-paying caregiving jobs that include benefits and the ability to collectively bargain. Investment in higher labor standards for care workers improve these jobs and supporting the economic security of women who fill them, help close the gender pay gap, and attract more workers to the care industry.<br></li><li><strong>Addresses Maternal and Infant Health Disparities</strong>. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling health disparities that are rooted in bias and systemic racism. America’s maternal mortality rates are among the highest in the developed world, and they are especially high among Black women and Native American women— regardless of their income or education levels. The Build Back Better proposal would make health insurance for women who buy it on their own more affordable by making the American Rescue Plan’s premium reductions permanent, saving women $600 a year. It also includes a $3 billion investment to improve maternal and infant health outcomes. Growing and diversifying the perinatal workforce, improving data collection to better understand the causes of maternal death and complications from birth, and investing in community-based organizations are priorities of this Administration.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Strengthening Family Economic Security</u></strong></p>



<p>When households do not have enough income, they are forced to make impossible trade-offs between paying for rent, education, healthcare, and food. These choices have consequences and limit the investments made in oneself and one’s children. The Build Back Better agenda makes significant investments to increase household stability and economic security.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Supports the construction or rehabilitation of over 1 million affordable rental housing units in building and small towns across the country. </strong>Before the pandemic, HUD estimated that nearly 5 million female-headed households that didn’t receive federal housing assistance paid more than half their income in rent or lived in severely inadequate units. The Build Back Better plan would bolster funding for successful housing subsidy programs to produce and preserve housing that is affordable for very- and extremely-low income renters.<br></li><li><strong>Addresses longstanding public housing capital needs.</strong> Nearly two million people across the country live in public housing. Approximately 75 percent of households living in public housing units are headed by women, and 33 percent of all households are headed by women with children. Nearly half of the nearly 1 million units of public housing are over 50 years old and many contain lead paint, mold, and other health hazards. The President’s plan calls for a transformative investment of $40 billion to rehabilitate and preserve public housing, addressing residents’ critical health and safety concerns. This is not just a safety issue but a racial justice issue, as approximately three in four public housing residents are people of color.<br></li><li><strong>Extends the Expanded Monthly Child Tax Credit</strong>. The Build Back Better proposal would extend the Child Tax Credit (CTC) expansion first enacted in the American Rescue Plan – increasing the credit from $2,000 per child to $3,000 per child six-years-old and above, and from $2000 to $3,600 per child for children under six. This means a monthly payment of&nbsp;$300 per month per child under 6 and $250 a month for each child six and older. Parents can use this tax credit on everything from diapers, to putting more food on the table, to paying the rent or mortgage. An <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/american-rescue-plan-act-includes-critical-expansions-of-child-tax-credit-and">estimated 66 million children</a> (90 percent) and their parents will benefit from this tax credit expansion including 9 million Black children and 18 million Latino children.<br></li><li><strong>Supports nutrition security</strong>. Nutrition insecurity has a negative and lasting impact on a child’s ability to learn and can put children at higher risk for diseases such as diabetes, heart disease, and high blood pressure. However, provide adequate nutrition can be an incredible financial burden for parents. The Build Back Better plan will expand free meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year. Additionally, the plan will invest more than $25 billion so that the families of all 29 million children eligible for free and reduced-price school meals will receive a $75 per child per month benefit to purchase nutritious foods during the summer.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Expanding Education, Training, and Job Opportunities for Women</u></strong></p>



<p>The&nbsp;Build Back Better agenda will ensure that the economy is built on a foundation of equity, by strengthening the education and workforce pipeline for more women to obtain high-quality in-demand jobs. These workforce development investments are based on evidence-based approaches to supporting workers, including women and people of color. Some of these approaches include wraparound services –such as child care and transportation – income supports, counseling, and case management, paired with high-quality training and effective partnerships between educational institutions, unions, and employers. These investments will ensure jobs have fair and equal pay, safe and healthy workplaces, and that workplaces are free from racial, gender, and other forms of discrimination and harassment. They will also help more women enroll in college, reduce their need to rely on student debt, and ensure they have the supports they need to complete their training program, certificate or degree.<br><br>The President’s Build Back Better plan:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protects the health, safety and rights of working women.</strong>&nbsp;This includes jobs with fair and equal pay, safe and healthy workplaces, and workplaces free from racial, gender, and other forms of discrimination and harassment. In addition to a $10 billion investment in enforcement as part of the plan’s workforce proposals, the President is calling for increased penalties when employers violate workplace safety and health rules. President Biden is also calling on Congress to ensure all workers have a free and fair choice to join a union by passing the Protecting the Right to Organize (PRO) Act. Unions benefit women’s wages;&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/union2.t02.htm">in 2020</a>, the median weekly earning of full-time workers 16+ was $1,067 for women who are members of unions, $1,057 for women who are represented by unions, and $862 for non-union women. His plan also ensures domestic workers receive the legal benefits and protections they deserve and tackles gender pay inequities.<br></li><li><strong>Invests in gender equitable workforce development programs and creates new career pathways for women.</strong> As more Americans <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/CLF16OV">rejoin</a> the workforce or <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/carolinecastrillon/2021/05/16/why-millions-of-employees-plan-to-switch-jobs-post-covid/?sh=13afaf2b11e7">seek out new opportunities</a> in a changing economy, we must ensure workers have ready access to the skills they will need to succeed, and improve racial and gender equity. This includes registered apprenticeships and pre-apprenticeships, creating one to two million new registered apprenticeships slots, and making these opportunities accessible to underserved populations, including women and people of color, through successful pre-apprenticeship programs, such as Women in Apprenticeship and Non-Traditional Occupations grants that help to expand pathways for women to enter and lead in all industries. It also includes sector-based training programs that provide millions of workers, including women and people of color, with in-demand training that leads to high-quality jobs in high-growth and critical industries and sectors including information technology, clean energy, public health, home care and child care, manufacturing and infrastructure. The President’s plan also creates a new subsidized jobs program that will invest in the creation of hundreds of thousands of subsidized employment opportunities for workers adversely affected by the economic crisis, especially public assistance recipients, long-term unemployed individuals and the underemployed. These investments also include the creation of career pathway programs in middle and high schools, prioritizing increased access to computer science and high-quality career and technical programs that connect underrepresented students to STEM and in-demand sectors through partnerships with both institutions of higher education and employers.<br></li><li><strong>Increases the affordability of, access to, and student success in education beyond high school. </strong>Women constitute <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/ipeds/TrendGenerator/app/build-table/2/2?rid=1&amp;cid=13">more than half</a> of all college students. At the same time, <a href="https://iwpr.org/iwpr-issues/student-parent-success-initiative/parents-in-college-by-the-numbers/">a number of women in higher education are raising children while pursuing a certificate or degree, often at community colleges. More than 20 percent</a> of all college students are parents; of those, over 70 percent are mothers and 43 percent are single mothers. Only <a href="https://iwpr.org/iwpr-issues/student-parent-success-initiative/investing-in-single-mothers-higher-education-state/">8 percent</a> of single mothers who entered college between 2013 and 2017 earned a degree or certificate within six years, compared to 49 percent of women students who were not parents. Additionally, women are more likely to face financial barriers while in college. They are about <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/fastfacts/display.asp?id=900">seven percentage points</a> more likely to take out federal loans than men, and have more federal student loan debt on average. Increased financial support for college <a href="https://direct.mit.edu/edfp/article/15/1/164/10312/Does-Broad-Based-Merit-Aid-Improve-College">can</a> <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0047272720301171?via%3Dihub">boost</a> completion rates. Increased financial support for college can boost completion rates. The President’s $109 billion plan will ensure that first-time students and workers wanting to reskill can enroll in a community college to earn a degree or credential for free. The President is calling for a $39 billion investment in tuition subsidies to increase affordability at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and Minority-Serving Institutions. The plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by approximately $1,500 and allows DREAMers to access Pell Grants. This will support the 43 percent of women in college who rely on Pell to afford their higher education goals. Finally, the President is proposing a bold $62 billion grant program to invest in completion and retention activities at colleges and universities that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges, which can be used for student support services that include child care.<br></li><li><strong>Advances equity in research and development and science, technology, engineering, and math</strong>. Discrimination leads to less innovation: one study found that innovation in the United States would quadruple if women, people of color, and children from low-income families invented at the same rate as other groups. Persistent inequities in access to R&amp;D dollars and to careers in innovation industries prevents the U.S. economy from reaching its full potential. The President’s plan includes $10 billion in new grants to HBCUs and MSIs, in addition to, funding for research infrastructure (ex. labs) and funding for equity in STEM education.<br></li><li><strong>Helps small businesses, including women-owned businesses and minority business enterprises, access capital and scale through over $30 billion in investments</strong><strong>.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden is calling on Congress to invest in federal programs that empower small firms to participate in federal research and other research and development initiatives that have the potential for commercialization. His plan will also support new grantmaking through the Minority Business Development Agency that will help small businesses owned by people of color access private capital. And, it will enable small businesses to drive the economic recovery by investing in the Small Business Administration’s 7(a) loan program and Small Business Investment Company program.<br></li><li><strong>Invests in teachers. </strong>For too long, we have underinvested in our teachers, <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/clr">76% of whom</a> are women. From teachers in training to veteran teachers, the President’s plan invests $9 billion in teachers, addressing teacher shortages, recruiting more teachers of color, improving teacher preparation and supporting teachers. The plan would invest in innovative and effective teacher training programs like residencies, that provide future teachers with a year of experience before they take charge of a classroom, double the annual scholarship for future teachers from $4,000 to $8,000 per year, and help schools leverage their expert teachers as mentors supporting new and struggling teachers, or as leaders in other areas, and compensate them for this work. All of these policies will disproportionately benefit women.</li></ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />



<p>[1] The study, which uses data from 2008, finds a loss of approximately $274,044 in 2008 dollars. This number is adjusted for inflation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
