<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 18:26:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Caribbean-American Heritage Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-caribbean-american-heritage-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 18:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54400</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America&#8217;s strength has always been rooted in our diversity.  Since our Nation&#8217;s founding, generation after generation of immigrants have helped build this country, and the prosperity and opportunity that draw so many immigrants to America would not be possible without the contributions and legacies of Caribbean Americans.  Today, millions of Caribbean Americans strengthen our country&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America&#8217;s strength has always been rooted in our diversity.  Since our Nation&#8217;s founding, generation after generation of immigrants have helped build this country, and the prosperity and opportunity that draw so many immigrants to America would not be possible without the contributions and legacies of Caribbean Americans.  Today, millions of Caribbean Americans strengthen our country through their vibrant cultures, traditions, languages, and values.  In recognition of National Caribbean-American Heritage Month, we honor the immeasurable ways Caribbean Americans have added to our American dream. </p>



<p>This month, our Nation also celebrates the extraordinary leadership and achievements of Vice President Kamala Harris, the first Black American of Jamaican heritage to hold this high office.  I am also honored to celebrate alongside brilliant and dedicated public servants of Caribbean heritage &#8212; including Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona, Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas, and Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice. </p>



<p>Every day, we see the invaluable contributions Caribbean American communities have made to our country.&nbsp; Our Nation has seen the persistence and character of generations of Caribbean Americans who have fought for equity and equality despite continued discrimination and hardship.&nbsp; In addition, public servants like our Nation&#8217;s first Supreme Court Justice of Puerto&nbsp;Rican descent, Sonia Sotomayor, and the late General Colin Powell, the son of Jamaican immigrants and the first Black&nbsp;Secretary of State, have made essential contributions to American society and blazed new trails in service to the American people.&nbsp; Caribbean American entrepreneurs, scientists, medical professionals, teachers, artists, police officers, athletes, and contributors in every field have also left a&nbsp;lasting impact on our society.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In spite of innumerable achievements and undeniable contributions, too many Caribbean Americans continue to face systemic barriers to success.&nbsp; Caribbean Americans have been impacted by systemic racism and disparities in opportunity.&nbsp; My&nbsp;Administration has taken a whole-of-government approach to advancing racial justice and equity in order to begin healing those wounds and strengthening opportunity for all.&nbsp; We will continue to use every tool at our disposal to ensure that every American &#8212; no matter who they are or where they come from &#8212; has equal access to the American dream.</p>



<p>During this National Caribbean-American Heritage Month, we&nbsp;honor the generations of Caribbean Americans who have built our Nation, shaped our progress, and strengthened our national character.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim June 2022 as National Caribbean-American Heritage Month.&nbsp; I encourage all Americans to join in celebrating the history, culture, and achievements of Caribbean Americans with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Ocean Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-ocean-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 18:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; From the air we breathe to the food we eat, our magnificent ocean touches every aspect of our lives. &#160;It helps regulate the climate, supports millions of jobs, and serves as a place for exploration, commerce, and recreation. &#160;As it sustains and connects us, the ocean is woven into the cultures of local and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; From the air we breathe to the food we eat, our magnificent ocean touches every aspect of our lives. &nbsp;It helps regulate the climate, supports millions of jobs, and serves as a place for exploration, commerce, and recreation. &nbsp;As it sustains and connects us, the ocean is woven into the cultures of local and Indigenous coastal and island communities. &nbsp;During National Ocean Month, we celebrate the beauty and bounty of our ocean and reaffirm our commitment to protecting and conserving our marine environments for a sustainable future.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fifty years ago, our Nation enacted laws that created a robust foundation for environmental protection: &nbsp;the Clean Water Act, the Coastal Zone Management Act, the Marine Mammal Protection Act, and the National Marine Sanctuaries Act. &nbsp;Through these laws, we have protected our coastlines, safeguarded marine wildlife, sustained fisheries, and improved water quality. &nbsp;Today, the United States is a global leader in protecting and using precious marine resources in a responsible and sustainable way &#8212; but there is still more work to be done.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Earlier this year, my Administration released a sobering report on sea level rise caused by climate change. &nbsp;Addressing this issue requires collaboration and commitment. &nbsp;Working with State, Tribal, Territorial, and local partners, we will co-develop ocean-based climate solutions, including the United States Ocean-Climate Action Plan, which will help us mitigate and adapt to the effects of the climate crisis.&nbsp; To guide our understanding of the ocean, coasts, and climate change, we must also invest in science and solutions that recognize and elevate Indigenous and local knowledge.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is a critical step forward in providing resources to enhance ocean and coastal observation, mapping, and forecasting &#8212; tools that will greatly improve the resilience of our coastal infrastructure and shorelines.&nbsp; The Natural Capital Accounts and National Nature Assessment I announced on Earth Day will also help us understand the ocean&#8217;s value to our economy, health, climate, and national security. &nbsp;My Administration is developing a National Ocean Plan to develop the ocean economy and create good-paying American jobs while protecting vital marine ecosystems. &nbsp;Toward that aim, we are already deploying offshore wind energy and joining international initiatives to manage the planet&#8217;s ocean equitably and sustainably.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are also working to restore coastal habitats and ecosystems with nature-based solutions that protect coastal communities from flooding and storms. &nbsp;These investments go hand-in-hand with my Administration&#8217;s America the Beautiful Initiative, which set a national goal to voluntarily conserve and restore at least 30 percent of United States lands and waters by 2030.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In taking these steps, we recognize that access to our ocean and its benefits have not always been equally distributed. &nbsp;Communities of color, Indigenous communities, and low-income communities have often been shut out from ocean-related opportunities while shouldering disproportionate climate burdens.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to delivering climate justice, expanding access to ocean opportunities, and diversifying ocean workforces.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During National Ocean Month, as we celebrate the beauty and power of our ocean, let us remember our shared responsibility to protect and preserve it.&nbsp; Together, let us recommit to caring for our ocean and enhancing its economic and ecological sustainability for generations to come.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as National Ocean Month. &nbsp;I call upon Americans to take action to protect, conserve, and restore our ocean and coasts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Homeownership Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-homeownership-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 18:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; &#160;For many Americans, a home is more than just a residence. &#160;It is a place that instills a sense of pride, security, and comfort that, no matter what challenges in life arise, they have somewhere to go and call their own. &#160;Whether owning or renting, a home is where we can live with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;For many Americans, a home is more than just a residence. &nbsp;It is a place that instills a sense of pride, security, and comfort that, no matter what challenges in life arise, they have somewhere to go and call their own. &nbsp;Whether owning or renting, a home is where we can live with dignity and watch our families grow. &nbsp;During National Homeownership Month, we recognize the importance of housing and reaffirm our commitment to ensuring that everyone has a place to call home.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Every American should be able to afford to rent or own a home of their own.&nbsp; Yet across the country, the price of housing &#8212; both for renters and homebuyers &#8212; is increasing, making it harder for people to find an affordable home.&nbsp; Our Nation is facing a housing shortage that is driving up prices &#8212; and with housing prices near record highs, too many families are unable to make other important investments, such as furthering their education or saving for retirement.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Throughout the pandemic, my Administration has helped people who have struggled, through no fault of their own, stay in their homes by providing financial relief to help pay the mortgage or the rent.&nbsp;&nbsp;To tackle the root causes of housing affordability, my Administration released a Housing Supply Action Plan, aimed at closing the nationwide shortfall of housing for purchase and rent in 5 years through a variety of measures: &nbsp;incentivizing States and localities to create the conditions for more housing, improving financing tools for a wider range of housing arrangements, enhancing existing forms of financing for housing construction, and addressing other barriers to housing supply and affordability, such as supply chain issues due to the pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;My budget also includes investments to address the critical shortage of affordable housing and provide first-generation down payment assistance to&nbsp;aspiring homeowners.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Homeownership is a major source of generational wealth for many Americans &#8212; it is a central part of the American dream. &nbsp;But for too many Americans &#8212; especially Black and Brown Americans &#8212; homeownership and the opportunity to build and pass down wealth through it are unattainable. &nbsp;Longstanding inequities in the housing system, from disinvestment to redlining and mis-valuation of homes in communities of color, have locked out entire generations from the American dream and the opportunity to build generational wealth.&nbsp; Housing also opens up opportunities that are tied to where one lives, and it is our shared responsibility to ensure that everyone has equitable access to those opportunities &#8212; from education and stable employment to quality health care and healthy food.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is committed to ending unlawful housing discrimination and advancing equity for underserved communities.&nbsp; Toward that aim, we have launched an aggressive effort to combat racial discrimination in housing.&nbsp; I also remain committed to expanding access to homeownership opportunities for first-time home buyers and minority homebuyers while ensuring that Black and Brown families receive a fair appraisal for their homes. &nbsp;Through the Property Appraisal and Valuation Equity Action Plan, we have developed the most wide-ranging set of Federal reforms in history to ensure that the color of a person&#8217;s skin does not determine the value of their home.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;As we mark National Homeownership Month, we recognize the importance of housing for all Americans. &nbsp;Whether owning, renting, or aspiring to do either, we renew our commitment to lowering costs and expanding access to safe, affordable homes that all Americans need and deserve.&nbsp;&nbsp;Together, we can ensure that every American has a safe place to call home.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as National Homeownership Month. &nbsp;I&nbsp;call upon the people of this Nation to safeguard the American Dream by ensuring that everyone has access to an affordable home in a community of their choice.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/31/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-jacinda-ardern-of-new-zealand-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 11:15 A.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, good morning, everybody. &#160;And it’s good to see a not-so-old but a good friend here.&#160; Prime Minister, welcome to the White House.&#160; And we last saw each other at the launch of the Indo-Pacific Framework &#8212; PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&#160; Yes. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; &#8212; which is, I think,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>11:15 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, good morning, everybody. &nbsp;And it’s good to see a not-so-old but a good friend here.&nbsp; Prime Minister, welcome to the White House.&nbsp; And we last saw each other at the launch of the Indo-Pacific Framework &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; which is, I think, a fairly big deal for all of us, and we need your guidance.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re &#8212; and, you know, it&#8217;s a pleasure to see you in person.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You understand that your leadership has taken on a critical role in this global stage &#8212; and it really has &#8212; galvanizing action on climate change; the global effort to curb violence, extremism, and online, like happened in Christchurch.</p>



<p>And &#8212; you know, we want to be &#8212; I want to work with you on that effort.&nbsp; And I want to talk to you about what those conversations were like, if you&#8217;re willing.</p>



<p>The United States is, you know &#8212; it’s just been &#8212; there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s an expression by an Irish poet that says, “Too long a suffering makes a stone of the heart.”&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s an awful lot of suffering.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been &#8212; I &#8212; I&#8217;ve been to more mass shooting aftermaths than, I think, any President in American history, unfortunately.&nbsp; And it’s &#8212; it’s just &#8212; so much of it is &#8212; much of it is preventable, and the devastation is &#8212; is amazing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday &#8212; or not &#8212; the day before, I was up &#8212; I was down in Texas.&nbsp; And people sat in a room &#8212; about 250 of them in a large room &#8212; with me for almost four hours.&nbsp; Not &#8212; nobody left.&nbsp; They waited until aft- &#8212; until I spoke to every single person in that room.&nbsp; Every single person, they waited to the very end.&nbsp; And the &#8212; they &#8212; the pain is palpable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you’ve been one of our closest partners with a long history and friendship.&nbsp; Eighty years ago, Marines landed in New Zealand before embarking on &#8212; into the Pacific Theater in World War Two.&nbsp; And I think I told you, when I met my &#8212; my &#8212; two of my mother&#8217;s brothers who were in the Pacific &#8212; they used to be able to deploy at the same time in those days, in World War Two.&nbsp; And one was shot down in New Guinea.&nbsp; And they never found the body.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, it’s &#8212; the history goes back a long way &#8212; a long way.</p>



<p>And I want to, by the way, recognize New Zealand’s significant support for Ukraine, as a lot of Indo-Pacific countries are doing now.&nbsp; And &#8212; because this is more than just a regional war going on.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I look forward to our conversations today.&nbsp; We have a lot to talk about.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m really, really delighted to have you here &#8212; really.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And can I say, Mr. President, thank you, so much &#8212; so much &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You &#8212; you can do anything you want.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And we really welcome this opportunity.</p>



<p>As you&#8217;ve said, we&#8217;ve spoken on several occasions.&nbsp; And what stood out to me on both those occasions were we traversed such similar issues, and not &#8212; not least, of course, our shared history.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You speak of your uncle&#8217;s service in the Pacific; my grandfather served in the Pacific.&nbsp; And I think that speaks to the personal connection but also the depth of our friendship and relationship as two countries.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are in an incredibly difficult international environment.&nbsp; But also, domestically, it is extraordinarily challenging as well.&nbsp; And can I bring the sincere condolences of the people of Aotearoa New Zealand for what you have experienced in Texas and in New York?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s been devastating to see the impact on those communities.</p>



<p>Our experience, of course, in this regard, is our own.&nbsp; But if there&#8217;s anything that we can share that would be of any value, we are here to share it.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, the work you’re doing with tech companies is really important, and I want &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Absolutely.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; to work with you there as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; And I absolutely look forward to updating you on some of the conversations we&#8217;ve had this week because I hold hope that we can make progress.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also wanted just to acknowledge your leadership in bringing to the table the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp; And whilst, of course, we are significant advocates for the CPTPP, the IPEF presents a significant opportunity to build the economic resilience of our region.&nbsp; So, I look forward to having a bit of a discussion about that opportunity as well.</p>



<p>I also want to acknowledge your significant leadership on Ukraine and how important that has been not only to us as we&#8217;ve looked to play a role as well, but globally as we look to make sure that we strengthen the international response to what is a threat to our values and, of course, the territorial sovereignty of Ukraine.</p>



<p>I do want to finish on a note of optimism.&nbsp; Climate change also is one of the greatest threats that we face.&nbsp; And I believe that, in you, not only have we seen the leadership but the opportunity that exists between our nations to work together on this incredibly difficult issue that will only be resolved if we work together.</p>



<p>So, thank you.&nbsp; With &#8212; as you&#8217;ve seen, we&#8217;ve got a lot to discuss, so &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We’ve got a lot to do.&nbsp; And I want to emphasize the last point you made: “working together.”</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Absolutely.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We are not coming to dictate or lay down the law.&nbsp; We &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; we have more work to do in those Pacific Islands as well.&nbsp; I mean, we’ve &#8212; and so, we talked at length about &#8212; in the past about my trip to Japan and Korea and then dealing with the Quad.&nbsp; And so &#8212; but I think there&#8217;s a lot of opportunity &#8212;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; Yeah, I agree.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; to make the world safer and deal with the environment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ARDERN:&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp; So, thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, will you meet with Senator McConnell on guns?&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I will meet with the Congress on guns.&nbsp; I promise you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>11:22 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United&#160;States – Aotearoa New Zealand Joint&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/31/united-states-aotearoa-new-zealand-joint-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A 21st-Century Partnership for the Pacific, the Indo-Pacific, and the World President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is honored to welcome Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of Aotearoa New Zealand to the White House. The leaders reaffirmed the strategic partnership between the United States and New Zealand, as expressed in the 2010 Wellington Declaration and the 2012&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>A 21<sup>st</sup>-Century Partnership for the Pacific, the Indo-Pacific, and the World</em></p>



<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is honored to welcome Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of Aotearoa New Zealand to the White House. The leaders reaffirmed the strategic partnership between the United States and New Zealand, as expressed in the 2010 Wellington Declaration and the 2012 Washington Declaration.</p>



<p>Our peoples have served side-by-side to uphold international peace and security for over a century; 80 years ago, during the Second World War, U.S. Marines arrived in New Zealand before embarking for the Pacific theatre. Together we honor that history of shared resolve in the face of aggression, in the pursuit of peace, and in our common respect for sovereignty, territorial integrity, and the peaceful resolution of disputes. We note that, since then, our ties have broadened and deepened, founded on shared values of democracy, fundamental freedoms, and the rule of law. Today, President Biden and Prime Minister Ardern committed to advance our longstanding partnership to meet 21<sup>st</sup>-century challenges: bolstering security and building resilience, including to climate change, in the Pacific; promoting prosperity in the Indo-Pacific; and combatting the climate crisis and ensuring the responsible use of technology around the world.</p>



<p>We meet at a time of great challenge. The COVID-19 pandemic continues to wreak a human and economic toll, even as the climate crisis becomes ever more urgent. Technology brings both opportunity and threat, including the scourge of online radicalization to violence. The rules-based international order that has long been the foundation of peace and prosperity is under pressure.In the Indo-Pacific, we face a challenging landscape, where the values, norms, and rules that have fostered stability, growth, and prosperity in recent decades are under threat. In Europe, meanwhile, Russia continues to wage its unjustified and unprovoked war in Ukraine. Taken together, these challenges call for common purpose and action, across the Atlantic and the Pacific.</p>



<p><strong>I. Regional Architecture and Security</strong></p>



<p>Our partnership is global, but it is centered in the Indo-Pacific. The United States and New Zealand are committed to realizing a region of sovereign, resilient, and prosperous states, based on the international rules-based order, where states, including and especially small states, can pursue their interests free from coercion. This vision is reflected in the Indo-Pacific Strategy of the United States, which New Zealand welcomes; and in New Zealand’s Indo-Pacific policy as outlined by Prime Minister Ardern in 2021.</p>



<p>The United States and New Zealand share a strong commitment to the regional architecture. We jointly recognize the importance of a strong and unified Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) to an open, inclusive, stable, and prosperous Indo-Pacific. We reaffirm our strong support for ASEAN centrality and the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific. We value the Pacific Islands Forum, of which New Zealand is a member and the United States is a Forum Dialogue Partner, as the preeminent political regional body and a critical driver of Pacific regional cooperation, security, and stability. We appreciate that the Quad—the grouping of Australia, Japan, India, and the United States—plays an important role in delivering practical support to the region, including providing COVID-19 vaccines and improving maritime domain awareness. We note the shared commitment among New Zealand and AUKUS partners to the peace and stability of the Indo-Pacific region, and to upholding the international rules-based order.</p>



<p>We reaffirm our steadfast commitment to the Pacific Islands region, with a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum at the center. Prime Minister Ardern welcomed the United States’ decision to heighten its engagement with this vital region, reflected in its recent appointment of a Special Presidential Envoy for Compact Negotiations and its commitments to expand its physical diplomatic presence across the Pacific. President Biden resolved to raise U.S. ambition in partnering with the Pacific Islands still higher and to match that ambition with resourcing.</p>



<p>Throughout our engagement, the United States and New Zealand will continue to support the Pacific region’s own priorities, which will be reflected in the Forum’s upcoming 2050 Strategy for the Blue Pacific Continent. At the top of this agenda is addressing the climate crisis, which, as the Pacific Islands Forum’s <em>Boe Declaration</em> states, is the single greatest threat to the Pacific and the health and well-being of its residents. New Zealand and the United States also affirmed their commitment to an approach to Pacific fisheries that is led by Pacific countries, protecting the marine environment, livelihoods, traditions, food security, and economic benefits.</p>



<p>Our countries will expand our work in the Pacific on infrastructure, including transportation and information-communications technology; cyber security; maritime security, including combatting illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; education and skills training; COVID-19 pandemic assistance and global health security; and economic recovery. At the same time, we will promote democratic governance, free and fair elections, media freedom, and transparency; we will increase respect for human rights and the rule of law, and expand access to justice in Pacific countries, including through a new joint program to bolster the role of women in the justice sector. To best deliver these and other commitments in the Pacific, President Biden and Prime Minister Ardern committed to deepen coordination between the United States and New Zealand, and with other likeminded allies and partners, as we work together in support of Pacific priorities.</p>



<p>We are concerned with growing strategic competition in the Pacific region, which threatens to undermine existing institutions and arrangements that underpin the region’s security. The United States acknowledged that Pacific Islands Forum Members have a strong commitment to support one another to meet the broader ambitions for the region’s security, as set out in the <em>Biketawa Declaration</em> and <em>Boe Declaration</em>. We recognize that Pacific Islands Forum Members have worked hard together to meet one another’s security needs, and today have the capacity and commitment to continue doing so. In this regard, we note with concern the security agreement between the People’s Republic of China and the Solomon Islands. In particular, the United States and New Zealand share a concern that the establishment of a persistent military presence in the Pacific by a state that does not share our values or security interests would fundamentally alter the strategic balance of the region and pose national-security concerns to both our countries.</p>



<p>A freer and more open Indo-Pacific depends on preserving the international rules-based order in the maritime domain. To that end, we reaffirm our support for freedom of navigation and overflight, in the South China Sea and beyond, in accordance with the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS). We oppose unlawful maritime claims and activities in the South China Sea that run counter to the rules-based international order, particularly UNCLOS. We reiterate our grave concerns regarding the human-rights violations in Xinjiang, and the erosion of rights and freedoms in Hong Kong, which undermines the high degree of autonomy enshrined in the Sino-British Joint Declaration and the Basic Law. We underscore the importance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait and encourage the peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues.</p>



<p>We affirm our commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and urge the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) to abide by its obligations under United Nations Security Council (UNSC) resolutions and return to negotiations. The leaders jointly condemn the DPRK’s destabilizing ballistic missile tests this year, including multiple launches of intercontinental ballistic missiles, as clear violations of UNSC resolutions; they reaffirmed their commitment to work with the international community to address DPRK sanctions violations, including its illicit ship-to-ship transfers. We condemn the coup in Myanmar and the military’s brutal attacks on civilians. We continue to call for the immediate cessation of violence, the release of all who are unjustly detained, unfettered countrywide humanitarian access, and a swift return to democracy.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond the Indo-Pacific, the leaders strongly condemned Russian President Vladimir Putin’s invasion of Ukraine, which is in flagrant violation of international law. President Biden and Prime Minister Ardern discussed the financial and military support that both countries have provided to Ukraine, reviewed the ongoing application of sanctions our two countries have designed to deny the Kremlin the means to continue to prosecute its war in Ukraine, and considered what further measures could be taken to bolster the diplomatic effort. Alongside the European Union and international partners, our countries have condemned the campaign of disruptive and destructive cyber activity by Russia against Ukraine. And as food-exporting nations, we recognize the importance of ensuring that global supply chains for food and agricultural products remain free and open, and we are concerned by the severe impact of Russia’s attacks on civilian infrastructure and its blockading of Ukraine’s sea ports on global food security.</p>



<p>We highlight the importance of full implementation of the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty and look forward to working together to achieve a meaningful outcome at the forthcoming Review Conference.</p>



<p>Today, we acknowledge that security and defense will become an ever-more-important focus of our strategic partnership. We look to increase the interoperability of our forces, including through personnel exchanges, co-deployments, and defense trade. Achieving this vision will require robust and sustained commitment to defense in the Pacific. As New Zealand takes delivery of new capabilities, we will look for opportunities for combined operations and to expand our cooperation in other ways. As the security environment in the Indo-Pacific evolves, so must our defense cooperation.</p>



<p><strong>II. Indo-Pacific Prosperity</strong></p>



<p>The United States and New Zealand will deepen our economic ties, with each other and the region. Bilaterally, we intend to work together to promote growth in both our economies for the benefit of all our citizens, and to explore how we can expand bilateral trade and investment in order to strengthen the security of our supply chains and economic resilience. To that end, the United States and New Zealand will resume annual Trade and Investment Framework Agreement (TIFA) discussions.</p>



<p>Regionally, the United States and New Zealand look forward to working together to progress the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF), alongside 12 other founding partners: Australia, Brunei, Fiji, India, Indonesia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam. President Biden and Prime Minister Ardern warmly welcomed Fiji’s recent decision to join IPEF as a founding member—the first Pacific Island nation to do so.</p>



<p>We reiterate the value of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC)—which</p>



<p>New Zealand hosted in 2021 and the United States will host in 2023—as a forum for supporting trade and economic growth in the region in fulfilment of APEC Leaders’ vision for an open, dynamic, resilient, and peaceful Asia-Pacific Community. We reaffirm our joint commitment to rationalize and phase out inefficient fossil-fuel subsidies that encourage wasteful consumption, recalling the Glasgow Climate Pact and APEC Leaders’ commitment to this goal.&nbsp; In doing so, we recognize that inefficient fossil-fuel subsidies distort markets, disadvantage renewable and clean energy, and undermine efforts to deal with the threat of climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We intend to ensure that a free and open rules-based global trade system built on high standards and long-standing principles serves the interest of the citizens of both of our countries; to that end, we affirm our commitment to reform and strengthen the World Trade Organization (WTO), and to work together to secure outcomes that provide for meaningful disciplines at the upcoming 12<sup>th</sup> WTO Ministerial Conference.</p>



<p><strong>III. 21<sup>st</sup>-Century Challenges</strong></p>



<p>Our deepening ties are vital to our ability to meet transnational challenges. Climate change poses an existential threat, in our countries and around the world, with the potential for devastating impacts in the Pacific region. We are urgently pursuing efforts toward net-zero emissions in our economies and limiting global average temperature rise to no more than 1.5 degrees, and commit to enhanced collaborative engagement on climate-change issues. We will work together to accelerate the uptake of the technologies, innovation, and investment needed for our transition to productive, sustainable, and inclusive low-emissions economies. We commit to producing plans to reduce methane emissions to support national and global efforts under the Global Methane Pledge. We will enhance our efforts to support an empowered low-emissions transition and to address climate impacts in the Pacific, including by supporting activities that build the resilience and adaptive capacity of small island developing states. We will also enhance our efforts to ensure the environmental integrity of carbon markets, and to ensure the mutual supportiveness of trade and climate policy.</p>



<p>As maritime democracies, we will cooperate on ocean governance. We will work together on protection and sustainable use of the ocean; decarbonizing the shipping sector, including by supporting the establishment of green-shipping corridors; and promoting maritime security, including by combatting challenges such as illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing. We also intend to work together on complementary approaches to achieve the objective of protecting maritime zones from challenge in the face of sea-level rise, through continued dialogue between law-of-the-sea experts. Noting our longstanding and shared interest in protecting Antarctica as a place for peace and science, and our decades of research collaboration, we reaffirm our commitment to the principles and the letter of the Antarctic Treaty system.</p>



<p>President Biden and Prime Minister Ardern committed to helping end the acute phase of the COVID-19 pandemic while also working to prevent, detect, prepare for, and respond to future global health emergencies and pandemic threats. With key partners, the United States and New Zealand have delivered more than 200 million life-saving doses of vaccine to the Indo-Pacific region, and we continue our efforts to address new phases of the pandemic. We will accelerate progress on immunization and increase access to testing, therapeutics, oxygen, and other lifesaving measures to prevent hospitalizations and deaths. Both leaders commended the commitments made at the recent Global COVID-19 Summit. In addition to supporting the ongoing work of the World Health Organization and the ACT-Accelerator, Prime Minister Ardern committed to support in-principle the establishment of a global health security fund for pandemic preparedness and response. Both leaders also reaffirmed their strong support for the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria, including as an ACT-Accelerator partner, and its Seventh Replenishment later this year. We affirm the importance of strengthening the resilience and responsiveness of the global health architecture, and are committed to negotiations underway on a new instrument to strengthen pandemic prevention, preparedness, and response, with a strengthened World Health Organization able to fulfill its central and coordinating role in international health work. They are also committed to working together to improve elements of the existing system, such as the International Health Regulations.</p>



<p>We must also address the virus of hate, online and offline. The leaders emphasized the need to take action to keep our people safe from gun violence. The Prime Minister expressed her personal condolences to President Biden and to the American people for the tragedies in Uvalde, Texas and Buffalo, New York.</p>



<p>In the face of online radicalization to violence, we share a commitment to work together to ensure that technology is used in ways that promote and advance human rights. As supporters of the Christchurch Call, we pledge to continue our work alongside civil society and the technology sector to counter terrorist and violent extremist content online, including racially or ethnically motivated violent extremism, while promoting human rights online and a free, open, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure internet. We look forward to our countries participating in&nbsp;the Christchurch Call Leaders’ Summit in September this year, during which we intend to announce new measures to better understand and address online radicalization by promoting algorithmic transparency and data access, designing and implementing evidence-based interventions, optimizing and closing loopholes in&nbsp;crisis response, and advancing innovation by drawing on multi-stakeholder partners.</p>



<p>Even as we address the dangers of misuse of technology, we are committed to working together to protect and amplify its benefits. As supporters of the Declaration for the Future of the Internet, and members of the Freedom Online Coalition, the Open Government Partnership, and the Global Partnership on AI, we commit to pursuing multi-stakeholder approaches to support an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure internet and the responsible and ethical use of emerging technology. We will continue to work together to build strategies and share best practices to counter disinformation and misinformation, the spread of which threatens our democratic values and institutions. We also recognize the need for a diverse cohort of young people to help us navigate a digitally enabled future in line with our shared values. We plan to look for training and placement opportunities in both New Zealand and the United States to support young practitioners in science and technology broadly, and to deepen our digital technology partnership.</p>



<p>Online and offline, we will advance the rights of all people in our societies, including women, minorities, and Indigenous peoples. We share a fervent commitment to gender equity and equality. We recognize that online harassment and abuse, particularly when targeted at women activists, journalists, and political figures, undermines the strength of democracies; Prime Minister Ardern committed New Zealand to join the Global Partnership for Action on Online Gender-Based Harassment and Abuse. We reaffirm our commitment to promoting human rights and democracy and countering corruption and authoritarianism globally, including through the Summit for Democracy Year of Action.</p>



<p>The two leaders committed to strengthening the U.S.-New Zealand strategic partnership across all areas of space cooperation. They welcomed the finalization of our bilateral Space Framework Agreement, which will facilitate future collaboration between the United States and New Zealand on the uses of outer space for peaceful purposes. They also looked forward to the initiation of joint feasibility studies under the Framework Agreement in support of space exploration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For 80 years, our diplomatic relationship has benefited our countries, the region, and the world. But today’s world demands new resolve and closer cooperation between us. The United States and Aotearoa New Zealand will strengthen our strategic partnership to meet the challenges of the 21<sup>st</sup> century, seize the opportunities of an interconnected economy, and work together to preserve the international rules-based system on which our security, prosperity, and sustainability depends. As they reaffirmed our countries’ unique partnership, President Biden and Prime Minister Ardern recalled the words inscribed on the Marine Corps Memorial plaque in Wellington, New Zealand: “To the people of New Zealand: If you ever need a friend, you have one.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Releases Tribal Playbook, Announces Massive New Tribal Funding from Bipartisan Infrastructure&#160;Law</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/31/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-tribal-playbook-announces-massive-new-tribal-funding-from-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House released a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Tribal Playbook to help Tribal governments unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure, including the more than $13 billion set aside in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law for Indian Country.  The Tribal Playbook, found at build.gov, builds on the release of the Bipartisan&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House released a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Bipartisan-Infrastructure-Law-Tribal-Playbook-053122-.pdf">Tribal Playbook</a> to help Tribal governments unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure, including the more than $13 billion set aside in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law for Indian Country.  The Tribal Playbook, found at <a href="/Users/AVRajan/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/DVACGF6D/build.gov">build.gov</a>, builds on the release of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Guidebook and provides Tribal communities with information on the more specific Tribal funding available under the law, in addition to the hundreds of billions available to Tribes on a competitive basis.<br><br>President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will send billions of dollars to Indian Country to provide affordable high-speed internet, safer roads and bridges, modern wastewater and sanitation systems, clean drinking water, reliable and affordable electricity, and good paying jobs in every Tribal community. As part of this effort, the Biden-Harris Administration is also committed to working with Tribal communities to help them access federal resources.<br><br><strong>Major Tribal Funding Streams in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes"><table><tbody><tr><td>Program Name</td><td>Agency            </td><td>Funding                </td><td> Description</td></tr><tr><td><strong>IHS Sanitation Facilities Construction Program</strong></td><td>HHS</td><td>$3.5 B</td><td>Funding to build infrastructure necessary to ensure a safe supply of drinking water, reliable sewage systems, and solid waste disposal facilities.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Tribal Transportation Program</strong></td><td>DOT</td><td>$3.0 B</td><td>Funding to increase safety, mobility, and access for Tribal communities.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Indian Water Rights Settlements</strong></td><td>DOI</td><td>$2.5 B</td><td>Funding to satisfy Federal obligations under Indian water rights settlements reached as of November 15<sup>th</sup>, 2022.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Tribal Broadband Connectivity Program</strong></td><td>DOC</td><td>$2.0 B</td><td>Funding for an existing grant program that invests in broadband infrastructure, distance learning, telehealth, and activities that promote access and adoption of these services.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Clean and Drinking Water Grants</strong></td><td>EPA</td><td>$0.9 B</td><td>Funding for several programs at EPA to promote safe, healthy, and clean drinking water through State Revolving Funds.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Tribal Transportation Facility Bridges</strong></td><td>DOT</td><td>$0.8 B</td><td>Funding for planning, designing, engineering, replacing, improving, or constructing bridges on Tribal lands.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Safety of Dams</strong></td><td>DOI</td><td>$0.3 B</td><td>Funding for the Bureau of Indian Affairs to improve the safety of dams, water sanitation, and other facilities.</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Climate Adaptation and Community Relocation</strong></td><td>DOI</td><td>$0.2 B</td><td>Funding to pursue climate-resilient planning, and implement managed retreat, expansion, protect-in-place, and relocation options for threats associated with the climate change and environmental degradation</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Tribal Orphaned Wells</strong></td><td>DOI</td><td>$0.2 B</td><td>Funding to plug, cap, and remediate orphan oil and gas wells on Tribal lands.&nbsp;</td></tr><tr><td>TOTAL</td><td>&nbsp;</td><td>&nbsp;</td><td>&gt; $13 billion</td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p>&nbsp;“We are committed to ensuring Indian Country will benefit from this once-in-a-generation investment,” said <strong>Mitch Landrieu, Senior Advisor &amp; Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator.</strong> “Building a better America requires these funds to reach Tribal communities that have been left behind for far too long.&nbsp; The President sees you, and major investments are on the way.”</p>



<p>This week, the Administration made progress in getting massive sanitation and water investments moving through the Indian Health Service and Environmental Protection Agency.&nbsp;&nbsp; The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law appropriates $3.5 billion to the Indian Health Service to build the infrastructure necessary to ensure a safe supply of drinking water, reliable sewage systems, and solid waste disposal facilities. The funding will promote high-quality health care and disease prevention in Tribal communities. The first year, FY 2022, spend plan is estimated at $700M and will be shared with Tribal communities through a <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/05/31/ihs-allocates-700-million-dollars-from-president-bidens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-to-improve-tribal-water-sanitation-systems.html">Dear Tribal Leader Letter today</a>. EPA’s Office of Water will send another <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/biden-harris-administration-and-epa-announce-actions-improve-drinking-water-and">$154 million this year to Tribes for water projects</a> through its Drinking Water and Clean Water State Revolving Funds. This funding will go to projects that replace lead pipes and address harmful pollutants, among other eligible uses. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>To help coordinate these and other water and wastewater infrastructure funds, EPA has revitalized the Tribal Infrastructure Task Force (ITF) through a new Memorandum of Understanding between seven federal agencies. Signatories include:</p>



<ul><li>The U.S Department of Agriculture;</li><li>The Environmental Protection Agency;&nbsp;</li><li>The U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development;</li><li>The Department of the Interior, Bureau of Indian Affairs;</li><li>The Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation;</li><li>The Department of Health and Human Services, Indian Health Service; and</li><li>The Department of Health and Human Services, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</li></ul>



<p>In addition, the Departments of Transportation and Energy will also release funding for Tribal infrastructure that will increase road safety and power unelectrified buildings. Today, DOE issued a Notice of Intent for a <a href="https://ie-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaId61c91716-9750-4c55-bca4-197fd1f8edb1">$15 million investment</a> to support powering unelectrified Tribal buildings.&nbsp; Earlier this month, the Department of Transportation announced <a href="https://highways.dot.gov/sites/fhwa.dot.gov/files/images/FY21%20Tribal%20Transportation%20Program%20Safety%20Fund%20Awards_0.pdf">nearly $9 million</a> for the Federal Highway Administration’s Tribal Transportation Safety Program. Soon, they will announce the availability of an additional $120 million for the program over five years from Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</p>



<p>Since President Biden signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law six months ago, the Biden-Harris Administration has hit the ground running to deliver results. The Administration has made key progress towards implementing the largest long-term investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. More than $110 billion has been announced and allocated to states, Tribes, territories and communities from formula and competitive programs for roads and highways, bridges, ports, airports, electric vehicle charging stations, water systems, high speed internet, and weatherization.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of that, the Administration has announced the following Tribal programs:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Fulfilling Tribal Water Settlements:&nbsp;</strong>The Department of the Interior announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/tribes-receive-17-billion-president-bidens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-fulfill">$1.7 billion&nbsp;</a>to fulfill Indian Water Rights Settlements,&nbsp;which will break down barriers and help create conditions that improve water resources management by providing certainty as to the rights of all water users who are parties to the disputes.</li><li><strong>Powering Unelectrified Tribal Buildings:</strong> In May, the Department of Energy announced a Notice of Intent for <a href="https://www.energy.gov/indianenergy/articles/us-department-energy-set-announce-funding-opportunity-deploy-energy">$20 million</a> in funding for Tribal nations to deploy energy infrastructure or integrated energy systems to provide power to Tribal buildings not connected to traditional centralized electric power grids.<br></li><li><strong>Dam Safety Programs in Tribal Communities:&nbsp;</strong>In mid-May, the Department of the Interior announced <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-announces-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-investments-dam">$29 million</a> from the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) for its Power, Irrigation, and Safety of Dams programs. This is the first allotment of approximately $150 million the BIL will invest over the next five years to address safety deficiencies at four BIA dams.<br></li><li><strong>Tribal Water Systems:</strong>&nbsp;The Department of the Interior announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-announces-10-million-bipartisan-infrastructure-law">$10 million</a>&nbsp;for tribal water systems and another&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-announces-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-investments">$10 million&nbsp;</a>for irrigation and power in Indian Country.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Drought Resilience:</strong>&nbsp;The Department of the Interior announced awards of&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=902691252e&amp;e=a280d5f75f">$420 million for rural water projects</a>&nbsp;for drought resilience, and <a href="https://www.usbr.gov/newsroom/#/news-release/4205">$240 million for aging water infrastructure</a> through the Bureau of Reclamation. This investment in rural water systems includes work related to pipeline connections, construction of water treatment plants and intakes, pump systems, reservoir construction and other efforts to provide potable water to rural and Tribal communities.&nbsp;The Bureau of Reclamation also announced application periods for hundreds of millions of dollars in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding opportunities for water infrastructure, some of which are still open.&nbsp; Funding for the maintenance of aging infrastructure, and water recycling and desalination projects have been advertised, with more on the way during the rest of 2022.<br></li><li><strong>Watershed Infrastructure Projects:</strong>&nbsp;The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) announced nearly&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=3313334b91&amp;e=a280d5f75f">$600 million</a>&nbsp;in funding for projects that improve or rehabilitate watersheds, rehabilitate dams, and improve flood prevention through its Natural Resource Conservation Service, including some in Tribal communities.<br></li><li><strong>Tribal Climate Resilience:&nbsp;</strong>The Department of the Interior announced <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-announces-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-funding-build">$46 million</a> in funding to Tribal communities to address the unique impacts of climate change in Indigenous communities.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Pacific Coastal Salmon Recovery Fund</strong>:&nbsp;&nbsp;NOAA announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/grant/pacific-coastal-salmon-recovery-fund">$100 million for the Pacific Coastal Salmon Recovery Fund</a>,&nbsp;including $34.4 million from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which supports&nbsp;conservation efforts in California, Oregon, Washington, Idaho, and Alaska and is essential to preventing the extinction of the 28 listed salmon and steelhead species on the West Coast. &nbsp;The jobs and economic benefits of salmon restoration activities are largely realized in local and rural communities.<br></li><li><strong>Great Lakes Restoration:</strong>&nbsp;EPA announced&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=d63566ed7c&amp;e=a280d5f75f">$1 billion over five years for the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative</a>, including $200 million in FY2022,&nbsp;to accelerate progress in the clean-up and restoration of the Great Lakes’ most environmentally degraded sites, securing clean water and a better environment for millions of Americans in the Great Lakes region, including in Tribal communities.<br></li><li><strong>Tribal Internet:</strong>&nbsp;NTIA has made&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=5a9fc3ac26&amp;e=a280d5f75f">34 awards totaling approximately $83 million</a>&nbsp;in funding through the Tribal Broadband Connectivity Program. These awards are part of the Biden Administration’s whole-of-government effort to connect everyone in America with affordable, reliable, high-speed internet. &nbsp;The program, which is receiving an additional $2 billion in funding through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, is directed to Tribal governments to be used for broadband deployment on Tribal lands, as well as for telehealth, distance learning, broadband affordability, and digital inclusion.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding builds off the Administration’s historic investment in Tribal communities in the American Rescue Plan, with $32 billion allocated to Tribal governments, including $20 billion in State and Local Fiscal Recovery Funds—a historic financial level of support for over 580 Tribal governments and the largest amount of funding to Tribal governments in ARP. To date, Tribal governments have obligated funds to nearly 900 projects that address the negative economic impacts of COVID and over 1,800 other projects that are helping Indian Country recover and strengthen capacity.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, And Intersex Pride Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-queer-and-intersex-pride-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; During Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex (LGBTQI+) Pride Month, we reflect on the progress we have made as a Nation in the fight for justice, inclusion, and equality while reaffirming our commitment to do more to support LGBTQI+ rights at home and abroad.&#160; I often say that America can be defined&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; During Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex (LGBTQI+) Pride Month, we reflect on the progress we have made as a Nation in the fight for justice, inclusion, and equality while reaffirming our commitment to do more to support LGBTQI+ rights at home and abroad.&nbsp; I often say that America can be defined by one word: &nbsp;possibilities.&nbsp; This month, we celebrate generations of LGBTQI+ people who have fought to make the possibilities of our Nation real for every American.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, the rights of LGBTQI+ Americans are under relentless attack.&nbsp; Members of the LGBTQI+ community &#8212; especially people of color and trans people &#8212; continue to face discrimination and cruel, persistent efforts to undermine their human rights.&nbsp; An&nbsp;onslaught of dangerous anti-LGBTQI+ legislation has been introduced and passed in States across the country, targeting transgender children and their parents and interfering with their access to health care. &nbsp;These unconscionable attacks have left countless LGBTQI+ families in fear and pain. &nbsp;All of this compounded has been especially difficult on LGBTQI+ youth, 45&nbsp;percent of whom seriously considered attempting suicide in the last year &#8212; a devastating reality that our Nation must work&nbsp;urgently to address.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This month, we remind the LGBTQI+ community that they are loved and cherished. &nbsp;My Administration sees you for who you are &#8212; deserving of dignity, respect, and support. &nbsp;As I said in my State of the Union Address &#8212; especially to our younger transgender Americans &#8212; I will always have your back as your President so that you can be yourself and reach your God-given potential. &nbsp;Today and every day, my Administration stands with&nbsp;every LGBTQI+ American in the ongoing struggle against intolerance, discrimination, and injustice.&nbsp; We condemn the dangerous State laws and bills that target LGBTQI+ youth.&nbsp; And&nbsp;we remain steadfast in our commitment to helping LGBTQI+ people in America and around the world live free from violence. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since my first day in office, I have taken historic action&nbsp;to ensure that everyone &#8212; no matter who they are or whom&nbsp;they love &#8212; has an equal place in our democracy.&nbsp; I signed a landmark Executive Order charging the Federal Government with&nbsp;preventing and combating discrimination on the basis of&nbsp;sexual&nbsp;orientation and gender identity. &nbsp;This includes non‑discrimination protections for LGBTQI+ Americans in housing, health care, education, employment, credit and lending services, and the criminal justice system.&nbsp; My Administration has expanded access to inclusive passports for transgender Americans and instituted reforms to the traveler screening process at United&nbsp;States airports. &nbsp;We&nbsp;are supporting the open service for&nbsp;patriotic transgender military members and providing better services for LGBTQI+ veterans. &nbsp;I am honored by the service of the first openly gay Cabinet Secretary and the first transgender person confirmed by the Senate and to have been able to establish the first White House Gender Policy Council.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there is more work to be done. &nbsp;That is why I continue to call on the Congress to pass the Equality Act, which will enshrine long overdue civil rights protections and build a better future for all LGBTQI+ Americans. &nbsp;We must also fight for LGBTQI+ seniors so that they can age with dignity. &nbsp;And we must confront the disproportionate levels of poverty, homelessness, and unemployment in the LGBTQI+ community.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This month, we honor the resilience of LGBTQI+ people, who are fighting to live authentically and freely. &nbsp;We reaffirm our belief that LGBTQI+ rights are human rights. &nbsp;And we recommit to delivering protections, safety, and equality to LGBTQI+ families so that everyone can realize the full promise of America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Queer, and Intersex Pride Month.&nbsp; I call upon the people of the United States to recognize the achievements of the LGBTQI+ community, to celebrate the great diversity of the American people, and to wave their flags of pride high.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br>                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Great Outdoors Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-great-outdoors-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:09:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; During Great Outdoors Month, we celebrate our Nation&#8217;s vast array of parks, wildlife refuges, forests, monuments, marine sanctuaries, waters, national conservation lands, and other natural treasures. &#160;Every day, Americans across the country draw inspiration and pride from the beauty of our magnificent outdoor spaces. &#160;From lush forests in Washington State and coral reefs in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During Great Outdoors Month, we celebrate our Nation&#8217;s vast array of parks, wildlife refuges, forests, monuments, marine sanctuaries, waters, national conservation lands, and other natural treasures. &nbsp;Every day, Americans across the country draw inspiration and pride from the beauty of our magnificent outdoor spaces. &nbsp;From lush forests in Washington State and coral reefs in the Virgin Islands to snow-capped mountains in Alaska and rolling hills in Vermont &#8212; the grandeur of the American landscape fills our souls and fuels our spirit of adventure. &nbsp;These iconic and stunning natural wonders have always been central to our heritage as a people and essential to our identity as a Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Boundless outdoor spaces across the country unite Americans of every age and background for hiking, fishing, canoeing, hunting, exploring, reflecting, and finding solace.&nbsp;&nbsp;As part of my Administration&#8217;s efforts to advance equity, diversity,&nbsp;and inclusion,&nbsp;we are committed to ensuring that everyone can access and enjoy America&#8217;s great outdoors.&nbsp;&nbsp;Outreach efforts &#8212; including the National Park Service&#8217;s Rivers, Trails, and Conservation Assistance program &#8212; expand trails, conserve rivers, and restore green space so that more people can benefit.&nbsp;&nbsp;We are also enhancing safe outdoor resources for communities so that more people can participate in healthy, active outdoor recreation and enjoy the physical and spiritual nourishment it provides. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, our lands and waters face unprecedented threats from climate change that require historic action to safeguard and preserve them. &nbsp;That is why my Administration is setting ambitious environmental standards and making bold climate commitments for the United States:&nbsp; reducing greenhouse gas emissions by up to 52 percent by 2030, reaching 100 percent carbon pollution-free electricity by 2035, and achieving net‑zero emissions economy-wide by 2050.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Together with our State, Tribal, and local partners,&nbsp;we also launched the America the Beautiful Initiative, our Nation&#8217;s first-ever voluntary conservation goal, to conserve and restore 30 percent of America&#8217;s lands and waters by 2030.&nbsp; We also spearheaded a $1 Billion America the Beautiful Challenge, combining Federal investments with private and philanthropic contributions to accelerate land, water, and wildlife conservation and restoration efforts across the country.&nbsp; And we&nbsp;are making critical investments through the Great American Outdoors Act for land acquisition and community-based conservation and recreation projects in national parks, national forests, public lands, and Tribal schools.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Land and ocean conservation is a crucial part of addressing the world&#8217;s climate challenges. &nbsp;Proper stewardship protects the&nbsp;outdoors while contributing to sustainability, climate mitigation, and climate resilience. &nbsp;It is estimated that as much as one-third of the global emissions reductions needed to&nbsp;stabilize the world&#8217;s climate can come from natural climate solutions. &nbsp;That&#8217;s why I issued an Executive Order on Earth Day to strengthen our Nation&#8217;s forests, communities, and local economies, and to take stock of nature and its benefits.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During Great Outdoors Month, I encourage Americans to take time to experience the natural wonders across our Nation.&nbsp; As we&nbsp;enjoy the great outdoor landscapes and seascapes, let us each recommit to doing our part in their stewardship, preservation, and sustainable use so they continue to be a source of inspiration for outdoor enthusiasts for generations to come.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as Great Outdoors Month.&nbsp; I urge all Americans to explore the great outdoors, to experience our Nation&#8217;s natural heritage, and to continue our Nation&#8217;s tradition conserving our lands and waters for future generations.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Black Music Appreciation Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-black-music-appreciation-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Music has the power to lift our spirits, comfort our souls, and inspire our hearts. &#160;It gives a voice to the human spirit, creating a common language that unites people and breaks down barriers. &#160;Perhaps no music has had as profound and powerful an&#160;impact in shaping America&#8217;s musical score as Black music. &#160;Intricately woven&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Music has the power to lift our spirits, comfort our souls, and inspire our hearts. &nbsp;It gives a voice to the human spirit, creating a common language that unites people and breaks down barriers. &nbsp;Perhaps no music has had as profound and powerful an&nbsp;impact in shaping America&#8217;s musical score as Black music. &nbsp;Intricately woven into the tapestry of our Nation, Black music enriches our lives and pushes the boundaries of creativity. &nbsp;Throughout the decades and across the country, Black music has fueled a myriad of genres &#8212; from rhythm and blues to jazz, gospel, country, rap and more. &nbsp;This month, we celebrate the extraordinary legacy of Black music on American culture and recognize the indelible impact it continues to have on the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For generations, Black music has conveyed the hopes and struggles of a resilient people &#8212; spirituals mourning the original sin of slavery and later heralding freedom from bondage, hard truths told through jazz and the sounds of Motown during the Civil Rights movement, and hip-hop and rhythm and blues that remind us of the work that still lies ahead. &nbsp;The music created by Black artists continues to influence musicians of all persuasions, entertain people of all backgrounds, and shape the story of our Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During Black Music Appreciation Month, we honor Black musicians, singers, and contributors to the music industry &#8212; past and present &#8212; whose innovative talents unite us in joy as&nbsp;much as in sorrow and healing.&nbsp; We pay homage to the musical legends whose artistic expressions help build community, generate empathy, and foster a sense of shared identity. &nbsp;And&nbsp;we&nbsp;celebrate Black artists who have used their songs to stand up to injustice, fight for equality, and reflect a mirror on society &#8212; reminding us all of our enduring obligation to deliver the promise of America for all Americans.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 2022 as Black Music Appreciation Month. &nbsp;I&nbsp;call upon public officials, educators, and all the people of the United States to observe this month by honoring Black Musicians and raising awareness and appreciation of Black music.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Readout of Meeting Between Prime Minister Ardern and Vice President&#160;Harris</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/31/joint-readout-of-meeting-between-prime-minister-ardern-and-vice-president-harris/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 17:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand and Vice President Kamala Harris met at the White House and jointly&#160;reaffirmed the strong and&#160;deep&#160;relationship&#160;between the United States and New Zealand, based on shared values, people-to-people ties, and cooperation across a wide range of bilateral, regional, and global challenges. The Prime Minister and the Vice President welcomed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand and Vice President Kamala Harris met at the White House and jointly&nbsp;reaffirmed the strong and&nbsp;deep&nbsp;relationship&nbsp;between the United States and New Zealand, based on shared values, people-to-people ties, and cooperation across a wide range of bilateral, regional, and global challenges.</p>



<p>The Prime Minister and the Vice President welcomed the completion of&nbsp;negotiations on&nbsp;the bilateral Space Framework Agreement, which will be the foundation of our already robust civil space cooperation in the years ahead. The Framework will underpin the two nations’ cooperation including in: space science, earth science, sustainability, education, and technology. The Prime Minister and the Vice President reviewed the growing&nbsp;space partnership between the United States and New Zealand,&nbsp;including in supporting space exploration and taking action on climate change. They looked forward to future exchanges between the two countries.</p>



<p>The Prime Minister and the Vice President agreed on the importance of establishing and upholding international rules and norms to promote the peaceful, sustainable, and responsible use of outer space. They agreed that our two nations will work together to uphold and strengthen a rules-based international order for space and that we will work constructively with commercial industry, allies, and partners, and through multilateral fora to support the safety, stability, security, and long-term sustainability of space activities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Prime Minister and the Vice President discussed mutual efforts to combat violent extremism and radicalisation. They condemned recent mass shootings in the United States, including in Buffalo, Laguna Woods, and Uvalde, and agreed that we all must stand up against hate and violence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
