<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:45:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh of Vietnam</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-deputy-prime-minister-pham-binh-minh-of-vietnam/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Vietnamese Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh. Mr. Sullivan emphasized the United States’ commitment to our comprehensive partnership with Vietnam, and discussed ways to deepen cooperation between the two countries in areas such as maritime security, the Mekong region, combatting climate change, and ending the COVID-19 pandemic.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Vietnamese Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh. Mr. Sullivan emphasized the United States’ commitment to our comprehensive partnership with Vietnam, and discussed ways to deepen cooperation between the two countries in areas such as maritime security, the Mekong region, combatting climate change, and ending the COVID-19 pandemic. Mr. Sullivan underscored the Biden-Harris administration’s commitment to ASEAN centrality and ASEAN’s essential role in the Indo-Pacific architecture and pledged that the administration would continue to engage at a high-level with Vietnam and partners throughout the region. Mr. Sullivan and Deputy Prime Minster Minh also discussed the South China Sea, including the United States’ support for the 2016 arbitral tribunal award. Additionally, Mr. Sullivan conveyed President Biden’s concern over the dire humanitarian and human rights situation in Ethiopia’s Tigray region and the urgent need for the UN Security Council to marshal support to address ongoing famine conditions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/u-s-covid-19-global-response-and-recovery-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 23:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More than&#160;600,000&#160;of our fellow Americans,&#160;and nearly 4 million people globally,&#160;have died due to COVID-19. The devastating impact of the pandemic has been felt at home and abroad, triggering health and economic crises. Globally, we are witnessing the first&#160;wide scale&#160;increase in extreme poverty in more than twenty years, the loss of decades of development progress,&#160;increases in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>More than&nbsp;600,000&nbsp;of our fellow Americans,&nbsp;and nearly 4 million people globally,&nbsp;have died due to COVID-19. The devastating impact of the pandemic has been felt at home and abroad, triggering health and economic crises. Globally, we are witnessing the first&nbsp;wide scale&nbsp;increase in extreme poverty in more than twenty years, the loss of decades of development progress,&nbsp;increases in gender-based violence,&nbsp;rising food insecurity, and increased unemployment—particularly among young people and women.&nbsp;Even as we gain confidence in&nbsp;United States (U.S.)&nbsp;domestic COVID-19 vaccination coverage, none of us are safe until all of us are safe. The risk of emergent, dangerous variants where COVID-19 transmission remains high poses a risk to us all.&nbsp; This disease knows no borders.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;U.S. will work with our partners to intensify the fight against&nbsp;COVID-19 around the world, pave the way to global recovery, and build back better national and global health security. Our first goal is to end the pandemic—at home and abroad. On January 21, 2021, President Biden released the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/National-Strategy-for-the-COVID-19-Response-and-Pandemic-Preparedness.pdf">National Strategy for the COVID-19 Response and&nbsp; Pandemic Preparedness</a>, including Goal 7, which details the Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive planrestore U.S. leadership globally and build better preparedness for future threats; re-engage with the World Health Organization (WHO) and seek to strengthen and reform it; urge the international COVID-19 public health and humanitarian response; restore U.S. leadership to the international COVID-19 response and advance global health security and diplomacy; and build better biopreparedness and expand resilience for biological threats.</p>



<p>In support of that strategy, the&nbsp;U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework&nbsp;provides a focused set of objectives and lines of effort under which U.S. departments of agencies are executing a whole-of-government response.&nbsp; This response&nbsp;aims to shorten the lifespan of and ultimately end the COVID-19 pandemic globally; mitigate its wider harms to people and economies and support the global recovery; and build back better to strengthen international readiness for future biological threats.&nbsp;The U.S. Government will pursue five objectives under the U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework that together constitute a comprehensive approach to managing the immediate global health crisis and ending the pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework<sup>&nbsp;</sup>also supports U.S. commitments to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/11/fact-sheet-united-states-and-g7-plan-to-defeat-the-covid-19-pandemic-in-2022-and-prevent-the-next-pandemic/">G7<sup>+</sup>&nbsp;Plan to Defeat the COVID-19 Pandemic in 2022 and Prevent the Next Pandemic</a>&nbsp;by supporting vaccination of the world’s most vulnerable populations, supporting last mile vaccination and getting shots in arms, providing personal protective equipment (PPE) and medical supplies where needed, strengthening supply, improving disease surveillance and early warning, supporting recovery, building resilience, and advancing global health security.</p>



<p>Read the full framework here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/U.S.-COVID-19-Global-Response-and-Recovery-Framework.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/U.S.-COVID-19-Global-Response-and-Recovery-Framework.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/2021-annual-report-to-congress-on-white-house-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since 1995, the White House has been required to deliver a report to Congress listing the title and salary of every White House Office employee. Consistent with President Biden’s commitment to transparency, this report is being publicly disclosed on our website as it is transmitted to Congress. 2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since 1995, the White House has been required to deliver a report to Congress listing the title and salary of every White House Office employee. Consistent with President Biden’s commitment to transparency, this report is being publicly disclosed on our website as it is transmitted to Congress.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/July-1-2021-Report-Final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House Staff</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before a Command Briefing from Incident Commander Mayor Daniella Levine Cava, Governor Ron DeSantis, Local Leaders, and First Responders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/01/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-command-briefing-from-incident-commander-mayor-daniella-levine-cava-governor-ron-desantis-local-leaders-and-first-responders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 18:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[St. Regis HotelMiami, Florida 10:41 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  (In progress) &#8212; and I’ve got to say that, you know, having been to, unfortunately, a lot of &#8212; like many of us have &#8212; a lot of disaster sites because of natural disasters, it&#8217;s &#8212; what you&#8217;re doing, in coordination among you all, has been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">St. Regis Hotel<br>Miami, Florida<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">10:41 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (In progress) &#8212; and I’ve got to say that, you know, having been to, unfortunately, a lot of &#8212; like many of us have &#8212; a lot of disaster sites because of natural disasters, it&#8217;s &#8212; what you&#8217;re doing, in coordination among you all, has been just admirable.  It really is impressive.<br><br>And so I just want to say thanks and listen and find out what I can do as President and what I can unleash, in terms of help, for whatever you need.<br><br>The governor and the mayor have been completely open with me, asked whatever they &#8212; whatever they&#8217;ve asked, I think we’ve been able to deliver.  And I think there’s more that we can do, including &#8212; I think I have the power &#8212; and we’ll know shortly &#8212; to be able to pick up 100 percent of the cost for the county and the state for 30 days.<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  Oh, my goodness, Mr. President.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I think I’m quite sure I can do that.  And so we’re going to do that. <br><br>And there’s going to be a lot &#8212; you all know it because a lot of you have been through it as well &#8212; there’s going to be a lot of pain and anxiety and suffering and even a need for psychological help in the days and months that follow.<br><br>And so, we’re not going anywhere.<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, for real.  But, again, I just want to, you know, start the day, if I could, getting as thorough briefing as you’re able to give me, and tell me what you need.  And that goes for both the senators and the congresswoman and anyone in Florida, just to pick up the phone to the Oval.  For real.  I’m not joking about it. <br><br>And I think the Gov will tell you &#8212; anything you ask for, we got.  And we have another group of teams coming from FEMA today.  How many people will it be?<br><br>PARTICIPANT:  At the end of the day, there should about 500 on the ground.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Five hundred on the ground.<br><br>So, again, this is your show.  We just want to make sure that whatever you need &#8212; and, you know, including &#8212; well, anyway, I’m talking too much.  Why don’t I &#8212; I want to hear from you guys.<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  All right.  Well, Mr. President, we cannot thank you enough for being here with us, for showing your extraordinary support from day one.  You called me that morning.  We hustled into a little room in the Family Reunification Center so I could take the call, and you said whatever we need.  And I said, “Bring FEMA,” and here they are, on the ground.<br><br>So it’s been an incredible collaboration from the beginning, with the federal, with the state.  We had our Florida Emergency Management Director, Kevin Guthrie, here immediately.  The governor has been here every single day.  The senators, I believe, the same, and our state and municipal leaders as well.<br><br>So the collaboration from the elected leadership to the police departments; all the municipals, of course, under the leadership of our incredible Miami-Dade Police Department, and Freddy Ramirez, our director; and, without a doubt, the fire department and our chief &#8212; our Fire Chief, Alan Cominsky, who has led the effort of these first responders who are in the &#8212; in the world&#8217;s hands.  <br><br>Everybody is praying and watching these incredible men and women as they proceed, day after day, and literally have to be pulled off the pile, Mr. President.  They are here to save lives.  That is what they live for.  And it is truly &#8212; it is truly humbling.<br><br>So, we all know this is an unprecedented devastating disaster unlike anyone has ever seen.  It&#8217;s shocked the world.  And the fact that we&#8217;ve all come together is what gives us hope, is what gives us strength and inspiration; it does for me every single day &#8212; as we talk to the family members, as you&#8217;ll soon be doing, as they are waiting and waiting for news of their loved ones, as you said, and also those who have been displaced.  I mean, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s just a crisis all around.<br><br>But we are working together to handle the crisis to get the answers about what happened here.  And we can update you on that.  And we are going to be examining every inch of this catastrophe with the full might of the federal, state, and local government to do so.<br><br>So, we want to make sure we all &#8212; the world wants to make sure that a tragedy of this nature never, ever happens again.<br><br>So, I &#8212; we have a briefing for you.  And I want to start with our governor.  And I want to thank you, Governor DeSantis.  Your team has been amazing, but you personally have been amazing.  You&#8217;ve been a steady, calming, reassuring, but forceful voice every step of the way.  And it&#8217;s been a pleasure to partner with you, truly.  Thank you.  Thank you.<br><br>GOVERNOR DESANTIS:  Thank you.  Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Let me say just one more thing.  You know what&#8217;s good about this &#8212; the way you&#8217;ve cooperated?  We&#8217;re letting the nation know we can cooperate. <br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  Yes, sir.  That&#8217;s right. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And when it&#8217;s really important &#8212;<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  That&#8217;s right. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  &#8212; when it&#8217;s really important &#8212; I was talking to Debbie about it on the way down &#8212; we come together.  This is &#8212; this is life and death. <br><br>And so, I don&#8217;t think &#8212; I just got back from about 12 days in Europe.  They wondered whether we can do this.  And you&#8217;re doing it.  I mean, just the simple act of everybody doing whatever needs to be done is a &#8212; and it really makes a difference, Gov. <br><br>GOVERNOR DESANTIS:  Well, thank you, Mr. President.  And you’ve recognized the severity of this tragedy from day one.  And you&#8217;ve been very supportive. <br><br>We, in Florida &#8212; you know, you&#8217;ll drive up and down these coastal roads, you&#8217;ll see these buildings.  And I&#8217;ve driven by that building; probably never thought twice.  And then something like this happens and you recognize in each individual unit there&#8217;s an amazing story. <br><br>And lives have been shattered irrevocably as a result of this.  We&#8217;ve already identified, unfortunately, fatalities &#8212; people who&#8217;ve been 92 years old, have been a matriarch of a wonderful family.  We have families with kids missing.  And we even have young newlyweds who hadn&#8217;t even been married a year who were in the tower when it collapsed.<br><br>And so the cooperation has been great.  The local &#8212; both the municipal and the county have been fantastic.  And you guys have not only been supportive at the federal level, but we&#8217;ve had no bureaucracy.  When we&#8217;re dealing with FEMA, we&#8217;re literally getting requests routed from local to state to federal in no time &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I promise you, there will be none.<br><br>GOVERNOR DESANTIS:  &#8212; and the approval is happening.  Yeah.<br><br>And so that &#8212; that really, I think, is important.  And so we’ve had people &#8212; this is the first response in Florida’s history, outside of a hurricane, where all of our search-and-rescue teams were mobilized.  So they’ve been going in and out of the rubble, searching, trying to find people, trying to rescue people &#8212; at a minimum, trying to identify anyone who may be deceased to bring closure to the families, which is very important. <br><br>But they’re tired, and this has taken a toll on them.  And so, the fact that we now have that search-and-rescue team from Virginia here &#8212; and I know we have some more on the way &#8212; that’s going to be helpful because this is grueling. <br><br>And obviously, the families’ lives have been shattered.  Mental health is going to be important.  We’re going to need some mental health support for some of the folks who’ve been in that rubble because it’s not easy to do. <br><br>And &#8212; but we thank you for the support.  And we do appreciate the collaboration for local, state, and federal. <br><br>And, you know, what we just need now is we need a little bit of luck, we need a little bit of prayers, and, you know, we would like to be able to see some miracles happen. <br><br>But I can tell you this: We’re not going to stop until we identify everybody and until we do what we need to do.  So, thank you, Mr. President.<br><br>MAYOR LEVINE CAVA:  Thank you, Mr. President.  I want to acknowledge the leadership of the First Lady, Casey DeSantis, as well, who is very, very focused on children and mental health issues and is bringing that agenda to our discussions.  And, of course, we’ve been including all of that, as you&#8217;ll learn from the briefings.  But we know how important First Ladies are, so we just wanted to be sure to give a shout out.<br><br>(The press is escorted out of the briefing.)<br><br>10:52 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Miami, FL</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/01/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-miami-fl/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:45:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22951</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Miami, Florida 8:55 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Okay, good morning.&#160; Today in Surfside, the President and the First Lady will receive a command briefing from Incident Commander Mayor Daniella Levine Cava, Governor Ron DeSantis, and Unified Command on the current status of the search-and-rescue efforts and the federal, state, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Miami, Florida</p>



<p>8:55 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, good morning.&nbsp; Today in Surfside, the President and the First Lady will receive a command briefing from Incident Commander Mayor Daniella Levine Cava, Governor Ron DeSantis, and Unified Command on the current status of the search-and-rescue efforts and the federal, state, and local resources being deployed as part of the response.&nbsp; Then they will thank the heroic first responders, search-and-rescue teams, and everyone who has been working around the clock for their tireless work.</p>



<p>The President and the First Lady will meet with the families who have been forced to endure this terrible tragedy to offer them comfort during this unimaginable, difficult time as search-and-rescue efforts continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the end of the day, the President will deliver remarks on the tragedy, how he and the nation stand with the families and survivors, and the federal government&#8217;s response efforts in coordination with our state and local partners.</p>



<p>On those efforts: As of 6:00 a.m. this morning, FEMA has deployed over 60 FEMA staff to support response efforts in Sunrise, Florida.&nbsp; FEMA is also deploying an additional 400 personnel across five urban search-and-rescue teams to assist with ongoing operation at the request of local officials.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each of the &#8212; each of the urban search-and-rescue team has 80 personnel, and all five deployed US&amp;R teams will arrive on site and be operational today.&nbsp; Two additional urban <s>and research</s> [search and] rescue teams are on standby to rapidly deploy and provide relief to the first responders who are working tireless &#8212; tirelessly if needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last evening, FEMA awarded more than $20 million in federal funding to the Florida Division of Emergency Management for Emergency Protective Measures.&nbsp; Given the circumstances and the unprecedented response underway, led by the state &#8212; by state and local officials, FEMA expedited this request for funding from the state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These funds will support the state and local governments&#8217; on-going, unbudgeted costs to conduct rescue operations.&nbsp; This additional fund &#8212; federal support from FEMA is authorized under the emergency declaration the President approved to coordinate disaster relief efforts, reimburse response costs, provide equipment and resources to assist with debris removal and emergency protective measures in order to try to save lives, and to provide temporary shelter and housing to alleviate the hardship and suffering for those who have been displaced.</p>



<p>With that, Alex, you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;&nbsp; Most Florida counties don&#8217;t require condo inspections.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if the President believes that there needs to be a change in local or federal policy to require more inspections and to prevent future situations like this from occurring?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll say this, the National Institute of Standards and Technology &#8212; NIST &#8212; announced last night that they&#8217;re launching a full investigation into what caused the partial collapse of the Champlain Towers South building.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>So, as you know, the President supported an investigation in order to <s>undermine</s> [understand] what caused the terrible tragedy and ensure nothing like it ever happened again.&nbsp; </a>So, we look forward to NIST&#8217;s conclusions once the investigation is complete.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to see what the investigation shows, and that will answer, hopefully, some questions that we all have on what happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s reaction to the CFO of the Trump Organization being indicted in New York?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, that&#8217;s &#8212; so, at this moment, I &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve seen the coverage, clearly, for the past 12 hours or so.&nbsp; But I refer you to the parties involved by any further &#8212; for any further comment.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to comment on any specific case at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And generally, this &#8212; the President, you know, believes and has made clear that he &#8212; it&#8217;s long past due for wealthiest Americans to pay their fair share.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s announced a number of initiatives to crack down on tax evasion by high-income individuals and big corporations.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t have anything further to say on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he think fringe benefits is a serious enough issue to justify going after the organization of a former President?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have anything to say about &#8212; about this particular case at all.&nbsp; I refer you to the authorities that are a part of this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; It sounds like you&#8217;re saying &#8212; you&#8217;re not &#8212; are you suggesting there was something improper?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is &#8212; what I&#8217;m saying is, in general, the President believes that the wealthiest among us should pay their fair share.&nbsp; And we see that in policies and legislation that he&#8217;s put forward, when we talk about the American Jobs Plan, the American Families Plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, he truly believes, as he&#8217;s &#8212; as we look at his economic policy &#8212; that everyone should pay their fair share, especially the wealthiest among us.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re saying.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not commenting at all on the particular investigation.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying, in general.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do you know if he paid his fair share?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying this is what he believes, in general.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, does the President today want to get a sense of how the building collapsed, what factors led to the collapse?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, like I said, there&#8217;s going to be an investigation that was announced last night.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to see how that goes and let the &#8212; let the invest- &#8212; let NI- &#8212; NIST, the experts there, do their investigation, and we&#8217;ll see where that takes us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, to just reiterate: The President’s goal today, his message today &#8212; and the First Lady &#8212; is to go there and to give &#8212; offer up comfort to the families, thank the first responders for their tireless effort.&nbsp; They’ve been working 24/7, around the clock, with this search-and-rescue effort.&nbsp; And so he wanted to go there to be &#8212; to thank them and also to send a message of unity to show how state, local, and federal government are coming together in this time, especially this time of tragedy for the community.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything he wants to hear from Governor DeSantis while he&#8217;s there?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, he&#8217;s going to be &#8212; he&#8217;s going to be meeting with Governor DeSantis when he lands.&nbsp; They &#8212; we have been &#8212; the President and the governor talked on the phone on Friday, and so the White House and FEMA have been in close contact with the governor&#8217;s team to coordinate federal assistance throughout the entire process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we&#8217;re &#8212; what the President wants to do is continue to offer whatever assistance that we may provide.&nbsp; I just listed out what we &#8212; what FEMA announced last night &#8212; what we continue to do to help the community, to help the state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s going to be the focus of today: How &#8212; what &#8212; how can we offer up comfort?&nbsp; What else can we do?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just a message of unity to be there for the people, for the community.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a question on the schedule.&nbsp; Are we actually going to the site of the building collapse?&nbsp; Or will we be &#8212; is the President going to be meeting with the first responders in Surfside, but not at that location?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, right now, as you can imagine, things have been &#8212; things have been kind of moving in the last &#8212; the last couple of hours, because we want to make sure that we don&#8217;t take away any resources and we do this in a safe way.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ll have more updates on that for you all later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, as you know, he&#8217;s going to be meeting with the first responders.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to be meeting with the family.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll &#8212; guys, we’ll let you know more of what else that looks like as for the day.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaker Pelosi was at the White House yesterday, obviously, for the bill signing.&nbsp; Did she and the President have a chance to discuss some of the legislative strategy forward on the bipartisan bill, on the reconciliation package?&nbsp; And would he encourage her to delink those, as he&#8217;s been asked to on several occasions by some of the Republicans?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I’ll say this: I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; any conversation to provide to all of you that he had with &#8212; you know, any private conversation that he had with the Speaker.&nbsp; He trusts the Speaker.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; He supports the Speaker.&nbsp; And she&#8217;s &#8212; she&#8217;s been a tremendous leader and partner over these past several months.</p>



<p>And so, as far as the process, when it comes to the bipartisan infrastructure framework, he leads that &#8212; he leaves that process to Congress.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to do what he did in Wisconsin, which is talk to the American people about the important elements of that framework.</p>



<p>As you know &#8212; we&#8217;ve said this over and over again &#8212; it is a historic investment in our country and infrastructure.&nbsp; And so, this is an agreement that he&#8217;s very proud of, and he&#8217;s going to continue to talk about it and work closely with Congress on getting it done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There were some questions yesterday about whether the elements of the hard infrastructure that are included in the bipartisan compromise preclude the White House from pushing for further elements of his Jobs Plan in the reconciliation package.</p>



<p>Jen, yesterday, said he will continue to advocate for the full package.&nbsp; But can you be clear about whether that includes pushing for more funding for some of these areas in the reconciliation package?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Like Jen said, he&#8217;s going to continue advocating aggressively.&nbsp; This is &#8212; you know, these are legis- &#8212; what he put forth in his legislative priorities this year is something that he is &#8212; he is committed to and will continue to push for them.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll do that in the reconciliation package.&nbsp;&nbsp; And some of the things that &#8212; you know, that were left out of the package, including incentive rebates for electric vehicles; clean energy tax credit; and the components of his American Families Plan, including extension of the Child Tax Credit, universal pre-K, ensuring community college is a real option for millions of Americans.</p>



<p>So he&#8217;s going to continue pushing what he believes in is incredibly important and that&#8217;s going to help the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, can I ask about the timing of today&#8217;s visit?&nbsp; Because you all have spoken about the concerns about taking resources away from an ongoing search-and-rescue effort.&nbsp; So &#8212; and, I mean, the incident was relatively recent.&nbsp; So why today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so, you know, we have been in regular consultation with state government and the mayor&#8217;s office since &#8212; since early this morning.&nbsp; And I know it&#8217;s like, what, eight o&#8217;clock in the morning, right now &#8212; it&#8217;s still early &#8212; but we have.</p>



<p>And the message that we&#8217;ve been given is very clear from the mayor&#8217;s office, from the governor&#8217;s office, from local official, which is, like, they wanted us to come today.&nbsp; Now is the time to come to offer up, you know, some &#8212; offer up comfort and show unity and from &#8212; from not just from him, but from the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so this is why he and the First Lady decided to come today.&nbsp; It was &#8212; a lot was because he was asked to come and he thought this was the right time to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When he meets with some of the families, we&#8217;re at a point now in the timeline where those on the ground are saying we&#8217;re talking about simply a recovery mission at this point and not a rescue mission.&nbsp; Has the President been briefed about the likelihood of survivors still being found in the in the rubble there?&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if you&#8217;ve had a chance to talk to him, but how does he prepare for the conversations that he&#8217;s going to be having with some of these families today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as far as that, you know, as we said, this is a rescue-and-search mission and continues to be that.&nbsp; You know, we haven&#8217;t gotten any indication of it not being exactly that, to continue to search and res- &#8212; to do the search and rescue, and looking for loved ones that &#8212; that are there in &#8212; in the site.&nbsp; And search-and-rescue operations, like I said, are still going on, and we&#8217;re hoping for the best.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but we, you know, we will refer you to the officials on the ground for anything more specific about what &#8212; what the status of what is happening on the ground.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) organizing those family meetings with 145, I guess, unaccounted for.&nbsp; Is it in groups?&nbsp; Is it any family of anyone who&#8217;s missing or perished?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t &#8212; (the interior door to the press cabin swings open) &#8212; careful.&nbsp; We&#8217;re about to lose Mike Memoli.&nbsp; Oh, my goodness.&nbsp; Hold on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perish the thought.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Perish the thought, indeed.</p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;ve been working with local officials on the ground and making sure that we&#8217;re meeting with the families that were impacted by this.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more &#8212; any more to tell them about, like, the process of it.&nbsp; But the &#8212; the important thing to remember is that the President is coming here with the First Lady to make sure that they are offering up, you know, their &#8212; you know, their services &#8212; their service &#8212; or service and just comfort to the &#8212; in this &#8212; in this time of tragedy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s the most important thing.&nbsp; This is about the community.&nbsp; This is about the people and everything that they&#8217;ve had to endure this past &#8212; this past several days.&nbsp; You know, this is an incredibly tragic time.&nbsp; And this is the President &#8212; this is a President that understands what that means &#8212; loss means.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s going to be his focus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And like I said, we&#8217;ve worked closely with folks on the ground in making sure that the families were there when he &#8212; when he was &#8212; when he &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any scheduling information over the next few days &#8212; the holiday weekend?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that one more time.&nbsp; I’m so sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Scheduling information over the next few days?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have anything more to share.&nbsp; I think we announced that he&#8217;s going to Michigan on Saturday, and then he will be doing the Fourth of July event with first responders and military families on Sunday for Fourth of July.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have any more further to share with that, Steve.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) said he was going to speak about voting rights issues this week, last week.&nbsp; Obviously, today came up on the schedule and that wasn&#8217;t originally.&nbsp; Is there something on the decks for next week that we should be &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don’t have anything to preview, but clearly, that is something that&#8217;s incredibly important to the President &#8212; is the voting rights issue.&nbsp; And he is going to speak to that in the upcoming days.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;ll have more to share once we have &#8212; once we have something locked in.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, is the White House or HUD or any &#8212; any other agencies in the federal government considering any other actions just to prevent things like what happened in Surfside happening again?&nbsp; Are there any executive actions you can take, anything HUD is looking at as you guys wait for the outcome of the investigation?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, right now, we don&#8217;t have anything else to announce or preview.&nbsp; I just listed out a bunch of efforts that FEMA is doing, on the funding that we&#8217;ve provided for the efforts on the ground.&nbsp; And once &#8212; I think the investigation will be incredibly important to kind of steer us and give us a sense of what could be next that we could do to prevent this from happening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen was asked yesterday about this situation &#8212; unusual situation in South Dakota with the National Guard where a private donation is being used to fund a deployment.&nbsp; I know she said she would get an answer.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you had an update on the White House&#8217;s view of the appropriateness of that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So the White House is focused not on political gestures but rather on putting in the work and delivering the solutions.&nbsp; The progress made at the southern border in the first 150 days under the administration is pretty clear.&nbsp; And so the administration has been significant &#8212; has made significant progress at establishing a well-managed and secure border while also treating people fairly and humanely. The American people support this approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Separately, DHS and CBP continue to leverage their longstanding relationship with state and local law enforcement, including deconflicting operations in the border region and responding to call &#8212; callouts from other law enforcement agencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Memoli, we may not &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; we may not make it to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; to Florida.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Karine, the former President is going to have a rally in Sarasota on Saturday night.&nbsp; Have you all taken a position on whether that should go ahead with?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, we&#8217;re in &#8212; we are not focused on the former President at all.&nbsp; We are focused primarily on the American people, what can the President do &#8212; this is what the President is focused on &#8212; what he can continue to do to make their lives better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, right now, today, is all about the community of Surfside: making sure we&#8217;re offering up our condolences, making sure we&#8217;re offering up all the help that we can provide to them at this time, and also lifting up our first responders who have been working tirelessly around the clock doing the work that they&#8217;re doing in their search and rescue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>9:12 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Today’s Agreement of 130 Countries to Support a Global Minimum Tax for the World’s Largest Corporations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-todays-agreement-of-130-countries-to-support-a-global-minimum-tax-for-the-worlds-largest-corporations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today marks an important step in moving the global economy forward to be more equitable for workers and middle class families in the United States and around the world. I want to thank all the signatories of the Paris OECD statement — 130 countries — for coming together to endorse a global minimum tax rate&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today marks an important step in moving the global economy forward to be more equitable for workers and middle class families in the United States and around the world. I want to thank all the signatories of the Paris OECD statement — 130 countries — for coming together to endorse a global minimum tax rate of at least 15 percent. These nations make up more than 90 percent of the world’s economy, which puts us in striking distance of full global agreement to halt the race to the bottom for corporate taxes.</p>



<p>With a global minimum tax in place, multinational corporations will no longer be able to pit countries against one another in a bid to push tax rates down and protect their profits at the expense of public revenue. They will no longer be able to avoid paying their fair share by hiding profits generated in the United States, or any other country, in lower-tax jurisdictions. This will level the playing field and make America more competitive. And it will allow us to devote the additional revenue we raise to making generational investments, which are necessary to keep America’s competitive edge razor sharp in today’s global economy.</p>



<p>I promised to lead the world to deliver a foreign policy for the middle class, and today, we are doing just that.</p>



<p>Reaching this consensus wasn’t easy. It took American vision, as well as a commitment to closely cooperate with our partners around the world. It’s a testament to how leadership rooted in our values can deliver important progress for families everywhere.</p>



<p>Building on this agreement will also require us to take action here at home. It’s imperative that we reform our own corporate tax laws, as I proposed in my Made in America tax plan. We must adopt the global minimum tax, among other measures I have proposed, to make sure corporations pay their fair share. Congress should pass my Made in America tax plan to bring good paying jobs home and make sure our tax code works for families, workers, and small businesses, not just profitable corporations and billionaires.</p>



<p>I commend Secretary Yellen for her efforts championing these discussions and look forward to continued productive negotiations. I look forward to full agreement in the fall.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the Supreme Court’s Voting Rights Decision in Brnovich v. Democratic National Committee</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-supreme-courts-voting-rights-decision-in-brnovich-v-democratic-national-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 16:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am deeply disappointed in today’s decision by the United States Supreme Court that undercuts the Voting Rights Act, and upholds what Justice Kagan called “a significant race-based disparity in voting opportunities.” In a span of just eight years, the Court has now done severe damage to two of the most important provisions of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I am deeply disappointed in today’s decision by the United States Supreme Court that undercuts the Voting Rights Act, and upholds what Justice Kagan called “a significant race-based disparity in voting opportunities.”</p>



<p>In a span of just eight years, the Court has now done severe damage to two of the most important provisions of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 – a law that took years of struggle and strife to secure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>After all we have been through to deliver the promise of this Nation to all Americans, we should be fully enforcing voting rights laws, not weakening them. Yet this decision comes just over a week after Senate Republicans blocked even a debate – even consideration – of the For the People Act that would have protected the right to vote from action by Republican legislators in states across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While this broad assault against voting rights is sadly not unprecedented, it is taking on new forms. It is no longer just about a fight over who gets to vote and making it easier for eligible voters to vote. It is about who gets to count the vote and whether your vote counts at all.</p>



<p>Our democracy depends on an election system built on integrity and independence. The attack we are seeing today makes clearer than ever that additional laws are needed to safeguard that beating heart of our democracy. We must also shore up our election security to address the threats of election subversion from abroad and at home.</p>



<p>Today’s decision also makes it all the more imperative to continue the fight for the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act to restore and expand voting protections. The Court’s decision, harmful as it is, does not limit Congress’ ability to repair the damage done today: it puts the burden back on Congress to restore the Voting Rights Act to its intended strength.</p>



<p>That means forging a coalition of Americans of every background and political party – from advocates, activists, and business executives – to raise the urgency of the moment and demand that our democracy truly reflects the will of the people and that it delivers for the Nation.</p>



<p>That is what Vice President Harris and I will continue to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is our life’s work and the work of all of us.</p>



<p>Democracy is on the line.</p>



<p>We can do this together.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph Biden on the Women, Peace, and Security Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/statement-by-president-joseph-biden-on-the-women-peace-and-security-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 13:25:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22889</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[June, 29, 2021 My Administration is committed to a simple but profoundly meaningful proposition—all people, everywhere, are entitled to be treated with inherent human dignity. Yet, in far too many places, women and girls are denied their basic rights, cut off from opportunity, subjected to violence and abuse, or prevented from pursuing their dreams and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">June, 29, 2021</p>



<p>My Administration is committed to a simple but profoundly meaningful proposition—all people, everywhere, are entitled to be treated with inherent human dignity. Yet, in far too many places, women and girls are denied their basic rights, cut off from opportunity, subjected to violence and abuse, or prevented from pursuing their dreams and ambitions. And, in conflicts around the world, rape and sexual violence are used systematically to terrorize civilians—not as incidental to conflict but as a weapon of war itself. It’s an atrocity, meant to destabilize nations and dehumanize communities, and it is intolerable.</p>



<p>I learned from my father that the cardinal sin was the abuse of power. That’s a major reason why fighting to eliminate all forms of gender-based violence in the United States and around the world has been a central part of my life’s work. Under my Administration, we will harness our full toolset to prevent and respond to gender-based violence wherever it occurs, including in areas of conflict. There is no justification or excuse. It’s just wrong. And advancing the rights of women and girls starts by ensuring their safety.</p>



<p>Beyond the moral imperative to advance gender equity and gender equality around the world; beyond principles of justice and fairness; beyond clear notions of right and wrong, it’s just basic math. No community, economy, or undertaking can reach its potential if women are denied the ability to fully participate in their societies—to contribute their ideas and energies. No nation will be able to keep up with the speed and scale of today’s challenges if half of its talent and brain power is left behind.<br><br>We know that everyone in a society does better when everyone participates. Economies grow. Poverty shrinks. Education rates and health outcomes improve. Political instability and extremism decline. When women are engaged fully in building and maintaining peace and security in their countries, we see more sustainable and more equitable outcomes, less conflict, and longer-lasting peace agreements. If we hope to succeed in building peace and prosperity and delivering real progress, women must be engaged at every step. That’s why, during the Obama-Biden Administration, we developed the first comprehensive National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security (WPS) in American history. And in 2017, the United States passed bipartisan legislation to translate those commitments into law.</p>



<p>This report takes stock of the progress we have made over the past few years in implementing that law, and points the way forward across four agencies of the United States Federal Government—the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the Department of Homeland Security, and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID)—as we continue to advance the Women, Peace, and Security agenda globally. It evaluates four lines of effort, including meaningful participation in decision-making processes related to conflict and crises, protection, internal U.S. capabilities, and partner support. While we have made important<br>strides, during the COVID-19 pandemic, we have unfortunately also seen too many examples where we are moving in the wrong direction. We have been reminded how fragile our progress can be and how quickly the potential of women and girls can be lost. The pandemic has exposed so many of the inequities in our world—hitting the most vulnerable the hardest, exacerbating challenges that impact the most marginalized in our societies—and as we rebuild, we cannot be content to just get back to where we were. We have to seize this moment to fundamentally change our approach.</p>



<p>While this <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/USG-Women-Peace-and-Security-Congressional-Report-June-2021.pdf">report </a>focuses on the Departments of State, Defense, and Homeland Security and USAID, I have instructed departments and agencies across the Federal Government to prioritize gender equity and equality. The persistent unequal treatment of women around the world— particularly women of color, LGBTQI+ women, and other women who face overlapping forms of discrimination—remains a critical, unfinished project of our time. I am committed to making the promotion of human rights for all people a core pillar of our foreign policy. Our goal is a world where every individual has the tools and the opportunity they need to thrive, where everyone can pursue their unique purpose free from the fear of violence. Empowering women globally—ensuring their inclusion in decision making and leadership positions—is essential to achieving that goal.</p>



<p>To view the report, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/USG-Women-Peace-and-Security-Congressional-Report-June-2021.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/USG-Women-Peace-and-Security-Congressional-Report-June-2021.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White House Releases Fact Sheets to Highlight Nationwide Need and Impact of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/white-house-releases-fact-sheets-to-highlight-nationwide-need-and-impact-of-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22869</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House released state fact sheets that highlight the need for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. The fact sheets highlight how the historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework will deliver for states and territories across the country – creating a generation of good-paying, union&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House released state fact sheets that highlight the need for the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-support-for-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework/">Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework</a>, the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century.<br> <br>The fact sheets highlight how the historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework will deliver for states and territories across the country – creating a generation of good-paying, union jobs, spurring economic growth, and positioning the United States to win the 21<sup>st</sup> century.<br><br>Individual fact sheets for each of the 50 states, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and other territories are linked below. A fact sheet on how the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework advances racial equity is also linked below.<br><br><strong><u>Fact Sheets by State/Territory:</u></strong><br><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-AK.pdf">Alaska</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-AL.pdf">Alabama</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-AR.pdf">Arkansas</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-AZ.pdf">Arizona</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-CA.pdf">California</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-CO.pdf">Colorado</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-CT.pdf">Connecticut</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-DC.pdf">District of Columbia</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-DE.pdf">Delaware</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-FL.pdf">Florida</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-GA.pdf">Georgia</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-HI.pdf">Hawaii</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-IA.pdf">Iowa</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-ID.pdf">Idaho</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-IL.pdf">Illinois</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-IN.pdf">Indiana</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-KS.pdf">Kansas</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-KY.pdf">Kentucky</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-LA.pdf">Louisiana</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-MA.pdf">Massachusetts</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-MD.pdf">Maryland</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-ME.pdf">Maine</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-MI.pdf">Michigan</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-MN.pdf">Minnesota</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-MO.pdf">Missouri</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-MS.pdf">Mississippi</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-MT.pdf">Montana</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-NC.pdf">North Carolina</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-ND.pdf">North Dakota</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-NE.pdf">Nebraska</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-NH.pdf">New Hampshire</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-NJ.pdf">New Jersey</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-NM.pdf">New Mexico</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-NV.pdf">Nevada</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-NY.pdf">New York</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-OH.pdf">Ohio</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-OK.pdf">Oklahoma</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-OR.pdf">Oregon</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-PA.pdf">Pennsylvania</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-PR.pdf">Puerto Rico</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-RI.pdf">Rhode Island</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-SC.pdf">South Carolina</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-SD.pdf">South Dakota</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-TN.pdf">Tennessee</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-TX.pdf">Texas</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-UT.pdf">Utah</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-VT.pdf">Vermont</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-VA.pdf">Virginia</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-WA.pdf">Washington</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-WI.pdf">Wisconsin</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-WV.pdf">West Virginia</a><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/BIF-Factsheet-WY.pdf">Wyoming</a><br> <br><strong><u>Fact Sheets by Issue:</u></strong><br><br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/29/fact-sheet-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework-will-address-barriers-communities-of-color-face-to-economic-opportunity/">Racial Equity</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Wildfire Preparedness Meeting with Cabinet Officials, Governors and Private Sector Partners</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/readout-of-president-bidens-wildfire-preparedness-meeting-with-cabinet-officials-governors-and-private-sector-partners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 01:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden convened a meeting with Governors from Western States, Cabinet and agency officials, and energy sector partners to discuss the critical need to work together to strengthen prevention, preparedness and response efforts for this wildfire season, which is on track to outpace last season. &#160;In the meeting, the President emphasized the importance of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden convened a meeting with Governors from Western States, Cabinet and agency officials, and energy sector partners to discuss the critical need to work together to strengthen prevention, preparedness and response efforts for this wildfire season, which is on track to outpace last season. &nbsp;In the meeting, the President emphasized the importance of making much-needed investments to prepare our country to do everything we can to address the growing and severe threat of wildfires and save lives. &nbsp;The President highlighted the series of actions his Administration is taking immediately to respond to wildfires this year,&nbsp;including making substantial investments in our firefighter personnel, increasing Federal firefighter pay and providing access to retention incentives, and extending the hiring of temporary firefighters to ensure a more effective response throughout this year’s fire season. &nbsp;The President also shared how the Biden Administration is improving our wildfire response capabilities including through the use of new technologies, and helping vulnerable communities mitigate the impact of fires through new funding. &nbsp;President Biden announced a $37 million grant award to California to support fire mitigation efforts as part of FEMA’s new Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities program.&nbsp; Last month, President Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/fact-sheet-biden-administration-invests-1-billion-to-protect-communities-families-and-businesses-before-disaster-strikes/">announced</a> the Administration will double funding for the program to $1 billion next year in order to invest in pre-disaster resilience and mitigation resources and help strengthen the ability of communities, families, and businesses to withstand extreme weather events and other disasters.<br><br>Vice President Harris spoke about how this administration is investing in resilience to protect against wildfires and extreme weather. &nbsp;President Biden and Vice President Harris asked the Governors what additional support and resources they need and what immediate actions can be taken by the Federal government to protect communities from wildfires, help them deal with drought conditions, and improve emergency preparedness. &nbsp;The Governors – who represent a range of states across the West – talked about the importance of working closely together and closely coordinating to prevent wildfires from happening and ensure response efforts are as speedy and effective as possible.&nbsp; The President and his Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall asked the three CEOs of Western utilities to describe how they can improve capacity to manage extreme demands on the grid, diminish the likelihood of power infrastructure sparking or being impacted by wildfires, and rapidly develop and deploy innovative new technologies to improve extreme heat management and wildfire prevention.&nbsp; The President also discussed the synergistic relationship between modernizing the grid and enabling a more resilient low carbon future.<br><br>The members of the Cabinet discussed their departments’ respective efforts to prepare for and mitigate the impacts of wildfires, and answered questions from the President about what more can be done to advance collaboration with states and the private sector on prevention and response. &nbsp;Secretary Vilsack discussed how we have to stop doing wildfire preparedness on the cheap and must make the much-needed investments in firefighting personnel, equipment and mitigation efforts.&nbsp; Forest Service Chief Christiansen outlined the steps being taken to increase firefighter pay, readiness and availability. &nbsp;Secretary Haaland highlighted DOI’s wildfire preparedness and response efforts.&nbsp; Secretary Mayorkas highlighted efforts to support wildfire response and elaborated on the FEMA grant funding being awarded to California today, and the new technologies they are developing to improve early detection of wildfires and meet first responders’ operational needs.&nbsp; EPA Administrator Regan described new technology tools that provide broader public access to prompt and reliable information and health guidance on air quality issues resulting from wildfire smoke in their communities, and Secretary Granholm noted the work being done to support reliable power generation during extreme weather events and prevent structural energy infrastructure failures that have the potential to ignite wildfires.<br><br>Joining President Biden and Vice President Harris in the meeting were members of their homeland security team and the following members of the administration:</p>



<ul><li>Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack</li><li>Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm</li><li>Secretary of Homeland Security Alejandro Mayorkas</li><li>Deputy Secretary of Defense Kathleen Hicks&nbsp;</li><li>Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency Michael Regan</li><li>Chief of the U.S. Forest Service Vicki Christiansen</li><li>Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Rick Spinrad</li><li>Administrator of FEMA Deanne Criswell</li></ul>



<p>The following eight Governors of western states:</p>



<ul><li>Governor of California Gavin Newson</li><li>Governor of Colorado Jared Polis</li><li>Governor of Nevada Steve Sisolak</li><li>Governor of New Mexico Michelle Lujan Grisham</li><li>Governor of Oregon Kate Brown</li><li>Governor of Wyoming Mark Gordon</li><li>Governor of Utah Spencer Cox</li><li>Governor of Washington Jay Inslee</li></ul>



<p>The following private sector CEOs:</p>



<ul><li>President and CEO of Portland General Electric Maria Pope</li><li>CEO of Bonneville Power Marketing Administration John Hairston</li><li>President and CEO of Edison International Pedro Pizarro</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
