<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 12:23:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act: Advancing Economic and Public Health Opportunities for Communities of&#160;Color</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/03/fact-sheet-bipartisan-infrastructure-investment-and-jobs-act-advancing-economic-and-public-health-opportunities-for-communities-of-color/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A little over a month ago, the President announced the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework—a bipartisan agreement to make the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. This week, the Senate is considering the Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act, a once-in-a-generation investment in our infrastructure. The bipartisan infrastructure agreement will grow&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>A little over a month ago, the President announced the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework—a bipartisan agreement to make the largest long-term investment in our infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. This week, the Senate is considering the Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act, a once-in-a-generation investment in our infrastructure. The bipartisan infrastructure agreement will grow the economy, enhance our competitiveness, and make our economy more sustainable, resilient, and just.</p>



<p>The agreement will also create good-paying, union jobs. With the remainder of the President’s Build Back Better Agenda, these investments will add, on average, around 2 million jobs per year over the course of the decade, while accelerating America’s path to full employment and increasing labor force participation.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act addresses economic disparities in our economy and the consequences of decades of disinvestment in America’s infrastructure that have fallen most heavily on communities of color. Through critical investments, the legislation increases access to good-paying jobs, affordable high-speed internet, reliable public transit, clean drinking water and other resources to ensure communities of color get a fair shot at the American dream.</p>



<p>These critical investments are first steps in advancing equity and racial justice throughout our economy. The President believes additional investments are needed in our nation’s caregiving infrastructure, housing supply, regional development, and workforce development programs to ensure that communities of color and other underserved communities can access economic opportunity and justice. And, earlier this summer in Tulsa, OK, President Biden announced a whole-of-government effort to increase the share of federal contracts going to small disadvantaged businesses by 50 percent over the next five years, leveraging the government’s purchasing power to help more Americans realize their entrepreneurial dreams.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act:</p>



<p><strong>DELIVERS HIGH SPEED INTERNET TO EVERY AMERICAN HOUSEHOLD</strong></p>



<p>There is a stark digital divide in America. Black families are 9% less likely to have high-speed internet than their white peers, and Latino Americans are 15% less likely. About 35% of individuals living on Tribal lands lack access to broadband service. Although studies suggest high levels of digital access for Asian Americans, these studies are often limited in scope and don’t identify key inequities. For example, broadband access and affordability in the Pacific Islands has long been a challenge. During the COVID-19 pandemic, there were stories of kids sitting in McDonald’s parking lots to log on to remote school in parts of the country. The President believes this is unacceptable.</p>



<p>The agreement’s $65 billion investment ensures every American has access to reliable high-speed internet with an historic investment in broadband infrastructure deployment, just as the federal government made a historic effort to provide electricity to every American nearly one hundred years ago. This includes a $2 billion investment in broadband in Tribal communities which were hit particularly hard by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>The bill will also help lower prices for internet service by requiring funding recipients to offer a low-cost affordable plan, requiring providers to display a “Broadband Nutrition Label” that will help families comparison shop for a better deal, and by boosting competition in areas where existing providers aren’t providing adequate service.</p>



<p><strong>ELIMINATES LEAD PIPES AND DELIVERS CLEAN DRINKING WATER TO EVERY HOUSEHOLD</strong></p>



<p>Across the country, pipes and treatment plants are aging and polluted drinking water is endangering public health. There are up to 10 million homes with lead service lines and pipes. Children in up to 400,000 schools and child care facilities are at risk of exposure to lead. Across the country, families of color are at the highest risk for lead exposure at home and in schools. Communities of color in cities like Chicago, Milwaukee, and Newark are also at particular risk. For kids, higher exposure to lead can negatively affect academic performance, and can lead to cardiovascular disease later in life. By some estimates, each lead service line replaced at a cost of $5,000 per line leads to $22,000 in health savings.</p>



<p>The deal makes the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history, replacing all of the nation’s lead pipes and service lines. From rural towns to struggling cities, the deal invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal Nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most. The deal also includes dedicated funding to deal with the dangerous chemical PFAS (per- and polyfluoroalkyl).</p>



<p><strong>INVESTS IN MORE PUBLIC TRANSIT OPTIONS AND ADDRESSING THE BACKLOG OF REPAIRS</strong></p>



<p>Asian American and African American workers commute by public transit at nearly 4 times the rate of white workers. For example, low-wage Black residents in Chicago spend 70 additional minutes commuting to work than their white peers. In New York City, the average Black resident spends 110 minutes more per week commuting to work than the average white resident.</p>



<p>The Framework’s historic investment in public transit—the largest federal investment in history—will reduce commute times and create more economic opportunities in communities of color. In addition, bus and transit workers are 31% Black and 19% Hispanic, compared to 12% and 18% respectively of the workforce overall.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure deal is the largest Federal investment in public transit in history, and devotes a larger share of funds from surface transportation reauthorization to transit in the history of the programs. It will repair and upgrade aging infrastructure, modernize bus and rail fleets, make stations accessible to all users, and bring transit service to new communities. It will replace thousands of transit vehicles, including buses, with clean, zero emission vehicles.</p>



<p><strong>CREATES A FIRST-EVER PROGRAM TO RECONNECT COMMUNITIES DIVIDED BY INEQUITABLE TRANSPORTATION INFRASTRUCTURE</strong></p>



<p>Significantportions of the interstate highway system were built through Black neighborhoods, destroying homes, schools, churches, and parks and causing lasting disconnection and disinvestment for residents who stayed.More broadly, historic investments in transportation infrastructure, especially highway construction, cut too many Americans off from opportunity, dividing and demolishing communities, and perpetuating economic and racial injustices. The legislation creates a first-ever program to reconnect communities divided by transportation infrastructure. The program will fund planning, design, demolition, and reconstruction of street grids, parks, or other infrastructure. This is in addition to other major grant programs that could fund elements of these projects.</p>



<p><strong>ELECTRIFY SCHOOL BUSES, IMPROVING THE AIR QUALITY FOR CHILDREN</strong></p>



<p>The legislation will make a critical down payment on helping the more than 25 million children and thousands of bus drivers who breathe polluted air on their rides to and from school. Diesel air pollution is linked to asthma and other health problems that hurt our communities and cause students to miss school, particularly in communities of color and Tribal communities. The legislation will deliver thousands of electric school buses nationwide, helping school districts across the country buy clean, American-made, zero emission buses, replacing the yellow school bus fleet for America’s children.</p>



<p><strong>REMEDIATES BROWNFIELD AND SUPERFUND SITES</strong></p>



<p>Across America, 26% of Black Americans and 29% of Hispanic Americans live within 3 miles of a Superfund site, a higher percentage than for the overall population. Proximity to a Superfund site can lead to elevated levels of lead in children’s blood. Recent studies demonstrate that cleaning up these sites can lead to a decrease in blood levels by approximately 13-26%.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act provides the full American Jobs Plan funding level—$21 billion—to create good-paying union jobs plugging orphan oil and gas wells, cleaning up abandoned mines, and remediating Brownfield and Superfund sites. As we transition to a clean energy future, the Bipartisan Infrastructure deal will begin to remedy economic injustice for communities across the country that have relied on the fossil fuel industry and have been affected most by the impacts of climate change and pollution, including rural communities and communities of color.</p>



<p><strong>SAFEGUARDS COMMUNITIES OF COLOR FROM CLIMATE CRISES AND EXTREME WEATHER RISKS</strong></p>



<p>People of color are more likely to live in areas most vulnerable to flooding and other climate change-related weather events. For example, in the wake of Hurricane Harvey, Black and Hispanic residents were twice as likely to report lost income. Tribal lands are significantly at risk to the effects of climate change and Alaska Natives are particularly vulnerable, as they face multiple climate impacts.</p>



<p>The legislation invests in helping communities build resilience to wildfires and floods through investments in forest management and upgrades to critical infrastructure—like elevating buildings, roads, and bridges, hardening physical infrastructure, and winterizing the power grid. And, it will fund state and local infrastructure improvements and emergency response strategies, such as planning grants to support development of evacuation routes or upgrading community shelters. The legislation will also make it easier for low-income families to buy flood insurance.</p>



<p><strong>INVESTS IN CLEAN ENERGY GRID TO MITIGATE THE DISPARATE IMPACTS OF POLLUTION ON COMMUNITIES OF COLOR</strong></p>



<p>Black, Latino, Asian American and Pacific Islander, and Native communities are more likely to be burdened by pollution. Black people are almost three times more likely to die from asthma related causes than their white counterparts. And more than one in three—or over 23 million—Latinos in the U.S. live in counties where the air doesn’t meet EPA public health standards for smog.</p>



<p>The legislation’s roughly $65 billion investment is the single largest investment in clean energy transmission in American history. It upgrades our power infrastructure, including by building thousands of miles of new, resilient transmission lines to facilitate the expansion of renewable energy. It creates a new Grid Deployment Authority, invests in research and development for advanced transmission and electricity distribution technologies, and promotes smart grid technologies that deliver flexibility and resilience. It invests in demonstration projects and research hubs for next generation technologies like advanced nuclear reactors, carbon capture, and clean hydrogen.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces Major Milestone in Administration’s Global Vaccination Efforts: More Than 100 Million U.S. COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccine Doses Donated and Shipped&#160;Abroad</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/03/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-major-milestone-in-administrations-global-vaccination-efforts-more-than-100-million-u-s-covid-19-vaccine-doses-donated-and-shipped-abroad/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 11:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Building off of last week’s announcement of additional actions that we are taking to stop the spread of the Delta variant and get more people vaccinated in the United States, President Biden will give an update on another critical piece of his strategy to end the COVID-19 pandemic: stopping the spread of the virus abroad.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Building off of last week’s announcement of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-announce-new-actions-to-get-more-americans-vaccinated-and-slow-the-spread-of-the-delta-variant/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">additional actions</a> that we are taking to stop the spread of the Delta variant and get more people vaccinated in the United States, President Biden will give an update on another critical piece of his strategy to end the COVID-19 pandemic: stopping the spread of the virus abroad. As one part of our strategy to do that, the President has promised that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world and is acting with the same urgency to combat the virus abroad as here at home. Today, the President will announce that the U.S. has now donated and shipped more than 110 million doses of its COVID-19 vaccines to more than 60 countries – a major milestone that cements the United States as the global leader in COVID-19 vaccine donations.  According to the United Nations, this is more than the donations of all other countries combined and reflects the generosity of the American spirit.<br><br>In June, the President committed to donate at least 80 million vaccines from the U.S. supply to countries throughout the world, and he promised to continue to share as we are able. Today’s announcement is a fulfillment of his promise and a significant down payment on hundreds of millions of more doses that the U.S. will deliver in the coming weeks. The United States has been able to share these doses because of the aggressive action the President took when he came into office to secure enough vaccines for all Americans.  The majority of these vaccines – made in the United States – were shipped through COVAX. The United States has also worked in close partnership with key regional partners, including the African Union and the Caribbean Community (CARICOM).<br><br>These more than 110 million doses – that are already saving lives around the world – are just the beginning of the Administration’s efforts to provide vaccines to the world. Starting at the end of this month, the Administration will begin shipping a half a billion Pfizer doses that the United States has pledged to purchase and donate to 100 low- income countries in need.<br><br><strong>Biden Administration’s Approach to Sharing U.S. Vaccines:</strong> Our goals are to increase global COVID-19 vaccination coverage, prepare for surges and prioritize healthcare workers and other vulnerable populations based on public health data and acknowledged best practice, and help our neighbors and other countries in need. Importantly, the United States has not and will not use its vaccines to secure favors from other countries. Our aim is to save lives.<br><br>The Administration looks at a variety of factors, including COVID-19 case rates, death rates, and hospitalizations; current vaccination rates; responses to surges; and a country’s ability to receive vaccines and put shots into arms.<br><br>We will continue to work with COVAX, regional partners such as the African Union and CARICOM, and other partners to ensure these vaccines are delivered in a way that is equitable and follows the science and public health data. This is a unique moment in history, and it requires American leadership, science and ingenuity, perseverance, and we are demonstrating that we can deliver results for people around the world.  <br><br><strong>To date, the U.S. has donated COVID-19 vaccines as follows:</strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td><strong>Afghanistan</strong></td><td>3,300,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Malaysia</strong></td><td>1,000,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Argentina</strong></td><td>3,500,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Mali</strong></td><td>151,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Bangladesh</strong></td><td>5,500,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Mauritania</strong></td><td>302,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Benin</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Mexico</strong></td><td>4,049,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Bhutan</strong></td><td>500,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Moldova</strong></td><td>301,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Bolivia</strong></td><td>1,008,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Morocco</strong></td><td>302,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Brazil</strong></td><td>3,000,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Mozambique</strong></td><td>302,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Burkina Faso</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Nepal</strong></td><td>1,534,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Cambodia</strong></td><td>1,058,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Niger</strong></td><td>316,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Cameroon</strong></td><td>303,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Nigeria</strong></td><td>4,000,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Canada</strong></td><td>2,500,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Pakistan</strong></td><td>5,500,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>CAR</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Panama</strong></td><td>503,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Colombia</strong></td><td>6,000,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Paraguay</strong></td><td>2,000,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Costa Rica</strong></td><td>500,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Peru</strong></td><td>2,000,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Djibouti</strong></td><td>151,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Philippines</strong></td><td>6,239,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Ecuador</strong></td><td>2,000,000</td><td></td><td><strong>PNG</strong></td><td>302,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>El Salvador</strong></td><td>3,000,000</td><td></td><td><strong>ROK</strong></td><td>1,012,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Eswatini</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Senegal</strong></td><td>302,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Ethiopia</strong></td><td>1,664,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Somalia</strong></td><td>302,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Fiji</strong></td><td>150,000</td><td></td><td><strong>South Africa</strong></td><td>5,660,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Gambia</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Sri Lanka</strong></td><td>1,500,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Georgia</strong></td><td>503,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Sudan</strong></td><td>604,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Guatemala</strong></td><td>4,500,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Taiwan</strong></td><td>2,500,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Guinea Bissau</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Tajikistan</strong></td><td>1,500,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Haiti</strong></td><td>500,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Tanzania</strong></td><td>1,058,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Honduras</strong></td><td>3,000,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Thailand</strong></td><td>1,500,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Indonesia</strong></td><td>8,000,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Tunisia</strong></td><td>1,000,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Jordan</strong></td><td>503,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Ukraine</strong></td><td>2,000,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Laos</strong></td><td>1,000,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Uruguay</strong></td><td>500,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Lesotho</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Uzbekistan</strong></td><td>3,000,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Liberia</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Vietnam</strong></td><td>5,000,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Madagascar</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong>Zambia</strong></td><td>302,000</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Malawi</strong></td><td>302,000</td><td></td><td><strong><u>Total</u></strong></td><td><strong><u>111,701,000</u></strong></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Virtual Fundraising Reception for the Democratic National&#160;Committee</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/02/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-virtual-fundraising-reception-for-the-democratic-national-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 02:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 7:19 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Tom.  Thanks for that introduction and for your generous support.  And I want to thank you all.  And, Jaime, for your support as well and being willing to take on the chairmanship.  You know, I didn’t have it like you did, but I remember when my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>7:19 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Tom.  Thanks for that introduction and for your generous support.  And I want to thank you all.  And, Jaime, for your support as well and being willing to take on the chairmanship. </p>



<p>You know, I didn’t have it like you did, but I remember when my dad &#8212; when things died up in Scranton; the coal dried up.&nbsp; He wasn’t a coalminer; my great grandfather was.&nbsp; But he wasn’t a coalminer, but everything else dried up.&nbsp; And he said &#8212; I remember him going home to my grandpop, who had four sons and a daughter, and asking him is it okay if his wife &#8212; my mother, Jean &#8212; and the three kids move in with him for a year or so until they got straightened away down in northern Delaware &#8212; a little town called Claymont.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that &#8212; and he said &#8212; I’ll never forget it.&nbsp; He said, “I’ll come home every weekend, Joey.&nbsp; Every weekend.&nbsp; There’s only 147 &#8212; 157 miles.”&nbsp; And I thought, &#8220;My God, that’s a million miles.&#8221;&nbsp; I was going &#8212; I was in third grade, going into fourth.&nbsp; And you know, it’s a &#8212;</p>



<p>They used to have an expression &#8212; and that’s never &#8212; and this is the God’s truth.&nbsp; We got down to Delaware, as he worked his way through, after five years, being able to buy a small three-bedroom home.&nbsp; He used to say, “Joey, a job is a lot more than a paycheck.&nbsp; It’s about &#8212; it’s about your pride.&nbsp; It’s about your place in the community.&nbsp; It’s about your ability to look your kids in the eye.&nbsp; It’s about your dignity.”&nbsp; And so it’s much &#8212; so much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, when I ran with your help &#8212; and I couldn’t have made it &#8212; with all the help of people on this line &#8212; you know &#8212; you know, we are part of something special because you allowed me to compete.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; I think we put together one of the most consequential campaigns in modern history.&nbsp; Because it really was, in my view, a battle for the soul of the nation: basic decency, building the middle class form the bottom up and the middle out, rather than waiting for everything to trickle down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And a lot of you are very successful people on the line, but you shared that view and you gave me the money and contributions to be able to complete &#8212; you know, I say &#8212; I should say “compete.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we’re bound together in one of the most consequential first six months in the history of this country not because of me &#8212; it’s about the country; it’s about people stepping up.</p>



<p>Think about the last six months.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>We delivered shots in arms of millions and millions of people.&nbsp; Checks in pockets to hundreds of millions of Americans.&nbsp; And maybe the thing that I’m proudest of: We got the biggest middle-class tax cut of all time with the help of the &#8212; cutting the child poverty in half through the childcare &#8212; the Child Tax Credit.</p>



<p>And 165 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; You got over 190 that have at least one shot &#8212; one shot.</p>



<p>It’s the fastest job growth in the first four months of any previous presidency.&nbsp; Period.</p>



<p>And a projected economic growth at nearly 7 percent &#8212; the highest in four decades.</p>



<p>And last week, they &#8212; the infrastructure plan that I introduced when I was running and put together with a bipartisan group &#8212; I had to make some compromises, but it’s going to make a gigantic difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, it’s going to transform the economy.&nbsp; It’s over &#8212; over a trillion dollars.&nbsp; It’s going to eliminate all lead pipes in America so people have decent drinking water.&nbsp; Build roads up to &#8212; up to snuff so we build them back to, you know, making sure that they are where the environment is now &#8212; not &#8212; we have to build them back better.&nbsp; Childcare.&nbsp; The caring economy.&nbsp; The eldercare.&nbsp; The things that the American public wants most.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Man, look &#8212; and delivering high-speed Internet to every American.&nbsp; Delivering clean water, as I said, to every American.</p>



<p>Building more resilient power grids.&nbsp; Installing electric vehicle charging stations&#8211; over 500,000.&nbsp; The largest investment in public transit in rail since the creation of Amtrak 50 years ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it’s all about, as my dad’s notion, it’s about creating good-paying American jobs for millions of middle-class people and the working-class people.&nbsp; And it’s about our economic competitiveness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, as a &#8212; as the Democratic Party, I think we’re going to be able to say, going into these off-year elections, as the chairman said, that we can deliver.&nbsp; We can deliver for the American people.&nbsp; We can bring the country together.&nbsp; We can make a difference in their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, it’s about including everyone this time around &#8212; Black, Latino, Asian American, Native American communities &#8212; because I said the administration and our efforts would reflect what the country looked like.</p>



<p>And as I said, we’re in the race for the 21st century economy and the rest of the world is not hanging around and waiting.&nbsp; We have to move fast.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the bottom line, for me, is this: that we’re signaling &#8212; we’re signaling to the rest of the world and to ourselves that we can function, we can deliver, we can do significant things.&nbsp; And we’ve got a lot more to do as we invest in physical infrastructure, also invest in human infrastructure, childcare, paid leave, universal pre-K through two years of &#8212; and two years of community college.</p>



<p>When I hear about, “Well, you know, that&#8217;s not &#8212; that&#8217;s not investing” &#8212; well, let me tell you, when I was Vice President, I was asked to do a survey along the Secretary of Commerce of the 500 CEOs of the five &#8212; Fortune 500 to see what their greatest needs are.&nbsp; We got the 340-some.&nbsp; You know what they said, almost to a person?&nbsp; They said, “We need a better-educated public.”&nbsp; Well, they&#8217;re not educating the public.&nbsp; And so, what are we going to do?&nbsp;</p>



<p>If I said to you tomorrow, “We can maintain exorbitant tax cuts for the super wealthy” &#8212; and many of you are &#8212; “or we can make sure that every kid, starting at age three, four, and five, is in preschool, not daycare, and they have access to community college so we&#8217;re the best-educated public in the world,” which do you think is going to best promote the country&#8217;s growth? You know what it is.</p>



<p>So, look, let me close.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m taking too much time.&nbsp; I want to meet each one of you.&nbsp; But, look, we need &#8212; the single-most important thing that we have to do is we have to protect the voting system, protect the sacred right to vote.&nbsp; It&#8217;s under assault in ways I haven’t seen in my entire career.&nbsp; And I was the guy who was able to get the Voting Rights exten- &#8212; Act extended 25 years before, when I was Chairman of the Judiciary Committee.&nbsp; And it wasn&#8217;t until the Supreme Court came along and said, “No, no, don&#8217;t need it anymore.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s about who gets to vote and whether the vote counts, and who gets to count that vote.&nbsp; We have a system that does both those things with independence and integrity.&nbsp; But what Republicans want to do is say a political party gets to decide if a vote counts.&nbsp; It&#8217;s outrageous.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to fight like hell so that doesn&#8217;t happen.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the most important things we can do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s a lot of work ahead.&nbsp; It’s not going to be easy.&nbsp;&nbsp;But I&#8217;m going to need you to do it.&nbsp; The DNC is going to need you.&nbsp; And because &#8212; here&#8217;s the deal: We won in 2020 as a unified party.&nbsp; As we look to 2022, we need to stay unified.&nbsp; The question the American people are going to be asking is whether we&#8217;re helping them and their families, and do we understand what they&#8217;re going through; do we understand their problem; can we deliver for them.</p>



<p>You know, as Democrats, we have to show that we understand, number one; we&#8217;re delivering, number two; and we&#8217;re keeping our promise.&nbsp; We just have to keep making our case &#8212; just as the Republican party today offers nothing but fear, lies, and broken promises.&nbsp; We have to keep cutting through the Republican fog &#8211;that the government isn&#8217;t the problem, and show that we, the people &#8212; we, the people, are always the solution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re the most unique country in the history of the world.&nbsp; You’ve heard me say this before.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the only country that&#8217;s organized based on an ide- &#8212; on an idea, not religion, ethnicity, geography &#8212; on an idea that we hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men and women are critical equal, endowed &#8212; you know the rest.</p>



<p>But you have to be able to vote.&nbsp; It’s the single-most important thing we could do.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to have to win races up and down the ticket.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, in 2018, I was out of office, but I campaigned in 58 districts &#8212; congressional districts they said we couldn&#8217;t win.&nbsp; We won back the United States Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, look, if we make the right decision in the next few years, in 50 years people are going to look back and say, “This was the moment that America won the 21st century.”&nbsp; I really believe that.&nbsp; But we can&#8217;t do it without you.&nbsp; You know, we have to prove that democracies can work.</p>



<p>I’ll conclude by saying &#8212; and the press on the line has heard me say this before &#8212; that Xi Jinping, and &#8212; who I met hours and hours with &#8212; over 25 hours &#8212; 24 hours alone.&nbsp; When I won, he called me to congratulate me.&nbsp; We spent two hours and, I think, almost 25 minutes on the phone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He believes, along with other autocrats, that in the modern world, things are changing so rapidly, so quickly that democracies can&#8217;t get their acts together and unite to compete with &#8212; with autocratic governments.&nbsp; He truly believes that.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s decided that they&#8217;re going to be the most powerful military force in the world, and the largest economy and the most organized economy in the world by 2045.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve got to demonstrate that democracies can work and protect.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s going to impact on our influence around the world more than anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we have to do some of this stuff together with others to get it done &#8212; get it done.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m convinced there&#8217;s not much we can&#8217;t do.&nbsp; I think the country is ready.&nbsp; And because of you, I think we&#8217;re going to be able to get it done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I want to thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you for everything you&#8217;ve done.&nbsp; And, you know, we got to prove we can make democracy work again.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, God bless you all for what you&#8217;ve done and going &#8212; going to do.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.</p>



<p>7:29 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UPDATED FACT SHEET: Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investment Jobs&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/updated-fact-sheet-bipartisan-infrastructure-and-investment-jobs-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 02:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 28, the President and the bipartisan group announced agreement on the details of a once-in-a-generation investment in our infrastructure, which was immediately taken up in the Senate for consideration. The legislation includes around $550 billion in new federal investment in America’s roads and bridges, water infrastructure, resilience, internet, and more. The bipartisan Infrastructure&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 28, the President and the bipartisan group announced agreement on the details of a once-in-a-generation investment in our infrastructure, which was immediately taken up in the Senate for consideration. The legislation includes around $550 billion in new federal investment in America’s roads and bridges, water infrastructure, resilience, internet, and more. The bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act will grow the economy, enhance our competitiveness, create good jobs, and make our economy more sustainable, resilient, and just.</p>



<p>The legislation will create good-paying, union jobs. With the President’s Build Back Better Agenda, these investments will add, on average, around 2 million jobs&nbsp;per year&nbsp;over the course of the decade, while accelerating America’s path to full employment and increasing labor force participation.</p>



<p>President Biden believes that we must invest in our country and in our people by creating good-paying union jobs, tackling the climate crisis, and growing the economy sustainably and equitably for decades to come. The bipartisan legislation will deliver progress towards those objectives for working families across the country. The bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act:</p>



<ul><li>Makes the largest federal investment in public transit ever</li><li>Makes the largest federal investment in passenger rail since the creation of Amtrak</li><li>Makes the single largest dedicated bridge investment since the construction of the interstate highway system</li><li>Makes the largest investment in clean drinking water and waste water infrastructure in American history, delivering clean water to millions of families</li><li>Ensures every American has access to reliable high-speed internet</li><li>Helps us tackle the climate crisis by making the largest investment in clean energy transmission and EV infrastructure in history; electrifying thousands of school and transit buses across the country; and creating a new Grid Deployment Authority to build a resilient, clean, 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century electric grid</li></ul>



<p>The President promised to work across the aisle to deliver results for working families. He believes demonstrating that democracies can deliver is a critical challenge for his presidency. Today’s agreement shows that we can come together to position American workers, farmers, and businesses to compete and win in the 21st century.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Roads, Bridges, and Major Projects<br></strong></span><br>One in five miles, or 173,000 total miles, of our highways and major roads and 45,000 bridges are in poor condition. Bridges in poor condition pose heightened challenges in rural communities, which often may rely on a single bridge for the passage of emergency service vehicles. The bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act will invest $110 billion of new funds for roads, bridges, and major projects, and reauthorize the surface transportation program for the next five years building on bipartisan surface transportation reauthorization bills passed out of committee earlier this year. This investment will repair and rebuild our roads and bridges with a focus on climate change mitigation, resilience, equity, and safety for all users, including cyclists and pedestrians. The bill includes a total of $40 billion of new funding for bridge repair, replacement, and rehabilitation, which&nbsp;is the single largest dedicated bridge investment since the construction of the interstate highway system. The bill also includes around $16 billion for major projects that are too large or complex for traditional funding programs but will deliver significant economic benefits to communities.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Safety</strong></span><br><br>America has one of the highest road fatality rates in the industrialized world. The legislation invests $11 billion in transportation safety programs, including a new, $5 billion Safe Streets for All program to help states and localities reduce crashes and fatalities in their communities, especially for cyclists and pedestrians.&nbsp;It includes a new program to provide grants to community owned utilities to replace leaky and obsolete cast iron and bare steel natural gas pipelines, some of which are over 100 years old. It will more than double funding directed to programs that improve the safety of people and vehicles in our transportation system, including highway safety, truck safety, and pipeline and hazardous materials safety.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Public Transit<br></span></strong><br>America’s transit infrastructure is inadequate – with a multibillion-dollar repair backlog, representing more than 24,000 buses, 5,000 rail cars, 200 stations, and thousands of miles of track, signals, and power systems in need of replacement. The legislation includes $39 billion of new investment to modernize transit, and improve accessibility for the elderly and people with disabilities. That is in addition to continuing the existing transit programs for five years as part of surface transportation reauthorization. In total, the new investments and reauthorization provide $89.9 billion in guaranteed funding for public transit over the next five years. This is the largest Federal investment in public transit in history, and devotes a larger share of funds from surface transportation reauthorization to transit in the history of the programs. It will repair and upgrade aging infrastructure, modernize bus and rail fleets, make stations accessible to all users through a new program with $1.75 billion in dedicated funding, and bring transit service to new communities with an additional $8 billion for Capital Investment Grants.&nbsp;It will replace thousands of transit vehicles, including buses, with clean, zero emission vehicles through an additional $5.75 billion, of which 5 percent is dedicated to training the transit workforce to maintain and operate these vehicles. And, it will benefit communities of color since these households are twice as likely to take public transportation and many of these communities lack sufficient public transit options.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Passenger and Freight Rail<br></span></strong><br>Unlike highways and transit, rail lacks a multi-year funding stream to address deferred maintenance, enhance existing corridors, and build new lines in high-potential locations. The legislation positions Amtrak and rail to play a central role in our transportation and economic future.&nbsp;This is the largest investment in passenger rail since the creation of Amtrak 50 years ago.&nbsp;The legislation invests $66 billion in rail to eliminate the Amtrak maintenance backlog, modernize the Northeast Corridor, and bring world-class rail service to areas outside the northeast and mid-Atlantic. Within these totals, $22 billion would be provided as grants to Amtrak, $24 billion as federal-state partnership grants for Northeast Corridor modernization, $12 billion for partnership grants for intercity rail service, including high-speed rail, $5 billion for rail improvement and safety grants, and $3 billion for grade crossing safety improvements.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">EV Infrastructure<br></span></strong><br>U.S. market share of plug-in electric vehicle (EV) sales is only one-third the size of the Chinese EV market. The President believes that must change. The bill invests $7.5 billion to build out the first-ever national network of EV chargers in the United States and is a critical element in the Biden-Harris Administration’s plan to accelerate the adoption of EVs to address the climate crisis and support domestic manufacturing jobs.&nbsp;The bill will provide funding for deployment of EV chargers along highway corridors to facilitate long-distance travel and within communities to provide convenient charging where people live, work, and shop. Federal funding will have a particular focus on rural, disadvantaged, and hard-to-reach communities.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Electric Buses</span></strong><br><br>American school buses play a critical role in expanding access to education, but they are also a significant source of pollution.&nbsp;The legislation will deliver thousands of electric school buses nationwide, including in rural communities, helping school districts across the country buy clean, American-made, zero emission buses, and replace the yellow school bus fleet for America’s children.&nbsp;The legislation also invests $5 billion in zero emission and clean buses and $2.5 billion for ferries. These investments will drive demand for American-made batteries and vehicles, creating jobs and supporting domestic manufacturing, while also removing diesel buses from some of our most vulnerable communities. In addition, they will help the more than 25 million children and thousands of bus drivers who breathe polluted air on their rides to and from school. Diesel air pollution is linked to asthma and other health problems that hurt our communities and cause students to miss school, particularly in communities of color and Tribal communities.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Reconnecting Communities</span></strong><br><br>Too often, past transportation investments divided communities – like the Claiborne Expressway in New Orleans or I-81 in Syracuse – or it left out the people most in need of affordable transportation options. In particular, significant portions of the interstate highway system were built through Black neighborhoods.&nbsp;The legislation creates a first-ever program to reconnect communities divided by transportation infrastructure. The program will fund planning, design, demolition, and reconstruction of street grids, parks, or other infrastructure through $1 billion of dedicated funding in addition to historic levels of major projects funding, for which these investments could also qualify.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Airports, Ports, and Waterways<br></span></strong><br>The United States built modern aviation, but our airports lag far behind our competitors. According to some rankings, no U.S. airports rank in the top 25 of airports worldwide. Our ports and waterways need repair and reimagination too.&nbsp;The bill invests $17 billion in port infrastructure and $25 billion in airports to address repair and maintenance backlogs, reduce congestion and emissions near ports and airports, and drive electrification and other low-carbon technologies. Modern, resilient, and sustainable port, airport, and freight infrastructure will support U.S. competitiveness by removing bottlenecks and expediting commerce and reduce the environmental impact on neighboring communities.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Resilience and Western Water Infrastructure<br></span></strong><br>Millions of Americans feel the effects of climate change each year when their roads wash out, airport power goes down, or schools get flooded. Last year alone, the United States faced 22 extreme weather and climate-related disaster events with losses exceeding $1 billion each – a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion. People of color are more likely to live in areas most vulnerable to flooding and other climate change-related weather events.&nbsp;The legislation makes our communities safer and our infrastructure more resilient to the impacts of climate change and cyber-attacks, with an investment of over $50 billion.&nbsp;This includes funds to protect against droughts, floods and wildfires, in addition to a major investment in weatherization. The bill is the largest investment in the resilience of physical and natural systems in American history.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Clean Drinking Water<br></span></strong><br>Currently, up to 10 million American households and 400,000 schools and child care centers lack safe drinking water.&nbsp;The legislation’s $55 billion investment represents the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history, including dedicated funding to replace lead service lines and the dangerous chemical PFAS (per- and polyfluoroalkyl).&nbsp;It will replace all of the nation’s lead pipes and service lines. From rural towns to struggling cities, the legislation invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal Nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">High-Speed Internet<br></span></strong><br>Broadband internet is necessary for Americans to do their jobs, to participate equally in school learning, health care, and to stay connected. Yet, by one definition, more than 30 million Americans live in areas where there is no broadband infrastructure that provides minimally acceptable speeds – a particular problem in rural communities throughout the country. The legislation’s $65 billion investment – which builds on the billions of dollars provided for broadband deployment in the American Rescue Plan – will help ensure every American has access to reliable high-speed internet with an historic investment in broadband infrastructure deployment, just as the federal government made a historic effort to provide electricity to every American nearly one hundred years ago.<br><br>The bill will also help lower prices for internet service by requiring funding recipients to offer a low-cost affordable plan, by requiring providers to display a “Broadband Nutrition Label” that will help families comparison shop for a better deal, and by boosting competition in areas where existing providers aren’t providing adequate service. It will also help close the digital divide by passing the Digital Equity Act (which creates new grant programs for digital inclusion), by requiring the Federal Communications Commission to adopt rules banning digital redlining, and by creating a new, permanent program to help more low-income households access the internet. Over one in four households will be eligible for this new Affordable Connectivity Benefit.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Environmental Remediation</span></strong><br><br>In thousands of rural and urban communities around the country, hundreds of thousands of former industrial and energy sites are now idle – sources of blight and pollution. 26% of Black Americans and 29% of Hispanic Americans live within 3 miles of a Superfund site, a higher percentage than for Americans overall. Proximity to a Superfund site can lead to elevated levels of lead in children’s blood.&nbsp;The legislation invests $21 billion in environmental remediation, making the largest investment in addressing the legacy pollution that harms the public health of communities and neighborhoods in American history, creating good-paying union jobs in hard-hit energy communities and advancing economic and environmental justice.&nbsp;The bill includes funds to clean up Superfund and brownfield sites, reclaim abandoned mine land and cap orphaned gas wells.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Power Infrastructure</span></strong><br><br>As the recent Texas power outages demonstrated, our aging electric grid needs urgent modernization. A Department of Energy study found that power outages cost the U.S. economy up to $70 billion annually.&nbsp;The legislation’s roughly $65 billion investment includes the single largest investment in clean energy transmission in American history. It upgrades our power infrastructure, including by building thousands of miles of new, resilient transmission lines to facilitate the expansion of renewable energy. It creates a new Grid Deployment Authority, invests in research and development for advanced transmission and electricity distribution technologies, and promotes smart grid technologies that deliver flexibility and resilience. It invests in demonstration projects and research hubs for next generation technologies like advanced nuclear, carbon capture, and clean hydrogen.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Offsets</span></strong><br><br>In the years ahead, the legislation will generate significant economic benefits. It is financed through a combination of redirecting unspent emergency relief funds, targeted corporate user fees, strengthening tax enforcement when it comes to crypto currencies, and other bipartisan measures, in addition to the revenue generated from higher economic growth as a result of the investments.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/02/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-47/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25789</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  4:18 P.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; And thanks for joining us.&#160; I&#8217;ll turn to Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci in a moment.&#160; First, I want to provide an update on our whole-of-government response to the pandemic.&#160; We remain concerned about the continued rise in cases driven by the Delta variant.&#160; These cases&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference </p>



<p>4:18 P.M. EDT<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; And thanks for joining us.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll turn to Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci in a moment.&nbsp; First, I want to provide an update on our whole-of-government response to the pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>We remain concerned about the continued rise in cases driven by the Delta variant.&nbsp; These cases are concentrated in communities with lower vaccination rates.&nbsp; In fact, the seven states with the lowest vaccination rates represent just about 8.5 percent of the U.S. population but account for more than 17 percent of cases.&nbsp; And one in three cases nationwide occurred in Florida and Texas this past week.&nbsp;<br><br>From the start, we&#8217;ve known that this virus is unpredictable.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we spent the last six months preparing for every scenario.&nbsp; As a result, we have the tools we need to manage this most &#8212; this.&nbsp; Most importantly &#8212; the tool that is most important is the highly effective vaccines.&nbsp; We have enough vaccines for every American who wants one.&nbsp; They&#8217;re free and they&#8217;re easily accessible &#8212; within five miles of where 90 percent of where Americans live.&nbsp;<br><br>And in just six months, we&#8217;ve already gotten 165 million Americans fully vaccinated &#8212; including 80 percent of seniors, who are the most vulnerable.<br><br>But we have much more work to do to put this pandemic behind us.&nbsp; There are still about 90 million eligible Americans who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; And we need them to do their part, roll up their sleeves, and get vaccinated.&nbsp; Each and every shot matters.&nbsp;<br><br>And last week, the President laid out several areas where we&#8217;re taking additional steps to get more Americans vaccinated.&nbsp; We expanded the tax credit to help small- and medium-sized businesses provide their employees paid time off to get themselves and also their families vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re working with school districts and pharmacies to bring vaccines to schools to make it as convenient as possible for students to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>In the past two weeks, we&#8217;ve seen a 50 percent increase in the average number of 12- to 17-year-olds getting vaccinated each day.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a very encouraging uptick.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also working with states to encourage vaccinations through incentives, which have made a difference throughout the vaccination effort.&nbsp; Last week, the President called on states and local governments to use funding they have received, including from the American Rescue Plan, to give $100 to anyone who gets fully vaccinated.&nbsp; Minnesota and New Mexico have already stepped up to answer the President&#8217;s call.&nbsp;<br><br>If financial incentives like these help us get more shots in arms, we should use them.&nbsp; But in addition to incentives, it&#8217;s time to impose some requirements based on the realities of different risks unvaccinated individuals pose versus those who have been vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Last week, the Department of Veteran Affairs announced it will require doctors and nurses and other healthcare workers who provide medical care to our veterans to get vaccinated.&nbsp; This is in lockstep with many healthcare employers around the country who are requiring vaccinations and will protect our veterans when they get medical care.<br><br>At the President&#8217;s direction, the Department of Defense is looking into how and when they will add the COVID-19 vaccination to the list of required vaccinations for the military.<br><br>And to protect the federal workforce, their loved ones, and their communities, the President announced that every federal government employee will be asked to attest to their vaccination status.&nbsp; Any federal employee who does not attest or is not vaccinated will be required to mask, no matter where they work; get tested once or twice a week; socially distance; and, generally, will not be allowed to travel for work.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re taking steps to apply similar standards to all federal contractors.&nbsp; It&#8217;s simple: If you want to do business with the federal government, get your workers vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>And the President has called on all employers around the country to protect their own workforces.&nbsp; And now we&#8217;re seeing positive momentum across the private sector.&nbsp; The Chamber of Commerce, the National Association of Manufacturers, and the Business Roundtable have all applauded the actions we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; Companies like Google, Walmart, and Disney have announced vaccination requirements for their employees, joining hundreds of universities and hospital systems across the country who are implementing similar requirements.&nbsp;<br><br>With these ongoing efforts, there&#8217;s a strong sense of progress.&nbsp; And you see it in the number of shots we&#8217;re getting into people&#8217;s arms each day.&nbsp;<br><br>Over the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve seen a nearly 70 percent increase in the average number of new people getting vaccinated each and every day.&nbsp; In the last seven days alone, 3 million Americans have gotten their first shot.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the highest seven-day totals since July 4th.<br><br>And just today, we hit 70 percent of adults with at least one shot, including 90 percent of seniors with at least one shot.&nbsp; These are significant milestones in our fight against the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>And it&#8217;s very important to note, in the states with the highest case rates, daily vaccination rates have more than doubled.&nbsp; The eight states with highest current case rates have seen an average increase of 171 percent in the number of people newly vaccinated each day over the past three weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Louisiana has seen a 302 percent increase in the average number of newly vaccinated per day; Mississippi, 250 percent;&nbsp;Alabama, 215 percent; and Arkansas, 206 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This increase in vaccination rates in states that have been lagging is a positive trend.&nbsp; Americans are seeing the risk and impact of being unvaccinated and responding with action.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what it&#8217;s going to take to get us out of this pandemic.</p>



<p>With that, let me turn it over to Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp; As of Saturday, CDC reported the seven-day moving average of daily new COVID-19 cases to be about 72,000 cases per day.&nbsp; This represents an increase of 44 percent from the prior seven-day average and higher than our peak of last summer.</p>



<p>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 6,200 per day, an increase of about 41 percent from the prior seven-day period.&nbsp; And seven-day average daily deaths have also increased to 300 per day &#8212; an increase of more than 25 percent from the previous seven-day period.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to start today by simply stating the obvious.&nbsp; While we desperately want to be done with this pandemic, COVID-19 is clearly not done with us, and so our battle must last a little longer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many of us have lost loved ones or have been ill ourselves.&nbsp; All of us have given up things in our lives that we enjoy.&nbsp; This is hard, this is heavy, but we are in this together.&nbsp; And as we learn more about COVID, we continue to rely on proven ways to protect ourselves, our children, and our loved ones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I told you I would give you scientific information as I have it, when I have it.&nbsp; Here is what we have learned in the last two weeks about the Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, the Delta variant is highly contagious. &nbsp;To put this in perspective, if you get sick with the Alpha variant, you could infect about two other unvaccinated people.&nbsp; If you get sick with the Delta variant, we estimate that you could infect about five other unvaccinated people &#8212; more than twice as many as the original strain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, infections with the Delta variant result in higher viral loads.&nbsp; This means that those who are infected have a larger burden of virus that they can spread to others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, those higher viral loads are seen not just in those who are unvaccinated and infected but also, and importantly, in the small proportion of those who are vaccinated and become infected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last week, we published data on an outbreak in Barnstable County, Massachusetts, where there were 346 confirmed cases of COVID-19 in people who were fully vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the summer, some towns in Barnstable County can have up to 240,000 visitors per month.&nbsp; Those with breakthrough infections had viral loads that were similar to people who were infected and unvaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This new finding, combined with data from other outbreak investigations and surveillance studies across the country, was critical in our decision to update our guidance for those who are fully vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since those data were released, several other studies have been released over just this past weekend that have corroborated these findings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Taken together, the Delta variant is different from prior strains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I understand this is all frustrating news, and I share this frustration.&nbsp; We continue to learn each day from emerging science and use this evidence to update our recommendations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because of what we now know about the Delta variant and infections in those who are vaccinated, we updated our recommendations, including recommending masks in public, indoor settings in areas with substantial and high transmission, shown in orange and red on this map.&nbsp; It is also the reason we continue to recommend universal indoor masking in K-through-12 schools throughout the country so our children can safely get back to school and safely stay there.</p>



<p>In all of this, there is still good news.&nbsp; Our vaccines are working to prevent severe illness, hospitalizations, and death.&nbsp; Vaccines are providing protection both for individuals and communities across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I have said before, this remains a pandemic of the unvaccinated, where the vast majority of spread is &#8212; in this country is among those who are unvaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to be clear: While vaccinated people can spread the virus if they get a breakthrough infection, the odds of them getting sick in the first place are far lower than those who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; And in fact, places with more vaccination generally have less disease.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can see this on a population level on this slide, where we compare case counts and vaccination coverage by state, with vaccination coverage on the horizontal axis and case counts on the vertical axis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>States with the highest vaccination coverage are the dots furthest to the right on the graph, and states with the highest case counts are the dots closest to the top.&nbsp; Notice that the states that have lower vaccination coverage &#8212; those further to the left &#8212; have higher rates of community transmission, as shown in red and orange.&nbsp; States that have higher vaccination coverage &#8212; further to the right &#8212; have lower rates of cases, as shown in yellow.</p>



<p>There is any direct correlation with vaccine coverage and case rates.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s worth reiterating that public health prevention strategies, including masks, continue to work while you&#8217;re unvaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the following outbreaks of cases in Barnstable County and in subsequent public health follow-up, we saw the power of vaccines and masks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the month of July, there were a total of 934 confirmed cases of COVID-19 linked to the outbreak in Barnstable County.&nbsp; With 73 percent of these infections in people who were vaccinated, there were only seven hospitalizations and no deaths.<br><br>Our vaccines did exactly what they were supposed to do: prevent severe disease, hospitalization, and death.<br><br>Furthermore, as cases increased, local public health officials implemented a package of public health prevention strategies, including increased testing, contact tracing, and indoor mask wearing.&nbsp; And within two weeks, test positivity fell from a peak of 15.1 percent to 4.6 percent.&nbsp; Public health prevention strategies work.<br><br>Let me end by reiterating three things you need to know. First, our vaccines are working to prevent severe illness, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; And if you are not vaccinated, please protect yourself and get vaccinated.<br><br>Second, masks will protect you and your family.&nbsp; If you are in an area of substantial or high transmission, please wear a mask in public indoor settings, regardless of your vaccination status.<br><br>And third, we need to keep our children safe and in school. Get everyone in your family over the age of 12 vaccinated and please wear masks in school.<br><br>Finally, we stand here with you, providing science and updated guidance in real time, to keep you and your families safe.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn it over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to take up on the theme that Dr. Walensky started with.<br><br>If I could have the first slide.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to be spending a couple of minutes addressing two issues that are very much on the attention of people throughout the country and the world.<br><br>The first is, as Dr. Walensky mentioned, the real-world effectiveness of vaccines in the context of the Delta variant, and, second, breakthrough infections, what they mean.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s discuss them a bit.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Let&#8217;s look at the real-world effectiveness against the Delta variant.&nbsp; If you look at the three components of PCR-confirmed infection, it&#8217;s 79 percent in a UK study.&nbsp; Symptomatic infection is 88 percent.<br><br>And just as Dr. Walensky mentioned, the vaccines are doing exactly what we&#8217;re asking them to do when it comes to keeping you out of the hospital, out of serious disease, and certainly preventing your death.<br><br>Just a quick comment on the 79 percent:&nbsp;That may look a bit low, but remember, the efficacy of the clinical trials that were published by the trials that gave you something like 94 or 95 percent was against clinically apparent disease.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re talking about here is just infection, so you would expect it to be a bit lower.&nbsp; This has important implications when you get into the discussion of what we call &#8220;breakthrough infections.&#8221;<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Now, if you take these data and look at them across multiple countries but ask the question, “What does a full component of a Pfizer mRNA provide with regard to protection against Alpha versus Delta in three separate countries?” &#8212; the data on the left are essentially the data I just showed you; Alpha now is in blue and Delta is in red.&nbsp;<br><br>When you get to Canada, you see a similar protection against hospitalization, which is the area a bit to the right in that middle panel, compared to symptomatic disease.&nbsp; When you get to Israel, you see what we now know from reports from Israel: that you see a diminution at around 64 percent for confirmed and symptomatic disease.&nbsp; This is likely due to the fact that Israel has started their vaccination program before the other countries, so you&#8217;re seeing a little bit down the pipe from the beginning.&nbsp; But note, again, the 93 percent consistently showing protection against advanced disease.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Now if you ask the question, “What about the reduced risk of either symptomatic infection, hospitalization, or death when you compare vaccinated individuals with unvaccinated people, what is the fold reduction when you&#8217;re in red, with unvaccinated, versus in blue, with full vaccinated?”&nbsp; As you can see for disease itself, it&#8217;s an eight-fold reduction.&nbsp; For hospitalization, 25-fold reduction.&nbsp; And for death, 25-fold reduction.<br><br>Let&#8217;s move on now to breakthrough infections.&nbsp; Just a couple of comments.&nbsp;<br><br>We can pass this slide.&nbsp; Go to the next slide, please.<br><br>The breakthrough infections: We have &#8212; no vaccine is 100 percent effective, and so you can expect breakthrough infections.&nbsp; So, even with a high vaccine effectiveness, most of these infections are going to be asymptomatic or mild.&nbsp; And we know that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already seen that from the experience in Massachusetts, in Provincetown, and we see it in all other situations.<br><br>An important point to bring up is that the greater percentage of people that are vaccinated, even with a high degree of protection, the absolute number of breakthrough infections might appear high.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not the critical number. The critical number is what is the proportion of the vaccinated people who, in fact, are getting breakthrough infections.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the critical one.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line of what we are saying is that &#8212; next slide &#8212; get vaccinated.&nbsp; I say that every single time.&nbsp; We all say it.&nbsp; The COVID vaccines give strong protection against the Delta variant, and it protects you, your family, and your community.<br><br>Back to you, Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Fauci, and thank you, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As you both stated, it&#8217;s never been more important to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we stop the spread of the Delta variant.&nbsp; And each and every shot matters.<br><br>And while we work to get more people vaccinated, the federal government is also helping states and communities respond to outbreaks.&nbsp;<br><br>Since launching our COVID-19 surge teams, we&#8217;ve been working directly with 10 states to support their efforts to combat rising cases with federal assistance and support.<br><br>Last week, we reiterated to all governors that we stand ready to help them in meeting this moment, whether that be through more testing, increasing treatments, vaccine access and uptake, or other state-specific needs.<br><br>For example, in Missouri, CDC experts are on the ground providing epidemiology, data analysis, and other public health support.&nbsp; FEMA in Missouri is helping to expand ambulance capacity, and HHS and FEMA are helping the state address their hospital needs.<br><br>We&#8217;re working with states like North Carolina on mobile vaccination clinics.&nbsp; In Tennessee, on public health staffing. And the administration is doing extensive outreach in states like Wyoming and Arizona to encourage more physicians to use lifesaving monoclonal antibody treatments &#8212; antibody treatments.&nbsp; Those are really effective, and we need to deploy them more and more where they&#8217;re needed.<br><br>The bottom line is, we&#8217;re doing everything we can to help more Americans get vaccinated and to help states fight the spread in their communities.<br><br>With that, let&#8217;s take a few questions.<br><br>First question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; And a reminder &#8212;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Could I please interject something?&nbsp; Jeff, I want to just add one thing.&nbsp; One of the slides was deleted &#8212; a technical difficulty that I&#8217;d just like to spend maybe 15 seconds.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Please.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s really important.&nbsp; When we talk &#8212; it was mistakenly deleted, and that&#8217;s the reason why I skipped by that other slide.&nbsp;<br><br>When you look at breakthrough infections, as I mentioned, they&#8217;re expected and usually asymptomatic.&nbsp;<br><br>As of July 26th, the CDC received 6,587 reports of breakthrough infections that resulted in hospitalization or death among 163 &#8212; fully vaccinated &#8212; million people.&nbsp; That is a percentage of 0.01 percent or less.<br><br>And when you look at the breakthrough cases, the percent of breakthrough cases in multiple locations, like D.C. and Virginia, the percent ranges from 0.26 to 0.03.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I&#8217;m sorry that was left out.&nbsp; The bottom line is they are rare, and they rarely result &#8212; not rarely, but unusually result in hospitalization or death.<br><br>Thanks, Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp;<br><br>Okay, first question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Please keep your question to one question.&nbsp; We&#8217;re very limited on time.<br><br>Jeff Mason, Reuters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks very much.&nbsp; Jeff, you said earlier that it was time to do &#8212; to have requirements with relation to the vaccine, and then you went on to list basically what you said last week about the VA and the &#8212; and DOD.&nbsp; Are there more requirements coming?&nbsp; Do you think that there should be more requirements coming?&nbsp; And can you respond broadly to the impression that you are playing down the breakthrough cases?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll take the &#8212; the first part of the question, and then I&#8217;ll turn it to Dr. Fauci because he just talked about breakthrough cases.<br><br>Jeff, as you know, in the federal government, we&#8217;ve now put forward a strong system that if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you can come back to work as normal.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re not vaccinated, there are quite strict rules that you need to follow around testing, social distancing, and masking.<br><br>The Department of Veterans Affairs, as you said, is an example of a vaccine requirement for all of their caregivers to our veterans.&nbsp; The President has asked the Department of Defense to look into how they will add COVID to the list of mandatory vaccinations for our armed forces &#8212; how and when they would do that.&nbsp; We will be looking, across the federal government, in other areas that could require these types of req- &#8212; mandates, if you will, for vaccination.<br><br>At the same time, I think it&#8217;s really encouraging that we&#8217;re seeing the private sector follow.&nbsp; I mentioned Walmart, Disney, and Google all announcing vaccine requirements, and there&#8217;s dozens of other companies that are doing these types of actions to protect their workers as they come back to work &#8212; universities, other health systems.<br><br>So, Jeff, I think you&#8217;re going to see a continued increase in vaccination requirements as people bring employees back to work.&nbsp;<br><br>Second question was around breakthroughs.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, what was the exact question about breakthrough, Jeff?&nbsp; I missed that.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; This is Jeff Zients.&nbsp; Jeff Mason was asking: Are we downplaying, in some way, the number of breakthrough infections that are happening across the country?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; No, no, we&#8217;re actually not, Jeff &#8212; Jeff Mason, that is.&nbsp; (Laughs.) &nbsp;I &#8212; as I mentioned in the discussion, when you look at the numbers &#8212; the total absolute numbers when you&#8217;re dealing with a cohort that you&#8217;re examining, that is a very high percentage of people who are vaccinated or large numbers &#8212; by definition, even with a high degree of efficacy, you&#8217;re going to see absolute numbers that are high.&nbsp;<br><br>The critical issue is: What is the relative number &#8212; the percent that I mentioned?&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the reason why &#8212; I apologize &#8212; I wanted to interject that slide that was left out: to show you the lower percentage of people who are in that category.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Is Sheryl Stolberg, New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; A lot of Americans remain very confused about the recommendations.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t understand why vaccinated people need to start wearing masks again.&nbsp; They&#8217;re confused about what this means for their children in schools.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if you think your messaging has been clear enough to the public.&nbsp; And what, if anything, are you going to do to try to address the confusion and maybe simplify things for ordinary Americans out there who don&#8217;t follow every nuance of the science?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr.&nbsp;Walensky?&nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY: Yeah, thank you, Sheryl.&nbsp; So maybe I&#8217;ll start with the children and say I think our guidance is very clear about where we should be in schools.&nbsp; And that is: Everyone who is in a K-through-12 school in the fall should be masked.&nbsp; Everyone across the country &#8212; adults, children, vaccinated, or unvaccinated &#8212; everyone should be masked.<br>In terms of the question about guidance for vaccinated people wearing masks, there are two components to what we&#8217;re trying to do here.&nbsp; One, is, we&#8217;re trying to save lives with our vaccines.&nbsp; And they’re working to do so, and that’s terrific.&nbsp; What they weren&#8217;t studied in the clinical trials is to whether they prevent transmission.&nbsp; Initially, they did with Alpha.&nbsp; Unfortunately, they no longer do with Delta.<br><br>The good news is that the vaccines really do work to prevent getting sick.&nbsp; However, for those people who do get sick, we are suggesting &#8212; the data suggests that you could potentially transmit.&nbsp; And for that reason, we are suggesting both vaccinated and unvaccinated, in areas of high disease burden &#8212; orange or red on the map &#8212; continue to wear masks so they don&#8217;t bring the disease home or to others who are unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; I would just add that, from day one, the President said we would lead with science and facts, and that continues to be the approach at CDC.&nbsp; And our other health experts are doing just that: leading with science and facts.<br><br>We never said that this was going to be easy, but the best thing we can do right now is listen to the science and get more people vaccinated and follow the CDC public health recommendations.<br><br>Next question.<br><br>OPERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Erin Billups at Spectrum.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp; I was wondering how much of any surveillance is being done to determine the amount of asymptomatic spread?&nbsp; Experts I&#8217;ve spoken to say not enough of this is happening.&nbsp;<br><br>Also, to help people get a sense of how much protection previous COVID infections offer &#8212; that&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve heard a lot of people point to as a reason they don&#8217;t need to be vaccinated.&nbsp; Is there any data on the number of people infected with Delta who had previous COVID infections, and whether that offered them any protection?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, first.&nbsp; And then, Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, we have numerous cohort studies that are examining exactly that.&nbsp; So we have several cohorts &#8212; tens of thousands of people across the country &#8212; where some of them are actually doing weekly PCR testing.&nbsp; These are cohorts of essential workers and healthcare workers.&nbsp; So we can actually examine how much disease is occurring in people who might be asymptomatic.&nbsp; That is the best epidemiologic way to study exactly that question.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; The &#8212;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; With regard to the second question that if you&#8217;re dealing with the same variant, if you get infected with an Alpha variant or another variant, and that you recover from that, you are pretty well protected for a reasonable period of time from reinfection.&nbsp; It isn&#8217;t perfect, but it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s good protection.&nbsp; You can&#8217;t doubt that.<br><br>The situation changes when you&#8217;re dealing with the evolution of a new variant, such as the Delta variant.&nbsp; And what we are seeing right now that there are reinfections.&nbsp; The protection you get from the original infection still exists somewhat, but reinfections occur at a much greater rate among individuals now than we did against the original Alpha.<br><br>So, bottom line is: When you&#8217;re dealing with a variant, you don&#8217;t get the kind of protection that you would have hoped to have gotten from a previous infection.<br><br>Regarding the issue of vaccinating people: There&#8217;s no doubt when you vaccinate someone who has had an original infection and who has recovered, not only do you increase the depth of the protection, not only do you increase the duration, but you also increase the breadth of it so that you cover not only the original, but the variants.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s the reason why the recommendation still holds that even though you&#8217;ve been infected previously, in the context of variants, it&#8217;s a good idea to get vaccinated anyway.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Go to Rachel Cohrs at STAT news.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; I had a question for Director Walensky about, you know, whether the CDC is tracking COVID-19 booster shots that may be authorized by physicians.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; We are just &#8212; thank you for that question, Rachel &#8212; we are just starting to gather data and get data on &#8212; and we can discern between people who have gotten second and third shots.&nbsp; We are trying hard to encourage people to report on the safety side if people have taken the initiative to get their third shot &#8212; again, not yet recommended &#8212; but we have the capacity and are looking at those data right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, anything to add there?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; No, nothing to add.&nbsp; She said it very well.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Alright.&nbsp; We got to do last question.&nbsp; Let’s go to Zeke with AP.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you all for doing this.&nbsp; I’m just following up on Jeff Mason’s question earlier for you, Jeff Zients, on the additional requirements.&nbsp; It seems what you&#8217;re trying to do here is impose some sort of cost on people who are unvaccinated as a stick there and sort of get them to roll up their sleeve and get the shot.&nbsp; So why isn’t the federal government going further on some of these &#8212; you know, whether it be mandating vaccination requirements for travel &#8212; across the federal workforce, for instance.&nbsp; You know, how far is the administration willing to go to sort of, you know, turn up the pressure on the unvaccinated to actually get shots?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, Zeke, I think we&#8217;ve taken significant steps here to make it difficult to come back to work, or more difficult to come back to work, if you&#8217;re not vaccinated.&nbsp; There&#8217;s so many reasons to get vaccinated that we&#8217;ve talked about &#8212; to protect yourself and to protect your loved ones.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s also a really straightforward way to return to work.&nbsp;<br><br>So for all federal employees, the path back to work if you&#8217;re vaccinated is straightforward.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re not vaccinated or you&#8217;re not willing to attest to being vaccinated, then you &#8212; we’re doing the right thing to protect the workforce, to protect the individual, their family, and their colleagues, which is rigorous testing, social distancing, and masking.&nbsp;<br><br>There are mandates at the VA for vaccination for their healthcare workers &#8212; their doctors and their nurses and other healthcare providers who take care of our veterans.&nbsp; That&#8217;s consistent with a lot of health systems across the country and a growing number of health systems that are requiring vaccination for their healthcare workers who are on the frontlines.&nbsp;<br><br>As I said earlier, the Department of Defense is looking into how and when they&#8217;ll add COVID to the list of mandatory vaccinations for active-duty military.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, we will continue to look across the federal government at other areas where requirement- &#8212; requiring vaccines, everyone be vaccinated may make sense, particularly in the healthcare setting.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re seeing it in the private sector.&nbsp; More and more companies are coming up with systems that are modeled after our system or similar to our system, or requiring vaccinations across the board.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;re seeing it at universities.&nbsp; You&#8217;re seeing it in health systems.&nbsp; So I think that this requiring of individuals to be vaccinated in order to come back to work or to go back to school is a growing trend and makes a lot of sense, given that we&#8217;re going to beat this pandemic by getting more and more people vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank everybody for today.&nbsp; I look forward to the next briefing.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>4:52 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COVID-Press-Briefing_2August2021_for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COVID-Press-Briefing_2August2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of&#160;Canada</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-prime-minister-justin-trudeau-of-canada-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Justin Trudeau, Prime Minister of Canada to thank him for the gift of Montreal smoked meats sent in congratulations for the Tampa Bay Lightning’s victory over the Montreal Canadiens for the Stanley Cup trophy. The President underscored the close alignment and friendship between the United States and Canada,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Justin Trudeau, Prime Minister of Canada to thank him for the gift of Montreal smoked meats sent in congratulations for the Tampa Bay Lightning’s victory over the Montreal Canadiens for the Stanley Cup trophy. The President underscored the close alignment and friendship between the United States and Canada, as they also discussed bilateral economic cooperation and their shared commitment to strengthening the resilience and competitiveness of the U.S. and Canadian economies. The President and Prime Minister then discussed the two Canadian citizens—Michael Kovrig and Michael Spavor—who are unjustly detained by the People’s Republic of China. The President condemned their arbitrary detention and reiterated his commitment to stand strong with Canada to secure their release.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki and White&#160;House American Rescue Plan Coordinator and Senior Advisor to the President Gene Sperling, August 2,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/02/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-white-house-american-rescue-plan-coordinator-and-senior-advisor-to-the-president-gene-sperling-august-2-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 23:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:00 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Hello. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Welcome back, Jen. MS. PSAKI:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Well, thank you.&#160; I know it’s a later briefing this afternoon.&#160; Good things are worth the wait. And with that, we are &#8212; I’m pleased to be joined today by Gene Sperling, who&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:00 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Hello.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Welcome back, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; I know it’s a later briefing this afternoon.&nbsp; Good things are worth the wait.<br><br>And with that, we are &#8212; I’m pleased to be joined today by Gene Sperling, who probably doesn’t need a great introduction as the former NEC Director in two administrations and the person who’s overseeing our American Rescue Plan implementation.&nbsp; He’s going to talk a little bit about where we are on housing, take a few questions, and then we will proceed with our normal series of events.<br><br>With that, go ahead, Gene.<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It’s good to be back.<br><br>You know, our President so deeply believes that every avoidable eviction of an American family hurt by this pandemic is an avoidable heartbreak and harm to a family’s economic security and dignity.&nbsp; And he has worked and instructed us, from day one, to do everything within our power to prevent unnecessary evictions for those who have been hurt through this pandemic.<br><br>What I wanted to do today is just give you a little background on the statement that is coming out today that deals with both evictions, our executive actions, and the emerge- &#8212; Emergency Rental Assistance Plan for state and local governments.<br><br>On evictions: The President has long fought for an eviction moratorium.&nbsp; He actually proposed extending the eviction moratorium until September 30th when he came into office, and I believe that was not possible due to reconciliation rules.&nbsp; But that was his initial policy position he put forward.<br><br>He has also supported the CDC extending the CD- &#8212; their eviction moratorium &#8212; first from June 20th to May 31st, then from May 31st until June 30th.&nbsp; And then, even when there was legal questions and legal risk, he supported them extending it through July 31st.&nbsp;<br><br>Unfortunately, the Supreme Court declared on June 29th that the CDC could not grant such an extension without clear and specific congressional authorization.&nbsp; But given the rising urgency of the spread of the Delta variant, the President has asked all of us, including the CDC, to do everything in our power to look for every potential legal authority we can have to prevent evictions.&nbsp;<br><br>To date, the CDC Director and her team have been unable to find legal authority, even for a more targeted eviction moratorium that would focus just on counties with higher rates of COVID spread.&nbsp;<br><br>But again, the President’s focus is for us to do everything within our power &#8212; or, I should say, everything within anyone&#8217;s power &#8212; to help prevent unnecessary, avoidable, and painful evictions.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things that is &#8212; that he is requesting today is that state and local governments extend or pass eviction moratoriums to cover the next two months.&nbsp; Right now, one out of three renters who are behind in the rent are actually protected beyond the federal eviction moratorium by extended state and local evictions moratoriums.&nbsp; The President is asking that all governors and mayors follow suit and extend moratoriums for up to &#8212; for not “up to,” but for two months.<br><br>Two, this President is asking that his departments that provide mortgage-backed lending extend whatever eviction moratoriums they have the power to extend.&nbsp; So that covers USDA and VA and HUD.&nbsp;<br><br>Third, we have already announced that those with federally backed mortgages may not evict without 30 days of notice.&nbsp; But today, the President is going further in his statement Friday and in &#8212; by the Cabinet members.&nbsp; And in his instruction today,&nbsp;he is asking that USDA, VA, and HUD, and the Treasury Department as well make clear that those who benefit from government-backed mortgages or even tax relief related to housing should not seek evictions without first seeking the Emergency Rental Assistance funding that allows &#8212; that makes landlords completely whole; that can pay up to 18 months of forward and back rent and utilities &#8212; that we want anybody who&#8217;s got a government-backed mortgage to seek that type of relief.&nbsp;<br><br>Finally, as the congressional leadership discussed and asked, we are going to do an all-agency review to make sure that we understand any potential reason why state and local governments are not getting funds out and making sure that we are using all authorities &#8212; whatever federal authority that we have &#8212; to prevent evictions.&nbsp;<br><br>On the state and local relief, as you know, there was $25 billion in initial Emergency Rental Assistance.&nbsp; Again, this is the rental assistance that goes &#8212; can make landlords completely whole and also keep families safely housed.&nbsp; It is a win-win solution.&nbsp;<br><br>Unfortunately, on January 19th, the Trump administration left by putting in place a completely unworkable, high-documented &#8212; high documentation guidelines that would have never worked.&nbsp; So, immediately, Treasury cleared up those guidelines and got the remaining funds out.<br><br>After that, the President, as part of the American Rescue Plan, added another $21.5 billion of Emergency Rental Assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, we have stressed and the President has continued to stress that state and local governments must do more &#8212; all of them &#8212; to accelerate the funding to these renters and landlords, particularly as we face the end of the eviction moratorium and the rise of the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, we recognize this is not an easy task.&nbsp; We, as a country, have never had a national infrastructure or national policy for preventing avoidable evictions.&nbsp; Matthew Desmond &#8212; many of you know, the author of “Evictions” &#8212; has estimated that 3.6 million evictions are filed every year in non-pandemic years and often for amounts as little as $500 or $600 of back rent.&nbsp;<br><br>So we realize the state and local governments are being asked to set up &#8212; are often being asked to set up some programs from scratch.<br><br>But we have listened to their concerns, we have listened to the concerns of others in the housing community, and we have responded.&nbsp; On May 7th and June 24th, we put forward significant guidance that made it clear that you can have simplified applications; you do not have to have documentation for income or non-traditional income or to show your hardship.&nbsp;<br><br>We put out things that allowed you to pay landlords in both payments or utilities for many tenants, and that you could use the funds not only to keep people in their homes, but to make sure that you could help people find new housing or help those homeless or at risk of being homeless.<br><br>With these reforms, we have seen many states and localities start to succeed, from Louisville to Houston, Harris County, to Virginia &#8212; to the state of Virginia.&nbsp; Many places are succeeding.&nbsp; We did see, in June, the numbers doubled to $1.5 billion in assistance that went out the door to renters and landlords helping 290,000 tenants.&nbsp; We expect these numbers to grow.&nbsp; But it will not be enough to meet the need unless every state and locality immediately accelerates funds to tenants.<br><br>The President is clear: If some states and localities can get this out efficiently and effectively, there&#8217;s no reason every state and locality can’t.&nbsp; There is simply no excuse, no place to hide for any state or locality that is failing to accelerate their Emergency Rental Assistance Fund.&nbsp;<br><br>So the President is asking today that, at the state and local court level, that they heed the call of the Department of Justice to pause evictions, to ensure that evictions are a last resort, not a first resort.&nbsp;<br><br>For those of you who remember, this is what we &#8212; the Department of Justice; Vanita Gupta &#8212; put out a major statement on and what we did &#8212; the White House summit with 46 cities &#8212; to work and encourage them to use these kind of diversionary proposals to avoid evictions.&nbsp;<br><br>At the request of the congressional leadership provi &#8212; mes- &#8212; mentioned, we&#8217;re investigating all reasons for any delay of state and local funds, and whether we have the power to compel more expeditious use.&nbsp;<br><br>He also is calling on utilities and landlords to use the funds that Congress has made available to them &#8212; the emergency eviction funds, but also other funds in water and heating that they can use before they move to evict.&nbsp;<br><br>And finally, he&#8217;s asking the Treasury Department to make clear: You cannot only use your Emergency Rental Assistance funds &#8212; the $46 billion &#8212; but any of the funds in the $300 billion state and local fund to help with dealing with housing needs of anyone hurt with the pandemic, and that includes working with courts and legal aid counselors, or to help give more incentives to landlords to cooperate with them, who are willing to house those who are homeless, those who are &#8212; have been evicted, or to provide more longer-term, stable housing to the most hard-pressed renters.<br><br>The message is very clear:&nbsp;This President wants to do everything within his power.&nbsp; We are still investigating what that legal authority is, whether there is any options that we can have on eviction moratoriums beyond what we&#8217;ve seen.&nbsp;<br><br>But you can be sure of one thing: Whatever is in the power of this President to do to prevent evictions, he is committed to doing.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nancy.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Gene.&nbsp; So, House Speaker Nancy Pelosi is still calling today for the administration to extend the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; She seems to believe that the administration can do it.&nbsp; So what is the disconnect here?&nbsp; Why does she believe you have the power to extend the moratorium but the administration is arguing you don’t?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; Well, I would say that on this particular issue, the President has not only kicked the tires; he has double, triple, quadruple checked.&nbsp; He has asked the CDC to look at whether you could even do targeted eviction moratorium &#8212; that just went to the counties that have higher rates &#8212; and they, as well, have been unable to find the legal authority for even new, targeted eviction moratoriums.&nbsp;<br><br>I mean, we share so much the goals of Speaker Pelosi and others on the Hill.&nbsp; You know, we mean this: This is a President who really understands the heartbreak of eviction.&nbsp; He is &#8212; the reason why he is pressing and pressing, even when legal authority looks slim, is because he wants to make sure we have explored every potential authority.&nbsp;<br><br>So, this is &#8212; again, this is a President who is double, triple, and quadrupling this, and is not just &#8212; and is responding by then saying, “If we don&#8217;t have legal authority in some place, then we need to do a wide administration and state and local look at where we do have the authority to act and prevent evictions.”<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But she and other House Democratic leaders said they got very little notice from the administration, that it felt that it was unable to extend the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; And Dick Durbin, the senator from Illinois, said a couple of hours ago, it looks like somebody “dropped the ball.”&nbsp; Did it take too long for the administration to determine that you weren&#8217;t going to be able to unilaterally extend the eviction moratorium?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; You know, I think the wording in the Supreme Court opinion was fairly, you know, clear that &#8212; they said the CDC did not &#8212; could not grant such extension without, quote, “clear and specific congressional authorization.”&nbsp; I think, really, what has happened, what we are all dealing with, is that the rise of the Delta variant is particularly harmful for those who are most likely to face evictions.&nbsp; And as that reality became more clear, going into the end of last week, I think all of us started asking, “What more could we do?”&nbsp;<br><br>And we were very focused and have been extremely focused on the state and local relief.&nbsp; Many of you might have saw that, on the 28th, we did a massive, wide effort to get news out to tenants and landlords where they could go.&nbsp; I compliment those like PayPal and Venmo who put it on the front of their app and tens of millions of people saw it.<br><br>But I think that when the Delta variant, you know, started to rise and that it hits this particular &#8212; you know, that it&#8217;s likely hit harder the people most likely to be low income, unvaccinated, that there was just an effort to go back and, again, double, triple, quadruple check.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; I think we&#8217;re &#8212; we were in that, and I think other people on the Hill have also been in.&nbsp;<br><br>So this was &#8212; this was us responding to a new reality and doing so with this aggressive set of actions that President Biden has asked, both at the state and local level, of his executive team, of even landlords, and those who run utilities.<br><br>But, I think, on the eviction moratorium issue, we have run into &#8212; we have run into, so far, what seems to be a very difficult obstacle from the Supreme Court ruling.&nbsp; And, again, the President went out of his way to push to the CDC today to look even at 30 days, even targeted to high &#8212; you know, counties with higher infections, and the CDC independently came back and said that they could not, at this time, find the legal authority.<br><br>I don&#8217;t think this means this President is going to give up.&nbsp; I think he&#8217;s going to keep looking and pushing and kicking the tires, and fifth, sixth looks.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to do everything we can.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is there &#8212; is there any &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Kaitlan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; contention or any &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kaitlan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thank you very much, Mr. Sperling.&nbsp; But the Delta variant has been around for weeks and has been the dominant strain in the United States for several weeks as well.&nbsp; So why did the President wait until Sunday to ask the CDC for a targeted moratorium focused on those areas with high case rates?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; I think what you&#8217;re seeing is a President who is just trying to do everything that he can in his power, and part of that is also going back to places where he has heard initially that we do not have legal authority.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s saying,<br>“This is so important I want to double and triple check.&nbsp; I want to ask the CDC independently, if they share that same reading of the Supreme Court&#8217;s view.”&nbsp; And I think he&#8217;s going to continue to look.<br><br>So I don&#8217;t think &#8212; I think this just reflects a continuation of a President who is looking at every possible authority we can do.&nbsp; And to be honest, when he is told there is not authority, his response is &#8212; because he cares so deeply &#8212; is to double, triple, quadruple check, and that&#8217;s exactly what him going to the CDC represented.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just think the question from progressive &#8212; even progressive Democrats &#8212; is that you got this ruling from the Supreme Court at the end of June, so why did it take so long to call on Congress to act?&nbsp; If it is so important to him, why did it take so long to go to the CDC for this 30-day moratorium that he was seeking?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; Well, again, I think that the fact that the Supreme Court had ruled that way &#8212; I mean, remember, we knowingly faced some legal risk &#8212; supported extending the moratorium to July 31st.&nbsp; The Supreme Court ruled, chose not to strike that down.&nbsp; But the ruling said very, very clearly that that was because it was rolling off on July 31st and that extensions would require congressional authorization.&nbsp; That &#8212; that is clear &#8212; those wordings are nothing special for us; they&#8217;re something anybody here, you know, can read.&nbsp;<br><br>I think what you saw was that, as the Delta variant was worse, that there was just, you know, the passion to not only look for everything we knew we had the power to do, but a lot of what he&#8217;s doing is asking us to check &#8212; double check, triple, quadruple check.<br><br>And that&#8217;s also in terms of what he&#8217;s asking those of us in the White House to do with the agencies.&nbsp; Where agencies have given more narrow opinions on their authorities and powers, he&#8217;s asking us to go back and push.<br><br>On, you know, again, the state and local moratorium, this is not insignificant.&nbsp; Thirty-three &#8212; one in three people are in states where they have some additional length of protection due to state and local moratoriums.&nbsp; The Supreme Court does not affect that.&nbsp; So, he is asking to extend that as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, I think, you know, what you&#8217;re seeing here is a consistent behavior.&nbsp; And I think the truth is many people came to the same realization, which was that even though the eviction moratorium was supposed to end on the 31st; even though the CDC had said it was their last extension; even though the Supreme Court had seemed to clearly state that, beyond that, had been &#8212; would require authorization, there was still a desire, a passion by this President to go back and say, “Are we sure?&nbsp; Are we sure?”&nbsp; And he is still asking that question.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what he was pressing with the CDC.<br><br>So, it&#8217;s not a first &#8212; it&#8217;s not that this is the first he&#8217;s doing on this.&nbsp; He is at &#8212; this is part of a continuation of him looking down every corner, kicking every tire, doing everything we can for whatever authority we have or policies we can do to protect people &#8212; protect against unnecessary evictions, particularly of those who&#8217;ve been hurt by the pandemic.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jonathan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gene, is there any indication, or is it the contention of this administration, that the undistributed funds that the state and local governments haven’t distributed haven&#8217;t been done so for political reasons?&nbsp; And if so, what&#8217;s your reaction to that?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, that they haven&#8217;t been distributed?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That they haven’t been distributed.&nbsp; You are investigating the non-distribution of some of those funds.&nbsp; Is &#8212;<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; I think much of it &#8212; I mean, again, I think that our country did not have a national infrastructure for doing this.&nbsp; I mean, $1.5 billion went out in June.&nbsp; That is not nearly enough.&nbsp; That is certainly more than has ever happened in a month in our country.&nbsp;<br><br>So Congress asked us to set that up, for that to be imposed at a state and local level.&nbsp; So it requires every state and local government, many of them to set up processes.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;m not tr- &#8212; again, I understand the challenges they were facing, but right now, there&#8217;s no excuse for somebody having a complicated application process.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no excuse for somebody to have excessive documentation.&nbsp; Your government has told you that you can create very simple application processes, and you are able to see that your peers in other states and cities are successfully implementing this.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, this is the time where we want to especially say: There&#8217;s no excuses.&nbsp; If it works in some places, there&#8217;s no reason it can&#8217;t work in every place.&nbsp;<br><br>If you ask me, I think there&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of excessive cautiousness and conservativism.&nbsp; And, you know, at some point, you have to push people that we are giving you the flexibility to get these funds out.&nbsp; We are not telling you &#8212; you can rely on self-attestation for hardship, for income.&nbsp; You can rely on both payments.&nbsp; You can rely on factual predicates like how low-income the housing area or neighborhood is.&nbsp;<br><br>At this point, some places may still feel like they have to be overly careful and cautious.&nbsp; And we are saying, &#8220;No you don&#8217;t.&nbsp; You need to get these funds out.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>But I will say the following, too: This &#8212; the American Rescue Plan, in addition to this funds, gave people $350 billion in state and local funds.&nbsp; Those funds are also available.&nbsp; So, when people say, &#8220;Well, we need more counselors,&#8221; or, &#8220;We could do more mediation if we could hire mediators or legal services,&#8221; or, &#8220;We could help support the court systems, you know, helping to tell people to first seek Emergency Rental Assistance&#8221; &#8212; they fully have that ability.&nbsp; They, in fact, have two pots of money: They can go from the Emergency Rental Assistance, or they can go from the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what can you do about that?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to tell you that Congress gave us a lot of sticks and punitive measures and carrots, but we&#8217;re doing everything we can, and we have.&nbsp;<br><br>If you look at the May 7th guidance that we did, it was very significant and it was widely praised by advocates around the country.&nbsp; It sped up the time that you had to give funds to a tenant directly, if a landlord didn&#8217;t participate.&nbsp; It made clear you could do bulk payments.&nbsp; It made clear you could rely on self-attestation.&nbsp;<br><br>And then when we heard that there were issues, like they weren&#8217;t sure they could help people who were homeless, we came back on June 24th and made clear that you can &#8212; that you could for a future debt obligation.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, I understand that &#8212; that hard is hard and setting up a national infrastructure on Emergency Rental Assistance, you know, immediately is a challenge.&nbsp; But I think we are now at the point where we feel people have had time, they have &#8212; we have listened to their concerns.&nbsp; We have given them enormous flexibility.&nbsp; They are seeing their peers, they&#8217;re seeing other states and cities succeeding, and there&#8217;s no excuse for them not doing so.<br><br>I will say that, on September 30th, the one stick you have is that the Treasury Department is allowed to reallocate among places that have not used 65 percent of their &#8212; of the first $25 billion. &nbsp;So that is something the Deputy Secretary of Treasury has made clear.<br><br>And we have reached out to so many cities, so many governors, so many meetings with the National League of Cities, national Conference of Mayors.&nbsp; And many of them are working very well with us.&nbsp; Many of them &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is happening with Florida, sir?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; &#8212; are doing but &#8212; but we &#8212; but we are &#8212; but we &#8212; but, you know, we are pressing harder now, as we should, with the end of the eviction moratorium.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you about Florida, sir?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just going to have (inaudible).<br><br>Justin, why don&#8217;t you go?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Gene, are you saying that Congress dropped the ball here, essentially?&nbsp; I mean, you said that they&#8217;ve written the plan and you guys don&#8217;t have a lot of tools to fix it.&nbsp; So, is that &#8212; is that what you&#8217;re saying?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; No, not at all.&nbsp; I think what they did was historic.&nbsp;&nbsp; I think that we, as a country, have never had a policy to prevent avoidable evictions.&nbsp; Again, Matt Desmond says, in a normal year, you have over 300,000 month, and actually, August is one of the worst.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the average between 2000 and 2016.&nbsp; And he &#8212; and the Eviction Lab shows that many of those people were evicted for just five, six hundred dollars of back rent.<br><br>So, I think the idea that Congress pushed for us to create a national infrastructure that we could get this out is &#8212; and to put the &#8212; put the amount of money in there that could help make landlords whole.&nbsp;<br><br>Remember, the thing about the Emergency Rental Assistance that&#8217;s so important is that it helps struggling landlords and struggling tenants.&nbsp; It can pay up to 18 month, forward or backwards, of back rent or back utilities.&nbsp; So, it is a way to make a landlord, who is struggling, whole, while also keeping that tenant and their family safe and secure.<br><br>I&#8217;m just expressing the reality of why &#8212; of the fact that we do whatever we can with the tools we have.&nbsp; And we have found that the guidance has worked: listening to people, making clear you could use self-attestation, making clear you could have low documentation.&nbsp;<br><br>It has worked in many places.&nbsp; Again, I mentioned Louisville; Harris County; Virginia.&nbsp; That&#8217;s just a small sample of the places it&#8217;s working.&nbsp;<br><br>So we think what Congress did was historic, and we think it has the potential to help enormously.<br><br>And, look, people shouldn&#8217;t think that this is hopeless.&nbsp; You know, yes, people do reports of 6 million being behind, but when you look at the poll survey and the federal &#8212; in the Philadelphia Federal Reserve, they&#8217;re talking about, you know, a little less than 2 million really, really being a threat.&nbsp; We help nearly 300,000.&nbsp; If we can get those numbers up &#8212; imagine if you were at 500,000; that meant you to be helping one and a half million over a few-month period.&nbsp;<br><br>So, if states and local governments rise to this great resources that this Congress wisely gave to them, there is every reason to believe that they could have a substantial effect in mitigating these evictions.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re pressing so hard, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re going to look for every bit &#8212; bit of authority or persuasion or guidance that we can make.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m just saying that the reality is there&#8217;s not like a punitive stick.&nbsp; That doesn&#8217;t mean that there was anything wrong with the &#8212; with what I think is really a historic element of the American Rescue Plan that I think could not only be helpful now, but going forward in preventing unnecessary evictions that we know have often heartbreaking and longer-term impacts on families and their economic and health stability.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to go to Yamiche.&nbsp; We got to wrap it up after that.&nbsp; Let’s go to the farther back.&nbsp; Go ahead, Yamiche.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp; And thanks, Jen &#8212;<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for adding one more.&nbsp; I guess my question is &#8212; it&#8217;s two part: One, why not force the Supreme Court to make this decision?&nbsp; And, two, is that decision not to actually go to the Supreme Court and force them to strike it down &#8212; does it have anything to do with fears that the Supreme Court might strike down the administration&#8217;s broad use of public health laws for other policies?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; You know, I do not neces- &#8212; I believe that people have been examining whether there is legal authority to go forward, period &#8212; whether it&#8217;s a legally available option.&nbsp;<br><br>For me personally: Yeah, I &#8212; you always have to worry about whether you do something that could create harm.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a factor to think about.&nbsp; Is it an overwhelming factor?&nbsp; I can&#8217;t tell you.&nbsp; But, you know, I think when you&#8217;re governing, you have to look at all these issues and &#8212; and see.<br><br>I think the President is still kicking every corner, because I think if there&#8217;s any chance that you could get this extension, he wants to know every available authority.&nbsp;<br><br>But it is a consideration that I think, you know, may have affected some of us.&nbsp; But I can&#8217;t say that that &#8212; I &#8212; you know, that &#8212; that I think, within our legal counsel in the CDC, I think they have spoken mostly about simply whether there is that legal authority to go forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have an example (inaudible)?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; But again, I want to make clear: You&#8217;ve seen this President is continuing to double, triple, quadruple check on those issues and to ask all of us to look in every corner and kick every tire and double, triple, quadruple check if there&#8217;s any possible way that we can afford.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you give an example of what might be the things that you&#8217;re worried about the Supreme Court striking down?&nbsp; What unnecessary &#8212; what, maybe, unintended consequences &#8212;<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; Are you trying to get me &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; might come from them?<br><br>MR. SPERLING: &nbsp;Are you trying to get me in trouble with Dana Remus? &nbsp;(Laughter.) &nbsp;Are you like &#8212; are you like trying to make me persona non grata with &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; with our General White House Counsel? &nbsp;I&#8217;ll pass. &nbsp;(Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it 2 million people though?&nbsp; Is that the number that this White House believes could end up losing their homes as a result of this?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; I am saying that those who are &#8212; no.&nbsp; Those are people &#8212; those are the estimates for &#8212; you know, 1.4 to 1.9 are people who fear that they could be at a deeper level.&nbsp; A large percent &#8212; a significant percentage of them are in states where there&#8217;s eviction &#8212; the moratorium is in increase.&nbsp;<br><br>We have lots of indications that the kind of diversionary policies that we are doing is helping.&nbsp; And also, remember we&#8217;re at almost 300,000.&nbsp; If we&#8217;re up to four or five hundred thousand, then you could be talking about helping well over a million people in a few-month period.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But how many people could lose their homes?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; But what I&#8217;m trying to say is that &#8212; what I was trying to say is that we are pushing hard because we do believe that if state and local governments were to accelerate &#8212; if all of them were to do as well as the best performers are &#8212; what I&#8217;m trying to say is that it could make a sizable impact<br>on mitigation because &#8212; you know, because you’re &#8212; because those type of numbers, over a few-month period, you could have a substantial impact.&nbsp; That said, not everyone.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what’s the number that America should brace for?&nbsp; How many people does this White House believe could lose their home because of this?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; I do not &#8212; I do not have an estimate.&nbsp; What I was trying to discourage against was the use of just the largest &#8212; I mean, sometimes people are just using what is the percentage of $45 billion, or what is the percentage of everybody who says they didn&#8217;t back-pay.&nbsp; And it can make it seem like things &#8212; it can understate the degree of progress.&nbsp;<br><br>If you feel like being able to help several hundred thousand a month over a few months, you know, it could matter a lot.&nbsp; And if we could get all the states and local governments, I&#8217;m saying that you could make a sizable impact.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But millions?<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; What&#8217;s that?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you foresee millions of people losing their homes?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; No.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Gene, thank you very much.&nbsp; He&#8217;s available.&nbsp; He works here, so &#8212;<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; No, I &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; he gets to help us out more.<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; No, I don’t. &nbsp;I just was identifying what a more targeted num- &#8212; estimates are of the people who say in surveys that they feel, at some point, not ju- &#8212; you know, at some point.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why this &#8212; and I&#8217;m saying that&#8217;s why the assistance is so important, because you could hit a sizable impact of people who could be at risk each month if everybody was operating.&nbsp; It would &#8212; could be a meaningful number, though, you know, every eviction is a heartbreaking.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, so I don&#8217;t want to play down those who might st- &#8212; who could still face it, but just to stress that the state and local governments accelerating &#8212; we’re at 290,000 &#8212; if it keeps getting larger and larger every month and sustains for several months, that it could have a sizable impact.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MR. SPERLING: &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Gene.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a native, though, it’s “<em>Loo-uh-vul</em>,” not “<em>Loo-ee-vil</em>.”&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MR. SPERLING:&nbsp; They’re just the team that beat Michigan in the finals.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Learning new things every day.&nbsp;<br><br>Okay, a couple things for you all at the top, in addition.&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, the Department of Education released their Return to School Roadmap, of great interest to many parents, students, educators, and communities across the country.&nbsp; It outlines their &#8212; the community resources and support they need for a safe and healthy school year this fall.&nbsp; Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, every school has the resources they need to ensure every student can learn in person, which is &#8212; absolutely remains our objective.&nbsp;<br><br>The Roadmap addresses three landmarks and provides strategies and resources to get communities there, including health and safety; vaccinations for Americans 12 and older and indoor masking; social, emotional, and mental health support for students; and accelerating academic achievement.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has been clear that it is a top priority to have children in school, in person, full-time this fall, and he has secured the resources to help ensure we can do that safely. &nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ll also note that I&#8217;ve invited Secretary Cardona to come join us in the briefing room this week, so we&#8217;re working to schedule that, as well, to give you all a briefing and an update.&nbsp;<br><br>I also wanted to note that with Congress on recess for most of August, we are launching a huge push throughout the month to promote President Biden&#8217;s Build Back Better agenda and highlight the success of the President&#8217;s first six months in office, especially in delivering economic relief to the American people, creating record number of jobs for an administration&#8217;s first five months, and spurring on the fastest economic growth during the first half of the year in almost four decades.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to a regular cadence of White House messaging to support the Build Back Better agenda, key principals &#8212; including the Vice President, the First Lady, the Second Gentleman &#8212; will fan out to hold events in communities across the country, touting the President&#8217;s Build Back Better plan to drive more economic growth and invest in America&#8217;s middle-class families by cutting taxes for families with children, lowering healthcare costs, and meeting with mom- &#8212; meeting the moment on climate change.&nbsp; The President also promote his agenda throughout the month.&nbsp;<br><br>They&#8217;ll be joined in that effort by the Cabinet, which will be stumping in every corner of the country on the importance of passing both the bipartisan infrastructure bill &#8212; can we call it the “BIB” now?&nbsp;&#8212; I’m going to try &#8212; and the Build Back Better agenda to invest in our economy’s strength, make life better for all families, and confront the existential challenge of climate change.&nbsp;<br><br>As part of that, in the first two weeks of August alone, 14 Cabinet secretaries will travel to at least 26 cities in 13 states and the District of Columbia, with additional events being added.&nbsp;<br><br>As just one example, Secretaries Walsh and Raimondo will be heading to New York City this Wednesday to highlight the broad support from both labor and business community for the President&#8217;s economic vision.<br><br>With that, Jonathan, kick us off.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; First, one follow-up to the evictions thing, and then moving on to &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; foreign policy.&nbsp; Quickly, on this: From the briefing we just received, it seems like the White House does not want to challenge this in court.&nbsp; But lawmakers &#8212; Democratic lawmakers who are unhappy with the response so far are basically saying &#8212; I&#8217;m paraphrasing &#8212; “Don&#8217;t let Brett Kavanaugh stand in the way of this.”&nbsp; Why not take executive action now to direct the CDC and deal with the court later on?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what you should have taken from the statement that was put out right before the briefing, and also Gene joining us in the briefing today, is that the President has not given up the option of legal action.&nbsp; He has asked his team to look, to kick the tires &#8212; just to keep the analogy going &#8212; and look at every authority, every option we have to keep more people in their homes.&nbsp; That is his objective.<br><br>At the same time, he&#8217;s also focused on the policy options that are at play, whether it&#8217;s encouraging states to use funding; to get the funding out; to extend the moratorium by 30 days, 60 days in some states, that can keep people in their homes; and to see what other policy options we have at our disposal.<br><br>So we are using every tool we can.&nbsp; He is still &#8212; we are still kicking the &#8212; looking at legal authorities to see what is possible.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s not going to take a step without legal authority to do so.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how much more time is he going to kick the tires?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s clearly a priority to the President, given the statement &#8212; the extensive statement we put out this afternoon.&nbsp; He was laser-focused on this all weekend &#8212; I can confirm for you &#8212; and has been from the beginning of the administration.<br><br>I mean, as a reminder, I know Gene touched on this, but he wanted to see an extension in January in the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; It obviously wasn&#8217;t in there. &nbsp;The CDC extended the moratorium not once but three times.&nbsp; We made clear when we did the last extension that that would likely be the last extension because of the legal limitations.&nbsp; But, you know, he&#8217;s going to keep pushing to see what the options are available to him and if there are any additional options available.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then the foreign policy matter: Now that the United States &#8212; per the Secretary of State&#8217;s statement yesterday &#8212; agrees with Israel and the UK that Iran was behind the attack against the ship, would the U.S. support an Israeli retaliatory strike on Iran?&nbsp; And how does this matter impact at all the U.S. position in the indirect nuclear talks, if they restart?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as a sovereign country, Israel is going to make their own decisions.&nbsp; But I will say that as it relates to our own engagement in nuclear talks &#8212; which we, of course, do have authorities over or do have decisions to make there &#8212; our view is that every single challenge and threat we face from Iran would be made more pronounced and dangerous by an unconstrained nuclear program.&nbsp;<br><br>So, put another way, constraining Iran’s nuclear program by returning to the JCPOA will put us in a better position to address these other problems.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean that it will take care of the other issues that had been ongoing concerns we&#8217;ve had with Iran.&nbsp; They are a bad actor on the global stage.&nbsp; They have threatened our own military, as we all know.&nbsp; But we continue to believe that pursuing a diplomatic path forward, that pursuing an opportunity to make sure we have greater visibility into what their nuclear capabilities are is in our national interest.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just quickly: On Friday, the President was asked whether Americans should expect more guidelines coming out because of COVID, because of the Delta variant.&nbsp; And he said, “In all probability.”&nbsp; So what&#8217;s on the table right now?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not &#8212; obviously, the President is keeping the option open of making sure that he is &#8212; that the CDC and our public health officials can make recommendations on what&#8217;s needed to keep the American people safe.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not in a position to preview that or to get ahead of any decisions they may make.<br><br>What I can reiterate, though, is &#8212; and you heard Dr. Fauci and Dr. Collins reiterate this, this weekend &#8212; we&#8217;ve been clear we&#8217;re not going back to the shutdowns of March of 2020.&nbsp; We are not going back to the economy shutting down.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made too much progress.&nbsp; Too many people are vaccinated.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been too much progress on the economic front.&nbsp;<br><br>But, again, he has said from the beginning that we&#8217;re going to be guided by the science, guided by our public health experts, and we&#8217;re not going to take options off the table of what they may recommend.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just on Israel, but different topic: The NIH Director says he doesn&#8217;t see a need for booster shots, yet we&#8217;re seeing this model out of Israel suggesting that boosters are beneficial.&nbsp; So is Israel ahead of the curve on this one?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if you&#8217;re referring to the Israel data from a couple of weeks ago &#8212; is that the data? &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; which was not fully extensive and fully published at the time; I&#8217;m not sure if there have been additional details since then &#8212; our health experts continue to look at whether there would be a need for boosters.&nbsp;<br><br>I would remind you, too: We have, from the beginning, planned for a range of contingencies as we have purchased supply of vaccines, just in case there are boosters needed. &nbsp;There hasn&#8217;t been a decision made by our public health experts that it is needed, even for a portion of the population.&nbsp; If that decision is needed, we will be prepared as a government.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, also following up: Last week, President Biden was asked about the Justice Department or &#8212; additional things that can be done for vaccine mandates.&nbsp; And he said that the Justice Department was looking at that.&nbsp; He didn&#8217;t have an answer yet.<br><br>Can you elaborate what the Justice Department may be looking at or exploring, in terms of mandating vaccines?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think Karine said this on Thursday or Friday &#8212; that a federal mandate from the federal government is not on the table.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think what the President was referring to is the fact that employers can take that step, just as the federal government &#8212; and you&#8217;ve seen agencies do that &#8212; has the authority to take that step, according to the OLC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, he&#8217;s not looking at it the way that the administration did with mask mandates, where it was mandated on federal property that you had to have a mask.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not a similar exploration of doing vaccines that way to encourage more people to get the vaccine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not across the country, no.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And, just to be clear, can vaccinated people be indoors with other vaccinated people?&nbsp; I mean, is that the &#8212; is that okay for people to be doing in &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know Dr. Collins spoke to this during one of his interviews this weekend, and the good news is there&#8217;s a COVID briefing coming up this afternoon where you can ask questions of our public health experts.&nbsp; But they&#8217;ve not changed that guidance in their &#8212; in their &#8212; the guidance from last week.&nbsp; They updated guidance on masks, but I certainly would encourage you to ask them that during the briefing.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Back to the evictions.&nbsp; Several states, including New York and Florida, have been slow to disburse available federal aid to landlords and renters.&nbsp; In Florida, some 2 percent of available funding has been disbursed.<br><br>So I&#8217;m wondering: Has the White House been in touch with Governor DeSantis, for instance, and other state leaders to see what the holdup is?&nbsp; And what do those discussions look like?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly &#8212; I can&#8217;t speak to any &#8212; any contact specifically with Governor DeSantis about this, but we have been in touch with state authorities and localities about what the holdup is or what the delay is in getting this funding out.<br><br>And as Gene conveyed very clearly, $1.5 billion has been &#8212; was distributed in June.&nbsp; That was faster &#8212; that was greater than the five months prior or the four months prior.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good step.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not nearly enough.<br><br>And certainly, getting the additional funding out there will help keep more people in their homes, which is our goal, which is Speaker Pelosi&#8217;s goal.<br><br>So, absolutely, we&#8217;re in touch with local housing authorities and leaders and states to ensure they&#8217;re moving this ball forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in light of the ACLU&#8217;s decision to go back to court over Title 42 and push the administration to roll that back, does the President view it as a Trump-era restriction that he just needs more time to unwind?&nbsp; Or after roughly six months of using it, does he now view it as a necessary tool to maintain control of the border?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Neither.&nbsp; The President views it as a public health measure where the CDC is going to continue to provide guidance on how long it needs to be in place.<br><br>We have not given a timeline of when we will &#8212; they will lift Title 42, but we will look for them to provide us that guidance.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And about public health at the border, is the President concerned that migrants who are coming in, in great numbers, are not being tested for COVID at their first point of contact with Border Patrol?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me give you a little bit of an understanding of what actually happens when people come across the border.&nbsp;<br><br>First, as &#8212; to Katie&#8217;s earlier question, there&#8217;s been no change in Title 42, so families and single adults are expelled, if possible, when apprehended at the southern border.&nbsp; That&#8217;s step one.&nbsp;<br><br>Those who can&#8217;t be expelled are often placed &#8212; and this, I think, goes to your question &#8212; in alternatives to detention programs while their cases are being reviewed.<br><br>CBP provides migrants with PPE from the moment they are taken into custody, and migrants are required to keep masks on at all times, including when they are transferred or in the process of being released.<br><br>Our other protocol is if anyone exhibits signs of illness in CBP custody, they&#8217;re referred to local health systems for appropriate testing, diagnosis, isolation, and treatment.&nbsp; That is our process.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just about COVID safety: Is President Obama setting the wrong example about how serious COVID-19 is by hosting a big birthday party with hundreds of people this week?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would certainly refer you to the team who is working for my former boss to give you more specifics of what the protocols are in place.<br><br>But I would note, first, that former President Obama has been a huge advocate of individuals getting vaccinated.&nbsp; When CDC provided guid- &#8212; has provided &#8212; what CDC has provided guidance on is for indoor settings in high or substantial high zones of COVID cases.&nbsp;<br><br>This event, according to all the public reporting, is outdoors and in a moderate zone.&nbsp; But in addition, there is testing requirements and other steps they are taking, which I&#8217;m sure they can outline for you in more detail.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is there any concern, just because &#8212; as you said here, and you&#8217;ve had people saying over the last couple days &#8212; vaccinated people can still spread this Delta variant around?&nbsp; So is there concern that this President Obama birthday party might become a super-spreader event?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, Peter, the guidance is about what steps people can take when they&#8217;re in public settings &#8212;&nbsp;indoor settings, specifically, was the new guidance &#8212; to keep themselves and others safe.<br><br>In terms of what protocols they are taking, I would refer you to them, and I&#8217;m sure they can give you more details.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just last one.&nbsp; So, people who are watching this at home and they see, “Well, if President Obama can have a party with several hundred people,” should they think that it is okay for them to have a party with several hundred people now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we certainly advise everyone to follow public health guidelines, which I know the former President, who is a huge advocate of getting vaccinated, of following the guidance of public health experts, would certainly advocate for himself as well.<br><br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senator Lindsey Graham has announced that he has tested positive for COVID after being vaccinated and will be doing some self-isolating, which could have an impact on &#8212; for example, the bipartisan infrastructure.&nbsp; So what is your reaction to that?&nbsp;<br><br>And, secondly, does the administration feel like they need to get more sources of information on breakthrough cases, given the anecdotal experience many people are having of seeing more incidents of that &#8212; beyond just the issue of hospitalizations and deaths, but more information about how much the breakthrough cases are spreading?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that every single piece of available evidence shows that breakthrough infections are rare and mild, and that is according to a range of data.&nbsp; So according to new research from Kaiser Family Foundation from January to July, the rate of breakthrough cases reported to states is below 1 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve seen data come out from England, Scotland, Canada, and Israel showing that vaccines are about 80 percent effective in preventing illness from Delta and about 90 percent effective in prese- &#8212; preventing hospitalizations by Delta.&nbsp;<br><br>CDC is actively tracking tens of thousands of people in cohort studies &#8212; as I think you know and we&#8217;ve talked about a little bit in here &#8212; some of them doing weekly PCR testing, which includes healthcare professionals, first responders, hospitalized adults, and people in long-term care facilities.&nbsp; Also states and hospital associations are reporting their own data.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, we know there&#8217;s an interest in getting that data.&nbsp; We support that.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky says that they plan to release that as well, which we, of course, support as well and it&#8217;s important for you all to look at.<br><br>But I would note that &#8212; and I thought this was important because if you look at the power of vaccinations, you&#8217;re looking at specifically the numbers of &#8212; according to seven-day averages of January versus July.&nbsp; January is, of course, the lighter numbers, and then the darker number is July.&nbsp; And if you look at hospital admissions and deaths, this is really in &#8212; because of the impact of the vaccine and how effective it is at preventing people from being hospitalized and dying from COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>We certainly do hope that Senator Graham is &#8212; has a speedy recovery and is &#8212; experiences mild symptoms.&nbsp; And, you know, we wish him the best of health through that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In places like Florida where hospitalizations are at a record level &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; is there any concern about the number of resources available, rationing of care, additional equipment that needs to be sent in, or personnel to assist?<br><br>MS. PSAKI: Well, one, we are &#8212; we stand ready and available to provide any assistance that is needed, whether that is Florida or any other part of the country.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done these strike forces.&nbsp; We are at a very different point in the pandemic than we were a couple of months ago.&nbsp; We have ample vaccine.&nbsp; We have ample experts.&nbsp; We have ample resources to provide them.<br><br>You know, I will note, as you touched on there, 20 percent of the cases we&#8217;re seeing are in Florida.&nbsp; There are steps and precautions that can be taken, including encouraging people to get vaccinated, encouraging people to wear masks, including allowing &#8212; allowing schools to mandate masks, and allow &#8212; allowing kids to wear masks, which is not the current state of play in Florida.<br><br>So, you know, at a certain point, leaders are going to have to choose whether they&#8217;re going to follow public health guidelines or they&#8217;re going to follow politics, and we certainly encourage all governors to follow the public health guidelines.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; As you know, UK and EU are now reopening to vaccinated travelers from the U.S.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on the decision-making process here in the U.S. about whether and when to reciprocate?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Certainly understand the question.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a lot of people out there who are eager to see loved ones, to travel, to return to flights between our country and many countries in Europe.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s ongoing discussions, on a policy level, with public health officials.&nbsp; As you know, we have these ongoing working groups, but I don&#8217;t have an update on the timeline of a decision.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then the HHS Inspector General announced today that they are opening an investigation into this large tent camp at Fort Bliss that houses migrant children because of reports that kids were having panic attacks and exhibiting self-harm.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: Have any changes been made already to address some of those concerns?&nbsp; And how big of a concern has this been for HHS and the White House?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, thank you for the question.&nbsp; Secretary Becerra did speak to this last week.&nbsp; HHS does take every allegation for wrongdoing seriously and swiftly report allegations not only to the officer &#8212; Office of the Inspector General, but to the appropriate local authorities.<br><br>I would say that there have been actions that &#8212; some of &#8212; some of the reports of conditions are several weeks old or even longer than that, and so there have been steps that have been taken to make improvements on the ground &#8212; including children at Fort Bliss meet with a case manager on a weekly basis, and we have close to 60 mental health and behavioral counselors on site working with the children.<br><br>One of the issues that was raised was the lack of mental health access, so that&#8217;s a step we&#8217;ve &#8212; that the HHS team has worked to improve.&nbsp; More than 1,000 staff at the ORR, at Fort Bliss, have received required training, including child best welfare practices, behavior management, trauma-informed care, cultural competence, and reporting.&nbsp; Training is ongoing as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is certainly an issue we take quite seriously.&nbsp; These reports were made directly to the Office of the Inspector General, and improvements have been made.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, we’re told you have a hard out soon, so maybe, like, two more.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; A couple of quick questions &#8212; one on vaccine misinformation.&nbsp; Since President Biden and the Surgeon General, you know, have spoken about the issue &#8212; you’ve spoken about it as well &#8212; has the White House seen the companies, specifically Facebook and the other social media companies, take any steps to address vaccine misinformation? &nbsp;Any notable changes that you have seen?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a really great question.&nbsp; I will have to talk to our team and see if there&#8217;s any specific &#8212; specific notes of improvement that we can call out.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that or connect you with them directly.&nbsp;<br><br>Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so the reason I ask is obviously because, you know, they &#8212; we&#8217;re seeing this increase in vaccinations again, and that seems to be tied to the number of cases going up.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re just sort of wondering if there is anything that we can tie back to maybe some of the misinformation campaigns being contained.&nbsp;<br><br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, I think that it&#8217;s hard to draw a connection to one specific step in any local community.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s no question &#8212; you see this anecdotally through a lot of your reporting &#8212; which is where people see their neighbor got a vaccine, their friends got a vaccine, and they&#8217;re okay.&nbsp; And on the flip side of it, they had a friend or a neighbor who was hospitalized, and it made them go and get a vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>So, certainly, it&#8217;s an ongoing battle against misinformation.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just on Facebook &#8212; though that is a mechanism for misinformation traveling, no question.&nbsp; It is through a range of mediums.&nbsp; We all have a responsibility.<br><br>But we are certainly seeing &#8212; in the states where there are higher case rates, we&#8217;ve seen record rates of enc- &#8212; I should say, very encouraging rates of vaccination.&nbsp; And that can be because of a number of factors.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, I just had one more on voting rights quickly.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are 100 state legislators who are converging in D.C. today from over 20 states.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be meeting with Texas Democrats.&nbsp; We did see the Vice President meet with Texas Democrats earlier.&nbsp; I just was curious if the President and the Vice President plan to meet with these lawmakers and if they have any message for them.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say the President and Vice President &#8212; the message to them is: We stand with you and believe that voting rights are a fundamental right for the American people across the country.&nbsp; And the President would love to sign voting rights legislation into law.&nbsp; He will continue to &#8212; this will continue to be a fight of his presidency, and that&#8217;s why he&#8217;s asked the Vice President to lead this effort.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two quick ones for you.&nbsp; The U.S. has now hit the President&#8217;s July 4th goal to get 70 percent of American adults with one shot.&nbsp; What is his reaction to that goal being a month late?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, his &#8212; it was a goal that he set &#8212; we set as an administration because we believe in bold, ambitious goals.&nbsp; I would say it&#8217;s a significant step that we have hit 70 percent of people in this country &#8212; of adults who are vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good sign.&nbsp; It will help protect communities.&nbsp; It will help protect families and save more lives.<br><br>But we&#8217;ve said from the beginning: Even when we set this goal, our work would not be done even when we reached it, and so we&#8217;re forging ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to follow up on something from Friday, which is that &#8212; that was said on Friday &#8212; agencies are going to be paying the cost of testing for workers who choose not to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Does that mean taxpayers are going to be paying for the tests of federal workers who chose not to get vaccinated?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I am &#8212; certainly, I can check with federal &#8212; with each agency.&nbsp; It may be different agency to agency, but it&#8217;s typically &#8212; probably would be a part of their funding.&nbsp; But I can check and see if there&#8217;s more clarification on that front.<br><br>I know we have to wrap, but, Mona, I know you came in and came out.&nbsp; So why don’t you end us off here?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I appreciate it, Jen.&nbsp; A couple of things.&nbsp; I wanted to follow up: I was asking the President on Friday before his departure why hasn’t he &#8212; I have an inkling, but for the American people &#8212; why hasn’t he signed an executive order on the VRA?&nbsp; That’s the one thing.<br><br>And then, to follow up on the eviction moratorium, for context, there are &#8212; of course, you probably know there is landlord state rentals [sic] &#8212; renters state type of situations.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, in the state of Florida, it is a landlord state, meaning the law favors landlords.&nbsp; Some of my research has indicated that renters are having a difficult time, in a general sense, and now that they have these tools that they can take advantage of from the government, they are facing more stress and lack &#8212; a lack of cooperation from these landlords.<br><br>I&#8217;ve gotten a lot of that over this past week.&nbsp; I have been following this since a month or so ago &#8212; reporting on this weekly.&nbsp; And what I&#8217;m hearing more and more is that people are afraid that they&#8217;re just not going to get the support because of that lack of cooperation.&nbsp; And I know it&#8217;s been addressed, but what do you think we can do &#8212; or the government can do even further to make sure that these states and local municipalities are cooperating?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Mona, I think one thing that&#8217;s really important is to make sure that communities understand best practices and that they know how to get this funding out.<br><br>As Gene touched on, there&#8217;s, unfortunately, a dispersed system across the country on how to distribute this funding to renters.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just &#8212; we&#8217;re not &#8212; the issues in the housing market &#8212; or the hous- &#8212; or keeping renters in their homes is not a new issue; it&#8217;s one that has existed for quite some time, as it sounds like you know well.&nbsp;<br><br>So, one of the things we&#8217;ve done is we&#8217;ve hosted these two summits with 46 of the cities with most tenants at risk to help jurisdictions set up these new eviction prevention programs.&nbsp; And certainly, we want to provide renters with the understanding of what their rights are in this regard &#8212; that this funding can go out until 2025; that this funding is something that the federal government has advocated for because we want people to stay in their homes.<br><br>There&#8217;s no question there&#8217;s more work to be done, but the President advocated for this because he wants to make sure more people can stay in their homes.<br><br>And you&#8217;re asking about the &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The VRA.&nbsp; Just principally, people want to know: If the President can sign an executive order for transgender rights, for example, why can&#8217;t he find the same power &#8212; does he have the same power to sign an executive order for the VRA?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he &#8212; the Voting Rights Act?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, Voting Rights Act.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First of all, I would say that the &#8212; in order to make change permanent, you need legislation and you need laws passed.&nbsp; And the President is looking forward to and eager to sign voting rights legislation into law.&nbsp; There have been ongoing discussions many of you have reported on, and he&#8217;s going to keep at it.<br><br>He did sign a voting rights executive order early on in the administration &#8212; a historic voting rights &#8212; voting rights executive order, which provided &#8212; which, you know, he wanted to tap into every authority he had from the federal government to protect people&#8217;s rights.&nbsp; But certainly, making laws permanent will protect them longer term.<br><br>I know &#8212; we&#8217;ll have a longer briefing tomorrow.&nbsp; Thanks so much, everyone, for your time.<br><br>3:59 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Incoming Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal&#160;Hulata</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-incoming-israeli-national-security-advisor-dr-eyal-hulata/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 22:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with incoming Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata.&#160; Mr. Sullivan congratulated Dr. Hulata on his new role and emphasized that he looks forward to working together to strengthen all aspects of the U.S.-Israel partnership.&#160; Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Hulata discussed the strategic challenges in the region, including&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with incoming Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata.&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan congratulated Dr. Hulata on his new role and emphasized that he looks forward to working together to strengthen all aspects of the U.S.-Israel partnership.&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Hulata discussed the strategic challenges in the region, including the threat posed by Iran, and agreed to consult closely on these issues.&nbsp; They also exchanged views about the opportunities in the region, including advancing the normalization of relations between Israel and countries in the Arab and Muslim world and recent positive developments in Israel’s relationship with Jordan.&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan also stressed the importance of pursuing positive steps related to the Palestinians, which are critical to peace, security and prosperity. &nbsp;They discussed the upcoming visit to Washington by Israeli Prime Minister Bennett, and Mr. Sullivan conveyed that President Biden looks forward to warmly welcoming Prime Minister Bennett to the White House soon.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-29/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 21:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Jonathan Eric Kaplan, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Singapore. &#160; &#160; &#160;Francisco O. Mora, of Florida, to be Permanent Representative of the United States of America to the Organization of American States, with the rank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jonathan Eric Kaplan, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Singapore.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Francisco O. Mora, of Florida, to be Permanent Representative of the United States of America to the Organization of American States, with the rank of Ambassador, vice Carlos Trujillo.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Amy Elizabeth Searight, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Jonathan Nicholas Stivers.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of&#160;Indonesia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-foreign-minister-retno-marsudi-of-indonesia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 21:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of Indonesia in Washington, D.C. to discuss opportunities to deepen the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership. Mr. Sullivan informed Foreign Minister Marsudi that the United States will provide an additional $30 million in COVID-19 assistance to Indonesia, bringing the total U.S. assistance to Indonesia since&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of Indonesia in Washington, D.C. to discuss opportunities to deepen the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership. Mr. Sullivan informed Foreign Minister Marsudi that the United States will provide an additional $30 million in COVID-19 assistance to Indonesia, bringing the total U.S. assistance to Indonesia since the start of the pandemic to more than $65 million.</p>



<p>Mr. Sullivan underscored the United States’ enduring commitment to Southeast Asia and reiterated our support for ASEAN centrality and ASEAN’s essential role in the Indo-Pacific’s regional architecture. He noted we will continue high-level engagement with Indonesia and the region as part of our efforts to promote a free and open Indo-Pacific. They also discussed a range of bilateral and regional issues including the climate crisis and the importance of freedom of the seas and adherence to UNCLOS principles in the South China Sea. They shared deep concerns regarding the crisis in Burma and recommitted to promoting a swift return to democracy.</p>



<p>On COVID-19, they discussed the surge of cases in Indonesia and Mr. Sullivan underscored that his thoughts are with all those affected and that the United States will continue to stand shoulder-to-shoulder with the Indonesian people and support them as they battle the pandemic. He noted that the new $30 million in U.S. assistance will support additional oxygen and medical supplies to treat COVID-19 patients and enhance Indonesia’s ability to get shots into arms by supporting cold chain vaccine distribution, facilities readiness, and other measures. They discussed U.S. efforts to serve as an arsenal of vaccines for the world and our singular focus on saving lives, and they welcomed the August 1 arrival of an additional 3.5 million U.S.-donated Moderna vaccine doses to Indonesia through COVAX, bringing the total to 8 million doses donated by the United States to Indonesia thus far. They also discussed the Defense Department’s donation of PPE to the Indonesian armed forces for distribution to the civilian medical system as part of the ongoing Garuda Shield exercise. Finally, they discussed Indonesia’s continued leadership in advancing global health security and agreed on the need to create sustainable global health partnerships to prepare for future biological threats.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
