<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 07:42:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Quad Joint Leaders’&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/24/quad-joint-leaders-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 07:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54061</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[oday, we &#8211; Prime Minister Anthony Albanese of Australia, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, Prime Minister Fumio Kishida of Japan, and President Joe Biden of the United States &#8211; convene in Tokyo to renew our steadfast commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific that is inclusive and resilient. Just over one year ago, Leaders&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>oday, we &#8211; Prime Minister Anthony Albanese of Australia, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, Prime Minister Fumio Kishida of Japan, and President Joe Biden of the United States &#8211; convene in Tokyo to renew our steadfast commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific that is inclusive and resilient.</p>



<p>Just over one year ago, Leaders met for the first time. Today in Tokyo, we convene for our fourth meeting, and our second in person, to demonstrate, at a time of profound global challenge, that the Quad is a force for good, committed to bringing tangible benefits to the region. In our first year of cooperation, we established the Quad’s dedication to a positive and practical agenda; in our second year, we are committed to deliver on this promise, making the region more resilient for the 21<sup>st</sup> century.</p>



<p>With the COVID-19 pandemic still inflicting human and economic pain around the world, tendencies for unilateral actions among states and a tragic conflict raging in Ukraine, we are steadfast. We strongly support the principles of freedom, rule of law, democratic values, sovereignty and territorial integrity, peaceful settlement of disputes without resorting to threat or use of force, any unilateral attempt to change the status quo, and freedom of navigation and overflight, all of which are essential to the peace, stability and prosperity of the Indo-Pacific region and to the world. We will continue to act decisively together to advance these principles in the region and beyond. We reaffirm our resolve to uphold the international rules-based order where countries are free from all forms of military, economic and political coercion.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Peace and Stability</strong><br>We discussed our respective responses to the conflict in Ukraine and the ongoing tragic humanitarian crisis, and assessed its implications for the Indo-Pacific. Quad Leaders reiterated our strong resolve to maintain the peace and stability in the region. We underscored unequivocally that the centerpiece of the international order is international law, including the UN Charter, respect for sovereignty and territorial integrity of all states. We also emphasized that all countries must seek peaceful resolution of disputes in accordance with international law.</p>



<p>The Quad is committed to cooperation with partners in the region who share the vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific. We reaffirm our unwavering support for ASEAN unity and centrality and for the practical implementation of ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific. We welcome the EU’s Joint Communication on the EU Strategy for Cooperation in the Indo-Pacific which was announced in September 2021 and increased European engagement in the Indo-Pacific region. We will champion adherence to international law, particularly as reflected in the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea (UNCLOS), and the maintenance of freedom of navigation and overflight, to meet challenges to the maritime rules-based order, including in the East and South China Seas. We strongly oppose any coercive, provocative or unilateral actions that seek to change the status quo and increase tensions in the area, such as the militarization of disputed features, the dangerous use of coast guard vessels and maritime militia, and efforts to disrupt other countries’ offshore resource exploitation activities.</p>



<p>Individually and collectively, we will further strengthen our cooperation with Pacific island countries, to enhance their economic well being, strengthen health infrastructure and environmental resilience, to improve their maritime security and sustain their fisheries, to provide sustainable infrastructure, to bolster educational opportunities, and to mitigate and adapt to the impacts of climate change, which pose especially serious challenges for this region. We are committed to working together to address the needs of Pacific island partners. We reaffirmed our support for Pacific Islands Forum unity and for Pacific regional security frameworks.</p>



<p>Among ourselves and with our partners, we will deepen our cooperation in multilateral institutions, including at the United Nations, where reinforcing our shared priorities to reform and enhance the resilience of the multilateral system itself. Individually and together, we will respond to the challenges of our time, ensuring that the region remains inclusive, open, and governed by universal rules and norms.</p>



<p>We reaffirm our commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, consistent with United Nations Security Council Resolutions (UNSCRs) and also reconfirm the necessity of immediate resolution of the issue of Japanese abductees. We also condemn North Korea’s destabilizing ballistic missile development and launches, including multiple intercontinental ballistic missile tests, in violation of UNSCRs, and call on the international community to fully implement these resolutions. We urge North Korea to abide by all of its obligations under the UNSCRs, refrain from provocations, and engage in substantive dialogue.</p>



<p>We remain deeply concerned by the crisis in Myanmar, which has caused grave humanitarian suffering and posed challenges to regional stability. We continue to call for the immediate end to violence in Myanmar, the release of all political detainees, including foreigners, engagement in constructive dialogue, humanitarian access, and the swift restoration of democracy. We reaffirm our support for ASEAN-led efforts to seek a solution in Myanmar and welcome the role of Special Envoy of the ASEAN Chair. We further call for the urgent implementation of the ASEAN Five Point Consensus.</p>



<p>We condemn unequivocally terrorism and violent extremism in all its forms and manifestations and&nbsp;&nbsp; reiterate that there can be no justification for acts of terror on any grounds whatsoever. We denounce the use of terrorist proxies and emphasize the importance of denying any logistical, financial or military support to terrorist groups which could be used to launch or plan terror attacks, including cross-border attacks. We reiterate our condemnation of terrorist attacks, including 26/11 Mumbai and Pathankot attacks. We also reaffirm UNSC Resolution 2593 (2021), which demands that Afghan territory must never again be used to threaten or attack any country or to shelter or train terrorists, or to plan or finance terrorist attacks. We emphasize the importance of upholding international standards on anti-money laundering and combating the financing of terrorism by all countries, consistent with FATF recommendations. We reaffirm that in our fight against global terrorism, we will take concerted action against all terrorist groups, including those individuals and entities designated pursuant to the UNSC Resolution 1267(1999).<br><br><strong>COVID-19 and Global Health Security</strong><br>For more than two years, the world has grappled with the devastating impacts of COVID-19 – on our communities, citizens, health workers and systems and economies. The Quad countries have led and will continue to lead global efforts for COVID-19 response, with a view to building better health security and strengthening health systems. We commit to adapt our collective approaches to get ahead of the virus with a focus on preparing for new variants, and getting vaccines, tests, treatments, and other medical products to those at highest risk.</p>



<p>To date, the Quad partners have collectively pledged approximately USD $ 5.2 billion to the COVAX AMC, approximately 40 percent of the total contributions from government donors. We are proud to have delivered over 670 million doses, including at least 265 million doses to Indo-Pacific. Noting significant expansion in the global supply of COVID-19 vaccines, we will continue to share safe, effective, affordable and quality-assured COVID-19 vaccines where and when they are needed.</p>



<p>We welcome the progress on the expansion of J&amp;J vaccine production at the Biological E facility in India under the Quad Vaccine Partnership&#8211; sustainable manufacturing capacity will yield long-term benefit in the fight against COVID-19 and future pandemics. In this regard, we look forward to the grant of WHO’s EUL approvals regarding the aforementioned vaccines in India. We celebrate the donation by the Quad to Cambodia and Thailand of WHO approved Made in India vaccines, together with Quad members’ other vaccine related support, as an example of tangible achievement of our collaboration.</p>



<p>We will continue to address both the COVID-19 response and preparedness against future health threats. We will accelerate getting shots in arms through last mile support of which over 2 billion USD has been provided in more than 115 countries globally by our four countries, and will also address vaccine hesitancy through a Quad-convened event this week at the World Health Assembly. We will coordinate our efforts including through the &#8220;COVID-19 Prioritized Global Action Plan for Enhanced Engagement (GAP),&#8221; and COVAX Vaccine Delivery Partnership.&nbsp; We welcome the successful 2nd Global COVID-19 Summit co-hosted by the United States, and joined by the Quad members, which galvanized $3.2 billion in financial and policy commitments. We will strengthen support for economic and social revitalization in the Indo-Pacific region.</p>



<p>In the long term, we will strengthen the global health architecture and pandemic prevention, preparedness and response (PPR) to build better health security, including by enhancing finance and health coordination and bolstering on-going science and technology cooperation, such as through clinical trials and genomic surveillance<strong>.</strong> Building on existing Quad collaboration, we will enhance our capacity to improve early detection and monitor new and emerging pathogens with pandemic potential, and work to increase resilience to epidemics and pandemics. For the development of new vaccines to prevent and contain infectious diseases, Quad partners have collectively committed $524 million to the next phase of CEPI’s work, accounting for about 50 percent of the total public investors.</p>



<p>We commit, as members of the Group of Friends of UHC, to take global leadership to further strengthen　and reform the global health architecture for enhancing PPR and promoting UHC in the lead up to the UN High Level Meeting on UHC to be held in 2023.<br><br><strong>Infrastructure</strong><br>We reaffirmed our shared commitment to deepen cooperation on infrastructure, which is critical to driving productivity and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region. We also share a commitment to addressing debt issues, which have been exacerbated by the pandemic in many countries.</p>



<p>Quad partners bring decades of skills and experience together to catalyse infrastructure delivery to the region. We are committed to working closely with partners and the region to drive public and private investment to bridge gaps. To achieve this, Quad will seek to extend more than 50 billion USD of infrastructure assistance and investment in the Indo-Pacific, over the next five years.</p>



<p>We will work to strengthen capacities of the countries in need to cope with debt issues under the G20 Common Framework and by promoting debt sustainability and transparency in close collaboration with finance authorities of relevant countries, including&nbsp; through the&nbsp; &#8220;Quad Debt Management Resource Portal,&#8221; which consists of multiple bilateral and multilateral capacity building assistance.</p>



<p>We also welcome the meeting of the development finance institutions and agencies of the four countries in the margins of the Quad Leaders’ Meeting. We are working closely with experts, our region and each other to link our toolkits and expertise to better connect the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>We will further deepen collaboration and pursue complementary actions in identified areas, such as regional and digital connectivity, clean energy, and climate resilience including disaster resilience in energy related facilities that reflect the region’s priorities including ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific, to contribute to sustainable and inclusive growth in the region.<br><br><strong>Climate</strong><br>Recognizing the urgent need to address climate change as emphasized in the latest IPCC reports, we will steadfastly implement the Paris Agreement and deliver on the outcomes of COP26, accelerating our efforts to raise global ambition, including reaching out to key stakeholders in the Indo-Pacific region and supporting, strengthening, and enhancing climate actions by partners in the region including through mobilizing climate finance, both public and private, and facilitating the research, development, and deployment of innovative technology.</p>



<p>Today, we launch the &#8220;Quad Climate Change Adaptation and Mitigation Package (Q-CHAMP)” with &#8220;mitigation&#8221; and &#8220;adaptation&#8221; as its two themes. Q-CHAMP includes ongoing activities under the Quad Climate Working Group on: green shipping and ports aiming for a shared green corridor framework building on&nbsp; each Quad country’s input; clean energy cooperation in clean hydrogen and methane emissions from the natural gas sector; strengthening clean energy supply chains, welcoming the contribution of the Sydney Energy Forum; climate information services for developing an engagement strategy with Pacific island countries; and disaster risk reduction, including disaster and climate resilient infrastructure such as the efforts through the Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure (CDRI). Its coverage includes new cooperation in clean fuel ammonia, CCUS/Carbon Recycling, cooperation and capacity building support to advance high integrity carbon markets under Article 6 of the Paris Agreement, climate-smart agriculture, knowledge sharing on subnational climate actions, and ecosystem-based adaptation. To make Q-CHAMP tangible, we are committed to expanding our programs, in support of climate actions between our four countries as well as in the Indo-Pacific region. We recognize the immense challenges posed by climate change to the island nations of the Pacific.</p>



<p>We welcome the new Australian Government&#8217;s commitment to stronger action on climate change, including through passing legislation to achieve net zero by 2050 and lodging a new, ambitious Nationally Determined Contribution.<br><br><strong>Cybersecurity</strong><br>In an increasingly digital world with sophisticated cyber threats we recognize an urgent need to take a collective approach to enhancing cybersecurity. To deliver on the Quad Leaders’ vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific, we commit to improving the defense of our nations’ critical infrastructure by sharing threat information, identifying and evaluating potential risks in supply chains for digitally enabled products and services, and aligning baseline software security standards for government procurement, leveraging our collective purchasing power to improve the broader software development ecosystem so that all users can benefit. The Quad partners will coordinate capacity building programs in the Indo-Pacific region under the Quad Cybersecurity Partnership, and will initiate the first-ever Quad Cybersecurity Day to help individual internet users across our nations, the Indo-Pacific region, and beyond to better protect themselves from cyber threats.</p>



<p><strong>Critical &amp; Emerging Technologies</strong><br>The Quad remains focused on harnessing critical and emerging technologies to enhance the prosperity and security of the region. In the area of 5G and beyond 5G, while welcoming the Prague Proposals on Telecommunications Supplier Diversity, we will advance interoperability and security through the signature of a new Memorandum of Cooperation on 5G Supplier Diversification and Open RAN. We are also deepening our engagement with industry, including through Open RAN Track 1.5 events, and exploring ways to collaborate on the deployment of open and secure telecommunications technologies in the region.</p>



<p>We have mapped the Quad’s capacity and vulnerabilities in global semiconductor supply chains and have decided to better leverage our complementary strengths to realize a diverse and competitive market for semiconductors. The Common Statement of Principles on Critical Technology Supply Chains, launched on the occasion of this Summit, advances our cooperation on semiconductors and other critical technologies, providing a cooperative foundation for enhancing our resilience against various risks to the region. &nbsp;Our cooperation in the international standardization organizations, such as the Telecommunication Standardization Bureau of the International Telecommunication Union, has made great progress, and we expect to strengthen such cooperation through the new International Standards Cooperation Network (ISCN). This cooperation will help ensure technology development in the region is guided by our shared democratic values. We continue to strengthen our horizon scanning cooperation following our deepened discussions in biotechnology through our efforts on mapping and a corresponding Track 1.5 and a future focus on quantum technologies. We will convene a business and investment forum for networking with industry partners to expand capital for critical and emerging technologies.<br><br><strong>Quad Fellowship</strong><br>We recognize that people to people ties are the bedrock of the Quad and welcome the official launch of the Quad Fellowship, which is now open for application. The Quad Fellowship will bring 100 students from our countries to the United States each year to pursue graduate degrees in STEM fields, and is administered by Schmidt Futures.&nbsp; The first class of Quad Fellows will begin their studies in the third quarter of 2023, and we look forward to building together a talented cohort of next-generation STEM minds who will lead our countries in cutting-edge research and innovation.<br><br><strong>Space &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br>Space-related applications and technologies can also contribute to addressing common challenges such as climate change, disaster preparedness and response, and sustainable uses of oceans and marine resources. Each Quad partner will endeavor to improve public access to Earth observation satellite data and applications. We will work together to create an Earth observation-based monitoring and sustainable development framework.&nbsp; We will endeavor to share space-based civil Earth observation data, along with providing a &#8220;Quad Satellite Data Portal&#8221; that aggregates links to our respective national satellite data resources. We will work together to develop space applications, including in the area of Earth observations, and provide capacity building support to countries in the region, including with regards to partnering on using space capabilities to respond to extreme precipitation events. We will also consult on rules, norms, guidelines and principles for the sustainable use of space, and extend support to countries in the region through joint workshops including in relation to the UN Committee on the Peaceful Uses of Outer Space (COPUOS) Guidelines for the Long-Term Sustainability of Outer Space Activities.<br><br><strong>Maritime Domain Awareness and HADR</strong><br>We welcome a new maritime domain awareness initiative, the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness (IPMDA), designed to work with regional partners to respond to humanitarian and natural disasters, and combat illegal fishing. IPMDA will support and work in consultation with Indo-Pacific nations and regional information fusion centers in the Indian Ocean, Southeast Asia, and the Pacific Islands by providing technology and training to support enhanced, shared maritime domain awareness to promote stability and prosperity in our seas and oceans. IPMDA embodies what the Quad stands for: catalyzing our joint efforts towards concrete results that help to make the region more stable and prosperous.</p>



<p>Delivering on our commitment following our virtual meeting on 3 March 2022, we announce today the establishment of the &#8220;Quad Partnership on Humanitarian Assistance and Disaster Relief (HADR) in the Indo-Pacific&#8221;. This Partnership will further strengthen our collaboration to effectively respond to disasters in the region.<br><br><strong>Closing</strong><br>Today, with a shared vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific, we once again emphasize the importance of fundamental values and principles, and commit to work tirelessly to deliver tangible results to the region. In doing so, we will regularize the Quad activities, including regular meetings by the Leaders and Foreign Ministers. We agree to hold our next in-person summit in 2023 hosted by Australia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Albanese of&#160;Australia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/24/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-albanese-of-australia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 07:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden met with Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in Tokyo. President Biden congratulated Prime Minister Albanese on his election and expressed gratitude for his decision to travel to Japan for the Quad Summit on his first day in office. President Biden reaffirmed his steadfast support for the US-Australia alliance and commitment to strengthening&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden met with Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in Tokyo. President Biden congratulated Prime Minister Albanese on his election and expressed gratitude for his decision to travel to Japan for the Quad Summit on his first day in office. President Biden reaffirmed his steadfast support for the US-Australia alliance and commitment to strengthening it further. He commended Australia’s strong support for Ukraine since Russia’s invasion, and the leaders agreed on the importance of continued solidarity, including to ensure that no such event is ever repeated in the Indo-Pacific. The leaders praised the swift progress the United States and Australia are making, together with the UK, under the AUKUS partnership. &nbsp;They agreed to work closely together to implement the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework and to collaborate in addressing the existential threat posed by climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Modi of&#160;India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/24/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-modi-of-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 07:09:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54053</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met with Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India today in Tokyo to reaffirm their commitment to work together for a more prosperous, free, connected, and secure world. The leaders reviewed the progress made in the U.S.-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership. They committed to deepen our Major Defense Partnership, encourage economic engagement that benefits&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met with Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India today in Tokyo to reaffirm their commitment to work together for a more prosperous, free, connected, and secure world. The leaders reviewed the progress made in the U.S.-India Comprehensive Global Strategic Partnership. They committed to deepen our Major Defense Partnership, encourage economic engagement that benefits both countries, and expand our partnership on global health, pandemic preparedness, and critical and emerging technologies. The leaders discussed their shared belief in the urgent need to address climate change. They looked forward to enhancing their partnership to accelerate India&#8217;s just energy transition, including through the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership, especially in the areas of renewables deployment, decarbonizing the energy and industrial sectors, zero-emissions vehicles, adaptation, and mobilizing related investment in India.<br><br>President Biden condemned Russia’s unjustifiable war against Ukraine. The leaders’ committed to continue providing humanitarian assistance, and discussed how to cooperate to manage disruptions caused by the war in Ukraine, in particular the rise in energy and food prices, to protect their respective citizens and the world.<br><br>President Biden and Prime Minister Modi renewed their commitment to a bilateral relationship rooted in a shared tradition of democracy, freedom, tolerance, and equal opportunity for all citizens. President Biden welcomed India’s role in the Summit for Democracy’s Year of Action.<br><br>They expressed pride in the achievements of the third Quad Leaders’ Summit held today and the growing strength of the Quad partnership. The leaders affirmed the outcomes of the U.S.-India 2+2 Ministerial Dialogue held on April 11 which made evident that the United States and India have a breadth of cooperation matched by few other partnerships. Proving that democracies can deliver for the global good:</p>



<ul><li>President Biden welcomed India’s decision to join the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, and expressed confidence that India’s participation will help ensure an open, connected and prosperous Indo-Pacific.<br></li><li>The two countries concluded an Investment Incentive Agreement which provides a framework for DFC to continue to expand its investment in India for private sector-led projects in critical areas such as renewable energy, agriculture, health, and SME financing.<br></li><li>The two countries are renewing the Indo-U.S. Vaccine Action Program, which since its establishment has yielded several success stories towards the discovery, development, and manufacture of India’s first indigenous and low-cost vaccines to address rotavirus and COVID-19. The two leaders also discussed expanding collaboration to combat antimicrobial resistance, as well as non-communicable diseases such as diabetes and cancer”<br></li><li>The two countries announced India’s joining the Combined Military Forces-Bahrain as an associate member.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li>The leaders welcomed the launch of a United States–India Initiative on Critical and Emerging Technologies (iCET), spearheaded by the National Security Councils of the two countries to expand partnership in critical and emerging technologies.<br></li><li>The U.S. plans to join six of India’s Technology Innovation Hubs to support at least 25 joint research projects in 2022 in areas such as artificial intelligence and data science to advance progress in applications such as agriculture, health and climate. The U.S. National Science Foundation and Department of Science and Technology of India will deepen this cooperation through the new U.S.-India Initiative on Critical and Emerging Technology.&nbsp;<br></li><li>Recognizing the fundamental role maritime domain awareness plays in preserving economic security and in responding to humanitarian crises, the leaders noted with pleasure the establishment of the Indo-Pacific partnership for maritime domain awareness.<br></li><li>The U.S. and India committed to expanding cooperation in new defense domains, including through space, cyber, and launching a dialogue on Artificial Intelligence this year.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden During Quad Fellowship Announcement Photo&#160;Spray</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/24/remarks-by-president-biden-during-quad-fellowship-announcement-photo-spray/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 06:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[KanteiTokyo, Japan 12:46 P.M. JST Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, is the policy of strategic ambiguity towards Taiwan dead? PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; No. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Could you explain?&#160; PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; No.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, do &#8212; would you send troops to Taiwan if China invaded? PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; The policy has not changed at all.&#160; I stated that when I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Kantei<br>Tokyo, Japan</p>



<p>12:46 P.M. JST</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, is the policy of strategic ambiguity towards Taiwan dead?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you explain?&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do &#8212; would you send troops to Taiwan if China invaded?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; The policy has not changed at all.&nbsp; I stated that when I made my statement yesterday.</p>



<p>12:47 P.M. JST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden, Prime Minister Kishida Fumio of Japan, Prime Minister Narendra Modi of India, and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese of Australia at the Second In-Person Quad Leaders’&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/24/remarks-by-president-biden-prime-minister-kishida-fumio-of-japan-prime-minister-narendra-modi-of-india-and-prime-minister-anthony-albanese-of-australia-at-the-second-in-person-quad-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 06:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[KanteiTokyo, Japan 10:35 A.M. JST PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&#160; (As interpreted.)&#160; Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.&#160; President Biden, Prime Minister Modi, Prime Minister Albanese: I am delighted to welcome my friends to Tokyo.&#160; In particular, I thank Prime Minister Albanese.&#160; Welcome to Tokyo.&#160; I would like to offer him my sincere congratulations for assuming the post&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Kantei<br>Tokyo, Japan</p>



<p>10:35 A.M. JST</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Good morning, ladies and gentlemen.&nbsp; President Biden, Prime Minister Modi, Prime Minister Albanese: I am delighted to welcome my friends to Tokyo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In particular, I thank Prime Minister Albanese.&nbsp; Welcome to Tokyo.&nbsp; I would like to offer him my sincere congratulations for assuming the post of prime minister, and thank you very much for flying over to Japan right after the election.</p>



<p>Since last year, with Joe taking the leadership, our four countries were able to meet from time to time at the leaders’ level.&nbsp; Japan is taking over the baton this year, and I am truly happy that this time we are able to hold the Quad Summit in Tokyo.</p>



<p>A grave incident which has fundamentally shaken the rule-of-law-based international order we value has happened since we met last September.&nbsp; Russian invasion into Ukraine squarely challenges the principles which are enshrined in the United Nations Charter.&nbsp; We should never, ever allow a similar incident to happen in the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>Because of the harsh reality unfolding, it is extremely significant for us to get together and show to the international society the four countries&#8217; solidarity and our firm commitment toward the shared vision of free and open Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>Today, as we meet in person, I am looking forward for a candid exchange of views on global and regional situations.</p>



<p>At the same time, I must say that without walking in step with the countries in the region, we cannot secure success for the Quad either.&nbsp; We should therefore listen carefully to the voices of the countries in the ASEAN, South Asia, as well as the Pacific Island countries so as to further advance cooperation conducive in solving urgent issues facing the region.</p>



<p>During this meeting, I wish to clarify the concrete progress of broad-based practical cooperation that we have worked so far and also to discuss on new areas of cooperation such as assisting in regional climate change countermeasures, maritime domain awareness, as well as humanitarian aid and disaster relief.</p>



<p>Now, first of all, may I invite Prime Minister Albanese to speak, please?</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER ALBANESE:&nbsp; Well, Prime Minister Kishida, President Biden, and Prime Minister Modi: Firstly, can I thank you for your sincere congratulations on my election as Australia&#8217;s 31st prime minister.&nbsp; It is an honor that this is my first act as prime minister to attend this important Quad Leaders Meeting here in Japan.</p>



<p>And as we gather today, I acknowledge all that the Quad has achieved, standing together for a free, open, and resilient Indo-Pacific region and working together to tackle the biggest challenges of our time, including climate change and the security of our region.</p>



<p>My government is committed to working with your countries, and we are committed to the Quad.&nbsp; The new Australian government&#8217;s priorities align with the Quad agenda, taking action on climate change and building a stronger and more resilient Indo-Pacific region through better economic security, better cybersecurity, better energy security, and better environmental and health security.</p>



<p>Our cooperation is built on the values that we share: a commitment to representative democracy, the rule of law, and the right to live in peace.</p>



<p>Today, we look ahead to the work we&#8217;re yet to do.&nbsp; As the Indo-Pacific is reshaped, our Quad partnership is needed now more than ever to meet the challenges and threats of a less certain world; to shape that world for the better; and build a stronger, more cooperative Indo-Pacific region that respects sovereignty.</p>



<p>The region is looking to us to work with them and to lead by example.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why my government will take ambitious action on climate change and increase our support to partners in the region as they work to address it, including with new finance.</p>



<p>We will act in recognition that climate change is the main economic and security challenge for the island countries of the Pacific.</p>



<p>Under my government, Australia will set a new target to reduce emissions by 43 percent by 2030, putting us on track for net zero by 2050.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have had a change of government in Australia, but Australia&#8217;s commitment to the Quad has not changed and will not change.&nbsp; And our commitment to ASEAN and its centrality has not changed.</p>



<p>My government has already committed to a greater focus on Southeast Asia, including the appointment of a special envoy for the region and $470 million in additional foreign aid over the next four years.&nbsp; This is in addition to our increasing assistance to the Pacific by over half a billion dollars, deepening our defense and maritime cooperation and using the power of proximity to strengthen our partnerships.</p>



<p>We will bring more energy and more resources to securing our region as we enter a new and more complex phase in the Pacific&#8217;s strategic environment.&nbsp; And we will continue to stand with you, our likeminded friends.&nbsp; And collectively, we will continue to stand up for each other.</p>



<p>We will stand firm on our values and our beliefs on what we know will enhance the stability and prosperity of our region and what is firmly in the interests of all those who call the Indo- Pacific home.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m honored to be among such close friends of Australia to take these next steps with you to pursue positive and practical ways to support a free, open, and resilient Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>I look forward to strengthening our Quad partnership, starting with a productive meeting today.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m delighted to hand over to Prime Minister Modi.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much, Prime Minister Albanese.&nbsp; May I now ask the Prime Minister Modi to speak?</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER MODI:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Your Excellencies &#8212; Prime Minister Kishida, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese, and President Biden.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Prime Minister Kishida, thank you very much for your wonderful hospitality.&nbsp; I am very pleased to be among friends today in Tokyo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First of all, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese, my heartfelt congratulations to you on your electoral victory.&nbsp; <a>Your being here with us within just 24 hours of your swearing-in demonstrates the strength of our friendship within the Quad and your commitment to it.</a></p>



<p>Excellencies, the Quad group has made an important place for itself on the global stage in a very short time today.&nbsp; The scope of the Quad has increased and also it is more influential.&nbsp; Our mutual trust, our determination are giving democratic forces a new energy and enthusiasm.</p>



<p>At the Quad level, mutual cooperation is encouraging a free, open, and inclusive Indo-Pacific region, which is a shared objective for all of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite the difficult circumstances of COVID-19, we have increased mutual coordination in several areas such as vaccine delivery, climate action, supply chain resilience, disaster response, and economic cooperation.&nbsp; This is ensuring peace, prosperity, and stability in the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Quad is moving forward with a constructive agenda for the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp; This will continue to strengthen the image of the Quad as a force for good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER KISHIDA:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you very much, Prime Minister Modi.</p>



<p>May I now invite President Biden.&nbsp; Joe, please.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; It&#8217;s wonderful to be together with friends and &#8212; at this transformative moment in the world, and we are at a transformative moment.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida, I want to commend you for the extraordinary leadership that, over the past few months, you&#8217;ve shown and for the gracious way in which you’ve hosted all of us.&nbsp;<br><br>And, Prime Minister Modi, it&#8217;s wonderful to see you again in person.&nbsp; The &#8212; and I thank you for your continuing commitment to making sure democracies deliver, because that&#8217;s what this is about: democracies versus autocracies.&nbsp; And we have to make sure we deliver.<br><br>Prime Minister Albanese, I welcome you to your first Quad meeting.&nbsp; Like I said, you got on a plane &#8212; you were sworn in and got on a plane.&nbsp; And I’m &#8212; if you fall asleep while you&#8217;re here, it&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Because I don&#8217;t know how you&#8217;re doing it.&nbsp; But &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; it is really quite extraordinary.&nbsp; Just getting off the campaign trail as well.<br><br>Congratulations on your election.&nbsp; As I told when you won &#8212; I called you &#8212; that we greatly appreciate your commitment of being here so soon after taking office.<br><br>Quad leaders met for the first time just over one year ago.&nbsp; It seems longer, but, to date, our partnership is central to achieving our goals and critical for the foundation of our continuing cooperation, in my view.<br><br>We already accomplished a great deal, as was referenced earlier: cooperating on COVID-19 response and health security &#8212; more to do, to state the obvious; partnering on 5G and technology supply chains, technology standards setting; and launching our &#8212; our Quad Fellowship Program, which I think can make a difference, which we talked about earlier.<br><br><a>At the same time, we&#8217;re navigating a dark hour in our shared history. &nbsp;The Russian brutal and unprovoked war against Ukraine has triggered a humanitarian catastrophe.&nbsp; And innocent civilians have [been] killed in the streets, and millions of refugees are internally displaced as well as exiled.</a><br><br>And this is more than just a European issue; it&#8217;s a global issue.&nbsp; The fact is that what &#8212; if you turn on the television and you&#8217;ll see what Russia is doing now, it appears to me that Putin is just trying to extinguish a culture.&nbsp; He&#8217;s not even aiming at military targets anymore; he&#8217;s taking out every school, every churc<a>h, every &#8212; every natural history museum as if to try to obliterate the Ukrainian culture.&nbsp; And the world has to deal with it, and we are.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>The global food crisis is made worse by Russia’s blocking Ukraine from exporting its millions of tons of grain.&nbsp; And also, as long as Russia continues the war, the United States will work with our partners to help be the global response, because it&#8217;s going to affect all parts of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, the United States must and will be strong, steady, and an enduring partner in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; We are in the Indo-Pacific &#8212; we are &#8212; we are an Indo-Pacific power.</p>



<p>I was once asked by &#8212; well, I won’t go into it.&nbsp; But I was once asked by the leader of China why I kept talking about being an Indo-Pacific power.&nbsp; And I said, “Because we are.&nbsp; We share the Pacific &#8212; one entire side of our country.”&nbsp; And we have been deeply involved with all of you for a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As long as Russia continues this war, we&#8217;re going to continue to be partners and gle- &#8212; lead a global response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we&#8217;re an Indo-Pacific power, as I said.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to stand with you, our close democratic partners.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to stand for the shared values that &#8212; and the shared vision we all have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, shortly before Russia launched this invasion, my administration published our Indo-Pacific strategy to advance a free, open, connected, secure, and resilient Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>Russia’s assault on Ukraine only heightens the importance of those goals &#8212; the fundamental principles of international order, territorial integrity and sovereignty, international law.&nbsp; Human rights must always be defended, regardless of where they&#8217;re violated in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the Quad has a lot of work ahead of us.&nbsp; It’s &#8212; the fact of the matter is &#8212; and we&#8217;ve a lot of work to do keeping this region peaceful and stable; tackling this pandemic and the next one; and addressing the climate crisis, as referenced by our new colleague; ensuring that technologies of the future are governed according to our values &#8212; governed according to our values.</p>



<p>But a short time &#8212; in a short time, we&#8217;ve shown the Quad isn&#8217;t just a passing fad.&nbsp; We mean business.&nbsp; We&#8217;re here to get things done for the region.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m proud of what we&#8217;re building together.&nbsp; And I look forward to our vital partnership flourishing and for many years to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, Mr. Prime Minister.</p>



<p>10:53 A.M. JST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Quad Leaders’ Tokyo Summit&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/fact-sheet-quad-leaders-tokyo-summit-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 01:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54048</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In Tokyo, President Biden, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese of Australia, Prime Minister Modi of India, and Prime Minister Kishida of Japan will advance the Quad’s ambitious and diverse agenda, including through a major new initiative to improve maritime domain awareness across the Indo-Pacific. The leaders of the Quad nations—Australia, India, Japan, and the United States—will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>In Tokyo, President Biden, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese of Australia, Prime Minister Modi of India, and Prime Minister Kishida of Japan will advance the Quad’s ambitious and diverse agenda, including through a major new initiative to improve maritime domain awareness across the Indo-Pacific.</em></p>



<p>The leaders of the Quad nations—Australia, India, Japan, and the United States—will meet on May 24, 2022 in Tokyo for the fourth time and the second time in person. Established in the wake of the 2004 Indian Ocean Tsunami to coordinate humanitarian assistance and disaster relief, the Quad has since become a leading regional partnership dedicated to advancing a common vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific through practical cooperation on diverse 21<sup>st</sup>-century challenges. With six leader-level working groups—on COVID-19 Response and Global Health Security, Climate, Critical and Emerging Technologies, Cyber, Space, and Infrastructure—the Quad is building habits of cooperation among our four countries that will support a more peaceful and prosperous Indo-Pacific. President Biden and his fellow Quad leaders welcome the following announcements from the Tokyo Summit:<br><br><strong>The Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness  </strong><br><br>At the Tokyo Summit, the Quad leaders will welcome a major maritime initiative: <strong>the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness (IPMDA).</strong> In close consultations with regional partners, IPMDA will offer a near-real-time, integrated, and cost-effective maritime domain awareness picture. This initiative will transform the ability of partners in the Pacific Islands, Southeast Asia, and the Indian Ocean region to fully monitor the waters on their shores and, in turn, to uphold a free and open Indo-Pacific. Quad countries are committed to contributing to the region’s maritime domain awareness—a fundamental requirement for peace, stability, and prosperity—through an investment in IPMDA over five years. The partnership will innovate upon existing maritime domain awareness efforts, rapidly bringing emerging technologies to bear for the greater good of the Indo-Pacific community.<br></p>



<ul><li>IPMDA will build a <strong>faster, wider, and more accurate maritime picture</strong> of near-real-time activities in partners’ waters. This common operating picture will integrate three critical regions—<strong>the Pacific Islands</strong>, <strong>Southeast Asia</strong>, and <strong>the Indian Ocean region</strong>—in the Indo-Pacific. The benefits of this picture are vast: it will allow tracking of “dark shipping” and other tactical-level activities, such as rendezvous at sea, as well as improve partners’ ability to respond to climate and humanitarian events and to protect their fisheries, which are vital to many Indo-Pacific economies. IPMDA will do so by:<br><br><strong>Harnessing commercially-available data</strong> <strong>using existing technologies</strong>. Through a combination of Automatic Identification System and radio-frequency technologies, Quad partners can provide an unprecedented “common thread” of activities. Because of its commercial origin, this data will be unclassified, allowing the Quad to provide it to a wide range of partners who wish to benefit.<br><br><strong>Extending support for information-sharing across existing regional fusion centers</strong>, such as the Information Fusion Center-Indian Ocean Region, based in India; the Information Fusion Center, based in Singapore; the Pacific Islands Forum Fisheries Agency, based in the Solomon Islands, and the Pacific Fusion Center, based in Vanuatu, both of which receive support from Australia.<br></li><li>Quad partners will begin immediate consultations on this opportunity with partners in the region. As the initiative proceeds, the Quad will identify future technologies of promise, allowing IPMDA to remain a cutting-edge partnership that promotes peace and stability throughout the region.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>The Quad Fellowship</strong><br><br>Quad leaders are proud to open applications for the <strong>Quad Fellowship</strong>, which will sponsor 100 American, Australian, Indian, and Japanese students to study in the United States each year for graduate degrees in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) fields. The Quad Fellowship empowers exceptional STEM graduate students to advance research and innovation throughout their careers with a lens of positive social impact. It does so by providing scholarships, immersive and inspiring events at the nexus of STEM and society, mentorship and career-advancing programming, and cross-cultural exchange opportunities.</p>



<ul><li>The Quad Fellowship <strong>application </strong><a href="http://www.quadfellowship.org/apply"><strong>is live</strong></a> and will remain open until June 30, 2022. The first class of Quad Fellows will arrive on campus in autumn 2023.</li></ul>



<p><strong>The Quad Vaccine Partnership and Global Health Security</strong><br><br>The Quad is committed to maintaining its global leadership in responding to the COVID-19 pandemic and bolstering global health security. To date, Quad partners have collectively provided 257 million safe and effective doses to the Indo-Pacific. Even as we continue to donate vaccines, we will adapt our collective approaches to and prepare for new variants, including by getting vaccines, tests, treatments, and other medical products to those at highest risk.</p>



<ul><li>The United States will provide <strong>COVID-19 boosters and pediatric doses</strong> to countries of greatest need, including in the Indo-Pacific.<br></li><li>The <strong>Biological E, Ltd facility in India</strong> will continue to use expanded vaccine-manufacturing capacity as part of the Quad Vaccine Partnership. Our support is building sustainable manufacturing capacity, including for booster shots, which will yield long-term benefit in the fight against COVID-19 and future pandemics.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The Japan Bank for International Cooperation (JBIC) and EXIM India decided to support a <strong>$100 million facility</strong>, which will bolster the Indian health care sector, including global capacity for COVID-19 countermeasures.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Climate</strong><br><br>The climate crisis is existential for each of our countries and for the Indo-Pacific. The Pacific Islands are particularly vulnerable; as the Pacific Island Forum’s Boe Declaration on Regional Security <a href="https://www.forumsec.org/2018/09/05/boe-declaration-on-regional-security/">states</a>, “climate change remains the single greatest threat to the livelihoods, security and wellbeing of the peoples of the Pacific.” After inaugurating a <strong>Climate Working Group</strong> at our first-ever leader summit, in March 2021, our four countries have meaningfully deepened and regularized our cooperation on meeting the climate crisis. The Quad leaders will launch further efforts on green shipping, energy supply chains, disaster risk reduction, and the exchange of climate information services.</p>



<ul><li>The Quad will broaden and elevate our work to combat climate change by inaugurating two ministerials in the coming months. U.S. Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg plans to convene <strong>Quad Transportation Ministers</strong> and relevant stakeholders to accelerate the work of the Shipping Task Force, including progress toward developing Green Shipping Corridors among Quad countries. U.S. Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm plans to meet with <strong>Quad Energy Ministers</strong> to catalyze Quad efforts to deploy clean hydrogen, minimize methane emissions, and develop a 10-Year Clean Energy Supply Chain Plan.<br></li><li>The Quad will cooperate on disaster risk reduction for extreme weather events, including through the <strong>Coalition for Disaster Resilient Infrastructure (CDRI)</strong>, building on the Quad’s joint session on strengthening Indo-Pacific infrastructure and communities at the International CDRI conference.<br></li><li>The <strong>Quad Climate and Information Service Task Force</strong>, dedicated to integrating and facilitating climate information services to the broader Indo-Pacific, will convene other Indo-Pacific countries at the September Asia-Pacific Ministerial Conference on Disaster Risk Reduction in Brisbane, to share best practices and gauge user needs in the region.<br></li><li>The Quad will advance the development of <strong>clean hydrogen</strong> and <strong>clean ammonia</strong> <strong>fuels</strong> and launch a series of roundtables on mitigating methane emissions across our liquified natural gas (LNG) sectors. The Quad will also cooperate to enhance capacity in the broader Indo-Pacific region to participate in high-integrity carbon markets.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Critical and Emerging Technologies</strong><br><br>Our four countries are committed to responsible innovation in critical and emerging technologies. Since launching the <strong>Critical and Emerging Technologies Working Group</strong> at the first-ever leader-level summit of the Quad, in March 2021, Quad partners have mapped collective capacity and vulnerabilities in global semiconductor supply chains, and launched the <em>Common Statement of Principles on Critical Technology Supply Chains</em>, which will provide a cooperative foundation for enhancing supply-chain resilience in the region. At the same time, Quad partners are exploring ways to collaborate on the deployment of open and secure telecommunications technologies in the region, working with industry through Open RAN Track 1.5 dialogues.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Through a new <strong>Memorandum of Cooperation on 5G Supplier Diversification and Open RAN</strong>, the Quad will cooperate on technical exchanges and testbed activity to advance interoperability and telecommunications cybersecurity.<br></li><li>The Quad has advanced technical-standards cooperation through the International Telecommunication Union’s Telecommunication Standardization Sector and will redouble its efforts through the new <strong>International Standards Cooperation Network</strong>, a mechanism for like-minded allies and partners to share information on technical-standards activities and to increase situational awareness, coordination, and influence in international critical and emerging technologies standards.<br></li><li>To unlock opportunities in critical and emerging technologies through stronger engagement with the private sector, the Quad will convene industry partners to discuss business and investment issues. A <strong>Quad Investors Network</strong>, an independent consortium of investors that seeks to advance access to capital for critical and emerging technologies within and across the Quad, is being launched today.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Cybersecurity</strong><br><br>The <strong>Quad Cybersecurity Partnership</strong> seeks to build resilience across our four countries in response to cybersecurity vulnerabilities and cyber threats. Its areas of focus are critical-infrastructure protection, led by Australia; supply-chain resilience and security, led by India; workforce development and talent, led by Japan; and software security standards, led by the United States. Its work is guided by <strong>new joint cyber principles</strong> to improve cyber resilience in a rapidly changing threat environment. These principles aim to prevent cyber incidents, prepare national and international capabilities for potential cyber incidents, and/or respond quickly and effectively to a cyber incident, when or should one occur.</p>



<ul><li>The Quad will strengthen information-sharing among Quad country <strong>Computer Emergency Response Teams</strong> (CERT), including exchanges on lessons learned and best practices.<br></li><li>The Quad will improve software and Managed Service Provider (MSP) security by coordinating <strong>cybersecurity standards</strong> for Quad governments’ procurement of software.<br></li><li>Quad partners will launch a <strong>Cybersecurity Day campaign</strong>, open to countries across the Indo-Pacific and beyond, as part of our continuing efforts to strengthen cybersecurity awareness and action. This program will provide basic cybersecurity information and training to the most vulnerable sectors of our countries and regions, including schoolchildren, small businesses, and the elderly. Quad partners will lead this campaign in partnership with industry, non-profits, academia, and communities to maximize its effectiveness and reach.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Space</strong><br><br>As leaders in space, Quad countries are strengthening cooperation and pooling our collective expertise to exchange satellite data, enable capacity-building, and consult on norms and guidelines.</p>



<ul><li>Quad partners will strengthen their commitments to the free, full, and open <strong>sharing of space-based civil Earth observation data,</strong> and will jointly develop and promote the concept of Open Science in the region and globally.<br></li><li>The United States will coordinate with Quad partners on its <strong>cooperative civil Earth observation programs,</strong> to include the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) GLOBE and DEVELOP programs; the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Community Satellite Processing Package (CSPP) and Satellite Proving Ground Flood Mapping Portal; as well as the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) National Land Imaging Program.&nbsp;<br></li><li>As extreme weather events become ever more common in the Indo-Pacific, Quad partners will convene technical experts to drive new cooperation and set the stage for additional <strong>disaster mitigation</strong> and <strong>humanitarian assistance and disaster relief</strong> workshops or training among Quad partners.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The Quad partners intend to host a two-day workshop on implementation of the <strong>Long-Term Sustainability (LTS) Guidelines for Indo-Pacific</strong> countries focused on LTS implementation and on how LTS implementation can lead to positive changes in domestic policy, regulations, and outcomes.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Infrastructure</strong><br><br>To help meet the Indo-Pacific’s enormous infrastructure needs, Quad leaders launched the <strong>Quad Infrastructure Coordination Group</strong>, which will deepen collaboration and pursue complementary actions, including in digital connectivity, transportation infrastructure, clean energy and climate resilience.</p>



<ul><li>In Tokyo, the Quad’s respective heads of development-financing agencies met to discuss enhanced engagement to address the infrastructure-financing gap in the region. This high-level effort—which includes Australia’s Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade and Export Finance Australia; India’s EXIM; Japan Bank for International Cooperation; and the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation—will coordinate our strategic approaches, among our countries and with the private sector, to leverage solutions-oriented tools that support investments in critical sectors such as healthcare, clean energy and climate, digital connectivity, sustainable infrastructure, and supply chains.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Humanitarian Assistance and Disaster Relief</strong><br><br>The Quad was forged in the wake of the 2004 Indian Ocean Tsunami. In recognition of that history and of present-day threats, the Quad established a new humanitarian assistance and disaster relief (HADR) mechanism.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Through the <strong>Quad Humanitarian and Disaster Relief Mechanism</strong>, Quad partners will be able to coordinate and mobilize our civilian-led disaster assistance efforts, with support from civil defense and military assets when needed, to respond to disasters in the Indo-Pacific. The Partnership provides a framework for Quad partners to coordinate on joint disaster responses and develop a greater understanding of their respective HADR operations. Quad partners may provide joint or coordinated assistance as requested by an affected state in the crisis-alert, crisis-response, or post-crisis-review phases of a disaster. Quad partners will also be able to work together to improve crisis preparedness and early warning.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call Previewing President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Final Day in&#160;Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/23/background-press-call-previewing-president-bidens-final-day-in-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 01:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 8:24 A.M. JST&#160;MODERATOR: &#160;Good morning, everybody. &#160;Thanks so much for joining us. &#160;And apologies for the delay. &#160;As we said in the invite, this call is on background, attributable to senior administration officials and embargoed until the call concludes.&#160;Not for reporting but just for your knowledge, joining us again is [senior administration official].&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:24 A.M. JST<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR: &nbsp;Good morning, everybody. &nbsp;Thanks so much for joining us. &nbsp;And apologies for the delay. &nbsp;As we said in the invite, this call is on background, attributable to senior administration officials and embargoed until the call concludes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Not for reporting but just for your knowledge, joining us again is [senior administration official]. &nbsp;I’m going to turn it over to [senior administration official].<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Thank you very much. &nbsp;And thank you all for joining. &nbsp;I’d like to give a very quick preview of today’s Quad meetings, and then I’ll be happy to take some questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think as you all know, one of the very early decisions that the President made upon coming to office was to elevate the Quad to the leader level for the first time. &nbsp;And I’d note that the Quad meeting, which was virtual, given the pandemic at the time &#8212; or the situation &#8212; the pandemic situation at the time &#8212; was in March of 2021 &#8212; it was &#8212; and at that meeting, the leaders committed that they would meet in person, which they did, in September of 2021, at the White House, hosted by the President.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then they had another virtual meeting in early March, and then they had &#8212; are obviously meeting today in Tokyo for the second in-person meeting. &nbsp;And I think that it’s significant because this is an extraordinary trajectory and one that really reflects, I think, the administration’s focus on the region and its vision of how we can bring likeminded partners, likeminded democracies to work together to deal with common challenges and issues.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think what’s also very impressive is that in the space of, you know, 15 months, the Quad has become, essentially, an increasing cornerstone for &#8212; or fixtures &#8212; develop- &#8212; I&#8217;d say it&#8217;s developing into a cornerstone, and certainly it&#8217;s a fixture in regional &#8212; the regional order.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then I think that it reflects a commitment pile for countries to work together. &nbsp;It reflects also a sense that &#8212; you know, the goal here is not to create a lot of formal structures. &nbsp;The goal is to find ways to work together on issues that are of interest to the region and to try and really, in many ways, bring public goods to the region by harnessing the activities of all four countries, which are quite significant, to be able to address issues that matter across the Indo-Pacific.<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the conversations with leaders, but I think we can preview some of the work that we expect to be announced. &nbsp;I think that at the Tokyo summit, the Quad leaders will welcome a major initiative on maritime domain awareness. &nbsp;And we expect it to be called the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness.<br>&nbsp;<br>In close consultation with regional partners, what we&#8217;re referring to is the IPMDA. &nbsp;And you know how government loves acronyms. &nbsp;IPMDA will offer a new real-time, integrated cost-effective maritime domain awareness picture. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we believe that this addresses a real need and something that the administration has heard a true demand signal from almost across the region, be it from Southeast Asia, be it in the Pacific, be it in South Asia, which is for much better maritime domain awareness. &nbsp;The ability to know what is happening in countries’ territorial waters and in their exclusive economic zones.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so the idea is the Quad partners will cooperate to help deliver this kind of capability across the region. &nbsp;And I think that, you know, we expect that this will integrate three critical regions &#8212; as I said, the Pacific Islands, Southeast Asia, and the Indian Ocean region &#8212; in the Indo-Pacific. &nbsp;And this will allow the tracking of dark shipping and other tactical-level activities, such as rendezvous at sea, as well as improves partners’ ability to respond to climate and humanitarian events, and to protect their fisheries, which are vital to so many Indo-Pacific economies.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the IPDMA [IPMDA] will do this by harnessing a combination of automatic identification system radiofrequency technologies. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Quad partners will be able to bring all these together into an unprecedented common thread of activities, and the data will be unclassified, so &#8212; which will allow the Quad to provide it to a wide range of partners who wish to benefit. &nbsp;And it recognizes that the primary demand on this in many ways is not from militaries, it is for &#8212; for the equivalent of Coast Guards to be able to do both rescue at sea, to be able to monitor fishing, to be able to track illegal fishing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so I think that, you know, the way this will work is that there&#8217;ll be support for this information sharing across existing regional fusion centers, including in the different regions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that we are very &#8212; we’re very happy about the fact that there is a real demand, and we think that this will address it. &nbsp;And we look forward to continuing to work very closely with our partners, both in the Quad and across the region, to deliver a capability which we think will be very important to countries and really give them the tools they need to better maintain their sovereignty, better ensure &#8212; or better combat illegal fishing, and better be able to do rescue at sea and other humanitarian activities.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Quad leaders will also announce the opening of applications for the Quad fellowship, which will sponsor 100 American, Australian, Indian, and Japanese students to study in the United States each year for graduate degrees in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, in terms of COVID, there will be a discussion &#8212; and I think you should expect some announcements with regard to COVID-19 boosters and (inaudible) pediatric doses for countries in the greatest need, and obviously including in the Indo-Pacific.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think you’ll also see the Quad leaders announce a range of initiatives in the climate space, critical technologies, and cyber. &nbsp;And we’ll have more for you on that later today.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then I would note that there will be, I think, some discussions about issues of common interest to the Quad partners and to the leaders. &nbsp;And I think that they &#8212; if, you know, the past has taught us &#8212; they will have very direct, very candid conversations. &nbsp;I think that we’ve all been impressed at how comfortable the leaders are with each other and how comfortable they are having very, very serious conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that there will be one significant development, which is there will be a new Australian leader. &nbsp;And we&#8217;re delighted that Prime Minister Albanese was sworn in yesterday and then almost immediately went &#8212; got on an airplane to come to Tokyo to participate in these meetings. &nbsp;As many of you saw, he mentioned in his acceptance speech about how he would be doing this. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think it&#8217;s also very significant that former Prime Minister Scott Morrison mentioned in his concession speech the importance of conceding so that there would be a new prime minister who will be able to come represent Australia at the Quad. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that that really highlights the bipartisan support in Australia, as I think there is throughout the region &#8212; or throughout the Quad partners for the Quad &#8212; and, I think, a recognition of how quickly it has become a very critical element in each country&#8217;s foreign policy. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In that vein, I would note that the President will have bilateral meetings with Prime Minister Modi of India and Prime Minister Albanese, and that will be his first meeting. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m sure many of you are aware the President called him on the flight from Seoul to Tokyo, and they had a good conversation. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ll have more on those meetings as they happen. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I will take your questions. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR: &nbsp;Thanks so much, everybody. &nbsp;Our speaker does have a little bit of a hard out, so we&#8217;re not going to be able to get through as many questions but we&#8217;re happy to try and take a couple. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>First, why don&#8217;t we go to Esther Oh with NHK.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Hi. &nbsp;Thank you so much for taking my question. &nbsp;Does the President think that with India not being on board when it comes to condemning Russia, that it undermines the purpose of the Quad? &nbsp;Is he going to be having any discussions with Prime Minister Modi about the U.S. doing more for India so that India can diversify its military acquisition and oil imports so that it&#8217;s less dependent on Russia?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And my second question is: I know that the administration has said that there are no plans as of now to expand Quad membership. &nbsp;But why not take advantage of the situation and extend an invitation to likeminded allies in the region?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;So, thank you. &nbsp; And those are obviously both very topical questions. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll start off with the second one. &nbsp;I think that there is a recognition on the part of the Quad members and certainly the United States that there is interest, and growing interest, in the region, in the Quad.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think that the decision for the time being is that the Quad needs to build and reinforce itself and that the leaders, I think, are &#8212; have the common view that before thinking about possible expansion &#8212; and I would stress no decision has been made either way &#8212; the Quad needs to reinforce its ability to function. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would stress again: This is an ad hoc grouping. &nbsp;It doesn&#8217;t have letterhead. &nbsp;There&#8217;s no central secretariat or, you know, headquarters. &nbsp;This is four likeminded partners who work together. &nbsp;There&#8217;s an increasing array of working groups. &nbsp;And I think that the idea is to get those working well before thinking about what the next steps might be &#8212; and that&#8217;s to say without prejudging at all what those next steps are. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think that that&#8217;s something that the leaders are very aware of &#8212; the strong interest &#8212; and that there is going to be continued thinking about it as the Quad is able to reinforce itself, develop itself, and continue to be effective and hopefully become more effective going forward. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to your questions about the discussions with the Prime Minister of India, I think that the President is very aware that countries have their own histories, they have their own interests, they have their own outlooks. &nbsp;And the idea is to build on the commonalities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Inevitably &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s true, with all the members of the Quad, there are some differences &#8212; the question is how they become &#8212; how they&#8217;re addressed and how they&#8217;re managed.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think the President is very much of the view that the way to do this is to have candid and direct conversations of the kind that really can only happen when leaders meet and are able to see each other in person and speak their minds. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that the President is very aware that India has its own history, its own views, and that, you know, at the same time, having these kinds of conversation helps him to understand the Indian perspective and, I think, allows India and Prime Minister Modi to understand his own perspective and to look for areas of common ground. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that there is a broad understanding of the fact that what is happening in Ukraine is a serious threat to the international order. &nbsp;I think that the issue is how the countries are better able to work together to try and find common ground to address it. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the &#8212; I think you can expect the President also to talk to India, talk to Prime Minister Modi about how the U.S. and India can continue the really extraordinary work that has been done over the past 22 years to strengthen and develop the relationship. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think it is quite significant that we are now at the fifth U.S. president, the third Indian prime minister &#8212; from both parties in each country &#8212; that have made very significant efforts to strengthen the bilateral relationship. &nbsp;And I think that that&#8217;s something the President appreciates and that you can expect to see continued. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR: &nbsp;Thanks so much. &nbsp;Next, let&#8217;s go to Patsy from Voice of America. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp; &nbsp;Hello, thank you for doing this. &nbsp;My question is about the specifics of the COVID commitments that you mentioned about the pediatric doses. &nbsp;I&#8217;m curious to know how it relates to the already existing commitment that was made by the Quad &#8212; I believe it was March of 2021 &#8212; to deliver a billion doses, mostly to Southeast Asian countries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I understand, that commitment has not been fulfilled because of the Indian manufacturer having issues with WHO approval. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So is that going to be part of that or in addition to that? &nbsp;And just, kind of, if you could, give us an update on the status of that 1 billion doses commitment. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Thank you very much. &nbsp;And that&#8217;s a great question. &nbsp;I think that, you know, you obviously are tracking some of the issues that have come up.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think that it&#8217;s worth highlighting that what the Quad partners committed to a year ago was to increase production capacity and, at the same time, to deliver doses. &nbsp;And I think that, to date, the Quad partners have collectively provided over 257 million safe and effective doses to the Indo-Pacific.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that that is, in our view, a fairly significant number. &nbsp;And at the same time, the investment in expanding capacity has clearly happened.<br>&nbsp;<br>You&#8217;re absolutely right that they&#8217;re still waiting for a final approval from the World Health Organization. &nbsp;I think that, you know, that one of the things that the Quad partners are committed to is making sure that doses are safe and effective, and not trying to do anything to try and prejudge the approval process.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re very proud of the work that has been done. &nbsp;I think that it is impressive. &nbsp;And I think that you will see that there will be the continued production doses. &nbsp;And I think we all are aware there&#8217;s going to be a need for boosters, there&#8217;s going to be a continued demand for doses. &nbsp;And I think that the Quad partners have shown a willingness and ability to try and meet that demand.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think that you&#8217;re going to see, over the course of the rest of this year, a continued flow of doses. &nbsp;And we look forward to being able to show, at the end of the year, how far the Quad came in terms of meeting and upholding its commitments.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR: &nbsp;Thanks so much, everyone. &nbsp;And as I mentioned, our speaker unfortunately has to run to another commitment. &nbsp;So that&#8217;s all the time we have for today.<br>&nbsp;<br>As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until the call concludes, which will be shortly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you, everybody.</p>



<p>8:39 A.M. JST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Designation of Colombia as a Major Non-NATO&#160;Ally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/23/memorandum-on-the-designation-of-colombia-as-a-major-non-nato-ally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 22:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential DeterminationNo.        2022-14  MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Designation of Colombia as a Major Non-NATO Ally By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k) (the &#8220;Act&#8221;), I hereby&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right">Presidential Determination<br>No.        2022-14 </p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Designation of Colombia as a Major Non-NATO Ally</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k) (the &#8220;Act&#8221;), I hereby designate Colombia as a Major Non-NATO Ally of the United States for the purposes of the Act and the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 <em>et seq</em>.).</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on Mental Health and&#160;Wellness</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/23/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-mental-health-and-wellness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 20:45:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Children’s National Hospital     Washington, D.C. 2:58 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  Good afternoon.  Monique and I were talking backstage, and I was asking her about her work.  And she said, “I &#8212; I can’t imagine doing anything else.”  In the midst of all that all of you do every day and what&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Children’s National Hospital<br><em>     Washington, D.C.</em></em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">2:58 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  Good afternoon.  Monique and I were talking backstage, and I was asking her about her work.  And she said, “I &#8212; I can’t imagine doing anything else.”  In the midst of all that all of you do every day and what you endure &#8212; and I asked you the same thing &#8212; “Would you do anything else?” &#8212; you haven’t quit yet.  (Laughter.)  And it’s because I know you’re not the quitting type, at all.<br><br>And &#8212; and I do truly believe that the work that all of you do is an extraordinary gift that you have and that you give.  And so it was very important to me and to the President that we would be here today to say thank you to all of you.  Thank you.<br> <br>And, Monique, thank you for sharing your story and for the 16 years of dedicated service you have provided.<br> <br>So before I begin talking a bit more about the issue of the importance of mental health, I do want to start by providing an update about the infant formula shortage.<br> <br>The first military plane landed yesterday with more than 70,000 pounds of specialty formula, and the second will arrive later this week.<br> <br>I know this is a scary situation for our parents and the caregivers who are taking care of these babies.  Our administration is working around the clock to ensure that there is enough safe baby formula available for all who need it.  And it is truly one of our highest priorities.<br> <br>So, today &#8212; (applause) &#8212; okay, yes.  And collectively, I know, one of our highest priorities.<br><br>We&#8217;re here today to talk about improving the mental healthcare and wellness of healthcare workers.  And it is my honor to be here, of course, with our Surgeon General, Vivek Murthy.<br> <br>Dr. Murthy, I will say that you have done extraordinary work over your career, and in particular, you have been tireless in the fight against COVID-19.  And you have been &#8212; and I have witnessed it since the first days of our administration &#8212; a trusted voice throughout the pandemic.  So, on behalf of our nation, thank you, Dr. Murthy.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And I’m also very proud to be here with the folks who make Children’s National the outstanding facility it is: the doctors, the nurses, the healthcare aides, the hospital staff, and support staff.<br> <br>All of you who have chosen to live a life that is a life of service and, in particular, a life that is about our children and healing them, protecting them, and caring for them in the way that you do, in the way that I know is very personal.<br><br>And I will tell you, I &#8212; I &#8212; most of my career &#8212; in fact, all of my career &#8212; children have been one of my main areas of focus &#8212; what we can do to protect them, to keep them safe, to protect their wellbeing, and to nurture them in all the ways we know we have a responsibility as a society to do.<br> <br>You know, when we talk about our children &#8212; I know for this group, we all believe that when we talk about the children of the community, they are a children of the community.  And in that way, we should all feel a direct sense of responsibility for their wellbeing.<br><br>When I was a young prosecutor many years ago, I saw firsthand how adverse childhood experiences can have a lasting effect on mental health.  And for decades, I have fought to improve children&#8217;s health and wellbeing.<br> <br>As District Attorney of San Francisco, I helped launch the Center for Youth Wellness to support children who were dealing with the effects of trauma.<br> <br>And as Attorney General of California, I launched a new bureau of the California Department of Justice that I named the Bureau of Children’s Justice to protect children from the types of trauma that can have lifelong effect.<br> <br>I believe that the work that you all do to help the children and families of this community and of our country is truly remarkable work.<br><br>For many of the people who come through the doors of this hospital, they spend time here that is probably one of the most difficult times in their lives.<br> <br>And as doctors, as nurses, as staff, you provide life-saving medical care.  And you also offer comfort at a time when it is most needed.  Your compassion, I truly believe, is light in the midst of darkness, often.  And you do so much to take care of your patients in their time of need, which is why I’m here to say we need to do a better job of taking care of you.<br> <br>The COVID-19 pandemic has, of course, brought increased attention to the mental health of workers in our healthcare system.  And we have asked so much of you over the course of these last two-plus years.<br><br>Some of you held the hands of those who were dying on behalf of their loved ones.<br> <br>All of you worked around the clock long before we understood how COVID-19 spread or what it did to the body.  And before you were even vaccinated or had protective equipment &#8212; the kind you needed &#8212; you were still here doing this work around the clock.<br> <br>You spent hour after hour, many in a windowless room, unable to speak about how you were feeling or only being able to speak with a small group who truly could understand what you were going through.  But you did it nonetheless.<br> <br>So there is an urgent need that we have, I believe, to address all of this and to address, of course, what has resulted: the stress, the burnout, the mental health challenges that you experienced most recently because of the pandemic. <br><br>Yet, I will also say, and we know, the problem existed, this burnout issue existed even before the pandemic.  And I’d like to recognize and thank the unions who are here who have long been a leading voice on this issue.<br> <br>And, you know, the term “burnout” was originally coined in the 1970s by a psychologist to describe the mental repercussions he experienced while working in a clinic.<br> <br>The choice to dedicate your life to helping people is a noble one, but too often it requires that you sacrifice so much of yourself.<br> <br>In 2019, more than half of all healthcare workers reported feeling burnt out.  And that was &#8212; again, that was before the pandemic.<br> <br>Each of you made enormous sacrifices to save lives under impossible conditions, which is why President Joe Biden and I are fighting to transform how mental health is understood, perceived, and treated for all Americans and, in particular, for our health workers.<br> <br>You deserve access to the mental healthcare that you need.  You deserve support and understanding when you are struggling.  And you deserve working conditions that support your mental health.<br> <br>That is why our administration has invested more than $100 million to expand mental health resources, including funding for healthcare organizations to create evidence-based programs around mental health and wellbeing for their employees.<br> <br>In addition, we have dedicated $200 million to train the next generation of community health workers, including workers who specialize in mental healthcare and are also a trusted voice in their communities.<br> <br>And today, Dr. Murthy released a new Surgeon General’s advisory to address health worker burnout.  It will include practical guidance about how to make workplace conditions safer, and it will recommend eliminating policies that punish people who seek help for mental health or addiction.<br> <br>I urge hospital systems and administrators to follow the Surgeon General&#8217;s advisory.<br><br>You know, the bottom line is this.  On this issue of mental health, you know, one way to think of it is this: If you knew someone who broke their arm, you would help them.  You would make sure they went to the hospital to get a cast.  And after they came home &#8212; well, on their way home, you’d probably open the door for them, you’d help them when they got home to get the support they need to heal through the point that they are feeling pain and then just need to heal.<br> <br>We have to do the same when it comes to mental health.  I think for too long our system has failed to understand the significance of this.  I think for too long, when we think about healthcare, we act as though the body just starts from the neck down, instead of understanding we also need to address healthcare from the neck up: mental health.<br><br>So, if you are struggling, please know you are not alone, that you are seen, and that you deserve to receive the help you desire and the help you need.<br> <br>The President and I are fighting to expand mental healthcare for all Americans because everyone should have access to the support they need to thrive.<br> <br>So, with that, I thank you all again, each one of you, for the work you do.  You are the angels walking among us.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br> END                3:09 P.M. EDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement on Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for&#160;Prosperity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/statement-on-indo-pacific-economic-framework-for-prosperity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 19:15:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53888</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the United States, Australia, Brunei Darussalam, India, Indonesia, Japan, Republic of Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam of the Indo-Pacific region, acknowledge the richness and the diversity of our vibrant regional economy. We share a commitment to a free, open, fair, inclusive, interconnected, resilient, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region that has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">We, the United States, Australia, Brunei Darussalam, India, Indonesia, Japan, Republic of Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam of the Indo-Pacific region, acknowledge the richness and the diversity of our vibrant regional economy. We share a commitment to a free, open, fair, inclusive, interconnected, resilient, secure, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region that has the potential to achieve sustainable and inclusive economic growth. We acknowledge our economic policy interests in the region are intertwined, and deepening economic engagement among partners is crucial for continued growth, peace, and prosperity.<br>&nbsp;<br>We recognize the COVID-19 pandemic has underscored the imperative of working closely together to ensure that economic recovery and advancement are grounded in resilience, sustainability, and inclusivity.&nbsp; The pandemic has also emphasized the importance of strengthening economic competitiveness and cooperation and securing critical supply chains, while stimulating job growth and improving economic opportunities, including for our workers, women, medium- and small-enterprises, and our societies’ most vulnerable groups.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the long term, economic competitiveness will be largely defined by our ability to harness technology, promote innovation, participate in the digital economy, justly transition energy systems and achieve energy security, and tackle the climate crisis in a manner that produces equitable, inclusive growth and improves socio-economic welfare. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to prepare our economies for the future, we are launching the process to establish the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity.<br>&nbsp;<br>This framework is intended to advance resilience, sustainability, inclusiveness, economic growth, fairness, and competitiveness for our economies.&nbsp; Through this initiative, we aim to contribute to cooperation, stability, prosperity, development, and peace within the region.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We invite participation from additional Indo-Pacific partners that share our goals, interests, and ambitions for the region.&nbsp; We are committed to collaborating with our framework partners in a manner that acknowledges the importance of technical assistance and capacity building, allows us to maintain a flexible approach, and delivers tangible benefits for our peoples.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, we launch collective discussions toward future negotiations on the following pillars.&nbsp; Framework partners will be engaging in such discussions on various ways to strengthen economic cooperation to achieve these goals, and we invite other interested Indo-Pacific partners to join us.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Trade:</strong> We seek to build high-standard, inclusive, free, and fair trade commitments and develop new and creative approaches in trade and technology policy that advance a broad set of objectives that fuels economic activity and investment, promotes sustainable and inclusive economic growth, and benefits workers and consumers.&nbsp; Our efforts include, but are not limited to, cooperation in the digital economy.&nbsp;<br><strong>&nbsp;<br>Supply Chains: </strong>We are committed to improving transparency, diversity, security, and sustainability in our supply chains to make them more resilient and well-integrated. &nbsp;We seek to coordinate crisis response measures; expand cooperation to better prepare for and mitigate the effects of disruptions to better ensure business continuity; improve logistical efficiency and support; and ensure access to key raw and processed materials, semiconductors, critical minerals, and clean energy technology.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Clean Energy, Decarbonization, and Infrastructure: </strong>In line with our Paris Agreement goals and efforts to support the livelihood of our peoples and workers, we plan to accelerate the development and deployment of clean energy technologies to decarbonize our economies and build resilience to climate impacts.&nbsp; This involves deepening cooperation on technologies, on mobilizing finance, including concessional finance, and on seeking ways to improve competitiveness and enhance connectivity by supporting the development of sustainable and durable infrastructure and by providing technical assistance.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Tax and Anti-Corruption: </strong>We are committed to promoting fair competition by enacting and enforcing effective and robust tax, anti-money laundering, and anti-bribery regimes in line with existing multilateral obligations, standards, and agreements to curb tax evasion and corruption in the Indo-Pacific region. This involves sharing expertise and seeking ways to support capacity building necessary to advance accountable and transparent systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are continuing to identify additional areas of cooperation based on consultations among partners to further our shared interests, with a view to advancing regional economic connectivity and integration. &nbsp;We look forward to jointly creating conducive environments to boost flows of commerce, trade, and investments amongst our economies, and to enhancing standards and access to opportunities for our workers, companies, and peoples in our combined markets.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
