<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 10:50:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Tokyo,&#160;Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/22/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-tokyo-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Tokyo, Japan 4:33 P.M. JST MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Okay, I just have a quick topper, and then we’ll have Jake Sullivan for you guys. Okay, just wanted to give a quick update on our administration’s work to speed up the import of infant formula and get more formula to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Tokyo, Japan</p>



<p>4:33 P.M. JST<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Okay, I just have a quick topper, and then we’ll have Jake Sullivan for you guys.</p>



<p>Okay, just wanted to give a quick update on our administration’s work to speed up the import of infant formula and get more formula to stores.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under Operation Fly Formula, the Departments of Agriculture and Health and Human Services are authorized to use Department of Defense contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards so it can get to stores &#8212; store shelves faster.</p>



<p>On Sunday morning &#8212; or later today &#8212; a military plane will arrive in Indiana with 78,000 pounds of specialty infant formula, enough for over half a million bottles.&nbsp; This formula was manufactured in an FDA-approved facility and will be inspected on arrival like all food imports.</p>



<p>We prioritize this for the first shipment because this formula types &#8212; type serves a critical medical purpose and is in short supply in the United States as the result of the Abbott Sturgis plant closure.</p>



<p>We are working with USDA and HHS to ensure this formula goes to those who need it the most.&nbsp; Due to the urgency of the situation, the Secretary of Defense approved U.S. military aircraft for this mission on Friday evening.</p>



<p>Typically, the process to transport this product from Europe to U.S. would take two weeks.&nbsp; Thanks to Operation Fly Formula, we cut that down to approximately three days.</p>



<p>This is a testament of the President&#8217;s commitment to pulling every lever to get more infant formula onto the market.&nbsp; And Operation Fly Formula is one tool that we are using to do so.</p>



<p>Okay, I have Jake Sullivan, as you all can see &#8212; National Security Advisor.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can we have you step in just a little bit?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Hey, guys, just very briefly, you all know we&#8217;re on our way to Tokyo.&nbsp; And the President will spend tomorrow with Prime Minister Kishida and will also join a number of other leaders, some in person but largely virtually, to launch the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.</p>



<p>And then, of course, on Tuesday, he&#8217;ll join the Quad leaders for the second Quad Summit and also have the opportunity to meet with Prime Minister Modi and to meet with a Prime Minister who will then &#8212; right now, Prime Minister-Designate; as of tomorrow, actual Prime Minister Albanese, who is flying up tomorrow to be able to join in person for the Quad on Tuesday, which we think is a real testament to Australia&#8217;s investment in the Quad as a critical vehicle for the Indo-Pacific and this new Prime Minister&#8217;s investment in hitting the ground running as a leader in the region and a close ally of the United States.</p>



<p>So, I’m happy to get into details on any and all things, but why don&#8217;t I just stop there and let you guys fire away.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are those meetings with Modi and Albanese one on one?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; What do you mean by “one on one”?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he meeting with them separately?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I mean, there’ll be other people in the room &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m talking about like &#8212; other than the Quad is what I meant.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Will have disti- &#8212; in addition to the Quad, he’ll have a distinct bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Modi and a distinct bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Albanese.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question about the Quad meeting.&nbsp; On Taiwan: To what extent do you think that you guys will be talking with the Quad and other allies in Asia about a concrete action plan on how to respond if China were to invade Taiwan?&nbsp; And do you think that that action plan could include both military response and an economic response?&nbsp; So can you share a little bit about how much he&#8217;ll talk about that with the &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It won&#8217;t be part of the formal agenda of the Quad.&nbsp; But, of course, significant security issues in the Indo-Pacific will come up, and all of the Quad members share an interest in peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More broadly, the Biden administration is invested in working with allies and partners to send a clear message of deterrence and to support the basic policy of the Biden administration, which is a One China policy, the Three Joint Communiqués, and the Taiwan Relations Act, that we do not want to see unilateral changes to the status quo and we certainly don&#8217;t want to see military aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we do want that message coming not just from us, but from a range of allies and partners, both in the region and beyond.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working with allies and partners accordingly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, just to follow up on Taiwan, two questions.&nbsp; One, do you think it will appear in the Quad statement?&nbsp; And two, why is it not in the IPEF, given how important it is to global supply chains?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the Quad statement.&nbsp; So, when we do the backgrounder tomorrow laying down the main components of Quad outcomes, you can pose that question at that point.</p>



<p>And then, in terms of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, I don&#8217;t think we have yet actually announced who is in and who is not in.&nbsp; That will be unveiled hopefully in a very dramatic fashion.&nbsp; No, I’m just kidding.&nbsp; That will be unveiled tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the list finalized?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The list is finalized.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Taiwan invited?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Taiwan won&#8217;t be part of the launch &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said will or will not?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It will not be part of the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.</p>



<p>Ambassador Tai met with her counterpart from Taiwan just a couple of days ago.&nbsp; You can find a readout of that conversation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are looking to deepen our economic partnership with Taiwan, including on high-technology issues, including on semiconductors and supply chains.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re pursuing that, in the first instance, on a bilateral basis while we work with a range of other countries through the framework.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more follow-up on IPEF: China was out with some statements of Liu, the gentleman who is &#8212; deals with their policy on the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp; Said it&#8217;s basically closed &#8212; a closed club; there&#8217;s no reason to be doing that; things should be open and allow everybody in the Asia Pacific, including China, to join. &nbsp;What would you say in response to that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a surprise to me that China has concerns about the number of countries, the diversity of countries who have expressed interest in and enthusiasm for IPEF.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, it&#8217;s natural that they&#8217;re going to try to find ways to raise questions.&nbsp; In this particular case, it&#8217;s just flatly untrue to call IPEF closed.&nbsp; It is by design and definition an open platform.&nbsp; And we do expect, in addition to the countries that join for the launch tomorrow, others will come along in the months and years ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That being said, the breadth of participation tomorrow was such that it will very much show that it&#8217;s anything but a closed club.&nbsp; It is a &#8212; it is a very wide-ranging membership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will South Korea be one of those countries?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, now you&#8217;re putting me in a funny spot, because I directly answered on Taiwan.&nbsp; If we start going down country by country, then I&#8217;ll be announcing the membership of the Quad just stan- &#8212; I mean, of the &#8212; of IPEF standing here right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m going to leave the announcement of the participation to whatever Karine and the press team want to &#8212; want to do with that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But anyway &#8212; yeah, so I&#8217;ll leave it there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is IPEF strictly just mostly economic policies at this point?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Or does it also include addressing maritime security, when you talk about countering China’s &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No, it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not a security arrangement.&nbsp; It is an economic arrangement focused around the further integration of Indo-Pacific economies, setting of standards and rules, particularly in new areas like the digital economy, and also trying to ensure that there are secure and resilient supply chains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In that sense, maritime security is a relevant issue.&nbsp; But IPEF will not be negotiating out maritime security arrangements.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, a quick follow, too.&nbsp; So, the administration &#8212; you, as well &#8212; have often framed foreign policy strategy as a global battle between autocra- &#8212; democracies and autocracies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m wondering how you balance trying to engage economically with someone like Prime Minister Modi, who himself has been accused, under the guise of democracy, of human rights abuses and maligning Muslim minorities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How do you balance accountability, approaching a bilateral like that, while also the desire to have an economic collaboration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; President Biden has been clear from the beginning of this administration that we&#8217;ll speak out when we see any form of departure from or deviation from basic principles, fundamental freedoms, human rights, the values of democratic institutions, and the rule of law.&nbsp; That&#8217;s true for a range of countries.&nbsp; And, you know, we don&#8217;t single India out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have found a way both to pursue practical cooperation with countries that are democratic and non-democratic, while at the same time being clear and consistent of where our values lie.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to push him on wheat exports?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to push Modi &#8212; is the President going to push Modi on wheat exports?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just say that food security will be a topic of conversation at the Quad.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about Russia?&nbsp; What about Russia and the invasion at large?&nbsp; What is he going to say to Modi about that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, they&#8217;ve already had the opportunity to engage on that.&nbsp; And the President had an extended discussion with Prime Minister Modi when they did a virtual Quad Summit back in April.&nbsp; I think it was back in April, maybe even March.&nbsp; I think it was in March.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they also got to speak about it when they had a short video bilateral meeting at the top of the 2+2 when the Indian ministers came to Washington.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it won&#8217;t be a new conversation.&nbsp; It will be a continuation of the conversation they&#8217;ve already had about how we see the picture in Ukraine and the impacts of Russia&#8217;s brutal invasion of Ukraine on a wider set of concerns in the world, including this food security concern.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, they&#8217;ll talk all of that through.&nbsp; And I will leave the specifics of it to what has been a set of private and constructive exchanges, and I expect that this will similarly be constructive and straightforward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, you&#8217;ve written a lot and talked a lot about there being a domestic angle to foreign policy.&nbsp; This weekend, you guys sent $40 billion to Ukraine.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to announce IPEF.&nbsp; How does this fit into the domestic angle?&nbsp; What&#8217;s your message to people who are struggling with inflation back home about why these things are important to them?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, also this weekend, the President announced and held up major &#8212; or lifted up major new investments in the United States, job-creating investments that will help power the industries of the future, help the communities where those investments take place, employ thousands of workers.&nbsp; And that was true when he went to Samsung on Friday night, and it was true with the announcement with Hyundai this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>So this trip has, in part, been about not just talking the talk when it comes to delivering for American workers and American families when the President is engaged in foreign policy, but actually walking the walk and backing it up with real numbers that begin with a “B.”</p>



<p>Now, when it comes to the war in Ukraine, the President has been very straightforward that if &#8212; that if we, the United States, do not work with likeminded allies to stand up to aggression, we will pay a greater cost tomorrow.&nbsp; So he actually believes that this investment in the Ukrainian people&#8217;s fight to defend their country and in support of our allies who live under the shadow of Russian aggression is a worthy investment in terms of the long-term contribution it makes to peace, security, and stability.<br><br>That will benefit American families and American workers.&nbsp; And we actually think that the American people understand that and, more than understand that, they very much support it.&nbsp; And we see that on a bipartisan basis with the overwhelming votes in both the House and the Senate for that funding.<br><br>With IPEF, IPEF is designed to put workers at the center &#8212; American workers.&nbsp; It&#8217;s designed to create the kinds of high-standard approaches to the digital economy, to the clean energy transition, to diverse and resilient supply chains, to open and transparent economic governance that will ultimately benefit American workers, American families.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ll hear that from the President tomorrow.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, Jake, I want to take a step back.&nbsp; The President, on this trip, has highlighted China&#8217;s economic slowdown.</p>



<p>In the past, building alliances like IPEF sometimes had been frustrated by China&#8217;s economic ascendancy and its rising power.&nbsp; What impact do you think the slowdown is having on the U.S.’s ability to build alliances in Asia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think that, also taking a step back, that all of the traditional expectations about trajectories of countries that have been baked in over the course of several years in the press narrative and, you know, in the public conversation, including in this region, are due for review and reconsideration.&nbsp; And the fact that the United States will grow faster than China this year, for the first time since 1976, is a quite striking example of how countries in this region should be looking at the question of trends and trajectories.<br><br>And &#8212; and so, what the President said yesterday in his remarks at the press conference was something he said repeatedly over the course of his career, which is: It&#8217;s never a good bet to bet against the United States.&nbsp; And actually, we think a lot of countries in this region are recognizing that fact.<br><br>And when you see the breadth of participation in IPEF tomorrow, we believe that that will be strong evidence that countries do want to bet on the United States, do want to be part of an economic arrangement with the United States where we&#8217;re setting rules together, we&#8217;re building diverse and resilient supply chains together, that American innovation is at the heart and American infrastructure investment is at the heart of the economic strategy of a lot of these countries.<br><br>So our view is that this is not about a zero-sum game with China.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about forcing countries to choose.&nbsp; But it is about offering a value proposition that we think countries are taking extremely seriously.&nbsp; And we think that&#8217;ll be on display tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, on &#8212; I was going to say, on China tariffs, is the administration close to deciding whether you&#8217;re going to ease those tariffs that the last administration put in place?<br><br>And then on inflation, do you think that lowering or easing some of those tariffs really would help with the inflation problem by helping reduce some prices for U.S. consumers?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So the President has asked his international economic team to run the analysis on the relationship between tariffs and inflation, both top-line inflation and, just frankly, the way that families experience inflation, which is: When they go to the store to buy everyday products, are the prices higher?&nbsp; Would removing tariffs lead price &#8212; those &#8212; those prices on those goods to be lower?<br><br>So he&#8217;s asked for that analysis, and he has also asked for the perspectives of the range of voices in his economic team for how to proceed when it comes to the overall approach to China trade.&nbsp; And he will make a decision, you know, as soon as he feels that he&#8217;s got the inputs he needs to do so.<br><br>So I won&#8217;t put a timetable on it.&nbsp; But, you know, he&#8217;s considering his options when it comes to moving beyond the Trump trade strategy as we look to chart a new way forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Jake, how long &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he &#8212; sorry, just to follow up &#8212; has he gotten the analysis back from those teams yet, or is he still waiting on that?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He has gotten analysis.&nbsp; He’s received detailed written work on this question, but he&#8217;s asked further questions and is looking for more input.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you tell us about the President&#8217;s briefing so far on monkeypox?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s your current understanding of whether there is a national stockpile of vaccine the President referred to?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So there &#8212; there is a vaccine that is relevant to treating monkeypox.&nbsp; We have vaccine available to be deployed for that purpose.</p>



<p>The &#8212; your question was about him being briefed?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And how often and by whom.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, he has been briefed.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been out on the road, giving him updates based on the written inputs we are getting from our health and medical team and, you know, walking through with him what the &#8212; what the current state of play looks like and, as we learn about cases both in the United States and elsewhere, making sure that he&#8217;s tracking the picture.</p>



<p>So he&#8217;s being apprised on this on a very regular basis and getting inputs from the key members of his health team.</p>



<p>On Korea, you&#8217;ve talked about the risk of a ballistic missile test, or something like that, during the President&#8217;s visit.&nbsp; What does it say that, so far, such an incident hasn&#8217;t occurred?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard to speculate, honestly.&nbsp; And anytime people start speculating on what North Korea might or might not do, they tend to have their expectations confounded one way or another.</p>



<p>So, all we can do is control our policy and our approach.&nbsp; So, we were prepared for any contingency while we were in Korea, we&#8217;re prepared for any contingency while we&#8217;re in Japan, and we will stay very closely lashed up with the ROK and Japan on this.</p>



<p>And if North Korea acts, we’ll be prepared to respond.&nbsp; If North Korea doesn&#8217;t act, North Korea has the opportunity, as we&#8217;ve said repeatedly, to come to the table and start negotiating (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick follow-up on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;(Inaudible) still saying that they could do a test?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, yes.&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how are you going to measure the seriousness, the sincerity that the President talked about yesterday?&nbsp; How are you &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the intelligence still say that there could still be a test?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There could be a test.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how are you going to measure the seriousness and sincerity?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The first step would be for North Korea to come forward and be prepared to actually engage in a dialogue.&nbsp; And thus far, they&#8217;ve not shown that they&#8217;re willing to do so.</p>



<p>From there, it &#8212; you can determine through the substance of those initial conversations whether you&#8217;re on a serious pathway or not.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not even at step one yet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why do you think they haven’t?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there preconditions for them getting vaccines from you?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there preconditions for them getting vaccines from you?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why do you think they haven&#8217;t engaged while they were engaged so much with the Trump administration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; They go through cycles where they respond and cycles where they don&#8217;t.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a cycle where they&#8217;re not.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been true across multiple administrations.&nbsp; And I just can&#8217;t speculate as to the rationale for them not (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s about this president versus that president?&nbsp; You think it&#8217;s just sort of a cycle that&#8217;s outside of that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean, every previous president going back to Bush &#8212; so Bush, Obama, Trump &#8212; faced a nuclear test.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t yet.&nbsp; We anticipate we may.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each one of them faced missile tests; each one of them worked on a diplomatic approach.&nbsp; And at various points during each of those presidencies, the North Koreans were forthcoming, and at various points during each of those presidencies, they weren&#8217;t.</p>



<p>And so you could ask the question: Why hasn&#8217;t there been a nuclear te- &#8212; why wasn&#8217;t there a nuclear test in the first year when there was for these other presidents?&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think it has so much to do with who&#8217;s in the Oval Office as their own rhythms and cadences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I just violated my own rule and started speculating about their motives &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; so I&#8217;ll stop.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine, can you talk about when the first shipments of weapons from this new package will arrive, or when you&#8217;re expecting them to go out?&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to be in there?&nbsp; Anything new?&nbsp; And do you have anything on these &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; When you’re saying “this new package,” do you mean the next &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The one he just signed yesterday.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, the $40 billion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The 40.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we expect him &#8212; so the way that it works is a portion of that $40 billion is drawdown authority.&nbsp; So Secretary of Defense and Secretary of State have to make a recommendation to the President of a drawdown package.&nbsp; They are actively working through that now.&nbsp; We expect it&#8217;ll come up to the President in the next couple of days for him to then be able to move out on.&nbsp; But we are on the receiving end of that based on the law and the process.&nbsp; So I would also go to the Pentagon and State to ask them, okay, you know, when &#8212; when are they going to push it forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what’s the latest, you guys believe, on what&#8217;s happening on the ground in Ukraine?&nbsp; And do you have anything on the high-ranking commanders being fired in the Russian forces?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then what about that allegation from the Russian Defense Ministry that they destroyed a large batch of Western weapons from the U.S. and &#8212; and the Europeans?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that true?&nbsp; Do we think that they really did destroy a lot of weapons?&nbsp; I saw Ukraine was confirming it, but anything you can share?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I have nothing to validate it and haven&#8217;t had the opportunity to consult with the Ukrainians on it.&nbsp; What I can say is that, you know, we have what we believe to be a diverse and resilient supply chain for these weapons into Ukraine.&nbsp; So even if there is a circumstance where the Russians are able to target and hit some shipment on the ground in Ukraine, that&#8217;s not going to fundamentally, from a strategic perspective, disrupt the military assistance we&#8217;re providing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you tell us about how John Kirby is coming over?&nbsp; How did that all come together?&nbsp; And can you describe what his role will be and how often we&#8217;ll see him in the briefing room?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, John Kirby, as you all know, is a very effective national security voice and advocate for the President&#8217;s policies.&nbsp; Actually, you know, I think a good partner to you all.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re excited to have him at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m particularly excited to have him at the NSC, because having a senior voice who can come do these gaggles instead of me will just be awesome.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m joking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m joking.</p>



<p>No, but &#8212; but otherwise, we&#8217;ll work out how it&#8217;s all going to play out in practice.&nbsp; The key thing is that John, at a moment when we&#8217;re dealing with a series of really critical national security issues, is just going to bring a great wealth of experience.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to be fun to work with for me; he’ll be fun to work with for the entire press team as well.</p>



<p>Q    There was reporting that he would basically fill the same role that Ben Rhodes did near the end of the Obama administration.  Is that sort of how you guys are seeing the role, or is it going to be different?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The thing about describing models like that &#8212; the “Ben Rhodes model” &#8212; they tend to be unique to an individual.&nbsp; And Ben, who is a very good friend of mine, is a unique individual and served in a unique capacity to President Obama.<br><br>John Kirby will have the &#8220;John Kirby model&#8221; of the role of Coordinator for Strategic Communications at the NSC.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll shape it based on his own, kind of, capabilities, the relationship he builds with the President and the rest of the team.&nbsp; And so I &#8212; I think the comparisons tend &#8212; tend not to illuminate.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We&#8217;re landing, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; Thanks, guys.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, is there a reason why Biden didn’t sign the aid bill on camera &#8212; the Ukraine aid package?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think he just wanted to sign it very quickly.&nbsp; And that was the &#8212; that was just the &#8212; we&#8217;ve always said: Once he got the bills, he would sign it quickly.&nbsp; And once the &#8212; once he was done with his event yesterday, he was able to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s been some questions about whether or not it had to be flown over.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your understanding of why it was flown over to sign?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, so that we can actually have the &#8211;the original copy for him to sign it.&nbsp; So, what happened was &#8212; and I think we&#8217;ve shared this with all of you &#8212; there was a &#8212; a staffer who was already scheduled to be here.&nbsp; And so, it came &#8212; it came with that staffer and was delivered to the President to sign.&nbsp; Yeah, there&#8217;s nothing &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s nothing really more to it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, now that the DPA has been invoked and the actions that you listed at the top for baby formula, can you say when parents in the U.S. who are trying to get baby formula will be able to readily, you know, get baby formula?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, you know, the President &#8212; you know, you&#8217;ve heard us say this: The President understands the struggle of moms and dads and parents and caregivers and making sure that &#8212; you know, making sure that we get &#8212; a child has, you know, a healthy &#8212; a healthy &#8212; a healthy way of eating.&nbsp; A healthy formula is &#8212; and safe &#8212; and safe formula &#8212; is our number one priority, which is why we&#8217;re &#8212; you know, which is why we have been very, very acutely aware of &#8212; of the process that we&#8217;ve initiated with the flyover and also the DPA.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you yet.&nbsp; We want to exp- &#8212; you know, make sure it goes very quickly, because it&#8217;s so critical.&nbsp; And we know what &#8212; what families are going through.&nbsp; I &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have an exact timeline.&nbsp; Clear- &#8212; clearly, we want this to happen as fast as possible, as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a reason, also, that the administration isn&#8217;t seeking a stay in the Title 42 case?&nbsp; I know that you&#8217;re appealing.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We’re appealing.&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t have much more than &#8212; than what the DOJ is doing is appealing Title 42.<br><br>You know, we continue to believe Title 42 is a health authority.&nbsp; It is an authority that CDC is &#8212; has that was given to them by Congress.&nbsp; And so that is kind of what we also agree with, which is the authority that Congress gave them.<br><br>Yep.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s let you get to your seat.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; Thanks a lot.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>5:02 P.M. JST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea at the Air Operations Center’s Combat Operations Floor on Osan Air&#160;Base</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/22/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea-at-the-air-operations-centers-combat-operations-floor-on-osan-air-base/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Osan Air BasePyeongtaek, Republic of Korea 1:52 P.M. KST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; First of all, I want to say thank you.&#160; And I wish you’d work on your biceps a little bit.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And you too, pal.&#160; It’s about as big as my thighs.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And I was a pretty good athlete.&#160; And I &#8212; I’m&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Osan Air Base<br>Pyeongtaek, Republic of Korea</p>



<p>1:52 P.M. KST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; First of all, I want to say thank you.&nbsp; And I wish you’d work on your biceps a little bit.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And you too, pal.&nbsp; It’s about as big as my thighs.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I was a pretty good athlete.&nbsp; And I &#8212; I’m worried about you, Captain.&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; first of all, it’s great to be here with the President.&nbsp; We had a &#8212; we’ve had great meetings thus far.&nbsp; We had a great state dinner last night as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and I want to say what I’m sure the President thinks as well: Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you to all of you &#8212; every one of you.&nbsp; You are &#8212; you are the frontline of everything we’re concerned about.&nbsp; You represent the commitment of our two countries made to each other and the strength of the U.S.-ROK alliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our alliance &#8212; our alliance was formed through shared sacrifice of the Korean War.&nbsp; And now, seven decades later, thanks to you, the Republic of Korea is a strong, thriving, and innovating democracy.&nbsp; And our alliance grows stronger every single day because of you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, Korean and American forces stand sentinel still to &#8212; the integration and coordination between our forces is essential as it was yesterday and 10 years ago and 20 years ago and 40 years ago, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact is that deterring threats and underwriting stability is as vital today for not only the Peninsula but for the world &#8212; for the world.&nbsp; That’s what the President and I spent the last couple of days talking about.&nbsp; It’s not just the Korean Peninsula, it’s the world.&nbsp; And so &#8212;</p>



<p>Should I stop and have that translated?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>(A translation is provided.)</p>



<p>The connections that you form serving together &#8212; not just as fellow service members, but as friends &#8212; helps knit our two nations together.</p>



<p>To all the American troops that are here and your families: Thank you for what you do to defend our country and our ally, and for representing our country so very well.</p>



<p>And to the Korean forces: Thank you as well for your service, for having our backs just as we have yours.&nbsp; I won’t attempt the Korean, but we &#8212; we &#8212; we’re &#8212; we go together, and we go together well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve been impressed.&nbsp; Thank you so very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, we go together.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; It is an honor and pleasure to visit Osan Air Base with President Biden today.&nbsp; In particular, as the President of the Republic of Korea, I am deeply grateful to all U.S. airmen, airwomen, and also Korean Air Force soldiers for their service and devotion to defend the peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula, and also to your families who are waiting for you across the Pacific Ocean.</p>



<p>I believe that friendship between the U.S. soldiers and officers and also with the Korean soldiers and officer is the real strength and power of ROK-U.S. alliance.<br><br>Since the outbreak of the Korean War, President Truman ordered to deploy U.S. forces to Korea just five days after the war.&nbsp; And the place near Osan Air Base was the very first place to be deployed, which the Smith Task Force was deployed and engaged for the first time with the DPRK forces at the Battle of Osan.<br><br>After the Korean War, the U.S. forces started to run air base in Osan.&nbsp; And also, soon after, Korea also made its command.<br><br>I believe that KAOC is the center &#8212; critical center to together respond to the DPRK’s increasing nuclear and missile threat, and also a symbol of the robust ROK-U.S. alliance.<br><br>I believe that I would like to show my deepest respect and extend my gratitude to all of you for your service protecting world peace and freedom and for your patriotism.<br><br>Thank you very much.</p>



<p>And I would like to note, with appreciation, that KAOC as the center of Korea&#8217;s three-pillar system to defend the North Korean missile threat.&nbsp; And I would like to mention the importance of your role and responsibility to defend the security of this Peninsula.<br><br>And today, I&#8217;m really &#8212; I am delighted to be here with President Biden.&nbsp; And I really feel assured, seeing you today, as the center of our defense.&nbsp; I would like to once again extend my deepest gratitude to you.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>2:10 P.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One Departure &#124; Pyeongtaek, Republic of&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/22/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-pyeongtaek-republic-of-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 09:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Osan Air BasePyeongtaek, Republic of Korea 3:26 P.M. KST Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, quick question: What have your health advisors told you your level of concern should be about monkeypox and the cases that are in the United States and around the world? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, they haven’t told me the level of exposure yet, but&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Osan Air Base<br>Pyeongtaek, Republic of Korea</p>



<p>3:26 P.M. KST</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, quick question: What have your health advisors told you your level of concern should be about monkeypox and the cases that are in the United States and around the world?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, they haven’t told me the level of exposure yet, but it is something that everybody should be concerned about.&nbsp; We’re working on it hard to figure out what we do and what vaccine, if any, may be available for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it is a concern in the sense that if it were to spread, it’s consequential.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all they have told me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any message for the new Australian leader &#8212; the new prime minister that you&#8217;ll be visiting with in Tokyo?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking forward to seeing him, and the Quad matters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you spoken to him yet?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ve called him and congratulated him, but that’s it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>3:27 P.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Hyundai&#8217;s Investments in Savannah,&#160;Georgia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/22/remarks-by-president-biden-on-hyundais-investments-in-savannah-georgia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 09:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53831</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grand Hyatt SeoulSeoul, Republic of Korea 11:22 A.M. KST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Thank you, Mr. Chairman. CHAIRMAN CHUNG:&#160; Thank you. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, thank you, Mr. Chairman.&#160; It&#8217;s &#8212; I think the last time we were together, we were at a university.&#160; Was it two thousand and &#8212; CHAIRMAN CHUNG:&#160; Yeah, Yonsei University.&#160; 2013. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Grand Hyatt Seoul<br>Seoul, Republic of Korea</p>



<p>11:22 A.M. KST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Chairman.</p>



<p>CHAIRMAN CHUNG:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Mr. Chairman.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; I think the last time we were together, we were at a university.&nbsp; Was it two thousand and &#8212;</p>



<p>CHAIRMAN CHUNG:&nbsp; Yeah, Yonsei University.&nbsp; 2013.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; 2013.&nbsp; He showed me a picture.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t have a lot more hair then either.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>It&#8217;s great to be here to announce the more than $10 billion in new investment in American manufacturing.&nbsp; This new commitment of $5 billion for advanced automotive technology and $5.5 billion investment to open a new factory near Savannah, Georgia, is going to create more than 8,000 new American jobs.</p>



<p>The plan is to break ground as soon as January of 2023.&nbsp; And the new facility should be rolling out the latest electric vehicles and batteries to power them by 2025.</p>



<p>And the workers in Georgia who will build these pla- &#8212; these plants and manufacture this new electric battery technology, it means economic opportunity for an awful lot of Americans.</p>



<p>And I want to commend my friends and the two senators in Georgia, Rafael Warnock and Jon Ossoff, for how they&#8217;ve been fighting for Georgia to be the magnet for this clean energy investment.</p>



<p>And these investments are part of a trend my administration &#8212; in my administration.&nbsp; Manufacturing jobs are coming back to America.</p>



<p>Even before these new investments, my administration, since coming to office, created 545,000 new manufacturing jobs since we took office.</p>



<p>And thanks to Hyundai, we are being part of this transformative automobile sector and accelerating us on the road where we’re going to be <s>handling </s>[heading] to &#8212; the United States &#8212; an all-electric future.  And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re shooting for.</p>



<p>Our administration is setting ambitious standards to cut pollution in cars and trucks and boost &#8212; boost fuel economy standards for those continuing to operate on gasoline.</p>



<p>And last year, standing together with the CEOs of major American manufacturers, along with the CEO and the head of the United Auto Workers, I signed an executive order setting a goal of having 50 percent of all new vehicles sold by the year 2030 be electric.&nbsp; And it’s an ambitious target, I know, but I believe we can meet it.</p>



<p>But we’re all committed to making it happen &#8212; auto companies, American UAW, and the &#8212; and the federal government as well &#8212; because all understand the same basic thing: Electric vehicles are good for our climate goals, but they’re also good for jobs, and they’re good for business.</p>



<p>Hyundai and any company investing in the United States would benefit greatly from entering into partnerships with some of the most highly skilled, dedicated, and engaged workers in the world, anywhere you can find.&nbsp; And that is American union members.</p>



<p>And again, every venture to manufacture electric vehicles and electric vehicle batteries would be made stronger by a collective bargaining relationship with our unions.</p>



<p>Investing aggressively in electric vehicles and battery production now &#8212; now, not tomorrow &#8212; now &#8212; is also important for strengthening our long-term economic security and accelerating progress toward a clean-energy future.</p>



<p>You know, because of Putin’s war, we’ve been sort of knocked off slightly, a little bit, because of the impact of the &#8212; impact of Russian oil on Europe.<br><br>But batteries &#8212; batteries that will be made at this new facility in Georgia are going to power cars without one drop of gasoline and increase security of our battery supply chains as well.</p>



<p>That’s going to serve &#8212; save families money at the pump because they can skip the pump altogether.  And instead, families will be able to stop at one of 500,000 new electric vehicle stations &#8212; part of the network we’re going to be building across America with the $7.5 billion in funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. </p>



<p>And the Chairman told me walking out here that they’re also going to be investing in battery techno- &#8212; in charging stations as well.</p>



<p>My administration &#8212; and, by the way, when you invest in a charging station along a highway, it’s a little bit like years and years ago, when we were starting to build automobiles in America and you’re investing in a gas station.&nbsp; Other things pop up around it.&nbsp; It has &#8212; it has an effect of generating economic growth just by putting in the station.&nbsp; And I think you’re going to see that as well in the United States.</p>



<p>My administration is supercharging efforts to lead the electric future.</p>



<p>We’re also making historic investments in battery &#8212; battery manufacturing, clean transit, and light rail.</p>



<p>For example, we’re going to be investing $5 billion to transform our fleet of nearly 500,000 polluting, diesel school buses into clean, all-electric vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And my climate and jobs agenda is making the United States a premier destination for savvy private firms looking to invest in the electric vehicle future.</p>



<p>In fact, today’s welcome announcement by Hyundai comes on top of an additional $100 billion of investments in the last year from companies in America &#8212; in American manufacturing to build electric vehicles and electric batteries.</p>



<p>And so, folks, the administration is going to stay laser-focused on innovation and batteries and EVs, building out our infrastructure and increasing the market demand.</p>



<p>So, Chairman Chung, thank you again for choosing the United States.&nbsp; We will not let you down.</p>



<p>And over these last two days, I’ve been focusing all my &#8212; all the ways in which the Republic of Korea and the United States can work closely together to shape the direction of our world for the better.</p>



<p>This deal is another prime example of how that partnership &#8212; and innovation, expertise, and values that drive both the Korean and American people &#8212; are delivering for the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I thank you all for being part of this very integral clean, electric vehicle future, not only here but in my country, and for deepening the ties between our two great democracies.</p>



<p>Thank you all so very much.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, are you concerned about a North Korean missile test while you’re here in Asia?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We are prepared for anything North Korea does.&nbsp; We’ve had &#8212; we’ve thought through how we would respond to whatever they do.&nbsp; And so, I am not concerned, if that’s what you’re suggesting.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a message for Kim Jong Un while you&#8217;re here?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; “Hello.”&nbsp; Period.</p>



<p>Thank you.<br><br>11:29 A.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister-Designate Anthony&#160;Albanese</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/22/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-designate-anthony-albanese/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 09:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke with Australian Prime Minister-Designate Anthony Albanese to congratulate him on his election as Australia’s 31st prime minister. President Biden reaffirmed the United States’ steadfast commitment to the U.S-Australia alliance and his intent to work closely with the new government to make it stronger still. President Biden expressed deep appreciation for the Prime Minister-Designate’s own early commitment to the alliance, reflected in his decision to travel almost immediately to Tokyo to attend&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke with Australian Prime Minister-Designate Anthony Albanese to congratulate him on his election as Australia’s 31<sup>st</sup> prime minister. President Biden reaffirmed the United States’ steadfast commitment to the U.S-Australia alliance and his intent to work closely with the new government to make it stronger still. President Biden expressed deep appreciation for the Prime Minister-Designate’s own early commitment to the alliance, reflected in his decision to travel almost immediately to Tokyo to attend the Quad Summit—a vital opportunity to exchange views and continue to drive practical cooperation in the Indo-Pacific. President Biden looks forward to a close partnership between our administrations that will benefit the American people, the Australian people, and the world, starting with consequential meetings in Japan this week.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea at Official&#160;Dinner</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/21/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea-at-official-dinner/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 02:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Museum of KoreaSeoul, Republic of Korea 7:40 P.M. KST PRESIDENT YOON:&#160; (As interpreted.)&#160; Mr. President, distinguished members of the U.S. delegation, all fellow supporters of our alliance, ladies and gentlemen: It is an honor to welcome you here tonight.&#160; This year marks 140th anniversary of our diplomatic ties, and next year we celebrate 70&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">National Museum of Korea<br>Seoul, Republic of Korea</p>



<p>7:40 P.M. KST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Mr. President, distinguished members of the U.S. delegation, all fellow supporters of our alliance, ladies and gentlemen: It is an honor to welcome you here tonight.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This year marks 140th anniversary of our diplomatic ties, and next year we celebrate 70 years of alliance between our two nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At today’s summit talks, Mr. President and I&nbsp; reaffirmed our enduring commitment to the robust ROK-U.S. alliance and to seek together a new promise and future for our two countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In 1950, when communist invasion put my beloved homeland in peril, America’s sons and daughters fought together and sacrificed their lives to defend the freedom of a country they never knew.&nbsp; Thus, the ROK-U.S. alliance was forged in blood on the battlefield of the Korean War.</p>



<p>Since then, the alliance has been a strong foundation which buttressed Korea’s economic growth and prosperity based on free democracy and market economy.</p>



<p>The KORUS FTA, since it came into effect a decade ago, has created many decent jobs and promoted investment in Korea as well as in the United States.&nbsp; The bond between the Republic of Korea and the United States will grow even deeper.&nbsp; The cooperation between our two nations will become only stronger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sharing universal values of free democracy, human rights, and rule of law, our alliance will go beyond security to a cutting-edge technology alliance and to a global comprehensive strategic alliance.&nbsp; I will draw and design a new future vision of our alliance with you, Mr. President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, there’s a line from the poem, “The Municipal Gallery Revisited,” by William Butler Yeats, one of your favorite poets.&nbsp; It goes:</p>



<p>“Think where man’s glory most begins and ends,</p>



<p>And say my glory was I had such friends.”</p>



<p>The United States is such friend to Korea and so is the Republic of Korea to the United States.&nbsp; So now let me propose a toast to our dear friendship, to our shared journey for the freedom and human rights of all citizens around the world, and to the peace and prosperity of the region and beyond.&nbsp; We go to together.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>(A toast is given.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had very productive meetings today.&nbsp; And &#8212; but even more importantly, we&#8217;ve gotten a chance to get to know one another personally.&nbsp; We shared a lot of stories from our &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; early beginnings, and I think maybe we told each other too much.&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But &#8212; (translator begins) &#8212; please.</p>



<p>The idea you would quote William Butler Yeats, I appreciate very much.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp; That wouldn’t happen in London.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Revit- &#8212; Revitalizing this alliance was one of my key foreign policy priorities when I took office last year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, your country&#8217;s democracy shows the power to be able to deliver for its people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re proud to say, as the general who was with me today can say as well, that our armed forces stand side-by-side, standing sentinel on a Peninsula for seven decades to preserve the peace and make possible that shared prosperity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;d like to raise a glass.&nbsp; May the alliance between our two great nations continue to flourish through all the decades ahead.&nbsp; And as our combined forces say, &#8220;We go together.&#8221;&nbsp; Hear, hear.</p>



<p>(A toast is given.)</p>



<p>7:48 P.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing President&#160;Biden’s Third Day in the Republic of&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/21/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-president-bidens-third-day-in-the-republic-of-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 8:39 A.M. KST MODERATOR:&#160; Good morning, everybody.&#160; I hope you all had a very restful second night in Seoul.&#160; Thanks again for joining us on this background press briefing this morning.&#160; As I mentioned on the invite, this call is on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and embargoed until the call&#8217;s conclusion.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:39 A.M. KST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; I hope you all had a very restful second night in Seoul.&nbsp; Thanks again for joining us on this background press briefing this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I mentioned on the invite, this call is on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and embargoed until the call&#8217;s conclusion.</p>



<p>Just as yesterday, joining us this morning we have [senior administration official].&nbsp; We&#8217;ll, of course, have some time for questions at the end, but I will turn it over to [senior administration official] right now.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you very much, [Moderator].&nbsp; And I want to thank all of you for joining.&nbsp; I hope that you&#8217;re all having a good trip.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll very quickly go over today&#8217;s schedule and then take some questions.</p>



<p>So I think &#8212; you know, to start off with, I think you’ve seen throughout the trip how our foreign policy and the work that has been done through &#8212; to strengthen and revitalize our alliances delivers for the American people.</p>



<p>I think, building on that, today President Biden and the Executive Chairman of Hyundai Motor Group will discuss Hyundai’s decision to invest in a new electric vehicle and battery manufacturing facility in Savannah, Georgia.</p>



<p>They will announce more than $11 billion in new investment in American manufacturing.&nbsp; And it will be a new commitment of $5.7 billion for advanced automotive technology and the $5.5 billion investment to open a new factory near Savannah that will create more than 8,000 new jobs.</p>



<p>I expect that you’ll see the President highlight how clean energy investments like this will help us reach our climate goals as well as create good-paying jobs and benefit American workers and businesses.</p>



<p>He will also thank Senators Warnock and Ossoff for their outstanding work on this effort and their other efforts to bring these jobs to Georgia.</p>



<p>After this, the President will head to the area near here where he will greet the Chargé d&#8217;Affaires of U.S. Embassy Seoul, Chris Del Corso, and the Embassy staff.</p>



<p>He will then go to Osan Air Base, where he will visit the Air Operations Center&#8217;s Combat Operations Floor.&nbsp; This is in Pyeongtaek, Republic of Korea, and where the President landed on Friday evening.</p>



<p>The President will be joined there by President Yoon, where they will both engage with U.S. and Korean military personnel while working side-by-side to secure the Korean Peninsula&#8217;s airspace.&nbsp; It will reflect the close integration of the U.S. and ROK militaries and demonstrate the strength of our almost 70-year-old alliance.</p>



<p>I think this is something that really does reflect the truly integrated nature of the U.S.-ROK relationship.&nbsp; And I think that people will be impressed at how closely they work together &#8212; our personnel and the Korean personnel work together.</p>



<p>After that, the President will greet U.S. service members and military families at Osan Air Base in Pyeongtaek, Republic of Korea.</p>



<p>And then the President and the delegation will take off to go to Japan.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re looking forward to a very good day.&nbsp; I think something that both highlights the linkages between the U.S. and the ROK economies, that focuses on the commitment to the future and to bringing the benefits of both cleaner climate &#8212; or for better climate and cleaner energy to American workers and families, and, at the same time, creates benefits here in Korea.</p>



<p>So, with that, let me take your questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>If anybody has a question, please use the &#8220;raise hand&#8221; function on the Zoom interface, and we&#8217;ll try to get through as many questions as we can.</p>



<p>Again, this call is on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and embargoed until it concludes.</p>



<p>Why don&#8217;t we start with Aamer Madhani from the Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you.&nbsp; I just wanted to ask &#8212; you know, the President on Friday, in his remarks at Samsung, made a point about encouraging Samsung and others that are going to be investing in the United States to hire union workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This new EV plant in Georgia is in a &#8220;Right to Work&#8221; state.&nbsp; It seems unlikely that the union presence will be as great as it may be in other places.&nbsp; And I was just wanting to know: What is the President&#8217;s thinking, what is the administration&#8217;s thinking on the balance of pulling in this foreign investment in the U.S., but also his strong belief that union shops are best for business and best for American workers?</p>



<p>And then secondly, I was just wondering: Coming out of this trip, is it time &#8212; has a conclusion been made that Korea should be joining the Quad and the Quad should be expanding?</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Those are both very good questions, Aamer.&nbsp; And let me start off with the first ones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think that the President is very, very focused on bringing investment to the United States &#8212; investment that creates jobs, that creates well-paying jobs, and, at the same time, that brings technology and brings capacity to the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, you heard his remarks about his views on the importance and value of union workforce.&nbsp; At the same time, I think the President rec- &#8212; you know, I think it&#8217;s clear the President believes that very strong.&nbsp; At the same time, the President believes that it is really important to do whatever he can and whatever the administration can to bring investment and bring jobs to the United States.&nbsp; So, I don’t think there’s any contradiction there.<br><br>Obviously, his views on unions are clear, and the value of union labor.&nbsp; But at the same time, it’s very, very important to do whatever is possible &#8212; and I think you heard his words: He’s encouraging any investor in the United States to look to have &#8212; to look to partner and work closely with unions.<br><br>On your question about the Quad, I think that it’s important not to get ahead of ourselves.&nbsp; I mean, you know, as much as it’s significant that we’re now looking at the fourth leader-level meeting of the Quad &#8212; you know, two have been virtual; one has been in person &#8212; and it’s pretty significant that only 16 months in the administration that you’re looking at the second in-person summit.<br><br>I think it shows the commitment that the President has and the other Quad leaders have to building out the Quad.&nbsp; I think it’s important to recognize this is still a relatively new organization &#8212; or it’s not even &#8212; a relatively new grouping that is still figuring out how to best work together.<br><br>It’s a group of likeminded democracies and, in that sense, it’s natural that &#8212; you know, to think about ways in which you can work with other likeminded democracies.&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s also important to recognize that the goal right now is to develop and build out what has already been laid out, rather than to think about new members.<br><br>And I think that down the road, there may be some of that.&nbsp; But I think that we have to wait and see what happens as the grouping itself finds its legs, finds more things to do, finds more ways to bring public goods to the region, and finds more ways to harmonize the existing efforts, which are quite significant, of these four countries to make sure that they&#8217;re promoting a free and open Indo-Pacific, promoting resilience, promoting the ability to work with other countries, and helping other countries advance their own interests.<br><br>So I think that, you know, we&#8217;ll wait and see.&nbsp; And, you know, very clearly, we&#8217;re going to wait and make sure that we have a successful Quad Summit on Tuesday and then move forward to build things out.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Andrew Restuccia with the Wall Street Journal.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Just two quick ones.&nbsp; Since the President is going to Japan today, I was hoping you could kind of look ahead to the IPEF signing and what that might look like.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re just wondering if you have a sense of which countries might sign on to that and if the text has been finalized at this point.<br><br>And then could you just update us on the situation on Australia with the new Prime Minister, Anthony Albanese, and whether that will &#8212; whether he&#8217;s for sure attending the Quad Summit and, you know, if that &#8212; if the timing of all of that will get sort of turned upside down because of the dynamics there in Australia?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, look, I&#8217;m going to try and hold off previewing too much of the Japan stop.&nbsp; Our focus today is making sure that we execute a successful Korea stop, obviously.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve got a very full program in Japan, both with bilateral engagements as well as, as you pointed out, the IPEF launch and then the Quad.<br><br>I think that our view is that it&#8217;s a little premature to be talking about which countries.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I will say that I think that we&#8217;re very satisfied with the very strong interest throughout the region in participating in the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.<br><br>And, you know, as you know, I think these things &#8212; there&#8217;s all &#8212; it will bring very, very bad luck if we say that anything has been finalized at this stage.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re very confident that we have everything in place for tomorrow.<br><br>I think that &#8212; on Australia, I think, first of all, you know, obviously, we &#8212; we look forward to working with Prime Minister-Designate Anthony Albanese and his government.<br><br>You know, the U.S.-Australia alliance is extraordinarily strong, and we work together on an extremely wide range of issues.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been partnership and, you know, shared sacrifice going back to World War One.&nbsp; I think, as you know, U.S. and Australian troops have fought together in every conflict since 1918.<br><br>And I think that the &#8212; we&#8217;re very confident that the alliance is in very, very strong shape, and look forward to working with the Prime Minister-Designate to further strengthen it.<br><br>At the same time, I think it&#8217;s important that, you know, as much as this is significant, it&#8217;s always great to see a democracy go through a successful election, and &#8212; it&#8217;s also important to note that we send our very best wishes to Prime Minister Morrison, who was a very, very strong and able partner.&nbsp; And the &#8212; we&#8217;re grateful for the work that he and his government did to both strengthening the alliance, expand the relationship, invest in the Quad, and, you know, commend his efforts.<br><br>I think we look forward to working closely with the new Prime Minister.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of ourselves.&nbsp; As you know, there is some process issues in Australia.&nbsp; But at the same time, I think it&#8217;s significant that Prime Minister Morrison, in his concession remarks, noted that one of the issues for his conceding was the importance of making sure that Australia was able to participate in the Quad.<br><br>And look, we’re confident that they’re going to participate in the Quad.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Geoff Earle.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I just want to do a Ukraine question because South Korea has a pretty substantial defense industry.&nbsp; Did the President do anything to encourage, you know, this government to provide lethal support?<br><br>And then, as he heads to Japan &#8212; I know it&#8217;s a different situation given their constitution, but they&#8217;ve been doing what I think we see as pretty impressive amounts of security &#8212; I’m sorry &#8212; non-security aid and economic aid plus, I think, some other stuff.&nbsp; But does he have an ask for them to try to get everybody moving in the same direction with more?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, that&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; And let me start off by saying that the President and President Yoon obviously talked about threats to the rules-based international order.&nbsp; And first and foremost is Russia’s brutal invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>The President commended the ROK for what they have done.&nbsp; And I think you will not be surprised to know the President feels very strongly that we need to work with likeminded partners around the world to try and do more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t want to get ahead &#8212; and, look, I don&#8217;t want to get too much into (inaudible) details.&nbsp; But I think that the key thing is that the President made very clear how impressed he is by what the ROK has done and the fact that the ROK’s actions, I think, have further reinforced the degree to which key allies in Asia are supporting our efforts and the efforts of the international community in Europe, in the same way that in recent years, European countries have (inaudible) much more attention, shown much more interest in ensuring peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>So for, I think, the President, there&#8217;s &#8212; the idea that these are two different theaters I think doesn&#8217;t make sense anymore.&nbsp; These are &#8212; there&#8217;s very strong linkages between both.&nbsp; I think in Japan, I think that you can expect &#8212; and I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of our discussion with him &#8212; but I think you can expect that at each stop the President is going to focus on his concerns about Ukraine and the importance he places on providing assistance to Ukraine.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Next let’s go to Kevin Liptak with CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the line in the joint statement about potentially expanding the joint military exercises.&nbsp; Do you have a timeline for how those discussions would proceed?&nbsp; And do you have an expectation of when you think those expanded joint drills might take place?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you were coming up with that joint statement, was there any concern that restarting the full-scale joint military exercises might forestall the diplomacy that you say you&#8217;re looking for with North Korea?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So those are great questions.&nbsp; I think &#8212; first and foremost, I think that you saw the line in the joint statement, obviously. &nbsp;I think that the view from both the &#8212; from the administration and, I think, from the Yoon administration is we&#8217;re going to leave this to the militaries to work out.&nbsp; I think that the important thing is that this is something where there&#8217;s clear signals being given to them that they need to figure out what it takes to best ensure military readiness and best ensure our ability to work closely together.</p>



<p>I think that in terms of working on the joint statement, I think that &#8212; you know, I would just call your attention to the fact that President Yoon, during his campaign, was very clear about his views, about the importance of strengthening the alliance and of ensuring that our militaries are best able to deter and respond to provocations, as well as work together to support broader peace and security in the region.</p>



<p>I think that the &#8212; you know, from our standpoint, the key things here is this is part and parcel of a broader effort to step up our ability to work together, both in the military sphere, but also many others.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re very satisfied with &#8212; and very pleased with the progress that was made, and, you know, we believe that it was a joint statement that is particularly impressive, given that it was done in the first 11 days of a new administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think all of you know it is a challenge for a new administration to come to office and then immediately start engaging in a visit of this kind to have an extensive and substantive joint statement that covers a significant number of issues.&nbsp; This isn&#8217;t something that is easy to do.</p>



<p>And so we&#8217;re very grateful to our ROK partners.&nbsp; I think it reflects President Yoon’s very, very clear guidance and great determination to strengthen the alliance.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re very satisfied with the outcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ve got time for one last question.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we go to Sebastian Smith with AFP.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thank you so much.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; So, on North Korea again: Is there any movement on the sense of whether a nuclear test could be in the offing?&nbsp; Because coming into this trip, both from South Korea and from the U.S., of course, you know, there was a lot of &#8212; it was rather &#8212; you know, sounded like it was being built up into something that could happen pretty much any &#8212; any moment.&nbsp; And now the President is leaving.&nbsp; So is that moment of danger passed?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And my other question.&nbsp; More &#8212; just zooming out, the President, again, talked yesterday about, you know, he&#8217;d be ready to meet &#8212; even meet Kim, you know, under some kind of circumstances.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve said many times you&#8217;re ready to talk without any preconditions.&nbsp; But are the North Koreans really in a place where they can be engaged in that kind of initiative?&nbsp; Because this has been going on for decades.&nbsp; And is the President considering &#8212; has he ever talked about making any kind of outreach, something a little more dramatic, something to break this sort of stalemate or paralysis that seems to go on for almost forever?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah, not necessarily what Donald Trump did, but something different, in other words.&nbsp; Or is it just going to be more of the same?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, thanks.&nbsp; Thanks for that question.&nbsp; I think that, you know, let’s just look more broadly at the issue.&nbsp; I mean, obviously, North Korea, the DPRK, is a very significant challenge in many ways, both in terms of being a threat to the ROK as well as its destabilizing activities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that the President, first of all, was very clear about his views on North Korea and on the DPRK and on what he believes needs to be done.&nbsp; I think that the policy has been very clear.&nbsp; I would say that it is worth keeping in mind the challenges of COVID.&nbsp; And I think that from our standpoint, we believe that one of the challenges for the DPRK is that there have been very significant movement restrictions.&nbsp; And I think that there&#8217;s no question that that has had a big impact inside the country.&nbsp; And now the outbreak probably makes it even more significant.</p>



<p>And so that may be a factor in their lack of response to our very, very repeated approaches on a variety of levels to try and engage and to make clear our willingness to talk and to talk about a very wide range of issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has said he is seeking serious and sustained diplomacy.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been clear about &#8212; that we stand ready &#8212; that we&#8217;re deeply concerned about the COVID outbreak and that we stand ready to work with the international community to provide assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think we have to acknowledge: Ultimately, these decisions are up to the DPRK to make.&nbsp; And I think that our view is that we strongly encourage them to choose a path of diplomacy.&nbsp; We believe that our offers are very &#8212; you know, are a sign of how committed we are.<br><br>In terms of dramatic gestures, I think that what the President was clear on is that we&#8217;re not looking for gestures, we&#8217;re looking for very serious engagement.&nbsp; And this is a decision that only the DPRK can make.<br><br>I think that we are &#8212; we&#8217;re very conscious of the fact that they’re facing significant domestic challenges.&nbsp; We believe that engagement could possibly help address those challenges &#8212; with us, with others in the international community &#8212; but that this is their decision to make.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much, everybody.&nbsp; Thanks so much for joining.&nbsp; As I said, this call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until the call concludes, which will be momentarily.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll of course be in touch for other calls over the course of the trip.<br><br>Have a great day, everyone.<br><br>9:00 A.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea in Joint Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/21/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea-in-joint-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 23:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The People&#8217;s HouseSeoul, Republic of Korea (May 21, 2022) 4:18 P.M. KST PRESIDENT YOON:&#160; (As interpreted.)&#160; Mr. President Biden, it is my honor to welcome you to the Republic of Korea.&#160; At this summit, we shared the goal of developing the ROK-U.S. alliance into a global, comprehensive, strategic alliance, and we discussed relevant actions to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The People&#8217;s House<br>Seoul, Republic of Korea<br><br>(May 21, 2022)</p>



<p>4:18 P.M. KST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Mr. President Biden, it is my honor to welcome you to the Republic of Korea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At this summit, we shared the goal of developing the ROK-U.S. alliance into a global, comprehensive, strategic alliance, and we discussed relevant actions to that end.&nbsp; Moreover, we engaged in a candid conversation, building friendship and trust.</p>



<p>Today, I also realized that President Biden and I see eye-to-eye on so many fronts.&nbsp; Over the past 69 years, the ROK-U.S. alliance has evolved into the linchpin of peace and prosperity in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, a longstanding mission of denuclearizing North Korea, as well as the COVID-19 crisis, shifting trade order, supply chain realignment, climate change, democracy in crisis, and numerous other new challenges confront our alliance.&nbsp; These challenges can be tackled only when countries sharing the universal values of a liberal democracy and human rights come together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ROK- U.S. alliance sets an exemplary model of such solidarity.&nbsp; Korea and the U.S., as global comprehensive strategic allies, stand ready to meet these challenges collectively and shape a rules-based order in that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These aspirations that President Biden and I share are well reflected in the joint statement we&#8217;re adopting today.&nbsp; In the negotiations leading up to the joint statement, our two countries’ deputies have exhibited trust and partnership, which I note with appreciation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A sustainable peace on the Korean Peninsula is underpinned by a principled and consistent policy towards North Korea.&nbsp; In lockstep coordination with the Biden administration, I commit to resolutely safeguard peace on the Korean Peninsula and encourage North Korea to come forward for dialogue and engage in practical cooperation.&nbsp; I will exert diplomatic endeavors to that end.</p>



<p>We, as the leaders of the two countries, reiterated our common goal of the complete denuclearization of the DPRK.&nbsp; There is no compromise for security.&nbsp; Under this shared belief, we concurred that strong deterrence against North Korea is paramount.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden affirmed the ironclad U.S. commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea and substantive extended deterrence.&nbsp; At the same time, our two countries hope to see North Korea take the path towards genuine denuclearization.&nbsp; Together with a community of nations, we pledge to spare no diplomatic efforts to that end.&nbsp;</p>



<p>U.N. Security Council resolutions will also be faithfully and fully implemented together with other countries.&nbsp; The door to dialogue remains open if North Korea genuinely embarks upon denuclearization.&nbsp; In partnership with the international community, I am prepared to present an audacious plan that will vastly strengthen its economy and improve the quality of life for its people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Currently, North Korea is struggling with a COVID-19 crisis.&nbsp; Putting aside political and military considerations, I am more than willing to provide assistance from humanitarian and human rights perspectives.&nbsp; I call on North Korea to respond to this proposal positively and begin taking practical steps towards denuclearization.</p>



<p>We live in an era where economy is security and security, in turn, is economy.&nbsp; Supply chain disruptions resulting from a change in global security order are directly linked to the lives of our people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To adapt to the new reality, the ROK- U.S. alliance must also evolve further &#8212; not just with words, but with actions.&nbsp; We should ceaselessly strive to deliver real benefits that can impact the peoples of our two countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden and I &#8212; in the field of semiconductors, batteries, civil nuclear power, space development, cyberspace, and other emerging industries &#8212; agree to step up our practical cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Market shocks stemming from a shifting international order will also be actively addressed through our collective response.&nbsp; And as a first step, our Offices of the President will launch an economic security dialogue so that in supply chains, advanced science and technology, and other areas of economic security, our two countries can have timely communication and cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>An orderly and well-functioning foreign exchange market is crucial to sustainable growth and financial stability.&nbsp; To that end, President Biden and I decided to engage in even closer consultation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For advanced reactors and small modular reactors development and export promotion, our two countries’ civil nuclear industries committed to work together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, our two nations, with regard to the defense industry now emerging as a future growth engine, concurred to initiate discussions on a reciprocal Defense Procurement Agreement that can be likened to an FTA in the defense sector.</p>



<p>Korea, amid the ravages of war, achieved a remarkable growth with the help of the United States and the wider international community.&nbsp; The world now recognizes us as an advanced democracy, the 10th-largest economy, and a cultural powerhouse.</p>



<p>We stand ready to proactively fulfill the role expected of us by the international community to honor our responsibility and commitment.<br><br>The Indo-Pacific is a region important to both our countries.  Our two nations will work in concert to build a rules-based order in the Indo-Pacific.  And taking that first step is to participate in the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.<br><br>With a view to expanding our contributions and roles in the region, we will also work to formulate a relevant strategy.<br><br>Our two countries, in response to immediate global challenges, will pursue even closer coordination.<br><br>A tragedy brought on by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine must be resolved swiftly so that the people can return to their peaceful, normal lives.<br><br>To that end, Korea and the United States decided to cooperate vigorously with the international community.<br><br>Building on the KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership, Korea will actively join the global fight against COVID-19.  A Global Health Security coordinating office will be established in Seoul as a way to contribute to sustainable global health security.<br><br>In addressing the existential threat to humanity posed by climate change, our two countries will endeavor to achieve our 2030 greenhouse gas reduction targets and 2050 net-zero emission goals through even greater coordination.<br><br>The friendship and trust I have forged with President Biden today will pave the way for further reinforcing our bilateral partnership for a new era.  Towards this goal, I hope our two countries will engage in frequent communication and close consultation with each other.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Next, we’re going to invite the President of the United States for his statement.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you for all the time that you gave me today, particularly our private conversations and the incredible hospitality and welcome we’ve received.<br><br>I&#8217;m honored to be able to be &#8212; to meet you so early in your tenure, and it’s a pleasure to get to know &#8212; get to know you personally.<br><br>I’m delighted to be back in your beautiful country and at a time when the alliance between the Republic of Korea and the United States has never been stronger, more vibrant, or, I might add, more vital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I believe that this trip is coming at a particularly interesting moment, because we’re seeing so many expectations in Asia and the broader Indo-Pacific region being updated.&nbsp; I &#8212; I’m looking forward to it even occurring more.<br><br>My administration is pursuing an economic strategy designed to grow our economy from the bottom up and the middle out, and it’s paying dividends.&nbsp; Even in the face of historic economic challenges, our economy is providing and proving to be resilient.</p>



<p>In fact, just yesterday, an independent analysis projected that the American economy is poised to grow at a faster rate than China &#8212; than the Chinese economy for the first time in 45 years, since 1976.</p>



<p>And our relationship with our allies &#8212; including, I’m proud to say, the Republic of Korea &#8212; are closer than they’ve ever been.&nbsp; And our people are growing even closer as we speak.</p>



<p>Our businesses are blazing new trails together.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it all goes to my core belief, something I’ve said for a long time: It’s never a good bet to bet against the United States of America.</p>



<p>We’re a nation that is all about one thing: possibilities.&nbsp; Endless possibilities.&nbsp; <a>And that optimism is a commitment and &#8212; commitment to an innovation where breaking barriers is something that Koreans and Americans share.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Yesterday, the President and I visited a factory where Korean and American innovation are working in tandem to produce the most advanced semiconductors in the world.&nbsp; And I welcome the billions of dollars of investment that Korean companies like Samsung are making in the United States &#8212; investments that will bring our two countries even closer together, cooperating even more closely than we already do, and help strengthen our supply chains, secure them against shocks, and give our economies a competitive edge.</p>



<p>Today, President Yoon and I discussed the broad range of issues, as he’s mentioned today &#8212; I apologize for repeating him &#8212; on both regional and global terms.&nbsp; The cooperation between the Republic <s>in</s> [of] Korea and the United States is vital to our shared strategic progress &#8212; at least, we both believe that.</p>



<p>From fighting this pandemic to strengthening global health security, health systems, and so that we can better be prepared for the next major global health event &#8212; and there will be others; from increasing our climate ambitions to accelerating climate solutions, like development of electric vehicles; from standing up to our shared &#8212; for our shared democratic values and defending a rule-based international order against threats in stability, our alliance is making important contributions to shape the future for our children.&nbsp; And Korea’s strong and its dynamic economy is a powerful example of that for the rest of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to thank the people of Korea for their strong support for the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Putin’s war against Ukraine isn’t just a matter for Europe, it’s an attack on democracy and the core international principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>



<p>And the Republic of Korea and the United States are standing together &#8212; part of a global response with our allies and partners around the world &#8212; to condemn Russia’s flagrant violations of international law, and to hold Russia accountable, and to support the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, the President and I will be visiting with the Korean and American troops who are still serving side-by-side even today, decades after our troops first fought valiantly together, to preserve the freedom of the Republic of Korea.</p>



<p>It’s emblematic of our strength and our continuing strength, and of the durability of our alliance and our readiness to take on all threats together.</p>



<p>And today, President Yoon and I committed to strengthening our close engagement and work together to take on challenges of regional security, including addressing the threat posed by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea by further strengthening our deterrence posture and working toward a complete denuclearization of the prin- &#8212; of the Korean Peninsula, as the President has already spoken to; promoting stability across the Taiwan Straits as well; and ensuring freedom of navigation, including in the South China Sea and beyond.</p>



<p>So thank you again, Mr. President, for your warm welcome, for your commitment to strengthening our alliance, and for explan- &#8212; expanding our global partnership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I look forward to years to come.</p>



<p>Now, I believe &#8212; who asks the first question?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Now we’re going to open the floor for questions and answers.&nbsp; The presidents of the two countries will be &#8212; designate a person that will be asking questions.</p>



<p>Now we&#8217;ll be taking a question from &#8212; a Korean journalist will be posing a question to the Korean president.&nbsp; So please raise your hand, and the president will designate a person for the question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.) &nbsp;Thank you for this opportunity to pose a question.&nbsp; My name is Han Ji-hoon, Yonhap News Agency.</p>



<p>First, regarding the concept of economic security, a number</p>



<p>of Koreans find the concept pretty unfamiliar.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what are the benefits the Korean economy can gain from the economic security promote &#8212; cooperation?&nbsp; What are the real benefits that can be experienced by the Korean people?<br><br>And in addition to that, you talked about universal values &#8212; solidarity and alliance &#8212; and you very much underscored that point.&nbsp; But if there are, for example, countries that cannot share those values &#8212; for example, strong export regulations or controls that the United States is imposing on other countries &#8212; do you think you can take &#8212; resort to those measures as well?<br><br>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; As you may be very well aware, economic security is probably something that you have already heard and seen through various newspaper channels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s say, for example, this is directly related to the livelihoods of our people.&nbsp; And important industrial goods, for them to be produced &#8212; for example, let&#8217;s say that we&#8217;re trying to produce and manu- &#8212; a car &#8212; the unique system of semiconductors.&nbsp; And, for example, we had (inaudible) water issues recently.&nbsp; And so these are materials that are critically needed for our daily lives as well as our industrial production. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And to secure stability in the supply chain is very much and directly related to the lives of the people as well as the national economy.&nbsp; And this is, in turn, related to the national security as well as military security.</p>



<p>And in the past, we had the WTO system that brought countries together to form a free and universal trading order, but due to the COVID-19 pandemic and the formation of the blocks in the market, we see permanent risks when it comes to the supply chain.&nbsp; So it is very important to stabilize the supply chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And especially our two countries, the United States and Korea, we share the values of democracy and human rights.&nbsp; And among the likeminded countries, they share the values that would be important to stabilize the supply chain.&nbsp; That is why we need to deal with the issue of economic security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The NSCs of the Offices of the President are given that authority to deal with this issue.&nbsp; And, for example, if there are any difficult issues to be resolved, then the two countries will be engaged in closer cooperation for economic security.&nbsp; And we decided to pursue this goal going forward.<br><br>In addition, if you look at the financial market or the foreign exchange market, there could be possible shocks.&nbsp; And when that happens, the two countries can step in to help with each other, and also related to the military security and also economic security.&nbsp; Especially in relation to the export of defense items, what the two countries hope to do is to initiate the negotiations in this area so that we can pave the way for promoting our cooperation in the specific fields.<br><br>This is not just cooperation in terms of words or empty words &#8212; empty promises. &nbsp;It is going to be an alliance that takes action together.&nbsp; And we decided to evolve our alliance even further.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the United States and Korea, we advocate democracy, human rights, and freedom.&nbsp; And even those countries that are not sharing those specific values, for the world peace, of course, we’re not trying to exclude them in the process, but we want these countries to be embraced in these universal values.</p>



<p>So, especially, we want to start this close solidarity and cooperation among the likeminded countries and countries that share the values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Now we&#8217;ll take the question from the American journalist who will be posing questions to the American President.&nbsp; Please raise your hand.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Trevor Hunnicutt.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; First of all, President Yoon, your joint statement mentions a number of initiatives that you&#8217;ll be taking on the security front, but it doesn&#8217;t mention whether you asked the President for nuclear bombers, submarines, or aircraft carriers.&nbsp; Are those of interest to you?&nbsp; And do you expect that the President will be deploying them?</p>



<p>And for you, President Biden, there is no mention in the joint statement about whether there would be any preconditions for you meeting with North Korea&#8217;s Kim or providing vaccines to North Korea.&nbsp; And so, I wanted to see if there are any preconditions for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, ahead of your meetings in Tokyo, I understand that they will be asking for you to consider rejoining the TPP that was negotiated by President Obama.&nbsp; Could you talk a little bit about your thinking about whether this Indo-Pacific Economic Framework can lead to a bigger trade deal in the region?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Would you like me to go first?</p>



<p>The answer with regard to would I meet &#8212; would I provide vaccines for North Korea and would I prepare to meet: The answer is yes.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve offered vaccines not only to North Korea but to China as well, and we&#8217;re prepared to do that immediately.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gotten no response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to whether I would meet with the leader of North Korea, that would be dependent on whether he was sincere and whether it was serious.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What was the other question you asked me?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The TPP &#8212; the TPP and whether there&#8217;s room for a broader trade deal to come out of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp; We understand that Japan and others would like you to consider &#8212; reconsider joining.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, I think what you&#8217;re going to see is &#8212; what we&#8217;re talking about in terms of this &#8212; this arrangement we&#8217;re discussing now, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s quite significant.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re talking about is, as it was pointed out, an economic strategy that &#8212; for the Ind- &#8212; the entire Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s working on &#8212; in critical areas in the supply chain, not just the semiconductors, but a range of other products as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Semiconductors, which is &#8212; we&#8217;ve already discussed a little bit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Infrastructure and making sure we make available the capacity to provide modern infrastructure to many of the countries in the region who may not have the capacity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Three, the &#8212; a digital economy, dealing with cybersecurity standards and sharing major standards of data access, based on the boundaries within trust.&nbsp; And that we &#8212; that needs to be done, in our view.</p>



<p>As well as a clean and renewable environment, clean energy technologies, a global minimum tax; the tax side of the equation, just like we &#8212; we recently negotiated; and deal with establishing foreign product- &#8212; practices act &#8212; effect internationally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All that is quite broad, and it is separate from and also semi-inclusive of what the TPP was about.&nbsp; So, this is the objective that I have in mind &#8212; we have in mind at the front end here.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; A journalist from the U.S. posed me a question regarding extended deterrence.&nbsp; Let me address that question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every day, we&#8217;re seeing North Korea advancing its nuclear and missile capabilities.&nbsp; And President Biden and I shared grave concerns.&nbsp; And more than anything else, we believe that this is something that merits our utmost attention.</p>



<p>President Biden also reiterated and reemphasized his commitment &#8212; the U.S. commitment to effective extended deterrence.&nbsp; And at the same time, key to our combined defense capability is the combined military exercises.&nbsp; And we are going to step up our exercises, and we will be coordinating between ourselves regarding the deployment of U.S. strategic military assets.&nbsp; We will take some time in coordinating between ourselves.</p>



<p>And regarding the cyber threats or the threats emanating from North Korea&#8217;s asymmetrical capabilities, we will continue to consult with one another as to how to counter those threats.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And at the same time, we will reactivate the EDSCG and we will continue to advance and step up our high-level consultative mechanisms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I hope that I answered your question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re taking questions from Korean journalists and American journalists.&nbsp; But &#8212; so, we&#8217;ll go back to the Korean journalists.&nbsp; So please keep your question to just one item.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am Cho Young-min from Channel A.&nbsp; Thank you very much for giving me this opportunity to pose a question.&nbsp; We &#8212; this is an extension of the previous question.</p>



<p>We talked about how to respond to the evolving nuclear threat of North Korea, that you said that you&#8217;re going to present an action plan to strengthen the effect of extended deterrence.&nbsp; So, regarding that action plan, I wonder what kind of specific discussions you had today.&nbsp; Did you see eye-to-eye on this action plan?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; In the past, when it came to extended deterrence, we just talked about a nuclear umbrella.&nbsp; That was what I thought about extended deterrence in the past.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But beyond that, there could be many other aspects, including fighters, bombers, and missiles.&nbsp; So, regarding the timely deployment of such strategic assets, we did engage in the discussions today.</p>



<p>And going forward, I believe that there will be more concrete discussions between our two sides.&nbsp; That was our agreement, and it will be between our NSCs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, as I already stated in the course of answering the question from the U.S. journalist: In order to prepare against a possible nuclear attack, our two countries combined military exercises, I believe, should be stepped up in many aspects.&nbsp; We had that discussion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; We are going back to the American journalist posing questions to the American President.&nbsp; This is going to be the last question, so please keep your question to just one item.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Seung Min, with the Washington Post.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; You are here in the region to promote the United States economic cooperation with South Korea and Japan.&nbsp; But the two countries have been locked in a trade dispute, on top of their bilateral relationship deteriorating for a number of reasons over in recent years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what kind of a role would the United States play here in resolving those and other disputes so that your administration can further your goal of &#8212; of bolstering your economic alliance with the region?</p>



<p>And then I have a question for President Yoon.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You only get one.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One per leader.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m protecting him.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>The answer is that we discussed that in generic terms.&nbsp; The fact is that I&#8217;ll be going from here to Tokyo and discussing this as well.</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s critically important that we have a very close trilateral relationship, including economically as well as &#8212; as militarily.&nbsp; And I think you&#8217;ll see that there are ways to deal with some of the trade barriers that were placed &#8212; some of which, by the way, were placed by my predecessor, which we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re looking at very closely right now.&nbsp; So, I think there&#8217;s a lot of room to move.</p>



<p>In addition to that, if &#8212; you know, I think you covered the fact that I spend a lot of time with the ASEAN nations, as well as the Quartet.&nbsp; There&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s a whole range of &#8212; things have changed.&nbsp; There is a sense among the democracies in the Pacific that there&#8217;s a need to cooperate much more closely &#8212; not just militarily, but in terms of economically and politically.</p>



<p>And so, we talked in &#8212; at some length about the need for us to make this larger than just the United States, Japan, and &#8212; and Korea but to the entire Pacific and the South Pacific and the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think this is an opportunity.&nbsp; You know, you&#8217;ve heard me say it a hundred times &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry to the American press to repeat it &#8212; but I really do think we&#8217;re at an inflection point in world history.&nbsp; Things are changing so rapidly.&nbsp; I think you&#8217;re seeing that &#8212; what you&#8217;re going to see more of is this is going to be competition between democracies and autocracies.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; And, unfortunately, I think I&#8217;m being proven to be correct &#8212; not just here, but around the world.</p>



<p>And again, we talked at length about &#8212; this is a &#8212; not only just regional, but it&#8217;s also a global alliance, in effect, of how we&#8217;re going to respond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I don&#8217;t mean a formal written alliance.&nbsp; But, for example, if you notice, Korea and Japan have both stepped up in support of Ukraine.&nbsp; You find that in &#8212; the Quad is supporting Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there&#8217;s a whole range of things that affect whether or not democracies can be sustained in the midst of this incredible change that is taking place.&nbsp; We both agreed that it could and should be and that, together, we can play a major part in having that done.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Your Cabinet nominees are overwhelmingly male.&nbsp; South Korea consistently ranks low among developed countries on professional advancement of women.&nbsp; And you, yourself, during your presidential campaign, proposed abolishing the Ministry of Gender Equality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What role should a leading world economy like South Korea play in improving the representation and advancement of women?&nbsp; And what will you and your administration do to improve the state of gender equality in this country?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; If you look at the public officials sector, especially the ministers in the Cabinet, we really didn&#8217;t see a lot of women advancing to that position thus far.&nbsp; Probably in various regions, equal opportunities were not fully ensured for women.&nbsp; We have actually a quite short history of ensuring that.&nbsp; So, what we&#8217;re trying to do is to very actively ensure such opportunities for women.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; This concludes the joint press conference.&nbsp; The presidents of the two countries will leave the room first.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; This concludes the joint press conference in the interest of time, and they have other schedules to attend to later on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we would like to thank the journalists once again for their time here and also for constructive questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>4:51 P.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on Deputy National Security Advisor Anne Neuberger’s Travel&#160;to Brussels </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/21/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-deputy-national-security-advisor-anne-neubergers-travel-to-brussels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 22:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Deputy National Security Advisory for Cyber and Emerging Technologies Anne Neuberger traveled to&#160;Brussels, Belgium&#160;on May 18&#160;to&#160;participate in&#160;a special&#160;cyber&#160;session of&#160;the&#160;NATO North Atlantic Council,&#160;which included&#160;National Cyber Coordinators&#160;alongside&#160;NATO&#160;National&#160;Permanent Representatives&#160;for the first time. &#160;During the special cyber session, she&#160;highlighted&#160;the need&#160;for&#160;Allies to&#160;enhance their&#160;work together to&#160;deter, detect, and respond to&#160;cyber threats, recognizing they&#160;will remain a fundamental aspect of 21stcentury geopolitics and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Deputy National Security Advisory for Cyber and Emerging Technologies Anne Neuberger traveled to&nbsp;Brussels, Belgium&nbsp;on May 18&nbsp;to&nbsp;participate in&nbsp;a special&nbsp;cyber&nbsp;session of&nbsp;the&nbsp;NATO North Atlantic Council,&nbsp;which included&nbsp;National Cyber Coordinators&nbsp;alongside&nbsp;NATO&nbsp;National&nbsp;Permanent Representatives&nbsp;for the first time. &nbsp;During the special cyber session, she&nbsp;highlighted&nbsp;the need&nbsp;for&nbsp;Allies to&nbsp;enhance their&nbsp;work together to&nbsp;deter, detect, and respond to&nbsp;cyber threats, recognizing they&nbsp;will remain a fundamental aspect of 21<sup>st</sup>century geopolitics and conflict. &nbsp;Neuberger&nbsp;specifically&nbsp;called for tighter coordination to respond to&nbsp;disruptive and destructivecyber activity against&nbsp;allies.&nbsp;She also&nbsp;underscored the importance of&nbsp;modernizing&nbsp;both NATO and&nbsp;national&nbsp;cyber defenses&nbsp;to&nbsp;further strengthen&nbsp;the alliance’s&nbsp;collective&nbsp;cybersecurity resilience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, Neuberger participated in bilateral meetings with senior European Union officials, emphasizing U.S. commitment to trans-Atlantic cooperation to secure the technologies and infrastructure of the future. Neuberger’s visit underscores the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to NATO, partnership with the EU, and international cooperation on cybersecurity and secure digital innovation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Reproductive Justice&#160;Leaders </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/21/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-reproductive-justice-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 15:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, Jennifer Klein, Director of the White House Gender Policy Council, and Rohini Kosoglu, Domestic Policy Advisor to the Vice President, hosted a meeting with reproductive justice leaders from across the country.&#160;Reproductive justice leaders shared their concerns about access to reproductive health care on the ground, describing the range of challenges that patients currently face&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, Jennifer Klein, Director of the White House Gender Policy Council, and Rohini Kosoglu, Domestic Policy Advisor to the Vice President, hosted a meeting with reproductive justice leaders from across the country.&nbsp;<br>Reproductive justice leaders shared their concerns about access to reproductive health care on the ground, describing the range of challenges that patients currently face as states pass extreme laws restricting access to critical health care. Participants also highlighted the disproportionate impact that abortion restrictions have on underserved communities, including communities of color and low-income women.<br><br>On Thursday, the Vice President&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/VP/status/1527351664432525317?s=20&amp;t=-WpEoNePRl1rtAw-uqMjQw">met</a>&nbsp;with doctors and nurses to discuss the impact that overturning&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade&nbsp;</em>would have on women’s health care. Later the day, White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre issued a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-oklahoma-abortion-bill/">statement</a>&nbsp;on the Oklahoma legislature’s latest bill, which is one of the most extreme efforts yet to undo fundamental reproductive rights.<br><br>Reproductive justice meeting participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Marcela Howell, In Our Own Voice: National Black Women’s Reproductive Justice Agenda</li><li>Guadalupe Rodriguez, National Latina Institute for Reproductive Justice</li><li>Sung Yeon Choimorrow, National Asian Pacific Women’s Forum (NAPAWF)</li><li>Marsha Jones, The Afiya Center </li><li>Neha Gill, Apna Ghar, Inc. </li><li>Sevonna Brown, Black Women’s Blueprint</li><li>Tammy Boyd, Black Women’s Health Imperative</li><li>Laura Jimenez, California Latinas for Reproductive Justice</li><li>Dr. Nusrat Ameen, Daya Inc.</li><li>Nadiah Mohajir, HEART</li><li>Camille Kidd, In Our Own Voice: National Black Women’s Reproductive Justice Agenda</li><li>Yvonne Hsu, National Asian Pacific Women’s Forum (NAPAWF)</li><li>Megan Simmons, National Birth Equity Collaborative</li><li>Candace Gibson, National Latina Institute for Reproductive Justice</li><li>Kelly Davis, New Voices for Reproductive Justice</li><li>Dazon Dixon Diallo, SisterLove</li><li>Dr. Krystal Redman, SPARK Reproductive Justice Now!, Inc.</li><li>Corrine Sanchez, Tewa Women United</li><li>Kimberly Inez McGuire, URGE: Unite for Reproductive &amp; Gender Equity</li><li>Deon Haywood, Women with a Vision</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
