<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 19:27:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Generation Equality Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/30/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-generation-equality-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 19:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via TeleconferenceSouth Court Auditorium 10:27 A.M. EDT VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Greetings from the White House.  President Macron, President López Obrador, Mis- &#8212; (applause) &#8212;  PRESIDENT MACRON:  Big applause to welcome you.  VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  (Laughs.)  Merci beaucoup.  It is &#8212; it is wonderful to be with you.   President Macron, Mr. Secretary-General, Madam Executive Director,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>10:27 A.M. EDT<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Greetings from the White House.  President Macron, President López Obrador, Mis- &#8212; (applause) &#8212; <br><br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Big applause to welcome you. <br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  (Laughs.)  Merci beaucoup.  It is &#8212; it is wonderful to be with you.  <br><br>President Macron, Mr. Secretary-General, Madam Executive Director, Shantel, and the Youth Task Force: Thank you for convening this forum.<br><br>Twenty-six years ago, government and civil society leaders from around the world came together in a forum not unlike this one.  In Beijing, in 1995, Hillary Rodham Clinton issued a clarion call to the world, and the United States became one of 189 nations to adopt the ambitious &#8220;Platform for Action.&#8221;  These are points of profound pride for our nation.  <br><br>And for me, it is an honor to be here with you now, as we recommit to make gender equality a reality.<br><br>Over the past five months, I have met many world leaders, and we have discussed some of the most pressing issues of our time: COVID-19, climate change, threats to security, and threats to democracy.  <br><br>And in these meetings, I have often made it a point to raise the importance of equal participation of women and girls, because I believe, as you all do, that addressing gender equity and equality is essential to addressing every other challenge we face, which is certainly true in light of the current threats to democracy.  <br><br>Around the world, democracy is in peril.  Strong men have become stronger.  Human rights abuses have multiplied.  Corruption is undermining progress as misinformation is undermining public confidence.  <br><br>And who gets hurt when democracies fall, when democracies falter?  Who gets hurt when democracies fail to live up to their promise?  Well, women and girls are among those who suffer.<br><br>At the G7 Summit, just weeks ago, world leaders pledged to unite against the threat of autocracy.  World leaders pledged to unite behind the principles of democracy.  And as we move forward, I believe that if we want to strengthen democracy, we must fight for gender equality.  <br><br>Because here&#8217;s the truth: Democracy is strongest when everyone participates, and it is weaker when people are left out.  And we&#8217;ve seen this here in the United States.  <br><br>When women have access to capital to start a small business, they can participate more fully and our democracy grows stronger.  <br><br>When women have access to reproductive healthcare to stay healthy, they can participate more fully and our democracy grows stronger.  <br><br>When women live free from the fear of violence, they can participate more fully and our democracy grows stronger. <br><br>Throughout my career, I have worked to protect women from violence and exploitation.  I know what happens when women are supported.  I know what happens when women are heard.  When women are heard, whether that is in the courtroom, in the workplace, in the halls of government, or at the ballot box, democracy is more complete.  <br><br>So I know, without doubt, gender equality strengthens democracy.  And, for our part, the United States will make a number of commitments today to reinforce our own institutions.  And these commitments have one thing in common: They will yield results &#8212; real, tangible results &#8212; that improve the lives of women in the United States and women around the world.  <br><br>So, in closing, I will address the young leaders who are participating in Generation Equality: I remain hopeful and optimistic because of you.  Our world needs your leadership.  And in that role, there are two things I want you to remember.  <br><br>First, remember to use the tools of democracy, whether that is the freedom of speech or the freedom to vote.  And if you do not yet have those freedoms, fight for them and know we will fight alongside you.  <br><br>And the second thing I want you to remember is this: Listen to those people who are not being heard.  Respect and embrace those whose experiences are different from your own, and recognize who is not in the room and invite them in.  And do not forget the power of your own story.  <br><br>When we bring people in &#8212; when we bring in all the people &#8212; we are more successful, our results are more impactful because democracy is strongest, because our world is stronger when everyone participates.  <br><br>Thank you.  Thank you all very much.  <br><br> 10:33 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the 50th Anniversary of the 26th Amendment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/30/a-proclamation-on-the-50th-anniversary-of-the-26th-amendment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 16:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Constitution recognizes that, as a Nation, we are constantly learning. &#160;Our Founders built that recognition into&#160;its original design, providing a mechanism to amend our Constitution as our Nation evolved.&#160; On July 1, 1971, our Nation ratified the 26th Amendment to the Constitution, lowering the voting age to 18.&#160; At the time, 18-, 19-, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Our Constitution recognizes that, as a Nation, we are constantly learning. &nbsp;Our Founders built that recognition into&nbsp;its original design, providing a mechanism to amend our Constitution as our Nation evolved.&nbsp; On July 1, 1971, our Nation ratified the 26th Amendment to the Constitution, lowering the voting age to 18.&nbsp; At the time, 18-, 19-, and 20-year-old Americans were fulfilling their civic duties: &nbsp;paying taxes, serving in our Armed Forces, acting as first responders, laboring in fields, factories, and service jobs across the country, and pursuing higher education. &nbsp;They were participating in our democracy and all of the responsibilities of citizenship in all ways except for one: &nbsp;they could not vote. &nbsp;A broad coalition, following in the footsteps of the suffragettes of the early 20th century and the civil rights activists of the 1960s, advocated, educated, and prevailed in persuading our Nation that those younger Americans were entitled to the right to vote.&nbsp; We&nbsp;also made a national commitment that the right to vote would never be denied or abridged for any adult voter based on their age.</p>



<p>My first race for the Senate was one of the first elections in which 18-year-olds could vote, and the energy and passion of Delaware&#8217;s young people helped propel me to an unlikely victory.</p>



<p>Fifty years later, younger voters remain essential to our civic infrastructure.&nbsp; They are not only voting in our elections &#8212; including at record rates in 2020 &#8212; but winning them.&nbsp; Younger Americans are lending their talent and vision to school boards, city councils, and county commissions; teenagers are serving as State legislators and mayors, and we are the better for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Younger voters are not waiting to inherit the future; they are building the future themselves.&nbsp; Young Americans have been on the front lines in the fight to defend the right to vote and&nbsp;expand access to the ballot box for all eligible voters.&nbsp; Their civic engagement extends beyond voting &#8212; with young Americans leading the calls for racial justice, climate action, gun violence prevention, and immigration reform among many other issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite the progress we have made, there remain persistent gaps in turnout between younger voters and their older counterparts. &nbsp;There is still more that we can and must do to deliver on the promise of the 26th Amendment.&nbsp; My Administration has made public service and civic education a priority, engaging younger Americans in our shared struggle for continual progress.&nbsp; I have directed Federal agencies to consider ways to make it easier to vote and to learn about voting, and to focus on the various ways that the Federal Government engages younger Americans, online and off.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s youth are more diverse than past generations &#8212; and laws aimed at suppressing voter turnout in Black and Brown communities also impact young voters. &nbsp;My Administration supports the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act to protect the fundamental right to vote and make our democracy more equitable and accessible for all Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, we honor the bipartisan expansion of voter enfranchisement.&nbsp; Let us continue our work to make the 26th Constitutional Amendment ever more meaningful in the months and years ahead.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim July 1, 2021, as the 50th Anniversary of the&nbsp;26th Amendment.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to participate in&nbsp;ceremonies and activities that honor the 26th formal modification of our national Charter, that recognize the contributions made by voters enfranchised by its terms, and that&nbsp;work toward full participation of all who are eligible to&nbsp;vote.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirtieth day of June, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-Harris Administration Acts to Address the Growing Wildfire Threat</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-acts-to-address-the-growing-wildfire-threat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22615</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The National Interagency Fire Center forecast predicts above normal fire potential for much of the West, in large part driven by severe drought conditions that are impacting nearly ninety percent of the region. &#160;Since 2015, the United States has experienced, on average, roughly 100 more large wildfires every year than the year before – and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The National Interagency Fire Center forecast predicts above normal fire potential for much of the West, in large part driven by severe drought conditions that are impacting nearly ninety percent of the region. &nbsp;Since 2015, the United States has experienced, on average, roughly 100 more large wildfires every year than the year before – and this wildfire season is already outpacing last season in terms of the number of large fires to date.&nbsp;Climate change is driving the devastating intersection of extreme heat, drought, and wildland fire danger across the United States.&nbsp; Decades of shifting development patterns, land and fire management decisions, and climate change have resulted in wildfires that move with a speed and intensity previously unseen.&nbsp; This has created conditions in which wildfires overwhelm response capabilities, resulting in billions of dollars in economic losses, damage to natural resources, devastation to communities, and the tragic loss of human life.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In preparation for this wildfire season, the Biden Administration has convened a series of meetings on wildfire preparedness and prevention efforts to determine what more can be done to prepare for and prevent wildfires.&nbsp; President Biden met last week with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell and his White House Homeland preparedness team to discuss ongoing efforts to prevent, prepare for and respond to extreme weather events and to underscore the importance of prompt delivery of support to communities in need.<br><br>Today, President Biden and Vice President Harris will meet with Governors from Western states, Cabinet officials and private sector partners to discuss specific actions the public and private sector are each taking to strengthen prevention, preparedness, mitigation, and response efforts – and to protect communities across our country from wildfires and their devastating impacts.&nbsp; During today’s meeting, the President will direct a number of actions, in close coordination with State and local governments and the private sector, to ensure the Federal Government can most effectively protect public safety and deliver assistance to our people in times of urgent need.&nbsp;<br><br>The President will also highlight the need to invest in wildfire prevention and risk mitigation efforts, including the nearly $50 billion in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><u>The Biden-Harris Administration Is Taking Action to Respond to Wildfires this Year:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Building a More Responsive and Resilient Wildland Firefighting Workforce</em></strong><br><br><strong>Bolster firefighter pay.</strong>  Firefighters must be fairly paid for the grueling work they are willing to take on.  From supporting COVID-19 efforts to fighting wildfires, our Federal wildland firefighters have been on nearly nonstop deployments since January 2020.  That is why today we are announcing that we are fulfilling the President’s commitment that firefighters will not make less than $15 an hour this year.  In addition, permanent firefighters working on the front lines paid at up to a GS-9 level will receive up to a 10 percent retention incentive and temporary workers who commit to continue this season would receive a $1000 Spot/Star Award this year.  These are short-term solutions to support our Federal wildland firefighters, especially due to the multiple impacts of COVID and climate change this year.  The Administration will work with Congress on longer-term much needed compensation, benefit, and work-life balance reforms for Federal wildland firefighters.<br><br><strong>Extend hiring of temporary firefighters to ensure effective response throughout this year’s fire season.  </strong>To mitigate concerns about Federal firefighter capacity this year, today we are announcing that the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) has approved an exemption to extend seasonal Department of Agriculture (USDA) and Department of Interior (DOI) wildland fire employees to work additional hours beyond their term.  Because of climate change, wildland firefighting is no longer a seasonal endeavor.  Fires are burning later into the season and temporary employees often reach their limited hours earlier in the year.  This week, OPM also approved an extension of the Forest Service’s (USFS) direct hire authority for wildland firefighters and support personnel.  These proactive personnel management actions will help sustain the Nation’s vital Federal wildland firefighting capacity.  We also recognize the need for a sustainable long-term staffing approach into the future that offers more permanent, stable employment.<br><br><strong>Continue transition to a more permanent firefighting workforce.  </strong>With fire seasons turning into fire years, it is imperative to have a year-round workforce that is available to respond at any time, that is supported and equitably compensated, and is available to undertake preventive actions like hazardous fuels management treatments during periods of low fire activity.  DOI has committed to hiring 210 new employees and converting 575 employees from career seasonal to full-time employees during this fiscal year.  Additionally, DOI is providing funding for 42 new tribal positions and the conversion of 153 tribal positions from career seasonal to full-time employees to support wildfire response.  USFS will continue to prioritize expanding its permanent wildland firefighting workforce.<br><br><strong><em>Improving Wildfire Response Capabilities</em></strong><br><br><strong>Provide robust response through 15,000 Federal firefighters and additional surge capacity.  </strong>Wildland firefighting is a complex, multi-agency effort, and our Federal firefighters work side-by-side with their State, Tribal, and local counterparts on a daily basis.  USFS and DOI maintain a capacity of over 15,000 Federal firefighters who are able to respond to wildfires across the nation.  USFS and DOI can also activate up to 13,000 additional employees throughout their departments to support wildfire response.  These surge employees provide additional capacity to the response, ranging from firefighting capabilities for qualified employees, to critical response support through incident management, acquisition, and human resources.  USFS and DOI have additional capacity to call 11,000 administratively determined personnel from outside their departments to support the response.  These employees are generally retired agency personnel who can be dispatched to support incident management teams and other firefighting functions.<br><br><strong>Train and equip military personnel to be ready to quickly support wildland fires as needed.  </strong>Congress made Federal funding available to train and equip the National Guard to conduct firefighting operations to support state response to wildfires.  All eleven states who requested this support have received the funding and training is underway.  The Department of Defense (DOD) has also pre-identified two military units, with 200 personnel each, to receive training and specialized equipment to support firefighting operations if required. <br><br><strong>Increase aviation capacity to support immediate response.  </strong>Aviation assets are critical in the management of wildfires to slow or decrease the intensity of the fire and enable safe operations for firefighters on the ground.  This year, the USFS has increased the overall capacity of airtankers and helicopters to ensure their availability during peak fire activity.  USFS and DOI share aviation resources, which includes up to 34 air-tankers and over 200 helicopters to boost our Nation’s wildfire response capabilities.  When needed, DOD is able to provide aviation support through National Guard and Air Force Reserve C-130 crews and helicopter transport crews and equipment to support medical evacuation or water drops for fire response.     <br><br><strong>Provide critical financial support to assist in wildfire response.  </strong>This Administration is ready to assist communities at the start of severe fires with critical Fire Management Assistance Grants (FMAGs).  Issued through the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), FMAGs assist states, local, and tribal governments with the mitigation, management, and control of fires which threaten such destruction as would constitute a major disaster.  FEMA has approved 9 FMAGs since the start of 2021. <br><br><strong><em>Utilizing Data and Technology to Protect Communities</em></strong><br><br><strong>Leverage satellite and emerging technologies to rapidly detect new, often remote, wildland fires.  </strong>The Federal government has a number of new, innovative ways to detect and notify emergency personnel when wildfires start.  The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) uses satellite-based early wildfire detection to provide initial location information to first responders, allowing them to attack fires more quickly.  NOAA is partnering with other Federal Departments and Agencies and state governments to expand the use of this technology and its associated notification system.  The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/budget_fy22.pdf">FY 2022 President’s Budget</a> includes $15 million to support fire weather activities, including a new NOAA Fire Weather Testbed to provide improved operations, service delivery, and decision making based on the latest science and research.  This virtual and onsite infrastructure will bring together fire weather community researchers, operational experts, and emergency managers across Federal, state, local, territorial, and tribal governments, academia, and the private sector to develop new, impact-based decision support tools, products, and models to address wildfires. The President’s Budget also proposes a new wildfire applications program within NASA to develop innovative tools and applications using satellite data and the latest science to assist with wildland fire management. Working with the wildland fire management agencies, this program will support community-based consortiums to co-develop and pilot applications in all phases of wildfires.<br><br><strong>Use research to improve early detection wildfire sensors.</strong>  The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) is also focusing its research agenda on innovations that will improve the Nation’s ability to predict, detect, and control wildfires.  Just two weeks ago, DHS Science and Technology <a>announced</a> successful Phase II trials of four prototype early detection wildfire sensors.  Through a variety of sampling sensors and advanced algorithms, these technologies, once deployed, will provide early warning to fire-vulnerable communities, ultimately providing valuable time that will aid responders and save lives. <br><br><strong>Use the latest science and technologies to enhance our wildfire response.  </strong>The Federal government manages all fires using a risk-based suppression strategy.  As we head into the peak of a long, arduous season, it is more important than ever we deploy firefighters when they have the highest probability of success.  USFS and DOI are using the latest science and technologies to enhance our operational capability and decision making so when firefighting resources are used, they are able to work safely and effectively and protect critical infrastructure and natural resources. USFS researchers have specifically created a mapping unit called “Firesheds” that aggregates areas that have similar fire behavior and community risk characteristics, allowing USFS to more effectively prioritize hazardous fuel treatments.  The Department of Energy (DOE), through the National Labs, have a variety of programs underway to develop sensors and patches to help prevent structural energy infrastructure failures that have the potential to ignite wildfires. <br><br><strong>Prepare to address potential power impacts as a result of wildfires.  </strong>Approximately 10 percent of wildfire ignitions are sparked by faults on electrical grid infrastructure or electric equipment failures.  There is also a growing risk of intentional power shutoffs in anticipation of or due to wildfires.  In order to minimize rolling blackouts during extreme heat and wildfire risk, DOE is prepared to authorize utilities to run power plants at their maximum capacity to best meet emergency needs.  DOE also uses its Environment for Analysis of Geo-Located Energy Information (EAGLE-I) tool to give first responders and State Emergency Management Officials information on the status of the power grid, which is critical in facilitating response and recovery efforts.  Finally, DOE will leverage the analytical capabilities of the National Laboratories to provide tools for damage assessments, predictive analysis, and grid management to support response efforts.  This tool is available to Federal, state, local, tribal governments and first responders and will include wildfire data in its analysis in 2022.<br><br><strong>Use research and modeling to protect firefighters and residents from smoke and dangerous air.  </strong>Wildfires can lead to smoke and water quality concerns that may impact public health, and the Administration is undertaking a number of efforts to mitigate these concerns.  NOAA uses satellite data and models to forecast smoke and communicate areas of dangerous air quality and low visibility.  During a wildfire, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) also monitors and models smoke, develops smoke outlooks, and supports community public health notifications and guidance.  EPA is developing and expanding availability of the Vehicle Add-on Mobile Monitoring System (VAMMS) for use in heavy smoke impacted areas to provide ground truth on smoke plume and air quality models.  EPA is also evaluating how filtration devices, such as facemasks and portable air cleaners, can reduce exposures during smoke episodes.  With funding from the American Rescue Plan, EPA is piloting a project with Western states to use schools as clean air shelters and cooling centers during heat and smoke events.<br><br><strong>Provide actionable information to help Americans stay safe during a wildfire. </strong><br>FEMA recently redesigned its Wildland Urban Interface website to highlight resources and information to assist states and local communities in preventing and preparing for wildfires.  EPA developed a wildfire smoke guide, in collaboration with a range of Federal and State partners, to provide specific information on the impacts of smoke and actions individuals can take to reduce their exposure.  EPA and the USFS launched the <a href="https://fire.airnow.gov/">AirNow Fire and Smoke Map</a>, which combines data from EPA’s air monitoring network with data from low-cost sensors, to improve air quality and smoke information available to the public during fire events.  In July, the EPA will add the Fire and Smoke Map to the AirNow mobile app, making this information more readily available to the public.<br><br><strong><em>Reducing the Risk of Wildfires throughHazardous Fuels Management and Mitigation Investments</em></strong><br><br><strong>Provide assistance to mitigate the impacts of future wildfires and protect communities</strong>. The Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) program provides a critical opportunity for governments to invest in resilience before a disaster.  In FY 2020, $500 million was made available through the BRIC program to support states, local communities, tribes, and territories for pre-disaster mitigation.  In May, the Administration doubled FEMA BRIC program resources – to $1 billion – for FY 2021.  Today, FEMA is announcing that one of the FY 2020 BRIC projects selected will provide $37 million in federal funds for an innovative wildfire mitigation project in Sonoma, CA that focuses on mitigation activities at both the large wildland-scale and the neighborhood-scale in order to build more resilient communities.  FEMA will soon announce additional FY 2020 BRIC projects selected for Federal funding. FEMA also provides assistance to mitigate future wildfires under the Hazard Mitigation Grant Program (HMGP) Post-Fire for communities.  FEMA Regional offices are coordinating with state and tribal partners to highlight the opportunities made available through these grant programs.<br><br><strong>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests nearly $50 billion to build resilience to wildfires and helps western communities prepare for droughts. </strong> Last year, the United States faced 22 extreme weather and climate-related disaster events with loses over $1 billion – a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion.  The bipartisan infrastructure framework will help the country prepare for those events by investing in forest management and upgrades to critical infrastructure &#8212; like elevating buildings, roads, and bridges, hardening physical infrastructure, and winterizing the power grid – as well as funding state and local infrastructure improvements and emergency response strategies, such as planning grants to support development of evacuation routes or upgrading community shelters.  The Framework will also make it easier for low-income families to buy flood insurance.  And it will help Western farmers, ranchers, tribes, families, and communities better prepare for future droughts. It will invest in ecosystem restoration, such as the restoration of wetlands that can reduce flood risk for communities.<br><br><strong>Invest in extreme wildfire protection through the FY 2022 Budget.  </strong>The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/budget_fy22.pdf">FY 2022 President’s Budget</a> includes over $30 billion in FY 2022 to support wildfire management and related activities and disaster relief.  This funding is necessary in order to ensure we have the resources necessary to better prepare and respond to wildfires and protect communities.<br><br><strong>More effective treatment of hazardous fuels.  </strong>This Administration understands the need to address forest management in the prevention of wildfires.  The President’s FY 2022 Budget has proposed a 62% increase in hazardous fuels funding across USFS and DOI.  This funding is used to reduce wildfire hazards by addressing the excessive accumulation of biomass (i.e., “hazardous fuels”) in targeted locations.  Investments in FY 2022 will be informed by a scientific, outcome-based national investment model that targets land treatments to areas where they can be most effective in protecting communities.  The USFS and DOI have identified more than 4 million acres that could be treated this year with the funding requested in the FY 2022 Budget.  The Administration looks forward to working with Congress to fully fund this critical program.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: United States to Announce Commitments to the Generation Equality Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-united-states-to-announce-commitments-to-the-generation-equality-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the United States joined global partners – including governments, civil society, and the private sector – in making commitments to the Generation Equality Forum, reasserting U.S. leadership on gender equity and equality on the world stage. The Generation Equality Forum (GEF), convened by UN Women and co-hosted by the governments of France and Mexico,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Today, the United States joined global partners – including governments, civil society, and the private sector – in making commitments to the Generation Equality Forum, reasserting U.S. leadership on gender equity and equality on the world stage.</em></p>



<p>The Generation Equality Forum (GEF), convened by UN Women and co-hosted by the governments of France and Mexico, marks the anniversary of the United Nation’s Fourth World Conference on Women held in Beijing over 25 years ago, where the world recognized that “women’s rights are human rights” and adopted an ambitious Platform for Action to achieve equality and opportunity for women around the world.&nbsp; While tremendous progress has been made since the Beijing Conference, serious gaps remain, which have been exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic. The Generation Equality Forum offers an opportunity to make bold, measurable commitments to build back better and accelerate progress towards the Beijing Platform and the Sustainable Development Goals.</p>



<p>The U.S. commitments reflect the Biden-Harris Administration’s domestic and global priorities, including policy and resource commitments to:</p>



<ul><li>Prevent and respond to all forms of gender-based violence;</li><li>Strengthen women’s economic security; and</li><li>Protect and advance sexual and reproductive health and rights.</li></ul>



<p>Our participation in the Generation Equality Forum is an important part of broader U.S. efforts to advance gender equity and equality, including in areas beyond the scope of commitments announced today, such as climate, science and technology, leadership and democracy, and education. This includes efforts underway to support the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-g7-leaders-launch-build-back-better-world-b3w-partnership/">Build Back Better World</a>&nbsp;Partnership to meet the tremendous infrastructure needs of low- and middle-income countries, particularly across the areas of gender equity and equality, climate, health and health security, and information and communications technology. Finally, as part of Generation Equality, we have also signed on to the Compact on Women, Peace, and Security and Humanitarian Action and will continue our robust implementation of the U.S. Women, Peace, and Security Act, which strengthens our efforts to prevent, mitigate, and resolve conflict by improving the participation of women in peace and security processes.<br><br>Our Generation Equality Forum commitments include:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence</strong></span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><br></span>Preventing and responding to gender-based violence is a significant pillar of the Biden-Harris Administration’s work on gender equity and equality. The “shadow pandemic” of alarming increases in rates of gender-based violence in the U.S. and globally underscore the urgency of our collective efforts.</p>



<p><strong><em>Domestic efforts to combat gender-based violence</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Create the first U.S. National Action Plan on Gender-Based Violence, led by the White House Gender Policy Council, to be launched in 2022.&nbsp; This plan will establish a whole-of-government approach to preventing and addressing gender-based violence (GBV) domestically and globally, with significant input from civil society.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Provide $450 million in supplementary funding through the President’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/American-Rescue-Plan-Fact-Sheet.pdf">American Rescue Plan</a>&nbsp;to prevent and respond to domestic violence and sexual assault. This includes $200 million for domestic violence services and support; $198 million for sexual assault services programs; and $49.5 million for a new program to fund culturally specific community-based organizations to improve access to services and safety for survivors in historically marginalized communities, with a primary focus on racial and ethnic minority communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Reauthorize and strengthen the Violence Against Women Act (VAWA), which passed the U. S. House of Representatives this spring with bipartisan support and is pending in the U.S. Senate.&nbsp; First passed in 1994 with then-Senator Biden as its champion, the VAWA is a landmark piece of bipartisan legislation that has transformed the nation&#8217;s response to gender-based violence, bringing critically needed resources to States, Territories, Tribes, and local communities to help prevent and improve the response to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Request, as part of the FY 2022 President’s Budget, an historic investment of $1 billion to support VAWA programs coordinated through the U.S. Department of Justice—a 95% increase over FY 2021 enacted levels.&nbsp; Also request $463.5 million to be administered through the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, including $250 million to provide cash assistance to survivors of domestic violence to support their short and long-term transition to safety and stability.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Improve prevention and response to sexual assault and harassment in the U.S. military, including by establishing an Independent Review Commission (IRC) on Military Sexual Assault, which conducted a thorough review and recently made significant recommendations on accountability, prevention, climate and culture, and victim support to the U.S. Secretary of Defense and the President.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Strengthen the U.S. National Action Plan on Trafficking in Persons to integrate the administration’s commitments to gender and racial equity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Propose “safe leave” as part of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/28/fact-sheet-the-american-families-plan/">American Families Plan</a>, a comprehensive paid family and medical leave program that would permit workers eligible to receive paid leave for reasons pertaining to sexual assault, stalking, dating or domestic violence.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>International efforts to combat gender-based violence</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Update and strengthen the 2016 U.S. Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence Globally,&nbsp;in coordination with the development of the first-ever U.S. National Action Plan to End Gender-Based Violence.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Request, as part of the FY 2022 President’s Budget, $175 million to prevent and respond to gender-based violence globally, as part of a $1.2 billion request for gender programming abroad.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Host the Fourth Trilateral Working Group on Violence Against Indigenous Women and Girls with the Governments of Mexico and Canada. The Biden-Harris Administration will relaunch this regional collaboration, which presents an opportunity to continue to improve and reaffirm our respective national and regional commitments to exchanging information about policies, programs and promising practices to prevent and respond to violence against Indigenous women and girls through increased access to justice and services, with a human rights and culturally-responsive approach.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Double the annual investment by the President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief in DREAMS–Determined, Resilient, Empowered, AIDS-Free, Mentored, Safe Partnership–which supports programs focused on economic strengthening, gender-based violence prevention, post-GBV care, and&nbsp;sexual and reproductive health services in Haiti and 14 African countries. The U.S. government will seek to continue this increased level of support during FY2022, pending Congressional notification and approval.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Announce U.S. commitments to the Call to Action on Protection from Gender-Based Violence in Emergencies 2021-2025 Road Map. The U.S. will strengthen its leadership role in addressing GBV within the humanitarian system to ensure this issue is prioritized and resourced from the outset of emergencies. Through the joint State/USAID Safe from the Start initiative, the U.S. will implement Call to Action commitments that seek to strengthen the quality of GBV programming, support improved GBV risk mitigation efforts, and improve resource tracking and accountability for GBV programming as part of humanitarian assistance.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Co-sponsor a resolution on “Ending violence against children through health systems strengthening and multisectoral approaches” during the 2021 World Health Assembly, which was passed by consensus. This resolution prioritizes WHO Member State actions on child protection, to prevent and address early, child, and forced marriage, child trafficking, exploitation and abuse of children and other actions that threaten the emotional, mental, and physical health of children.</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Advance Women’s Economic Security and Promote Economic Justice&nbsp;</span></strong></p>



<p>The Biden Administration has taken critical steps to strengthen women’s economic security through the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/American-Rescue-Plan-Fact-Sheet.pdf">American Rescue Plan</a>&nbsp;and has proposed once-in-a-generation investments as part of the American Jobs Plan and American Families Plan. The Administration is also committed to advancing women’s economic opportunity and security around the world.</p>



<p><strong><em>Domestic efforts to strengthen women’s economic security</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Provide immediate relief for women and families through the American Rescue Plan (ARP), helping hard-hit households recover from the economic impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic. The ARP expands the Child Tax Credit, allowing more families to benefit, increasing the size of the benefit, and distributing benefits monthly. And it includes a historic investment of more than $40 billion in child care and early learning. States, tribes, and territories can use these investments to help child care providers—who are disproportionately women of color—avoid potential closure and ensure that they can operate safely and increase pay and benefits for care workers, who are also disproportionately women of color. These funds can also be used to help parents better afford high-quality child care.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Propose, as part of the American Jobs Plan, a major investment in care infrastructure, including a $400 billion investment in expanding access to home- or community-based care, expanding access to long-term care services under Medicaid, and additional investments to modernize schools and child care facilities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Strengthen the workforce pipeline for all, including more women and communities of color, to access in-demand jobs through the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/31/fact-sheet-the-american-jobs-plan/">American Jobs Plan</a>, including by investing in apprenticeships and other workforce development programs like Women in Apprenticeship in Non-Traditional Occupations. This commitment includes ensuring jobs with fair and equal pay, safe and healthy workplaces, and workplaces free from racial, gender, and other forms of discrimination and harassment.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Propose, through the American Families Plan (AFP), a $1 trillion commitment to working families, helping cover basic expenses that families need and care most about: making child care and higher education more affordable, lowering the cost of health care over the long term, and continuing to reduce child poverty and put money in parents’ pockets by extending the historic expansion of the Child Tax Credit in the American Rescue Plan. This investment in working families also includes establishing a comprehensive national paid family and medical leave program.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Work with Congress to pass key legislation for women’s employment in addition to the American Jobs Plan and American Families Plan, including the Pregnant Workers Fairness Act, which passed the U.S. House of Representatives this spring with bipartisan support.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>International efforts to strengthen women’s economic security</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Mobilize at least $12 billion—an average $2.4 billion per year, from January 2021 through December 2025—as part of the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation’s new 2X commitment to invest in businesses that advance gender equity in emerging markets.&nbsp; These funds will support 15 million women and girls, including from marginalized communities and fragile and post-conflict settings.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Announce that the Development Finance Corporation will establish 2X Technical Assistance Pilot Program to help private sector clients advance gender equity in their businesses, such as by increasing the number of women in leadership or developing products or services designed specifically to meet the differentiated needs of their women clients.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Establish the Gender Equity and Equality Action (GEEA) Fund—with $100 million in FY 2021 and a request of $200 million in the FY 2022 President’s Budget—to advance economic security for women and girls globally, prevent and respond to gender-based violence, and support underserved and marginalized populations. In addition, the GEEA Fund will help address the disproportionate impact that COVID-19, climate change, and conflict and crisis have on women and girls.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Promote women’s entrepreneurship around the world, including through grants to grassroots and community-led organizations through the Inter-American Foundation and grants to gender-inclusive digital services for women-owned businesses through the U.S.-African Development Foundation.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Commit $33 million in FY 2020 funds to advance gender equity and equality in the Northern Triangle by increasing women’s economic access, agency, and power while reducing gender-based violence in the community, workplace, and household. In addition, commit $2.2 million in FY 2020 funding to small grants for 15 local organizations in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras that advance women’s economic participation through the Inter-American Foundation.</li></ul>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Protect and Expand Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights</strong></span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><br></span>The Biden Administration is committed to advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights in the U.S. and around the world. Everyone should have access to quality, affordable health care regardless of their income or where they live.</p>



<p><strong><em>Domestic efforts to protect and expand sexual and reproductive health and rights</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Remove, as part of the President’s first budget, the Hyde Amendment restriction from government spending bills, reflecting the President’s support for expanding access to health care, including reproductive health care, through Medicaid and other federally-funded programs.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Review rules for Title X of the Public Health Services Act, which provides Federal funding for family planning services that primarily benefit low-income patients, to ensure access to family planning and other preventive health care. The Department of Health and Human Services published a notice of proposed rulemaking related to the Title X program entitled &#8220;Ensuring access to equitable, affordable, client-centered, quality family planning services.&#8221; This proposed rule revises the 2019 rules by readopting the 2000 regulations, with several modifications needed to strengthen the program and ensure access to equitable, affordable, client-centered, quality family planning services for all clients, especially for low-income clients.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Direct $50 million in supplemental funding to the Title X Family Planning Program through the American Rescue Plan, in addition to a&nbsp;proposed $340 million to the Title X Program in the President’s discretionary budget request.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Expand Medicaid postpartum coverage from 60 days to 12 months, ensuring that more new mothers can retain health coverage and stay healthy.</li><li>Propose, as part of the President’s FY 2022 discretionary budget request, $200 million to reduce maternal mortality rates and end race-based disparities, and as part of the American Families Plan, a $3 billion investment to further address the maternal health crisis in the United States, which has a particularly significant impact on Black and Indigenous women, by growing and diversifying the perinatal workforce, improving data collection to better understand the causes of maternal death and complications from birth, and investing in community-based organizations.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>International efforts to protect and expand sexual and reproductive health and rights</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Issued a Presidential Memorandum on January 28, 2021 to protect and expand access to comprehensive reproductive health services and care, which rescinded the harmful Mexico City Policy, among other actions.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Propose, as part of the President’s FY 2022 budget request, resuming funding for the UN Population Fund (UNFPA), including $56 million in the FY 2022 President’s Budget, a 72% increase over the FY 2021 enacted level. Funding for UNFPA would directly support the provision of sexual and reproductive health services in fragile contexts, where access to such services is limited.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Support the World Health Organization’s (WHO) strengthening of internal operations, including efforts to prevent and address sexual exploitation and abuse within their workforce and the broader health sector, and to bolster WHO’s capacity to deliver critical services and technical guidance, including in emergency contexts.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Assess the current status of HRP (the UN Development Programme/UN Population Fund/UN Children’s Fund/WHO/World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction) and how U.S. expertise can align to support its work. The HRP is the primary instrument within the United Nations system for research in human reproduction, and U.S. engagement will help advance critical research, including building research capacity of lower income countries.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Commit publicly with like-minded countries to a series of progressive meetings on continuing and expanding essential sexual and reproductive health service delivery on the margins of WHA and WHO regional committees, the UN General Assembly, World Economic Forum, and World Bank fall meetings, among others.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Commit to supporting women in the global health workforce and affirm U.S. support of the Gender Equal Healthcare Workforce Initiative and its pillars, which aims to minimize and address inequities and inequalities female health workers face globally. This includes harassment and violence, pay inequities, and lack of opportunities for professional training and advancement.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Names Fifth Round of Judicial Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/president-biden-names-fifth-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing eight new candidates for the federal bench and one new candidate&#160;for District of Columbia courts, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing eight new candidates for the federal bench and one new candidate&nbsp;for District of Columbia courts, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.<br><br>For example, this slate includes:</p>



<ul><li>A woman who would be the first federal judge of South Asian descent in Michigan</li><li>A labor lawyer and former union organizer who would also be the first AAPI judge from Oregon on the Ninth Circuit</li><li>An Assistant U.S. Attorney who would be the second woman of color to ever serve on the federal bench in Virginia</li><li>A former prosecutor with the Department of Justice’s Public Integrity Section who would be the first Hispanic judge on the Court of Federal Claims</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-left">This is President Biden’s fifth round of names for federal judicial positions, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 32.<br><br>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move at an unparalleled speed with respect to judicial nominations. His first judicial nominations announcement was made faster than that of any new President in modern American history, and today’s announcement continues that trend.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>CIRCUIT COURTS</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>TOBY J. HEYTENS</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Toby Heytens has served as the Solicitor General for the Commonwealth of Virginia since his appointment in 2018. Mr. Heytens previously served as a Professor of Law at the University of Virginia School of Law from 2014 to 2018 and as an Associate Professor of Law from 2010 to 2014 and from 2006 to 2007. During his tenure at the University of Virginia School of Law, he also frequently served as a co-director of its Supreme Court Litigation Clinic. From 2007 to 2010, Mr. Heytens served as an Assistant to the Solicitor General at the U.S. Department of Justice. From 2003 to 2006, Mr. Heytens worked in the Supreme Court and Appellate Practice Group at O’Melveny &amp; Myers LLP in Washington, D.C. Mr. Heytens served as a Bristow Fellow in the Office of the Solicitor General at the U.S. Department of Justice from 2001 to 2002. Mr. Heytens served as a law clerk for Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg on the U.S. Supreme Court from 2002 to 2003 and for Judge Edward R. Becker on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit from 2000 to 2001.<br><br>Mr. Heytens received his B.A. from Macalester College in 1997 and his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 2000.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>JENNIFER SUNG</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Jennifer Sung has been a member of the Oregon Employment Relations Board since her appointment in 2017. Previously, she was a partner at McKanna Bishop Joffe LLP in Portland, where she worked from 2013 to 2017. From 2007 to 2013, Ms. Sung worked at Altshuler Berzon LLP in San Francisco. While in private practice, she was a litigator specializing in labor, employment, and constitutional law, and she represented labor organizations and employees in arbitrations, administrative proceedings, and civil litigation in state and federal courts. From 2005 to 2007, Ms. Sung was a Skadden Fellow at the Brennan Center for Justice at New York University School of Law. Ms. Sung served as a law clerk for Judge Betty Binns Fletcher on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2004 to 2005. Before law school, she was an organizer with the Service Employees International Union Local 1199 from 1998 to 2001 and with the Service Employees International Union Local 74 from 1996 to 1998.<br><br>Ms. Sung received her J.D. from Yale Law School in 2004 and her B.A. from Oberlin College in 1994.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">DISTRICT COURTS</span></strong><br><br><strong>JANE M. BECKERING<br><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the Western District of Michigan</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Judge Jane M. Beckering has served on the Michigan Court of Appeals since 2007, where she oversees both civil and criminal proceedings. Judge Beckering is the Chief Judge Pro Tempore of the Court. She is also President-Elect of the Grand Rapids Bar Association and previously served on the Michigan Supreme Court Committee on Model Civil Jury Instructions. Prior to becoming a judge, Judge Beckering was a trial lawyer in private practice for 17 years. She founded the law firm of Buchanan &amp; Beckering, PLC in Grand Rapids, Michigan, primarily focused on representing plaintiffs in civil litigation. She began her law career as an associate with McDermott, Will &amp; Emery, P.C. in Chicago. Judge Beckering received her J.D. from the University of Wisconsin in 1990 and her B.A. from the University of Michigan in 1987.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>PATRICIA TOLLIVER GILES</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Patricia Tolliver Giles has served in the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Virginia since 2003, and currently serves as Managing Assistant U.S. Attorney. She previously served as an Assistant U.S. Attorney in the Major Crimes Unit from 2003 to 2019. She also serves on the Attorney General’s Transnational Organized Crime Task Force, MS-13 Subcommittee. From 2000 to 2003, Ms. Giles was an associate at Cooley Godward LLP. Her work included a wide variety of commercial cases in the areas of contracts, intellectual property, securities, and employment law. Ms. Giles served as a law clerk for Judge Gerald Bruce Lee on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 1998 to 2000. Ms. Giles received her J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1998 and her B.A. from University of Virginia in 1995.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SHALINA D. KUMAR</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Chief Judge Shalina D. Kumar has served on the Oakland County Sixth Circuit Court since 2007. She was appointed Chief Judge of the Circuit Court by the Michigan Supreme Court in January of 2018. In addition to her chief judge duties, Judge Kumar retains a full caseload covering both civil and criminal matters. Throughout her years on the bench, Judge Kumar has served as a presiding judge of the Adult Treatment Court, the Chairperson of the Oakland County Criminal Assignment Committee, the bench liaison to the Oakland County Bar Association Circuit Court Committee, a member of the Michigan State Bar Professionalism Committee, and a member of the Executive Committee of the Michigan Judges’ Association. Prior to taking the bench, Judge Kumar was a civil litigator in private practice from 1997 to 2007, including as an associate with Weiner &amp; Cox P.L.C. from 2004 to 2007 and Sommers, Schwartz, Silver &amp; Schwartz P.C. from 2000 to 2004. Judge Kumar graduated from the University of Michigan in 1993 and the University of Detroit-Mercy School of Law in 1996.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong>MICHAEL S. NACHMANOFF</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Judge Michael S. Nachmanoff has served as a U.S. Magistrate Judge for the Eastern District of Virginia since 2015. Before his appointment to the bench, Judge Nachmanoff served for 13 years in the Office of the Federal Public Defender for the Eastern District of Virginia, serving as Chief Federal Public Defender from 2007 to 2015, Acting Federal Public Defender from 2005 to 2007, and First Assistant Public Defender from 2002 to 2005. Prior to serving as a federal defender, Judge Nachmanoff was a partner at Cohen, Gettings &amp; Dunham, P.C. He joined the firm as an associate in 1996 and was a partner from 2000 to 2002. At the firm, Judge Nachmanoff’s practice consisted of complex civil litigation, white collar federal criminal defense, and state court criminal cases. Judge Nachmanoff served as a law clerk for Judge Leonie Brinkema on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 1995 to 1996. Judge Nachmanoff received his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1995 and his B.A. from Wesleyan University in 1991. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>COURT OF FEDERAL CLAIMS</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>ARMANDO O. BONILLA<br><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Federal Claims</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Armando O. Bonilla has been the Vice President of Ethics and Investigations at Capital One since 2018. Bonilla previously served at the U.S. Department of Justice in a variety of roles from 1994 to 2018. He served as Associate General Counsel for the U.S. Marshals Service from 2017 to 2018; as Associate Deputy Attorney General from 2010 to 2017; as a prosecutor in the Public Integrity Section of the Criminal Division from 2002 to 2010 and in the Asset Forfeiture and Money Laundering Section of the Criminal Division from 2001 to 2002; and as a trial and appellate attorney in the Civil Division’s Commercial Litigation Branch from 1994 to 2001. Mr. Bonilla served as a law clerk for Judge Garrett E. Brown, Jr. on the U.S. District Court for the District of New Jersey from 1992 to 1994.<br><br>Mr. Bonilla received his J.D., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from Seton Hall University School of Law in 1992 and his B.A. from West Virginia University in 1989.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>CAROLYN N. LERNER</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Federal Claims</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Carolyn N. Lerner is currently the Chief Circuit Mediator for the U.S. Courts of the D.C. Circuit, a position she has held since 2017. She was previously unanimously confirmed to head the U.S. Office of Special Counsel, where she served from 2011 to 2017. Ms. Lerner is an adjunct law professor at Georgetown University Law Center, and was previously an adjunct law professor at George Washington University Law School. Ms. Lerner was a founding partner of the civil rights and employment law firm Heller, Huron, Chertkof, Lerner, Simon &amp; Salzman, where she practiced from 1997 to 2011. While at her law firm, from 2003 to 2005, Ms. Lerner served as the federal court-appointed Special Inspector for the Office of Special Inspector at the D.C. Department of Corrections. From 1991 to 1996, Ms. Lerner was a litigation attorney at Kator, Scott, Heller &amp; Huron, a civil rights and employment law firm. She began her legal career as a law clerk for Chief Judge Julian Abele Cook, Jr. on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan.<br><br>Ms. Lerner received her J.D. from New York University Law School in 1989, where she was a Root-Tilden Scholar, and her B.G.S, with distinction, from the Honors College at the University of Michigan in 1986.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>LOCAL D.C. COURTS</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SEAN C. STAPLES<br><em>Nominated to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Judge Sean C. Staples is a Magistrate Judge assigned to the Criminal and Domestic Violence Divisions on the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. Before his appointment to the bench, Judge Staples was an attorney with the Children’s Law Center from 2006 to 2013, last serving as the Guardian ad Litem Project Director. From 2000 to 2006, Judge Staples was a clinical professor in the Criminal Division of the D.C. Law Students in Court Program, supervising law students in the representation of adults and juveniles in D.C. Superior Court. Judge Staples served as a law clerk for Judge Robert E. Morin of the D.C. Superior Court from 1998 to 1999. Judge Staples received his J.D. from the Catholic University of America Columbus School of Law in 1996 and his B.S. from Syracuse University in 1991.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Finalizing Preparations for Libyan Elections</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/29/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-finalizing-preparations-for-libyan-elections/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 23:54:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I commend the work of the Libyan Political Dialogue Forum (LPDF) as its members meet in Geneva this week to finalize preparations for Libya to hold historic national elections on December 24, 2021.&#160;As the Berlin II conference affirmed, the United States stands together with our Libyan and international partners in full support for holding presidential&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I commend the work of the Libyan Political Dialogue Forum (LPDF) as its members meet in Geneva this week to finalize preparations for Libya to hold historic national elections on December 24, 2021.&nbsp;As the Berlin II conference affirmed, the United States stands together with our Libyan and international partners in full support for holding presidential and parliamentary elections on time that will enable Libyans to choose their own leaders and re-establish their sovereignty after years of civil conflict and economic upheaval. This builds on recent progress with the establishment of the interim Government of National Unity.</p>



<p>We are encouraged by the positive atmosphere and spirit of compromise in which the LPDF is meeting, with active United Nations facilitation, to adopt the constitutional and legislative arrangements needed for elections. We support the Libyan people as they chart a path toward a more stable, prosperous, and secure future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework Will Address Barriers Communities of Color Face to Economic Opportunity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/29/fact-sheet-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework-will-address-barriers-communities-of-color-face-to-economic-opportunity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework addresses economic disparities in our economy and the consequences of decades of disinvestment in America’s infrastructure that have fallen most heavily on communities of color. Through critical investments, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework increases access to good-paying jobs, affordable high-speed internet, reliable public transit, clean drinking water and other resources to ensure&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework addresses economic disparities in our economy and the consequences of decades of disinvestment in America’s infrastructure that have fallen most heavily on communities of color. Through critical investments, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework increases access to good-paying jobs, affordable high-speed internet, reliable public transit, clean drinking water and other resources to ensure communities of color get a fair shot at the American dream.</p>



<p>These critical investments are first steps in advancing equity and racial justice throughout our economy. The President believes additional investments are needed in our nation’s caregiving infrastructure, housing supply, regional development, and workforce development programs to ensure that communities of color and other underserved communities can access economic opportunity and justice. And, earlier this month in Tulsa, OK, President Biden announced a whole-of-government effort to increase the share of federal contracts going to small disadvantaged businesses by 50 percent over the next five years, leveraging the government’s purchasing power to help more Americans realize their entrepreneurial dreams.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework:</p>



<p><strong>DELIVERS HIGH SPEED INTERNET TO EVERY AMERICAN HOUSEHOLD</strong></p>



<p>There is a stark digital divide in America. Black families are 9% less likely to have high-speed internet than their white peers, and Latino Americans are 15% less likely. About 35% of individuals living on Tribal lands lack access to broadband service. And although studies suggest high levels of digital access for Asian Americans, these studies are often limited in scope and don’t identify key inequities. For example, broadband access and affordability in the Pacific Islands has long been a challenge. During the COVID-19 pandemic, there were stories of kids sitting in McDonald’s parking lots to log on to remote school in parts of the country. The President believes this is unacceptable.</p>



<p>The Framework invests $65 billion to make high-speed broadband available to all Americans, to bring down high-speed internet prices across the board, and to close the digital divide. His plan will also invest in long overdue expansion of broadband on Tribal lands, in consultation with Tribal Nations. With the 1936 Rural Electrification Act, the Federal government made a historic investment in bringing electricity to nearly every home and farm in America, and millions of families and our economy reaped the benefits. Broadband internet is the new electricity. It is necessary for Americans to do their jobs, to participate equally in school learning and health care, and to stay connected.</p>



<p>In addition to achieving President Biden’s goal of connecting every American to reliable high- speed internet, the Framework will drive down prices for internet service and close the digital divide by making broadband more affordable, including in low-income communities and communities of color.</p>



<p><strong>ELIMINATES LEAD PIPES AND DELIVERS CLEAN DRINKING WATER TO EVERY HOUSEHOLD</strong></p>



<p>Across the country, pipes and treatment plants are aging and polluted drinking water is endangering public health. There are up to 10 million homes with lead service lines and pipes. Children in up to 400,000 schools and child care facilities are at risk of exposure to lead.</p>



<p>Across the country, families of color are at the highest risk for lead exposure at home and in schools. Communities of color in cities like Chicago, Milwaukee, and Newark are also at particular risk. For kids, higher exposure to lead can negatively affect academic performance, and can lead to cardiovascular disease later in life. By some estimates, each lead service line replaced at a cost of $5,000 per line leads to $22,000 in health savings.</p>



<p>The Framework makes the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history, replacing all of the nation’s lead pipes and service lines. From rural towns to struggling cities, the Framework invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal Nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most.</p>



<p><strong>INVESTS IN MORE PUBLIC TRANSIT OPTIONS AND ADDRESSING THE BACKLOG OF REPAIRS</strong></p>



<p>Asian American and African American workers commute by public transit at nearly 4 times the rate of white workers. For example, low-wage Black residents in Chicago spend 70 additional minutes commuting to work than their white peers. In New York City, the average Black resident spends 110 minutes more per week commuting to work than the average white resident.</p>



<p>The Framework’s historic investment in public transit – the largest federal investment in history – will reduce commute times and create more economic opportunities in communities of color.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests $48.5 billion to modernize transit, and improve accessibility for older Americans and people with disabilities. It will clear the backlog in public transit repairs, and build new transit. It will replace thousands of transit vehicles, including buses, with clean, zero emission vehicles.</p>



<p>These investments will yield significant returns for communities of color. Investments in public transit help people get better jobs and higher wages, and raise economic growth and productivity. One study found that a metropolitan area’s 10 percent increase in transit seats or rail service miles per capita is associated with up to $1.8 billion per year in increased wages. Another study found that improved transit access increases labor force participation.</p>



<p><strong>CREATES A FIRST-EVER PROGRAM TO RECONNECT COMMUNITIES DIVIDED BY INEQUITABLE TRANSPORTATION INFRASTRUCTURE</strong></p>



<p>Significant portions of the interstate highway system were built through Black neighborhoods, destroying homes, schools, churches, and parks and causing lasting disconnection and disinvestment for residents who stayed. More broadly, historic investments in transportation infrastructure, especially highway construction, cut too many Americans off from opportunity, dividing and demolishing communities, and perpetuating economic and racial injustices. The Framework creates a first-ever program to reconnect</p>



<p>communities divided by transportation infrastructure. The program will fund planning, design, demolition, and reconstruction of street grids, parks, or other infrastructure. This is in addition to other major grant programs that could fund elements of these projects.</p>



<p><strong>ELECTRIFY SCHOOL BUSES, IMPROVING THE AIR QUALITY FOR KIDS</strong></p>



<p>The Framework will make a critical down payment on helping the more than 25 million children and thousands of bus drivers who breathe polluted air on their rides to and from school. Diesel air pollution is linked to asthma and other health problems that hurt our communities and cause students to miss school, particularly in communities of color and Tribal communities. The Framework will deliver more than 35,000 electric school buses nationwide, helping school districts across the country buy clean, American-made, zero emission buses, replacing a sizable percent of the yellow school bus fleet.</p>



<p><strong>REMEDIATES BROWNFIELD AND SUPERFUND SITES</strong></p>



<p>26% of Black Americans and 29% of Hispanic Americans live within 3 miles of a Superfund site, a higher percentage than for Americans overall. Proximity to a Superfund site can lead to elevated levels of lead in children’s blood. Recent studies demonstrate that cleaning up these sites can lead to a decrease in blood levels by approximately 13-26%.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework provides the full American Jobs Plan funding level &#8212; $21 billion – to create good-paying union jobs plugging orphan oil and gas wells, cleaning up abandoned mines, and remediating Brownfield and Superfund sites. 26% of Black Americans and 29% of Hispanic Americans live within 3 miles of a Superfund site, a higher percentage than for Americans overall. As we transition to a clean energy future, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework will begin to remedy economic injustice for communities across the country that have relied on the fossil fuel industry and have been affected most by the impacts of climate change and pollution, including rural communities and communities of color.</p>



<p><strong>SAFEGUARDS COMMUNITIES OF COLOR FROM CLIMATE CRISES AND EXTREME WEATHER RISKS</strong></p>



<p>People of color are more likely to live in areas most vulnerable to flooding and other climate change-related weather events. For example, in the wake of Hurricane Harvey, Black and Hispanic residents were twice as likely to report lost income. Tribal lands are significantly at risk to the effects of climate change and Alaska Natives are particularly vulnerable, as they face multiple climate impacts.</p>



<p>The Framework invests $52 billion in helping communities build resilience to wildfires and floods through investments in forest management and upgrades to critical infrastructure &#8212; like elevating buildings, roads, and bridges, hardening physical infrastructure, and winterizing the power grid. And, it will fund state and local infrastructure improvements and emergency response strategies, such as planning grants to support development of evacuation routes or upgrading community shelters. The Framework will also make it easier for low-income families to buy flood insurance.</p>



<p><strong>INVESTS IN CLEAN ENERGY GRID TO MITIGATE THE DISPARATE IMPACTS OF POLLUTION ON COMMUNITIES OF COLOR</strong></p>



<p>Black, Latino, Asian American and Pacific Islander, and Native communities are more likely to be burdened by pollution. Black people are almost three times more likely to die from asthma related causes than their white counterparts. And more than one in three &#8212; or over 23 million &#8212; Latinos in the U.S. live in counties where the air doesn’t meet EPA public health standards for smog.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework helps meet this challenge by making the single largest investment in clean transmission in American history. It creates a Grid Development Authority at the Department of Energy to enable a national, clean energy power grid and funds to support activities that reduce the impacts to the electric grid, and protect communities from extreme weather, wildfire, and natural disasters. It deploys long distance, high voltage transmission to enhance reliability and resilience, lower costs, and integrate the highest value clean energy resources. It invests in research and development for advanced transmission and electricity distribution technologies, and smart grid technologies that deliver flexibility and resilience. And, it invests more than $22 billion in demonstration projects and research hubs for next generation technologies like advanced nuclear reactors, carbon capture for industrial plants, and green hydrogen.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Memorandum for the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development on the Delegation of Certain Functions and Authorities Under the Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/29/a-memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-state-the-secretary-of-defense-the-secretary-of-homeland-security-and-the-administrator-of-the-united-states-agency-for-international-development-on-the-delegation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 21:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the authority to submit to the Congress the reports required by sections 5(a) and 8(b) of the Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017 (Public Law 115-68).<br><br>The delegation of authority provided in this memorandum shall apply to any provisions of any future public laws that are the same or substantially the same as those provisions referenced in this memorandum.<br><br>The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/29/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 21:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[La Crosse Municipal Transit UtilityLa Crosse, Wisconsin 12:58 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Thank you, Laurie.  Please, please, please sit down.  I once said that to a big crowd; it was in the evening.  I said, “Please, sit down.”  And there were no seats.  They were out in a football field.  (Laughter.)  And the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">La Crosse Municipal Transit Utility<br>La Crosse, Wisconsin</p>



<p>12:58 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Thank you, Laurie.  Please, please, please sit down.  I once said that to a big crowd; it was in the evening.  I said, “Please, sit down.”  And there were no seats.  They were out in a football field.  (Laughter.)  And the press pointed out, “Biden is losing it.”  (Laughter.)  Well, I can see you all have seats.  (Laughter.)<br><br>Laurie, thank you very much.  I told Laurie, when she was showing me the bus she&#8217;s driving now: Back when I was in law school, I drove a school bus during the summers to pick up spending money.  And from one bus driver to another, Laurie, I want to thank you for all you do to make this city run, to help folks get where they need to go.  And you do it in a way that sometimes is not always easy. <br><br>I&#8217;m glad to be here with great Wisconsin leaders.  Gov, I guess I landed at the airport just a few minutes before you did.  Thank you for making the effort to be here.  And my good friend, Tammy Baldwin &#8212; Senator Baldwin is here.  And Congressman Ron Kind is &#8212; and, Mom, thank you for raising a good kid.  (Applause.) <br><br>And Mayor Reynolds.  I was telling the Mayor &#8212; he just won reelec- &#8212; he won election.  And I said, “You know, I always wonder why everybody runs for mayor,” because they &#8212; it&#8217;s the hardest job in American politics.  They know where you live.  You can&#8217;t go to the grocery store.  “Why is that pothole still there?”  I get it.  You don&#8217;t even control that. <br><br>But anyway, Mr. Mayor, thank you for your service.  Thank you for willing to serve. <br><br>I&#8217;m here in Wisconsin to celebrate a step forward for my country &#8212; our country &#8212; to talk a little bit about what it&#8217;s going to mean for working families here in Wisconsin and across the nation. <br><br>When I was sworn in five months ago, I pledged to put my whole soul into bringing America together.  I said I was running for three reasons, the last one of which I said is unite America. <br><br>I admit it&#8217;s difficult, and I think some of my friends in the press thought it was impossible.  I still don&#8217;t think it is but &#8212; because I believe that there&#8217;s nothing we cannot do if we bring &#8212; come together as a nation, Democrats and Republicans.  And we’re really divided on a whole range of things. <br><br>But if you look back across our history, from the Transcontinental Railroad to the creation of the Internet, you can see the truth in that idea, about coming together.  Because America &#8212; America has always been propelled into the future by landmark national investments &#8212; investments that only the government has the capacity to make; only the government, working together, could make.<br><br>Today happens to mark &#8212; coincidental &#8212; but today is the <s>60th</s> [65th] anniversary of one of those significant investments to change the nation.  Sixty-five years ago today, President Dwight Eisenhower signed the bill that created the Interstate Highway System.  Sixty-five years ago today.  That was the last infrastructure investment of the size and scope of what &#8212; the agreement I&#8217;m about to talk about today. <br><br>It&#8217;s time for us to write a new chapter in that story.  After months of careful negotiation, of listening, of compromising together in a good faith, moving together, with ups and downs and some blips, a bipartisan group of senators got together and they forged an agreement to move forward on the key priorities of my American Jobs Plan &#8212; and one of them is sitting in front of me. <br><br>As a result, this is a generational investment &#8212; a generational investment to modernize our infrastructure, creating millions of good-paying jobs &#8212; and that&#8217;s not coming from me; that’s coming from Wall Street &#8212; millions of good-paying jobs that position America to compete with the rest of the world in the 21st century &#8212; because China is way out-working us, in terms of infrastructure. <br><br>And it&#8217;s going to make the world of difference for families here in Wisconsin.  Here&#8217;s what it&#8217;s going to do: This deal will put American workers to work in good-paying jobs, not minimum wage jobs, not 15-dollar-an-hour jobs.  Prevailing wage job, good-paying jobs, repairing our roads and our bridges. <br><br>You all know why that matters.  One in five miles of highway and roads in America are in poor condition.  One in five miles.  Some states it’s worse where the weather is tougher.  Five perc- &#8212; 50 years &#8212; <s>50</s> [40] percent of our bridges are over 50 years old.  More than 1,000 bridges here in Wisconsin are rated as structurally deficient by engineers.  One thousand just in Wisconsin. <br><br>And I&#8217;m not &#8212; that doesn&#8217;t make Wisconsin better or worse; it&#8217;s &#8212; all across the nation is this way.  The bridges &#8212; the 10 most traveled bridges in America need repair, and some need to be completely rebuilt.  More than 600 &#8212; more than 600 here in the state of Wisconsin &#8212; bridges have weight limits to prevent trucks from crossing.  That means long detours for farmers heading to market.<br><br>It’s more than just an inconvenience; it’s about safety, as well.  In November 2019, a school bus in Arcadia, Wisconsin, tipped over going around a curve and went into a ditch with 20 students on board.  It wasn’t because of snow or ice; it was just an old country road.  It was rough conditions.  Thank God nobody was seriously injured at the time.<br><br>But this is a drain on our economy, as well.  Typical American &#8212; typical American &#8212; and it varies slightly from state to state &#8212; but the typical American pays a hidden tax of more than $1,000 a year in wasted time &#8212; wasted time and fuel due to traffic congestion.<br><br>Now, in the more the rural areas, the less the congestion.  But it creates other difficulties.<br><br>You all know that feeling: losing time, sitting in traffic, or being rerouted because the bridge isn’t wide enough or the road is poorly maintained.<br><br>This deal is going to put Americans back to fixing all of that, and good-paying jobs.  This deal will also put Americans to work replacing 100 percent of our nation’s lead water pipes.  You know, there’s 400,000 &#8212; well, I won’t get into the numbers; I get a little carried away &#8212; but it’s really dangerous.  Every single American child, at home or in school, will soon be able to turn on that faucet, and their moms and dads know that the water they’re drinking is clean and safe.<br><br>I’ll give you an example of why that matters.  Just look at the city of Milwaukee.  Milwaukee has more than 160,000 water service lines.  More than 70,000 of them, nearly half, have lead service lines.<br><br>And, by the way, I’m not &#8212; it’s not picking on Wisconsin, Gov.  Every state is like this.  But just to know what you’re going to be doing for the state of Wisconsin here.<br><br>You know, we know that exposure to lead in drinking water can trigger a number of serious problems.  Even low levels of lead can cause behavior and learning problems in children, impairing their growth.<br><br>There are up to 10 million homes with lead pipe service lines and pipes.  Children in up to 400,000 schools &#8212; 400,000 schools &#8212; and childcare facilities are at risk of exposure to lead.  This deal contains the largest investment in clean drinking water and waste water infrastructure in American history.<br><br>This deal also provides something you’re very familiar with in the Island.  It provides funding to get dangerous chemicals out of our water systems, known as PFAs, or &#8220;forever chemicals.&#8221;  This is a problem all across the country, and I know that you’re feeling it right here &#8212; right here.<br><br>Here in La Crosse County, just this spring, the state had to provide free bottled water to thousands of people on French Island because they were worried about those chemicals in the groundwater, which were linked to cancer and other illnesses.  We’ll pay for that.  We’ll get that done. <br><br>We’re also going to surge federal resources to help address the forever chemicals not just here, but all across America.  Unfortunately, Wisconsin is not unique in this problem.<br><br>This deal will also put Americans to work building transmission lines &#8212; the largest investment in clean energy transmission in American history.  Power outages cost the U.S. economy up to &#8212; now, this is &#8212; now, we know this, but until you add it up, it doesn’t seem to be that big a deal.  It costs the economy, Congressman, $70 billion annually.  You hear me?  Nationally, $70 billion annually.<br><br>And as climate change induces extreme weather events more and more frequently, we need to make investments to build a more resilient grid to carry this electricity. <br><br>The majority of the nation’s grid is aging.  Some components are over a century old.  And 70 percent of transmission and distribution lines are well into the second half of their lifespans.  You saw what happened in Texas this winter: The entire system in the state collapsed.  The entire system. <br><br>That’s why we have to act.  This deal will modernize the power grid to be more energy efficient and resilient to &#8212; and resistant to extreme weather; resilient against bad actors who try to hack and attack the grid.  Because I just spent a lot of time in Europe trying to work on that.<br><br>And it’s going to strengthen and revitalize our natural infrastructure, like our coastlines and levees, while preparing our physical infrastructure for wildfires, floods, and other extreme weather. <br><br>Anybody ever believe you&#8217;d &#8212; you hear &#8212; turn on the news, and it&#8217;ll say it was 116 degrees in Portland, Oregon.  A hundred and sixteen degrees.  &#8220;But don&#8217;t worry, there is no global warming.  It doesn&#8217;t exist.  It&#8217;s a figment of our imagination.&#8221;  Seriously. <br><br>When a severe storm rolls in, like you had in some parts of the state just recently, the power is going to be less likely to go out, town water systems will be able to withstand what happens if we &#8212; once we make these investments.<br><br>And all &#8212; as all of you know, America has one of the highest road fatality rates of anywhere in the industrial world.  Let me say that again: the highest road fatality rates of any industrial nation in the world.  I lost a wife and daughter and almost lost two sons.<br><br>Look, our fatality rate is double the rate in Canada on a per capita basis.  I bet every one of you here can tell me what the most dangerous intersections in your town are.  I&#8217;ll lay eight to five, no matter what the town is.  Maybe you don&#8217;t have many, but everybody knows what intersections are the most dangerous.<br><br>When you&#8217;re teaching your kid to drive, what do you do?  You tell them, &#8220;No, don&#8217;t go down that road when you come home.&#8221;  I&#8217;m being deadly earnest.  &#8220;When you come home, come home the other way.&#8221;<br><br>Well, guess what?  We got an agreement to invest $11 billion to help cities and localities reduce crashes and fatalities in the community &#8212; especially for cyclists and pedestrians, which are increasingly significant. <br><br>This deal is going to more than double the funding directed to state and local programs that improve the safety of people in vehicles, including highway safety, truck safety, pipeline and hazardous materials safety. <br><br>I won&#8217;t even get into this now, but, you know, we have &#8212; we have thousands of miles of pipeline.  The vast majority of those pipes are 60 years or older &#8212; some of them more than 80 years old.  A lot of them are leaking. <br><br>This is the United States of America, for God&#8217;s sake.  What are we not doing? <br><br>This deal will also help high-speed Internet and make sure it&#8217;s available to every American home, including 35 percent of rural families who currently go without it. <br><br>As of last spring, more than 82,000 children here in Wisconsin, which prides itself on its education, didn&#8217;t have reliable Internet access at home.  Think about that year &#8212; in a year of remote schooling.  When so many of our needs and our connections were forced to move online, tens of thousands of Wisconsin kids got left behind. <br><br>Did you ever think, here in America, that kids would have to sit in a fast-food parking lot just to do their schoolwork and homework because they could connect online?  Not a joke.  Ask any mom who has kids in school or a dad who is taking care of them.  No child should have to do that. <br><br>And no farmer here in Wisconsin should lose business because they don&#8217;t have a reliable connection to the Internet &#8212; know when to buy, know when to sell, and know what&#8217;s going on. <br><br>You know, back in 1936, the federal government brought electricity to nearly every home and farm in America, and it spread the opportunity out for cities in every part of the country.  It changed the lives and fortunes of thousands and thousands of homeowners, thousands of hometowns, and millions of American families.  And it set the stage for a massive, sustained economic boom that would follow World War Two.<br><br>High-speed Internet is the equivalent of that today.  It&#8217;s a similar &#8212; it&#8217;s an equivalent of that.  It isn&#8217;t a luxury; it&#8217;s now a necessity, like water and electricity.  And this deal would provide for it for everyone, while bringing down the cost of Internet service across the board. <br><br>This deal has also put Americans to work through a first-ever national effort to install electric vehicle charging stations &#8212; 500,000 charging stations nationwide along our highways and in rural and disadvantaged communities as well. <br><br>Think about what that can mean to the American autoworker and the future of electric vehicles.  China is going full bore.  They&#8217;re providing more electric vehicles than any nation in the world.  You know, it used to be, when I first got to the United States Senate, actually a couple of &#8212; actually, in the ‘60s, when I was getting out &#8212; the late ‘60s, when I was getting out of law school, what happened?  We invested more in R&amp;D and investment and manufacturing than any nation in the world. <br><br>Now we’re number eight in the world.  China used to be number nine; now they’re number two in the world. <br><br>And when you build a charging station, it spurs even more investment and more infrastructure around it &#8212; the local convenience store, the local hamburger place.  You know, think about &#8212; nobody is old enough, but my dad used to tell me &#8212; because he worked, back in the days, for the American Oil Company &#8212; they came along with the &#8212; the combustion engine.  You needed to be able to put gas in the engine.  I mean in the car &#8212; the tank.  Well, guess what?  You had to build gas stations. <br><br>One of my dad’s jobs and my Grandpop Biden’s jobs was to go from city to city convincing them it was okay to bury these great big tanks with gasoline in them.  And entire communities grew up around it. <br><br>Well, this is exactly what we have to do with regard to electric vehicles.  This deal is also going to help our cities, our towns, our school districts deploy electric buses.  Thirty-five thousand electric school buses that are accounted for.  And there are about 475,000 school buses in this country, 95 percent of them like the ones you had here &#8212;<br><br>(A child falls off their chair.)  Is he okay, honey?  You sure?  He took a little bit of a tumble.<br><br>Ninety-five percent of them run on diesel.  So, every day, more than 25 million kids and thousands of bus drivers breathe polluted air on the way to and from school. <br><br>Diesel air pollution is linked to asthma and other health problems.  It hurts communities.  It causes students to get sick and miss time in school. <br><br>We owe it to our kids to clean up the school buses, and this deal will help do just that.<br><br>I know that the city of La Crosse is getting two electric transit buses this fall &#8212; I think I saw them both.  I was down in the Carolinas, looking at the bus company where you’re going to buy them &#8212; charging stations to power them. <br><br>This bipartisan deal &#8212; by the way, you had half Republicans and half Democrats come along and present this deal and negotiate this deal.  It’s going to help advance that effort. <br><br>This deal also &#8212; also modernizes our outdated airports, ports, and waterways.  That means fewer delays that drain away so much money from families and from businesses.  There’s no good reason why that zero &#8212; zero of the top 25 airports in the world are in American.  Zero.  Not one in the United States of America.<br><br>This deal will put Americans to work through long-overdue national environmental cleanups.  That means good-paying jobs, capping hundreds of thousands of abandoned oil and gas wells that need to be cleaned up and capped &#8212; methane leaks &#8212; protecting the health of our communities.  Making the same money it took to dig that well.  And there’s thousands of them. <br><br>Not to mention, this deal represents the largest investment in American passenger rail and in freight rail since the creation of Amtrak. <br><br>Now, I know I’m “Mr. Amtrak.”  I’ve traveled over 2 million miles on Amtrak.  I commuted every day.  I get it.  I know you think I’m nuts.  But after my wife and daughter were killed, I decided to commute back and forth to Delaware.  It was a 257-mile roundtrip. <br><br>I’ll tell you a real quick story.  I shouldn’t bore you with it.  But, you know, the Secret Service &#8212; they’re the best in the world &#8212; doesn’t like you taking Amtrak because it stops too many times &#8212; the train.  They want me flying home in the small jets that were available as Vice President.  And that cost a lot of money, so I would go home on Fridays, you know, because my mom was passing away.  I’d go home on Amtrak.  And they published &#8212; they keep fastidious record of the miles you travel in an air- &#8212; in a Air Force aircraft as President and Vice President. <br><br>And toward the end of my term, a headline came out in all of the papers: “Biden travels…” &#8212; I think it was 1.3 or 1.7 million miles on Air Force planes.  And so, I’m getting on the train on that Friday, and these guys who all became my family &#8212; all &#8212; the conductor.  And a guy named Angelo Negri came up, and he goes, “Joey, baby!”  Grabs my cheek like that.  (Laughter.)  And I thought they were going to shoot him.  I really did.  (Laughter.) <br><br>I said, “No, no, no, no, no, no, no.  He’s a friend.”  He was like, &#8220;What the hell.&#8221;  And he said, “Big deal, Joey.  A million…&#8221; &#8212; whatever it was &#8212; &#8220;…three-hundred thousand miles.  You know how many miles you&#8217;ve traveled on Amtrak, Joey?&#8221;  And I said, &#8220;No, Ang.  I don&#8217;t.&#8221;  And he said, &#8220;At that retirement dinner, we calculated it.  We estimated 127 days a year, 250 miles back and forth, 3 &#8212; 36 years, then as Vice President.  Joey, you traveled more on Amtrak.&#8221;  (Laughter.)<br><br>Well, I &#8212; and when they named a station after me in my city, someone complained that Biden is using his influence.  I said, &#8220;Hell, they should name the whole Northeast Corridor after me.&#8221;  I&#8217;ve &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; more than anybody else. <br><br>But all kidding aside, studies show that if you can get to your destination in the same amount of time or less on rail than you can by car, people will take rail.  And, Gov, you know this better than anybody.  Imagine if you could get from Chicago &#8212; from La Crosse to Chicago in two hours, instead of four and a half.  That&#8217;s what this will allow us to build the capacity to do.<br><br>And besides, it will not only make your travel easier, not &#8212; I don&#8217;t know why you&#8217;d go to Chicago, but &#8212; you know, all kidding aside &#8212; it would reduce the largest source of pollution in America: vehicle travel.<br><br>We&#8217;re not just tinkering around the edges here.  We&#8217;re going to invest $66 billion in rail to eliminate backlogs, bring world-class rail service to areas outside the Northeast.<br><br>Here in Wisconsin, we’ll add new stops in Green Bay, Madison, and Eau Claire.<br><br>This deal also makes the largest investment in public transit in American history.  A whole lot of people here in Wisconsin depend on public transportations, like the bus system here in La Crosse, to get to work, to school, and get around.  Because of this deal, it will be safer, quicker, cleaner, more frequent, and more avail- &#8212; more reliable. <br><br>More transit options mean more people can access good job &#8212; access good jobs as well.  One study found that it leads to higher wages for workers because businesses can attract more customers with the rail.<br><br>This bipartisan breakthrough is a great deal for the American people &#8212; not just for folks in the cities, not just for red states or blue states, but for everybody.<br><br>And this job &#8212; this jobs &#8212; the jobs that are going to be created here &#8212; largely, it&#8217;s going to be those for blue-collar workers, the majority of whom will not have to have a college degree to have those jobs. <br><br>A lot of those folks are being left behind now.  The guys I grew up with in Scranton and Claymont are being left behind.  This is the answer for good-paying jobs.  Jobs is jo- &#8212; jobs not just in our biggest cities, along our coasts, but in small towns across the country so families can build wealth and opportunity in rural hometowns and don&#8217;t have to leave when they&#8217;re grown up. <br><br>We&#8217;ve said it all along: This is a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America.  And long before, families in Wisconsin are going to see the benefits firsthand. <br><br>Look, I&#8217;m always quoting my dad because he was smart and I loved him.  My dad used to say, “Joey, a job is about a lot more than a paycheck.  It&#8217;s about your dignity.  It&#8217;s about respect.  It&#8217;s about your place in the community.&#8221;  I mean he really would say this.  When he lost everything in Scranton and we had to move down to Claymont, Delaware &#8212; a little steel town. <br><br>And he said &#8212; and the deal is going to deliver breathing room.  All he said was, &#8220;All you want, as a middle-class person, is just to have a little bit of breathing room.  Not &#8212; just a little bit of breathing room.&#8221; <br><br>That&#8217;s why we got to build this economy from the bottom up and the middle out, not trickle down &#8212; creating good-paying jobs with dignity and jobs that cannot be outsourced.<br><br>And critically, we’re going to get it all done without raising taxes on a single American earning less than $400,000.  Now, all of you making over $400,000, I love you, but I don&#8217;t mind a little bit if your taxes go up a little bit. <br><br>But all kidding aside, I made a commitment: Nobody &#8212; I would not support anything that raised a penny in tax on someone making under 400 grand.  And that means, in this bill, there is no gas tax.  Working families have already paid enough.<br><br>Instead, we’re going to pay for these investments, in part, by giving the Internal Revenue Service the resources it needs to collect taxes on the wealthiest Americans who owe but are currently not paying under the existing tax rules. <br><br>And, by the way, it&#8217;s not done by this &#8212; it will be done by conservative economists and liberal economists.  It cracks down on tax cheats, not just hardworking, middle-class Americans.<br><br>And there&#8217;s a lot of important investments in this deal that are long overdue.  Economists of all stripes agree that it&#8217;s going to create good jobs and dramatically strengthen our economy in the long run.  It makes it easier for businesses to seamly [seamlessly] transport their goods, makes it easier for workers to more easily access job opportunities.<br><br>But the reason this agreement matters so much &#8212; it&#8217;s about what it represents.  This deal isn’t just the sum of its parts; it’s a signal to ourselves and to the world that American democracy can come through and deliver for all our people.  We can be united.<br><br>I just met with the G7.  I just met with all of NATO.  And I just met with Putin.  The autocrats think that democracy can&#8217;t keep up with autocrats.  Not a joke. <br><br>But it’s living proof that we can still come together in this country and accomplish something big and transformational.<br><br>I know that neither the Democrats nor Republicans get everything they want in this agreement.  It&#8217;s not all that I proposed.  But that’s what our economy is all about.  That’s what it means to compromise and reach consensus.  And that&#8217;s what every &#8212; in the heart of every democracy.<br><br>And we can&#8217;t give up on what we &#8212; keep finding ways to come together.  Because every time we negotiate in good faith and come together to get something big done, we break a little more of the ice that too often keeps us frozen in place and prevents us from solving the real problems people are facing.<br><br>Let me be clear: There’s much more to do.  And I&#8217;m going to continue to fight for more.  I am going to keep working with Congress to pass even more of my economic agenda so we can keep building an economy from the bottom up and the middle out.<br><br>As we bring home key parts of my American Jobs Plan, I’m going to make the case &#8212; and I&#8217;ve told this to the negotiators &#8212; I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I&#8217;m going to continue to make the case there &#8212; critical investments are still needed, including those in my Family Plan &#8212; American Family Plan.<br><br>Maybe the most important among them is extending the Child Tax Credit, which will significantly benefit middle-class and working folks.  Let me explain what that is. <br><br>Pretty soon, taxpayers in America are going to get a significant check back from the IRS.  For example, if you are &#8212; if you &#8212; if you have to pay taxes and you have a good income, you get to deduct $2,000 per dependent &#8212; per child.  And that comes off the bottom line of your taxes, and you probably still owe more after that’s cut off. <br><br>But for families &#8212; for families who, in fact, don’t have that big a tax bill, they don’t get anything from this.  So, we changed the law this year, and it’s cutting child poverty by 40 percent.  And here in Wisconsin, by July 15th, we’re going to start &#8212; they&#8217;re going to be picking up the phone and calling you to say, “Thanks, Gov.”  And they&#8217;re going to get checks from the IRS. <br><br>Here’s what&#8217;s in it: For every child you have under the age of six, you&#8217;re going to get $3,600.  And for every child under the age of &#8212; between &#8212; over the age of 12, you&#8217;re going to get $3,000.  So, you&#8217;ll actually get a cash payment instead of just a credit against your taxes, because you don&#8217;t pay that many taxes if you&#8217;re &#8212; if you&#8217;re making &#8212; if you&#8217;re making the minimum wage or you&#8217;re making $20-, $30-, $40,000 a year.  And people say, “Well, that&#8217;s a giveaway.”  You guys, I think it&#8217;s time to give ordinary people a tax break.  The wealthy are doing fine.  (Applause.)  No, I mean it.  I mean it. <br><br>Why is this not a tax break for working folks, when the stuff we give to the super wealthy are called “tax breaks”?  Look, major action on clean energy, housing, caregiving, on child and paid leave, universal pre-K, free community college. The human infrastructure is intertwined with our physical infrastructure.  It’s going to help us create more good jobs, ease the burden on working families, and strengthen our economy in the long run. <br><br>And I&#8217;m going out &#8212; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m going to be out there making the case for the American people until this job is done; until we bring this bipartisan deal home; until our human infrastructure, also, needs are met; until we have a fair tax system to pay for all of this. <br><br>And, by the way, what I&#8217;m talking about in the Family Plan &#8212; let me tell you how I&#8217;m going to pay for it.  And the American people, in the polling data, overwhelmingly support it. If we just raise the corporate tax to 28 percent &#8212; it used to be 35 percent.  It was supposed to come down to 28; it’s now 21.  If you raise it to 28 percent, you know how much money that raises?  $1.4 trillion.  If you have a minimum global tax, which we agreed to in Europe &#8212; that means so corporations can’t avoid paying the taxes at home &#8212; that would generate, in America, $385 billion.  If you end deductions for foreign corporations who ship their profits out of the United States, that raises $260 billion in these tax havens.<br><br>You know, there are 30 corporations in America of Fortune 500 making billion &#8212; I’m &#8212; I come from the corporate capital of the world, Delaware.  Not a joke.  More corporations are incorporated in Delaware than all the rest in America combined.  Okay? <br><br>And guess what?  Fifteen of the Fortune 500 companies last year paid &#8212; I mean, 30 &#8212; excuse me &#8212; paid zero taxes, and they made billions of dollars.  Paid not a penny in tax, not a single cent.<br><br>I&#8217;m not trying to punish anybody.  I&#8217;m just saying, “Let&#8217;s be fair.”  If you just set up a minimum tax &#8212; you had to pay at least 15 percent of your earnings as a corporation &#8212; that alone would raise $230 billion. <br><br>The point is, I have never had a reputation of being someone who&#8217;s out there trying to just out-tax people.  But here&#8217;s the deal, folks: I think it&#8217;s about time there be fairness in the tax code.  I don’t want you paying more than your share.<br><br>But the tax cut that was passed under Trump &#8212; the $2 trillion, not a penny of which was paid for &#8212; where did it go?  Over 80 percent of it went to the top one quarter of 1 percent.  I think you should be able to be a billionaire.  I think you should be able to be a millionaire.  But, for God&#8217;s sake, at least pay.  Pay your fair share.  Pay your fair share.<br><br>Folks, there’s a lot of work ahead to finish the job I’ve just outlined.  There’ll be more disagreements to resolve, more compromises to forge along the way. <br><br>But, today, the American people can be proud of Democrats and Republicans; families here in Wisconsin can be proud; Congress can be proud, because this country came together, forged a bipartisan deal &#8212; which a lot of has to do with your state &#8212; your senator &#8212; that delivers for everybody.  We’ve shown the world and, just as importantly, we&#8217;ve shown ourselves that American democracy can come through.  There&#8217;s nothing &#8212; nothing, nothing &#8212; beyond our capacity when we come together as one nation.<br><br>So, thank you, Wisconsin.  Thank you all for who you are and what you do.  May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.  Thank you, Wisconsin.  (Applause.) <br><br>1:31 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>March 2021 Visitor Log Records Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2021/06/29/march-2021-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in March 2021. This set includes 1215 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 2679. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in March 2021. This set includes 1215 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 2679.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
