<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 15:51:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Official Previewing the Second Global COVID&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/12/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-official-previewing-the-second-global-covid-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 15:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference(May 11, 2022) 6:06 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Good evening.&#160; And thank you for joining our background call previewing tomorrow&#8217;s Global COVID Summit.&#160; This call will be held on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&#160; And it will now be embargoed until 7:00 a.m. tomorrow, May 12th.&#160; For your awareness, not for your reporting,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>(May 11, 2022)</p>



<p>6:06 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good evening.&nbsp; And thank you for joining our background call previewing tomorrow&#8217;s Global COVID Summit.&nbsp; This call will be held on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And it will now be embargoed until 7:00 a.m. tomorrow, May 12th.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For your awareness, not for your reporting, the officials on this call are [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I will pass it off to [senior administration official].  Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Welcome, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks so much for taking the time today to join us.&nbsp; I’m &#8212; our office’s mission is to coordinate across the government to prevent, detect, and respond to pandemic and infectious disease threats that face America and the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, we want to brief you on the sum- &#8212; on the Global COVID Summit that the United States will cohost tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, the United States has delivered over 500 million doses of vaccines to over 100 countries as part of the 1.2 billion doses committed by the United States at the last summit in September.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. has also led the world in COVID-19 funding, committing over $19 billion in funding to date in vaccinations, tests, treatments, oxygen, and humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve partnered with countries to improve their capacity to make their own vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This has truly been an unprecedented public health effort to save lives around the world and keep Americans safe from the next variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Thursday, the United States will continue our leadership globally by cohosting the Global COVID-19 Summit with Belize, which is serving as the CARICOM chair, with Germany as the G7 presidency, with Indonesia as the G20 presidency, and Senegal as the Africa Union chair.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have made great progress since the last summit, but the pandemic is not over.&nbsp; And now is the time to continue to respond and also prepare for the next variant and the next pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The overarching purpose of the summit are really twofold.&nbsp; One is to redouble our efforts to control COVID-19.&nbsp; And the second is to ensure the world is prepared for the next one &#8212; the next pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will be joined by partners from around the world, including governments, multilateral organizations, philanthropies, businesses, and civil society leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there are really three priorities: &nbsp;</p>



<p>First, we want to prevent complacency.&nbsp; The pandemic is not over.&nbsp; We have the need to continue to address new subvariants, which continue to emerge, slowing vaccinations.&nbsp; We need funding both at home and from countries and other stakeholders to get more shots into arms and other vital lifesaving resources to the world.&nbsp; So the summit will focus on securing new resources and policy commitments to control COVID in 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, we want to prevent deaths, and that means focusing on the most vulnerable.&nbsp; Since January of 2021, when deaths were at their highest around the world and a seven-day average of 14,000 deaths a day &#8212; now they&#8217;re down to about 2,000 deaths per day.&nbsp; That is some progress that countries around the world have contributed to, health workers have contributed to, but we still have more to do.&nbsp; Two thousand deaths a day is still too many.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The summit will focus on getting vaccines, tests, and treatments to those at highest risk, like the elderly, the immunocompromised, and frontline and health &#8212; and other health workers around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We do have the tools to control COVID &#8212; vaccines, tests, and now new antiviral medicines &#8212; but medical breakthroughs are not enough.&nbsp; We need more funds to hire vaccinators to support vaccination sites, to support fridges to store vaccines, to support fuel to &#8212; for vehicles to deliver vaccines to people out of reach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also need new funding to purchase new treatments and expand test and treatment strategies like we&#8217;ve done for HIV/AIDS and malaria, and like we&#8217;re doing for COVID here in America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The third thing we want to do is to prevent future variants and pandemics.&nbsp; Delta and Omicron emerged in other parts of the world before they reached America.&nbsp; The next pathogen is also likely to emerge in another part of the world.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not a matter of “if,” but “when.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The truth is we&#8217;ve learned we can stop outbreaks at their source by investing in the capacities of countries to carry out surveillance and detect the next variant and threat; to develop and manufacture medicines, vaccines, and test locally; and to equip local health workers, clinics, and hospitals to ensure that those lifesaving measures reach people who need them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To do that, the summit will call for countries to invest in the new Global Pandemic Preparedness and Health Security fund at the World Bank.</p>



<p>This is not a talk-the-talk summit, it&#8217;s a walk-the-walk summit.&nbsp; In advance of the summit, we&#8217;ve called on leaders of governments, civil society, businesses, and philanthropy to make significant new commitments to get shots into arms, expand access to tests and treatments, and enhance health security, and prevent future variants and pandemics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are doing our part in this effort by securing funding to embark on responding to this pandemic, to continue to respond to it in an unprecedented fashion.&nbsp; We are doing our part by convening the world around a coordinated effort, an urgent effort to save lives.&nbsp; Other countries are doing their part by providing new resources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the hard-fought progress we&#8217;ve made and the momentum we have is at serious risk without congressional action.&nbsp; Countries are declining our doses because they don&#8217;t have the resources they need to get shots into arms, whether they’d be fridges to store the doses or information campaigns to combat hesitancy.</p>



<p>The President, as you know, has requested $22.5 billion in emergency funding to continue our COVID response.&nbsp; That includes $5 billion that will ensure the continuation of our vital, proven work to get shots into arms globally and to expand access to therapeutics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, you will hear a loud call from the United States for Congress to act with the urgency that this virus warrants.&nbsp; We know the virus is not waiting for Congress to act, so we need urgent, urgent action, not empty words.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to turn it now to my colleague, [senior administration official], who will give you a sense of what to expect at the summit tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], over to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; So what will we see tomorrow at the summit?&nbsp; First, you&#8217;ll see that countries and the private sector stepped up.&nbsp; The summit includes leaders from all over the world, as you can see from the advisory that we released yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During the summit, the U.S. will join the four cohost countries &#8212; again, those are Senegal, Germany, Indonesia, and Belize &#8212; to kick off this summit.</p>



<p>And then at least 10 world leaders and heads of state will speak, as well as at least a notable &#8212; many notable govern- &#8212;&nbsp; non-governmental speakers will speak throughout the summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vice President Harris will also join world leaders during Thursday&#8217;s COVID Summit.&nbsp; She’ll give remarks on the devastating impacts of COVID on Americans and the steps we&#8217;re taking to manage the threat of new variants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She’ll also call on the international community to continue to step up and take action to manage the current threat and prepare for future threats.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. government is bringing the full force of its power to bear.&nbsp; Secretary of State Blinken, Ambassador to the United Nations Linda Thomas-Greenfield, Secretary of Health and Human Services Becerra, USAID Administrator Power, G7 and G20 Sherpa and Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh, and COVID Response Coordinator Ashish Jha will all be participating tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The opening session will be followed by three sessions that focus on major challenges that we face in moving from COVID-19 as an emergency to COVID-19 &#8212; eventually &#8212; as a controllable respiratory disease, and to a world that is truly prepared for the biological risks that we face and that are growing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These sessions include focusing on getting vaccines to the world and particularly to the most vulnerable, saving lives by expanding access to tests and treatments, and presen- &#8212; preventing future catastrophes by investing now in health security capacity and workforce.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To date, the summit has leveraged in new money more than $3.1 billion in commitments.&nbsp; These are additional to what has been raised at other points in 2022.&nbsp; They are on top of existing commitments.&nbsp; That’s $3.1 billion.&nbsp; That would not have happened without U.S. leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if the U.S. is to remain a leader protecting Americans and the world from dangerous disease threats, we need Congress to act now to provide more funding for the COVID response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] said, there&#8217;s a lot of chatter about what the U.S. is or isn&#8217;t bringing to the summit.&nbsp; It&#8217;s clear what we&#8217;re bringing: We&#8217;re bringing leadership and over $3.1 billion in leverage commitments that wouldn&#8217;t have arisen without us convening this summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We come to this summit as the leader in the global COVID response.&nbsp; We’ve pioneered an unprecedented and urgent effort to navigate getting over half a billion lifesaving doses to hundreds of countries around the world with no strings attached.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re the first country to buy doses for the sole purpose of donations &#8212; not a small amount, a billion of them.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve provided billions in funding for the “last mile” to work to get shots into arms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That didn&#8217;t happen overnight, and it didn&#8217;t happen by accident.&nbsp; It happened because countries and organizations want to step up to the United States and for the administration &#8212; because he has been a leader in this response, President Biden, from day one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This week, you&#8217;re going to see important commitments of all types.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see major countries and regional bodies.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see Canada.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see the European Commission.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see the Republic of Korea.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see Spain and France contributing hundreds of millions of new dollars to get shots into arms.&nbsp; And relatedly, you&#8217;ll see low-income countries committing to accelerations to vaccinate their most vulnerable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You&#8217;ll see political and substantial financial commitments to establish a new Health Security and Pandemic Preparedness fund at the World Bank so that it can stand up this summer.&nbsp; This is something the administration has personally championed.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been ab- &#8212; we have to be able to walk and chew gum at the same time by preparing now, because the next pandemic could come at any time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;ll also see commitments from companies to look at setting lower prices for treatments and tests, to work with governments and international organizations to expand access for those most at risk &#8212; country by country, community by community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, you’ll see commitments to help provide facts to overcome the dis- and misinformation which has plagued &#8212; pardon the pun &#8212; this pandemic.</p>



<p>You’ll see companies and other groups stepping up in some really creative ways.&nbsp; We’ve been really heartened by the responses that we’ve gotten from all over the world.&nbsp; This is the power of the United States convening power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we’re also digging deep ourselves.&nbsp; So, in terms of what we’re bringing to the table:</p>



<p>We will be providing additional funding for the Global Health Security and Pandemic Preparedness fund at the World Bank.&nbsp; Building on our initial seed pledge of $250 million to establish that fund, we’ll be increasing our pledge by an additional $200 million, for a total of $450 million.&nbsp; The fund will provide sustained financing for improving local, national, and global capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to pandemics and other disease or infectious disease threats.</p>



<p>There is now a strong global consensus to establish this new Pandemic Preparedness and Global Health Security fund at the World Bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You may have seen several weeks ago that Indonesia, the G20 president, issued a strong statement from finance ministers signaling political consensus and directing those next steps for this fund to the World Bank and the WHO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secretary of the Treasury Yellen, WHO Director-General Tedros, and others have been very publicly vocal about amplifying why this fund is critical to lessen or prevent the next pandemic as part of the overarching reforms of the global health architecture.</p>



<p>Last week, the World Bank sent a memo to their board noting the concept of this is, in its own words, “opening for business by September of 2022.”</p>



<p>We’re also pleased to announce this week that the United States National Institutes of Health licensed 11 COVID-19 research tools and early-stage vaccine and diagnostic candidates to the Medicines Patent Pool under the World Health Organization COVID-19 Technology Access Pool.&nbsp; This includes licensing the NIH stabilized spike protein technology, which is a key component included in multiple existing COVID-19 vaccines. These licenses will enable manufacturers from all over the world to develop vaccines, treatments, and diagnostics for COVID-19 using these technologies, and to distribute them to low- and middle-income countries.</p>



<p>In addition to this important step taken by the NIH, the FDA is also committed to doing its part to facilitate greater global access to these lifesaving products, including through a rapid review of generic products for the global COVID response.</p>



<p>Through the FDA, we confirm our commitment to conduct thorough and efficient reviews of COVID-19 response products.&nbsp; While COVID-19 remains a public health emergency, FDA will prioritize the review of these COVID-19 therapeutics, including applications seeking tentative approval of generic products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>FDA grants tentative approvals for products that meet the requirements for FDA approval but cannot be approved for exclusivity or patent reasons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, the United States also will pilot test-and-treat strategies for the most vulnerable populations in low- and middle-income countries to help prevent deaths from COVID-19.&nbsp; The U.S. Agency for International Development will use $20 million in order to provide technical assistance and service delivery in up to eight countries to support rapid deployment of tests and treatments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will leverage $80 million from the global fund that they will use to procure rapid test kits and oral COVID-19 antiviral drugs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It will build on an additional $22 million from Unitaid to provide &#8212; to produce over $120 million in investments to introduce test-and-treatment strategies in over 20 countries in 2022.&nbsp; This collaborative early investment will catalyze test-and-treat adoption and expansion in additional countries.</p>



<p>And this commitment to pilot test-and-treat activities is a down payment on U.S. leadership that can be fully realized if Congress acts to provide the President’s requested COVID-19 supplemental funding.</p>



<p>Despite these commitments to combat COVID-19 and to enhance future preparedness against health threats &#8212; I just want to end by underscoring: Our progress and momentum against COVID-19 is at serious risk without congressional action.&nbsp; We continue to urge the Congress to act promptly to provide supplemental resources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without additional emergency COVID-19 funding, the United States will be unable to purchase additional lifesaving treatments for the American people, the United States will be less able to stop the spread of dangerous new variants from around the world, and the United States will be unable to keep vaccinating the world against COVID-19 and getting shots in arms to save lives here, at home, and abroad.</p>



<p>Again, we’re grateful to the world for stepping up at this summit and this critical moment, and we’re optimistic that the commitments that we and others are making will save lives and better prepare us for future threats.</p>



<p>With that, I’ll turn it back over to [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration officials].&nbsp; Moderator, would you mind giving directions again on how to ask questions?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t see the other two major global vaccine developers on the list of attendees.&nbsp; Were Russia and China invited by the U.S. or any of the other hosts, or did they decline?&nbsp; Or is there a reason that they&#8217;re not involved in this?&nbsp; And how does that affect your ability to reach more people on the globe?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Anita, thank you.&nbsp; We &#8212; in terms of whether Russia was invited: No, we did not extend a commitment ask to them.&nbsp; And with other countries, we have extended and asked for a financial or policy commitment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Your second part of your question was: “How does that affect our efforts to lead the world and for the global response?”&nbsp; Well, you know, I think you&#8217;ll &#8212; you heard from my colleague that we&#8217;re finding amongst the countries, the companies, the philanthropies, and the nonprofits that have committed to this effort that we&#8217;ve mobilized $3.1 billion of financing towards the global fight.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s clear other countries are stepping up to do their part.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The administration is stepping up to do its part by virtue of cohosting this, by virtue of continuing to lead with the $19 billion of financing provided to us through the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; And the fight is not done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so now we really need Congress &#8212; specifically Republicans in Congress &#8212; to show up not with empty words, but with action, and to act on securing and enacting the supplemental while lives remain at risk here and around the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for holding this call.&nbsp; You said the Vice President will be participating.&nbsp; Is President Biden playing any role in this in any form?&nbsp; And can you give us any sense of conversations he&#8217;s had with some of these leaders in an effort to sort of engage them in adding value to the sum that you&#8217;re trying to collect?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Peter, for your question.&nbsp; The Vice President will join leaders in the headline session at tomorrow&#8217;s summit.&nbsp; She&#8217;ll give remarks on the devastating impact of COVID on Americans and the steps that we&#8217;re taking to manage threats of new variants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what this is partly about.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about saving lives abroad.&nbsp; But we also know new variants come from &#8212; have come from abroad, and this is about stopping those because that will also ensure the gains we&#8217;ve made in this country are protected and American lives are saved, and that businesses and schools continue to not be disrupted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President will address participants, and he will have a resounding commitment to ensuring that the goals of the summit &#8212; to prevent complacency, to prevent deaths, and to prevent future variants and pandemics &#8212; are front and center.&nbsp; His team has been engaged with the teams of the other cohosts all the way up to their presidencies.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been meeting almost every other day, if not every day, to plan this together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, this summit &#8212; the commitment here and the progress we&#8217;ve made overall just wouldn&#8217;t be happening without the leadership of both the President, the Vice President, and several members &#8212; as you heard &#8212; of the Cabinet that are going to be speaking tomorrow.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, again, for joining our call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, this call is now embargoed until 7:00 a.m. tomorrow, May 12th, and it’s on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Also, for planning purposes only, the summit is scheduled to start at 9:00 a.m. tomorrow.&nbsp; And you can look at our advisory for the livestream link.&nbsp; And it will kick off with the President&#8217;s remarks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to all.</p>



<p>6:27 P.M. EDT</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Global Covid-19&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/12/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-global-covid-19-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 15:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 9:36 A.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, Madam Ambassador.&#160; And thank you, all of you, for co-hosting this very important convening: Prime Minister Briceño; the President, of course, Sall of Senegal; and Chancellor Scholz; and President Widodo.&#160; Thank you all.&#160; And I also see my friend, Prime&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>South Court Auditorium<br><em>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></em></p>



<p>9:36 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Ambassador.&nbsp; And thank you, all of you, for co-hosting this very important convening: Prime Minister Briceño; the President, of course, Sall of Senegal; and Chancellor Scholz; and President Widodo.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; And I also see my friend, Prime Minister Trudeau.&nbsp; And, President Sánchez, I want to thank you as well and everyone who is here with us today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today marks a solemn milestone for us in the United States: the loss of one million American lives due to COVID-19.&nbsp; One million lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today and every day, we remember them, of course, and we honor them.&nbsp; And I send my prayers to their loved ones.&nbsp; And I recognize all the pain that has been endured by them and those who have lost loved ones around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>I believe we owe it to their memories and to the millions of other lives lost around the world to renew our fight against this deadly virus, which brings me to why, of course, we are all gathered here today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Over the last two years, as we all know, COVID has had a devastating impact on people around the globe: economic shocks, a massive disruption to so many parts of our daily lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>And of course, yes, we have made remarkable progress.&nbsp; Yet without continued action, lives and livelihoods will continue to be at risk.&nbsp; This is why our administration is hard at work in Washington, D.C., doing everything we can.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you heard just a moment ago from President Joe Biden, there are a number of ways in which we have and will continue to take action.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have called upon the United States Congress for $22.5 billion dollars in additional emergency funding to battle COVID. &nbsp;Five billion dollars of that would be dedicated to continue our leadership in helping to save lives around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>We will continue to advocate for these lifesaving resources as part of our global commitment.<br>&nbsp;<br>All of you in this headliners session have also taken very important steps and have made key commitments, and we thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>In our collective words and actions, we are all making clear complacency is not an option.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we gather today, our goals are twofold: One, we must continue to respond to the threat.&nbsp; And two, we must prepare for the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>As long as the COVID virus is present in one country, it impacts all of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>This pandemic, of course, knows no borders, and we must continue to work together to find solutions.<br>&nbsp;<br>We still &#8212; as has been said, we still need to make vaccines, tests, and new treatments accessible to all and especially to those who are highest at risk: the elderly, the immunocompromised, and healthcare workers.<br>&nbsp;<br>I am also aware that countries throughout the world need more training for doctors and nurses and community health workers; and more technical assistance, including freezers, to help get shots in arms.&nbsp; We look forward to partnering with all of you on this.<br>&nbsp;<br>We must also keep an eye to the future.&nbsp; We have learned key lessons in the past two years &#8212; lessons about the importance of early detection and surveillance; the need to leverage the private sector and non-profits to scale production of medicines and tests and vaccines; the transformative power of investments in health systems and health workers; the complicated mechanics of donating and distributing hundreds of millions of vaccines around the world; and the lifesaving benefits of a global health security fund.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last year, at this very summit, we discussed this particular lesson.&nbsp; And you’ll recall I urged us to work together to develop a new financing system and mechanism.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks to President Widodo and Prime Minister Draghi, through the G20, we have consensus to establish this fund.&nbsp; And I know we all know and have said it will help us on very critical issues like early detection and warning systems, and investments in rapid recovery and response.&nbsp; And this is just the beginning.<br>&nbsp;<br>The way I see it is this: As we think about moving forward, I believe we can also come together &#8212; in addition to everything we have discussed &#8212; come together to shape new international norms on these issues.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Together, we can establish common understandings that guide our collective action: that all countries, regardless of GDP, should have access to lifesaving vaccines, tests, and therapeutics; that nations should be transparent and share information early and often; that leaders should prioritize the most vulnerable and the overlooked; and that we must recognize and address inequities in our systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>The future, of course, will present other global health crises, but they don’t have to become catastrophes if we do this work together.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now is the time, we know, for bold thinking and concrete action.&nbsp; And I look forward to this discussion and continuing discussions, and the work we will do together to shape the future of global health and health security around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all.<br>&nbsp;<br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 9:42 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2nd Global COVID-&#8288;19 Summit&#160;Commitments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/2nd-global-covid-19-summit-commitments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The second Global COVID-19 Summit, co-hosted by United States, Belize, Germany, Indonesia, and Senegal, convened over partners and organizations from around the world to accelerate collective efforts to get shots into arms, enhance access to tests and treatments, protect the health workforce, and finance and build health security for future pandemics and other health crises.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The second Global COVID-19 Summit, co-hosted by United States, Belize, Germany, Indonesia, and Senegal, convened over partners and organizations from around the world to accelerate collective efforts to get shots into arms, enhance access to tests and treatments, protect the health workforce, and finance and build health security for future pandemics and other health crises.</p>



<p>The Summit garnered new financial commitments totaling more than $3 billion in new funding, not yet announced, above and beyond pledges made to date in 2022. This includes over $2 billion for immediate COVID-19 response and $962 million in commitments toward a new pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank. We encourage partners to join, as much more is needed to control COVID-19 and build better health security.</p>



<p><strong><u>Commitments<a id="_ftnref1" href="#_ftn1"><sup><strong><u><sup>[1]</sup></u></strong></sup></a> from Government, Other Partners, and Entities</u></strong></p>



<p><em>Note: Country text is being validated with host governments and is not yet final.</em></p>



<ul><li><strong>African Union:</strong> Will expand and continue its Saving Lives and Livelihoods Program to purchase COVID-19 vaccines for the African people, support the delivery of the vaccines, and support vaccination rollout programs at country level&nbsp;and increase vaccine manufacturing in Africa in&nbsp;partnership with Africa CDC and the Mastercard Foundation and other partners. Will also, through coordination by Africa CDC, strengthen public health institutions, increase local capacity for producing medical products, strengthen the health workforce, and establish action-oriented partnerships through its New Public Health Order Program.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Australia:&nbsp; </strong>Pledged additional AUD $85 million in 2022 to COVAX and has delivered on the first half of its commitment made at the first Global COVID-19 Summit, to share 60 million vaccine doses by the end of 2022. Announced a AUD 375 million second phase for the Health Security Initiative for the Indo-Pacific region as well as committed AUD 100 million to the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Austria</strong>: In 2022, committed to provide EUR 1.6 million annually to CEPI from 2022-2024 for a total of EUR 4.8 million. Delivering up to 14 million vaccine doses by mid-2022.&nbsp; Committed to remain active in donating vaccines and providing financial support and emergency assistance.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Belgium</strong>: Will provide an additional EUR 15 million for COVID-19 vaccination efforts, including EUR 10 million for the ancillary costs needed for vaccine delivery and EUR 5 million for COVAX.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Belize:</strong>&nbsp;Will accelerate efforts to vaccinate 70% of the population by September 2022 and promote boosters for at risk populations. Will support an extensive public education campaign to overcome vaccine hesitancy. Will construct a BZE1 6.8 million hospital to better serve community health needs and to expand and provide an additional BZE 3.2 million to the National Health Insurance Program.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Canada</strong>: Will provide CAD 732 million&nbsp; in funding for the Access to COVID-19 Tools-Accelerator (ACT-A), enabling Canada to meet its fair share for the 2021-2022 ACT-A budget cycle, assessed at CAD 747 million. This funding includes a previous allocation of CAD 220 million&nbsp; to the COVAX Advance Market Commitment (AMC), announced by the Prime Minister on April 8, 2022 at the Gavi COVAX AMC Summit, and builds on the CAD 15 million announced by the Prime Minister on October 30, 2021, in support of COVAX Manufacturing Task Force partners. &nbsp;Canada is contributing to the international pandemic response and will continue to work with partners to ensure that we strengthen our collective ability to prevent, prepare and respond to disease outbreaks going forward.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Belize: </strong>Will accelerate efforts to vaccinate 70% of the population by September 2022 and promote boosters for at risk populations. Will support an extensive public education campaign to overcome vaccine hesitancy. Will construct a $16.8 million hospital to better serve community health needs and to expand and provide an additional BZE 3.2 million to the National Health Insurance Program.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Botswana</strong>: Commits to vaccinate at least 80 percent of its population according to the Country’s National Vaccine Deployment plan, implementing the second stage of Phase 4 (5–12-year-olds) by mid-2022 pending successful consultation. Commits to sharing lessons learned on its success with other countries to help them reach Botswana’s levels of vaccination success , the third highest vaccination rate in Africa.&nbsp; Will continue to focus on improving and accelerating vaccine uptake and coverage. Commits to setting policy to offer and avail free treatment to all people who are infected with COVID-19, have mild to moderate as well as severe illness, or are at risk for death due to risk factors, with treatment modalities are based on Botswana’s updated treatment guidelines. Commits to manufacturing COVID-19 vaccines to improve local and regional equitable vaccines supply chain by the end of 2022, drawing lessons from the global demand-supply mismatch and non-equitable distribution of vaccines.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Colombia: </strong>Will continue to vaccinate the 2 million Venezuelan migrants in Colombia and other historically excluded populations. Will share lessons on vaccinating populations from government partnerships with the private sector. Will provide technical assistance for mass vaccination campaigns, to improve supply chain logistics, and for surveillance of possible adverse events related to vaccination. Will also contribute to the discussions within the WHO on ways to strengthen prevention, preparedness, and response to pandemics.&nbsp; Will increase the number of migrants registered in the social security system from 400,000 to 900,000 in 2022.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Côte D’Ivoire: </strong>Will increase vaccine demand creation and uptake, and accelerate vaccine coverage while immediately prioritizing fully vaccinating and providing boosters to key sub-populations such as teachers, healthcare workers, people with comorbidities, and adolescents. Will strengthen genomic sequencing to identify new variants. Will expand and sustain health system capacity and financing; increase domestic health budgets; and improve funds disbursement to enable timely salary, incentive, and other supportive payments for health care workers. Committed to continue promoting the One Health approach and strengthening the national One Health platform.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Denmark: </strong>Will provide over USD 10 million for vaccine rollout via ACT-A (COVAX). &nbsp;Minister Møller Mortensen expressed support for strengthening WHO and &nbsp;support for WHO agreement on pandemic preparedness, prevention, and response.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>European Union</strong>: The European Union budget will provide 300 million euro for vaccination support. Will provide 100 million euro for other ACT-A pillars.  Will provide $450 million USD for the pandemic preparedness and global health security financial intermediary fund at the World Bank.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>France</strong>: Will provide EUR 220 M: 100 million euros to COVAX, 50 million euros to ACT-A, and 70 million euros to strengthen vaccine production capacity in developing countries, including Rwanda, Senegal, and South Africa.</li><li><strong>Georgia:</strong> According to the National Vaccine Deployment Plan, intends to vaccinate at least 65% of population by mid-2022.&nbsp; Will use the&nbsp;Financial Incentives scheme to continue to motivate citizens over 50 years old.&nbsp;Pediatric doses of Covid-19 vaccine will be made available for 5-12 year old kids&nbsp;&nbsp;In order to provide access to novel drugs, will continue to procure antivirals the treatment of mild Covid-19 patients with the high risk of hospitalization in March 2022.&nbsp; Has extended its COVID-19 vaccination and treatment program for all Ukrainian citizens who entered the country after the war crisis.&nbsp; Is implementing an active information and communication campaign with support from USAID, WHO, European Commission and other international partners.&nbsp; Commits to a full program accelerating vaccine coverage while immediately prioritizing fully vaccinating and providing boosters to at-risk populations, accelerating vaccine coverage for vulnerable populations, saving lives with access to tests and treatments, supporting health and frontline workers, and expanding and sustaining health capacity and financing including support for the establishment of a global health security and pandemic preparedness fund.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Germany: </strong>Will contribute EUR 50 million toward the establishment of a new global health security and pandemic preparedness fund housed at the World Bank. Committed EUR 1.1 billion to ACT-A’s 2021/2022 replenishment cycle earlier in 2022 and an additional EUR 224 million for bilateral projects to help increase vaccine uptake. Part of Germany’s overall contribution are EUR 850 million targeted support for vaccine logistics and strengthening of absorption capacities, especially in African countries (“LastMile Initiative”) bilaterally and multilaterally through ACT-A. &nbsp;All contributions are subject to parliamentary approval.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>India:&nbsp;</strong>Will continue to extend boosters coverage&nbsp;to eligible populations and expand vaccinations to those under age 18, and continue working towards&nbsp;complete&nbsp;vaccination coverage for India’s adult population.&nbsp;With the increased&nbsp;funding allocated for the 2022-2023 domestic health budget,&nbsp;will&nbsp;provide&nbsp;insurance coverage for healthcare workers,&nbsp;increase the number of health and wellness centers. Will&nbsp;increase the number of integrated public health and regional disease control laboratories, as well as bio-safety labs.&nbsp;Is increasing&nbsp;zoonotic surveillance, and will continue to&nbsp;supply&nbsp;vaccines and work on&nbsp;extending&nbsp;a SARS -CoV2 genomic consortium to neighboring countries.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Indonesia: </strong>Will provide $5 million to CEPI for the period of 2022-2026, adding to the $1 million contribution made in 2020.&nbsp; Will continue accelerating vaccination efforts to achieve the WHO vaccination goal of the 70% population, including for the 189 million people of Indonesia by June 2022, while ensuring equitable access to vaccines across income and age groups, and those most at risk. Earmarked Rp122,54 trillion of the 2022 national budget to continue vaccination efforts, care for COVID-19 patients, provide health worker and tax incentives, and support local governments.&nbsp; As Co-Chair of COVAX AMC EG, commits to contribute to the global effort to ensure equitable access to vaccines and getting shots in arms, and to increase local and regional vaccine production capacity and research capability, including for vaccines beyond COVID-19 pandemic, including through the use of WHO mRNA technology hubs. In the framework of ACT-A, will continue to accelerate global equitable access to vaccines, therapeutics, diagnostics, and PPE through its roles as Co-Chair of the Tracking and Accelerating Progress Working Group and as Member of the Facilitation Council, the Financial and Resource Mobilization Working Group, and the Vaccine Manufacturing Working Group.&nbsp; As G20 President, supports the establishment of a new financing facility to ensure adequate and sustained financing for pandemic prevention, preparedness and response, with a central coordinating role of the WHO, and supported by the World Bank and in close cooperation with international partners.&nbsp; Commits to strengthen the central role of WHO in coordinating global health actions through leadership in the Working Group on Strengthening WHO Preparedness and Response to Health Emergencies together with the United States.&nbsp; Through multilateral cooperation , seeks political and financial support for developing countries, including as Co-Host of COVAX AMC Summit and Second Global COVID-19 Summit, and ACT-A diplomatic outreach with likeminded partners.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Italy: </strong>Will provide an additional 200 million euros to the ACT Accelerator, as well as31 million additional vaccine doses via COVAX.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Japan: </strong>Will contribute up to $500 million to COVAX and expand the scope of the Last One Mile Support of additional $30 million US dollars to 17 new Latin American and the Caribbean and African countries. Pledges to contribute $300 million to CEPI. Will provide assistance of up to $200 million USD through JICA to enhance local production capacity for pharmaceutical and medical products including vaccines in Africa. Total contributions increase from $3.9 billion USD announced at the first Summit to $5 billion USD.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Lichtenstein: </strong>Provided CHF 300,000 to COVAX in 2022.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Nepal:</strong> Will accelerate vaccine coverage and immediately prioritize fully vaccinating and providing boosters to at-risk populations. Will provide a detailed plan and targets at the national and sub-national level for getting shots into arms and overcoming key barriers for at-risk populations, and will track and report on full vaccination and booster rates by key subgroups. Will designate a “high-level leader” to coordinate with donors, multinational development banks, and the COVID-19 vaccine delivery partnership.&nbsp; Will also develop a national and community level strategy to expand access to testing and prompt treatment, focusing on those at highest risk and integrating COVID-19 testing /treatment with existing health systems, and will update relevant testing and treatment guidelines. Will improve and expand community access to testing and treatments and pharmacovigilance programs. Will support health and frontline workers by providing PPE and water, sanitation, and hygiene access, and training.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>New Zealand: </strong>Will provide NZD 2.25 million to UNICEF to fund COVID-19 diagnostics in Vietnam and to maintain essential health services in the Philippines, and NZD 8 million to the Global Fund’s COVID-19 Response Mechanism for lifesaving tests, treatments and personal protective equipment. Will continue its support in the Pacific region to enable access to and uptake of vaccines within comprehensive public health responses to the COVID-19 pandemic, as well as continuing its support for health security and health systems strengthening.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Nigeria: </strong>Will support vaccination efforts for 112 million citizens above age 18 towards a vaccination goal of 70% of the population being vaccinated by December 2022. Will expand access to COVID 19 testing and treatment, focusing on those at highest risk, and will integrate testing/treatment into existing health systems while prioritizing COVID-19 for monthly reporting on the Integrated Disease Surveillance and Reporting system platform. Will train an additional 10,000 frontline healthcare workers by December 2022 on basic infection prevention and control measures, ensuring availability of oxygen, and eliminate stock-outs of PPE. Will strengthen laboratory capacity for genomic sequencing and specimen bio-banking for both diagnostics and surveillance activities, and will implement a national bio-bank policy. Will designate highest-level leadership to coordinate relevant government sectors to achieve these goals, in collaboration with the international community and its development partners, and will progressively increase domestic health budgets. Will promote businesses in Nigeria to integrate health security into organizational policies and business goals.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Norway: </strong>Provided USD 222 million to the 2021/2022 budget cycle of ACT- A. Supports establishing a global health security and pandemic preparedness fund housed at the World Bank.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Pakistan</strong>: Will accelerate vaccine coverage from 82 percent to 90 percent and provide boosters to eligible and at-risk populations, including school-aged children eligible for vaccines (age 12-18), by summer 2022. Plans to launch a second iteration of its robust national vaccination campaign in late May, striving to vaccinate hard-to-reach populations.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Palau: </strong>Will maintain a proactive and robust response to the ongoing pandemic, maintain and enhance existing services and plans including non-COVID essential services, and will strengthen social protection programs for the vulnerable and affected population.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Philippines:</strong> The Philippine government committed to measures to boost efforts for expanding health care capacity that adheres to global standards, to adopt systematic approaches for effectively implementing emergency programs, and to develop a Comprehensive Pandemic Response Framework that will safeguard the country from future pandemics.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Republic of Korea:</strong> Will provide $300 million USD for ACT-A over 3 years, from 2023-2025. This builds on the $212 million USD committed to ACT-Accelerator since its launch. Support developing countries move toward vaccine self-sufficiency by establishing WHO Global Biomanufacturing Workforce Training Hub. Express political support for the pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Rwanda:</strong> Will vaccinate five- to eleven-year-old children with at least one dose by the end of 2022 and will vaccinate at least seventy percent of the total population with the primary series (two shots) by June 2022. Will double booster coverage from thirty percent to sixty percent of those eligible, and will continue to expand the Government of Rwanda’s capacity to locally manufacture vaccine.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Saudi Arabia: </strong>Provided $2.8 million to the WHO in 2022 to provide logistical support for vaccine delivery in order to vaccinate ten percent of Yemenis.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Senegal:</strong> Commits, with Institut Pasteur de Dakar (IPD), to facilitating the new $200 million Madiba (Manufacturing in Africa for Disease Immunization and Building Autonomy ) biotechnology platform, which will include production of vaccines against COVID-19 and other diseases.&nbsp; In support of the project, Senegal has mobilized financing of $91 million, including an EIB loan of $79 million, and has made a 3.3 Hectares site available.&nbsp; The project also benefits from grants from IFC, DFC, EIB, EU, and AFD, amounting to $14 million.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Spain: </strong>Will provide EUR 100 million to support new COVID-19-related bilateral projects. Will provide USD 200 million for the purchase of 30 million vaccines for donation through COVAX and bilaterally, as needs dictate. When combined with previous donations, Spain will have pledged to donate up to 100 million vaccines, remaining as one of the largest vaccine donor worldwide.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>South Africa:</strong> South Africa is committed to work with African leaders to achieve vaccine coverage through mass campaigns across the continent.&nbsp; We continue to advocate for a TRIPS waiver in the WTO to improve global access to vaccines, therapeutics, and diagnostics.&nbsp; Committed to getting more life-saving vaccines to those in need, South Africa is donating 5 million doses of the Pfizer vaccine and 10 million doses of the J&amp;J vaccine to other African countries.&nbsp; It has contributed $10 million to the Global Fund and plans to contribute financial support to the ACT-Accelerator.&nbsp; As an AU Champion will work towards a goal of 200 million tests administered by the end of 2022 by resourcing and supporting member states to implement Africa CDC’s Enhanced Surveillance Strategy, which includes community-based testing, wastewater testing, and sentinel surveillance.&nbsp; In the same capacity, &nbsp;we tabled at the AU Summit in February and got an endorsement for a common agenda for manufacturing vaccines, medicines, diagnostics, therapeutics, and health products on the continent.&nbsp; The continent’s largest COVID-19 vaccine manufacturing plant opened in South Africa last year, and mRNA hubs for tech transfer have been opened in South Africa, Egypt, Senegal, Tunisia, Kenya and Nigeria.&nbsp; Multilateral agencies and philanthropists need to be procured vaccines and boosters from African manufacturers to ensure the developing capabilities of the continent are retained. Finally, South Africa supports the formation of the Fund as a mechanism to finance global health security.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Sweden: </strong>Committed its health experts to help improve international global health architecture and help advance policies on improved pandemic preparedness.&nbsp; Donated 10 million vaccine doses to COVAX.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Taiwan:</strong>&nbsp; Pledges an additional contribution of $1.5 million to support the fight against COVID. &nbsp;Will continue to provide PPE and medical equipment to fight COVID worldwide, having contributed $70 million in this effort since April 2020.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Tanzania</strong>: Will vaccinate 70% of eligible Tanzanians by fall 2022.&nbsp; Will launch intra-Tanzanian regional information sharing workshops for COVID–19 mitigation.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Thailand:</strong> Will donate over 3.3 million doses of COVID-19 vaccines, worth $14.5 million, in 2022. Will continue investing in the development of COVID-19 vaccines and cooperate with global partners on vaccine testing, research and development, and production. Will continue working actively on disease prevention and health emergency preparedness in neighboring countries to better address particularly communicable and emerging diseases. Supports in principle the initiative to establish the pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>United Arab Emirates</strong>: Will provide $10 million in financial contributions and $50 million in-kind assistance of equipment.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>United Kingdom: </strong>Since December, has committed £265 million [$327 million] to the global response to COVID-19 as part of the commitment to ending the acute phase of the pandemic in vulnerable countries and future pandemic preparedness, including £105 million to expand testing capacity globally and boost oxygen supplies, and £160m as part of the UK-hosted Global Pandemic Preparedness Summit to support CEPI to reduce the time to develop vaccines against new health threats – including new COVID variants – to just 100 days. The UK has spent over £2.1 billion since 2020 to help end the pandemic, address its social and economic impacts and to support global efforts to fund, and distribute vaccines fairly.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>United States</strong>: Committed an additional $200 million to the pandemic preparedness and global health security financial intermediary fund (FIF) at the World Bank in 2022, bringing the U.S. total pledge to the FIF to $450 million to date.&nbsp; Committed to share U.S. Government COVID-19 vaccine-related intellectual property and research tools for greater global access.&nbsp; Committed to rapid review of generic products for global COVID-19 response. Committed to pilot “test and treat” strategies for the most vulnerable populations in low and middle-income countries to help prevent hospitalizations and deaths from COVID-19.&nbsp; Committed to additional vaccination support through Global VAX.&nbsp; Committed to expand investments in&nbsp;bilateral global health security programs.&nbsp; Committed to expand dose donations to include boosters and pediatric doses to accelerate global vaccine coverage.&nbsp; Committed to improving guidance for vaccine development to enhance protection. These commitments build on previous commitments announced in 2022, including support for a financing facility for COVID-19 vaccine purchases and delivery through the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation and advancing COVID-19 vaccine research and development through the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Commitments<a href="#_ftn2" id="_ftnref2"><sup><strong><u><sup>[2]</sup></u></strong></sup></a> from Non-Governmental Organizations, Private Sector, Philanthropies</u></strong></p>



<p>In addition, we have received commitments from more than 50 organizations, including local and international non-governmental organizations, businesses, philanthropies, advocacy groups, faith-based organizations, and other members of civil society.&nbsp; To date, new commitments in 2022 outlined below exceed $700 million for vaccinating the world, saving lives now, and building better health security.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.abbott.com/"><strong>Abbott</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Abbott will make available to low and middle income countries (LMICs) a dedicated portion of its global manufacturing capacity for WHO EUL-approved antigen rapid diagnostic tests (Ag RDTs), amounting to a minimum of 20 million tests per month and a total of 240 million tests for an entire year, a commitment that amounts to nearly a quarter of the global goal of ensuring access to 1 billion tests in 2022 announced in September.<strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.abtassociates.com/"><strong>Abt Associates</strong></a><strong>:&nbsp; </strong>Commits to convening a global coalition to identify health system innovations that emerged during the COVID-19 pandemic that can be adapted and scaled to transform future health systems and Build Better Health Security. As a trusted partner of the governments of the United States, United Kingdom and Australia, Abt Associates developed tools and innovations in our work and will share them broadly. We invite other countries and partners to engage in this collaboration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.aahi.org/"><strong>Access to Advanced Health Institute</strong></a><strong> </strong><strong>and </strong><a href="https://immunitybio.com/"><strong>Immunity Bio</strong></a><strong>:&nbsp; </strong>commit to manufacturing next-generation T-Cell vaccines for pandemic preparedness that are stable at room temperature, rapidly modifiable to address current and emergent pathogens, and provide potent, broad and durable protection in sub-Saharan Africa at the billion dose scale by 2025.&nbsp; Commit to bringing the latest immune-stimulating cell therapy and vaccine technology through clinical trials and centers of excellence to develop licensed vaccines and breakthrough immunotherapies that address the pandemics of infectious disease and cancer around the Globe.&nbsp; Committed to expend $1 billion USD over the next 5 years to produce billions of doses of vaccines, fusion proteins, and natural killer cell therapy at our million square feet of 11 plants we currently own globally.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.africafrontlinefirst.org/"><strong>Africa Frontline First</strong></a><strong> (AFF): </strong>Commits to raising $15M by September 2022 in the first phase of its work to build better health security. AFF is a collaborative new financing initiative led by Her Excellency Ellen Johnson Sirleaf to professionalize 200,000 community health workers across 10 African countries by 2030. This workforce will expand critical surveillance, testing, and treatment for emerging disease threats, maintain life-saving care during emergencies, and provide quality jobs, particularly for women.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://amref.org/"><strong>Amref Health Africa, HQ</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to increase access to and uptake of COVID-19 vaccines in thirty-one countries in Africa. The activities will be led across 11 projects with multiple partners to support the administration of over 4.5 million vaccine doses across 31 countries in East and Southern Africa, training over 15,000 community health workers, and facilitating access to vaccines in hard-to-reach areas. To ensure delivery of this commitment, $46,117,000 has been secured to date.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.gatesfoundation.org/"><strong>The Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits up to $125 million to Build Better Health Security through vaccine research and development, enhanced integrated disease surveillance, workforce capacity development, and expanded access to pandemic tools in low- and middle-income countries. These new investments, which are an extension of the foundation’s longstanding commitment to health equity, are aimed at ending this pandemic and ensuring the world is prepared to prevent another pandemic.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><a href="https://www.blackrock.com/corporate/about-us/social-impact">BlackRock Foundation</a>: </strong>Commits $5 million to ensure immediate, equitable access to Covid-19 diagnostic tools across the world, in partnership with FIND &#8211; the global alliance for diagnostics &#8211; to keep people safe, halt new variants in their tracks and address urgent clinical needs. BlackRock will support FIND to deliver on the goal of increasing the number of daily Covid-19 tests taken in low-income countries from 7.3 per 100,000 individuals to 100 per 100,000 by the end of 2022.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.usccb.org/"><strong>Catholic Relief Services – US Conference of Catholic Bishops</strong></a><strong> (CRS): </strong>Commits to work with its in-country teams to increase vaccine coverage and uptake, directly supporting COVID-19 vaccinations in 22 countries and mobilizing at-risk populations in over 100 countries. CRS will engage local stakeholders to facilitate collaboration and connect local partners with donors to advance localized funding. CRS will mobilize American Catholics to advocate for an equitable global response and will engage with peer organizations through the INGO COVID-19 Vaccine Collaborative.&nbsp; Commits to leveraging its network of over 1500 partners to communicate essential information to reduce COVID-19 transmission, illness and death. CRS will serve as the Global Fund C19RM lead in Republic of Congo, Guinea, Mali, Niger and Sierra Leone, leading on procurement for tests and other commodities. CRS will address the secondary impacts of COVID-19, such as education disruption, the loss of primary caregivers, fraying social cohesion, and increasing hunger and malnutrition.&nbsp; Commits to using its available resources to identify, finance, and fill gaps in health systems in the countries in which it operates. CRS will continue implementing activities to address vaccine hesitancy, conducting primary research to inform vaccine strategies, supporting faith-based organizations, and financing critical health workforce trainings. Further, CRS will continue to work with Ministries of Health and other health service providers to strengthen the capacity of resilient health systems.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.clintonhealthaccess.org"><strong>Clinton Health Access Initiative</strong></a> <strong>(CHAI)</strong>:&nbsp; Commits to ensuring affordable and effective antiviral COVID-19 treatment is available in low- and middle-income countries. CHAI has negotiated agreements with generic suppliers to make generic Paxlovid (nirmatrelvir/ritonavir &#8211; NIR/r) available at under $25 USD per treatment course for treatment of COVID-19. Equitable access to oral antiviral medications, especially for high-risk populations, will help save lives and limit the impact of future surges.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://cepi.net/"><strong>Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations</strong></a><strong> (CEPI): </strong>Commits to helping fill the gaps in vaccine research and development that threaten to undermine progress against COVID-19, working in partnership with institutions in low- and middle-income countries. Such research, including clinical trials on “mix-and-match” and fractional dosing, will help to inform COVID-19 vaccination strategies globally. Commits to funding the development of broadly protective COVID-19 vaccines and working to enable equitable access to these globally.&nbsp; Will work to reduce global pandemic risk by delivering innovative R&amp;D programs that help to develop safe, effective, globally accessible vaccines in 100 days. This includes advancing vaccines against known threats; producing a library of prototype vaccines against critical viral families; investing in vaccine manufacturing innovations; advancing enabling science programs critical to rapid vaccine development; and connecting stakeholders to enable rapid countermeasure development, effective response and equitable access.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://coregroup.org/"><strong>CORE Group</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Will work with country partners to provide training on addressing vaccine misinformation through social behavioral change norms and provide evidence-based communication training and tools to increase demand and uptake for COVID-19 vaccine. CORE Group will conduct knowledge sharing events and sessions at the regional and global levels, to share innovative ideas of addressing vaccine hesitancy, share tested and translated resources, and convene civil society to improve COVID19 vaccine uptake.&nbsp; Will convene global stakeholders to ensure implementation strategies around health security with a One Health approach and advocate for greater representation of civil society, including people with disabilities, women and children, and under-served communities, to be included in the planning and discussions around their own health security. We commit ensuring evidence-based technical direction and collaboration around Covid-19, global health security, through an integrated multi-sectoral approach, at our October 2022 Global Health Practitioner Conference.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.covidcollaborative.us/"><strong>COVID Collaborative</strong></a><strong>: </strong>COVID-19 has now left a staggering 10.4 million children worldwide orphaned by the death of a parent or grandparent caregiver. Many of these children face abuse, violence, and institutionalization. That is why COVID Collaborative, in collaboration with Oxford University, and with support from The New York Life Foundation, commits to advocate for and catalyze country-level policies to incorporate family-based care for COVID-bereaved children into national COVID-19 response plans, focusing on high-burden countries in sub-Saharan Africa.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/us/en.html"><strong>Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu Limited</strong></a><strong> (Deloitte): </strong>Commits up to US $3 million to make publicly available a playbook that outlines processes and protocols that enable society to provide and scale health-care support and resources, thereby helping to address COVID-19 variants and surges, in support of the goal to Build Better Health Security</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.finddx.org/"><strong>FIND</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to enhancing efforts for timely testing, including self-testing, in vulnerable groups, providing vital information to assess transmission in diverse populations and formulate strategies to prioritize those most at risk. These efforts will also help focus testing and treatment strategies. Commits to supporting LMIC governments in the development and roll-out of scaled up testing and test-and-treat programmes, focused on vulnerable populations and equitable global access, as well as maintaining the data gathering and reporting systems that will allow global, regional and national decision-making based on the best possible information about the state of the pandemic.&nbsp; Commits to identify and work with partners for the development and validation of multipathogen diagnosis and care pathways, which must include COVID-19. These new tools and diagnostic pathways will also be designed and tested to strengthen surveillance systems for both endemic and pandemic-prone pathogens, and link to the use of enhanced capacity for genomic sequencing.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.theglobalfight.org/"><strong>Friends of the Global Fight Against AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria</strong></a><strong>:</strong>&nbsp; Commits to partner with other organizations to lead advocacy for new investments in pandemic preparedness that are grounded in human rights, integrated with health systems, and include multiple stakeholders.&nbsp; The organization will help mobilize global advocacy to remind donors that the US is hosting the replenishment of the Global Fund, another effective tool in building health systems and preparing for the next pandemic alongside a new pandemic preparedness fund.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.fhi360.org/"><strong>Family Health International (FHI) 360</strong></a><strong>:&nbsp; </strong>Commits to engaging in at least 20 LMICs with governments, local organizations, and communities to build their capacity to provide COVID-19 vaccine service delivery and generate demand for COVID-19 vaccines. FHI 360 commits to documenting and sharing innovative ideas and approaches to overcoming vaccine hesitancy globally.&nbsp; Commits to converting technical tools and resources to global goods and taking proactive efforts to make these tools available to LMICs and promote their use for strengthening COVID-19 response programs. FHI 360 commits to enhance health workers’ capacity to deliver oxygen to patients in clinical settings and improve oxygen ecosystems in at least 25 LMICs, to promote equitable access to the highest quality clinical services possible.&nbsp; Commits to support at least 15 LMICs to achieve their health security goals and achieving International Health Regulations (IHR) targets and achieve Sustainable Development Goals. FHI 360 commits to developing new tools and technologies to support these efforts.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://globalhealth.org/"><strong>Global Health Council</strong></a><strong> (GHC):</strong> Commits to continued advocacy with U.S. congressional leaders to accelerate financing for COVID-19 vaccination campaigns. Global COVID-19 supplemental funding is urgently needed to support these national and sub-national campaigns to make progress toward the 70% target, prioritizing groups like frontline health workers, the elderly, and the immunocompromised. GHC will continue to bolster commitments amongst stakeholders within multilateral organizations and ensure these bodies are sustainably-resourced and well-equipped to address the world’s most pressing health needs.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.ghtcoalition.org/"><strong>Global Health Technologies Coalition</strong></a><strong> (GHTC): </strong>Committed to amplify evidence of gaps in upstream vaccine research and development (R&amp;D) for the COVID-19 response and work to ensure political support and additional resources to support R&amp;D of next-generation vaccines designed to better reach the last mile and address emerging variants and for strengthening regional research and manufacturing capacities. This includes expanding multisector support for clinical research, strengthening regulatory pathways, and mobilizing sustainable financing for regional manufacturing hubs. Will hold public- and private-sector stakeholders accountable to unlocking funding and advancing research to expand the pipeline of affordable, easy-to-deploy diagnostics and therapeutics, particularly for use in low-resource settings.&nbsp; Will galvanize partners to push for more efficient regulatory pathways for novel COVID-19 technologies; bolstered testing, surveillance, genomic sequencing, and data sharing to better detect and monitor emerging variants; and strengthened regional manufacturing capacities.&nbsp; Supports the creation of a new pandemic preparedness fund and will leverage its network to highlight how the fund should be utilized to bolster country and regional pandemic research and development (R&amp;D) capacities. GHTC is also supporting the Global Health Security Agenda R&amp;D Task Force to develop a tool that enables countries to assess their R&amp;D preparedness capabilities with the goal of aligning emerging financing with articulated R&amp;D gaps.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.google.org/"><strong>Google.org</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Donating an additional $150 million in Search ads to the World Health Organization, Gavi, government agencies, and nonprofits to ensure users searching on COVID-19 related topics such as vaccines, testing, or economic recovery initiatives are connected with credible sources. This brings Google.org’s total in-kind global commitment to COVID-19 recovery to over $1 billion.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://helpageusa.org/"><strong>HelpAge USA</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to promoting the dignity, wellbeing, and voice of older people. We are working with partners at global, regional, national, and local levels to develop and implement inclusive community engagement and advocacy strategies that effectively support COVID-19 vaccine access and uptake among older people and achieve global vaccine equity. Our organization&#8217;s goal aligns with the summit&#8217;s objective to vaccinate the world.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.henryschein.com/"><strong>Henry Schein, Inc.:</strong></a><strong> </strong>Henry Schein commits to working in partnership with the WHO to develop platforms for supply chain data collection to strengthen the resilience of the global healthcare supply chain.&nbsp; This work represents an expansion of the Pandemic Supply Chain Network (PSCN), a public-private partnership founded in 2015. Henry Schein serves as private sector lead of the PSCN, with more than 60 companies participating together with the WHO and other multilaterals. Henry Schein is contributing its core competencies to support this effort, and a cash donation of $25,000.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.unilever.com/news/hygiene-behaviour-change-coalition/"><strong>The Hygiene and Behaviour Change Coalition 2</strong></a><strong> (HBCC2): </strong>Will encourage vaccine uptake and combat vaccine hesitancy alongside continued hygiene messaging, using its hygiene and behaviour change platform to incorporate vaccine confidence messaging where vaccines are available. The coalition will reach millions through incorporating vaccine messages into public campaigns and programmes, and create digital tools that support people with information on COVID-19 vaccines, including where it is available and how to access it (where applicable).&nbsp; Will help millions of people by supporting measures to reduce transmission of COVID-19 in 18 countries across Africa and Asia by provision of critical WASH products and services as hygiene remains the first line of defence against the virus until vaccines reach all. The coalition will provide communities with hygiene advice and training, products, and handwashing facilities in institutions such as schools, health centres and public places.&nbsp; Will work with national governments and institutions to strengthen local capacity and build resilience of health systems and communities against new COVID-19 variants and future pandemics. The hygiene vulnerabilities and inequalities the pandemic has exposed must be eradicated if we are to defeat the virus and improve health security for all. HBCC2 will advocate for increased investment in hygiene and pandemic preparedness at national and global level.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.rescue.org/"><strong>International Rescue Committee</strong></a><strong> (IRC): </strong>Commits to extending the capacity of governments to deliver Covid-19 vaccines in humanitarian settings as soon as delivery funds and doses become available to us. Based on our current infrastructure and capacity, we can deliver 32 million doses, fully vaccinating 16 million people. With $160 million dollars and sufficient doses, we could reach nearly all eligible people in the fragile and conflict affected settings where we work across 30 countries.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://ipghealth.com/"><strong>IPG Health/McCANN HEALTH</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Committed to working with countries to develop more effective ways to increase COVID-19 vaccine uptake.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://livinggoods.org/"><strong>Living Goods</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to supporting community health workers (CHWs) to ensure high levels of uptake of COVID-19 vaccines and to combat COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy. Living Goods commits to supporting government operations for widespread COVID-19 vaccine rollout to the individuals in the rural communities served by Living Goods-supported CHWs. Finally, Living Goods commits to encouraging uptake of COVID-19 vaccination among frontline health workers and other high-risk populations.&nbsp; Commits to working in partnership with governments to train all staff and community health workers (CHWs) we support in COVID-19 prevention, early case detection, reporting procedures, and personal safety measures. Living Goods commits to supporting CHWs to educate communities on prevention, testing and where to receive care. Living Goods commits to using digital tools to support CHWs to conduct COVID-19 case screenings and connect CHWs with disease surveillance networks.&nbsp; Commits to partnerships with the governments of Kenya, Uganda, Burkina Faso, and others to build resilient community health systems that can withstand shocks. This includes supporting governments to strengthen digital tools that enable the delivery of health services and ensure pandemic preparedness. Over the next five years, Living Goods commits to supporting 32,000 CHWs and their supervisors to reach 18 million people across five countries with quality care.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://msh.org/"><strong>Management Sciences for Health</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Is costing vaccine delivery to the last mile so that countries, multilateral institutions, and donors can prepare to effectively deliver critical COVID-19 vaccines and achieve the goal of vaccinating the world. This work will help countries better allocate financial resources through evidence-based and sustainable strategies. To date, the organization has supported the vaccination of almost 17 million people across several countries. Management Sciences for Health is committed to Saving Lives Now by continuing to provide access to critical health services, medicines, and other therapeutics across countries, including in fragile and conflict-affected states. The organization continues to focus on strengthening pharmaceutical-sector governance, national public health institutions, regulatory and information systems, infection prevention and control measures, response coordination mechanisms, and emergency supply chains for COVID-19 commodities across governments, the private sector and civil society. Management Sciences for Health is announcing new investments in learning critical lessons from the COVID-19 response by convening a global workshop to examine critical gaps in health security and develop impactful, responsive, and essential recommendations for better pandemic preparedness. MSH is committed to working with country policymakers and government officials to ensure the necessary national policies are in place so that countries are better prepared for future threats through a multihazards approach to pandemic preparedness.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://medaccess.org/"><strong>MedAccess</strong></a>: Commits to provide a $100 million guarantee to accelerate access to COVID-19 vaccines through the COVAX cost-sharing mechanism. The guarantee is part of a $200 million risk sharing facility, with the Open Society Foundations, that will help COVAX respond to country demand for additional doses to meet national vaccination targets.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://mastercardfdn.org/"><strong>Mastercard Foundation</strong></a>: Mastercard Foundation is deploying USD $200 million in partnership with a collaborative of seven African higher education institutions to strengthen the resilience of public health systems in Africa and enabling them to contribute to economic development, and prosperity. To do so, this initiative will train 30,000 front-line health providers and policy shapers and is projected to create 20,000 health sectors jobs; and to enable 2,000 health ventures to improve and expand primary health services and products in the next 10 years.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.merck.com/"><strong>Merck &amp; Co., Inc.</strong></a><strong> (Merck)</strong>:&nbsp; Committed to make two million patient courses of its investigational oral antiviral COVID-19 medicine, LAGEVRIO (molnupiravir), available to USAID at Merck’s best access price to increase access in lower-income countries.&nbsp; This builds on previous efforts, including an agreement with UNICEF to supply up to 3 million courses of LAGEVRIO and voluntary licenses to generic manufacturers and the Medicines Patent Pool facilitating access in over 100 low and middle income countries.&nbsp; Committed to provide $5 million annually in 2022-2024 to support efforts to understand how to build vaccine confidence and reach underserved populations through use of social media.&nbsp; This builds on Merck’s earlier funding to help establish The Vaccine Confidence Fund to support research exploring how online communications can influence offline health behavior and build vaccination confidence, and its related announcement with multi-sector stakeholders of the Alliance for Advancing Health Online.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.nti.org/"><strong>Nuclear Threat Initiative</strong></a><strong> (NTI): </strong>Nuclear Threat Initiative (NTI): Commits to support the Financial Intermediary Fund by using the Global Health Security Index as a tool to inform pandemic preparedness needs—so resources can be allocated to countries most in need and to address the most significant gaps. NTI also commits to contribute $35,000 to the Fund once established—reflecting our view that catalytic funding is needed to guard against current and future biological threats.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.nursingnow.org/"><strong>Nursing Now Challenge</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to engaging its network to build advocacy skillsets for early-career nurses and midwives to deepen their storytelling skills and to launch local, regional and global efforts to vaccinate the world. The NNC network of <a href="https://www.nursingnow.org/immunisation-advocacy-champions/">immunization </a><a href="https://www.nursingnow.org/immunisation-advocacy-champions/">advocacy champions</a> will be led by early-career nurses and midwives. They will lead their own vaccine advocacy campaigns and will deliver their voices to at least three global policy forums and quarterly online events.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.opensocietyfoundations.org/"><strong>Open Society Foundations</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Open Society Foundation’s impact investment arm, the Soros Economic Development Fund (SEDF), commits to provide a $100 million procurement guarantee designed to strengthen COVAX’s capacity to increase the distribution of COVID-19 vaccines to low- and middle-income countries. Together with an additional $100m guarantee from MedAccess, the guarantees would free up an additional $200m in donor funds, and position COVAX to deploy an additional 190 million vaccine dosages to low- and middle-income countries globally in 2022.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="http://www.ospreyfdn.org/"><strong>Osprey Foundation</strong></a>: Committing $4,000,000 to faith-based organizations that can positively influence COVID-19 vaccine access and uptake in sub-Saharan Africa. Commits to increase vaccine demand in several sub-Saharan African countries by supporting faith leaders and their networks to overcome disinformation and address the root causes of vaccine hesitancy for their communities in both digital and non-digital realms. Concurrently, Osprey Foundation will fund faith-based interventions to improve the delivery of COVID-19 vaccines by strengthening the core of last-mile vaccine infrastructure, improving vaccine readiness, and supporting effective vaccine rollout initiatives.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.pandemicactionnetwork.org/"><strong>Pandemic Action Network</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to press governments, multilateral agencies, and donors to galvanize the necessary investments, coordination, and incentives to support delivery of accelerated, robust, and equitable global vaccination plans to achieve equitable global immunization levels. In support of this and all Summit goals, Pandemic Action Network commits to mobilize at least 100 new partners, and Network partners commit to invest at least US$175 million by the end of 2022.&nbsp; Commits to support efforts to drive forward a dynamic global test-to-treat strategy, increase transparency on pricing and supply of tools to fight COVID-19, and advocate to prioritize access to testing, timely reporting, and treatments. The Network also commits to and to create a steady drumbeat of advocacy, coordination, and civic engagement and hold partners accountable for their commitments.&nbsp; In 2022, commits to work with the World Bank, WHO, governments, and other stakeholders to design and launch a dedicated new global fund for pandemic preparedness; mobilize significant new political and financial commitments for the fund; promote cross-country, cross-regional cooperation, and sharing best practices and lessons learned to inform more effective and equitable preparedness and response plans and implementation, to be ready either for the next COVID surge or next potential pandemic.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.path.org/"><strong>PATH</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to supporting COVID vaccination campaigns by providing training, mentorship and supervision to health workers tasked with vaccination and to deploying and scaling digital tools to track vaccination and generate demand through targeted social media campaigns. This includes a $5 million investment to reach an estimated 20 million vaccine-hesitant individuals in two years. Additionally, PATH will support the development of a new affordable COVID-19 vaccine that could be manufactured in Brazil, Thailand and Vietnam.&nbsp; Commits to working with stakeholders to improve oxygen delivery in 10 countries. PATH will work with local partners to build their diagnostics capacities and support the advancement of more affordable and reliable COVID diagnostics in LMICs. PATH will stand up interoperable digital systems in four countries to provide the country governments with the information they need to identify and manage outbreaks vaccination coverage, manage vaccine supplies, and track vaccination records. Commits to leveraging our technical expertise to equip world leaders with the information they need to design a better architecture for global health security. PATH commits to advocating for the funding needed to establish the new global health security and pandemic preparedness fund and holding leaders accountable for other commitments made during the 2nd COVID-19 Summit.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.paxsapiens.org/"><strong>PAX </strong></a><a href="https://www.paxsapiens.org/"><strong><em>sapiens</em></strong></a><strong><em>: </em></strong>Will work with engaged civil society, philanthropic, government, and private sector actors to identify and promote sustainable funding sources for pandemic prevention, new approaches to information sharing, institutional design, and standards for data collection and sharing, and to encourage new donors to support pandemic prevention. PAX’s work will include grantmaking through the previously announced commitment of $200 million, convening and engagement with other organizations, and developing new information for effective prevention.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.perkinelmer.com/"><strong>PerkinElmer</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to saving lives now by making COVID-19 tests available to all low- and middle-income countries for under $5 per test based on volume commitment and supply chain feasibility.&nbsp; PerkinElmer knows that detecting COVID-19 is still a public health challenge in many places and believes this will enable critical access to diagnostics.&nbsp; PerkinElmer remains dedicated to continuing to develop accessible diagnostic solutions to address the global public health challenges created by the COVID-19 pandemic.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.pfizer.com/"><strong>Pfizer Inc.</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Will work to solve concrete challenges to vaccine distribution: working with partners, including UPS, to enable extended use of its shippers to deliver 9.3 million doses to regional vaccination centers in 36 states in Nigeria; expanding its partnership with drone delivery service Zipline to enable transportation of more 380,000 mRNA vaccines on 1,485 drone flights to remote areas; and completing studies to support the extension of transportation time to 48 hours at 2-8 degrees.&nbsp; Pfizer’s COVID-19 oral treatment could significantly change the COVID-19 treatment paradigm, potentially reducing illness severity, hospitalization rates and deaths among a broad population of patients, subject to regulatory authorization or approval. Working with partners such as UNICEF, Pfizer will supply nirmatrelvir [PF-07321332] tablets and ritonavir tablets to countries in need, including emerging economies in Sub-Saharan Africa, Asia, and the Americas. This agreement is part of Pfizer’s comprehensive strategy to work toward worldwide equitable access.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://covid19advocacy.org/"><strong>Platform for ACT-A Civil Society &amp; Community Representatives</strong></a><strong> (co-hosted by WACI Health, Global Fund Advocates Network (GFAN) and STOPAIDS): </strong>Will advocate for support of the TRIPS waiver and sharing of vaccine equipment and doses with COVAX and countries.&nbsp; Will advocate for and coordinate community CSO input on a test and treat strategy.&nbsp; Will mobilise support to fully fund ACT-A, advocating for robust health system perspectives, supporting greater community representation in ACT-A and future mechanisms.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://rabinmartin.com/our-work/private-sector-roundtable-for-global-health-security/#:~:text=What%20is%20the%20PSRT%3F,the%20global%20health%20security%20community."><strong>Private Sector Roundtable on Global Health Security</strong></a><strong> (PSRT): </strong>The Private Sector Roundtable on Global Health Security (PSRT) – a cross-industry coalition of companies committed to leveraging private sector expertise to strengthen health security – commits to expand efforts to build regional/country capacity in pandemic prevention, preparedness and response. We will seek to partner with a regional institution and three low-middle-income countries in that region to provide a suite of tools, trainings and expert guidance over the next three years to Build Better Health Security.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.rotary.org/en"><strong>Rotary International</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to providing access to our public health infrastructure and network built to facilitate polio eradication and provide free health services to vaccinate the world.&nbsp; Rotary Family Health Days and National Immunization Day campaigns are available to accelerate vaccine coverage in multiple regions with at-risk populations in high-risk countries.&nbsp; With Rotary’s 1.4 million members worldwide, and over 55,000 African members, our health infrastructure, and relationships with local and national government health departments remain active. Rotary can quickly mobilize, as strategy, structure, accountability, and funding become available.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.rockefellerfoundation.org/"><strong>The Rockefeller Foundation</strong></a><strong>:</strong> The Rockefeller Foundation’s Global Vaccination Initiative commits USD 55 million to support country-led efforts to fully vaccinate 90% of the most at-risk populations in Africa, Asia, Latin America, and the Caribbean. Funding will support programs to increase vaccine demand – access, trust, and information – while leveraging data from trusted, credible sources to strengthen health systems to meet the needs of the most vulnerable.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.sabin.org/"><strong>Sabin Vaccine Institute</strong></a><strong>:&nbsp; </strong>Commits $9 million through its Global Immunization program in 2022 to better understand and address vaccine delivery, acceptance and demand barriers in LMICs; bolster collaboration among immunization professionals; foster action to address barriers in universal vaccination development; and better apply epidemiology to maximize vaccine rollout effectiveness. Sabin commits to fostering the action of 3,000+ close-to-community professionals delivering vaccinations in LMICs – including health workers, program managers, researchers and journalists.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://seedglobalhealth.org/"><strong>Seed Global Health</strong></a><strong>:&nbsp; </strong>Research estimates that for every $1 allocated to vaccine production, $5 is needed for delivery, with majority cost being associated with health worker training, support, and protection. Establishing integrated health worker networks from the last mile to the facility is critical to enabling access to vaccinations. .&nbsp; Seed Global Health commits to partnering with governments to train and deploy the health workers required to put shots in arms while supporting counter-misinformation campaigns to reduce vaccine hesitancy.&nbsp; Health workers deliver every element of pandemic response and preparedness. Commits to scale our direct work in training and care to sustain essential services to an additional 3 million people; to protect education to strengthen the pipeline of health workers; to respond to emergencies on the frontlines, modeling new methodologies of diagnosis and care; and to align and mobilize the political commitment and resources to support health workers and save more lives. Health workers are the backbone of resilient health systems and pathway to economic recovery and global health security.&nbsp; Commits to mobilize a social contract for health workers, to galvanize action beyond applause. Centered on core principles that provide the evidence-based rationale, framework and accountability, this compact will mobilize and align investments, policies, and programming around long- term country-led planning, to scale-up and protect fit-for-purpose health workforces in service to the world.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.taskforce.org/"><strong>The Task Force for Global Health</strong></a>: Will partner with countries to strengthen immunization programs and field epidemiology training. Through Hepatitis, Polio and Neglected Tropical Diseases programs, we’ll support COVID-19 efforts for the most vulnerable. We’ll distribute <a href="https://taskforce.org/equipping-clinical-care-facilities%e2%80%8b/">medical supplies/equipment</a> and support public health worker mental health and resilience. We’ll convene thought leaders to envision building upon COVID-related investments for sustainable systems. We’ll advance the scientific understanding of rare adverse events after COVID-19 vaccinations, advancing evidence-based decision-making.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.thermofisher.com/us/en/home.html"><strong>Thermo Fisher Scientific</strong></a><strong><u>:</u></strong> In partnership with Afrigen Biologics and Labotec, we are providing cutting-edge technology and personalized capacity building to enable production of the first locally designed and constructed COVID vaccine for Africa. Our support for this WHO-coordinated, end-to-end, sustainable mRNA vaccine production hub includes facility design and bacteria cultivation tools to support DNA plasmid creation, as well as investing in time and expertise to transfer technical knowledge and support so scientists and healthcare leaders can create their own future.&nbsp; As part of our Mission to enable our customers to make the world healthier, cleaner and safer, we have a responsibility to provide access to COVID-19 diagnostic solutions that reach every population, community and individual, regardless of geography or socioeconomic circumstance.&nbsp; We will continue to provide low price, high-quality diagnostic solutions to Governments, United Nations and other global partners because testing is the cornerstone of a continuum of care and treatment of COVID-19 globally. We recognize the importance of building upon lessons learned from the COVID-19 pandemic and will continue to collaborate with Governments, the United Nations and other global partners to create resilient systems to better prevent, detect and respond to the next emerging pathogen.&nbsp; This includes helping to create federated, open pathogen surveillance systems, designing and funding knowledge transfer programs to enable the next generation of scientists in LMICs, and investing in local manufacturing models.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://unfoundation.org/"><strong>United Nations Foundation</strong></a><strong>: </strong>The United Nations Foundation supports Building Better Health Security through encouraging high ambition, sustained attention, and diverse coalitions to strengthen multilateral capacities for preparedness and response. This includes convening and engaging partners to support Geneva-based processes; supporting solutions for incremental financing, including a Financial Intermediary Fund housed at the World Bank; and engaging Member States in New York and capitals to diversify and broaden a high ambition coalition for this agenda.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://about.ups.com/ae/en/social-impact/the-ups-foundation.html"><strong>UPS Foundation</strong></a>: Commits to the pro-bono delivery of COVID-19 vaccines to countries below the average vaccination rate for Africa. In 2022, the UPS Foundation also plans to deliver 2 million doses to Cameroon, up to 3 million to Ethiopia, and up to 4 million to Zambia. The UPS Foundation commits to expanding upon its existing Ghana medical drone network in 2022 to provide the delivery of critically needed supplies and expand access to quality health care. In-country transportation has been committed for 1 million doses to new Zipline drone distribution centers in Nigeria and Kenya. In Malawi, the UPS Foundation is funding in-country drone delivery provided by Swoop Aero and Village Reach with plans to reach 3 million people. In partnership with UNICEF, the UPS Foundation is funding ‘Ultra Cold Vaccine Training’ in Malawi, Nigeria, Ethiopia, and Kenya.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.ups.com/us/en/healthcare/Home.page"><strong>UPS Healthcare</strong></a><strong><u>:</u></strong> Commits to delivering 5.9 million vaccines to Nigeria in addition to the 9.3 million previously delivered. The shipment is funded through UNICEF and USAID, and coordinated with technical expertise from UPS and donated ultra-cold chain equipment. To date, UPS Healthcare has delivered more than 1.4 billion COVD-19 vaccine doses to over 110 countries.</li></ul>



<ul><li> <a href="https://wellcome.org/"><strong>Wellcome Trust</strong></a><strong>: </strong>As a founding partner of the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness and Innovations we committed $150M to CEPI this year, as part of Wellcome’s commitment to spend&nbsp;£16B over the next ten years on science to improve health. This includes funding for Infectious Disease and Pandemic Preparedness, to help buildnetworks to detect outbreaks before they escalate, to trainpublic health professionals and enhance capacity globally, and expand Research and Development of countermeasures.&nbsp; Wellcome also supports mobilising additional funds to prevent future pandemics, and is providing £10 million in seed funding toward establishing the pandemic preparedness and global health security Financial Intermediary Fund at the&nbsp;World Bank, signalling our early philanthropic commitment to working in partnership with others in the fund.&nbsp;We applaud this Summit which comes at a critical moment. We believe these collective commitments will contribute to ensuring equitable health security for all and the world has the knowledge and networks in place to prevent and respond to emerging threats whilst remaining committed to long standing endemic health issues of importance to communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.womeningh.org/"><strong>Women in Global Health</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Commits to advocate for: Equal leadership representation in global health governance, including pandemic decision making and advisory bodies; a new social contract for women health workers with safe, decent and equally paid work.&nbsp; This includes protection from harm and personal protective equipment designed for women’s bodies; and addressing the gender dimensions and impacts of pandemic policies and programmes, using sex disaggregated data.</li></ul>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />



<p><a id="_ftn1" href="#_ftnref1"><sup>[1]</sup></a> All commitments made in 2022 are counted toward the goals of the 2<sup>nd</sup> Global COVID-19 Summit. Of these, approximately $3.1 billion were raised in new funds, not yet announced.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref2" id="_ftn2"><sup>[2]</sup></a> All commitments made in 2022 are counted toward the 2<sup>nd</sup> Global COVID-19 Summit.&nbsp; Of these, approximately $700 million was raised in new funds, not yet announced.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. FACT SHEET: The 2nd Global COVID-⁠19&#160;Summit:</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/u-s-fact-sheet-the-2nd-global-covid-%e2%81%a019-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53024</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Preventing Complacency and Prioritizing Preparedness Today, the United States, Belize, Germany, Indonesia, and Senegal convened other heads of state and world leaders from international organizations, the private sector, philanthropies, non-government organizations, and other partners for the 2nd Global COVID-19 Summit. &#160; The United States issued a call to redouble global efforts to control the COVID-19&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Preventing Complacency and Prioritizing Preparedness</em></p>



<p>Today, the United States, Belize, Germany, Indonesia, and Senegal convened other heads of state and world leaders from international organizations, the private sector, philanthropies, non-government organizations, and other partners for the 2nd Global COVID-19 Summit. &nbsp;<br><br>The United States issued a call to redouble global efforts to control the COVID-19 pandemic and prepare for future health emergencies.&nbsp; The U.S. &nbsp;urged the world to prevent complacency and to keep political will strong. We also called on leaders to accelerate financial and policy commitments – country by country, community by community – to get shots into arms; expand access to tests and treatments; protect those at highest risk; and prevent future catastrophes by building and financing country capacity, health workers, disease surveillance, and medical countermeasures, including through the new health security fund at the World Bank<strong>.</strong></p>



<p><strong>Vice President Harris highlighted U.S. leadership and called on Congress to </strong><strong>continue to make Americans and the world safer by promptly providing the $22.5 billion in supplemental funding for responding to COVID-19 that the Administration requested on March 2, 2022, <u>including $5 billion to support the global effort</u> to stop the spread of potential new variants, get shots into arms, expand access to tests and treatments, and save lives here at home and abroad.</strong></p>



<p>U.S. leadership in vaccinating the world, saving lives, and building better health security</p>



<p>This Summit continues to highlight American leadership in the global COVID-19 response. &nbsp;As the world’s largest donor, the United States has to date provided more than $19 billion in health, humanitarian, and economic assistance and has committed to provide 1.2 billon vaccine doses to the world for free, of which we have already provided more than 535 million doses.</p>



<p>At the Summit, the United States called the world to action alongside co-hosts Belize, Germany, Indonesia, and Senegal. &nbsp;Leaders from around the world made bold new commitments to control COVID-19 and prevent future health crises.&nbsp; The U.S. announced new commitments to the global COVID-19 response and pandemic preparedness, building on substantial U.S. commitments made to date and during the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/22/fact-sheet-president-bidens-global-covid-19-summit-ending-the-pandemic-and-building-back-better/">last global COVID-19 Summit</a>:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Additional funding for a pandemic preparedness [and global health security] fund housed at the World Bank.&nbsp; </strong>Building on its initial commitment of $250 million previously announced at the first Global COVID-19 Summit, the United States intends to increase its initial contribution toward the establishment of the new pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank by an additional $200 million, for a total of $450 million. Combined with funding pledged today by other donors, this funding makes a total of at least $960 million in seed funding in advance of the Fund’s launch this summer.&nbsp; The Fund will provide sustained financing for improving national, regional, and global capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to pandemics and other infectious disease threats.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Sharing U.S. Government COVID-19 vaccine-related intellectual property and research tools for greater global access. </strong>Through the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the United States has recently licensed research tools and the intellectual property for several COVID-19 technologies to the Medicines Patent Pool, through the WHO COVID-19 Technology Access Pool. The licenses include the patent for the stabilized spike protein used in multiple existing COVID-19 vaccines. These licenses will enable manufacturers from around the world to use these technologies.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The United States, through the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA), confirms its commitment to conducting thorough and efficient reviews of COVID-19 response products. While COVID-19 remains a public health emergency, FDA will prioritize the review of COVID-19 therapeutics, including applications seeking tentative approval of generic products.&nbsp; FDA grants tentative approvals for products that meet the requirements for FDA approval but cannot be approved for exclusivity or patent reasons.&nbsp; <strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Test and Treat Strategy</strong>. The United States, alongside the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria (“Global Fund”), Unitaid, and other ACT-Accelerator partners, will promote “test-and-treat” strategies for the most vulnerable populations in low and middle-income countries to help prevent hospitalizations and deaths from COVID-19. The Global Fund will procure up to $80 million in COVID-19 rapid test kits and oral COVID-19 antiviral drugs, which would be linked to $20 million of American Rescue Plan Act funds that the U.S. Agency for International Development plans to use to quickly scale up test-and-treat implementation in up to eight countries globally in 2022, in coordination with other U.S. Government programs, including PEPFAR.&nbsp;It would build on an additional $22 million from Unitaid to produce over $120 million in investments to introduce test and treatment strategies in over 20 countries in 2022. This collaborative early investment would catalyze test-and-treat adoption and expansion in additional countries<strong>. This commitment is a down payment on U.S. leadership that can be fully realized if Congress acts to provide the President’s requested COVID-19 supplemental funding.</strong></li><li><strong>Additional vaccination support through Global VAX.</strong> Building on the more than $1.7 billion in funds committed to date, The United States, through the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), is providing an additional $15 million the U.S. Initiative for Global Vaccine Access (Global VAX), a whole-of-government effort to accelerate and expand vaccine readiness uptake in high-need countries, including 11 surge support countries. This funding will enable CDC to provide additional technical assistance and service delivery to countries for vaccination efforts, with a focus on high-risk populations. This will build upon $1.7 billion the United States is already providing through Global VAX.</li><li><strong>Expanded investments in&nbsp;bilateral global health security programs. &nbsp;</strong>To advance the Global Health Security Agenda and to accelerate the implementation of U.S. Global Health Security Strategy, the U.S. government will expand the number of global health security intensive support partner countries by eight this year, including to three new regions. This will improve countries’ capacities to prevent, detect, and respond to future COVID-19 variants and future health threats.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding dose donation types to include boosters and pediatric doses to accelerate global vaccine coverage</strong>. The United States is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/05/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-hhs-public-health-officials-april-5-2022/">expanding Pfizer vaccine dose types</a> being donated globally to now include boosters and pediatric doses, as part of our 1 billion Pfizer dose donation commitment. This will help accelerate progress towards the 70% vaccination target and expand the availability of doses available for those at highest risk and for children globally.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Improving guidance for vaccine development to enhance protection. </strong>The United States, through the FDA, is committing to help align global health authorities and the WHO to provide advice to COVID-19 vaccine producers to inform which strains they use as the basis for vaccines, using predictions about the predominance of future strains and which strains will lead to vaccines that provide the broadest protection against unknown future variants.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Financing facility for COVID-19 vaccine and ancillary supply purchases and delivery through the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC). </strong>&nbsp;DFC has set up a vehicle to provide up to $1 billion in loan guarantees to Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, to provide bridge financing guaranteeing commitments from other donors. This will allow COVAX to react immediately in a crisis to purchase and deliver ancillary supplies and vaccines on behalf of developing countries participating in the COVAX Advance Market Commitment.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Advancing COVID-19 vaccine research and development through the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI).&nbsp; </strong>At least $50 million of the U.S. Government’s <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/mar-8-2022-usaid-announces-150-million-stimulate-and-accelerate-development">recent $150 million, 3-year pledge to CEPI</a> will support COVID-19 vaccine research in addition to the development of other vaccines and countermeasures for future emerging infectious diseases, with the goals of making vaccines more broadly protective and easier to administer in low-resource settings.</li></ul>



<p>Despite these commitments to combat COVID-19 and enhance future preparedness against health threats<strong>, there is more work to be done to ensure the United States can continue to lead, to make Americans and the world safer.</strong>&nbsp; President Biden continues to urge Congress to act promptly to provide supplemental resources. Without additional emergency funding, the United States will be unable to purchase additional life-saving treatments for the American people.&nbsp; The United States will be less able to stop the spread of possible new variants from around the world.&nbsp; The United States will be unable to keep vaccinating the world against COVID-19 and getting shots into arms, to save lives here at home and abroad.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden and President von der Leyen on occasion of the second Global COVID-&#8288;19 Summit, May 12,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/statement-from-president-biden-and-president-von-der-leyen-on-occasion-of-the-second-global-covid-19-summit-may-12-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53019</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States of America and the European Union are implementing the U.S.-EU Agenda for Beating the Global Pandemic, Vaccinating the World, Saving Lives Now and Building Back Better Health Security of September 22, 2021. Today, Presidents Biden and von der Leyen reaffirmed milestones in their strong cooperation towards the five headline goals of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States of America and the European Union are implementing the <strong>U.S.-EU Agenda for Beating the Global Pandemic, Vaccinating the World, Saving Lives Now and Building Back Better Health Security </strong>of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/22/a-u-s-eu-agenda-for-beating-the-global-pandemic-vaccinating-the-world-saving-lives-now-and-building-back-better-health-security/">September 22, 2021</a>. Today, Presidents Biden and von der Leyen reaffirmed milestones in their strong cooperation towards the five headline goals of the Agenda, and they previewed further joint action below:</p>



<p><strong><em>Vaccine equity and ‘shots-in-arms’. </em></strong>Having shared a combined total of more than one billion COVID-19 vaccine doses, and in line with a commitment to share a total of 1.9 billion doses around the world, the EU and U.S. seek to ensure ongoing <strong>deliveries are based on country demand, informed by best practices and reach ‘tarmac to arms’</strong>, with focus on sub-Saharan Africa. Through support from Team Europe and U.S. Global VAX programs, both sides recognise that vaccine equity starts with best practice donation principles including adequate and transparent planning in <strong>cooperation with governments, in-country partners, COVAX (as part of ACT-A), Africa Vaccine Acquisition Task Team (AVATT), World Health Organization (WHO), the COVID- 19 Vaccine Delivery Partnership (CoVDP), </strong>and others. Given that dose supply is currently not constrained, the partnership should pay particular attention to enhancing vaccine readiness, strengthening logistics, combating hesitancy, and building longer-term capacity by means of health systems strengthening, and immediate capability for vaccine uptake as part of the global COVID-19 Vaccine Delivery Partnership. To strengthen our partnership, the U.S. and EU will actively consult with partners including AVATT, CoVDP, and COVAX on strategies to accelerate vaccine absorption. The U.S. and EU will strengthen dialogues with multilateral development banks and global partners aiming towards better uptake of and sustainable financing for in-country vaccination operations.<br><br></p>



<p><strong><em>Strengthening global supply chains and manufacturing. </em></strong>The need to ensure vaccine and therapeutic dose supply and administration in the face of supply chain constraints led to the <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/STATEMENT_21_4847">launch</a> of the joint <strong>EU-U.S. COVID-19 manufacturing and supply chain task force </strong>in September 2021. The leaders expect that the task force will extend its activities to provide <strong>early warning of supply chain bottlenecks </strong>that could hamper global availability of vaccines and treatments, and to coordinate efforts to sustain vaccine and therapeutics production capabilities for variants and future pandemics, including in Africa.<br><br></p>



<p><strong><em>Enhanced EU-US coordination to improve global health security architecture. </em></strong>Enhancing pandemic prevention, preparedness and response (PPR) capacities requires strong international cooperation, and the U.S. and the EU are committed to cooperate to this end, including under the lines of effort of the COVID-19 Prioritized Global Action Plan for Enhanced Engagement (GAP). Enhanced PPR requires a strengthening of the global health architecture, including of the WHO at the center, and sustainable financing. Presidents Biden and von der Leyen welcomed the support of the G20 under Indonesia’s leadership, and committed to cooperate on the establishment of a new <strong>Financial Intermediary Fund (FIF) for pandemic preparedness and global health security </strong>at the World Bank, including its <strong>sustainable capitalization</strong>, governance and structure. The U.S. and EU committed to support the early design and implementation of the FIF. The leaders will also cooperate towards the conclusion of a convention, agreement or other international instrument on pandemic prevention, preparedness and response at the WHO, and targeted amendments to the International Health Regulations, in order to <strong>strengthen the global rulebook for pandemic PPR</strong>. The EU and the U.S. are working together with <strong>expert dialogue </strong>to forge consensus on targeted IHR amendments and the content of a pandemic instrument. They also recognise the importance of engagement with other partners to take forward both sustainable financing for PPR and a strengthened WHO.<br><br></p>



<p><strong><em>Preparing for the future, pathogen detection and monitoring, joint threat assessment and response. </em></strong>The EU and U.S. will collaborate to improve pathogen monitoring and threat assessment, leveraging existing and novel approaches, providing integrated surveillance, real-time monitoring, early warning systems, forecasting and analytics, intelligence exchange, supporting rapid response networks, and an ‘always-ready’ health emergency workforce to prevent or mitigate cross-border outbreaks, all within a One Health approach.</p>



<p><strong><em>Research and development for new vaccines, therapeutics and diagnostics. </em></strong>Acknowledging the importance of swiftly reacting to pandemics, the U.S. and EU support science to shorten the cycle for the development of safe and effective vaccines, therapeutics and diagnostics from 300 to 100 days following the identification of such threats and work to make them widely available. In the near term, the EU and U.S. committed to deepen <strong>cooperation to identify and evaluate variant adapted, more broadly protective, and next generation vaccines, therapeutics and diagnostics, while ensuring their safety and efficacy</strong>. The U.S. and the EU will work towards aligning R&amp;D investments with manufacturing and manufacturing capabilities development, and will conclude a formal administrative arrangement on preparedness and response for public health threats to be signed this month between the European Commission Health Emergency and Preparedness Response Authority (HERA) and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Remembering the 1,000,000 Americans Lost to&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/12/a-proclamation-on-remembering-the-1000000-americans-lost-to-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we mark a tragic milestone: &#160;one million American lives lost to COVID-19. &#160;One million empty chairs around the dinner table. &#160;Each an irreplaceable loss. &#160;Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a Nation forever changed because of this pandemic. &#160;Jill and I pray for each of them. As a Nation, we must not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we mark a tragic milestone: &nbsp;one million American lives lost to COVID-19. &nbsp;One million empty chairs around the dinner table. &nbsp;Each an irreplaceable loss. &nbsp;Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a Nation forever changed because of this pandemic. &nbsp;Jill and I pray for each of them.</p>



<p>As a Nation, we must not grow numb to such sorrow. &nbsp;To heal, we must remember. &nbsp;We must remain vigilant against this pandemic and do everything we can to save as many lives as possible. &nbsp;In remembrance, let us draw strength from each other as fellow Americans. &nbsp;For while we have been humbled, we never give up.&nbsp; We can and will do this together as the United States of America.</p>



<p>In memory of the one million American lives lost to COVID-19 and their loved ones left behind, I hereby order, by the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States, that the flag of the United States shall be flown at half-staff at the White House and on all public buildings and grounds, at all military posts and naval stations, and on all naval vessels of the Federal Government in the District of Columbia and throughout the United States and its Territories and possessions until sunset May 16, 2022.  I also direct that the flag shall be flown at half-staff for the same period at all United States embassies, legations, consular offices, and other facilities abroad, including all military facilities and naval vessels and stations.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twelfth day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden Marking One Million American Lives Lost to&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/statement-from-president-joe-biden-marking-one-million-american-lives-lost-to-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we mark a tragic milestone: one million American lives lost to COVID-19. One million empty chairs around the dinner table. Each an irreplaceable loss. Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a nation forever changed because of this pandemic. Jill and I pray for each of them. To those who are grieving, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we mark a tragic milestone: one million American lives lost to COVID-19. One million empty chairs around the dinner table. Each an irreplaceable loss. Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a nation forever changed because of this pandemic. Jill and I pray for each of them.</p>



<p>To those who are grieving, and asking yourself how will you go on without him or what will you do without her, I understand. I know the pain of that black hole in your heart. It is unrelenting. But I also know the ones you love are never truly gone. They will always be with you.</p>



<p>As a nation, we must not grow numb to such sorrow. To heal, we must remember. We must remain vigilant against this pandemic and do everything we can to save as many lives as possible, as we have with more testing, vaccines, and treatments than ever before. It’s critical that Congress sustain these resources in the coming months. &nbsp;</p>



<p>In remembrance, let us draw strength from each other as fellow Americans. For while we have been humbled, we never give up.&nbsp;We can and will do this together as the United States of America.</p>



<p>May God bless the one million American lives lost and their loved ones left behind.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Democratic National Committee&#160;Fundraiser</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-democratic-national-committee-fundraiser-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 03:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Marriott Marquis ChicagoChicago, Illinois 5:39 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you, Gov.&#160; Gov, you’ve been a great friend and a great partner on COVID, the economy, and so much more.&#160;&#160; And like most everybody in this room who is involved in public life, I remember them that was there first.&#160; Thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Marriott Marquis Chicago<br>Chicago, Illinois</p>



<p>5:39 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, Gov.&nbsp; Gov, you’ve been a great friend and a great partner on COVID, the economy, and so much more.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And like most everybody in this room who is involved in public life, I remember them that was there first.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; You made a big difference in my being able to stand here as President of the United States.&nbsp; Many of you in this audience did as well.&nbsp;<br><br>I know you&#8217;ve been here a long time, so I&#8217;m not going to make a long, formal speech to you.&nbsp;<br><br>But look, you know, I want to thank Jaime Harrison for his leadership.&nbsp; And, you know, if things were working okay until we got to South Carolina in the primary, then we won every single county.&nbsp; So thank you, Jaime.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank all of you for the support and generosity.&nbsp; I can go around the room and at least 15 of you were deeply involved with my campaign &#8212; and even before the campaign, in my career.&nbsp; So thank you for all you&#8217;ve done.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Look, you know, I&#8217;m proud of the progress we&#8217;ve made.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot more to do, but I&#8217;m proud of the progress we&#8217;ve made.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve talked about how &#8212; you know, people say, “Well, you know, Biden won.”&nbsp; Well, it was a fairly low bar to get over because of the nature of how much the last guy changed American politics.&nbsp; He changed it in a way that made it more petty.&nbsp;<br><br>When I ran &#8212; you may remember &#8212; no reason why you should, but I remember I said, “I&#8217;m running to restore the soul of America; to rebuild the backbone of the country, the middle class of America; and to try to unite the country because democracies can&#8217;t function very well unless we can arrive at consensus.”&nbsp;<br><br>I also said at the time, and I&#8217;ve been saying since then, that we&#8217;re really in a battle worldwide between democracies and oligarchies.&nbsp; The fact of the matter is, I&#8217;ve spent a lot of time with Xi Jinping &#8212; they tell me more than any other world leader has.&nbsp; When he was vice president and I was vice president, I traveled 17,000 miles with him.&nbsp; Spent a lot of time since he&#8217;s been &#8212; since I got elected President talking to him.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s a very bright guy, but very &#8212; he doesn’t have a democratic &#8212; with a small “d” &#8212; bone in his body.&nbsp;<br><br>But he knows exactly what he wants.&nbsp; He knows exactly what he&#8217;s trying to do.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s very straightforward.&nbsp; He makes the point that, at this inflection point in history, world history &#8212; and it comes about every four or five generations &#8212; this fundamental change that takes place not because of any one particular leader, but because the nature of the change occurring in the world, whether it&#8217;s technology or anything else.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And he thinks that democracies require consensus, they can&#8217;t operate quickly enough in this changing world.<br><br>Your children are going to see more change in the next 10 years than we&#8217;ve seen in the last 50 years &#8212; the last 100 years, possibly &#8212; in the world and in the United States.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s a lot at stake &#8212; a whole lot at stake.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I believe &#8212; and I come at this with an enormous sense of optimism.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s any nation in the world that’s better prepared to deal with the changing world than the United States of America.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re the only nation in the world that has come out of every crisis stronger than we went into it.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; Every crisis we&#8217;ve ever encountered &#8212; war, famine, whatever it was &#8212; we&#8217;ve come out stronger than when we went in.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been my objective, because I believe the American public and the world is ready.&nbsp;<br><br>When I was first elected, I attended my first meeting of the G7 &#8212; the democracies in Europe and a few in Asia &#8212; in England.&nbsp; And I sat down and I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And they looked at me &#8212; two of them, I will not, because it was &#8212; they were private meetings &#8212; not say who said it &#8212; but two of the world leaders looked at me and said, “But for how long?”&nbsp; “But for how long?”&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things I think we &#8212; we sort of underestimate is that imagine what we&#8217;d be thinking if tomorrow we went back and the news on television showed a group of hundreds of people &#8212; not at war &#8212; breaking down the doors of the British Parliament, killing two or three of the people who work there &#8212; guards there &#8212; and doing what was done on the 6th of &#8212; the 6th of January.&nbsp; Imagine what we’d think.&nbsp;<br><br>We are the democracy of the world.&nbsp; And it really is true.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not &#8212; that it&#8217;s not chauvinism about America.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just a fact.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things I realized that &#8212; Senator Braun and I worked a long time together.&nbsp; One of the things I realized, Carol, was that I knew that we were the essential nation as &#8212; as the former Secretary of State, who we just buried, would say &#8212; but I didn&#8217;t fully appreciate it until I became President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about Joe Biden; it’s about the office of the presidency.&nbsp;<br><br>The rest of the world looks to us.&nbsp; They expect us to lead.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; We are the essential nation.&nbsp; We are the essential nation.&nbsp;<br><br>And that gives us so many incredible opportunities if we&#8217;re not afraid to take them and move them, and take on this new sort of petty, mean-spirited notion that has guided the other team.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s still a lot of good Republicans in the Senate.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s amazing to me how they&#8217;re cowered by Trump and how he has such concern.<br><br>I&#8217;ve had &#8212; I, obviously, will never name them, but I have &#8212; six of them have told me &#8212; senators I used to serve with; we served with; some of them you served with, Carol &#8212; said that, “You know, I agree with you on such and such a thing.&nbsp; But if I vote for it, they&#8217;ll primary and I&#8217;ll lose my seat.”&nbsp; Doesn&#8217;t go to political courage, but it goes to the recognition that there still are a lot of Republicans who want to get things done.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But we have to take on the &#8212; MAGA Republicans &#8212; “Make America Great Again” Republicans.&nbsp; I think they&#8217;re the most extreme party.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the Republican Party is now.&nbsp; Not everybody Republican believes that.&nbsp; But the fact of the matter is, they run the show &#8212; the MAGA Republicans,<br><br>The idea that they do the things that they’re doing now, and the things that they’re saying &#8212; I think if we had sat down here five years ago, seven years ago, eight years ago, and said this was going to happen, you’d all look at me &#8212; and I would have thought myself &#8212; nuts saying some of the things that they’re saying.&nbsp; But it really is beyond the pale.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, one of the things that I think we have to do is not just talk about what we&#8217;ve done &#8212; and we don&#8217;t do that enough, and that&#8217;s my fault.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I remember, with Barack, when we passed the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; I said, “Barack, you ought to take a victory lap.”&nbsp; And I remember what he said to me.&nbsp; He said, “We don&#8217;t have time, Joe.&nbsp; There&#8217;s too much to do.”&nbsp; Everything but locusts has landed on his desk.&nbsp; Locusts landed on my desk.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>But really, think about what we&#8217;ve done so far.&nbsp; You know, if you just do it in terms of just practical &#8212; practical application of what has usually been the mid- &#8212; the measures by which people measure whether or not an administration is functioning, we&#8217;re in a situation where we&#8217;ve gone from 2 million people with vaccinations when we took over office to 220 million fully vaccinated.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gone from jobs &#8212; a jobs report to 428,000 jobs last month, 8.3 million jobs my first 15 months in office &#8212; more than any President has in American history.&nbsp; Well, it’s not about me.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, but it really isn’t about me.&nbsp; What it&#8217;s about is that &#8212; you know, the Republicans say that, well, the things we did with the Recov- &#8212; with the legislation we passed is causing inflation.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Well guess what?&nbsp; The first year in office, we&#8217;ve reduced the deficit by $350 billion.&nbsp; In fact &#8212; $350 billion &#8212; reduced the deficit.&nbsp; And this year, we&#8217;re on track, in the next two months, to reduce the deficit by 1 trillion 500 billion dollars.&nbsp; Never happened before in American history.&nbsp;<br><br>But look, the biggest investments that have ever been made &#8212; and the governor talks about it and does it really well on what he’s &#8212; and how he uses the funding &#8212; is in infrastructure.&nbsp; One&nbsp;<s>billion</s>&nbsp;[trillion] two hundred&nbsp;<s>million</s>[billion] dollars in infrastructure.<br><br>We used to have the number-one infrastructure in the world &#8212; the world.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what drove our growth.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what drove our prosperity.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what moved us.&nbsp; We&#8217;re now number 14 in the world &#8212; the United States of America.&nbsp; China is now number two.<br><br>And look, the idea that we&#8217;ve sat around and haven’t moved until now &#8212; but now, we &#8212; there’s, you know, 6,000 &#8212; 60,000 miles of road in your state that we&#8217;re going to be able to take care of.&nbsp; No, I mean it.&nbsp; I know you know it.&nbsp; You know it better than anybody.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s a whole range of &#8212;<br><br>(Cellphone rings.)<br><br>I know that’s Trump calling.&nbsp; He always does this when I talk.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But &#8212; but all kidding aside, what we&#8217;re doing here is that we’ve made the biggest investments in infrastructure; historic investments in solar, wind, and battery technology &#8212; notwithstanding the fact that we still need one vote to get the $508 billion that is still left in my legislation that we thought we were going to get passed.&nbsp; We were one vote short, but we&#8217;re going to get it done.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to get it done.&nbsp;<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal: The historic investments are one thing, but, you know, one of the things I&#8217;ve tried to do when I got elected &#8212; and because I talked with many of you about this in detail beforehand &#8212; I said I&#8217;d have administration that looked like America &#8212; an administration that looked like America.&nbsp;<br><br>We have the most diverse administration in American history by a longshot &#8212; by a longshot.&nbsp; Over half our major appointees &#8212; both Senate confirmed as well as appointed &#8212; are women.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re in a situation where we have a significant number of all minorities that are &#8212; look, I mean, we&#8217;ve appointed more &#8212; more circuit court of appeals judges who are Black women than every other President in American history.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we have a &#8212; we have an associate justice about to go on the Court, God willing, who is brilliant.&nbsp; But I tell you, she&#8217;s going to be the first &#8212; I made a commitment there’d be the first Black woman on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; And it matters.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I think because &#8212; because of how outrageous some of the things that former President Trump has done and said, I think we found ourselves at a position where it was almost like, “How could that happen?&nbsp; How can that be?”&nbsp; And I think, in a sense &#8212; until we got elected and we changed presidents, I think people started to lose faith in the capacity of the American government to deliver &#8212; to deliver, to make life better for people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We have so many opportunities available to us.&nbsp; So many opportunities.&nbsp;<br><br>We have to remember that we&#8217;re talking about a relatively small number of people who are the MAGA Republicans.&nbsp; We may be talking about as much as one third of the electorate.&nbsp; That&#8217;s more than I&#8217;d ever thought would occur.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But we got to take the fight to them.&nbsp; We got to make our case and make it very strongly, in my opinion.&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, we have a strong record to run on.&nbsp; The economy is &#8212; our economy is one of those that we believe is from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; Because when the middle class does well, everybody does just fine.&nbsp; The wealthy do very well.&nbsp; The poor have a road up.&nbsp; And the middle class has built the country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s who&#8217;s built the country.&nbsp;<br><br>We find ourselves protecting and expanding civil rights.&nbsp; Well, we got to speak out more.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to make sure that we make our case and keep repeatedly making our case.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we have to have &#8212; you know, reasserting America&#8217;s leadership in the world, because we are.&nbsp;<br><br>Look at &#8212; I’ll bet you &#8212; I can tell you that there are &#8212; a vast majority of the foreign policy establishment and military establishment are surprised at how incompetent the Russians have been so far &#8212; looking at how they’ve conducted themselves.&nbsp; And yet, we &#8212; we tended to think they were 10 feet tall &#8212; many folks.&nbsp;<br><br>It doesn&#8217;t mean we won’t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to put a single American troop in Ukraine.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to make sure Ukraine has what they need to be able to defend themselves.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal: The point is that I think we have to start looking at the world as it really is.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard me say before, I think we&#8217;re &#8212; you know, about every &#8212; anywhere from three to five generations, we reach an inflection point of world history where things began to change, whether it&#8217;s because of technology, the environment, or changes in the relationship amongst nations.&nbsp; They change in a big way.&nbsp; And we have to be in a position to understand that we have the capacity to try to make sure that in this inflection point, we know what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;<br><br>And we have an opportunity to increase &#8212; increase not to decrease &#8212; the whole notion of equity in the world, the whole notion of how we look at one another, the whole notion of &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>For example, you know, Putin is in a situation &#8212; and my last discussion with him was a while ago &#8212; was, you know, his &#8212; the tundra in the Arctic in Russia is burning, burning, burning.&nbsp; No, I mean, literally burning&nbsp; &#8212; leaking methane, which is so much more dangerous than any other thing that can affect the environment.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not going to &#8212; it&#8217;s not&#8211; it&#8217;s not going to freeze again.&nbsp;<br><br>So, there&#8217;s so many things that have to be dealt with, but they present enormous opportunities if we are &#8212; and gather ourselves together and figure out who &#8212; remind ourselves of who we are and what we want to do.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And look, the other thing I&#8217;d say is that, you know, the whole idea &#8212; if this draft opinion in the Supreme Court turns out to be the opinion of the Supreme Court, it is everything that some of us talked about before.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You may remember I led the fight to defeat Robert Bork’s nomination as Associate Justice of the Supreme Court, because I was convinced &#8212;<br><br>When we started off that nominating hearing, I said &#8212; because I&#8217;d read everything he had ever written and every decision he’d ever written &#8212; and he was a bright &#8212; he was a brilliant guy.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I said to him &#8212; I said, “Judge…” &#8212; he had been a judge.&nbsp; And I said, “Judge, let me describe to you what I think your constitutional philosophy is and mine, and you tell me whether we &#8212; whether we differ, whether I accurately am portraying it.”&nbsp;<br><br>And I said, “Judge, you believe that the Constitution &#8212; the Ninth Amendment is an inkblot in the Constitution and, secondly, that there is no such thing as a right to privacy in the Constitution.&nbsp; And you believe the rights you possess are because the government gave them to you.&nbsp; They gave them to you.&nbsp; I believe the rights I possess are because I&#8217;m a child of God, because I just exist.&nbsp; And I, by implication, gave up some of those rights to the government for purposes of making society function.”&nbsp; And I went on from there.&nbsp; And he said, “I agree, it&#8217;s exactly the difference.”&nbsp;<br><br>Well, look, what we&#8217;re talking about here.&nbsp; It’s not only the brutality of taking away a woman&#8217;s right to control her own body and all the damage that does physically, psychologically, practically.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But it also, if you read the opinion &#8212; if it turns out to be the same opinion &#8212; basically says there is no such thing as a right to privacy.&nbsp; Mark my words: If that decision holds, it&#8217;s not only we&#8217;re going to be fighting for a woman&#8217;s right to control her own body and the brutality that goes along with having to give birth in a circumstance that is something beyond what &#8212; that can be tolerated, but what else is going to happen?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Mark my words: They&#8217;re going to go after the right of the &#8212; Supreme Court decision on the right of same-sex marriage.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to go after &#8212; they&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be back to Griswold vs. Connecticut, where there was a time in Connecticut law where it said a married couple, in the privacy of their own bedroom, cannot use contraception; it was a decision &#8212; the government can make the decision you can&#8217;t do that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;re going to see these decisions up for grabs and further split the United States.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be arguing about things we shouldn&#8217;t have to argue about.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think it&#8217;s important that as we go forward &#8212; and you&#8217;re going to hear me talking more about not only what we&#8217;ve done, but what they&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, if you take a look at what the leader &#8212; their &#8212; the head of their campaign committee, the distinguished senator from &#8212; Republican senator from Florida &#8212; he talks about that what he has in mind is that they&#8217;re going to &#8212; he&#8217;s laid out the only plan put forward in the last years, what the Republican Party stands for, what they&#8217;re going to run on.&nbsp;<br><br>And what they say is &#8212; it&#8217;s really quite basic.&nbsp; They&#8217;re making the point that what happens is that what they&#8217;re going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re going to increase taxes on 90 percent of the American public, people making a &#8212; excuse me, 70 percent of the American public &#8212; people making under $100,000 a year are going to have tax, because the notion is everybody should pay something.&nbsp; Even a family that&#8217;s raising three kids, in fact is making 25-, 30,000 bucks a year, they should be paying federal taxes.&nbsp; Nothing for people who can afford to pay more.&nbsp;<br><br>Secondly, there is a provision in the bill they put forward &#8212; the law they&#8217;re proposing &#8212; that every five years, Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid will be on the chopping block, that Congress will have to affirmatively again vote to put them into the law.&nbsp; Otherwise, they will &#8212; it goes out of the law.&nbsp;<br><br>And you know what they&#8217;re going to do, those of you hold public office.&nbsp; If that were ever to pass and they were to take control, what they&#8217;re going to do is they&#8217;ll use that as a bargaining chip.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll say, “Unless you vote for such and such, unless you end your attempt to try to force environmental regulations in place, we&#8217;re going to cut the following elements of one of those programs.”&nbsp;<br><br>The idea that &#8212; and it&#8217;s in writing &#8212; that every five years you&#8217;d have to reauthorize Social Security, which you&#8217;ve paid into your whole life &#8212; have to reauthorize that?&nbsp; I won&#8217;t go through it all, and I&#8217;m going &#8212; taking too much of your time.&nbsp; But is really a genuinely radical agenda.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think we have to point out how radical it is &#8212; how radical it is &#8212; so people are reminded what&#8217;s at stake here, not only internationally, but domestically, in terms of people&#8217;s basic fundamental rights, in terms of education.<br><br>Did you ever think we&#8217;d be in a position in the year 2022 &#8212; we&#8217;d be talking about banning books in schools?&nbsp; I mean, you know, the idea that you cannot mention &#8212; you cannot mention to the school.&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to happen to a gay child, an L[G]BTQ child in school?&nbsp; I mean, this thing &#8212; it’s one thing to take on Disney World.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to storm Cinderella&#8217;s castle before this is over.&nbsp;<br><br>But I mean it.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; If I told you these things, I think you&#8217;d think I was crazy.&nbsp; You may think I&#8217;m crazy anyway, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but &#8212;<br><br>So, folks, we got a lot of work to do.&nbsp; We got a lot of work.&nbsp; I think we can pick up three Senate seats.&nbsp; And I think we can increase our majority in the House, but we have to do it by more than just a couple of votes.&nbsp; We have to do it by more than a couple of votes, because it&#8217;s getting much too close.&nbsp;<br><br>If, in fact, they were to win back the House and/or the Senate, we got a different world we&#8217;re in.&nbsp; We got a different world we&#8217;re in.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, again, I&#8217;m taking too much of your time.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s why what you&#8217;re doing is so damn important.&nbsp; It really makes a difference.&nbsp; It makes a gigantic difference.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we&#8217;re going to be hopefully having the DNC spend a lot more time and, quite frankly, money making the larger generic case.&nbsp; And we can do it honestly, without having to exaggerate or make up things that are not on the docket.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I want to thank you all so very, very much for the time and the effort.&nbsp; And I realize your time is even more valuable than your contribution because you all are people of consequence who are &#8212; have a lot you have to do.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, the &#8212; we have to make sure we keep this clear contrast on either side.&nbsp; This is &#8212; as I said, this is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.&nbsp; This is a different breed of cat.&nbsp; I mean, all kidding aside, it really is.&nbsp; It really is.<br><br>There&#8217;s some really decent Republicans in the House and the Senate, but they&#8217;re so overwhelmed and intimidated.&nbsp; And some of them are just leaving.&nbsp; They’re giving up their seats and just moving &#8212; moving out of public life.<br><br>And, you know, if the Court follows this leaked opinion, it has the potential to generate significant enthusiasm to get out and vote, but it also has an enormous potential if &#8212; if we fail, what that will mean &#8212; what that will mean.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, folks, we &#8212; these guys are doing everything &#8212; I got involved in politics &#8212; I’ll end with this &#8212; because of civil rights.&nbsp; I come from a state that has the eighth-largest Black population in America as a percent of population: Delaware.&nbsp; We have &#8212; we&#8217;re the eighth-largest population.&nbsp;<br><br>As a matter of fact, we were one of those border states in the Civil War.&nbsp; We were a slave state, to our shame, like Maryland and &#8212; anyway.<br><br>And &#8212; and so it is &#8212; that&#8217;s what got me involved.&nbsp; I used to &#8212; we moved from Wilmington &#8212; from, excuse me, Scranton, Pennsylvania, where there were very few African Americans, down to Wilmington, to a place called Claymont, Delaware, which was a &#8212; it sits on the border of the Pennsylvania state line, where there are more oil companies and refineries than in Houston, Texas.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I went to a little Catholic school called Holy Rosary, which is &#8212; I was in third grade.&nbsp; And it was up what they call a Philadelphia pike, a four-lane access road.&nbsp; It was &#8212; where it went through the little town of Claymont.&nbsp; It was &#8212; I-95 is.&nbsp; It replaced it, in effect.&nbsp;<br><br>And I remember asking my mother &#8212; it was too dangerous to walk up because of the streets you had to cross.&nbsp; So my mother would drive me from this apartment complex we moved into.<br><br>And I remember, dropped off in the parking lot, I’d always see this bus go by.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re all Black kids in the bus.&nbsp; At the time, they weren&#8217;t called “Black kids”; there were “negroes” on the bus.&nbsp;<br><br>And I asked why.&nbsp; She told me they weren&#8217;t allowed to go to school &#8212; and this was before Brown vs. the Board in Delaware, which &#8212; and we were one of the cases &#8212; Delaware was &#8212; in Brown vs. the Board.&nbsp; And I thought to myself, “What&#8217;s going on?”<br><br>But the point is that &#8212; think about it.&nbsp; Think about it: where we are today, what we&#8217;re fighting over.&nbsp; There are more restrictive efforts to restrict the right to vote today than there’d been in my whole political career.&nbsp; I thought we were well by that.&nbsp;<br><br>I was chairman of the Judiciary Committee of the United States Senate, and I was able to extend the Voting Rights Act for 25 years.&nbsp; I got Strom Thurmond to vote to extend it.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;<br><br>And I thought, “Well, my God, we can do it.&nbsp; We can defeat hate.”&nbsp; But I made a big mistake, a lesson I learned: Hate never goes away; it just hides.&nbsp; It hides under the rocks.&nbsp; And when somebody breathes oxygen under those rocks, it comes out in ways that we never thought it would &#8212; I never thought I&#8217;d see again.&nbsp;<br><br>And look where we are now.&nbsp; Look at all the states that have changed the means by which people can vote, letting the states decide whether or not the vote counts, count the vote.&nbsp; I mean, come on.&nbsp; What in God&#8217;s name is going on?<br><br>So, there&#8217;s so much at stake.&nbsp; I&#8217;m convinced we will succeed if we make our case.&nbsp; I&#8217;m convinced that we will be able to do this.&nbsp; But we also have to understand that if we miss, what&#8217;s at stake?<br><br>A distinguished senator from your neighboring state of Wisconsin, Ron Johnson &#8212; he&#8217;s made it very clear.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going after &#8212; repeal the Affordable Care Act again.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve expanded it so people are saving 2,400 bucks a year on their &#8212; on their healthcare costs.&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, we&#8217;re going to need to control the House and the Senate.&nbsp; And we need your support to reach out to those registered voters and convince them that it&#8217;s worth their effort, that it matters.&nbsp; It matters to us a great deal.&nbsp; It matters to them.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think that &#8212; it sounds a little melodramatic, but I can say this to a sophisticated audience involved in politics, as you all are.&nbsp; I really do think we&#8217;re still in the battle for the soul of America.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;<br><br>I wasn&#8217;t going to run again, as Billy Brodsky knows.&nbsp; We went to school together.&nbsp; I really wasn&#8217;t.&nbsp; I was a professor at the University of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; I was enjoying it.&nbsp;<br><br>But when those folks came marching out of the fields in Charlottesville, Virginia, carrying torches &#8212; torches, chanting the same anti-Semitic bile &#8212; the same anti-Semitic bile chanted in the streets of everywhere from Nuremberg to Berlin in the early ‘30s &#8212; exact language, by the way.&nbsp; Go check it out.&nbsp; Carrying swastikas, accompanied by the Ku Klux Klan.&nbsp; And a young woman was killed in the process.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And the then-President of the United States was asked &#8212; was asked the question, “What do you think?”&nbsp; He said there are very good people on both sides.<br><br>We can&#8217;t let this happen, guys.&nbsp; So, we have to &#8212; we have to &#8212; and it&#8217;s going to be hard.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be hard, because inflation is going to scare the living hell out of everybody.&nbsp;<br><br>I was raised in a family where when gas prices went up significantly and food went up, it was &#8212; it mattered to my family.&nbsp; It mattered.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re making progress, but there’s going to be a way to go.&nbsp; Our inflation rate is lower than almost any other nation &#8212; industrial nation in the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a situation where we find ourselves with supply chain problems and Putin&#8217;s gas tax in the extreme.&nbsp;<br><br>But we have a problem we have to deal with.&nbsp; In the meantime, we can&#8217;t take our eye off all that could happen if we do not prevail.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I&#8217;m counting on you all.&nbsp; I really mean it. &nbsp;And the DNC is going to have to play an increasingly important role in how we get this done.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I apologize for going on so long, but thank you very much for listening.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>6:09 P.M. CDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Philippine President-Elect Ferdinand Marcos&#160;Jr.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-philippine-president-elect-ferdinand-marcos-jr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 02:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President-elect Ferdinand Marcos Jr. of the Philippines to congratulate him on his election. President Biden underscored that he looks forward to working with the President-elect to continue strengthening the U.S.-Philippine Alliance, while expanding bilateral cooperation on a wide range of issues, including the fight against COVID-19, addressing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President-elect Ferdinand Marcos Jr. of the Philippines to congratulate him on his election. President Biden underscored that he looks forward to working with the President-elect to continue strengthening the U.S.-Philippine Alliance, while expanding bilateral cooperation on a wide range of issues, including the fight against COVID-19, addressing the climate crisis, promoting broad-based economic growth, and respect for human rights.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers 40th Annual&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-international-brotherhood-of-electrical-workers-40th-annual-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 01:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[McCormick Place Convention CenterChicago, Illinois 4:10 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hell, hello, hello!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; I want to start off by saying two things.&#160; Number one, the only reason I&#8217;m standing here as your President of the United States of America is because of the IBEW came on with me&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">McCormick Place Convention Center<br>Chicago, Illinois</p>



<p>4:10 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hell, hello, hello!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; I want to start off by saying two things.&nbsp; Number one, the only reason I&#8217;m standing here as your President of the United States of America is because of the IBEW came on with me early.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And secondly, is Delaware in the house?&nbsp; Anybody from Delaware?&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Holler loudly, man, because I want to see you after this is over.<br><br>Folks, please sit down.&nbsp; Please sit down.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, Lonnie, I want to thank you.&nbsp; You’re a de- &#8212; a dear friend and one of the great leaders of labor of our time.&nbsp; I mean that.&nbsp; You’ve been there every time.<br><br>And I also want to thank the IBEW’s Kenneth Cooper, Chris Erickson, Paul Nobel.<br><br>And as I said early on, the IBEW was with me when I was a kid running for the Senate in Delaware.&nbsp; And some of them are back there somewhere.<br><br>And I’m also proud of our Secretary of Labor &#8212; a card-carrying union member &#8212; Marty Walsh &#8212; fighting for union and worker power every day. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But, Lonnie, I only have one problem: Sometimes I can&#8217;t understand him.&nbsp; He talks about&nbsp;<em>cars</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>car&nbsp;barns&nbsp;&#8212;&nbsp;</em>(said in Boston accent) &#8212; and all that kind of thing.&nbsp; I wonder what he&#8217;s talking about sometimes.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s the best, man.&nbsp; If you got to be in a foxhole, you want him with you.<br><br>And, folks, there&#8217;s an expression where I come from: “You go home with them that brung you to the dance.”&nbsp; You all brought me to the dance, and I mean it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I said early on that I was going to be the most pro-labor, -union President we&#8217;ve ever had for a simple reason: You allow &#8212; (applause) &#8212; you allow workers to maintain their dignity.&nbsp; You allow them to hold their heads up high.&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp; It’s a lot more than just what you do in terms of their paychecks and their benefits, but it’s about their dignity.&nbsp;<br><br>My dad used to have an expression.&nbsp; He said, “Joey, a job is a lot more than a paycheck.&nbsp; It’s about your dignity.&nbsp; It’s about your place in the community.&nbsp; It’s about…”&nbsp; And I swear to God it’s what he&#8217;d say.&nbsp; “It’s about being able to look your kid in the eye and say, ‘Honey, everything is going to be okay.’”&nbsp;<br><br>Well, the union movement in the United States of America is the primary reason why that happened &#8212; the primary reason why that happened.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, look, there&#8217;s so much &#8212; we&#8217;ve done a lot, but there&#8217;s so much more to do.<br><br>So I &#8212; basic thing is, first of all: Thank you, thank you, thank you for your support.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>You&#8217;re the reason I&#8217;m standing here today as President.&nbsp; I’ve never forgotten not only what you’ve done for me, but what you’ve done for America.&nbsp; I’ve said this before, I&#8217;ll repeat it again &#8212; when I spoke to you a couple &#8212; about a year ago: You literally built this country.<br><br>If every investment banker in America would go on strike, not a whole hell of a lot would happen.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; If you all went on strike nationwide, the country would shut down &#8212; shut down.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>You’ve heard it a thousand times when I was running for office &#8212; a thousand times: The middle class built this country.&nbsp; Your plan was to build this economy around you, from the middle up and the bottom down &#8212; the bottom up.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m so sick and tired of trickle-down economics that only trickles to a few people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>When the middle class does well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy do just fine.<br><br>As I&#8217;ve said, Wall Street didn’t build this country, the middle class did.&nbsp; And unions built the middle class, not labor. &nbsp;Unions built the middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That’s a tr- &#8212; it’s a fact.&nbsp; That’s a fact.<br><br>With your help, we’re seeing the strongest job creation in modern times.<br><br>We inherited an economy on the brink of a great depression &#8212; millions of people losing their jobs, losing their homes, but even more importantly, losing hope.<br><br>But look at the economy today: 8.3 million jobs in my first 15 months in office &#8212; a record.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>The unemployment rate now stands at 3.6 percent, the fastest decline &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment at the start of any President’s term on record.<br><br>Jobs and companies are coming home again.&nbsp; We’re making “Buy America” a reality, not just a slogan.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Look, folks, our economy has gone from being on the mend to being on the move.&nbsp; You know, it started with my American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Because of it, we had the best year of state and local job growth in 20 years.&nbsp; We gave governors &#8212; great governors like the one in this state &#8212; we&nbsp;gave them a whole lot of money.&nbsp; We added back 460,000 jobs &#8212; critical state and local workers, educators, firefighters, police officers.&nbsp; This includes a record 279,000 education jobs in 2021, because they didn’t have the tax base to be able to hire them.&nbsp;<br><br>The American Rescue Plan provided eviction relief, funding for states and cities to allocate to landlords and renters &#8212; help them keep a roof over the heads &#8212; 5 million households.<br><br>Remember those long lines you’d see on the television and people lining up in all kinds of vehicles just to get a box of food in their trunk?&nbsp; How quickly we forget people were hurting.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And what did the MAGA crowd want to do?&nbsp; Forget it.&nbsp; Forget it.&nbsp;<br><br>God, this is the United States of America.&nbsp; The idea that people would have to wait in line an hour or hour and a half to get a box of food in their trunk &#8212; it’s just unbelievable.<br><br>You know, the American Rescue Plan helped 41 million people put food on the table &#8212; 41 million; the money in the pockets of hardworking Americans who, through no fault of their own, were in trouble, giving families what my dad called “just a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp;<br><br>And now, not only has “Infrastructure Week” finally arrived after four years of the other guy, we can look forward to the infrastructure decade for 10 years.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s a fact.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I know you’re all over the country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And the projects are coming to you.&nbsp; It’s not just for a year;&nbsp;it’s for the next decade &#8212; 10 years.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Here in Illinois alone there are over 6,000 miles of highway, 2,300 bridges in poor condition.<br><br>This year alone, Illinois will receive 1 billion 900 million dollars in highway funding for roads and bridges and $297 million dedicated &#8212; dedicated to funding for bridges that are in disrepair.<br><br>You know, I was going to Pittsburgh a couple of months ago, early &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Woo!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah, I like Pittsburgh, man.&nbsp; But I was going to Pittsburgh a couple months ago to speak. &nbsp;And as I got there, a bridge going over a culvert about &#8212; looked like about 200 yards long and about, at the top, probably 120 feet from the little creek below &#8212; totally collapsed.&nbsp; Totally collapsed.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank God one of the only things that the COVID crisis did was their kids weren’t in school; otherwise there’d be hundreds of kids in school buses going across there at the time.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This is the United States of America.&nbsp; The idea we have bridges that are collapsing, or about to collapse &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; it just drives me crazy to think about it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, look, Mayor Lightfoot talked about how Chicago has lead service pipes &#8212; more lead service pipes in drinking water than any other city in America, affecting nearly 400,000 Chicago homes.<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; That lead causes brain damage, particularly to kids, in those pipes.&nbsp; The law is going to fix that, because every American deserves to be able to turn on a spigot and drink clean water.&nbsp; Nationwide, 10 million homes.<br><br>Because of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we’ve announced nearly $3 billion to modernize more than&nbsp;<s>300</s>&nbsp;[3,000] airports across all 50 states &#8212; just like this year.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Chicago airports are going to receive &#8212; just this year &#8212; nearly $100 million that can be used to improve runways, taxiways, and terminals.<br><br>You know, some of you may remember, if you’re from New York City, when I was Vice President, I landed there to meet with a group of &#8212; to go in and speak to a union convention.&nbsp; I came back out to LaGuardia.&nbsp; And when I was in there, I said &#8212; and I walked into the terminal and there was a sign &#8212; one of the escalators wasn’t working.&nbsp; It’s the God’s truth.&nbsp; I looked up the escalator.&nbsp; It said, “Will be fixed in one month.”&nbsp;<br><br>One of the finest cities in all of America and you have a sign saying it’s going to take a month to fix an escalator.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I made a comment about that at the &#8212; at the union I spoke to and the group I spoke with.&nbsp; And it made instant news: “Biden was criticizing…”<br><br>Here’s what I said: I said, “If I took you to an airp- &#8212; blindfolded you, put you in an airport in Beijing and one in New York and I said to you, ‘Where are you: Beijing or New York?’”&nbsp;&#8212; you would’ve thought the Beijing airport was the American airport with no one in it.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; As I went back to get on Air Force Two, I’m standing there and I get off &#8212; I get out of the vehicle and I’m on the runway, and there’s nine guys and two women with their yellow, you know, bibs on and everything, who worked at the airport.&nbsp; I thought, “Oh, God.&nbsp; I’m not going to get up on the train &#8212; up on the plane.”&nbsp;<br><br>Do you know what they said?&nbsp; “Thank you. &nbsp;Thank you, thank you, thank you.”&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; They ended up investing almost a billion dollars in the airport, and it works.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This is the United States of America!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We used to have the finest infrastructure in the world.&nbsp; We were rated number one in the world; we’re now rated number 14. &nbsp;The United States of America.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; I would argue it’s because of the greed of the folks at the top not wanting to get things done.&nbsp;<br><br>But, folks, look, we’ve announced $5 billion, including $615&nbsp;<s>billion</s>&nbsp;[million] this year alone so the IBEW can get to work building a national network of 500,000 charging stations all across America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; This guy here is part of the reason.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>He won&#8217;t rem- &#8212; he won&#8217;t remember this, but I met with all the heads of &#8212; the CEOs of the major car companies.&nbsp; And you may remember General Motors back then, when I first got elected, was suing California because they said they had a higher standard for emissions than other states, and they couldn’t have a na- &#8212; a local standard higher than a federal standard.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I talked to Mary Barra.&nbsp; And about two weeks later, she called me and said, “We’re dropping our suit.&nbsp; We’re dropping our suit.”&nbsp; And I listened, and she said, “We’re going to go all electric by 2035.”&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; Five hundred thousand charging stations are going to have to be built as we build these things.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I think this guy is partially to blame.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Look, more than $20 billion so IBEW workers can modernize our electric grid, building larger and more resilient transmission lines that can withstand storms and get new and clean energy to our homes.&nbsp;<br><br>Think about it, folks: Who the hell but you crazy guys climb up poles in the middle of a storm to try to replace a generator?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, I’m serious.&nbsp; I’m genuinely serious.&nbsp; People don’t get &#8212; we have to let people know more of what you actually do.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’re investing $65 billion so that highly skilled and certified IBEW wor- &#8212; members can deliver affordable high-speed &#8212; high-speed Internet everywhere &#8212; rural, urban, suburban.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Just this week, I announced that 40 million low-income Americans from families of four earning less than $55,000 a year will get high-speed Internet installed in their homes for free.&nbsp; Free!&nbsp; Free!&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And we worked it out with the Internet companies.&nbsp; Nearly 40 percent of households in America will qualify.<br><br>We can’t be a country where a mother has to drive up to a McDonald’s parking lot in the evening with her child just so he can get on the Internet to do his homework.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Again, this is the United States of America, for God’s sake.&nbsp;<br><br>And what this means to all of you is good-paying union jobs.&nbsp; Jobs you can raise a family on.&nbsp; Jobs that can’t be outsourced.<br><br>This law is about more than rebuilding infrastructure.&nbsp; It’s also how about rebuilding the middle class.&nbsp;<br><br>As I said, unions built the middle class.&nbsp; And that’s why we made sure that the Infrastructure Law included significant labor protections.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>For example, the overwhelming majority of the funds included in the law are subject to Davis-Bacon requirements, so folks rebuilding our country can earn a prevailing wage.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Look, it’s why we’re strongly encouraging grantees who get infrastructure funding to use project labor agreements to ensure that workers building the major projects are well-trained, highly-skilled, and have a voice on the work site.<br><br>That’s why I continue to call on Congress to fully and finally pass the PRO Act, which makes &#8212; (applause) &#8212; which makes it easier for workers to organize a union.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I’m not just saying this to be pro-union.&nbsp; I’m saying this because I’m pro-America.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, when Congress passed the National Labor Relations Act in 1935, it didn’t just say that we should “allow” unions.&nbsp; Everybody forgot this for a long time.&nbsp; What it said is: We, the federal government, should “encourage” unions and collective bargaining.&nbsp; That’s what it said.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There’s a reason for that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Let’s be clear for our Republican friends: You can’t say you’re working &#8212; you’re for working people and vote against the PRO Act.&nbsp; It’s not consistent.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Look, you all know why this matters.&nbsp; Union members get higher wages, better benefits and health insurance, paid leave; protections against discrimination and harassment; and safer and healthier workplaces.<br><br>But there’s another reason: Workers join unions to gain power.&nbsp; That’s what it’s about.&nbsp; The only way to match power is with power.&nbsp; It’s the only way it can be done.&nbsp; You can’t count on the good graces of major corporations to decide they’re going to help. &nbsp;Power is needed to be exerted to deal with power.&nbsp; Power over the decisions that affect your lives.&nbsp;<br><br>Unions provide, in one word, democracy.<br><br>Rebuilding America with union labor is also smart for business.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; This is the point I make &#8212; and, by the way, I’m not getting many arguments from CEOs.&nbsp; It’s smart for business.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; When union workers are on the job, projects are completed efficiently and professionally, and they ultimately save money.<br><br>For folks at home, maybe you’re not in a union or know anyone who is in a union, but know this: It’s hard work.&nbsp; You got to earn it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Ask a journeyman electricians, anyone &#8212; a journeymen electricians here today &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I’m serious.&nbsp; Think about this.&nbsp; And you guys got to talk &#8212; with all due respect, you got to talk more about this.<br><br>The fact is: It takes four to five years as an apprentice &#8212; 8,000 hours of training.&nbsp; Now, granted, you get paid while you&#8217;re doing it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But the power goes out in a storm &#8212; why do you think &#8212; who climbs up that pole while the snow and the rain are still coming down?&nbsp; Union workers.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the best workers in the world.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the most qua- &#8212; this is not &#8212; again, I&#8217;m not trying to be nice to you all.&nbsp; No, I really &#8212; I mean this sincerely.<br><br>Why, if you have the capacity, would you not hire a union worker, whatever the job is &#8212; not just IBEW, a union worker &#8212; to do the job?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Seriously.<br><br>We all talk about &#8212; you go to college for four years.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; When you got to be an apprentice and it takes up to five years to get your apprenti- &#8212; to go through the program, you&#8217;re getting a hell of an edu- &#8212; you&#8217;re working like hell.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why you&#8217;re the most qualified people in the world &#8212; not just here, in the world.<br><br>And we&#8217;re beginning to see the effects of unions and the impact on everything from what you see going on in Ukraine right now.&nbsp; Our stuff isn&#8217;t falling apart.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Theirs is.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; Theirs is.&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So, folks, their quality of work is good for the American taxpayer. &nbsp;We&#8217;re not costing the American taxpayers money.&nbsp; We&#8217;re saving them money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, no &#8212; I &#8212; I &#8212; you guys don&#8217;t say this enough, quite frankly.&nbsp; Excu- &#8212; if you don&#8217;t mind my saying so.&nbsp; All in the family here.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t say it enough.<br><br>It’s good for families in every neighborhood where infrastructure projects are underway.<br><br>Look, but here’s the deal: Building an economy from the bottom up and middle out doesn’t happen by itself.<br><br>For example, I know folks are concerned about inflation.&nbsp; I come from a family &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; like most of you, where if the price of gasoline went up significantly and the price of food went up, that&#8217;s what we talked about at the dinner table and the kitchen table.&nbsp; It meant a lot.&nbsp; We felt it.&nbsp; We felt it.&nbsp; I understand.<br><br>That’s why I’ve got a plan to lower the costs for everyday things that make most people &#8212; who work to have, who need it.&nbsp; And that would fundamentally change the standard of living if we just made things more affordable.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s more than one way to deal with the impact on a family than what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to beat inflation.&nbsp; But beyond that, it&#8217;s all about the quality of life.<br><br>You know, I remember my dad used to say &#8212; if he had an opportunity &#8212; my dad, I guess, made &#8212; back in the late &#8217;60s, he probably made the equivalent of $20,000 a year.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t a bad salary, but it wasn&#8217;t great.&nbsp; He had four kids.<br><br>And if someone came along and said to my dad, &#8220;I can guarantee that your salary is going to go up 500 bucks a year every year for the next 10 years, or we can make sure your kid can go to college with a lot cheaper than it costs now.&nbsp; I can make sure your cost of electricity and energy in your home is down, not up.&nbsp; I can make sure that you&#8217;re going to be in a position where you&#8217;re going to have &#8212; the roads in front of the house are going to be paved.&nbsp; What do you ask for?&#8221;<br><br>My dad would say, &#8220;All the rest relates to my standard of living.&#8221;&nbsp; That&#8217;s what middle-class folks are concerned about.&nbsp; And not being embarrassed in front of their kids when they can&#8217;t do something that they know they should be able to do for them.<br><br>I really mean it.&nbsp; Again, it gets back to a word that&#8217;s probably overused in my house.&nbsp; As my grandfather would say, &#8220;Maybe it&#8217;s the Irish of it.&#8221;&nbsp; The word &#8220;dignity.&#8221;&nbsp; The simple dignity.<br><br>And so, there are so many things we can do that don&#8217;t do anything other than make the country better and don&#8217;t cost the taxpayers more money if we just decide to be fair and everybody would begin to pay their fair share.<br><br>Look, folks, you know, an example of my plan would be to let Medicare negotiate the price of prescription drugs like the Department of Veterans Affairs does.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We say to the &#8212; the companies that are &#8212; the drug companies, &#8220;We&#8217;re only going to pay X number of dollars for the following thing.&nbsp; If you don&#8217;t want to do that, we&#8217;re not going to buy any of your drugs.&#8221;&nbsp; Well, since you got thousands of people and when you&#8217;re talking millions of people, they say, &#8220;Okay.&#8221;<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal, going back to this idea &#8212; just making sure we have basic dignity.<br><br>You know, putting a cap on the price of insulin &#8212; many of you have children &#8212; or maybe some of you have Type 2 diabetes.&nbsp; People with Type 2 diabetes need their insulin shots.&nbsp; Need them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like an option &#8212; not like an option.<br><br>Well, guess what?&nbsp; It costs the drug companies 10 bucks &#8212; you hear me?&nbsp; &#8212; $10 to make that insulin and &#8212; counting in all the research and development they did to get to that point.<br><br>Yet, you know what the average cost of insulin for a month for a Type 2 diabetic is?&nbsp; And there&#8217;s 200,000 kids out there who have Type&nbsp;<s>2</s>&nbsp;[1] diabetes.&nbsp; They &#8212; the average cost is $640 a month.<br><br>Now, what the hell do you do, as a mom or a dad, if you don&#8217;t have private insurance and you don&#8217;t have coverage?<br><br>Not only do you look at your child &#8212; I mean this sincerely and from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; You look at your child, and not only do you worry about where they&#8217;re going to live &#8212; because you got to divide up what little you have and maybe stretch it out.&nbsp; What do you think it does to you as a parent, looking at your child?&nbsp; Talk about being deprived of your personal dignity.<br><br>What the hell are we doing?&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Think of the difference that it would make for millions of Americans struggling every single month to afford insulin for their child.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Take childcare: In a city like this or any major cities in America, it costs about $14,000 a year per child who’s not at school age.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I remember.&nbsp; I was 29 years old.&nbsp; You guys helped to get me elected to the United States Senate.&nbsp; I wasn’t old enough to be sworn in.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I was down in Washington, interviewing staff before I was sworn in.&nbsp; And I got a phone call from the first responders in my state.&nbsp; They said, “You got to come home.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been an accident.”&nbsp; I said, “What happened?”&nbsp; They said, “Well, a tractor trailer broadsided your wife&#8217;s car with your three kids while they were Christmas shopping.”&nbsp; And the poor young woman they put on the phone to tell me said, “And your wife is dead.&nbsp; Your daughter is dead.&nbsp; And your boys are really hurt.”<br><br>So, I went home, obviously.&nbsp; And I didn’t want to stay in the Senate.&nbsp; I wanted no part of it.&nbsp; But because of some really fine men &#8212; one Republican and five Democrats &#8212; they convinced me that, “Well, Joe, just come and stay six months.&nbsp; Help us organize.”&nbsp; See how smart I was?&nbsp; We had elected 58 Democrats and a Democratic governor in my state that would have appointed a Democrat.&nbsp; So, I said okay.&nbsp; I thought I had to go because &#8212; to help.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, one of the things I found out was: How am I going to take care of my two little boys?&nbsp; Almost three and almost four.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford daycare.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford childcare.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And I was making $42,000 a year, which was a lot of money, as a U.S. senator.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford it.&nbsp; Thank God I got a big family.&nbsp; My dad would say, “Family is the beginning, middle, and the end.”&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>My sister moved in, and I bought an old farmhouse.&nbsp; And my brother was single, moved in.&nbsp; Took a barn and turned it into an apartment.&nbsp; Every morning, I’d drive to the train station to drop my kids off at my mom&#8217;s.&nbsp; I had a lot of help.<br><br>But it made me realize: How about that single woman with a high-school education or less, with two little kids without a dad &#8212; how in God&#8217;s name they can make it.&nbsp; And yet, how can they go to work?&nbsp;<br><br>The point being that if we just said anyone making under &#8212; a family making under 120 grand a year would not have to pay more than 7 percent of their income for childcare, we’d cut in half the cost of childcare on a yearly basis, making it easy for &#8212; much easier for a whole lot of people to be able to work.&nbsp; It’d put over 200,000 women back in the job market who are leaving only because they can&#8217;t afford &#8212; can&#8217;t afford childcare.&nbsp;<br><br>Folks, imagine what that would mean to the standard of living for a household.<br><br>Folks, there&#8217;s no reason why we shouldn&#8217;t get a tax credit for weatherizing your homes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Make it more efficient to buy electric vehicles.&nbsp; My plan does that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I met with nearly a dozen CEOs of America&#8217;s largest utility companies.&nbsp; Literally a dozen of them came to see me.&nbsp; They confirmed that if we pass the investments allowing families to &#8212; if they weatherize their homes, to write it off &#8212; a tax credit &#8212; it will immediately lower the bills of these families an average of $500 a year.<br><br>We can do these things without making a lot of sacrifices.&nbsp; We just asked the large corporations, the wealthiest Americans just to begin to pay part of their fair share of taxes.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>No one making less &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no one making less &#8212; no one making under $400,000 a year, I promise you, will pay an additional penny in federal taxes.&nbsp; I said that at the beginning, and I&#8217;ve kept that commitment.<br><br>Meanwhile, right now, the average billionaire &#8212; there’s about 790 of them or so in America &#8212; you know what their average tax rate is?&nbsp; Eight percent.&nbsp; E-I-G-H-T.&nbsp; Eight percent.&nbsp; Now &#8212; in federal taxes.&nbsp; But most of you are likely paying two to three times that much.&nbsp;<br><br>No billionaire should be paying a lower tax rate than a teacher, a firefighter, an electrician, a cop.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, I mean it.&nbsp; And they shouldn&#8217;t be paying 90 percent either.&nbsp; If we just moved the tax rate back to 39 percent, we’d have enough money to pay for all these things &#8212; for them, for people making tens of millions of dollars.&nbsp;<br><br>This is about fairness.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about dignity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about fiscal responsibility.<br><br>My Republican colleagues say these programs to help the working-class and middle-class people &#8212; that&#8217;s &#8212; they say that&#8217;s why we have inflation.&nbsp; They&#8217;re dead wrong.&nbsp;<br><br>Under my predecessor, the great MAGA king, the deficit increased every single year he was President.&nbsp; The first year of my presidency &#8212; the first year, I reduced the deficit &#8212; literally reduced the deficit by $350 billion.&nbsp; First year.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And this year &#8212; and this year, we&#8217;re on track to cut the federal deficit by 1 trillion 500 billion dollars &#8212; the biggest decline in debt ever in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>It matters to families, because reducing the deficit is one of the main ways that we can ease inflationary pressures.<br><br>But pay close attention.&nbsp; I believe in bipartisanship.&nbsp; Right now, the majority of our Republican friends just see things differently.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want to solve inflation&nbsp;&#8212; inflation by lowering the costs.&nbsp; They want to solve it by raising taxes and lowering your income.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, you think I&#8217;m making this up. &nbsp;If I didn’t see the actual document, I’d think you &#8212; I was making it up.&nbsp; I happen to think it’s good &#8212; a good thing when American families have more money in their pockets.&nbsp; American workers deserve a raise.&nbsp;<br><br>All this concern &#8212; “Ameri- &#8212; wages went up 5 percent.&nbsp; Oh my God.”&nbsp; I thought that we were supposed to see happen.&nbsp;<br><br>Republicans in Congress have proposed a plan that will make working families and American families poorer.&nbsp; Now, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m not usually this discreet about my Republican friends.&nbsp; I get along with a lot of them &#8212; used to anyway.&nbsp;<br><br>But Senator Rick Scott, a Republican from Florida, laid out a plan in writing &#8212; the Ult- &#8212; well, it’s called the &#8212; I call it the “Ultra-MAGA” plan &#8212; Make America Great Again plan.&nbsp; It’s in writing.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And here’s what it does: It raises taxes on 75 million American families, over 95 percent of whom earn less than $100,000 a year in a combined income.&nbsp; It would raise taxes by nearly $1,500 per family.&nbsp; It’s all in writing.&nbsp; You can go online.&nbsp;<br><br>They’ve got it backwards.&nbsp;<br><br>I’ve proposed a minimum tax for billionaires, but congressional Republicans have proposed a minimum tax for teachers, firefighters, and electricians.&nbsp;<br><br>And while on this &#8212; you know, 55 of the Fortune 500 &#8212; Fortune 500 companies in 2020 &#8212; 55 of them paid zero in federal taxes after making $40 billion.&nbsp; Forty billion dollars.&nbsp; Zero in federal taxes.&nbsp; It isn’t right.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I proposed a minimum tax for corporations that asks them to pay their fair share in taxes.&nbsp; Senator Scott’s plan lets them off, no pun intended, scot-free.<br><br>I want to strengthen Social Security benefits to make folks who have worked for their whole lives and have paid into it &#8212; make sure they have it.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to give Medicare the power to negotiate drug prices.&nbsp; I want states to continue to expand Medicaid.&nbsp;<br><br>And the ultra-MAGA Republicans’ proposal puts &#8212; here’s what it does: It puts Social Security, Medicare &#8212; this is the Republican plan now; the only one out there &#8212; and Medicaid on the chopping block every five years.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Here’s how it works: Their plan explicitly states that, every five years it will require a vote on whether or not to continue each of these programs.&nbsp; Republicans in Congress want to put Medicare’s very existence up for a vote every five years.&nbsp; Same with Social Security and Medicaid.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, really, ask yourself: How well are you going to sleep at night knowing that every five years everything you’ve paid into may not be there?<br><br>Not &#8212; this is &#8212; this is serious.&nbsp; The MAGA Republicans are going to vote on whether you’ll have Social Security, Medicare, or Medicaid and what amount you get.&nbsp; Every five years it’s reconsidered.<br><br>Now, I have to admit it’s unlikely they’ll vote Social Security totally out of existence.&nbsp; But what do you think they’re likely to do if this were to pass?&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;ve been a &#8212; I&#8217;ve been in Congress a long time.&nbsp;&nbsp;I was pretty good at what I did in Congress.&nbsp; I guarantee you what they do every five years &#8212; they&#8217;ll hold hostages to get their way.<br><br>They’ll say, “If, in fact, you don&#8217;t vote for this particular thing, we&#8217;re going to cut Social Security.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to cut Medicaid.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to cut whatever.”<br><br>The idea you&#8217;d have to renegotiate Social Security every five years?&nbsp; I mean, this is in writing.&nbsp; Look it up.<br><br>You know, they&#8217;re going to say, “If you don&#8217;t stop investing in clean energy &#8212; because we don&#8217;t like it, we don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s global warming &#8212; we&#8217;re going to cut the following.”<br><br>Folks, this is not who we are.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve got to keep fighting for an economy that&#8217;s about fairness, dignity, and opportunity; that&#8217;s about America &#8212; about America.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, you know, as my mother used to say, “Out of everything bad, Joey, something good will happen if you look hard enough for it.”&nbsp; So let me close it this.<br><br>Last month, I visited the main airport in Portland, Oregon, which is undergoing major renovations being funded by the Bipart- &#8212; (applause) &#8212; being funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I met a woman named Lauren of IBEW Local 48.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; She came up to me.&nbsp; She shared what the job meant to her, how she grew up poor and was raised by a single mom, how she bounced around in different careers until she came in a &#8212; until she became an apprentice with the IBEW.<br><br>She’s putting in her years and the thousands of hours that she needs to put in to become a journeyman electrician.&nbsp; Lauren told me that the airport will symbolize the crown jewel of the Pacific Northwest but it will also symbolize something else: a better life &#8212; a better life for an IBEW member.&nbsp; That means fairness and dignity in the workplace.&nbsp;<br><br>And it’ll be a symbol for a better America because the IB- &#8212; IBEW is just getting started.<br><br>Folks, I promised you that I’d be the most pro-union President in American history &#8212; (applause) &#8212; because I know this: In a crisis, America always counts on you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; So you can count on me to keep fighting for you!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Keep going!&nbsp; Keep building!&nbsp; Keep the faith!&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>4:49 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
