<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:33:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-65/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52793</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Donald R. Cravins, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Minority Business Development.&#160; (New Position) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Rebecca Lee Haffajee, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services, vice Richard G. Frank. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; David P. Pekoske, of Maryland, to be Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration for a term&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Donald R. Cravins, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Minority Business Development.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rebecca Lee Haffajee, of Massachusetts, to be an Assistant Secretary of Health and Human Services, vice Richard G. Frank.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; David P. Pekoske, of Maryland, to be Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration for a term of five years.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hugo F. Rodriguez, Jr., of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Nicaragua.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at Signing of S. 3522, the “Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease Act Of&#160;2022”</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-s-3522-the-ukraine-democracy-defense-lend-lease-act-of-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Oval Office 3:08 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, welcome, folks.&#160; Today I’m joined by Senator Cardin &#8212; Ben Cardin; Elissa Slotkin; and the Congresswoman Victoria Spatz &#8212; Spartz, excuse me, who &#8212; I was just talking to her about still having family back in Ukraine.&#160; God love you.&#160;&#160; I &#8212; we’re going to &#8212; I’m&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Oval Office</p>



<p>3:08 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, welcome, folks.&nbsp; Today I’m joined by Senator Cardin &#8212; Ben Cardin; Elissa Slotkin; and the Congresswoman Victoria Spatz &#8212; Spartz, excuse me, who &#8212; I was just talking to her about still having family back in Ukraine.&nbsp; God love you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; we’re going to &#8212; I’m about to sign a bill that these folks are responsible &#8212; and, of course, the Vice President, excuse me.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The &#8212; I’m signing a bill that provides another important tool in our efforts to support the government of Ukraine and the Ukrainian people in their fight to defend their country and their democracy against Putin’s brutal war.&nbsp; And it is brutal.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank members of Congress here for getting this passed and everyone who supported the bill.&nbsp; And the bill demonstrates that support for Ukraine is pivotal at this moment.</p>



<p>Every day, Ukrainians pay with their lives, and they fight along &#8212; and the atrocities that the Russians are engaging in are just beyond the pale.&nbsp; And the cost of the fight is not cheap, but caving to aggression is even more costly.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re staying in this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, we celebrated VE Day &#8212; Victory in Europe Day &#8212; marking the end of a transition of the devastation as a consequence of World War Two and Allied nations’ defeat of the scourge of fascism in Europe.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, Europe is honoring another important day on the anniversary.&nbsp; On May 9th, 1950, just years after the end of World War Two, Europe began to work to strengthen the bonds of unity among the nations, particularly the economic unity and the shared economic prosperity.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The idea ultimately grew into the &#8212; what is now a 27-nation European Union &#8212; an economic powerhouse and a global force for peace and close partners of all &#8212; on all the issues we face.</p>



<p>And it really has &#8212; I&#8217;ve said from the very beginning: It&#8217;s &#8212; it’s something that is good for everyone.&nbsp; It brings these countries together in ways that &#8212; and they cooperate closely economically.&nbsp; They also cooperate in other ways.&nbsp; And you’ve seen it in their support for Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with Putin’s war once more bringing wanton destruction into Europe, and to &#8212; to reaffirm the enduring commitment to the future grounded in democracy, human rights, and peaceful resolution to disagreements, I&#8217;m now going to sign this bill.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, I thank my colleagues who are standing behind me.&nbsp; And &#8212; because it really matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The bill is signed.)</p>



<p>There you go.  Done.  Thank you.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:13 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden on the Affordable Connectivity&#160;Program￼</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/09/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-affordable-connectivity-program%ef%bf%bc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 20:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 1:47 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Welcome to the sunny Rose Garden.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you. That old saying, “All that needs to be said has already been said, but I’m going to say it again.”&#160; (Laughter.) Look, Alisha, thank you very much for your story. And I wanted&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>1:47 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Welcome to the sunny Rose Garden.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>That old saying, “All that needs to be said has already been said, but I’m going to say it again.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Look, Alisha, thank you very much for your story.<br><br>And I wanted to &#8212; I want to thank the Vice President, Vice President Harris, for leading this effort and this administration on this issue.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’m proud to announce today that our administration has brought together Democrats, Republicans, the private sector to lower the high-speed Internet costs for tens of millions of Americans.<br><br>You know, but before we get into the details, I want to talk about why this matters.&nbsp; You already know that, actually, from hearing my two colleagues speak before me.<br><br>But here in the United States of America, how many times have you seen a mom or a dad drive up to a parking lot outside a McDonald’s and &#8212; just so they could get connected to the Internet so their kid could do their homework during the pandemic, literally?&nbsp; It’s just not right.&nbsp; It’s not who we are.<br><br>And we saw, during the pandemic, how essential high-speed Internet really is in allowing seniors to connect with their doctors through telemedicine, as the Vice President referenced, when it wasn’t safe to go in person; allowing students to keep learning back when schools were closed; allowing millions of &#8212; millions workers to do their job remotely; allowing small businesses to stay afloat on the strength of their online sales; allowing farmers to use precision agriculture technology to improve their yields; and allowing countless families to stay connected to the people they love, even when they weren’t able to get together.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the need for high-speed Internet is &#8212; is a little bit like what used to be probably what my grandfather talked about: needing to have a telephone.&nbsp; It’s pretty consequential.&nbsp; And it’s only going to keep growing, this need.&nbsp; High-speed Internet is not a luxury any longer, it’s a necessity.&nbsp;<br><br>And that’s why the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law included $65 billion to make sure we expand access to broadband Internet in every region of the country &#8212; urban, suburban, and rural &#8212; everywhere &#8212; everywhere &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so every household in America can get connected.<br><br>By &#8212; by expanding access it’s only &#8212; it’s only part of the challenge, though, as was referenced by the Vice President.&nbsp; It was about affordability as well.&nbsp; And today, too many families simply can’t afford to get connected, even if there’s access to get connected.&nbsp; So they go without high-speed Internet or they sacrifice other necessities in order to make it work.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why &#8212; that’s why, in November, when we passed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill, we also created something called the Affordable Connectivity Program.&nbsp; I refuse to call it the “ACP.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I am so tired of acronyms in Washington.&nbsp; I can’t stand it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I cannot stand it.&nbsp; But I’m going to have to learn, aren’t I?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Here’s how it works: If your household income is twice the federal poverty level or less &#8212; that’s about $55,000 per year for a family of four or $27,000 for an individual &#8212; or a member of your household is on Medicaid or Supplemental Security Income or a number of other programs, you’re eligible to &#8212; for affordably connect &#8212; the Affordable Connectivity Program.&nbsp;<br><br>Nearly 40 percent of the households in America qualify.&nbsp; And if you qualify, you’re going to get a $30 credit per month toward your Internet bill, which me- &#8212; which most folks &#8212; will mean they get on for nothing.&nbsp; Look &#8212; zero.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Let me explain: In the past, 30 bucks a month meant you had to settle for a slow Internet service, unless you wanted to pay a heck of a lot more out of pocket.&nbsp; But over the last few months, my administration has worked closely with Internet providers &#8212; this is a case where big business stepped up &#8212; urging them to cut their prices and raise their &#8212; their speeds.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m trying to get others to do the same thing with inflation but that &#8212; these guys are the best.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Well, look, we secured commitments from 20 providers &#8212; most of whom are here in the garden today.&nbsp; Going to lower prices for high-speed Internet for tens of millions of households.&nbsp; So, now families who are eligible can select a plan from pr- &#8212; a participating provider and receive high-speed Internet at no cost, in most cases.<br><br>These include providers like AT&amp;T.&nbsp; Is AT&amp;T here?&nbsp; Thank you, man.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>AT&amp;T, Comcast &#8212; Comcast, where are you?&nbsp; Stand up, man.&nbsp; Let them see you.&nbsp; Frontier, Spectrum, and Verizon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;You’re really changing people’s lives.&nbsp; You really are.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Along with smaller providers serving rural areas, like Jackson Energy Authority in Tennessee and Ideatek in Kansas.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Are you guys here?&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>All told, providers taking part &#8212; you know, everybody &#8212; it’s &#8212; you’re going to cover about 80 percent of the United States’ population, including about half the rural population.&nbsp; Each of the &#8212; each of them has committed to offering families who use this program at least one high-speed plan that is fully covered.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, Verizon lowered the price of its high-speed service from $40 a month to $30 a month.&nbsp; Spectrum doubled the speed of its $30-a-month plan for eligible households.&nbsp; And we made sure that there would be no hidden fees, no tricks.&nbsp; This is straight stuff.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This means fast Internet, good download speeds, with no data caps and no extra fees for millions of American families.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s going to change people’s lives.&nbsp; You know, in &#8212; from rural Appalachia to Brooklyn to the Black Belt.&nbsp; Families who have struggled to get the Internet that they need &#8212; even getting &#8212; finding if they could connect to it, let alone if they could afford it &#8212; for schoolwork, telemedicine, standing a &#8212; starting a business, and so much more &#8212; and will finally get connected reliably and affordably.<br><br>And I want to thank the companies who are working with us to deliver this for all families.&nbsp; It’s a big deal.&nbsp; And this is a great example of what we can achieve if the federal government and the private sector work together to solve serious problems.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And this is &#8212; not only is it this great news for family budgets, it also means more jobs, more new small businesses, more connectivity.&nbsp; So many people in so many communities that have been left behind.&nbsp; Already, more than 11.5 million have signed up and are on the program.&nbsp; Thousands more are signing up each day.&nbsp; And you can get started by taking advantage of this &#8212; in this new phase today.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re &#8212; but we urge &#8212; there’s about 30 million additional people who are eligible for this plan that basically get free Internet and good Internet.&nbsp; We want each of you &#8212; each and every one of you to take advantage of the chance and cut your Internet cost.</p>



<p>To find out if you’re eligible, you can dial 877-384-2575.&nbsp; Now, if you got that, you’re way ahead of me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; 877-384-2575, and &#8212; for English or Spanish.</p>



<p>Or if you’re able to get onto the Internet, just visit, Get- &#8212; just go to GetInternet.gov, and you’ll be able to connect as well.<br><br>You know, we’re also working with local, state, and federal agencies, as well as local and national organizations, to help get more eligible families enrolled so they can get connected.&nbsp; You got to know how to know, as a friend of mine used to say.&nbsp; You know, this program is a big deal.&nbsp; It’s the only one &#8212; only one piece of work that we’re doing to try to bring down the cost of high-speed Internet to every single American.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re also promoting the &#8212; competition.&nbsp; More than 65 million Americans live in a place with only one high-speed Internet provider.&nbsp; Research shows that when you live somewhere with limited Internet options, you pay five times more on average than families that have more choices.&nbsp; That’s what the lack of cont- &#8212; lack of competition does: It raises the prices you pay.&nbsp; So, we’re working to fix that problem as well.<br><br>For example, my administration is taking steps to put a stop to the exclusive deals that landlords make with Internet companies.&nbsp; Because [of] those sweetheart arrangements, millions of Americans who live in apartment buildings only have one Internet option.&nbsp; And they &#8212; they can stop &#8212; if they can stop those exclusive deals, then families will have options to choose a provider that they want, and that means companies will have to compete for their business, which in turn means lower prices.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In addition, more than 30 million Americans live in places where the speeds are too slow or where there is no broadband and there&#8217;s no infrastructure at all.&nbsp; That’s especially true in rural communities.&nbsp; And as I said at the start: Thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we’re delivering high-speed Internet infrastructure to every part of the country.&nbsp; And I mean that literally &#8212; every part of the country.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line is this: My top priority is fighting inflation and lowering prices for families and the things they need.&nbsp; Today’s announcement is going to give millions of families a little more &#8212; a little more breathing room to help them pay their bills.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You know, we worked with Democrats and Republicans and business and non-profits to make this happen.&nbsp; And we’re going to keep working to fight inflation and lower cost of &#8212; to all American families for a lot of other things as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But again, I want to thank the businesses that are here today.&nbsp; I want to thank the Internet companies &#8212; or the providers.&nbsp; It really matters.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to change people’s lives.&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, you know, one of the things that is &#8212; it’s a totally different subject, and I&#8217;m just going to touch it for a second.&nbsp; There&#8217;s an awful lot of growing data that what&#8217;s happened because of COVID and other things &#8212; the mental health problems are &#8212; have become a serious problem.&nbsp; Feeling left out, feeling you can&#8217;t participate, not knowing what to do.<br><br>I know &#8212; and Vivek Murthy, the Surgeon General, is going to talk about this in another context.&nbsp; But, you know, I really think that just knowing that you belong, knowing and feeling that you can get access to what other people get on a regular basis will make a big difference for people.&nbsp;<br><br>So, God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; And all the members of Congress who made this happy &#8212; I was going to name each one of you, and I was told don’t, because people who aren’t here wanted to be here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I &#8212; but I think I should name you anyway, shouldn’t I?&nbsp; I mean &#8212; no?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t know, man.&nbsp;&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>They’re all in the front here, and they&#8217;re all doing a hell of a job.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>I started off – and I had the list, I said, “Give me the…”&nbsp; And I started off with saying, “Cheri Bustos.”&nbsp; And they said, “Wait, there&#8217;s a lot of people who aren’t here.&nbsp; Don’t do it.”&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; But I &#8212; and the people who are here are, you know,&nbsp;John Hickenlooper, Cheri Bustos, Dan Kildee &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; Debbie Dingell, Tom O’Halleran, Eliza [sic] Slotkin &#8212; excuse me, Elissa Slotkin, and &#8212; and Representative Stansbury.&nbsp; So &#8212; but there&#8217;s a lot more to it, but anyway.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; It’s going to make a big difference.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp; And stick around and sunbathe.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>2:00 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris Reduce High-Speed Internet Costs for Millions of&#160;Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/09/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-reduce-high-speed-internet-costs-for-millions-of-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration Secures Commitments from 20 Internet Providers to Cut Prices and Increase Speeds High-speed internet service is no longer a luxury—it’s a necessity. But too many families go without high-speed internet because of the cost or have to cut back on other essentials to make their monthly internet service payments. Lowering prices—including the cost&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration Secures Commitments from 20 Internet Providers to Cut Prices and Increase Speeds</em></p>



<p>High-speed internet service is no longer a luxury—it’s a necessity. But too many families go without high-speed internet because of the cost or have to cut back on other essentials to make their monthly internet service payments. Lowering prices—including the cost of high-speed internet service—is President Biden’s top priority. Today, President Biden and Vice President Harris are announcing that they have secured private sector commitments that will lower high-speed internet costs for millions of American families.</p>



<p>As part of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the President and Vice President worked with Democrats and Republicans to create the Affordable Connectivity Program (ACP), which allows tens of millions of American households to reduce their internet service costs by up to $30/month (or $75/month on Tribal lands). To ensure the most efficient use of those public dollars and to deliver maximum cost savings to families, the Biden-Harris Administration has secured commitments from 20 leading internet providers—covering more than 80% of the U.S. population across urban, suburban, and rural areas—to either increase speeds or cut prices, making sure they all offer ACP-eligible households high-speed, high-quality internet plans for no more than $30/month.</p>



<p>From large providers like AT&amp;T, Comcast, and Verizon serving dozens of states, to smaller providers serving rural areas like Jackson Energy Authority in Tennessee and Comporium in North Carolina, the commitments will allow tens of millions of ACP-eligible households to receive high-speed internet at no cost.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is also launching a comprehensive effort to make sure as many ACP-eligible households as possible take advantage of this new program by:</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Launching GetInternet.gov:</u></strong> <a href="http://www.GetInternet.gov">GetInternet.gov</a> is a simple, easy-to-use website with details on how Americans can sign up for ACP and find participating internet providers in their area.<br></li><li><strong><u>Reaching out to eligible households through federal agencies:</u></strong> Households qualify for ACP based on their income or through their participation in one of several other federal programs, like Pell Grants, Medicaid, or Supplemental Security Income. Agencies that manage these programs will be coordinating an effort to reach out to households that qualify for ACP through programs they help administer.&nbsp;For example, the Social Security Administration will email all 1.6 million Supplemental Security Income recipients who have a “My Social Security” account, letting them know that they are eligible for the Affordable Connectivity Program.<br></li><li><strong><u>Partnering with states and cities:</u></strong> The Administration is partnering with states and cities to spread the word as well. For example, Michigan, Massachusetts, Philadelphia, Mesa, Arizona, and New York City will text millions of eligible households.<br></li><li><strong><u>Collaborating with public interest organizations:</u></strong> Public interest organizations, including the United Way, Goodwill, Catholic Charities USA, and UnidosUS, will train their national networks to conduct direct enrollment and outreach. And Propel, a mission-driven financial technology company, will provide information via the Providers app to connect more than 5 million low-income families with the program.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Today’s announcement is just one part of the President’s strategy for lowering the cost of high-speed internet for all Americans. New <a href="https://www.ntia.doc.gov/category/grants">grant</a> <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/capital-projects-fund#:~:text=The%20American%20Rescue%20Plan%20provides,to%20the%20public%20health%20emergency.">programs</a> <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/policy-issues/coronavirus/assistance-for-state-local-and-tribal-governments/state-and-local-fiscal-recovery-funds">providing</a> tens of billions of dollars for broadband infrastructure construction will require providers to offer affordable internet options. New rules will soon require providers to display a “<a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-acts-empower-broadband-consumers-through-transparency-0">Broadband Nutrition Label</a>” that will make it easier to comparison shop for the best deal on internet. The FCC has adopted rules to ban sweetheart deals between internet providers and landlords that restrict the internet options available to millions of Americans who live <a href="https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-acts-increase-broadband-competition-apartment-buildings-0">in apartment buildings</a>. And the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/competition/">competition agenda</a> is focused on providing Americans with more good options for internet service where they live—driving down prices and increasing the quality of service.<br><br><strong><u>THE AFFORDABLE CONNECTIVITY PROGRAM (ACP)</u></strong><br>President Biden and Vice President Harris worked with Democrats and Republicans to create the Affordable Connectivity Program (ACP)—the largest high-speed internet affordability program in our nation’s history. Experts estimate that <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/610831a16c95260dbd68934a/t/6272e30e12eafe18e06dec58/1651696399310/Broadband-Connectivity-Fact-Sheet-CPSP-2022.pdf">48 million households</a>—or nearly 40% of households in the country—qualify for the ACP either because their income is at or below 200% of the Federal Poverty Level, or because a member of the household meets one of the other criteria below:</p>



<ul><li>Participates in one of the following programs:<ul><li>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP), formerly known as Food Stamps</li><li>Medicaid</li><li>Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC)</li><li>Supplemental Security Income (SSI)</li><li>Federal Public Housing Assistance (FPHA)</li><li>Veterans Pension and Survivors Benefit</li><li>Free and Reduced-Price School Lunch Program or School Breakfast Program, including at U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) Community Eligibility Provision schools</li><li>Federal Pell Grant (received in the current award year)</li><li>Lifeline</li><li>Certain Tribal assistance programs, including Bureau of Indian Affairs General Assistance, Head Start (only households meeting the income qualifying standard), Tribal Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (Tribal TANF), and Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations<br></li></ul></li><li>Meets the eligibility criteria for a participating broadband provider’s existing low-income internet program.</li></ul>



<p>Under the terms of the ACP, an eligible household that signs up for the program will receive a discount of up to $30/month on any internet service plan a participating provider offers. Households on Tribal Lands are eligible for a discount of up to $75/month. As of now, more than 1,300 internet service providers participate in the program, and more than 11.5 million households have signed up to receive the ACP benefit.<br><br><strong><u>NEW PRIVATE SECTOR COMMITMENTS</u></strong><br>To make the most of this program, the Biden-Harris Administration asked participating internet service providers to either reduce prices and or raise speeds to offer ACP-eligible households a high-speed internet plan for no more than $30/month. For these purposes, the Administration views a sufficiently high-speed plan as one that offers download speeds of at least 100 Megabits per second everywhere that the provider’s infrastructure is capable of it. That’s fast enough for a typical family of four to work from home, do schoolwork, browse the web, and stream high-definition shows and movies. In addition, the Administration asked providers to offer such plans with no fees and no data caps.</p>



<p>For example, as part of this initiative, Verizon lowered the price for its Fios service from $39.99/month to $30/month for a plan that delivers download and upload speeds of at least 200 Megabits per second, and Spectrum doubled the speed of the $30/month plan it makes available to ACP participants from 50 to 100 Megabits per second (download).</p>



<p>Each of the following companies committed to offer all ACP-eligible families at least one high-speed plan for $30/month or less, with no additional fees and no data caps.</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.allocommunications.com/community-connect-residential/">Allo Communications</a></li><li><a href="https://info.cincinnatibell.com/acp">AltaFiber</a> (and <a href="https://hawaiiantel.com/acp">Hawaiian Telecom</a>)</li><li>Altice USA (<a href="https://www.optimum.com/affordable-connectivity-program">Optimum</a> and <a href="https://www.suddenlink.com/affordable-connectivity-program">Suddenlink</a>)</li><li><a href="https://www.astound.com/acp">Astound</a></li><li><a href="http://www.att.com/acp">AT&amp;T</a></li><li><a href="https://www.breezeline.com/acp">Breezeline</a></li><li><a href="https://www.internetessentials.com/">Comcast</a></li><li><a href="https://www.comporium.com/affordable-connectivity-program-connected-package/">Comporium</a></li><li><a href="https://www.getfrontierfiber.com/acp-offer#3UP">Frontier</a></li><li><a href="https://ideatek.com/low-income-assistance/">IdeaTek</a></li><li><a href="https://www.cox.com/residential/internet/low-cost-internet-plans.html">Cox Communications</a></li><li><a href="http://www.eplusbroadband.com/acp">Jackson Energy Authority</a></li><li>Mediacom </li><li><a href="https://mlgc.com/acp/">MLGC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.spectrum.com/cp/broadband-get-qualified?p1=1-877-958-7103&amp;opredirect=acp">Spectrum</a> (Charter Communications</li><li><a href="https://starry.com/acp/">Starry</a></li><li><a href="https://www.verizon.com/home/fios-forward">Verizon</a> (Fios only)</li><li><a href="https://www.vermontel.com/acp">Vermont Telephone Company</a></li><li><a href="http://www.vexusfiber.com/acp">Vexus Fiber</a></li><li><a href="https://www.wowway.com/affordable-connectivity-program">Wow!</a> Internet, Cable, and TV</li></ul>



<p>These companies serve urban, suburban, and rural communities across the country. Collectively, they offer high-speed internet services in areas in which over 80% of the U.S. population lives, including nearly 50% of the rural population. The Biden-Harris Administration is grateful for the efforts of these companies, and encourages additional internet service providers to join this effort to close the digital divide by offering high-speed, low-cost plans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on the U.S. and G7 Actions to Impose Additional Severe Costs for Putin&#8217;s War Against&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/08/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-the-u-s-and-g7-actions-to-impose-additional-severe-costs-for-putins-war-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 16:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 7:21 A.M. EDT&#160;MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks everyone for joining us.&#160; I know it’s pretty early on a Sunday morning.&#160;&#160;So we’re going to turn it over to [senior administration official] who is going to be our speaker for your awareness.&#160;&#160;But this call is on background, and it’s attributable to a “senior administration official.”&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>7:21 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks everyone for joining us.&nbsp; I know it’s pretty early on a Sunday morning.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we’re going to turn it over to [senior administration official] who is going to be our speaker for your awareness.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this call is on background, and it’s attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; The contents of this call are going to be embargoed until 12:00 p.m. today.<br>&nbsp;<br>So with that, I’m going to turn it over to [senior administration official] to give some remarks, and then we’ll take some questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Over to you, [senior administration official].<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [moderator].&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, as well for joining early.&nbsp; And Happy Mother’s Day.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our sanctions design from the start has been predicated on applying economic pressure where we have an asymmetric advantage, where we and our allies produce something Russia needs and can’t easily get from anywhere else.&nbsp; And in doing so, we strengthen Ukraine’s position on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.&nbsp; That was the premise for cutting off Russia from the leading financial centers of the world &#8212; New York, London, Tokyo, Switzerland, Singapore.&nbsp; The oxygen of any market-based economy is financial capital, and that’s been deprived for &#8212; that’s been taken away from Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s why we’ve denied critical technology inputs and investment capital Putin needs to replenish his weaponry and diversify growth away from just oil and gas.&nbsp; That’s why we’ve denied access to critical markets that Putin needs to sell his goods.&nbsp; No export is more important to Putin than oil; it’s the main artery of his economy.&nbsp; And the EU is now on the cusp of joining the U.S., Canada, and the UK in cutting off this trade.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the same logic applies to the services ban we are announcing today.&nbsp; Russia has long relied on services provided by G7 countries to operate a modern economy, especially services provided by the United States and the United Kingdom, which are the dominant service providers in the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So today we’re banning the provision of accounting services, management consulting, marketing &#8212; all services that are used to operate multinational businesses, but also to potentially create workarounds from sanctions or to hide ill-gotten wealth.&nbsp; That’s why we’re shutting down these services.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re also announcing today that U.S. advertising dollars, broadcast technology, video cameras, microphones, equipment for sound will no longer be available to the three most watched state-owned or -controlled Russian TV stations that enable Putin’s propaganda machine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Some of you have reported on the lies upon lies that are spread on these mouthpieces of the Kremlin, such as claiming the people of Bucha were not killed until days after Russians left the region, or that the placement of dead Ukrainian bodies was staged, or that the brave Ukrainians defending their country are actually the aggressors.<br>&nbsp;<br>After today, no U.S. company can be in the business of funding or supporting the disinformation machine that masks the truth of Putin’s barbaric invasion behind lies and deceit.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re also adding to our export controls and sanctions that directly degrade Russia’s war efforts, including controls on industrial engines and bulldozers.&nbsp; The EU is moving in tandem with additional controls on chemicals, for example, that feed directly into Russia’s military industrial complex.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These new controls will further limit Russia’s access to components that it needs to replenish and restock its military capabilities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As a result of our export controls applied to date, Russia’s two major tank plants, the Uralz- &#8212; I’m going to mispronounce these &#8212; the Uralvagonzavod Corporation and the Chelyabinsk Tractor Plant have halted work due to the lack of foreign components.&nbsp; Russian companies that operate heavy machinery made by Caterpillar or John Deere are reporting halts in their production or significant disruptions.&nbsp; Boeing has halted major operations in Russia and ended all exports of spare parts to Russian airlines, as has Airbus.<br>&nbsp;<br>The last thing we’re doing today is we’re adding 2,600 visa restrictions in response to ongoing human rights violations and atrocities committed by Russian military officials and Belarusian officials, and we’re sanctioning more bank executives from the largest bank in Russia, Sberbank, as well as the third-largest bank, Gazprombank.&nbsp; The latter of which we have not previously touched with sanctions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Taken together, today’s actions are a continuation of the systematic and methodical removal of Russia from the global financial and economic system.&nbsp; And the message is: There will be no safe havens in the Russian economy if Putin’s invasion continues.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Happy to take your questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Could we please queue up the directions to ask the questions?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; And, yes, Happy Mother&#8217;s Day.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], can you just give a little more on this?&nbsp; You mentioned they were bulldozers &#8212; these are export controls.&nbsp; Can you dive a little bit more into that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And can you update us on what you&#8217;re seeing in terms of Russian efforts to evade or circumvent?&nbsp; Is this continuing to be a problem?&nbsp; Is clamping down part of the discussion for the G7?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, on services, does consulting services count?&nbsp; A lot of these major Russian companies &#8212; oligarchs &#8212; have consultants across the U.S.&nbsp; Is that being halted as well?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, Josh.&nbsp; So first, on the export controls: I mentioned bulldozers, but also industrial engines.&nbsp; And these are all &#8212; these are all asymmetries.&nbsp; So we supply components that Russia needs to feed its military industrial complex.&nbsp; I would add chemicals, auto parts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These are &#8212; we started out with foundational technology inputs.&nbsp; So, you know, we placed a lot of focus on Western microchips and the impact that&#8217;s having on precision-guided missiles.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re moving &#8212; we&#8217;re broadening into industrial products that have a similar effect, we think, on Putin&#8217;s ability to prosecute his war ambitions.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve added these products.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it&#8217;s really a powerful combination because while Europe certainly has the bulk of the traded goods relationship with Russia, we do too.&nbsp; And now that we&#8217;ve added services, you can think of these as working in tandem.&nbsp; Europe has the bulk of the goods relationship with Russia.&nbsp; The U.S. and the UK have historically provided most of the services from the West to Russia, and we&#8217;re cutting both off.&nbsp; And they should mutually reinforce each other.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Your second question was on Russia&#8217;s efforts to evade or circumvent sanctions, and I am not hearing of any success Russia is having in supplying these parts from anywhere else.&nbsp; I mean, we mapped this out pretty carefully beforehand, in terms of our export controls and especially on technologies.&nbsp; And we picked &#8212; we picked goods, we picked services, we picked technologies that we and the Europeans and the G7 and our partners in Asia were the dominant suppliers of.&nbsp; And we don&#8217;t think Russia has many options other than to try to produce these goods or services domestically, which I think would be a very tall task.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Lastly, your question on management consulting: Yes, that is within the scope of these of this services ban.&nbsp; We know that these management consulting firms have tended to provide their services to the largest companies in Russia, often state-owned enterprises under the control of the Kremlin.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The same is true of the big four accountants.&nbsp; They employ over 10,000 people in Russia.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve &#8212; together, the accountants and the management consultants, they&#8217;ve been asked, we think, by Russian companies to help them figure out how to reformulate their business strategies in the wake of sanctions &#8212; in some cases, how to get around these sanctions or, in the case of accountants, how to hide some of their wealth.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re shutting that &#8212; we&#8217;re shutting that down.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; One is: I don&#8217;t see lawyers or legal services on this list, and I want to ask, why?&nbsp; Because American lawyers historically have been valuable to Russian businesspeople in hiding their money and making investments.&nbsp; Why aren&#8217;t they on the list?<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, could you speak a little bit about the problem of blowback of these and other sanctions on the Western economy?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, David, you&#8217;re right; legal services are not on the list.&nbsp; And we made a judgment, at least for now, that if there was a desire to seek due process through a U.S. lawyer, we would allow that to continue.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re reevaluating, you know, the breadth of these services, sanctions every day.&nbsp; And depending on how we see behavior change over time, we can certainly broaden the sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>The UK has also not banned legal services at this point either, but we&#8217;re closely talking.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking very actively about whether we ought to broaden.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;ll just watch what happens in the aftermath of this ban.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the spillovers, David, we&#8217;re focused, as you know, on the three main spillovers from Putin&#8217;s invasion: energy &#8212; energy being the most important to the developed world, but also food insecurity, which is, I think, the dominant concern across much of the developing world.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing all we can on both fronts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll start with food.&nbsp; You know all of the statistics: 30 percent of the world&#8217;s wheat exports come from Ukraine and Russia, 20 percent of corn, 80 percent of sunflower oil, and about one sixth of fertilizer.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s having a global impact.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What can we do about it?&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re speaking out as loudly as we can that this is not the time for countries to have export bans on their food exports.&nbsp; For countries that have spare production capacity and food, they should produce more.&nbsp; For countries that have stockpiles of food, they should release those stockpiles to the countries most in need.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the international financial institutions, the IMF and the World Bank, they can provide a targeted support to countries that have the most acute food insecurity problems.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s really important to prevent balance of payments issues as this invasion &#8212; if this invasion continues.<br>&nbsp;<br>On energy, there&#8217;s a lot to say.&nbsp; We are &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re taking action together on Putin’s main export source, which is oil &#8212; and gas to a lesser extent &#8212; because that helps to fund his war machine.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the main source of relevance from the Russian economy to the rest of the world. &nbsp;We want to downgrade his status as a leading energy supplier.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we want to do that while maintaining global energy supplies at a steady level.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve released over 200 million barrels from a strategic reserves.&nbsp; We&#8217;re encouraging domestic producers to respond to price signals and get together with Wall Street and see this as a moment for securing America&#8217;s energy independence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, we can certainly surge natural gas supplies to Europe as much as we can.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also working with partners in Qatar and Australia to add more natural gas supply to Europe, because that&#8217;s the key pressure point on the continent.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this is going to be an ongoing effort; it&#8217;s not going to be easy.&nbsp; We have to do all of this, of course, while we&#8217;re ceding our transition towards cleaner and more reliable energy sources.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re &#8212; you know, the President, you’ve heard him say he wants to double down, triple down, quadruple down on that transition.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much for doing this.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, you mentioned that this was the first time you&#8217;ve gone after Gazprombank which, as you noted, was the number three bank.&nbsp; I assume that was because of the overall European sensitivity about going after gas and Gazprom.&nbsp; But tell us a little bit about what changed your mind there, and what changed the Europeans’ minds?<br>&nbsp;<br>And second: How clear have you been to the Russians about exactly what they would need to do to get sanctions removed?&nbsp; Because since we&#8217;ve &#8212; it sounds like we&#8217;ve had a couple of different standards set for what the ultimate U.S. objective here is.&nbsp; And, of course, sanctions wouldn&#8217;t come off all at one time.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m just wondering what kind of clarity you have delivered to the Russians about what exactly they need to do to reverse this?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, David.&nbsp; On the first question, just to clarify: We are not sanctioning Gazprombank, in the same way that we did with SpareBank or VTB or any of the other largest banks.&nbsp; This is not a full block.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not freezing the assets of Gazprombank or prohibiting any transactions with Gazprombank.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we&#8217;re signaling is that Gazprombank is not a safe haven, and so we&#8217;re sanctioning some of their top business executives &#8212; they&#8217;re the people who sit at the top of the organization &#8212; to create a chilling effect.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you&#8217;re right that Gazprombank is the main way in which Russia sells gas to Europe, and so that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve been cautious about shutting down its operations while Europe is still importing gas from Russia.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t want Gazprombank to be seen as a safe haven, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve taken action against its top &#8212; his top &#8212; its top people.<br>&nbsp;<br>With respect to rollback, a few things: One, we would never do a deal on sanctions rollback without Ukraine at the head of the table.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The second, if we get to the point at which this is being discussed, it really would depend on the overall shape and scope of the diplomatic agreement that&#8217;s being negotiated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, third, any kind of deal like that requires trust, and Putin hasn&#8217;t given the world any reason to trust his word.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the last thing I would say is: We know, David, these sanctions work through market-based channels.&nbsp; Markets are forward looking.&nbsp; So once you change the direction of sanctions, you know, the market could very well price in the endpoint of that process.&nbsp; So in the same way that the market has applied a multiplier as these sanctions have been put on, it could very well do the same when they begin to be taken off.&nbsp; We know that, and that&#8217;s an important consideration.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Just a couple of follow-up questions on these things.&nbsp; Number one, can you clarify when all of these sanctions will be put into place?&nbsp; Does it kickoff today?<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, can you give any more details about what the President will be discussing with his G7 counterparts?&nbsp; I presume this will be a good chunk of that discussion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And number three, can you respond broadly to some criticism that these and other sanctions are hurting not only Putin and his government, but also people in Russia who would be &#8212; and who are standing up to him and working on resistance to Russia and the Kremlin?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, Jeff.&nbsp; So these sanctions we&#8217;re announcing go into effect in the U.S. today, or, in some cases, they get published to the Federal Register tomorrow &#8212; the export controls, for example &#8212; but they&#8217;re going to be unveiled today.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ll see a factsheet on this shortly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Other jurisdictions in the G7 are following their own processes.&nbsp; The Europeans are still finalizing their package, so they can speak to the timeline.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the purpose of the G7 meeting today, it&#8217;s really about honoring the incredible sacrifices that our people made, the people of Ukraine made, and even the citizens, of course, of the Soviet Union to defeat fascism.&nbsp; And to say, together: Putin is dishonoring those sacrifices by spreading his lies, his disinformation about the barbarism that he is committing in Ukraine.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s really a chance to speak the truth and to demonstrate our continued unity and our commitment to strengthening Ukraine&#8217;s hand on the battlefield and at the negotiating table, and to also ratchet up the pain on Putin, which segues to your third question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, these sanctions are not an end to themselves; they&#8217;re intended to change the strategic calculus of the target.&nbsp; And Putin, like any autocrat, has a social contract.&nbsp; And he has taken away the freedom of the people of Russia in exchange for stability, and he&#8217;s no longer delivering upon that.&nbsp; And so, if thousands of body bags are coming home, if debit cards aren&#8217;t working, if shelves aren&#8217;t stocked the way they used to, all people can buy anymore are knockoff clothes and phones and cars.&nbsp; And if Russia is eventually in default and the country is bankrupt, the question we&#8217;re putting to him: Is that the endgame he was really looking for?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys, thanks so much for doing this call.&nbsp; Just a few more questions.&nbsp; To follow up, I think, on Jeff’s last question: Obviously, we had heard that this call today was deliberately planned to come ahead of Victory Day.&nbsp; I wonder if you could preview any of the President&#8217;s remarks today &#8212; either to G7 or if he&#8217;s going to speak about it tomorrow &#8212; specifically, on the day where a lot of folks feel like it&#8217;s going to mark a new chapter in the Russian invasion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And secondly, on sanctions, we know that you&#8217;ve added, of course, more people to the list, but I wonder if &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to butcher her name &#8212; if there&#8217;s been an update on the U.S.’s thinking about sanctioning Putin’s rumored girlfriend, Alina Kabaeva &#8212; we&#8217;ve reported that the EU at least has thought about putting her on the list &#8212; and if you expect that to come up today?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then on the media portion &#8212; obviously, this is something that you guys are kind of moving into this area &#8212; I wonder, in terms of when you&#8217;re talking about blocking U.S. advertising dollars, how much of an impact do you guys think that that practically will have?&nbsp; And has there been an effort on the U.S.’s part to kind of counter the messaging that these different propaganda machines have had actually in Russia to the Russian people?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say &#8212; I’ll try to say a bit more about the G7 meeting.&nbsp; You know, I think what you’ll hear from the leaders today is that we have &#8212; we can take stock of where we are.&nbsp; And we all, I think, have the same perspective on where Putin has &#8212; where Putin has failed in this effort.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, in terms of his objectives, he set out, first and foremost, to divide the West, but we&#8217;re stronger and more united than at any point in the post-Cold War era.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he aimed to undermine or topple Ukraine&#8217;s leadership, but the democratically elected government of Ukraine still stands.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he seemed to expect a quick victory in Kyiv, but it&#8217;s still standing.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s now retreated and focused elsewhere.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is already a failure for Putin.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;re going to continue to honor the brave fighting that&#8217;s taking place by Ukraine&#8217;s people, and listen to President Zelenskyy, and just recommit to staying the course, to staying unified.&nbsp; And to ratcheting up the costs on Putin to strengthen Ukraine’s hands on the battlefield and, again, at the negotiating table.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of Putin&#8217;s girlfriend, I don&#8217;t have anything for you there.&nbsp; I know the EU is looking at this; we&#8217;re looking at this.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have an announcement for you to make on that front today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then lastly, on the media &#8212; the media actions, the TV stations &#8212; just to give you a bit more: We are sanctioning the three main television stations in Russia: Channel One, Russia, One, NTV.&nbsp; These are all stations owned by the state or controlled by the state or owned by one of Putin&#8217;s closest allies.&nbsp; They&#8217;re also among the most widely watched in Russia.&nbsp; It&#8217;s how most people in Russia get their news from the television.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, the reality is: Western companies were among the top advertisers on these stations last year &#8212; well above $300 million worth of advertising.&nbsp; A lot of these advertisers have announced since the invasion that they&#8217;re going to cut their business activity with these stations, but we want to make sure that decision endures and just send a broader signal that U.S. companies should not be in the business of funding Russian propaganda.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The other element of this sanction is that Russian TV stations, in many cases, rely on Western technology to broadcast the propaganda.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what I was referring to when I mentioned the video cameras, the microphones, the controls for digital sound, lighting equipment, software servers.&nbsp; Russia can try to produce these components domestically.&nbsp; But the idea here is to make that commercially difficult, unprofitable, put more of the burden on the Russian state.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not going to be in the business of helping them broadcast some of the lies and the deceit that you hear from Putin every day.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; The contents of this call are embargoed until 12:00 p.m. Eastern today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You guys should have also gotten the factsheet &#8212; embargoed until 12:00 p.m.&nbsp; If you didn&#8217;t, please feel free to reach out to me and we&#8217;ll make sure you get that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thanks again, everyone, for joining.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>7:44 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and G7 Partners Impose Severe Costs for Putin’s War Against&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/08/fact-sheet-united-states-and-g7-partners-impose-severe-costs-for-putins-war-against-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden and G7 Leaders Meet with President Zelenskyy to Continue our Efforts to Support Ukraine and Build on our Unprecedented Sanctions and Export Controls Today, President Biden and G7 Leaders met with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine to reinforce our shared commitment to strengthen Ukraine’s position on the battlefield and at the negotiating table. Our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>President Biden and G7 Leaders Meet with President Zelenskyy to Continue our Efforts to Support Ukraine and Build on our Unprecedented Sanctions and Export Controls</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden and G7 Leaders met with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine to reinforce our shared commitment to strengthen Ukraine’s position on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.<br><br>Our unprecedented sanctions are already exacting an immense toll on Russia’s economy and our export controls have strangled Russia’s access to critical technology and the supply chains it needs to sustain its military ambitions. Putin’s war is projected to wipe out the last 15 years of economic gains in Russia. As a result of our export controls, Russia is struggling to replenish its military weapons and equipment. Russia’s two major tank plants – Uralvagonzavod Corporation and Chelyabinsk Tractor Plant – have halted work due to lack of foreign components. Almost 1,000 private sector companies have left Russia, and reports indicate that more than 200,000 Russians, many of whom are highly skilled, have fled the country. All of these costs will compound and intensify over time.<br><br>Putin has failed in his initial military objective to dominate Ukraine – but he has succeeded in making Russia a global pariah. Today, the United States, the European Union and G7 committed to ratchet up these costs by collectively taking further measures, consistent with each partner’s respective legal authorities and processes.<br><br><strong>Targeting State-Controlled Media Within Russia That Bolster Putin’s War. </strong>The United States will sanction three of Russia’s most highly-viewed directly or indirectly state-controlled television stations in Russia – Joint Stock Company Channel One Russia, Television Station Russia-1, and Joint Stock Company NTV Broadcasting Company. All three stations have been among the largest recipients of foreign revenue, which feeds back to the Russian State’s revenue.<br><br><strong>Banning Services that Help Finance Putin’s War and Aid Sanctions Evasion. </strong>The United States will prohibit U.S. persons from providing accounting, trust and corporate formation, and management consulting services to any person in the Russian Federation. These services are key to Russian companies and elites building wealth, thereby generating revenue for Putin’s war machine, and to trying to hide that wealth and evade sanctions. This action builds on previous prohibitions to restrict the export of goods related to aerospace, marine, electronics, technology, and defense and related materiel sectors of the Russian economy.<br><br><strong>Cutting off Imports of Russian Oil and Reducing Dependence on Russian Energy. </strong>The United States has already banned the import of Russian oil, gas, and coal. Today, the entire G7 committed to phasing out or banning the import of Russian oil. This will hit hard at the main artery of Putin’s economy and deny him the revenue he needs to fund his war. The G7 also committed to work together to ensure stable global energy supplies, while accelerating our efforts to reduce dependence on fossil fuels.<br><br><strong>Impose further export controls and sanctions to degrade Russia’s war efforts.  </strong>The United States will issue a new rule that imposes additional restrictions on Russia’s industrial sector, including a broad range of inputs and products including wood products, industrial engines, boilers, motors, fans, and ventilation equipment, bulldozers, and many other items with industrial and commercial applications. These new controls will further limit Russia’s access to items and revenue that could support its military capabilities. The United States also sanctioned Limited Liability Company Promtekhnologiya, which produces rifles and other weapons that have been used in military operations in Ukraine; seven shipping companies, which own or operate 69 vessels; and one marine towing company. The Nuclear Regulatory Commission will also suspend general licenses for exports of source material, special nuclear material, byproduct material, and deuterium to Russia.<br><br><strong>Impose Sanctions on Russian Elites and their Family Members and Visa Restrictions on Russian and Belarusian Officials Undermining the Sovereignty, Territorial Integrity, or Political Independence of Ukraine. </strong>The United States imposed approximately 2,600 visa restrictions on Russian and Belarusian officials in response to their ongoing efforts to undermine the sovereignty, territorial integrity, or political independence of Ukraine. Additionally, the United States issued a new visa restriction policy that applies to Russian Federation military officials and Russia-backed or Russia-installed purported authorities who are believed to have been involved in human rights abuses, violations of international humanitarian law, or public corruption in Ukraine. The United States also sanctioned eight executives from Sberbank– the largest financial institution in Russia and uniquely important to the Russian economy, holding about a third of all bank assets in Russia; twenty-seven executives from Gazprombank – a prominent Russian bank facilitating business by Russia’s Gazprom, one of the largest natural gas exporters in the world; and Moscow Industrial Bank and its ten subsidiaries.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>G7 Leaders’ Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/08/g7-leaders-statement-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, on 8 May, we, the Leaders of the Group of Seven (G7), alongside Ukraine and the wider global community, commemorate the end of the Second World War in Europe and the liberation from fascism and the National Socialist reign of terror, which caused immeasurable destruction, unspeakable horrors and human suffering. We mourn the millions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<ol><li>Today, on 8 May, we, the Leaders of the Group of Seven (G7), alongside Ukraine and the wider global community, commemorate the end of the Second World War in Europe and the liberation from fascism and the National Socialist reign of terror, which caused immeasurable destruction, unspeakable horrors and human suffering. We mourn the millions of victims and offer our respect, especially to all those who paid the ultimate price to defeat the National Socialist regime, including the western Allies and the Soviet Union.</li><li>Seventy-seven years later, President Putin and his regime now chose to invade Ukraine in an unprovoked war of aggression against a sovereign country. His actions bring shame on Russia and the historic sacrifices of its people. Through its invasion of and actions in Ukraine since 2014, Russia has violated the international rules-based order, particularly the UN Charter, conceived after the Second World War to spare successive generations from the scourge of war.</li><li>Today, we were honoured to be joined by Ukraine’s President Volodymyr Zelenskyy. We assured him of our full solidarity and support for Ukraine’s courageous defence of its sovereignty and territorial integrity, and its fight for a peaceful, prosperous and democratic future within its internationally recognised borders, with the liberties and freedoms that so many of us enjoy today.</li><li>President Zelenskyy underlined the strong resolve of Ukraine to protect its sovereignty and territorial integrity. He stated that Ukraine’s ultimate aim is to ensure full withdrawal of Russia’s military forces and equipment from the entire territory of Ukraine and to secure its ability to protect itself in the future and thanked G7 members for their support. In this regard, Ukraine emphasised that it relies on its international partners, in particular on G7 members, in providing necessary assistance in the domain of defense capabilities, as well as with a view to ensuring a swift and effective recovery of Ukraine’s economy and to securing its economic and energy security. Ukraine has entered into discussions with international partners on security mechanisms for a viable post-war peace settlement. Ukraine remains committed to working closely with G7 members to support Ukraine’s macroeconomic stability in the face of the challenges posed by the full-scaled Russian invasion, massive destruction of critical infrastructure and disruption of traditional shipping routes for Ukrainian exports. President Zelenskyy noted his country’s commitment to uphold our common democratic values and principles, including respect for human rights and the rule of law.</li><li>Today, we, the G7, reassured President Zelenskyy of our continued readiness to undertake further commitments to help Ukraine secure its free and democratic future, such that Ukraine can defend itself now and deter future acts of aggression. To this end, we will pursue our ongoing military and defence assistance to the Ukrainian Armed Forces, continue supporting Ukraine in defending its networks against cyber incidents, and expand our cooperation, including on information security. We will continue to support Ukraine in increasing its economic and energy security.</li><li>Together with the international community, we, the G7, have provided and pledged additional support since the start of the war exceeding USD 24 billion for 2022 and beyond, in both financial and material means. In the coming weeks, we will step up our collective short-term financial support to help Ukraine close financing gaps and deliver basic services to its people, while also developing options – working with the Ukrainian authorities and international financial institutions – to support long-term recovery and reconstruction. In this regard, we welcome the establishment of the International Monetary Fund’s Multi-Donor Administered Account for Ukraine and the European Union announcement to develop a Ukraine Solidarity Trust Fund. We support the World Bank Group’s support package to Ukraine and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development’s Resilience Package.</li><li>We call on all partners to join our support for the Ukrainian people and for refugees, and to help Ukraine to rebuild its future.</li><li>We reiterate our condemnation of Russia’s unprovoked, unjustifiable and illegal military aggression against Ukraine and the indiscriminate attacks against civilians and civilian infrastructure, which has resulted in terrible humanitarian catastrophe in the heart of Europe. We are appalled by the large-scale loss of human life, assault on human rights, and destruction that Russia’s actions have inflicted on Ukraine.</li><li>Under no circumstances can civilians and those not taking an active part in the hostilities be legitimate targets. We will spare no effort to hold President Putin and the architects and accomplices of this aggression, including the Lukashenko regime in Belarus, accountable for their actions in accordance with international law. To this end, we will continue to work together, along with our allies and partners around the world. We reaffirm our support for all efforts to ensure full accountability. We welcome and support the ongoing work to investigate and gather evidence on this, including by the Prosecutor of the International Criminal Court, the independent investigation commission mandated by the United Nations Human Rights Council and the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe’s mission of experts.</li><li>We further condemn Russia’s attempts to replace democratically elected Ukrainian local authorities with illegitimate ones. We will not recognise these acts in violation of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</li><li>We will continue to counter the Russian strategy of disinformation, which deliberately manipulates the global – including the Russian – public in the hope of shrouding the Russian regime’s culpability for this war.</li><li>Our unprecedented package of coordinated sanctions has already significantly hindered Russia’s war of aggression by limiting access to financial channels and ability to pursue their objectives. These restrictive measures are already having a significant impact on all Russian economic sectors – financial, trade, defence, technology, and energy – and will intensify pressure on Russia over time. We will continue to impose severe and immediate economic costs on President Putin’s regime for this unjustifiable war. We collectively commit to taking the following measures, consistent with our respective legal authorities and processes:<br><br>a. First, we commit to phase out our dependency on Russian energy, including by phasing out or banning the import of Russian oil. We will ensure that we do so in a timely and orderly fashion, and in ways that provide time for the world to secure alternative supplies. As we do so, we will work together and with our partners to ensure stable and sustainable global energy supplies and affordable prices for consumers, including by accelerating reduction of our overall reliance on fossil fuels and our transition to clean energy in accordance with our climate objectives.<br><br>b. Second, we will take measures to prohibit or otherwise prevent the provision of key services on which Russia depends. This will reinforce Russia’s isolation across all sectors of its economy.<br><br>c. Third, we will continue to take action against Russian banks connected to the global economy and systemically critical to the Russian financial system. We have already severely impaired Russia’s ability to finance its war of aggression by targeting its Central Bank and its largest financial institutions.<br><br>d. Fourth, we will continue our efforts to fight off the Russian regime’s attempts to spread its propaganda. Respectable private companies should not provide revenue to the Russian regime or to its affiliates feeding the Russian war machine.<br><br>e. Fifth, we will continue and elevate our campaign against the financial elites and family members, who support President Putin in his war effort and squander the resources of the Russian people. Consistent with our national authorities, we will impose sanctions on additional individuals.</li><li>We continue to work with our international partners and invite them to stand with us and to follow suit with similar actions, including to prevent sanctions evasion, circumvention and backfilling.</li><li>President Putin’s war is causing global economic disruptions, impacting the security of global energy supply, fertiliser and food provision, and the functioning of global supply chains in general. The most vulnerable countries are affected most severely. Together with partners globally, we are stepping up our efforts to counter these adverse and harmful impacts of this war.</li><li>President Putin’s war against Ukraine is placing global food security under severe strain. Together with the United Nations, we call on Russia to end its blockade and all other activities that further impede Ukrainian food production and exports, in line with its international commitments. Failure to do so will be seen as an attack on feeding the world. We will step up efforts to help Ukraine to keep producing in view of the next harvest season and exporting, including by alternative routes.</li><li>In support of the United Nations Global Crises Response Group, we will address the causes and consequences of the global food crisis through a Global Alliance for Food Security, as our joint initiative to ensure momentum and coordination, and other efforts. We will closely cooperate with international partners and organisations beyond the G7, and, with the aim of transforming political commitments into concrete actions as planned by various international initiatives such as the Food and Agriculture Resilience Mission (FARM) and key regional outreach initiatives, including towards African and Mediterranean countries. We reiterate that our sanctions packages are carefully targeted so as not to impede the delivery of humanitarian assistance or the trade of agricultural products and reaffirm our commitment to avoid food export restrictions which impact the most vulnerable.</li><li>The G7 and Ukraine stand united in this difficult time and in their quest to ensure Ukraine’s democratic, prosperous future. We remain united in our resolve that President Putin must not win his war against Ukraine. We owe it to the memory of all those who fought for freedom in the Second World War, to continue fighting for it today, for the people of Ukraine, Europe and the global community.</li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Tennessee State University 2022 Spring Undergraduate Commencement&#160;Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/07/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-tennessee-state-university-2022-spring-undergraduate-commencement-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 22:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nashville, TN THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Good morning.  Good morning.  Jada, thank you for that introduction and for your 4.0.  How about that?  Greetings, Tigers.  Greetings to all of you.  (Applause.) And to the members of the board, distinguished faculty, and staff, thank you for this tremendous honor.    I cannot say enough about the president of this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Nashville, TN</em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Good morning.  Good morning.  Jada, thank you for that introduction and for your 4.0.  How about that? <br> <br>Greetings, Tigers.  Greetings to all of you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And to the members of the board, distinguished faculty, and staff, thank you for this tremendous honor.   <br> <br>I cannot say enough about the president of this university, Dr. Glenda Glover.  (Applause.)  Dr. Glover, you have been a tremendous friend to me for many years, and I thank you for your leadership.  And Tennessee State is extremely fortunate to have you as its leader.<br> <br>To the class of 2022: Congratulations to all of you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And we are, of course, joined today by your professors and your coaches and university staff who have been by your side for every step of this journey.  Let’s give them another round of applause.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And to all of the families and the loved ones who are here &#8212; the parents and the grandparents, the aunties and the uncles, the godparents: I thank you.  I thank you. <br> <br>I know over these last years, it has been you who have delivered the care packages, who have offered up a place to do laundry.  You spent money when they called you and said, &#8220;I need a little bit for books or maybe my sorority dues.&#8221;  (Applause.) <br> <br>And through it all, you were just a phone call or a text away.<br> <br>And to all of you &#8212; to all of you in these stands: These graduates are your legacy.  When they walk across this stage today and receive their diploma, you will walk with them.  And I recognize the pride in your eyes.  I can see it from here.<br> <br>Graduates, I know it has been a long, hard road, but you all made it.  You made it. <br> <br>And right now, I&#8217;m going to ask you to take a moment.  Take a moment and look to your left and look to your right.  And take a good look at the folks sitting around you right now.  These are the folks who have been by your side, literally and virtually, since your first day as a Tiger.<br> <br>Together, you all have been through $10 Tuesdays<br>at Slim &amp; Husky’s.  (Laughter.) <br> <br>Together, you all have been through last-minute scrambles to memorize a speech for freshman Public Speaking.<br> <br>Together, you have been through the return to campus and, just as importantly, through the return to in-person homecoming.<br> <br>You made it through together.<br> <br>I speak from personal experience when I say &#8212; hear me now &#8212; there are future members of your wedding party in this class.  Someone sitting near you will ask you to be godparent to their child.<br> <br>Over the years, you will reach out to some of the people around you when you&#8217;ve had a bad day or a great one, and they will reach out to you, too.<br> <br>And many of them might be present for your swearing-in after your election to public office.<br> <br>Class of 2022, you made it through.<br> <br>And it cannot be denied also that your class has traveled a stony road &#8212; a pandemic that took away so much of the college experience that you once imagined.<br> <br>And the world that you graduate into is unsettled.  It is a world where long-established principles now rest on shaky ground. <br> <br>We see this in Ukraine, where Russia’s invasion threatens international rules and norms that have provided unprecedented peace and security in Europe since World War Two.<br> <br>We believed that the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity had, for the most part, prevailed &#8212; that democracy had prevailed.  But now, the certainty of fundamental principles is being called into question, including the principles of equality and fairness.<br> <br>Inequality has always, sadly, existed in our world.  The gaps between the rich and the poor, men and women, the global north and global south have existed throughout our history.<br> <br>And through this pandemic, the gaps have become much larger.  Globally, extreme poverty is on the rise, as is extreme wealth.<br> <br>You graduate into an unsettled world, both abroad and here at home.<br> <br>In the United States, we are once again forced to defend fundamental principles that we hoped were long-settled: principles like the freedom to vote, the rights of women to make decisions about their own bodies &#8212; (applause) &#8212; even what constitutes the truth, especially in an era when anyone can post anything online and claim it is a fact.<br> <br>We must also grapple with the urgent issues that have not been settled.  Some of them have been accelerated during your lifetime, like the need to address the climate crisis.<br> <br>Some we have been struggling with since the founding of our nation: disparities in who has access to healthcare, disparities in how people are treated by the criminal justice system, disparities in wealth and who has access to the capital required to succeed and thrive.<br> <br>And, graduates, I look at this unsettled world and, yes, I then see the challenges, but I&#8217;m here to tell you, I also see the opportunities.  The opportunities for your leadership.  The future of our country and our world will be shaped by you.<br> <br>And when I speak about &#8220;you,&#8221; I am talking about you as the class of 2022, as graduates of TSU.  You as individuals, each with your own lived experience.<br> <br>Each of these pieces of who you are comes with very special attributes, its own approach &#8212; these attributes &#8212; to tackling the biggest challenges of today. <br> <br>As the class of 2022, you bring possibility to the table.  You are a generation that grew up online and survived a pandemic.  You are familiar with a world that, for many of us, feels a bit strange and new.  You have been engaged with this world since you were little.<br> <br>And yet, of course, you do still have some prove to do.<br> <br>Most importantly, you have the ability to see what can be, unburdened by what has been.  To look at the challenges facing us and find solutions that generations before could have never imagined.<br> <br>You are, of course, more than just the class of 2022.  You are also a product of the education you received here on this campus.  And as soon-to-be graduates of Tennessee State, you are fueled by self-determination, fueled by big ambitions.<br> <br>Students from all over the world come here because they have big dreams. <br> <br>Now, I didn&#8217;t attend Tennessee State, but I am a fellow HBCU graduate.  (Applause.)  And I’d like to share a little story with you.  A story about the first time I flew on the vice presidential helicopter, which is called “Marine Two.”<br> <br>Now this day &#8212; it was not long after I was sworn in, and we were flying from Andrews Air Force Base to the official residence of the Vice President.  And one of the Marines asked me to look out the window. <br> <br>As it turns out, they had a surprise for me.  The helicopter was circling around Howard University, my alma mater.  I looked out the window of that helicopter, Marine Two, and I saw that we were over The Yard, which is Howard’s version of The Courtyard. <br> <br>As I looked down out of the window, I saw myself at 17 years old walking across campus with a big stack of books tucked under my arms at a place just like this.  That reinforced that I could be anything, do anything even if it had never been done before.  (Applause.)  Like you.  Like you and full of hope, full of dreams, with a future full of possibility just like you. <br> <br>I stand before you today as the Vice President of the United States of America and as a proud graduate of an HBCU to say: There is no limit to your capacity for greatness &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and there is no obstacle you cannot overcome, and there is no barrier you cannot break.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Your time at Tennessee State has unlocked unimaginable opportunities for your future, because you see, HBCUs like this &#8212; well, they are cathedrals of education.  And the value of this education is that it teaches you something very special: That, yes, you can be anything and do anything.<br> <br>And this brings me to the third reason why I know that you will play an essential role in shaping our nation’s future.  Each of you has your own story, your own way of looking at the world, shaped by every moment that brought you to this point.<br> <br>I was around your age when I decided that I wanted to take on systemic problems from the inside of the system, that I would look for solutions through the lens of my own experience and perspectives, and that I wanted and needed to be in the rooms where the decisions were being made.<br> <br>Graduates, you stand on the brink of a new frontier where we are building the platforms for the next phase of technology, where we are conducting the research that will lead to the next great medical breakthrough &#8212; maybe even the cures for cancer or lupus or lifesaving reforms to maternal healthcare &#8212; where we are defining the fundamental principles that will underpin the 21st century.  And we need you in the room helping to make these decisions.<br> <br>As Vice President, I spend a lot of time in these rooms.  I preside over debates in the United States Senate.  I consult with experts at the Goddard Space Flight Center as the Chair of the National Space Council.  I host bilateral meetings with heads of state at the White House.<br> <br>These are the rooms where decisions are being made.  And these are the rooms that I was taught early on by my family, my mentors, and professors, who always believed that I should know that I could be and should be in those rooms, just as I believe you should be in these rooms.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Graduates, we need you.  We need you to run companies and make decisions about who has access to capital. <br> <br>We need you to serve at the highest levels of government and determine our country’s standing in the world.<br> <br>We need you to work in our hospitals and in our courtrooms and in our schools.<br> <br>We need you to shape the future of technology.<br> <br>We need you because your perspective &#8212; the sum total of your intellect and your lived experience &#8212; will make our country stronger. <br> <br>And so, when you are in those rooms, my advice to you is to be true to yourself.  Hold close the values that your grandparents, your parents, your pastors, and your neighbors instilled in you.  Have the courage and conviction to follow your moral compass.<br> <br>And with that, there is one last message I will leave you with today.  I want you all &#8212; each and every one of you &#8212; to always remember that you are not alone, that you come from people, that you come with people. <br> <br>Because I promise you: There will be a time when you will walk into a boardroom or a courtroom or maybe even the Situation Room, and you will walk into the room and find you are the only person in that room who looks like you or has had your life experience.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And at that moment, you must remember you are not in that room alone.  Always know that you carry the voices of everyone here and those upon whose shoulders you stand.<br> <br>I started this address talking about how today also belongs to your family, and so I will end by talking about my own mother. <br> <br>She was the first person to tell me that my thoughts and my experiences mattered.  My mother would often say to me, “Kamala, you may be the first to do many things.  Make sure you are not the last.”<br> <br>I have been many firsts in my lifetime.  And as I look out at all of you today, I know I will not be the last.  (Applause.) <br> <br>I cannot wait to see the future you will create.<br> <br>Your country is so proud of you.<br> <br>Congratulations on this tremendous achievement.<br> <br>May God bless you.  And may God bless America.  Thank you all.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Responds to Early Wildfires in New&#160;Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/07/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-responds-to-early-wildfires-in-new-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 14:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Early season wildfires in New Mexico and across the Southwest are devastating communities and ravaging landscapes.&#160; So far this year, the number of acres burned across the United States is approximately 78% above the 10-year average.&#160; Much of the West, Plains, and Texas remain in a historic drought with above average temperatures and below normal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Early season wildfires in New Mexico and across the Southwest are devastating communities and ravaging landscapes.&nbsp; So far this year, the number of acres burned across the United States is approximately 78% above the 10-year average.&nbsp; Much of the West, Plains, and Texas remain in a historic drought with above average temperatures and below normal precipitation, creating the conditions for more large and dangerous wildfires this year.&nbsp; While the National Wildland Fire Preparedness Level remains at Level 2 (of 5), the Southwest Region was elevated to Preparedness Level 4 on April 19<sup>th</sup>, the earliest date this has ever occurred.&nbsp; New Mexico has been particularly hard hit, with six of the Nation’s ten large wildfires currently burning in the State, consuming more than 250,000 acres.&nbsp; This has created an unprecedented situation in the State, with far reaching impacts on communities, families, and livelihoods.</p>



<p><strong>The Biden Administration is taking prompt action to ensure that all applicable Federal resources are mobilized to help New Mexico communities respond to and recover from these devastating wildfires.</strong>&nbsp; The President receives regular briefings on the spread of fires in New Mexico from his Homeland Security Advisor.&nbsp; On Wednesday May 4, he approved a Major Disaster Declaration for Colfax, Lincoln, Mora, San Miguel, and Valencia Counties in New Mexico to support the State in responding to and recovering from several intense wildfires.</p>



<p><strong>Robust Wildfire Response</strong></p>



<p>The National Interagency Fire Center continues to surge resources to the area to address this early start to the region’s wildfire season, including firefighting crews, aircraft, engines, and incident management teams from the U.S. Forest Service (USFS) and the Department of the Interior (DOI).&nbsp; These Federal firefighters joined state, local, and Tribal firefighters in New Mexico for a unified and coordinated response growing to nearly 2,700 personnel as of May 6</p>



<p>FEMA has approved six Fire Management Assistance Grants to support New Mexico this year.&nbsp; These funds will support the state in providing mitigation, management, and control of the fires, as well as provide funding for emergency work, including procuring equipment and supplies for responders, supporting evacuation requirements such as traffic control and sheltering residents, pre-positioning resources to support the response, and establishing field camps and meals for responders.</p>



<p>Throughout the response, the Department of Energy’s Los Alamos National Laboratory (LANL) in Los Alamos, New Mexico has been working to ensure the safety and security of facilities and staff and is actively engaged with the surrounding community and response officials.&nbsp; LANL has pre-positioned assets to assist the Los Alamos Fire Department and Federal responders with the protection of key facilities.&nbsp; LANL is also continuing ongoing efforts to mitigate the risk of wildfire through fuels reduction activities. In addition, the Laboratory’s Wildland Fire team has reduced undergrowth and other fuels in the forests around the Lab property for many years and the Lab has prepared to prevent the spread of fire on Lab property.</p>



<p><strong>Support to Communities</strong></p>



<p>The President’s approval of a Major Disaster Declaration on May 4 provides <a href="https://www.fema.gov/disaster/4652">additional Federal funding</a> to help communities recover from the impacts of these fires.&nbsp; This support includes financial assistance for temporary and long-term housing, repairs, and other critical needs for people who have had to evacuate and makes available low-interest loans from the Small Business Administration for businesses and homeowners impacted by the fires.&nbsp;</p>



<p>FEMA has pre-positioned meals, water, and shelter items for 30,000 people.&nbsp; In addition, the American Red Cross and New Mexico have established shelters for residents who are displaced from their homes.</p>



<p>A Federal Coordinating Officer is on the ground and working with the State to identify and address emerging or unmet needs.&nbsp; FEMA’s Incident Management Assistance Team is embedded with the State Emergency Operations Center to assist with coordination of all Federal resources available to the State, and they are continuing to work with the State to conduct joint preliminary damage assessments that will inform recovery planning.&nbsp; FEMA has placed multi-lingual disaster survivor assistance teams on the ground to work directly with New Mexico residents impacted by the fires to ensure they have access to and are able to register quickly for Federal assistance.</p>



<p><strong>Resilient Recovery</strong></p>



<p>Looking ahead, the summer Southwestern monsoon season and associated heavy rains can cause substantial watershed impacts from burned areas. These events can result in significant soil erosion, flooding, and debris flows and impact both natural resources and communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;Federal agencies are working with the State and local communities to anticipate and prepare for potential flooding and to support post-fire mitigation activities.&nbsp;&nbsp;The USFS has established a statewide post-fire response and recovery team with New Mexico, the Natural Resource Conservation Service, the Farm Bureau, and other Federal interagency partners to coordinate efforts and access to funding for environmental response, stabilization, and recovery.</p>



<p>DOI and USFS interagency Burned Area Emergency Response teams have already been assigned to the New Mexico Fires. Teams are composed of resource specialists who determine the need for, prescribe, and can implement emergency treatments to minimize threats to life or property or prevent further damage to natural and cultural resources on Federal land. Assessments completed by these teams will support development of post fire recovery plans and actions in coordination with the state.</p>



<p>The USDA has made resources available to support farmers and ranchers whose land, crops, or livestock have been damaged or lost as a result of wildfires.&nbsp; These programs include the Livestock Indemnity Program; Emergency Assistance for Livestock, Honey Bees, and Farm-raised Fish; Forage Disaster Program; and the Noninsured Crop Disaster Assistance Program.&nbsp; USDA also provides low-interest loans to help farmers and ranchers recover from production and physical losses and reestablish their operations.&nbsp; Local USDA staff at county service centers near the declared counties are available to assist farmers and ranchers with accessing this assistance.</p>



<p>USDA also has programs to support mitigation and recovery, including an Environmental Quality Incentives Program to assist with immediate needs and long-term support to help recover from natural disasters and conserve water resources, an Emergency Conservation Program to rehabilitate farmlands damaged by disaster, and an Emergency Forest Restoration Program to restore private forestlands.&nbsp; USDA’s Emergency Watershed Protection Program can also help relieve imminent threats to life and property caused by fire that impairs a watershed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden Administration will continue to work hard to ensure that the Federal government does everything it can to provide support to New Mexicans who need help as a result of these early and extremely damaging wildfires. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Trudeau of&#160;Canada</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-trudeau-of-canada/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 01:45:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada. Both leaders underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine and economic and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada. Both leaders underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine and economic and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected by the violence. The President lauded Canada’s close partnership throughout this crisis, and leadership in enacting comprehensive sanctions and restrictions on Russia. The leaders also discussed their upcoming participation in the Summit of the Americas in June, and their shared vision for green and equitable growth for the hemisphere, among other Summit goals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
