<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 03:46:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Calls for a Three-Month Federal Gas Tax&#160;Holiday</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/fact-sheet-president-biden-calls-for-a-three-month-federal-gas-tax-holiday/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The price of gas is up dramatically around the world, and by almost $2 per gallon in America, since Putin began amassing troops on the border of Ukraine. President Biden understands that high gas prices pose a significant challenge for working families. That’s why he has taken action in recent months to boost the supply&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The price of gas is up dramatically around the world, and by almost $2 per gallon in America, since Putin began amassing troops on the border of Ukraine. President Biden understands that high gas prices pose a significant challenge for working families. That’s why he has taken action in recent months to boost the supply of oil and gas, including an historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, and encouraging oil companies and refiners to boost capacity and output to get more supply on the market.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, he is calling on Congress and states to take additional legislative action to provide direct relief to American consumers who have been hit with Putin’s Price Hike. Specifically, he is calling on Congress to suspend the federal gas tax for three months, through September, without taking any money away from the Highway Trust Fund. And he is calling on states to take similar action to provide some direct relief, whether suspending their own gas taxes or helping consumers in other ways.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><em>Federal Gas Tax Holiday</em></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>Right now, the federal government charges an 18 cent tax per gallon of gasoline and a 24 cent tax per gallon of diesel. Those taxes fund critical highways and public transportation, through the Highway Trust Fund. But in this unique moment, with gas prices near $5 a gallon on average across the country, President Biden is calling on Congress to suspend the gas tax for three months – until the end of September – to give Americans a little extra breathing room as they deal with the effects of Putin’s war in Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is also calling on Congress to make sure that a gas tax holiday has no negative effect on the Highway Trust Fund. With our deficit already down by a historic $1.6 trillion this year, the President believes that we can afford to suspend the gas tax to help consumers while using other revenues to make the Highway Trust Fund whole for the roughly $10 billion cost. This is consistent with legislation proposed in the Senate and the House to advance a responsible gas tax holiday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden understands that a gas tax holiday alone will not, on its own, relieve the run up in costs that we’ve seen. But the President believes that at this unique moment when the war in Ukraine is imposing costs on American families, Congress should do what it can to provide working families breathing room.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><em>State and Local Action</em></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to federal gas tax relief, the President is calling on state and local governments to provide additional consumer relief. Already, some states and local governments have acted: for example, in Connecticut and New York, governors temporarily suspended their gas taxes, and in Illinois and Colorado, governors delayed planned tax and fee increases. And, around the country, in states like Michigan and Minnesota, states and local leaders are considering a number of forms of consumer relief – from temporary suspensions and pauses on state sales tax on gas to consumer rebates and relief payments. The President believes more states and local governments should do so.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><em>Ongoing Actions to Blunt the Impact of the Putin Price Hike</em></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>Today’s announcements follow a series of actions the President has taken to lower gas prices for American families.</p>



<ul><li>The President announced the release of a record 1 million barrels per day from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve, which just last week a leading oil market analyst confirmed has been critical to keeping prices from rising even more.</li><li>He rallied international partners to join us, releasing a combined 240 million barrels of oil on the market.</li><li>He expanded access to biofuels like E15—gasoline that uses a 15 percent ethanol blend—to increase supply and lower prices at thousands of gas stations across the country.</li><li>He and his Administration are engaging with oil and refining companies to ask them to work with the Administration to bring forward concrete solutions that increase refinery capacity and output. Secretary Granholm is meeting with these CEOs this week.</li></ul>



<p><br>Already, the United States produced more oil under the first year of this Administration than it did under the first two years of the prior Administration, and is on track to set new records next year. At the same time, the President understands that our efforts to increase energy production in the near-term must be coupled with medium- and long-term efforts to transition our economy away from fossil fuels produced by autocrats and to clean energy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Call with President Pedro Sánchez&#160;of Spain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-pedro-sanchez-of-spain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 21:43:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and President Pedro Sánchez of Spain spoke today about preparations for the NATO Summit, which will be held in Madrid on June 29-30, 2022.  The leaders welcomed the opportunity to see each other on the upcoming trip. President Biden thanked President Sánchez for Spain’s hosting of the summit, at which Allies&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and President Pedro Sánchez of Spain spoke today about preparations for the NATO Summit, which will be held in Madrid on June 29-30, 2022.  The leaders welcomed the opportunity to see each other on the upcoming trip. President Biden thanked President Sánchez for Spain’s hosting of the summit, at which Allies will continue to chart the course of NATO’s transformation over the next decade.  President Biden expressed appreciation for Spain’s close cooperation in response to Russia’s war in Ukraine, including its provision of security and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine and its support for strong sanctions on Russia. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccines for Children Under&#160;Five</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/21/remarks-by-president-biden-on-covid-19-vaccines-for-children-under-five/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 21:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 3:55 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; Thanks. As you can tell, I didn&#8217;t want to leave the clinic.&#160; Those children were wonderful. Thank you, Arseme [sic] &#8212; Arsema, and &#8212; for that introduction.&#160; And Jill and I were honored to visit your clinic today.&#160; We met with your fellow nurses&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>3:55 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>As you can tell, I didn&#8217;t want to leave the clinic.&nbsp; Those children were wonderful.</p>



<p>Thank you, Arseme [sic] &#8212; Arsema, and &#8212; for that introduction.&nbsp; And Jill and I were honored to visit your clinic today.&nbsp; We met with your fellow nurses and staff who are stepping up each and every day.&nbsp; And we met with families of young children.&nbsp; And there were about, I guess, 17, 18 families there waiting for their vaccine shots or have just gotten their vaccine shots, and, finally, COVID-19 vaccinations for children over five years of age.&nbsp; Finally, some peace of mind.&nbsp; You know, this is &#8212; or, shall I say, under five years.&nbsp; We have them for over five years.&nbsp; But over five months to &#8212; six months to five years.</p>



<p>And a historic &#8212; this is a very historic milestone, a monumental step forward.&nbsp; The United States is now the first country in the world to offer safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines for children as young as six months old.&nbsp; In the first time in our fight against this pandemic, nearly every American can now have access to lifesaving vaccines.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re ready.</p>



<p>My administration, with the help of the CDC, has been planning and preparing this moment &#8212; for this moment for a long time.&nbsp; Since I took office, we&#8217;ve been committed to making sure every parent has the opportunity to protect their children from COVID-19.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve secured enough doses and we&#8217;re launching a comprehensive effort with states, local health departments, pediatricians, family doctors, pharmacies, rural health clinics, community health centers, and other trusted messengers and partners to get the word out to get &#8212; help to get shots in arms.</p>



<p>Parents will soon be able to start scheduling an appointment and addressing vaccines at pediatricians’ offices, children&#8217;s hospitals.</p>



<p>Our largest pharmacies &#8212; partners and &#8212; that are Walgreens, CVS, and Walmart &#8212; are already scheduling appointments for later this week.</p>



<p>And starting today, you can go to Vaccines.gov and find information and appointments near you.&nbsp; More and more locations will be ramping up, and more vaccines are delivered to providers in your areas every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These vaccines are safe and effective, and are approved after extensive scientific review by the Food and Drug Administration &#8212; the FDA &#8212; and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention &#8212; the CDC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I know some parents might have questions.&nbsp; I encourage you to talk to the doctor &#8212; after you make a plan to get your child vaccinated &#8212; for your children older than five years of age.</p>



<p>For everyone else: Get your shots.&nbsp; Get your boosters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And let’s be clear: Elected officials shouldn’t get in the way and make it more difficult for parents who want their children to be vaccinated, who want to protect them and those around them.&nbsp; This is no time for politics.&nbsp; It’s about parents being able to do everything they can to keep their children safe.</p>



<p>Together, we&#8217;ve come a long way in our fight against COVID with vaccines, treatments, and other tools that are widely available.</p>



<p>More than 220 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; More than 100 million Americans are boosted.&nbsp; Daily deaths due to COVID-19 are down 90 percent.&nbsp; And now, vaccinations are available for nearly every American.&nbsp; And we’ll remain vigilant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will make sure that this is not only a good day but it’s good from this point on &#8212; proof that there is nothing beyond our capacity when we work together as the United States of America.</p>



<p>I want to thank you again, Arsema.&nbsp; And may God bless you, our healthcare workers across the country and continue &#8212; who continue to step up and help put this pandemic behind us.</p>



<p>And, Doc, did you want to say anything?&nbsp; You don’t have to.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to, sir.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Or just &#8212; whatever you like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick question on the Chevron CEO’s complaint today.&nbsp; He said that your administration has largely criticized the oil and gas industry and at times vilified it, and that the administration needs to take a change in approach in order to make progress on reducing energy prices and to increase supply.&nbsp; Do you have a reaction to that, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He&#8217;s mildly sensitive.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t know they’d get their feelings hurt that quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, we need more refining capacity.&nbsp; This idea that they don&#8217;t have oil to drill and to bring up is simply not true.&nbsp; This piece of the Republicans talking about, “Biden shut down fields” &#8212; wrong.&nbsp; There are 9,000 of them, okay?</p>



<p>So they &#8212; we ought to be able to work something out whereby they&#8217;re able to increase refining capacity and still not give up on transitioning to renewable energy.&nbsp; They&#8217;re both within the realm of possibility.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, if you were to decide to go for a federal gas tax holiday, do you believe Congress would support that?&nbsp; And how would you feel about the fact that those funds are used for something that is a big priority for you &#8212; repair of roads and infrastructure and all of that?&nbsp; Is that work the &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have a giant infrastructure bill we passed &#8212; giant &#8212; 1.2 &#8212; $1.2 trillion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;d be worth &#8212; it would be worth it for you to &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; It’s not like &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s not like before.&nbsp; Look, it will have some impact, but it&#8217;s not going to be impact on major road construction and major repairs.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sounds like you may have made a decision?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, let me put this way: I&#8217;m in the process.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll have a decision before the week is out.&nbsp; But you asked me an explicit question about whether or not &#8212; how would I feel; is it going to, in fact, make it difficult to maintain our roads.&nbsp; The answer is: We have plenty of capacity to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you going to talk to President Xi before you make any decision on the China tariffs?&nbsp; Do you want to have an engagement with him before you do something &#8212; anything on that?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I plan on having a conversation with President Xi.&nbsp; We haven’t set a time yet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, any changes on your planned trip to Israel, given what’s happened with the parliament?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I think you spoke with Larry Summers recently.&nbsp; And he just said that in order to defeat inflation, we will have to accept higher unemployment.&nbsp; What would be your answer to that?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, there’s other &#8212; there’s other economists who don’t think that’s the case.&nbsp; And we’re in the process of working through all of this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you received a briefing on the guns legislation?&nbsp; The senators say that they’ve gotten to a legislative text point.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Very brief &#8212; briefly before I walked into the room to make sure I say: Let them announce it, and then I’ll speak to it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you satisfied?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll let them announce it.&nbsp; And then I’ll speak to it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you accounting &#8212; I know you’re looking for more money from Congress for this vaccine campaign and for COVID funding going into the fall.&nbsp; How much of the supply of vaccines for these small children is there?&nbsp; And how many of the nation’s kids will you be able to get vaccinated before you need more money from Congress?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, we’ll get through at least this year.&nbsp; We do need more money.&nbsp; But we don’t just need more money for vaccines for children, eventually; we need more money to plan for the second pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There’s going to be another pandemic.&nbsp; We have to think ahead.&nbsp; And that’s not something the last outfit did very well.&nbsp; That’s something we’ve been doing fairly well.&nbsp; That’s why we need the money.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ahead of your trip, sir: Prime Minister Boris Johnson said recently there is “Ukraine fatigue.”&nbsp; There are some leaders who are calling for negotiations with Putin.&nbsp; Are you afraid that there is a fracture within this alliance that you’ve said has been united so far?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I’m not afraid.&nbsp; But what I do think is there &#8212; at some point, this is going to be a bit of a waiting game: what the Russians can sustain and what Europe is going to be prepared to sustain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think we have to &#8212; that’s one of the things we’re going to be speaking at &#8212; in Spain about.</p>



<p>Thank you all so very, very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">4:03 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications John&#160;Kirby</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/21/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-nsc-coordinator-for-strategic-communications-john-kirby-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 20:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56029</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:07 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello.&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Good afternoon, right?&#160; All right.&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I hope you guys enjoyed a long holiday weekend.&#160; It&#8217;s good to see everyone here.&#160; Today I&#8217;m joined by John Kirby, who is the National Security Council &#8212; was it &#8212; Coordinator for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:07 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Good afternoon, right?&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I hope you guys enjoyed a long holiday weekend.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good to see everyone here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today I&#8217;m joined by John Kirby, who is the National Security Council &#8212; was it &#8212; Coordinator for Strategic Communications.&nbsp; I got to get that right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he&#8217;s happy to take a few questions.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s been some news out there in his world.&nbsp; So, why don&#8217;t you take it away.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Just a couple things at the top, everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think you saw this morning that the administration announced important policy changes with respect to anti-personnel landmines.&nbsp; After conducting a comprehensive policy review, the United States is now joining the vast majority of countries around the world in committing to limit the use of anti-personnel landmines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The use of these weapons put more civilians at risk of being injured by unexploded mines, including children, long after the fighting is stopped.&nbsp; And the President believes strongly that we need to curtail their use worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this new commitment will align U.S. policy outside of the Korean Peninsula with the key requirements of the Ottawa Convention.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the international treaty that prohibits the use of stockpiling the production and the transfer of these weapons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States is the world&#8217;s singes- &#8212; single-largest financial supporter of steps to mitigate the harmful consequences of landmines and explosive remnants of war all around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since 1993, the United States has provided over $4.2 billion in aid to over 100 countries for conventional weapons destruction programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m happy to take questions on that a little bit later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last thing I just want to open up with is: I think you know the President is preparing for his next trip.&nbsp; This will be to the &#8212; to Germany for the G7, and then on to &#8212; to Madrid for the NATO Summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He came into office with the express purpose of revitalizing and reinforcing our allies, our alliances, and our partnerships around the world.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what he&#8217;s done with the G7 and with NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>His leadership and diplomacy elevated these partnerships as central to meeting the biggest challenges of our time and advanced our shared values to define the decades to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He has been unafraid to use the convening power of the United States, which is still ample, still relevant, still viable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The free world has demonstrated incredible unity and resolve to advance three key objectives that I think you&#8217;re going to see are central to this trip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re going to get some time a little bit later on in the week to preview the trip with more detail.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll just tell you, these are the three overarching objectives the President has:</p>



<p>One, our unwavering &#8212; reinforcing our unwavering support of a democratic, sovereign, and prosperous Ukraine, and holding Russia accountable for his war of aggression.</p>



<p>Two, managing the disruptions in the global economy, including energy and food prices, that are caused by this war of aggression that are impacting families all over the world, including here at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And three, charting an affirmative vision for the world in which democracies can deliver and that we are confident will win over autocratic and corrupt visions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, we&#8217;ll have more to share later in the week &#8212; including a background call I think we&#8217;re going to be doing here and the next day or so.&nbsp; And you guys will all get an invitation to that.</p>



<p>And with that, I’ll take some questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, John.&nbsp; What can you tell us about this second American who appears to have died in combat in Ukraine?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know a whole lot.&nbsp; But &#8212; but I think you saw the State Department has confirmed that another American citizen has been killed in the fighting in Ukraine.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d point you to State for more details on that.</p>



<p>Obviously, at the outset, our hearts go out to the family, which are clearly enduring an incredible grief here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, we want to stress that this is not the place or the time for Americans to go to Ukraine.&nbsp; It is a war.&nbsp; And if you want to help the people of Ukraine, there&#8217;s a whole lot of other, better options to do that than going and putting yourself in harm&#8217;s way in the middle of that war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said yesterday that he speaks to Volodymyr Zelenskyy three or four times a week.&nbsp; Is that accurate, or is that a bit of hyperbole?&nbsp; We only get a readout of their conversations once every couple of weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; He speaks to Mr. Zelenskyy on a routine, regular basis.&nbsp; And I couldn&#8217;t sit here and give you the exact count &#8212; this is the beginning of week three for me here &#8212; but he speaks to the President &#8212; President Zelenskyy on a very routine, regular basis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would add it&#8217;s not just the President.&nbsp; The Department of Defense, the Department of State, the Secretary of State and Secretary of Defense speak with their counterparts, again, on a routine, regular basis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Chairman of the Joint&nbsp; Chiefs &#8212; Joi- &#8212; Ji- &#8212; ugh, I’ll try this again using syllables &#8212; the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff talks to &#8212; to his counterpart regularly, too.</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s an awful lot &#8212; and I would go so far as to say “almost daily” &#8212; conversation with Ukrainians at lower staff levels at both DOD and the Department of State.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; April.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, John.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Hey, April.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; Going back to Ukraine: Could you talk about the implications of the grains issue that’s heightening in Ukraine?&nbsp; Has the President of Ukraine talked to the AU about it &#8212; the African Union about it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, the repercussions of what happened in Texas, on a national security front, when it comes to basically calling President Biden the “Acting” President.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; So, I’m going to come back to you on the second one, because I’m not completely sure I understand the question.</p>



<p>But on the first one &#8212; let me just do the grain one first.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about this before: President Putin is, no kidding, weaponizing food.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s just call it what it is: He&#8217;s weaponizing food.&nbsp; He&#8217;s got an essential blockade there in the Black Sea so that nothing can leave by sea &#8212; and that&#8217;s, of course, how Ukraine has historically gotten its grain to markets.</p>



<p>And so the President is working with leaders around the world to see if there&#8217;s other overland ways we can do that.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s exploring a range of options, and he&#8217;s keeping an open mind about how that would look.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s lots of other &#8212; of our partners, particularly in Europe, who also want to see that done.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s a lot of work being done here.</p>



<p>But as I said, I think the other day last week, you know, we know time is not on our side.&nbsp; I mean, this grain is a perishable commodity, so we want to get it out as fast as we can.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And on second question: On the national security front, especially as we&#8217;re seeing what&#8217;s happening with the January 6th Committee, what does it do on the national security front for Texas to make those strong statements about the 2020 election?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I&#8217;m afraid I didn&#8217;t see the comments.&nbsp; Can you elucidate?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Texas Republican &#8212; the Texas Republican platform, I think, is what she’s (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I don’t &#8212; thank you, no.&nbsp; They’re rejecting the Pre- &#8212; what&#8217;s happening is they&#8217;re saying the President is the “Acting” President.&nbsp; The state of Texas is saying (inaudible).</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Oh, oh, oh.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I did.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I can take that one, too, if it’s okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it’s &#8212; on the national security part.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, there’s &#8212; okay.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; On the national security front.&nbsp; I mean, look, the President is the democratically elected Commander-in-Chief of this country, and the men and women who serve in uniform understand that.&nbsp; And with the exception of what looks like a small number of Texas legislatures, the American people recognize that.</p>



<p>And he has the authority, he has the power, he has the responsibility to defend this country.&nbsp; And the things that we&#8217;re talking about today, whether it&#8217;s landmine use or grain shipments or assisting Ukraine, is all about our national security.&nbsp; And the President is charged with preserving and maintaining that national security.</p>



<p>And it &#8212; you know, again, with the &#8212; with the exception of a small number of folks there in Texas, the American people recognize that and understand that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; John, what do you make of the Kremlin saying that the Americans captured in Ukraine aren&#8217;t covered under the Geneva Convention protections for prisoners of war?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, we&#8217;ve seen the comments by Mr. Peskov, with respect to this, not ruling out certain protections.</p>



<p>I would tell you a couple of things. One, we still are trying to learn more about these two individuals.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, it&#8217;s appalling that a public official in Russia would even suggest the death penalty for two American citizens that &#8212; that were in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re going to &#8212; again, we&#8217;re going to continue to try to learn what we can here about this and, again, stay in touch as much as we can with the families.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If they’re not afforded protections under the Geneva Convention, what&#8217;s the course of action that you’re thinking about?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;d be useful for us to get into hypotheticals right now, Jacqui.&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;ve got &#8212; we got more homework here to do.</p>



<p>But I do think it&#8217;s important for us to make it clear: totally appalling for even the suggestion that &#8212; that that result could be the outcome here for these two individuals.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just going to go (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, John.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; John, the Chinese have imported a record amount of oil from Russia, and the trade between the two countries is growing.&nbsp; What message do you have to the Chinese related to this?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I think this is just a piece of China&#8217;s willingness to continue to go along with &#8212; with Russia.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re seeing this as a &#8212; yet another example of a growing collaboration between China and Russia with respect to Ukraine.</p>



<p>And we have, as we&#8217;ve said at the outset, called on China to be a responsible power here and to join the rest of the world in condemning what Russia has done in Ukraine and in enforcing sanctions against Russia for it.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s just another example.</p>



<p>And look, it&#8217;s also another example of how global security really is interconnected.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just about security on the European continent.&nbsp; It&#8217;s connected, what&#8217;s happening in Ukraine &#8212; this is a perfect example of how it&#8217;s connected to &#8212; to national security &#8212; our national security interests and those of allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But at what point did it rise to the level where they&#8217;re breaking sanctions or pushing the line on those sanctions that the U.S. would like to impose?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, again, they haven&#8217;t been participants in this &#8212; in the sanction regime so far.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a follow-up.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; You can follow up, and then (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, John.&nbsp; Also, India has been buying a lot of the Russian oil that the Europeans aren’t buying.&nbsp; So how does the administration keep financial pressure on Russia?&nbsp; And what does this say about U.S-Indian relations that Prime Minister Modi is making these purchases?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Look, India is also a very key strategic partner in the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s many ways that &#8212; that that partnership represents itself both in defense and security, economic as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we&#8217;ll let Indian leaders speak to their economic policies.&nbsp; What I can just tell you is we value this bilateral relationship with India and we continue to want &#8212; obviously, every country has to make their decisions for themselves.&nbsp; These are sovereign decisions.&nbsp; But we want as much pressure put internationally on Russia as possible.</p>



<p>There needs to be &#8212; just the last point: There needs to be costs and consequences for what Mr. Putin is doing.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Francesca.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What, if anything, will President Biden be asking G7 leaders to do next week to bring down the cost of energy and bring down the cost of food?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the agenda too much today.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have more to talk about the trip in the next day or so with more specifics.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not really prepared today to go into too much detail.</p>



<p>But as I said in my opening comments, one of the things &#8212; one of the objectives that the President has here for the G7 is to talk to international leaders inside the G7 about supply chain issues, food and fuel supply around the world, and trying &#8212; and trying to minimize the pressures that it has put on populations all over the world.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll have more a little bit later.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything that you think that they can do, working in coordination, to prevent a global recession?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I think leadership matters a lot here.&nbsp; Multilateral leadership matters a lot &#8212; because this isn&#8217;t just affecting the United States, it&#8217;s affecting the whole world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know the President is looking forward to having discussions with world leaders about what, together, they can do &#8212; whether it&#8217;s increase production or less &#8212; more capacity for refining, less dependence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is one of the reasons, you know, that the President is so committed to clean energy here in this country, is to &#8212; that&#8217;s one way of making us energy independent too.&nbsp; So, advancing &#8212; it&#8217;s also good for the climate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there&#8217;s an awful lot of crosscutting objectives here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A Russia follow-up.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Just two more because we &#8212; go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe, John, the Peskov comments &#8212; obviously, in coordination with Vladimir Putin &#8212; do you believe they&#8217;re about more than the discrete facts involving these Americans, but a signal &#8212; a larger, sort of, tactical signal to the &#8212; to the American president, to the government about ways they can use American citizens as a part of this conflict?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; You know, I gave up a long time ago trying to get inside Mr. Peskov’s head and certainly Mr. Putin’s.&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard to know with great accuracy the answer to your question.</p>



<p>But either way, it&#8217;s equally alarming, whether they actually mean what they&#8217;re saying here and that this could be an outcome &#8212; that they could levy a death penalty against two Americans that were fighting in Ukraine &#8212; or that they just feel it&#8217;s a responsible thing for a major power to do &#8212; to talk about doing this as a way of signaling the President of United States and the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Either one of them is equally alarming.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why, again, we find it appalling.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I take the last one?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; John, why the United States is trying to block the African countries to work with Russia?&nbsp; There is discussion going on right now at the Senate that the United States is trying to force, basically, the African countries not to work with Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t know if you&#8217;re aware: Russia have relation with many African countries, and Angola is one of them &#8212; and many other countries.&nbsp; But right now, it looks like there is a discussion going on in &#8212; at the Senate that the United States is trying to make African countries not to work with Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the beginning, President Biden said that he will work with all nations &#8212; Europe, Asia, and even African countries &#8212; diplomatically.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t let the African countries decide who to work with, instead of just impose them not to work with, for example, Russia?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, I can&#8217;t speak for what the discussions that are going on in the Senate about this.&nbsp; But you kind of answered the question yourself when you went back to what the President has long said about his foreign policy objectives and goals.</p>



<p>Look, he respects and understands that sovereign nations make sovereign decisions.&nbsp; Sovereign nations get to decide who they&#8217;re going to associate with or who they&#8217;re not going to associate with.&nbsp; He understands that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also understands and, I think, has been very clear with leaders around the world that there needs to be consequences for what Mr. Putin is doing in Ukraine.&nbsp; There needs to be costs.&nbsp; He needs to be held accountable for this unprovoked war of aggression.</p>



<p>And so, it&#8217;s difficult for him to look at countries around the world who might be willing not to impose those consequences, who might be looking for ways to reward Mr. Putin for what he is doing in Ukraine.&nbsp; So is it principled &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And why he is forcing countries not to work with Russia?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; This isn&#8217;t about &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why don’t &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Ma’am?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; let them decide?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; No, ma’am.&nbsp; This is not about forcing.&nbsp; And again, I &#8212; I won’t &#8212; I can&#8217;t speak to the language you&#8217;re talking about from the Senate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This isn&#8217;t about forcing anybody.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about &#8212; it&#8217;s about standing up for a principle.&nbsp; And, look, the principle here is the principle of sovereignty.&nbsp; So &#8212; so it cuts both ways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, obviously, sovereign nations need to be able to make their own decisions.&nbsp; The President understands that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why, you know, when we were talking about whether Ukraine would or wouldn&#8217;t join NATO, it&#8217;s not up to Mr. Putin to get a veto on that.&nbsp; Sovereign nations have to make that decision and so does the NATO Alliance.&nbsp; He understands the sovereign decisions that nations in Africa have to make.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But he also believes and stands strongly on the principle that Mr. Putin needs to suffer consequences for this war of aggression &#8212; consequences around the world as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, he doesn&#8217;t believe that it&#8217;s in the interests of what&#8217;s going on in Ukraine &#8212; or European security, for that matter &#8212; for Mr. Putin to be able to get off scot-free here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when the President will travel to Africa?&nbsp; John, he traveled to Europe, Asia, but not Africa.&nbsp; When?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a trip announcement to make today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Kirby, is the President tracking the situation in Ethiopia?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yes, he is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also on the &#8212; the billions of dollars that have flowed to the Ukraine, how much of that money has gone to gun manufacturers in the U.S.?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; How much money has gone to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How much of the $40 billion &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Are you talking about the money &#8212; the money that we are sup- &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The money that has been approved to Ukraine.&nbsp; How much of that money has gone to gun manufacturers here in the U.S.?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Okay, if you mean defense contractors, we can give you that, and I can &#8212; we can have somebody get you the &#8211;the amount of contracts that are going to be or are being let under the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative.&nbsp; This is for defense articles &#8212; weapons and systems that Ukraine needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you&#8217;re asking me how many are go- &#8212; you mean like firearm manufacturers here in the United States?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; How much of the &#8212; of the money that has gone to Ukraine, how much of that money actually goes to Ukraine &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; To the degree that we &#8212; that we supply small arms and ammunition &#8212; right? &#8212; to Ukraine, we can get you that figure.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have it handy.&nbsp; But those are &#8212; that’s small arms and ammunition &#8212; combat arms that they&#8217;re using in the field.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we get caught up a lot talking about HIMARS &#8212; right? &#8212; long-range rocket systems and artillery systems and tanks and all that &#8212; all those big-ticket items that the Ukrainians say they need.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s true they do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what they&#8217;ll also tell you is that the bullets and the small arms are making a big difference every single day, because the fighting in the Donbas is close combat.&nbsp; A lot of long-range fires, lots of artillery &#8212; no question.&nbsp; But there &#8212; it&#8217;s a lot of small-arms combat, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we &#8212; we forget about that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an important set of defense articles and systems that we&#8217;ve been sending to Ukraine, and we&#8217;re going to continue to do it for as long as we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as for the exact figures, we have to get that for you.</p>



<p>Thank you, everybody.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a lot of time, guys, because we have to leave for &#8212; at 1:45, I believe, for the President&#8217;s travel &#8212; local travel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, so I have something really quick at the top and then I&#8217;ll take your questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So today, President Biden and the First Lady are visiting a local COVID-19 vaccination clinic, hosted by the DC Health, to highlight the recent authorization and recommendation of COVID-19 vaccines for children under the age of five.</p>



<p>This weekend, the CDC formally recommended use of a COVID-19 vaccine for this age group following the FDA’s authorization on June 17th, marking a key milestone that ensures, for the first time since the pandemic began, that nearly every American can access protections from lifesaving COVID-19 vaccines, including our youngest Americans age six months and up.</p>



<p>Following the visit, the President will deliver remarks at the White House on COVID-19 vaccines for children under five and the historic progress the country has made in fighting COVID-19 with safe, effective vaccines available virtually to all Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Josh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two subject areas, since I know we’re going fast &#8212; by 1:40.&nbsp; What data is President Biden looking at for the gas tax holiday?&nbsp; And is he expecting congressional support and state-level action?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I’ll take your second question first.&nbsp; As you know, the President said he&#8217;s going to make a decision about this by the end of this week.&nbsp; The way we see it is there would be congressional action.&nbsp; Congress would take &#8212; would need to take action.</p>



<p>To your first question, the President is looking at an array of options to &#8212; to figure out how he&#8217;s going to help give relief to the American public, especially as they are looking at gas prices at the pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a number-one priority for the President.&nbsp; He&#8217;s looking at an array of options.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything specific for you &#8212; to share with you at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gotcha.&nbsp; And then, secondly, real fast: What is President Biden&#8217;s reaction to Texas authorities saying the police response in Uvalde was an “abject failure” and that the gunman, in theory, could have been stopped within three minutes?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, this is something that the President has talked about this very deeply.&nbsp; He &#8212; it is very &#8212; the actions that we have seen and the reports that we have seen is deeply concerning.&nbsp; The President has said that.</p>



<p>As you know, DOJ is doing a review.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to leave it to their findings and their review before we&#8217;ll say anything more, but it is deeply disturbing to hear the reports on what happened on the ground on that day.</p>



<p>Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the issue of the federal gas tax, has the White House started reaching out to Congress yet on this, working with members to try and get them on board with this?&nbsp; Because, as you know, you would of course need their approval for any suspension.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Absolutely, we would definitely, as I said, need Congress to act on this.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t lay out &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to lay out on &#8212; on any outreach that we&#8217;ve made to Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President, as you all know, understands the stress that the American public is feeling across the country.&nbsp; This is why he has taken action himself when it comes to tapping the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; a historic amount of oil &#8212; 1 million of barrels of oil a month &#8212; I mean, a day, I should say, just to be exact; and also asking &#8212; getting his partners to do 240 million barrels as well.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s ethanol 15, as he has been able to make sure that we give relief to thousands &#8212; thousands and thousands of Americans across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is something that has been a complete priority for the President.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything specific to lay out about meetings coming up or meetings that have happened.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the President said he&#8217;s not planning to sit down with any oil and gas CEOs as he makes his decision.&nbsp; Why not?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as I can confirm here &#8212; I know it&#8217;s been &#8212; kind of been reported out there: Secretary Granholm is going to be meeting with the seven CEOs on Thursday &#8212; this coming Thursday.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the first step that he wanted to make sure happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, our goal is to make sure that we have a sit-down conversation where we come up with solutions, that we work with the CEOs to figure out what else that we can do to move &#8212; to move that capacity forward.</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; the meeting is happening on Thursday with Secretary Granholm, and she&#8217;s going to sit down with the CEOs.&nbsp; And hopefully, we have some solutions that come out of the meeting.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said that’s the first step.&nbsp; Is the &#8212; so the President is not ruling out meeting with them?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I’m &#8212; the President spoke to this himself yesterday, which is like he&#8217;s not going to be meeting with the &#8212; with the CEOs.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let that stand and speak for himself.</p>



<p>The way that we view this is &#8212; what I mean by “first step” is they&#8217;re going to sit down and have a conversation.&nbsp; The second step is coming up with solutions and ideas.</p>



<p>Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said last week that there&#8217;s no inevitability around a recession, but there is a greater deal of market concern about exactly that.</p>



<p>And I know that inflation is your number-one concern, but can you talk a little bit about if you&#8217;re doing anything at all to prevent a recession or a rise in unemployment?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the way that we see this &#8212; and you&#8217;ve heard us talk about this that we&#8217;re in a moment of transition.&nbsp; We have seen &#8212; we are in a unique situation with our &#8212; with the historical gains with our economy.&nbsp; The way that we see it, this unemployment rate has held steady at 3.6, which is also near historic lows; business and investment remain strong; household balance sheets remain strong.</p>



<p>There was an analysis that came out recently that showed middle-class Americans had an additional $10,000 in savings than before the pandemic.&nbsp; Another analysis found that all income groups had higher checking account balances at the end of March than they had pre-pandemic.</p>



<p>So, we see that the strengths that we &#8212; our economic strength that we have seen from this past year from the action that the President has taken with the American Rescue Plan, with what we have seen with the historical gains, that is going to help us deal with a recession.</p>



<p>Right now &#8212; we don&#8217;t see a recession right now.&nbsp; That is not &#8212; we&#8217;re not in a recession right now.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re in a transition where we will &#8212; we are going to go into a place of stable and steady growth, and that&#8217;s going to be &#8212; that&#8217;s going to be our focus.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more.&nbsp; AAA was out with a report today saying that there&#8217;s going to be a record number of people driving for the Fourth of July holiday.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering what that tells you about whether inflation is, in fact, the top concern for the American people and whether there&#8217;s a role for conservation to play, given the extreme demands on energy supplies right now.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say &#8212; say a little bit more.&nbsp; You&#8217;re saying &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, Americans are happy, it would seem, to go out and &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; Oh, I see what you&#8217;re saying.&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and to pay as much money as gas costs to go on vacation and do all of the things that they would normally do &#8212; in fact, more so than in the past.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, how do you &#8212; how do you &#8212; what do you think about that?&nbsp; And do you think it&#8217;s appropriate given the constraints on energy supplies globally right now?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, Americans are going to do what they feel is right for themselves and for the family &#8212; for their family.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not something for us to make a judgment on.</p>



<p>I think what we&#8217;re seeing right now is &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve been in a pandemic for some time.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; and I think Americans are feeling as if, this summer, it&#8217;s time to get out and go visit families.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s a reaction that we&#8217;re seeing there.</p>



<p>But I have to say a lot of that is &#8212; is thankful to the President and the work that he has done to make sure that more than 220 million people get &#8212; are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; That matters.</p>



<p>Today, he&#8217;s going to visit a COVID health center where our &#8212; where we are going to be able to vaccinate our youngest among us, which is the zero to five.&nbsp; That&#8217;s about 18 million young people, which is &#8212; a lot of that work is due because of what the President has been able to do, and the American Rescue Plan, and the stra- &#8212; the vaccination strategy that he put &#8212; that he put forward the moment that he walked into this administration.</p>



<p>Look, I &#8212; it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not for me to say what Americans can do or can&#8217;t do.&nbsp; But I do think this is kind of the &#8212; kind of the pendulum swinging as we are &#8212; as we are &#8212; more people vaccinated and more folks are feeling more comfortable and more safe to get out there.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll go to the back in a second.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; What kind of visibility does the administration have into the, quote, “logistical error” that prevented Brittney Griner, who&#8217;s being held in Russia, from speaking by phone with her wife?&nbsp; And how was a mistake like that acceptable given, kind of, the stakes of this moment?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, this was an unfortunate mistake and the Department &#8212; the Department of State is working to rectify this as quickly as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From what I understand, there is a phone &#8212; a phone interview has been scheduled.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak to when.&nbsp; That is up to Brittney Griner’s partner to decide &#8212; her wife to decide if that &#8212; if they want to make that public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anything else, I would defer you to the State Department.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has &#8212; Brittney Griner’s wife talked about meeting with the President or her desire to meet with the President.&nbsp; Is that something that&#8217;s on the table or an option at this point?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to share about &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything to share about a potential phone conversation or meeting.</p>



<p>What I can say is that the State Department has been in regular touch with Mrs. Griner.&nbsp; She&#8217;s also spoken to Secretary Blinken, which we have mentioned before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is certainly &#8212; any American that is held &#8212; that is held abroad is a priority for this President.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve spoken to that. &nbsp;And we will do everything that we can to bring &#8212; to bring them home &#8212; to bring her home.</p>



<p>I’ll go to the back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on Roe v. Wade?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hold on a second.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can hear me.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’m trying to go to somebody I haven’t gotten yet.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; So, in these deliberations about the gas tax, does the President have concerns about &#8212; what are his concerns about endorsing such an idea?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Endorsing a gas tax?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; He endorses congressional action on a gas tax holiday.&nbsp; Are there concerns that he has about doing that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the President has been very clear in making sure that he does everything that he can to elevate &#8212; to alleviate the &#8212; you know, the pain that American families are feeling when it comes to gas prices.</p>



<p>He said all options are on the table.&nbsp; He has not &#8212; he said himself &#8212; just to reiterate what he said yesterday: He has not made a decision on this.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll have something more by the end of the week.</p>



<p>But &#8212; but this is about making sure that we deliver for the American people as it relates to gas, as it relates to increases &#8212; increase in cost.</p>



<p>And so, again, we have said this from day one: All options are on the table.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I guess I’m trying to understand: What are the drawbacks that he sees?&nbsp; And does he think an endorsement could help Republicans get on board if it requires congressional action?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President right now.&nbsp; He has not &#8212; he &#8212; we have not laid out this decision.</p>



<p>Once we &#8212; once we have, I&#8217;m happy to have that conversation right here or in my office, however you wish.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, right now, all options are on the table.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to do everything that he can to make sure he relieves some pain and some pressure that Americans are feeling at the pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Question about Ethiopia, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, gosh.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Does the President have any thoughts on the Colombian elections this weekend?&nbsp; And does he have any plans to speak to the President-elect?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any calls to read out to you at this time.&nbsp; You know, the United States congratulates the people of Colombia on a free and fair election.&nbsp; The President looks forward to working with President-Elect Petro and to advance the U.S.-Colombia relationship and tackle key issues together, including climate change, building more fair and resilient economies, security, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have a call to read out at this point or to announce at this point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, when it comes to the federal gas tax, former President Obama has called it &#8212; called it a “gimmick” back when it was being considered during his administration.&nbsp; A number of Republican and Democratic congressional leaders over the years have said the same thing: It saves people a couple of dollars when they fill up, but it decimates the Highway Trust Fund.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why is it suddenly on the table for this President when it seemed like it was an idea that the White House had sort of set to the side for months?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, the President has &#8212; has always said all options are on the table.&nbsp; This is one of those options.&nbsp; He was asked a question yesterday, and he answered it.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have anything to announce at this time.&nbsp; Once we do, we will and be happy to answer all the questions around that decision once &#8212; and if he makes that decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, he has said &#8212; he has been very clear he wants to make sure that he is, you know, dealing with what the Americans are facing at the pump, which is high &#8212; high prices due to inflation, due to &#8212; that part of it is the pandemic, part of it is Putin&#8217;s war on Ukraine and the &#8212; Putin’s tax hike.&nbsp; So he wants to do everything that he can to make sure that we are answering &#8212; answering those calls of trying to lower the costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) follow up, Karine?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, that&#8217;s it?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, thank you, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You could stay and (inaudible) in the back, please?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; How about &#8212; well, I actually have to go with him today so I can&#8217;t stay.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll take &#8212; but I&#8217;ll take one more question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll take a question in the back.</p>



<p>Phil, I know you had your &#8212; do you want to &#8212; you had a question.&nbsp; No?&nbsp; Oh, you&#8217;re passing.&nbsp; You&#8217;re passing.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Can you confirm that the White House intends to issue a rule on reducing nicotine levels in cigarettes?&nbsp; And if so, can you give us some details about that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to comment on any leak &#8212; leak information.&nbsp; I have no final decision to preview at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what I can say is: One of the President&#8217;s key Unity Agenda item is ending cancer as we know it, including by reigniting the Cancer Moonshot Initiative.&nbsp; Already have been steps from the FDA to address the impact of &#8212; impact other tobacco products like <s>methanol</s> [menthol] and flavored ga- &#8212; cigars have on the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I&#8217;ve mentioned here before, and I will take this opportunity to remind everyone, that what the Office of Management and Budget regular &#8212; regulatory agenda is and is not: Agencies place on the regulatory agenda a list of all the proposed and final rules they are currently planning to issue in the months ahead.  However, no policy decision has been made at this time.  And I don&#8217;t have anything else to preview for you at this time.  Okay, we&#8217;ll see you guys tomorrow. </p>



<p>1:41 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President-Elect Gustavo Petro of&#160;Colombia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-elect-gustavo-petro-of-colombia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 19:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke with President-elect Gustavo Petro today to congratulate him and Vice President-elect Francia Marquez on their election. President Biden commended the Colombian people for holding free and fair elections and reaffirmed U.S. support for Colombia. He underscored that he looks forward to working with the President-elect to continue strengthening bilateral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke with President-elect Gustavo Petro today to congratulate him and Vice President-elect Francia Marquez on their election. President Biden commended the Colombian people for holding free and fair elections and reaffirmed U.S. support for Colombia. He underscored that he looks forward to working with the President-elect to continue strengthening bilateral cooperation, including on climate change, health security, and implementation of the 2016 Peace Accord. President Biden also welcomed the opportunity to discuss bilateral security and counternarcotics cooperation. They discussed the importance of mutual respect and partnership as the foundation of the U.S.-Colombia relationship, and agreed to have their teams follow up and engage directly on shared interests.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Prescription of Method of Designating a Member of the Military Sentencing Parameters and Criteria&#160;Board</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/21/memorandum-on-the-prescription-of-method-of-designating-a-member-of-the-military-sentencing-parameters-and-criteria-board/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 19:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SUBJECT:       Prescription of Method of Designating a Member of the Military Sentencing Parameters and Criteria Board By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;539E(e)(4)(B) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, Public Law&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Prescription of Method of Designating a Member of the Military Sentencing Parameters and Criteria Board</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;539E(e)(4)(B) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, Public Law 117-81, 135 Stat. 1541, 1700 (2021), I hereby order as follows:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;If the chief trial judges designated under article 26(g) of the Uniform Code of Military Justice, 10 U.S.C. 826(g), do not include a trial judge of the Navy, then the Judge Advocate General of the Navy shall designate as a voting member of the Military Sentencing Parameters and Criteria Board (Board) either the Chief Judge of the Department of the Navy or a Navy trial judge assigned to the Navy and Marine Corps Trial Judiciary.</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;If the chief trial judges designated under article 26(g) of the Uniform Code of Military Justice, 10 U.S.C. 826(g), do not include a trial judge of the Marine Corps, then the Staff Judge Advocate to the Commandant of the Marine Corps, in consultation with the Judge Advocate General of the Navy, shall designate as a voting member of the Board a Marine Corps trial judge assigned to the Navy and Marine Corps Trial Judiciary.</p>



<p>This memorandum constitutes the regulations provided for in subsections (ii) and (iii) of section 539E(e)(4)(B) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.                                </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden to Nominate Dr. Arati Prabhakar to Lead Office of Science and Technology&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/president-biden-to-nominate-dr-arati-prabhakar-to-lead-office-of-science-and-technology-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 17:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Former Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and National Institute of Standards and Technology leader would make history as the first woman, immigrant, or person of color confirmed to head OSTP Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate Dr. Arati Prabhakar to serve as Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Former Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency and National Institute of Standards and Technology leader would make history as the first woman, immigrant, or person of color confirmed to head OSTP</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate Dr. Arati Prabhakar to serve as Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), and once confirmed to this position, also as Assistant to the President for Science and Technology. In this capacity, Dr. Prabhakar will be the President’s Chief Advisor for Science and Technology, a co-chair of the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology, and a member of the President’s Cabinet.</p>



<p>“Dr. Prabhakar is a brilliant and highly-respected engineer and applied physicist and will lead the Office of Science and Technology Policy to leverage science, technology, and innovation to expand our possibilities, solve our toughest challenges, and make the impossible possible,” said President Biden. “I share Dr. Prabhakar’s belief that America has the most powerful innovation machine the world has ever seen. As the Senate considers her nomination, I am grateful that Dr. Alondra Nelson will continue to lead OSTP and Dr. Francis Collins will continue to serve as my acting Science Advisor.”<br><br>Prabhakar has been unanimously confirmed by the Senate before, to lead the&nbsp;National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), and was the first woman to hold that role. She later served as director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), the birthplace of breakthrough technologies like stealth aircraft and the Internet.</p>



<p>If confirmed to lead OSTP, Prabhakar would become the third Asian American, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander to serve in President Biden’s Cabinet, joining Vice President Kamala Harris and U.S. Trade Representative Katherine Tai. Today’s nomination is historic, with Prabhakar being the first woman, immigrant, or person of color nominated to serve as Senate-confirmed director of OSTP.</p>



<p><strong><u>Dr. Arati Prabhakar, nominee to serve as Director, Office of Science and Technology Policy</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Arati Prabhakar has led two different federal R&amp;D agencies and worked with startups, large companies, universities, government labs, and nonprofits across a wide variety of sectors to create powerful new solutions for critical challenges. She is an engineer and applied physicist with extensive management and leadership credentials.</p>



<p>Prabhakar served as director of DARPA, the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, from 2012 to 2017. At DARPA, she oversaw teams that prototyped a system for detecting nuclear and radiological materials before a terrorist can build a bomb, that developed tools to find human trafficking networks in the deep and dark web, and that enabled complex military systems to work together even when they were not originally designed to do so. She also established a new office to spur novel biotechnologies. Under her leadership, DARPA kick-started the development of a rapid-response mRNA vaccine platform, making possible the fastest safe and effective vaccine development in world history in response to COVID-19.</p>



<p>Prabhakar was unanimously confirmed by the U.S. Senate to lead the&nbsp;National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), taking the helm at age 34 as the first woman to lead the agency. At NIST, which she led from 1993 to 1997, she helped take from early seed stage to national scale the Manufacturing Extension Partnership to boost the competitiveness of small- and mid-size manufacturers, and the Advanced Technology Program to stimulate early-stage advanced technology development. She also reinforced NIST’s long-time mission in measurement science and technology that underpins commerce and high-quality manufacturing.</p>



<p>Between her Federal leadership roles, Prabhakar spent 15 years in Silicon Valley, helping bring R&amp;D to deployment as a company executive and as a venture capitalist. Her work included components for consumer electronics and semiconductor process technology. In 2019, she founded Actuate, a non-profit organization bringing new actors to the table to develop solutions to the challenges of climate, health, trustworthy data and information technology, and opening access to opportunity for every person.</p>



<p>Prabhakar’s family immigrated from India to the United States when she was three years old – first to Chicago and then settling when she was age 10 in Lubbock, Texas, where she went on to get her electrical engineering degree from Texas Tech University. She was the first woman to earn a Ph.D. in applied physics from the California Institute of Technology, where she also earned an M.S. in electrical engineering. She started her career in the legislative branch as a Congressional Fellow at the Office of Technology Assessment.</p>



<p>She is a fellow of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers and a member of the National Academy of Engineering, and was a fellow at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Bill Signed: S. 1097, S. 2520, and S.&#160;3823</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/21/press-release-bill-signed-s-1097-s-2520-and-s-3823/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 16:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, June 21, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 1097, the &#8220;Federal Rotational Cyber Workforce Program Act of 2021,&#8221; which establishes a Federal rotational cyber workforce program for the Federal cyber workforce; Thank you to Senators Peters, Hoeven, and Rosen and Representatives Khanna and Mace for their leadership. S. 2520, the &#8220;State and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, June 21, 2022, the President signed into law:<br><br>S. 1097, the &#8220;Federal Rotational Cyber Workforce Program Act of 2021,&#8221; which establishes a Federal rotational cyber workforce program for the Federal cyber workforce;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Peters, Hoeven, and Rosen and Representatives Khanna and Mace for their leadership.<br><br>S. 2520, the &#8220;State and Local Government Cybersecurity Act of 2021,&#8221; which requires the Department of Homeland Security to increase collaboration with State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments on cybersecurity issues;</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Peters, Portman, and Rosen, and Representative Neguse for their leadership.<br><br>S. 3823, the &#8220;Bankruptcy Threshold Adjustment and Technical Corrections Act,&#8221; which raises certain bankruptcy threshold limits and makes technical corrections to the Bankruptcy Administration Improvement Act.</p>



<p>&nbsp;Thank you to Senators Grassley, Durbin, Whitehouse, and Cornyn, and Representatives Neguse and Cline for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Changes to U.S. Anti-Personnel Landmine&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/fact-sheet-changes-to-u-s-anti-personnel-landmine-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing important policy changes to U.S. Anti-Personnel Landmine policy. After conducting a comprehensive policy review, the United States is joining the vast majority of countries around the world in committing to limit the use of anti-personnel landmines (APL).These changes reflect the President’s belief that these weapons have disproportionate impact on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing important policy changes to U.S. Anti-Personnel Landmine policy. After conducting a comprehensive policy review, the United States is joining the vast majority of countries around the world in committing to limit the use of anti-personnel landmines (APL).These changes reflect the President’s belief that these weapons have disproportionate impact on civilians, including children, long after fighting has stopped, and that we need to curtail the use of APL worldwide. They also complement longstanding U.S. leadership in the clearance of landmines and other explosive remnants of war.<br>&nbsp;<br>The new commitment announced today will align U.S. APL policy outside of the Korean Peninsula with the key requirements of the Ottawa Convention – the international treaty prohibiting the use, stockpiling, production, and transfer of APL – which has more than 160 parties, including all of our NATO Allies. This means that United States will:</p>



<ul><li>Not develop, produce, or acquire APL;</li><li>Not export or transfer of APL, except when necessary for activities related to mine detection or removal, and for the purpose of destruction;</li><li>Not use APL outside of the Korean Peninsula;</li><li>Not assist, encourage, or induce anyone, outside of the context of the Korean Peninsula, to engage in any activity that would be prohibited by the Ottawa Convention; and</li><li>Undertake to destroy all APL stockpiles not required for the defense of the Republic of Korea.</li></ul>



<p>Additionally, the United States will undertake diligent efforts to pursue materiel and operational solutions to assist in becoming compliant with and ultimately acceding to the Ottawa Convention, while ensuring our ability to respond to contingencies and meet our alliance commitments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new policy announced today represents a further step to advance the humanitarian aims of the Ottawa Convention, and to bring U.S. practice in closer alignment with a global humanitarian movement that has had a demonstrated positive impact in reducing civilian casualties from APL.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Even as the United States takes this further step, the unique circumstances on the Korean Peninsula and the U.S. commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea preclude the United States from changing anti-personnel landmine policy on the Korean Peninsula at this time.&nbsp; As the United States commits to continuing our diligent efforts to pursue material and operational alternatives to APL, the security of our ally the Republic of Korea will continue to be a paramount concern.<br><br><strong>World Leader in Humanitarian Mine Action</strong><br><br>The United States is the world’s single largest financial supporter of steps to mitigate the harmful consequences of landmines and explosive remnants of war around the world, including through land clearance and medical rehabilitation and vocational training for those injured by these weapons.&nbsp; Since the United States Humanitarian Mine Action Program was established in 1993, the United States has provided over $4.2 billion in aid in over 100 countries for conventional weapons destruction programs. Through this assistance, the United States has:</p>



<ul><li>Helped 17 countries become free from the danger of landmines;</li><li>Provided assistive devices and other rehabilitation services to over 250,000 people in 35 countries through the U.S. Agency for International Development-managed Leahy War Victims Fund.</li></ul>



<p>This vital U.S. assistance has helped post-conflict countries consolidate peace and set the stage for reconstruction and development.  Clearance efforts and victim assistance programs return land and infrastructure to productive use and assist in the rehabilitation and reintegration into society of survivors of mine and explosive remnants of war incidents.<br> <br>Further information on U.S. humanitarian demining and conventional weapons destruction programs can be found in the State Department’s annual To Walk the Earth in Safety report.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on Changes to U.S. Anti-Personnel Landmine&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/21/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-changes-to-u-s-anti-personnel-landmine-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing an important step to limit the United States’ use of anti-personnel landmines. At the President’s direction, the United States will align its policy concerning use of these weapons outside of the Korean Peninsula with key provisions of the Ottawa Convention, the international treaty prohibiting the use, stockpiling, production, and transfer of anti-personnel landmines. Additionally, the President will prohibit the development, production,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing an important step to limit the United States’ use of anti-personnel landmines. At the President’s direction, the United States will align its policy concerning use of these weapons outside of the Korean Peninsula with key provisions of the Ottawa Convention, the international treaty prohibiting the use, stockpiling, production, and transfer of anti-personnel landmines. Additionally, the President will prohibit the development, production, and acquisition of anti-personnel landmines prohibited under the Ottawa Convention, and will direct the Department of Defense to undertake diligent efforts to pursue alternatives to anti-personnel landmines that would be compliant with and ultimately allow the United States to accede to the Ottawa Convention, while ensuring our continued ability to respond to global contingencies. <br> <br>The world has once again witnessed the devastating impact that anti-personnel landmines can have in the context of Russia’s brutal and unprovoked war in Ukraine, where Russian forces’ use of these and other munitions have caused extensive harm to civilians and civilian objects. President Biden is committed to continuing the United States’ role as the world’s leader in mitigating the harmful consequences of anti-personnel landmines worldwide.  Since 1993, the United States has invested more than $4.2 billion in more than 100 countries to promote international peace and security through conventional weapons destruction programs.  We will continue this important work as we take another step to reclaim American leadership on the world stage.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
