<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 20:02:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala Harris on Meeting with the Family of George Floyd</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-meeting-with-the-family-of-george-floyd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 19:55:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the President and I met with the family of Mr. George Floyd. Mr. Floyd should be alive today. He should be with his family who continue to show courage, grace, and resilience. One year ago, a cellphone video revealed to the country what Black Americans have known to be true for generations. The verdict&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the President and I met with the family of Mr. George Floyd. Mr. Floyd should be alive today. He should be with his family who continue to show courage, grace, and resilience.</p>



<p>One year ago, a cellphone video revealed to the country what Black Americans have known to be true for generations. The verdict finding Derek Chauvin guilty of murder provided some measure of justice. But one verdict does not address the persistent issue of police misconduct and use of excessive force. It does not take away the Floyd family’s pain, nor the pain of all those families who have grieved the untimely loss of a loved one.</p>



<p>We need to do more.</p>



<p>After Mr. Floyd was murdered, Senator Cory Booker, Representative Karen Bass, and I introduced the Justice in Policing Act to hold law enforcement accountable and build trust between law enforcement and the communities it serves. Congress must move swiftly and act with a sense of urgency. Passing legislation will not bring back those lives lost, but it will represent much needed progress.</p>



<p>We must address racial injustice wherever it exists. That is the work ahead.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the First Anniversary of George Floyd’s Murder</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-first-anniversary-of-george-floyds-murder/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, in the Oval Office, I met with George Floyd’s family. Although it has been one year since their beloved brother and father was murdered, for the family – for any family experiencing a profound loss – the first year can still feel like they got the news a few seconds ago. And they’ve had&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, in the Oval Office, I met with George Floyd’s family.</p>



<p>Although it has been one year since their beloved brother and father was murdered, for the family – for any family experiencing a profound loss – the first year can still feel like they got the news a few seconds ago. And they’ve had to relive that pain and grief each and every time those horrific 9 minutes and 29 seconds have been replayed.</p>



<p>Yet the Floyd family has shown extraordinary courage, especially his young daughter Gianna, who I met again today. The day before her father’s funeral a year ago, Jill and I met the family and she told me, “<em>Daddy changed the world</em>.”</p>



<p>He has.</p>



<p>His murder launched a summer of protest we hadn’t seen since the Civil Rights era in the ‘60s – protests that peacefully unified people of every race and generation to collectively say enough of the senseless killings.</p>



<p>Last month’s conviction of the police officer who murdered George was another important step forward toward justice. But our progress can’t stop there.</p>



<p>To deliver real change, we must have accountability when law enforcement officers violate their oaths, and we need to build lasting trust between the vast majority of the men and women who wear the badge honorably and the communities they are sworn to serve and protect. We can and must have both accountability and trust and in our justice system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The negotiations on the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act in Congress are ongoing. I have strongly supported the legislation that passed the House, and I appreciate the good-faith efforts from Democrats and Republicans to pass a meaningful bill out of the Senate. It’s my hope they will get a bill to my desk quickly.</p>



<p>We have to act. We face an inflection point. The battle for the soul of America has been a constant push and pull between the American ideal that we’re all created equal and the harsh reality that racism has long torn us apart.</p>



<p>At our best, the American ideal wins out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It must again.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces His Intent to Appoint Members to the Commission of Fine Arts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/president-biden-announces-his-intent-to-appoint-members-to-the-commission-on-fine-arts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to appoint four new members to the Commission on Fine Arts: Peter Cook, Principal, HGA ArchitectsPeter Cook is a Principal at HGA Architects. Among Cook’s high-profile projects are the Smithsonian Institution’s National Museum of African American History and Culture, Watha T. Daniel / Shaw Neighborhood Library, Embassy of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to appoint four new members to the Commission on Fine Arts:<br><br><strong><u>Peter Cook, Principal, HGA Architects</u></strong><br>Peter Cook is a Principal at HGA Architects. Among Cook’s high-profile projects are the Smithsonian Institution’s National Museum of African American History and Culture, Watha T. Daniel / Shaw Neighborhood Library, Embassy of South Africa, and Saint Elizabeth’s East Gateway Pavilion. Cook is a member of the American Institute of Architects, Washington, D.C. Chapter and the National Organization of Minority Architects. He holds a Master of Architecture from Columbia University’s Graduate School of Architecture, Planning &amp; Preservation, and a Bachelor of Arts in Visual &amp; Environmental Studies from Harvard University.<br><br><strong><u>Hazel Ruth Edwards, Professor and Chair, Howard University Department of Architecture in the College of Engineering and Architecture</u></strong><br>Dr. Hazel Ruth Edwards has been Professor and Chair of the Department of Architecture, College of Engineering and Architecture at Howard University since July 2016. Appointed in 2016, Edwards is the first female to chair the department since architecture education began at Howard in 1911. Her unique career has combined place-based research with planning and urban design practice and teaching. She is a certified planner with the American Institute of Certified Planners (AICP) and was elected to their College of Fellows (FAICP) in 2018.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><u>Justin Garrett Moore, Inaugural Program Officer, Humanities in Place, Andrew Mellon Foundation</u></strong><br>Justin Garrett Moore is a transdisciplinary designer and urbanist. He recently took a job at the Andrew Mellon Foundation as the Inaugural Program Officer of the Humanities in Place program. Moore previously served as Executive Director of the City of New York Public Design Commission. He is a member of the American Planning Association&#8217;s AICP Commission, the Urban Design Forum, and the Black urbanist collective BlackSpace. Justin is an adjunct faculty member at Columbia University&#8217;s Graduate School of Architecture, Planning and Preservation and the Yale School of Architecture.<br><br><strong><u>Billie Tsien, Partner, Todd Williams Billie Tsien Architects</u></strong><br>Billie Tsien is an architect and a founding partner with Tod Williams of the New York City-based studio Tod Williams Billie Tsien Architects | Partners.&nbsp;Their work is committed to reflecting the values of non-profit, cultural and academic institutions through an architecture that is serene and enduring.&nbsp;Currently serving as President of the American Academy of Arts and Letters, she is also a member of the National Academy of Design, American Academy in Rome, and the American Philosophical Society.&nbsp;Maintaining an active academic career as the Charles Gwathmey Professor in Practice at Yale University, she is steadfast in her mission to create a better world through architecture and to contribute to supporting a broader and more diverse cultural landscape.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Opens Pacific Coast to New Jobs and Clean Energy Production with Offshore Wind Development</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/fact-sheet-biden-administration-opens-pacific-coast-to-new-jobs-and-clean-energy-production-with-offshore-wind-development/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[White House Marshals Departments of the Interior, Defense, and Energy to Advance California Offshore Areas for Wind Energy Development and Good-Paying, Union Jobs Today, the White House convened National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy, California Governor Gavin Newsom, Interior Secretary Deb Haaland, and Under Secretary for Defense for Policy Dr. Colin Kahl to announce an effort&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>White House Marshals Departments of the Interior, Defense, and Energy to Advance California Offshore Areas for Wind Energy Development and Good-Paying, Union Jobs</em></p>



<p>Today, the White House convened National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy, California Governor Gavin Newsom, Interior Secretary Deb Haaland, and Under Secretary for Defense for Policy Dr. Colin Kahl to announce an effort to advance areas for offshore wind off the northern and central coasts of California – opening up the Pacific Coast to its first commercial scale offshore clean energy projects. This significant milestone is part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s goal to create thousands of good-paying, union jobs through the deployment of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/29/fact-sheet-biden-administration-jumpstarts-offshore-wind-energy-projects-to-create-jobs/">30 gigawatts (GW) of offshore wind by 2030</a>. These initial areas for offshore wind development in the Pacific Ocean could bring up to 4.6 GW of clean energy to the grid, enough to power 1.6 million American homes.</p>



<p>More specifically, the Department of the Interior, in coordination with the Department of Defense, has identified an area (“the Morro Bay 399 Area”) that will support three gigawatts of offshore wind on roughly 399 square miles off California’s central coast region, northwest of Morro Bay. The Department of the Interior is also advancing the Humboldt Call Area as a potential Wind Energy Area, located off northern California. These identified areas will enable the build out of a significant new domestic clean energy resource for years to come.</p>



<p>Because the Defense Department engages in significant testing, training, and operations off the coast of California that are essential to national security, the Defense Department played a critical role in identifying these new areas for offshore wind development. The Department of the Interior acknowledges the critical nature of current and future military testing, training, and operations and that the operational integrity thereof is a national security imperative. It will work closely with the Department of Defense to ensure long-term protection of military testing, training, and operations while pursuing new domestic clean energy resources.</p>



<p>Because the outer continental shelf falls away much more quickly into much deeper waters in the Pacific than it does in the Atlantic Ocean, new floating offshore wind technology will be deployed in offshore California waters. Notably, and as a further demonstration of the Biden administration’s whole-of-government approach to clean energy development, the. Department of Energy, through its Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy and ARPA-E, has invested more than $100 million in researching, developing, and demonstrating floating offshore wind technology. These investments have helped position the United States as a leader in the emerging global floating offshore wind market.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement comes after the Biden Administration announced a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/29/fact-sheet-biden-administration-jumpstarts-offshore-wind-energy-projects-to-create-jobs/">set of bold actions to catalyze offshore wind energy</a> as part of the President’s commitment to building new American infrastructure and a clean energy future that creates good-paying, union jobs. And, it follows the Administration’s <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-approves-first-major-offshore-wind-project-us-waters">approval of the first major offshore wind project</a> in U.S waters advancing the construction and operation of the Vineyard Wind project in Massachusetts.</p>



<p><em>Administration leaders shared their perspective on today’s announcement and collaboration:</em></p>



<p><strong>National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy: </strong>“Today’s announcement again demonstrates that by taking a whole-of-government approach, the U.S. can smartly develop our nation’s world-class offshore wind energy resources, deploy new technologies that our government has helped to advance, and create thousands of good-paying, union jobs – all in the service of combating the climate crisis. I salute the Departments of the Interior, Defense, and Energy, and our partners in California, for all they have done to make this possible.”</p>



<p><strong>California Governor Gavin Newsom:</strong> “Developing offshore wind to produce clean, renewable energy could be&nbsp;a game changer to achieving California’s clean energy goals and addressing climate change – all while bolstering the economy and creating new jobs. This historic announcement, which could provide clean power for up to 1.6 million homes over the next decade, represents the innovative approach we need for a clean energy economy that protects the coasts, fisheries, marine life, and Tribal, and cultural resources we value so much as Californians.”</p>



<p><strong>Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland: </strong>“I believe that a clean energy future is within our grasp in the United States, but it will take all of us and the best-available science to make it happen. Today’s announcement reflects months of active engagement and dedication between partners who are committed to advancing a clean energy future. The offshore wind industry has the potential to create tens of thousands of good-paying union jobs across the nation, while combating the negative effects of climate change. Interior is proud to be part of an all-of-government approach toward the Biden-Harris Administration&#8217;s ambitious renewable energy goals.”</p>



<p><strong>Under Secretary for Defense Policy Dr. Colin Kahl: </strong>“Tacking the climate crisis is a national security imperative and the Defense Department is proud to have played a role in this important effort. The Defense Department is committed to working across the U.S. government to find solutions that support renewable energy in a manner compatible with t essential military operations.&nbsp;Throughout this effort, the Defense Department has worked tirelessly with the White House, the Department of the Interior, and the State of California to find solutions that enable offshore wind development while ensuring long-term protection for testing, training, and operations critical to our military readiness.&nbsp;The Defense Department applauds this step and looks forward to continued coordination to address the climate crisis.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White House Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the Meeting Between President Joe Biden and President Vladimir Putin of Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/25/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-president-vladimir-putin-of-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden will meet with President Putin in Geneva, Switzerland on June 16, 2021. The leaders will discuss the full range of pressing issues, as we seek to restore predictability and stability to the U.S.-Russia relationship. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden will meet with President Putin in Geneva, Switzerland on June 16, 2021. The leaders will discuss the full range of pressing issues, as we seek to restore predictability and stability to the U.S.-Russia relationship.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden During Briefing on the Atlantic Hurricane Outlook and Preparedness Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/24/remarks-by-president-biden-during-briefing-on-the-atlantic-hurricane-outlook-and-preparedness-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FEMA HeadquartersWashington, D.C. 1:44 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hey, the press.&#160; Welcome.&#160; I have a very brief opening statement here.&#160; Administrator Criswell, thanks for &#8212; thanks for hosting us.&#160; You know, I wanted a tested veteran for FEMA, and that&#8217;s exactly what I got in the new head of FEMA.&#160; I really do appreciate it.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">FEMA Headquarters<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>1:44 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hey, the press.&nbsp; Welcome.&nbsp; I have a very brief opening statement here.&nbsp;<br><br>Administrator Criswell, thanks for &#8212; thanks for hosting us.&nbsp; You know, I wanted a tested veteran for FEMA, and that&#8217;s exactly what I got in the new head of FEMA.&nbsp; I really do appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>She served as a fire safety officer &#8212; I got to turn this on &#8212; a fire safety officer in &#8212; in Iraq and Afghanistan &#8212; that qualifies for any tough job &#8212; and played a critical role at FEMA before, and &#8212; and was a leader in response to something I was deeply involved in as Vice President at the time: Superstorm Sandy.&nbsp; Thank you for all that great work.&nbsp;<br><br>Already this year, FEMA has stepped up and vaccinated America and responded to winter storms, reminding us that we can never be too prepared.&nbsp;<br><br>My administration is going to bring every resource to bear &#8212; every resource to bear every time to help American people &#8212; the American people weather emergencies.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;re going to spare no expense, no effort to keep Americans safe and respond to crises when they arise.&nbsp; And they certainly will.&nbsp;<br><br>Now it&#8217;s time to get ready for the busiest time of the year for disasters in America: hurricane season in the south and east, and the fire season out west.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m here today to make it clear that I will insist on nothing less than readiness for all of these challenges.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make sure the men and women of FEMA and our other key agencies have everything they need &#8212; everything they need, because they&#8217;ve got an incredibly difficult job.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I&#8217;m announcing that FEMA is going to make $1 billion available to the states, territories, Tribes, and rural communities through the Building Resilience Infrastructure and Communities program &#8212; the so-called BRIC program.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s going to double the funding available of la- &#8212; from last year, and it&#8217;s going to help communities, including those too often overlooked, and it&#8217;s going to invest in resilience and better protect themselves to serve for other climate events that we&#8217;re going to be facing.<br><br>Last year, as you all know, we faced the most named storms on record.&nbsp; Seven out of the thirty named storms alone claimed 86 lives and caused more than $40 billion in damage.&nbsp;<br><br>This year, NOAA is focusing on another severe season, perhaps &#8212; and God willing &#8212; not as bad as 2020, but still quite bad.&nbsp; We all know that these storms are coming.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be prepared; we have to be ready.&nbsp; We have to be ready.&nbsp;<br><br>When disaster strikes, we have to be there to protect and also help people recover.&nbsp; And so it&#8217;s about &#8212; not about red states and blue states.&nbsp; You all know that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about having people&#8217;s backs in the toughest moments that they face, ready with food, water, blankets, shelters, and more.&nbsp;<br><br>But there&#8217;s, you know, there &#8212; to be, you know, beginning this effort for 2021 is &#8212; I think we&#8217;ve learned a few lessons from last year as well.&nbsp; There&#8217;s help us &#8212; we &#8212; there, you know, being there to help clear roads, rebuild Main Streets, and so that the families can get back to their lives &#8212; that&#8217;s what FEMA does every single day.&nbsp; As my mother would say, “They’re doing God’s work.”<br><br>Today &#8212; today&#8217;s briefing is a critical reminder: We don&#8217;t have a moment to lose in preparing for 2021.&nbsp; And so, again, I want to thank you for all that you do.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m looking forward to hearing from you all.&nbsp; And I thank the press for coming in.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>1:48 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Democratic Opposition Leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-democratic-opposition-leader-svyatlana-tsikhanouskaya-of-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18319</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan spoke today with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus. Mr. Sullivan conveyed the United States’ strong support for the demands of the Belarusian people for democracy, human rights, and fundamental freedoms.  Mr. Sullivan praised the bravery and selfless sacrifice of democratic leaders like Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya, her husband, Syarhey, and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan spoke today with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus. Mr. Sullivan conveyed the United States’ strong support for the demands of the Belarusian people for democracy, human rights, and fundamental freedoms.  Mr. Sullivan praised the bravery and selfless sacrifice of democratic leaders like Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya, her husband, Syarhey, and the hundreds of other Belarusian democracy activists, independent journalists, and civil society leaders who languish in Belarusian jails as political prisoners of the Lukashenka regime.  Mr. Sullivan strongly condemned the brazen and dangerous grounding of a Ryanair flight between two EU member states on May 23 and the subsequent removal and detention of journalist Raman Pratasevich.  Mr. Sullivan cited the U.S. demand for the immediate release of Mr. Pratasevich and all political prisoners in Belarus, as well as the need for free and fair elections under OSCE observation to resolve the current crisis.  Finally, Mr. Sullivan made clear that the United States, in coordination with the EU and other allies and partners, will hold the Lukashenka regime to account.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br> ###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Simon Coveney of Ireland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-foreign-minister-simon-coveney-of-ireland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:27:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Foreign Minister Simon Coveney of Ireland to discuss our strong bilateral relations and cooperation on a number of shared global challenges.  Mr. Sullivan and Foreign Minister Coveney condemned the forced diversion of a flight between two EU member states and the subsequent removal and arrest of journalist&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Foreign Minister Simon Coveney of Ireland to discuss our strong bilateral relations and cooperation on a number of shared global challenges.  Mr. Sullivan and Foreign Minister Coveney condemned the forced diversion of a flight between two EU member states and the subsequent removal and arrest of journalist Raman Pratasevich in Minsk by the Lukashenka regime, and they agreed to remain in close touch on an appropriate response.  They also discussed Ireland’s role in addressing challenges to peace and security as a non-permanent member of the UN Security Council.  Mr. Sullivan and Foreign Minister Coveney reaffirmed their commitment to protecting the gains of the Good Friday Agreement for all communities in Northern Ireland.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Diversion of Ryanair Flight and Arrest of Journalist in Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-diversion-of-ryanair-flight-and-arrest-of-journalist-in-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 23:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Belarus’s forced diversion of a commercial Ryanair flight, traveling between two member states of the European Union, and subsequent removal and arrest of Raman Pratasevich, a Belarusian journalist traveling abroad, are a direct affront to international norms. The United States condemns in the strongest possible terms both the diversion of the plane and the subsequent&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Belarus’s forced diversion of a commercial Ryanair flight, traveling between two member states of the European Union, and subsequent removal and arrest of Raman Pratasevich, a Belarusian journalist traveling abroad, are a direct affront to international norms. The United States condemns in the strongest possible terms both the diversion of the plane and the subsequent removal and arrest of Mr. Pratasevich. This outrageous incident and the video Mr. Pratasevich appears to have made under duress are shameful assaults on both political dissent and the freedom of the press. The United States joins countries around the world in calling for his release, as well as for the release of the hundreds of political prisoners who are being unjustly detained by the Lukashenka regime.</p>



<p>I join the many calls for an international investigation to ascertain the complete facts of the case. I welcome the news that the European Union has called for targeted economic sanctions and other measures, and have asked my team to develop appropriate options to hold accountable those responsible, in close coordination with the European Union, other allies and partners, and international organizations.</p>



<p>For months, the Belarusian people have made their voices heard—demanding democracy, respect for human rights, and the preservation of fundamental freedoms. I applaud the courage and determination of Belarusians fighting for basic rights, including journalists like Raman Pratasevich and opposition leaders like Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya and her husband, Syarhey Tsikhanouski. The United States will continue to stand with the people of Belarus in their struggle.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi of Egypt</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-president-abdel-fattah-al-sisi-of-egypt-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 21:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi of Egypt. President Biden thanked Egypt for its successful diplomacy and coordination with the United States to end the recent hostilities in Israel and Gaza and ensure violence does not reoccur. The two leaders consulted on the urgent need to deliver humanitarian assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi of Egypt. President Biden thanked Egypt for its successful diplomacy and coordination with the United States to end the recent hostilities in Israel and Gaza and ensure violence does not reoccur. The two leaders consulted on the urgent need to deliver humanitarian assistance to those in need in Gaza and to support rebuilding efforts in a manner that benefits the people there and not Hamas. President Biden said he has asked Secretary of State Antony Blinken to visit the region for follow up on these urgent needs. Regarding the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam, President Biden acknowledged Egypt’s concerns about access to Nile River waters and underscored the U.S. interest in achieving a diplomatic resolution that meets the legitimate needs of Egypt, Sudan, and Ethiopia. The two leaders also discussed their commitment to upholding Libyan plans for national elections in December and the removal of all foreign military and irregular forces from Libya. They also affirmed their support for the Iraqi government’s efforts to strengthen Iraq’s full sovereignty and independence. President Biden underscored the importance of a constructive dialogue on human rights in Egypt. The two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to a strong and productive U.S.-Egypt partnership.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
