<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:30:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Five Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/president-biden-announces-five-key-nominations-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 20:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following five individuals to serve in key roles: Ramin Toloui, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Economic and Business Affairs, Department of State Jennifer Clyburn Reed, Nominee for Federal Co-Chair of the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission Leslie Bluhm, Nominee for Member of the Board of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following five individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Ramin Toloui, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Economic and Business Affairs, Department of State</li><li>Jennifer Clyburn Reed, Nominee for Federal Co-Chair of the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission</li><li>Leslie Bluhm, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</li><li>Lisette Nieves, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</li><li>Flor Romero, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Ramin Toloui, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Economic and Business Affairs, Department of State</u></strong></p>



<p>Ramin Toloui is Professor of the Practice for International Finance at Stanford University, and Tad and Diane Taube Policy Fellow at the Stanford Institute for Economic Policy Research. His teaching and research focus on international economic policy, financial crises, and the economic impact of artificial intelligence. He recently led the policy review for international economics on the Biden-Harris Transition Team, in addition to serving on the State Department agency review team. Prior to joining Stanford, Toloui had a two-decade career spanning public service and investment management. He served in the Obama-Biden Administration as Assistant Secretary for International Finance at the Department of the Treasury, representing the United States in forums like the G7 and G20. Previously he was Global Co-Head of Emerging Markets Portfolio Management at the Pacific Investment Management Company (PIMCO), overseeing more than $100 billion in investments. He began his career as a civil servant at the Department of the Treasury. Toloui earned his A.B. degree in economics from Harvard University and an M.Phil. degree in International Relations from Oxford University, where he was a Rhodes Scholar.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jennifer Clyburn Reed, Nominee for Federal Co-Chair of the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Jennifer Clyburn Reed is a career educator whose education and teaching experience span 28 years in public and private schools and universities. A recent retiree from the University of South Carolina (UofSC), she holds Bachelors, Masters and Specialist degrees from UofSC and an earned doctoral degree from Nova Southeastern University (NSU) in Florida.</p>



<p>Prior to directing a research and teaching center at UofSC , she taught elementary and middle school and served as school site coordinator of the Advancement via Individual Determination (AVID) program, a college preparatory system designed for students with academic potential, many of whom were first generation college attendees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While Director, Dr. Reed also co-coordinated the design and implementation of the Apple Core Initiative (ACI), a scholarship program for incoming freshmen to the USC College of Education’s teacher education program. Currently, she serves on the selection committee for the $1.7 million Emily Clyburn Honors College Scholarship at South Carolina State University, a public HBCU.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Reed is a member of Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc. and a Rotarian. She is co-owner of a property investment company, 49 Magnolia Blossom, LLC and President of its non-profit arm, Magnolia Blossom SC. Dr. Reed is also the CEO of Palmetto Issues Conference, LLC, an issues-based advisory group advocating for accessible and equitable policies in education, health, housing and infrastructure.</p>



<p>Dr. Reed is married to Mississippi native Walter A. Reed. They have two adult children &#8211; Walter A. Clyburn Reed and Sydney Alexis Reed. The Reed family resides in South Carolina.</p>



<p><strong><u>Leslie N. Bluhm, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</u></strong></p>



<p>Leslie N. Bluhm is a social entrepreneur who empowers people to tackle challenges through collaborative action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In 1991, she co-founded Chicago Cares, Inc., the city’s leading volunteer service organization. Chicago Cares builds group volunteer programs that meet the critical needs of the community while using the volunteer experience to educate volunteers from diverse communities about each other; building trust, empathy and connection.</p>



<p>Leslie was named one of six Chicagoans of the year by Chicago Magazine and was named to Crain’s 40 under 40. She serves on the board of directors of Chicago Cares, The Chicago Community Trust, The Museum of Contemporary Art Chicago, OneGoal, Whitney Museum of American Art, Shining Hope for Communities, and Rush Street Interactive, Inc.</p>



<p>She earned a BA from the University of Michigan and a JD from the University of Chicago Law School. She and her husband David Helfand reside in Chicago and have two sons.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Lisette Nieves, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</u></strong></p>



<p>Lisette Nieves is the President of the Fund for the City of New York (FCNY), charged with developing and helping to implement innovations in policy, programs, practices and technology to advance the functioning of government and nonprofit organizations in New York City and beyond. Lisette is also a Distinguished Clinical Professor with NYU, overseeing doctoral students and supporting change and innovation research initiatives in the doctoral program Leadership and Innovation, which she co-founded.</p>



<p>Lisette has also served in a variety of cross sector leadership positions. She is an experienced social entrepreneur and public sector leader. She has supported community social entrepreneurs and educators through her prior work with Lingo Ventures, a company she co-founded focused on growth, talent recruitment/retention, and change management. Lisette also served as the Belle Zeller Distinguished Visiting Professor in Public Policy at the City University of New York at Brooklyn College. Lisette was the founding Executive Director of Year Up NY, an innovative workforce development program, where, in the span of five years, she grew the organization from a $250,000 seed grant to a $6 million operation with over 20 corporate partnerships. Her interest in workforce and education led to her dissertation on the relationship between student work and school roles, for which she received the 2016 Dissertation of the Year Award by the (NCSD – AACC). Lisette also began her career in service serving full time in New York as a City Volunteer Corps member before she attended Brooklyn College for her undergraduate degree. She was also a proud team member of the launch of the AmeriCorps program under the Clinton administration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lisette holds a B.A. from Brooklyn College, a B.A./M.A. from the University of Oxford, an M.P.A. from the Woodrow Wilson School at Princeton University and a doctorate with distinction in Higher Education Management at the University of Pennsylvania. She is a Truman Scholar, Rhodes Scholar, Aspen Pahara Fellow and a 2020 Richard P. Nathan Public Policy Fellow. Her board affiliations include the Edwin Gould Foundation, AVID, The Education Trust, NewSchools Venture Fund, Jobs for the Future (JFF), Stand for Children, Ellevation and a Trustee of the New York Public Library.</p>



<p><strong><u>Flor Romero, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of AmeriCorps</u></strong></p>



<p>The daughter of first-generation Salvadoran immigrants, Flor Romero is a social worker who has dedicated her career to historically marginalized communities through equity and access initiatives.</p>



<p>At age 14, Flor realized the importance of resources that were missing in her hometown to help the community thrive. As a Psychology major at UCLA, she was found a work-study job that aligned with her passion and goals: Jumpstart, an early education AmeriCorps organization dedicated to helping bridge the achievement gap between minority students and their affluent peers. For her four years at UCLA, Flor stayed with Jumpstart, which inspired her to pursue a Master’s degree in Social Work with a focus on social change and innovation at the University of Southern California.</p>



<p>Throughout her career, Flor has led community-focused projects, working with stakeholders and leaders on foster care and adoption, mental health, education, and more. During her time at USC, she spearheaded a successful reading program across the Los Angeles Unified School District, the second-largest school district in the nation, working closely with schools in Los Angeles County and increasing reading among students. Currently she works at Fraser Communications, where she works on accounts that strive for equal opportunity.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Attack on United Nations Compound in&#160;Herat</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-attack-on-united-nations-compound-in-herat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 19:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States strongly condemns the attack on the United Nations compound in Herat, Afghanistan that resulted in the death of an Afghan guard. The United Nations in Afghanistan is a civilian entity focused on supporting peace efforts, promoting the rights of all Afghans and providing humanitarian and development assistance. Attacks against civilian UN personnel&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States strongly condemns the attack on the United Nations compound in Herat, Afghanistan that resulted in the death of an Afghan guard. The United Nations in Afghanistan is a civilian entity focused on supporting peace efforts, promoting the rights of all Afghans and providing humanitarian and development assistance. Attacks against civilian UN personnel and facilities are prohibited under international law.<br><br>We reiterate our call for an immediate reduction in violence in Afghanistan, and for all regional actors to encourage the parties to return to negotiations without delay so that the Afghan people can achieve a durable and just political settlement that brings the peace and security they deserve.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris in Virtual Meeting with Governors on&#160;Wildfires</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/30/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-in-virtual-meeting-with-governors-on-wildfires/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 19:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via TeleconferenceSouth Court Auditorium &#160;12:03 P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Jay, you’re beginning to convince the American people there is a thing called “climate crisis.”&#160; About time.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160;GOVERNOR INSLEE:&#160; Indeed.&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, thank you all for being here.&#160; I’m going to make a brief statement here and then we’ll get to ask the Vice President to say&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>&nbsp;<br>12:03 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Jay, you’re beginning to convince the American people there is a thing called “climate crisis.”&nbsp; About time.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR INSLEE:&nbsp; Indeed.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you all for being here.&nbsp; I’m going to make a brief statement here and then we’ll get to ask the Vice President to say a few words, get to some questions, and we’ll get down to business, if that’s okay with you all.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, one month ago, we convened the first of what will be a regular presidential briefing on wildfire preparedness.&nbsp; And we’re joined by many of the governors who &#8212; we were joined by many of the governors who are with us today, as well as experts from across the administration and leaders from the electric utility sector.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I said then that the threat of Western wildfires this year was as severe as it’s ever been.&nbsp; And in the past month, we’ve sadly seen the truth of that being played out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Since our &#8212; our last meeting, the number of large, uncontained wildfires has nearly doubled to 66 &#8212; 66 of those fires.&nbsp; And the number of firefighters on the job to battle them has tripled.&nbsp; Over 3.4 million acres have already burned.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In Oregon, the Bootleg Fire has destroyed more than 400 structures, including more than 160 homes.&nbsp; In California, the Dixie Fire has grown to over 220,000 acres and our firefighters are working in really rugged and dangerous conditions and terrain.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The number of states are experiencing the impacts of smoke from these fires, degrading their air quality, not just where the fires are burning, but all the states moving east &#8212; not all, but most.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In short, we’ve got big, complex wildfires burning across multiple areas.&nbsp; And despite the incredible &#8212; and I’m not &#8212; this is not being solicitous &#8212; the incredible bravery and heroism of our firefighters, our resources are already being stretched to keep up.&nbsp; We need more help, particularly when we also factor in the additional nationwide challenges of pandemic-related supply chain disruptions and our ongoing efforts to fight COVID.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ve had a few COVID clusters at our fire camps, which further limits resources.&nbsp; It’s just one more reason why it’s so darn important that everyone get vaccinated, I might add.<br>&nbsp;<br>Sadly, we’ve also lost two brave firefighters in the last month in a plane crash in Arizona, and five were seriously injured last week battling the Devil’s Creek fire in Montana.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It’s &#8212; to state the obvious, and you governors know it better than anybody &#8212; it is really, really dangerous work, and it takes incredible bravery to do it.&nbsp; And these heroes deserve to be paid &#8212; and paid well &#8212; for their work.&nbsp; That’s why, last month, I was able to announce &#8212; and it’s not paying that well, in my view, to be honest with you &#8212; immediate action to make all federal firefighters making at least $15 an hour.&nbsp; I think they deserve more than that.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re also working with Congress to make sure that our firefighters are paid better permanently.&nbsp; Permanently.&nbsp; So far, FEMA has approved 20 Fire Management Assistance Grants totaling up to $100 million to help states pay for the cost of fighting these fires.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re also working with FEMA and the Defense Logistical Agency to get ahead of this emergency supply chain challenges.&nbsp; And we still have some supply chain challenges relating to hoses and a number of other things.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re trapped &#8212; we’ve tapped additional aircraft from the Department of Defense to aid in the fire detection and firefighting.&nbsp; We also welcome the support of our allies, from Australia, for example, sending a large air tanker to which it’s going to begin flying missions this week.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And last month, I also noted that the EPA would be launching an upgrade app for mobile phones to easily share location-specific information with the public about the effects of fire and smoke on air quality for them.&nbsp; It’s now even more important, because smoke from many of these fires burning in the West and along the Canadian border is affecting air quality in states across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As of today, the upgrade app &#8212; the upgrade AirNow app is live and ready for use.&nbsp; Folks in affected areas should download this important tool as quickly as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I also encourage our states and county leaders to continue partnering with FEMA, as many of the leaders on the scene today are leveraging our Public Alert and Warning systems to communicate information directly and quickly about &#8212; to the public about wildfires, evacuations, power outages, and more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know several of the governors’ states have used this system recently and send &#8212; to send warnings of evacuation orders, and it has undoubtedly helped people and, we don’t know for certain, but likely saved some lives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we’re in for a long fight yet this year, and the only way we’re going to meet those challenges is by working together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Wildfires are a problem for all of us and we have to stay closely coordinated in doing everything we can for our people.&nbsp; That’s why I asked the governors to join us &#8212; Democrats and Republicans alike &#8212; so they can update me and the Vice President directly on what they need and what we can possibly do more of.&nbsp; And so we can discuss what’s needed today &#8212; we have to meet an urgent danger at hand &#8212; a plan for what we can do to make sure we’re better prepared next time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One of the important aspects of the &#8212; of the bipartisan infrastructure deal that is before the Senate now is it includes billions of dollars &#8212; billions of dollars &#8212; to strengthen wildfire preparedness, resilience, and response.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It includes funding for prevention efforts, like forest management, and to restore millions of acres of high-risk areas to protect homes and public water sources for drinking.&nbsp; And &#8212; you know, and overlaying all of this is the necessity to successfully confront climate change.<br>&nbsp;<br>We may &#8212; we have some significant changes we’re making in these two pieces of legislation that, God willing, will pass in the next month or so.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we can’t ignore how the overlapping and intertwined factors of extreme heat, prolonged drought, and supercharged wildfire conditions are affecting the country.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, this is a challenge that demands our urgent, urgent action, both today and, as you all know better than anyone else in the country, not just today, but tomorrow, next year, and the year after.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I want to thank you, Governors, for your leadership during what is an incredibly challenging period for all of you.&nbsp; God, love you.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going through &#8212; anyway.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’d like to ask, now, the Vice President to make a few comments.&nbsp; And then, I have some questions for all and we get in a discussion, with your permission.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Vice President.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We stand with you.&nbsp; We stand with you, and this is a commitment from our administration that we will not only stand with you, but stay in touch with you, mostly to hear from you.&nbsp; We know that the way that we can help you manage and expand your capacity is through the partnership that we have &#8212; the federal and state government, along with local governments.<br>&nbsp;<br>This &#8212; this issue is ongoing.&nbsp; Each year, as we have discussed, it gets worse.&nbsp; It affects real people &#8212; everything from children who are breathing the smoke to parents who are up at night, concerned that they may get an evacuation order at any &#8212; at any moment.&nbsp; So, know that we are here to maximize the federal capacity to support the states.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m in D.C., but, of course, I&#8217;m a California girl and I care deeply about this.&nbsp; We &#8212; as I think I&#8217;ve shared with many of you, our family has been under evacuation orders in the last couple of years.&nbsp; And &#8212; and our folks should not have to fear that they are &#8212; they are going to lose their home, everything they have, much less risk their lives in these moments.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you all for your courage, for your leadership, and I look forward to staying in touch with you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, I asked the staff &#8212; because I think it&#8217;s &#8212; I&#8217;ve had the great honor of being, over the last 15 years, in your states and in the wilderness areas and the national parks.&nbsp; And I asked my staff to put together maps where exactly where the fires are and the areas they&#8217;re in and what they&#8217;re affecting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I want to start off with you, Governor Gianforte, up in Montana.&nbsp; You have your hands full, man.&nbsp; And I &#8212; looking at &#8212; at the map, all away from, you know, Poverty Flats and Crooked Creek, all the way up into Ruby and Hay Creek, and the other end of the state.&nbsp; But the big fires look like they&#8217;re in Trail Creek and Alder Creek &#8212; in those areas that are significant.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I got &#8212; I have a simple question, and it&#8217;s a complicated one, but what can we do for you that &#8212; that we&#8217;re just not getting done now?&nbsp; What additional help can we give you now that &#8212; that is not &#8212; not there yet?<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, cut through all the &#8212; all the jargon about, you know, all that we policy wonks are talking about various programs.&nbsp; Bottom line: What do you need and can we help &#8212; you know, that we haven&#8217;t?<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR GIANFORTE:&nbsp; Good morning, Mr. President, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; I want to thank you for the opportunity to join you, and I want to answer your question because there are some things we can do to collaborate and work closer together.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just to give a moment of background: As we meet this morning, our heroic firefighters are confronting 19 largescale fires in Montana alone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And to put that in perspective: Just since January 1st, we&#8217;ve had 1,600 fires start in Montana and we&#8217;ve burned about 220,000 acres.&nbsp; These wildfires threaten the safety of our communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That Poverty Flats fire that you mentioned, in the last week, burned from initial start to 65,000 acres currently threatening 1,200 households out in the Big Horn County area, our first responders.&nbsp; These devastate our local communities and the costs keep mounting.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve spent &#8212; the state has spent $13 million since July 1st alone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It could have been much worse.&nbsp; And this gets to your question, Mr. President.&nbsp; Without our state&#8217;s commitment &#8212; and we&#8217;ve shared this with Forest Service and BLM, and they&#8217;ve been very cooperative &#8212; to aggressive initial attack, Montana &#8212; without that commitment, we would have had many more largescale fires.&nbsp; And we ask that our federal partners join us in applying this operating principle.&nbsp; Whether it&#8217;s a fire that starts on private, state, or federal land &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR GIANFORTE: &#8212; fires are easier to manage when they&#8217;re smaller.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR GIANFORTE:&nbsp; And when we get after them, we do much better.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As we continue to confront this wildfire season, we&#8217;re also focused on addressing Montana&#8217;s forest health crisis.&nbsp; We published, earlier this year, the Montana Forest Action Plan, which identifies 9 million acres of forest land with significant forest health issues and an elevated risk of wildfire.&nbsp; Of those acres at risk, we found about 4 million acres that would benefit most from cross-bounty [sic] &#8212; boundary forest management.<br>&nbsp;<br>Given the need to actively manage our forests, I&#8217;ve charged our Department of Natural Resources and Conservation to double the number of acres it treats with active forest management this year at 25,000 acres.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is just a starting point.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll actively manage private, state, and federal land with a variety of treatment types, including thinning, logging, and prescribed burn.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve also invested in 14 different cross-boundary projects in Montana this year.&nbsp; These projects demonstrate the importance of working together across ownership &#8212; ownership boundaries to create meaningful, landscape-scale change.&nbsp; And using funds from the state&#8217;s fire suppression account and the Forest Service State and Private Forestry Division, we&#8217;ll expand existing work and jumpstart new activities.<br>&nbsp;<br>But it&#8217;s not up, totally, to us.&nbsp; We ask that our federal partners join us in doing what needs to be done year-round to reduce the risk of catastrophic wildfires.<br>&nbsp;<br>Of the 9 million acres at high risk, 60 percent of those are on federal land.&nbsp; This makes tools like the Good Neighbor Authority and stewardship contracting more important than ever.<br>&nbsp;<br>The benefits are really clear: We have healthier forests, improved wildlife habitats, more recreational opportunities, and more good-paying jobs, and, most importantly, less severe wildfires.&nbsp; Without active forest management, we can&#8217;t be successful in our forest health improvements.<br>&nbsp;<br>In closing, I just want to say &#8212; I want to thank our federal partners.&nbsp; We have good collaborative relationships here in Montana with the Forest Service and BLM.&nbsp; I also want to thank Governor Newsom and Governor Cox for sending crews to help us deal with these fires that are currently burning.&nbsp; We have thousands of first responders on the frontlines, right now, protecting our communities, natural resources, and livelihoods across Montana, across the western United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>So many people have sacrificed, and I can&#8217;t thank them enough.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t measure it in dollars spent or acres burns &#8212; burned.&nbsp; We have to keep them and their loved ones in our thoughts and our prayers.<br>&nbsp;<br>I agree with you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Now is the time to act.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s all about aggressive initial attack and getting more proactive in our forest management.<br>&nbsp;<br>Again, Mr. President, Vice President Harris, I want to thank you for letting me join you today.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Greg, let me ask you another question, if I may.&nbsp; There&#8217;s press in the room, and lots of times, I know I do and we all do, use terms which those of us who are in public office &#8212; whether it&#8217;s President, Senator, Governor, et cetera &#8212; use, and I don&#8217;t think &#8212; understandably, the American people don&#8217;t fully understand what they mean.&nbsp; And &#8212; and even I &#8212; sometimes the press has so much to cover, I&#8217;m not sure they &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>You talked about the Forest Health Plan.&nbsp; And talk about, as I say to my staff all the time, in plain English, what’s that mean.&nbsp; Explain a little bit what that means.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR GIANFORTE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, we have many forests in Montana that have not had good stewardship.&nbsp; The growth has gotten to the point &#8212; I can take you 10 miles west to the state capital in Helena and show you a federal forest where 90 percent of the trees are standing dead.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been killed by beetle when &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;Right.&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR GIANFORTE:&nbsp; And this really creates a tinderbox situation.&nbsp; It reduces habitat.&nbsp; So. very &#8212; very little wildlife lives there.&nbsp; And when we get a lightning strike or a campfire out of control and a fire starts in a forest like that, we put firefighters at risk.&nbsp; They&#8217;re very hard to control.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The state has been very proactive.&nbsp; We &#8212; the state has about 5 million acres.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been very active in being stewards of those grounds.&nbsp; And when we thin a forest &#8212; this is not clear cuts &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR GIANFORTE:&nbsp; &#8212; but when we thin, when we remove excess fuels, water comes back into surface streams, wildlife comes back into that community.&nbsp; And when wildfire goes through a managed forest, it doesn’t then get into the crown.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t burn as hot.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have the devastation.&nbsp; And structures aren&#8217;t threatened.&nbsp; So everybody wins when we have good stewardship of the forest.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That&#8217;s really important.&nbsp; I &#8212; believe it or not, I knew that.&nbsp; But that’s really important for people to get it.&nbsp; Because we talk about thinning out the forest.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about a lot of trees, because of climate change as well, where you have bugs, insects, eating up the trees as well, making things that &#8212; that are changing and killing the forest themselves, and they become real tinder.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s like, you know, dropping a match in a &#8212; you know, in &#8212; almost like in a pool of fuel.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so going in and cutting all that out is not the same as going in &#8212; I&#8217;m glad you made the point of clear cutting &#8212; going in and just &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I &#8212; look, we do have, and we&#8217;re &#8212; I&#8217;m hopeful that we&#8217;re going to get a lot of the infrastructure plan passed and the Recovery Act that has a lot of money in here to help you all manage these forests and to have much more money in there for the &#8212; for the Bureau of Land Management &#8212; anyway &#8212; to be able to give you the help you need.&nbsp; Because your state, which I&#8217;ve been through, is a magnificently beautiful state.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s &#8212; and, I mean &#8212; and the thing &#8212; you know, you &#8212; I come from the state of Delaware.&nbsp; And, you know, you had &#8212; we had more acreage burned last year than the state of Delaware and Maryland combined &#8212; combined.&nbsp; For you all out in Montana, that ain’t (inaudible).&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; But I want people to get a sense of how massive &#8212; how massive these fires are and how they affect water systems and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Anyway, but that&#8217;s &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry to take your time, but I wanted you to be able to explain that so people understand that are listening to this.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me ask you &#8212; let me ask you, Governor Inslee: You know, you&#8217;ve been talking about the impacts of environmental change for a long, long time.&nbsp; And one of the things &#8212; and I asked him to show me &#8212; to get me a map of where all your fires are in your state.&nbsp; And when you have Delancy and Cub Creek 2 and Cedar Creek &#8212; I mean, they&#8217;re massive fires.&nbsp; Massive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And what are &#8212; you know, as you look at what&#8217;s transpired over the past month and you look at the road ahead of this wildfire scene, what is your biggest concern, Jay?&nbsp; What is your biggest concern?&nbsp; And again, I ask you the same question: What is the thing we can do most?&nbsp; I mean, you go all the way from Delancy down to “Lil’ Crick,” as they say &#8212; in the Creek &#8212; you know down in the southwest &#8212; southeast part of your state.&nbsp; What are &#8212; what are your biggest concerns?<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR INSLEE:&nbsp; Well, first off, thanks for your leadership, Mr. President.&nbsp; It is so refreshing to have a President who really cares about the Western Forest.<br>&nbsp;<br>My biggest concern might surprise you because all of the governors share these immediate concerns.&nbsp; We have a huge need for additional aerial assets, additional dozer bosses so we can get our dozers into fire lines.&nbsp; We need new tra- &#8212; more trained people.&nbsp; We do have an emerging concern about our fuel supply for our aerial assets.&nbsp; Everything we need to fight forest fires is in dire need across the Western United States, not just in Washington State.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had a thousand fires.&nbsp; It&#8217;s burned four times more at this time of year than normal.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had two and a half times more acreage burn in the last decade than the previous.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So those are the obvious concerns.&nbsp; And everything you need to fight a fire, we &#8212; we could use your help on.&nbsp; And I think you&#8217;ve been totally on top of this, and so I thank you for your leadership on all of these things, including management issues.&nbsp; There&#8217;s unanimity, there&#8217;s bipartisan acceptance of the need for active management.&nbsp; We&#8217;re acti- &#8212; we&#8217;re managing our forests, just like Montana is, to try to get in and reduce fuel.<br>&nbsp;<br>But here&#8217;s the surprising thing, when you asked me this question, or the thing that I worry most about: The thing I worry most about is if, for some reason, the Congress did not follow your leadership in this reconciliation and infrastructure bills that allowed you to realize your vision of creating millions of jobs while fighting climate change.&nbsp; That&#8217;s my biggest worry right now.&nbsp; Because the fact of the matter is there is nothing in human intervention against these fires while climate continues to ravage our forest.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, we used to think of these things are forests.&nbsp; They really, now, just fields of fuel, and they&#8217;re fields of fire with just one spark because they&#8217;re so dry.&nbsp; And that aridity creates something like gasoline on the floor of our forest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There is only one way to prevent these forests from being gone in the la- &#8212; in the next century effectively, to be totally unrecognizable, and that is to succeed in following your vision in the reconciliation bill for a clean energy standard, for a huge transition to the electrification of our transportation fleet, to a civilian climate corps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I want to tell you we are going to be with you, as you stand tall, while you negotiate this reconciliation bill to say, “Look, we have to have those climate investments.&nbsp; There is only one way to save these forests from the ravages of climate.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our own federal scientists have said that if we accept a one-degree centigrade change, we&#8217;ll have 600 percent increase in these fires on a regular basis.&nbsp; We won&#8217;t recognize these forests as forests anymore unless we succeed with your vision.<br>&nbsp;<br>So when you start having those discussions with Mr. Klain and Steve Ricchetti and everyone else at the end of the reconciliation process, you got to know you&#8217;re going to have an army behind you standing tall for those things.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, there&#8217;s some other small things that I&#8217;m talking to your staff about, about having better independent assistance for towns like Malden that burned down.&nbsp; There&#8217;s some other coordination.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR INSLEE:&nbsp; But that&#8217;s the thing that&#8217;s going to ultimately decide whether these forests survive in the next century.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks for your leadership, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you for saying that.&nbsp; But, you know, one of the things that I say to all your colleagues: When I &#8212; when it was proposed to me by some folks that we should have a Civilian Climate Corps of thousands of young people trained to do these things and &#8212; at first, it didn&#8217;t &#8212; you know, I said, &#8220;Yeah, yeah, that sounds good.&#8221;&nbsp; And then I started looking at it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the truth of it is, it&#8217;s not fundamentally different, in terms of the help it can provide across the board training a lot of these &#8212; I&#8217;m talking about thousands of young people getting paid to be trained and trained well for a very &#8212; it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not fundamentally different than the Civilian Corps put together in the Depression that was &#8212; had a different purpose.&nbsp; They were building a building.&nbsp; They were doing a whole range of things.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I just think I&#8217;d encourage &#8212; and also, we&#8217;ll send it to all of you.&nbsp; But all you governors &#8212; Democrat, Republican &#8212; take a look at it and see if you think I&#8217;m &#8212; you know, I may have &#8212; you know, as my mother would say, my eyes are bigger than my stomach.&nbsp; You know that I may have a bigger appetite.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I &#8212; I really think it can &#8212; can be helpful.&nbsp; And there &#8212; again, I say to your colleagues, there&#8217;s a lot of money in here to be able to deal with your immediate needs as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, anyway.&nbsp; Thanks, Jay.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll get &#8212; I know you have this, but I want to get &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR INSLEE:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; more of it to you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, Gavin, I &#8212; or, Governor, you know, I applaud your your &#8212; your establishing the Wildfire and Forest Resilience Task Force, which I&#8217;ve learned is co-chaired by your Secretary of Natural Resources. &nbsp;I think it&#8217;s a great example of being able to coordinate federal, state, local because this is getting real &#8212; this is &#8212; this is getting &#8212; this is &#8212; this needs a lot of coordination.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I understand that PG&amp;E, which provides electric to 17 million of your folks &#8212; I understand they recently announced underground 10,000 miles of power lines.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that true?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s that going to do to the cost of energy in your state?&nbsp; And &#8212; I mean, because that&#8217;s expensive stuff.<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a million to three and a half million dollars a mile to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; &#8212; underground in California.&nbsp; Do the math on 10,000 miles.<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, do the math on decades of neglect.&nbsp; Ten thousand miles is a drop in the bucket.&nbsp; They have 106,000 miles of distribution line.&nbsp; Twenty-five thousand just in high-risk, fire-prone areas which will only grow.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a 10-year commitment.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important, but I want to put it in perspective.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also want to put something else in perspective.&nbsp; Your eyes, Mr. President, are not wider than your stomach.&nbsp; California is proving your theory.&nbsp; Over a year and a half ago we established the Climate Corps in this state.&nbsp; It&#8217;s inspiring beyond words.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also inspired the philanthropic sector &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It really is, isn&#8217;t it?&nbsp; I mean, it&#8217;s not a joke.&nbsp; It is inspiring when you see it.&nbsp; I mean, it&#8217;s incredible, I think.&nbsp; But &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s the one thing this country needs more than anything else, and that&#8217;s common experiences and to focus on the things that bind us together, not just divide us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This transcends politics.&nbsp; We have kids from urban and rural parts of the state, across every conceivable difference, and they&#8217;re advancing together in ways that truly are awe-inspiring.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, Mr. President, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s a vision we can manifest.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not asserting it; we&#8217;re proving it.<br>&nbsp;<br>In a small way, you have the opportunity to do it in &#8212; at scale.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, I just want to briefly &#8212; because there&#8217;s so many of us &#8212; a quick update.&nbsp; We&#8217;re blowing past every record, and not in a good way.&nbsp; We&#8217;re at over 5,700 fires year-to-date.&nbsp; We suppressed 59 just yesterday with some initial attacks.&nbsp; Over half a million acres already burned in California.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>To put in perspective &#8212; a record-breaking year.&nbsp; Last year, we were at 130,000 acres burned.&nbsp; We&#8217;re at 504,000 as I speak to you today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here&#8217;s the answer to your question.&nbsp; And forgive me for being so pointed again, respecting your time, but I want to be a little bit more specific.<br>&nbsp;<br>Jay referenced it obliquely.&nbsp; Please pay attention to this fuels issue.&nbsp; We had to get our National Guard to get some emergency fuel supplies for our aerial fleet a week ago.&nbsp; This is a major issue, and it&#8217;s not just impacting our aerial suppression strategies on the West Coast.&nbsp; It&#8217;s increasingly, as you may know, impacting commercial aviation.&nbsp; It is a major issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, we just simply need more boots on the ground.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t do without you.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got 7,400 people &#8212; 7,400 already.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not in fire season.&nbsp; Fire season in California is late September, October, into November.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in July.&nbsp; We already have 7,400 personnel actively working to suppress fires.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last year, the federal government asked us for over 5,000 mutual aid support that we could not provide.&nbsp; That gives you a sense of what the federal government wanted from California last year to send to other states.&nbsp; That should give you a sense of how far behind we are with federal support.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have four DC-10s, Mr. President.&nbsp; Four.&nbsp; Now, DC-10s aren&#8217;t the answer to every problem.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t fly over 35 knots.&nbsp; They have restrictions; there are legendary restrictions.&nbsp; But the reality is there is four for the country, and we&#8217;re competing.&nbsp; They&#8217;re all contracted.&nbsp; We compete with you.&nbsp; We compete with other states.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t even have access right now to DC-10s.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We lost that 747 &#8212; that iconic 747 &#8212; that now has been converted to a cargo plane.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve seen that in Australia, not just across the West Coast.&nbsp; That&#8217;s now been grounded by a private contractor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are the largest civil aviation fleet for firefighting in the world &#8212; California.&nbsp; We do not come close to having the tools in the air that we need.&nbsp; We need your support to su- &#8212; to dramatically increase the aerial support, in addition to boots on the ground.<br>&nbsp;<br>Final two quick points: Every year, we&#8217;re competing &#8212; and you have a lot of legislators that have been doing heroic work in Democratic states, governors &#8212; and Republican states &#8212; trying to get access to the Pentagon satellite technology for early detection.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a game changer for us.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re getting it on a year-to-year basis, but it&#8217;s hard.&nbsp; Every year, we fight to get a one-year extension on that access to a critical tool of technology.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d encourage you to help us so we&#8217;re not just fighting every year for something that I think you would support and the Pentagon, at the end of the day, final analysis will approve.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But here&#8217;s the final thing, and it&#8217;s the elephant in the room.&nbsp; I was with Governor Sisolak two days ago in his state of Nevada.&nbsp; The reason why is we had a fire that was on federal property.&nbsp; Fifty-seven percent of the forest property in California is federal, just three percent under California jurisdiction.&nbsp; Three percent.&nbsp; Fifty-seven percent under U.S. Forest Service.&nbsp; U.S. Forest Service is spectacular.&nbsp; We have deep admiration and respect, but there&#8217;s a culture that, too often, is, &#8220;Wait and see.&#8221;&nbsp; We can&#8217;t afford that any longer.&nbsp; This was a federal fire.&nbsp; They waited.&nbsp; And what we saw is the fire took off because we didn&#8217;t put enough initial assets.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Greg was making an oblique point here.&nbsp; I want to be a little bit more explicit: We need your help to change the culture, in terms of the suppression strategies, in this climate, literally and figuratively, to be more aggressive on these federal fires.<br>&nbsp;<br>That fire bled into Nevada and, obviously, impacted not just our two states, but deeply impacted the redundancy of this concern that comes out every year around jurisdictions and incident command and the imperative that we&#8217;re all on the same page, in terms of those initial attack strategies.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, forgive me for being longwinded, but I wanted to get those clear &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doing this.&nbsp; I want to find out what &#8212; what&#8217;s the greatest concerns you have.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I will &#8212; when this meeting is over, I will be on the phone with the Department of Defense and talking about the access to satellite capability.<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; but &#8212; I&#8217;m looking down the list here.&nbsp; All right, I will follow up with you, Gov &#8212; or the Vice President will; she has a mild interest in California &#8212; with all the points you just raised, and I &#8212; and I do appreciate it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, I want to get to each one of you, but we&#8217;re going to ask the &#8212; I think now is the time the press is going to leave the room.&nbsp; Am I correct?<br>&nbsp;<br>(Press is ushered out.)<br>&nbsp;<br>12:34 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Intent to Nominate and Appoint Leaders to Serve in Key Religious Affairs&#160;Roles</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/president-biden-announces-intent-to-nominate-and-appoint-leaders-to-serve-in-key-religious-affairs-roles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate and appoint individuals to serve in key roles at the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom: Rashad Hussain, Nominee for Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom Deborah Lipstadt, Nominee for Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism with the Rank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate and appoint individuals to serve in key roles at the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom:</p>



<ul><li>Rashad Hussain, Nominee for Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom</li><li>Deborah Lipstadt, Nominee for Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism with the Rank of Ambassador</li><li>Khizr Khan, Appointee for Commissioner of the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</li><li>Sharon Kleinbaum, Appointee for Commissioner of the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</li></ul>



<p>Today’s announcement underscores the President’s commitment to build an Administration that looks like America and reflects people of all faiths. Hussain is the first Muslim to be nominated to serve as the Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom, and Lipstadt is a renowned scholar of the Holocaust and antisemitism.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rashad Hussain, Nominee for Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom</u></strong></p>



<p>Rashad Hussain is Director for Partnerships and Global Engagement at the National Security Council.&nbsp;He previously served as Senior Counsel at the Department of Justice’s National Security Division.&nbsp;During the Obama Administration, Rashad served as U.S. Special Envoy to the Organization of Islamic Cooperation (OIC), U.S. Special Envoy for Strategic Counterterrorism Communications, and Deputy Associate White House Counsel. In his roles as Envoy, Hussain worked with multilateral organizations such as the OIC and UN, foreign governments, and civil society organizations to expand partnerships in education, entrepreneurship, health, international security, science and technology, and other areas.&nbsp;Rashad also spearheaded efforts on countering antisemitism and protecting religious minorities in Muslim-majority countries. Prior to joining the Obama Administration, Rashad worked on the House Judiciary Committee, served as a judicial law clerk to the Hon. Damon Keith on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit, and was an Associate Counsel to the Obama-Biden Transition Project.&nbsp;Rashad received his J.D. from Yale Law School, where he served as an editor of the Yale Law Journal, and Master’s degrees in Public Administration (Kennedy School of Government) and Arabic and Islamic Studies from Harvard University.&nbsp;He has also taught as Adjunct Professor of Law at Georgetown Law Center and the Georgetown School of Foreign Service.&nbsp;He speaks Urdu, Arabic, and Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Deborah Lipstadt, Nominee for Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism with the Rank of Ambassador</u></strong></p>



<p>Deborah&nbsp;E.&nbsp;Lipstadt is&nbsp;Dorot Professor of Modern Jewish History and Holocaust Studies at Emory University, where she was the founding director of the Institute for Jewish Studies. She&nbsp;is&nbsp;the author of&nbsp;<em>Beyond Belief: the American Press</em>&nbsp;<em>and the Coming of the Holocaust 1933-1945</em>;&nbsp;<em>History on Trial: My Day in Court with a Holocaust Denier</em>;&nbsp;<em>The Eichmann Trial</em>;&nbsp;<em>Holocaust: An American Understanding&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Antisemitism: Here and Now</em>.&nbsp;After the British writer and Holocaust denier David Irving sued her for libel, a&nbsp;ten-week trial in London in 2000 resulted&nbsp;in an overwhelming victory for Lipstadt. Lipstadt&nbsp;is currently on the Boards of the Jewish Forward Advisory Committee&nbsp;and&nbsp;the American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee and serves as a judge for the Rohr Prize in Jewish Literature. She has also served in several roles at the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, including&nbsp;twice as a Presidential Appointee to the Museum’s Council, and was asked by President George W. Bush to represent the White House at the 60th anniversary of the liberation of Auschwitz.&nbsp;Lipstadt was previously a member of the U.S. Department of State’s Advisory Committee on Religious Persecution Abroad and&nbsp;was a Board Member of Hillel International, The Defiant Requiem, and The Covenant Foundation.&nbsp;She&nbsp;has received numerous awards for her research and writing and is the recipient of nine honorary degrees. Lipstadt&nbsp;received a B.A. from City College in New York and an M.A. and Ph.D. from Brandeis University. She is fluent in Hebrew.</p>



<p><strong><u>Khizr Khan, Appointee for Commissioner of the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</u></strong></p>



<p>Khizr Khan, founder of the Constitution Literacy and National Unity Project, is an advocate for religious freedom as a core element of human dignity. After immigrating to the United States in 1980, he attended Harvard Law School and obtained his LL.M degree. He is licensed to practice law before the Supreme Court of the United States, various Federal District Courts, and Washington, DC and New York State courts. In his law practice, he devotes a substantial amount of his time to providing legal services to veterans, men and women serving in uniform, and their families.</p>



<p>Khizr Khan is a Gold Star parent of U.S. Army Captain Humayun Khan. Capt. Humayun Khan was a University of Virginia graduate who was killed while serving in Iraq as he stopped an attack on his camp and saved the lives of scores of U.S. soldiers and Iraqi civilians. He was posthumously awarded the Purple Heart and Bronze Star with Valor. He was buried in Arlington National Cemetery Section 60 with full military honors.</p>



<p>Khizr Khan lives in Charlottesville, Virginia. He is author of three books, including<em> An American Family-A Memoir of Hope and Sacrifice</em>, <em>Founding Documents of the United States of America</em>, and <em>This is Our Constitution</em>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sharon Kleinbaum, Appointee for Commissioner of the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</u></strong></p>



<p>Rabbi Sharon Kleinbaum serves as spiritual leader of Congregation Beit Simchat Torah (CBST) in New York City. She was installed as CBST’s first rabbi in 1992, arriving at the height of the AIDS crisis when the synagogue was in desperate need of pastoral care and spiritual leadership. She guided the congregation through a period of loss and change, while addressing social issues and building a strong and deeply spiritual community. Under her leadership as Senior Rabbi, CBST has become a powerful voice in the movement for equality and justice for people of all sexual orientations, gender identities, and expressions. Rabbi Kleinbaum has long been involved in the fight for human rights, including religious freedom. She previously served on the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom in 2020. For many years Rabbi Kleinbaum has been ranked by <em>Newsweek</em> among the 50 most influential rabbis in America. Rabbi Kleinbaum is also a Commissioner on New York City&#8217;s Commission on Human Rights, serves on Mayor de Blasio&#8217;s Faith Based Advisory Council, and serves on the boards of the New York Jewish Agenda and the New Israel Fund.</p>



<p>Sharon Kleinbaum’s longtime leadership of Congregation Beth Simchat Torah and her outspoken activism have made her a powerful voice for religious freedom, LGBTQ rights and other human rights in America and around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Passing of Former United&#160;States Senator of Michigan Carl&#160;Levin</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-former-united-states-senator-of-michigan-carl-levin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For thirty years, Carl Levin and I served together in the United States Senate. He was one of the most honorable and decent people I have ever known. Brilliant, humble, and principled, Carl earned the trust of his constituents and colleagues by doing the work. He studied the issues in detail. He forged consensus across&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For thirty years, Carl Levin and I served together in the United States Senate. He was one of the most honorable and decent people I have ever known.<br><br>Brilliant, humble, and principled, Carl earned the trust of his constituents and colleagues by doing the work. He studied the issues in detail. He forged consensus across the aisle. He built coalitions across his beloved Michigan. With his head tilted down, his eyes peering over his glasses – Carl always looked people straight into their own eyes, listened with an open mind, and responded the way he saw it with respect.<br><br>Over the course of his thirty-six years in the Senate, the longest serving Senator in Michigan history, he showed how democracy – and our institutions – can deliver and work for the people.<br><br>As chairman and ranking member of the Armed Services Committee during my time leading the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, I saw how he built consensus to protect our national security, uphold our values, and honor the service of every patriot in uniform. He led on critical issues ranging from the nonproliferation of nuclear weapons, ending the use of torture, and recognizing the dignity of every American and allowing them to serve regardless of who they are and who they love.<br><br>A son of Detroit who never forgot where he came from, Carl always stood up for the American worker and the iconic American auto industry. In the midst of the Great Recession in 2009, with Detroit on its back and the industry on the brink, we worked together to do everything we could to get them back up. And they did because of Carl.<br><br>On education, gun safety, on holding corporate America accountable for abuse and greed, and so much more – Carl always looked out for the people.<br><br>Each time I traveled to Michigan with Carl over the years was special. We would talk about how we both got first involved in public life because of issues of civil rights and first got started in elected office – he on the Detroit City Council and I on the New Castle County Council. We would talk about the beauty of the Great Lakes and the Detroit RiverWalk. Most of all, we would talk about family.<br><br>Jill and I send our love to his beloved Barbara, their children, and grandchildren. Despite the full life he lived, we know the void his loss leaves. We know despite his courageous fight against cancer, it still leaves behind a heavy toll. We’re also thinking of our dear friends, his brother and former Congressman Sandy Levin, and his nephew Congressman Andy Levin, who share Carl’s commitment to service and country.<br><br>Carl Levin embodied the character of the people of Michigan he served throughout his remarkable career. Above all, he embodied the best of who we are as Americans.<br><br>May God bless a great American, a dear friend, and a good man.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to Japan to Attend the Closing Ceremony of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Olympic&#160;Games</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-japan-to-attend-the-closing-ceremony-of-the-tokyo-2020-summer-olympic-games/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 16:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to Japan to attend events of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Olympic Games and the Closing Ceremony on Sunday, August 8, 2021. The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation. Members of the Presidential Delegation: Mr.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to Japan to attend events of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Olympic Games and the Closing Ceremony on Sunday, August 8, 2021.</p>



<p>The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation.</p>



<p>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</p>



<p>Mr. Raymond Greene, Chargé d’Affaires ad interim, U.S. Embassy Tokyo</p>



<p>The Honorable Marcia Bernicat, Senior Official for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment and Acting Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, U.S. Department of State.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the Arrival of the First Flight of Operation Allies&#160;Refuge</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-arrival-of-the-first-flight-of-operation-allies-refuge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today is an important milestone as we continue to fulfill our promise to the thousands of Afghan nationals who served shoulder-to-shoulder with American troops and diplomats over the last 20 years in Afghanistan. This morning, the first flight of Operation Allies Refuge has arrived in the United States, carrying Afghans who are eligible for Special&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today is an important milestone as we continue to fulfill our promise to the thousands of Afghan nationals who served shoulder-to-shoulder with American troops and diplomats over the last 20 years in Afghanistan. This morning, the first flight of Operation Allies Refuge has arrived in the United States, carrying Afghans who are eligible for Special Immigrant Visas (SIV) and their families. These arrivals are just the first of many as we work quickly to relocate SIV-eligible Afghans out of harm’s way—to the United States, to U.S. facilities abroad, or to third countries—so that they can wait in safety while they finish their visa applications.<br><br>These first Afghans are able to come directly to the United States because they have already completed extensive background checks and security screening by the Intelligence Community and the Departments of State and Homeland Security. They will complete the final steps of their visa applications and required medical checks at Fort Lee, in Virginia, before traveling onward to begin their new lives in the United States.<br><br>I want to honor all those in the United States who have spoken out on behalf of these brave Afghans, including the proud community of veterans, who have consistently advocated for the Afghans who were by their side in the field in Afghanistan, often serving as translators and interpreters. And I want to thank the diplomats and public servants across our government and around the world who are working tirelessly as part of Operation Allies Refuge.<br><br>Although U.S. troops are leaving, we will continue to support Afghanistan through security assistance to Afghan forces, as well as humanitarian and development aid to the Afghan people to help them sustain their achievements of the past 20 years.&nbsp; We will also continue our diplomatic support for the peace process.&nbsp; We call for an immediate reduction in violence in Afghanistan, and for all regional actors to encourage the parties to return to negotiations without delay so that the Afghan people can achieve a durable and just political settlement that brings the peace and security they deserve.<br><br>Most of all, I want to thank these brave Afghans for standing with the United States, and today, I am proud to say to them: “Welcome home.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-the-Record Press Call by Senior Deputy Advisor Russ Travers and Ambassador Tracey Jacobson on Operation Allies&#160;Refuge</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/30/on-the-record-press-call-by-senior-deputy-advisor-russ-travers-and-ambassador-tracey-jacobson-on-operation-allies-refuge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25481</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  (July 29, 2021) 10:01 A.M. EDT&#160;MS. HORNE: Good morning, everyone.&#160; Thanks for joining us today.&#160; Today’s call will be on the record, and its contents will be embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time tomorrow &#8212; that’s Friday, July 30th.&#160;Our speakers today are going to be Senior Deputy Homeland Security Advisor Russ Travers from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"> (July 29, 2021)</p>



<p>10:01 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. HORNE: Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us today.&nbsp; Today’s call will be on the record, and its contents will be embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time tomorrow &#8212; that’s Friday, July 30th.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our speakers today are going to be Senior Deputy Homeland Security Advisor Russ Travers from the National Security Council and Ambassador Tracey Jacobson from the State Department Afghanistan Coordination Task Force.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Russ, we’ll turn it over to you to get started.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, Emily.&nbsp; And thanks all for joining.&nbsp; As Emily said, my name is Russ Travers.&nbsp; I&#8217;m the Senior Deputy Homeland Security Advisor at the NSC.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think you know, on the 14th of July, the White House announced Operation Allies Refuge that would support relocations of interested and eligible Afghan nationals and their families who have supported the government and are in the SIV application pipeline.&nbsp; This is not a new program.&nbsp; Helping the brave Afghans who have supported our work in Afghanistan has been a long bipartisan priority in Washington.<br>&nbsp;<br>The original NDAA authorization for Special Immigrant Visas from Iraq and Afghanistan &#8212; it was actually passed under the second Bush administration; it was re-upped in both the Obama and the Trump administrations; and we welcome strong bipartisan support for SIVs in Congress today, including the recent passage in the House of legislation in support of streamlining the application process and increasing the overall numbers of visas authorized.<br>&nbsp;<br>Since President Biden&#8217;s announcement this April that U.S. forces would be leaving Afghanistan, the administration&#8217;s immediate focus has been on interested and eligible Afghan nationals and their families who have supported the U.S. and our partners in Afghanistan and are in the SIV application pipeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>I am immensely proud to announce our first group of Afghan special immigrants to be relocated under Operation Allies Refuge is now on their way to America.&nbsp; This flight represents a fulfillment of the U.S. commitment and honors these Afghans’ brave service in helping support our mission in Afghanistan, in turn helping to keep our country safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>America has a longstanding tradition of welcoming refugees and others to the United States.&nbsp; We, alongside our civil society partners and tens of thousands of volunteers across our nation, look forward to welcoming these friends and partners to their new communities in the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They have all completed rigorous security background checks conducted by the intelligence community and the Departments of State and Homeland Security.&nbsp; And they now join the over 70,000 Afghans who have received SIVs and started new lives in the U.S. since 2008.<br>&nbsp;<br>Their arrival is the culmination of an enormous effort across the U.S. government and one that is a high moment of our careers.&nbsp; So many of us have deep, personal connections here, whether we served at Embassy Kabul, worked alongside these Afghans as diplomats or servicemembers, or worked to advance the Afghan peace process.<br>&nbsp;<br>It is important to emphasize that our first priority is relocating to the United States about 700 Afghan principal SIV applicants and their immediate families who have completed the majority of the process including a thorough background check.<br>&nbsp;<br>Including family members, we estimate there will be approximately 2,500 Afghans in this group, and we have something over 200 people on this first flight, principal applicants and their families.<br>Once these Afghan special immigrants are paroled into the U.S. and complete a medical exam as required by law, they will be resettled to cities across the country with assistance through the United States Refugee Admissions Program.&nbsp; We expect to continue relocating applicants and their families over the course of a few weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>In closing, I want to emphasize that the safety and privacy of these brave individuals and their families has been the North Star during this entire process.&nbsp; Accordingly, we are not going to speak to any details about the routes or timing of their transit.&nbsp; You can appreciate that they are in the midst of a long, very grueling journey, and our focus right now is on welcoming them safely and protecting details that may impact the travel of future SIV arrivals.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, with that, I&#8217;ll turn thing over to Ambassador Jacobson for more detail on the State-Department-headed interagency task force.<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; Good morning everyone.&nbsp; On behalf of all the members of the task force, I want to say how honored and privileged we are to be working as part of the overall interagency effort on this important process.<br>&nbsp;<br>We launched this task force last Monday to bring together the expertise and the individuals from across the interagency to meet the President&#8217;s initial instruction to start relocating Afghans &#8212; Special Immigrant Visa applicants &#8212; before the end of July, but also to work together to find efficiencies to innovate, to streamline the process going forward to maximize the number of people that we will be able to relocate.<br>&nbsp;<br>And on our team, it&#8217;s not just the State Department.&nbsp; We also have Department of Homeland Security, Health and Human Services, and, of course, the Department of Defense.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think Russ has said most of what we have on the process, but just so you know, this initial group that we&#8217;re talking about of 700-plus principal applicants and their families that we&#8217;re bringing through, through this process, have undergone extensive screening.&nbsp; They are at the very end of the immigrant visa process, lacking only a couple of steps that we will be performing at Fort Lee.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They have all been COVID tested.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve had a fitness-to-fly exam.&nbsp; And we have offered vaccines in Kabul to those who are interested in having them, and we will also be offering those vaccines at Fort Lee.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, at Fort Lee, they will need a medical clearance, as required by DHS, to grant them immigrant status.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what will be happening at Fort Lee &#8212; is that medical and the DHS processing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then we&#8217;re working with our partner, IOM, which will relocate people around the country.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be taking information from them &#8212; the travelers.&nbsp; When they have particular connections in the United States &#8212; family or other connections &#8212; IOM will look to resettle them in those locations.&nbsp; And otherwise, they will go where IOM has capacity, with assistance through the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program under the State Department Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to continue to work on this.&nbsp; We will continue to relocate eligible SIV applicants and their families who have our gratitude for their service.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I also want to underscore that the U.S. partnership with Afghanistan is continuing.&nbsp; As Secretary Blinken said, &#8220;even as we&#8217;re withdrawing our forces, we&#8217;re remaining very much engaged in Afghanistan: supporting the government, economic assistance, development assistance, assistance for the security forces, and diplomacy to try to bring the parties together for a peaceful resolution of the conflict.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our Consular Section in Kabul is going to continue processing SIVs.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re very much looking forward to our Afghan colleagues taking their first steps as new immigrants in our country and very pleased to join today on this call.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. HORNE: Thank you.&nbsp; Operator, we&#8217;re ready for some questions now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much. &nbsp;&nbsp;A question about the other Afghans &#8212; womens leaders, human rights leaders, educators.&nbsp; Is there any plan being considered to evacuate other people who are being targeted and can be targeted by the Taliban if they want to leave beyond the SIV program?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; Well, as you suggest, Andrea, the SIV program is statutory.&nbsp; It has very specific requirements and would not cover many of these individuals.&nbsp; However, U.S. Embassy Kabul can make referrals to the U.S. Refugee Admission Program for any Afghans who are well known to the embassy and have both imminent and compelling protection concerns.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this would, by definition, include women&#8217;s leaders, activists, human rights defenders, civil society, and journalists.&nbsp; So, there is that program available.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, I&#8217;d like to follow up on Andrea&#8217;s question.&nbsp; The administration has been considering doing or creating an equivalent of what &#8212; of the programs for Iraqis that has been suspended.&nbsp; It was for, I guess &#8212; I can&#8217;t remember the exact term, but it&#8217;s a special visa; it’s not an SIV.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Iraqi program was suspended because of a fraud investigation that is still going on.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if the administration is still considering creating the second category of visas for Afghans who do not meet the SIV requirements, but are U.S affiliated and under threat or other Afghans who are also under threat from the Taliban, particularly women, women pilots &#8212; that kind of person.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; Do you want to answer, Tracey?&nbsp; Want me to?<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; Sure, just to say that it&#8217;s true the administration is considering a variety of different options, and we&#8217;ll have more on that for you in the future.&nbsp; Nothing on that today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;Hi. &nbsp;Thanks very much for doing the call. &nbsp;(Inaudible) kind of a logistical question. &nbsp;How long will (inaudible) the refugee program? &nbsp;I mean, obviously, we would very much like to speak with them and do stories, which I gather isn&#8217;t going to happen at Fort Lee. &nbsp;But I&#8217;d like any information you can provide about access &#8212; media access (inaudible) these folks in the coming weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; So, excuse me, you cut out during that call a little bit, but I think what you were asking is how long do we expect them to be at Fort Lee and can you speak to the applicants afterwards.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s the question I&#8217;m going to answer, and if it was a different question, I apologize.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; No, no, that’s it.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, this is the first time we&#8217;re doing this, and it&#8217;s a sort of big lift for State PRM, for DHS, and for the NGO colleagues that are working with us to process these medical exams and the DHS adjustment of status.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking at about seven days.&nbsp; We hope, over time, to shorten that.&nbsp; But that is our planning horizon for this first flight, and we&#8217;ll see how it goes, and we will learn from the experience of this first flight and apply it to future flights.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of engaging with these individuals, you know, they&#8217;re entitled to their privacy.&nbsp; If any of them express an interest in speaking to the media &#8212; and some of them may &#8212; we will work to hook you up.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re not going to ask them to speak to the media given that these folks have, in recent days, left their entire lives behind and immigrated to the United States with just their luggage.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re going to let them settle in and resettle.&nbsp; But if any of them are keen to talk to you, we&#8217;ll let you know.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, there.&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for holding the call.&nbsp; A couple of questions about the folks who are still left behind in Afghanistan.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken with people in the process who say that they have a dangerous road between where they live and getting to Kabul.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t know, if they go to Kabul, how many &#8212; how long they&#8217;ll have to wait, if they&#8217;ll have to go back to their dangerous home province.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Is there any support being offered for them once they get to Kabul so they can stay there?&nbsp; And are you still considering an option of just expediting all of these applicants out to Guam or another safe area where the processing can continue and they won’t be in danger from the Taliban advances?<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; I’ll take that one, Russ, if you like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; Sure, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; We&#8217;re going be moving folks as fast as we logistically can.&nbsp; We do lack the capacity to bring people to Kabul from other parts of the country or to house them in Kabul itself.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>While we&#8217;re focused on this initial group of applicants who are very far along in their SIV process, bringing them to the United States, we are also looking, in the coming weeks, to start moving people who are less farther along to a third-country location so that they can be safe while their visa processing continues.&nbsp; And those individuals, when they finish that processing, will be brought to the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what I have for you now on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for holding this call and for taking my question.&nbsp; What advice do you have for SIVs in Afghanistan who haven’t heard anything yet?&nbsp; Is there someone they can contact?&nbsp; Should they be reaching out to the embassy?<br>&nbsp;<br>And I have two follow-ups.&nbsp; One is: Did you say there are 750 or 250 on the flight?&nbsp; And then how long after the pullout of troops will you continue with this program?<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; So, I do apologize &#8212; there were three questions there.&nbsp; As to the exact number on the flight, it is just over 200.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not 250.&nbsp; We don’t want to get into exact details, but, you know, we initially manifest the flight, and then, of course, some people who test positive for COVID are not allowed to fly, and they will have to quarantine and isolate in accordance with CDC guidelines before we will put them on another flight.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We absolutely intend to continue this program after the pullout of troops.&nbsp; In terms of who people can contact, it&#8217;s the same organization that they contact with regards to their SIV.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; the National Visa Center is the organization that fields inquiries from applicants.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; And I would just add that the 700-plus is the cohort that we&#8217;re talking about of SIVs who are at this relevant stage &#8212; have had all their security vetting &#8212; so it&#8217;s they and their families that will be looking to relocate over the coming days and weeks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. HORNE:&nbsp; All right, thank you, everyone.&nbsp; That concludes our call.&nbsp; Reminder that the contents are embargoed until 5:00 a.m., tomorrow, Friday morning.&nbsp; And we are on the record today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks all.<br>&nbsp;<br>10:17 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meeting with Legislators on&#160;DACA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-legislators-on-daca/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 02:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today President Biden and Vice President Harris met with a group of Senators and House members who have been longtime leaders on immigration reform and integral partners in this work. &#160;They discussed their shared support for Dreamers and the actions this Administration is taking to protect them, their livelihood, and their ability to stay in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today President Biden and Vice President Harris met with a group of Senators and House members who have been longtime leaders on immigration reform and integral partners in this work. &nbsp;They discussed their shared support for Dreamers and the actions this Administration is taking to protect them, their livelihood, and their ability to stay in the United States. &nbsp;Dreamers are as American as the rest of us, and they make our country a better place with their talents and contributions.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden and Vice President Harris expressed their strong support for including immigration reform in upcoming reconciliation legislation to enable Dreamers, TPS recipients, farmworkers and essential workers to gain long-awaited pathways to citizenship.&nbsp; President Biden and Vice President Harris thanked the lawmakers for their tireless leadership on immigration reform and reiterated their dedication to establishing an immigration system that is orderly, fair, humane, and reflects American values.<br><br>Senators and House Members expressed their gratitude for the Administration’s enduring commitment and support for providing pathways to citizenship through reconciliation.<br><br>Lawmakers who participated in the meeting were:</p>



<ul><li>Senator Dick Durbin (D-IL)</li><li>Senator Catherine Cortez Masto (D-NV)</li><li>Senator Bob Menendez (D-NJ)</li><li>Senator Alex Padilla (D-CA)</li><li>Senator Ben Ray Lujan (D-NM)</li><li>Congressman Jerry Nadler (D-NY-10)</li><li>Congressman Pete Aguilar (D-CA-31)</li><li>Congresswoman Zoe Lofgren (D-CA-19)</li><li>Congresswoman Lucille Roybal Allard (D-CA-40)</li><li>Congressman Raul Ruiz (D-CA-36)</li><li>Congresswoman Linda Sanchez (D-CA-38)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/29/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I&#8217;m going to be late to a very important date.&#160; If I miss this &#8212; getting out to see my wife &#8212; I&#8217;m in trouble.&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; President Biden, how did your meeting on DACA go?&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It went very well.&#160; What I think we sh- &#8212; I think we should include in the reconciliation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to be late to a very important date.&nbsp; If I miss this &#8212; getting out to see my wife &#8212; I&#8217;m in trouble.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, how did your meeting on DACA go?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It went very well.&nbsp; What I think we sh- &#8212; I think we should include in the reconciliation bill the immigration proposal.&nbsp; My staff is putting out a message right now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you think the country will have another wave &#8212; another peak of cases?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Say again?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the United States will have another wave of cases, another peak of coronavirus cases?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I hope not.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, did you talk to Kyrsten Sinema about the reconciliation package when you spoke to her on infrastructure the other day?&nbsp; She says she&#8217;s not on board with the $3.5 trillion (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; She&#8217;s on board for passing if in fact she sees all the pieces of it.&nbsp; That’s why she allowed the budget to go forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
