<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:34:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 552(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/16/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-552c2-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 552(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United&#160;States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 552(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section 552(c)(2) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $10&nbsp;million in commodities and services from the inventory and resources of any agency of the United States Government to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet:  Reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act&#160;(VAWA)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/fact-sheet-reauthorization-of-the-violence-against-women-act-vawa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, President Biden signed into law the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022, bipartisan legislation passed by Congress as part of the Omnibus appropriations package. One of the driving forces of President Biden’s career has been fighting back against abuses of power.&#160; That force led him to write and champion the groundbreaking&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, President Biden signed into law the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022, bipartisan legislation passed by Congress as part of the Omnibus appropriations package.</p>



<p>One of the driving forces of President Biden’s career has been fighting back against abuses of power.&nbsp; That force led him to write and champion the groundbreaking Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) as a U.S. Senator, landmark legislation that first passed in 1994.&nbsp; In the nearly three decades since, he has worked with Members of Congress from both parties to pass legislation to renew and strengthen VAWA three times: in 2000, 2005, and 2013. &nbsp;Each time, he worked to expand access to safety and support for all survivors and increase prevention efforts.&nbsp; Preventing and responding to gender-based violence wherever it occurs, and in all of its forms, has remained a cornerstone of the President’s career in public service—from VAWA reauthorization to a national campaign to combat campus sexual assault to reforms to address sexual assault and harassment in the military. &nbsp;</p>



<p>While incidents of domestic violence and sexual assault have declined significantly since VAWA first took effect—and efforts to increase access to services, healing, and justice for survivors have improved with each iteration of VAWA—much work remains.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The 2022 reauthorization of VAWA strengthens this landmark law, including by:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Reauthorizing all current VAWA grant programs until 2027 and, in many cases, increasing authorization levels.&nbsp;</li><li>Expanding special criminal jurisdiction of Tribal courts to cover non-Native perpetrators of sexual assault, child abuse, stalking, sex trafficking, and assaults on tribal law enforcement officers on tribal lands; and supporting the development of a pilot project to enhance access to safety for survivors in Alaska Native villages.</li><li>Increasing services and support for survivors from underserved and marginalized communities—including for LGBTQ+ survivors of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault and stalking; funding survivor-centered, community-based restorative practice services; and increasing support for culturally specific services and services in rural communities.</li><li>Establishing a federal civil cause of action for individuals whose intimate visual images are disclosed without their consent, allowing a victim to recover damages and legal fees; creating a new National Resource Center on Cybercrimes Against Individuals; and supporting State, Tribal, and local government efforts to prevent and prosecute cybercrimes, including cyberstalking and the nonconsensual distribution of intimate images.</li><li>Improving prevention and response to sexual violence, including through increased support for the Rape Prevention and Education Program and Sexual Assault Services Program; expansion of prevention education for students in institutions of higher education; and enactment of the Fairness for Rape Kit Backlog Survivors Act, which requires state victim compensation programs to allow sexual assault survivors to file for compensation without being unfairly penalized due to rape kit backlogs.</li><li>Strengthening the application of evidence-based practices by law enforcement in responding to gender-based violence, including by promoting the use of trauma-informed, victim-centered training and improving homicide reduction initiatives.</li><li>Improving the healthcare system’s response to domestic violence and sexual assault, including through enhanced training for sexual assault forensic examiners.</li><li>Updating the SMART Prevention Program and the CHOOSE Youth Program to reduce dating violence, help children who have been exposed to domestic violence, and engage men in preventing violence.</li><li>Enacting the National Instant Criminal Background Check System (NICS) Denial Notification Act to help state law enforcement investigate and prosecute cases against individuals legally prohibited from purchasing firearms who try to do so.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Over the past year, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken significant steps to prevent and respond to gender-based violence at home and abroad:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Increased funding for domestic violence and sexual assault services.&nbsp; </strong>Directed&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/10/25/hhs-announces-nearly-800-million-american-rescue-plan-funds-support-domestic-violence-sexual-assault-survivors-their-children.html" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$1 billion in supplemental funding</a>&nbsp;for&nbsp;domestic violence and sexual assault services&nbsp;through the American Rescue Plan (ARP) in response to the pandemic, including&nbsp;<a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/fysb/grant-funding/2021-fvpsa-american-rescue-plan-culturally-specific-program-instruction-guidance" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$49.5 million for culturally-specific community-based organizations</a>&nbsp;that help survivors from historically marginalized communities access the services and support they need. The ARP also provided approximately 70,000 housing choice vouchers to local Public Housing Authorities in order to assist individuals and families, including those who are fleeing, or attempting to flee, from domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, or human trafficking.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Reformed the military justice system to address sexual assault, harassment, and related crimes. </strong>Signed into law&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/27/statement-by-the-president-on-s-1605-the-national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2022/">National Defense Authorization Act</a>, which included&nbsp;sweeping reforms to the military justice system—the most significant since the Uniform Code of Military Justice was established more than seventy years ago—and implemented the President’s campaign promise to address the scourge of sexual assault in our armed forces.&nbsp;In conjunction with the President’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/01/26/executive-order-on-2022-amendments-to-the-manual-for-courts-martial-united-states/">Executive Order</a>&nbsp;on military justice reform, this bipartisan, historic law adopts core recommendations of&nbsp;the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-results-of-the-independent-review-commission-on-military-sexual-assault/">Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault</a>, as called for by President Biden, and fundamentally shifts how the military prosecutes and investigates sexual assault, domestic violence, sexual harassment, and other serious crimes, and increases prevention initiatives and support for survivors.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Ended forced arbitration for sexual assault and harassment.&nbsp; </strong>Signed into law the&nbsp;Ending Forced Arbitration of Sexual Assault and Sexual Harassment Act&nbsp;of 2021—bipartisan legislation that empowers survivors of sexual assault and harassment by giving them a choice to go to court instead of being forced into arbitration.</li><li><strong>Directed action to protect students from campus sexual assault.&nbsp; </strong>Directed the Department of Education to&nbsp;review Title IX regulations&nbsp;and other agency actions to ensure that all students have an educational environment that is free from discrimination on the basis of sex. &nbsp;The Department is developing a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking currently under review that will address the need for protection for students who experience campus sexual assault while treating all students fairly.</li><li><strong>Increased resources for survivors of crime, including gender-based violence.&nbsp; </strong>Signed into law the&nbsp;Amendments to the Victims of Crime Act&nbsp;(VOCA), which passed Congress with strong bipartisan support and expands the allocation of resources for the Crime Victims Fund. This has already resulted in an increase of hundreds of millions of dollars of non-taxpayer funding for essential and lifesaving services to crime victims around the country, including survivors of gender-based violence.</li><li><strong>Led multinational effort to address online harassment and abuse.&nbsp; </strong>Launched the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse during the 2022 meeting of the United Nations Commission on the Status of Women, together with the governments of Denmark, Australia, the United Kingdom, and Sweden. This multinational initiative will align countries, international organizations, and civil society to better prioritize, understand, and address the growing scourge of technology-facilitated gender-based violence.</li><li><strong>Prioritized the crisis of Missing or Murdered Indigenous People, including gender-based violence.</strong> &nbsp;Issued an executive order directing the Departments of Justice, Interior, Homeland Security and Health and Human Services to create a strategy to improve public safety and justice for Native Americans and to address the epidemic of missing or murdered Indigenous peoples, which disproportionately affect Native women, girls, and LGBTQI+ individuals; the Department of the Interior established the Missing and Murdered Unit to pursue justice for missing or murdered American Indians and Alaska Natives.</li><li><strong>Strengthened regional leadership on violence against Indigenous women and girls.&nbsp; </strong>Re-launched the United States’ leadership and participation in the&nbsp;Trilateral Working Group on Violence Against Indigenous Women and Girls&nbsp;with the Governments of Mexico and Canada. The White House will host the Fourth Convening of the Trilateral Working Group this summer to improve and reaffirm our respective national and regional commitments to prevent and respond to violence against Indigenous women and girls through increased access to justice and prevention services.</li></ul>



<p>On International Women’s Day in 2021, President Biden signed an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-establishment-of-the-white-house-gender-policy-council/">Executive Order</a> creating the White House Gender Policy Council and calling for the development of the first-ever government-wide National Action Plan to End Gender-Based Violence, as well as an update to the 2016 United States Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence Globally. These strategies will provide a roadmap to guide the Biden-Harris Administration’s whole-of-government effort to end gender-based violence—and in so doing, create a society where survivors are supported and all people can live free from abuse.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/16/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United&#160;States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&nbsp;1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $800 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet on U.S. Security Assistance for&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/fact-sheet-on-u-s-security-assistance-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 17:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49259</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden today announced an additional $800 million in security assistance to Ukraine, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in just the past week, and a total of $2 billion since the start of the Biden Administration. The assistance will take the form of direct transfers of equipment from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden today announced an additional $800 million in security assistance to Ukraine, bringing the total U.S. security assistance committed to Ukraine to $1 billion in just the past week, and a total of $2 billion since the start of the Biden Administration. The assistance will take the form of direct transfers of equipment from the Department of Defense to the Ukrainian military to help them defend their country against Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.<br><br>The new $800 million assistance package includes:</p>



<ul><li>800 Stinger anti-aircraft systems;</li><li>2,000 Javelin, 1,000 light anti-armor weapons, and 6,000 AT-4 anti-armor systems;</li><li>100 Tactical Unmanned Aerial Systems;</li><li>100 grenade launchers, 5,000 rifles, 1,000 pistols, 400 machine guns, and 400 shotguns;</li><li>Over 20 million rounds of small arms ammunition and grenade launcher and mortar rounds;</li><li>25,000 sets of body armor; and</li><li>25,000 helmets.</li></ul>



<p>In addition to the weapons listed above, previous United States assistance committed to Ukraine includes:</p>



<ul><li>Over 600 Stinger anti-aircraft systems;</li><li>Approximately 2,600 Javelin anti-armor systems;</li><li>Five Mi-17 helicopters;</li><li>Three patrol boats;</li><li>Four counter-artillery and counter-unmanned aerial system tracking radars;</li><li>Four counter-mortar radar systems;</li><li>200 grenade launchers and ammunition;</li><li>200 shotguns and 200 machine guns;</li><li>Nearly 40 million rounds of small arms ammunition and over 1 million grenade, mortar, and artillery rounds;</li><li>70 High Mobility Multipurpose Wheeled Vehicles (HMMWVs) and other vehicles;</li><li>Secure communications, electronic warfare detection systems, body armor, helmets, and other tactical gear;</li><li>Military medical equipment to support treatment and combat evacuation;</li><li>Explosive ordnance disposal and demining equipment; and</li><li>Satellite imagery and analysis capability.</li></ul>



<p>In addition to the U.S.-produced short-range air defense systems the Ukrainians have been using to great effect, the United States has also identified and is helping the Ukrainians acquire additional, longer-range systems on which Ukraine’s forces are already trained, as well as additional munitions for those systems.</p>



<p>The United States continues to expedite the authorization and facilitation of additional assistance to Ukraine from our Allies. At least 30 countries have provided security assistance to Ukraine since the Russian invasion began. In 2022, the Department of State authorized third-party transfers of defensive equipment from more than 14 countries, a number that continues to grow as Allies and Partners increase support to Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Nikolay Patrushev, Secretary of the Russian Security&#160;Council</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-nikolay-patrushev-secretary-of-the-russian-security-council-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 14:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with General Nikolay Patrushev, Secretary of the Russian Security Council, to reiterate the United States’ firm and clear opposition to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. Mr. Sullivan clearly laid out the United States’ commitment to continue imposing costs on Russia, to support the defense of Ukraine’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with General Nikolay Patrushev, Secretary of the Russian Security Council, to reiterate the United States’ firm and clear opposition to Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. Mr. Sullivan clearly laid out the United States’ commitment to continue imposing costs on Russia, to support the defense of Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and to reinforce NATO’s eastern flank, in continued full coordination with our Allies and partners.&nbsp;Mr. Sullivan told General Patrushev that if Russia is serious about diplomacy then Moscow should stop attacking Ukrainian cities and towns. Mr. Sullivan also warned General Patrushev about the consequences and implications of any possible Russian decision to use chemical or biological weapons in Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces Resources for Historically Black Colleges and Universities that Have Recently Experienced Bomb&#160;Threats</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-resources-for-historically-black-colleges-and-universities-that-have-recently-experienced-bomb-threats/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 12:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris To Make Announcement During White House Event March 16th, 2022 In the last three months, more than one-third of our country’s Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) have received bomb threats. While, thankfully, no explosive devices were found on any of these campuses, significant and lasting damage has been done by threatening the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris To Make Announcement During White House Event</em> <em>March 16<sup>th</sup>, 2022</em></p>



<p>In the last three months, more than one-third of our country’s Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) have received bomb threats. While, thankfully, no explosive devices were found on any of these campuses, significant and lasting damage has been done by threatening the safety and security of the students, faculty, and staff at these institutions. As a result of these threats, learning has been disrupted, critical resources have been diverted to emergency response, and there has been an increased burden on already overwhelmed campus mental health systems. HBCU students – already experiencing negative impacts from the pandemic such as lingering effects of illness, trauma, and basic needs insecurities – are now experiencing additional stress and anxiety because of these bomb threats that can negatively affect their academic success.</p>



<p>It is important to view these recent and repeated threats through both the lens of the present day as well as our country’s history. HBCUs were founded to educate Black people in an America that refused to accept them as full human beings and prevented them – because of racial discrimination – from attending other colleges. Threats to the education and well-being of Black Americans and HBCUs are an unfortunate part of American history. The bomb threats that we witnessed in January, each week in February – Black History Month, and this month are reminiscent of the attempts during the Civil Rights Era to intimidate and provoke fear in Black Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is taking a whole-of-government approach in responding to these threats and ensuring the safety and well-being of students, staff, and faculty. Immediately following the first reports of the threats, Education Secretary Cardona and Homeland Security Secretary Mayorkas hosted a briefing with more than 40 presidents of HBCUs from across the nation to share information on grant programs, training resources, and other tools available to HBCUs to strengthen campus safety and security. Leaders from the Department of Education (ED) and other federal agencies have visited HBCU campuses. During these visits, federal officials heard firsthand about the need to modernize and update their operations, including campus safety and security, as well as the need for more resources to help bolster mental health services due to increased apprehension across the campus community.</p>



<p>Today, in response to these needs, Vice President Kamala Harris is announcing that HBCUs that have recently experienced a bomb threat resulting in a disruption to the campus learning environment are eligible for grant funds. These grant funds are from the Project School Emergency Response to Violence (Project SERV) program at ED. Project SERV provides short-term, immediate funding for local educational agencies and institutions of higher education that have experienced a violent or traumatic incident to assist in restoring a safe environment conducive to learning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ED will work with the HBCUs that have received recent bomb threats to determine if Project SERV can help get funds to their campuses for immediate needs, such as targeted mental health resources or enhanced security, to restore the learning environment on their campuses. ED is able to provide this funding to HBCUs to ensure students feel safe on their campuses. ED staff will work with each HBCU to help determine their specific immediate needs. Awards typically range from $50,000 to $150,000 per school.</p>



<p>In addition to the short-term funds provided through Project SERV, the Biden-Harris Administration is providing HBCUs a compendium of resources that are available across the federal government – from ED, Department of Health and Human Services, Department of Homeland Security, and Department of Justice – to help with long-term improvements to campus mental health programs, campus safety, and emergency management planning and response. The resource guide offers a centralized source of information on grant programs and technical assistance activities across federal agencies.</p>



<p>These announcements today build off the historic investments and support the Biden-Harris Administration has already delivered to HBCUs – $5.8 billion in total to date, including more than $2.7 billion in American Rescue Plan funding – to ameliorate chronic underfunding and help address critical needs brought on by the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Educational opportunity is a fundamental element of the American promise and HBCUs have played an outsized role in securing that opportunity for Black people. As President Biden indicated in Executive Order 14041 – which re-established the White House Initiative on HBCUs – HBCUs have a proud history and legacy of achievement. That legacy continues, with more than 100 HBCUs, located in 19 states, the District of Columbia, and the U.S. Virgin Islands that serve nearly 300,000 students annually. These storied institutions have excelled, in the face of discrimination, and their strength and convictions will not be compromised by these violent bomb threats.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden Jr. Honoring the Victims of the Fatal Shootings in&#160;Atlanta</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/16/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-honoring-the-victims-of-the-fatal-shootings-in-atlanta/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago today, eight people, six of them women of Asian descent, were tragically killed by a gunman who attacked three Asian-run businesses. These horrific murders shook communities across America and underscored how far we have to go in this country to fight racism, misogyny, and all forms of hate—and the epidemic of gun&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago today, eight people, six of them women of Asian descent, were tragically killed by a gunman who attacked three Asian-run businesses. These horrific murders shook communities across America and underscored how far we have to go in this country to fight racism, misogyny, and all forms of hate—and the epidemic of gun violence that enables these extremists.<br><br>In the aftermath of these senseless deaths, the Vice President and I traveled to Atlanta to meet with leaders of the Asian American community. We heard about the terror and anguish that too many Asian Americans have felt since the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic, when anti-Asian xenophobia, harassment, and violence skyrocketed to alarming levels. Grandparents afraid to leave their homes. Small business owners targeted and gunned down. Families living in fear for their lives just walking down the street in America. It was a stark reminder that anti-Asian violence and discrimination have deep roots in our nation, with Asian American women experiencing the compounded harms of being targeted on account of their race as well as their gender.<br><br>Today, we honor the victims, their families, and the Atlanta community that has shown extraordinary resilience in the face of tragedy. While nothing we do can bring the victims back, their loss has compelled us to reckon with our nation’s long legacy of anti-Asian sentiment and gender-based violence, and recommit ourselves to delivering the full measure of justice, safety, and dignity the Asian American and Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander community and all communities deserve. I was proud to sign the bipartisan COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act into law last May, which dedicated new tools and resources across government and law enforcement to help prevent, track, and respond to acts of hate, along with new Department of Justice grants and other measures to enhance community engagement, empowerment, and education.<br><br>This tragedy is also yet another reminder of the gun violence epidemic. My Administration has taken more executive action to reduce gun violence than any other Administration it its first year. But there is more to do—and Congress must act.<br><br>On this somber anniversary, my Administration remains fully committed to advancing safety, inclusion, and belonging for all Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders—especially the women and girls who disproportionately bear the burdens of hate—and to reducing the gun violence that terrorizes our communities. Together, we must build a future where no one fears violence.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris During a Conversation with Current and Former Members of the U.S. Women&#8217;s National Soccer&#160;Team</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/16/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-during-a-conversation-with-current-and-former-members-of-the-u-s-womens-national-soccer-team/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 07:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium Eisenhower Executive Office Building 3:34 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Welcome, everyone, to the White House.  Welcome.  Welcome.  As has been introduced, we are gathered together with really wonderful leaders.  Obviously, you all have been champions, in terms of your skill and your dominance in terms of women&#8217;s soccer, but we are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>3:34 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Welcome, everyone, to the White House.  Welcome.  Welcome.  As has been introduced, we are gathered together with really wonderful leaders.  Obviously, you all have been champions, in terms of your skill and your dominance in terms of women&#8217;s soccer, but we are here today because you also have been leaders on an issue that affects most women and has affected most women in the workforce, and it&#8217;s the issue of pay equity.</p>



<p>So, thank you for joining us at the White House for this important discussion, which really is going to center on your leadership &#8212; what you all have done; what you have accomplished; the challenges that you&#8217;ve faced, both personally and professionally, in terms of getting us to this point where we have now seen extraordinary success because of your commitment to the issue and your willingness to be a voice for so many others on and off the field.</p>



<p>So, with that, I want to thank you all.  And of course, we should mention that you have won four World Cup Games and four Olympic golds.  (Applause.)  So &#8212; absolutely. </p>



<p>So, Kelley, let&#8217;s talk &#8212; I want to start with you, because it&#8217;s about being a player rep in the Players Association Union.  And we still see that there are issues throughout the workforce around women being underpaid. </p>



<p>But can you talk a bit about the fight that you all had and the role of the Players Association in reaching the settlement?</p>



<p>MS. O&#8217;HARA:  For sure.  You know, I think a lot of people hear our fight for equal pay and they think compensation, which is definitely what it&#8217;s about.  But there are a lot of other things that we were fighting for. </p>



<p>There was a lot of unequal treatment.  And that came in the form of playing surfaces, travel standards, promotion and investment in the game. </p>



<p>And Julie &#8212; we were actually talking before we got up here &#8212; how far we&#8217;ve come even from when they were playing.  And I don&#8217;t know if you want to mention &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. FOUDY:  A long time ago.</p>



<p>MS. O&#8217;HARA:  &#8212; some things.  Yeah, but &#8212; but all that is to say &#8212; and to answer your question about the Players Association, we were facing all these things.  And I think that the Players Association &#8212; it&#8217;s been around for generations, but we really reinvigorated it in 2017.  And I think that dedicating time to setting it up in a way that we were able to achieve certain things allowed us to realize our collective voice and, like, the power of our unity. </p>



<p>And I think without the Players Association, we wouldn&#8217;t have been able to achieve what we&#8217;ve done in the past couple years. </p>



<p>And although we filed as individuals, not on behalf or with the Players Association, we were able to see it through because of that. </p>



<p>And I&#8217;m really thankful that it did start so long ago and these generations have put in the work.  But, you know, we took the steps to create it the way we needed it, and it allowed us to get it over the line. </p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  And the Players Association, it&#8217;s a union.</p>



<p>MS. O&#8217;HARA:  Yes.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  It&#8217;s a players&#8217; union.  And so, that meant that you wouldn&#8217;t have to &#8212; even though you filed as individuals, in terms of the lawsuit, that, in terms of your advocacy and the fight for equal pay, you knew that you weren&#8217;t alone.  You all were in it together. </p>



<p>MS. O&#8217;HARA:  For sure.  I think that feeling that unity and recognizing how powerful we were, I think, was a big reason why we were able to keep fighting, because it was not easy. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And so, can you describe what the fight was?&nbsp; And maybe even just talk about what it was before, right?&nbsp; The strengthening of the Players Association and the kind of collective advocacy &#8212; what was it like before then?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. FOUDY:&nbsp; Well, way back, Kelley and I were discussing &#8212; you know, we were fighting for bagels, you know, after training and having, you know &#8212; &#8220;Everyone put in five bucks, so you can…&#8221;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. CONE:&nbsp; In between two training sessions.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. FOUDY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; &#8220;…you can get, you know, bagels and cream cheese.&#8221;&nbsp; Or, &#8220;Hey, can we get a massage therapist?&#8221;&nbsp; Or, &#8220;Hey, can we stay at maybe a little bit nicer hotel?&#8221;&nbsp; I mean, just the basics that you start to hear about, and it festers a little bit more, and, you know, the little things become bigger things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, the thing that makes me so proud is this is &#8212; this goes back to the &#8217;90s, of us, you know, threatening to actually strike an Olympics and not play in an Olympics and in locking out because we felt like that was our only leverage we had.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to see them &#8212; and one of the things we were so cognizant of is, &#8220;Okay, we&#8217;ve got to teach the younger kids what this fight is so that when we&#8217;re gone, they&#8217;re going to carry that baton.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, when we &#8212; the &#8220;old bags,&#8221; as we call ourselves &#8212; see them take it and really take it to a whole new level &#8212; we were fighting for equitable pay; they&#8217;re fighting for equal pay, as they should be.&nbsp; And it just warms your heart because it&#8217;s not easy.&nbsp; It was incredibly courageous, and it took a ton of energy and time and focus, and they just were locked in on getting it done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then you have a woman who is the president of U.S. Soccer, who can help them get it over the line.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, it was a full circle moment for a lot of us &#8212; a proud moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So, let&#8217;s go to the &#8212; we were talking backstage about the inside-outside game &#8212; right? &#8212; the advocacy from the outside.&nbsp; And then, really most of the reforms and most of the advances that we&#8217;ve ever seen, in terms of equality and the fight &#8212; the ongoing fight for equality &#8212; has required the push from the outside, but it requires also allies, at the very least, on the inside &#8212; if not advocates on the inside, also.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, can you talk a little bit about what that experience was like for you, as a former player, but then being the president and what that meant in terms of the difficulties you must have experienced from the inside, understanding the push from the outside?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. CONE:&nbsp; Yeah, you know, for me, I feel like it has been over two decades of work.&nbsp; It started off, as Julie said, fighting for bagels between training sessions.&nbsp; And now this larger group of women, through the last two decades, are literally changing the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And for me, I&#8217;m also a coach, so to know that these young girls are now growing up and they can realize their dreams and they&#8217;re going to be fairly compensated for that, I think that&#8217;s why this is so important.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not necessarily for the people sitting here today, but it&#8217;s for the future of not only the future soccer players, but women in general.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s why this is important.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why leadership is important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And getting to your point is, you know &#8212; I sat beside Jules and Bri when we were doing our CBA negotiations.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think you can just sit on the outside and keep complaining unless you&#8217;re willing to get inside and help create change.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, that is why I do what I do.&nbsp; Because I think having people on the inside that understand the players and what it&#8217;s like to be out on the field representing your country and what that means to you, I think, is really important to create change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But as you said backstage, you know, our work isn&#8217;t done yet.&nbsp; We still have a lot of work to do, both in our sport and in our country and worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In our sport, I know that I&#8217;m going to have willing partners in CONCACAF and FIFA to spread what we have done here to the rest of the world.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp; And you were just re-elected president, right?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. CONE:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, you were.&nbsp; Fantastic.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you mind sharing with us without &#8212; you don&#8217;t have to name names, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; what were people in the inside saying about why this hadn&#8217;t happened or where there was resistance?&nbsp; What &#8212; how were they justifying that in their own minds, much less for the &#8212; the best interest of the game and, to your point, what you represent, which is the United States of America?</p>



<p>MS. CONE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; You know, I think that &#8212; I think people in my boardroom come at from different perspectives.&nbsp; So not everyone thinks the same thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think the challenges from the U.S. soccer standpoint was that there were two separate contracts for the men and the women, because the women wanted guaranteed pay, where the men were paid to play.&nbsp; And so, trying to find equal with totally different structures of contracts was forever elusive.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re in CBA &#8212; CBA negotiations right now and trying to get to one structure so it&#8217;s very clear that everything, compensation wise, is equal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then the other thing is the FIFA World Cup prize money is drastically different.&nbsp; The men&#8217;s World Cup winner for the last World Cup got $38 million for winning it, whereas our women who won the World Cup only received $4 million from FIFA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there &#8212; there are already built-in status quo differences that were systemic that we need to keep working to change.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What was the inf- &#8212; and maybe I&#8217;ll go to Briana.&nbsp; What was the inflection point?&nbsp; Like, what &#8212; what started to turn the movement and bring it to the next level?&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; </a>I think what&#8217;s important to note: When you get on the U.S. women&#8217;s national team, you have a dual mandate.&nbsp; The first is superb soccer.&nbsp; I mean, we have the expectation of winning everything.&nbsp; And so, if you think about it from that point of view, in our day, we were expected to win World Cups and Olympic Games.&nbsp; And then, in present day, these amazing women had the same expectation, and we were both able to do that.&nbsp; So every cycle, we&#8217;ve won either the Olympic Games or the World Cup.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s that part of it.</p>



<p>And the second part is to fight and raise the bar higher.&nbsp; And so, I think, for me, I&#8217;ve continued to talk about equal pay, even though I don&#8217;t play anymore.&nbsp; And Julie does it; and now Cindy is obviously back in the arena, in a different position, fighting for that as well.&nbsp; But I think, for me, when I read about the team &#8212; and I consider them my team still, even though I haven&#8217;t played with most of them.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; We all do.</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; We all.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I consider it my team too.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp;&nbsp; My &#8212; my sisters &#8212; right, your team too.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah, when I saw that my team was essentially sticking their necks out there like we did with the boycott in ’95 &#8212; basically putting our Olympic dreams on the line.&nbsp; For me, I wanted to be an Olympian since I was eight.&nbsp; So, putting my name out there to potentially lose my opportunity &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; &#8212; was very, very difficult but very, very powerful, and we knew we had to do it.&nbsp; And I think when I saw that they filed that lawsuit, I thought it was so brave &#8212; so incredibly brave.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s the &#8212; it was the next evolution of the battle to be able to get U.S. soccer to take us more seriously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What was the risk that they took when they filed that lawsuit &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; knowing it hadn&#8217;t been done before?&nbsp; Right?</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What was the risk?</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; So &#8212; so when you file a lawsuit, in my opinion, you have your name on the dotted line of a legal document.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; And so there&#8217;s that pressure and that connotation going along with that.&nbsp; And then to still have to try and win stuff, to go out there and play hard all the time that, I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>PARTICIPANT&nbsp; Win stuff.</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; To win stuff.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Gold medals.&nbsp; Things like that.&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; To win a World Cup, to win Gold medals &#8212; that&#8217;s the expectation, even though you have this high level of time and energy, as everybody can attest to, pouring into something else.&nbsp; It almost, like, diverts from the goal, which should only be to win, not to do all these other things.</p>



<p>And so, I think having your name on a legal document &#8212; there&#8217;s all this extra effort in, you know, paying for lawyers and getting prepared and having maybe a potential trial or whatever it is.&nbsp; All that extra effort, I think, is the thing that&#8217;s so different with the lawsuit versus maybe other ways to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s such an excellent point.&nbsp; As a general matter, when women are fighting for pay equity in any industry or in any employment setting, to require that the way that she will actually achieve parity in pay based on the value of work; to require that that &#8212; that that would take a lawsuit, the intervention of a court, the rule of law, means that she&#8217;s got to do her job every day, whatever that job is in whatever that industry is, and deal with the lawsuit.</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp; Absolutely.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And all that requires, in terms of the time spent but, to your point, the vulnerability to put your name on a legal document and then put yourself in a court setting that is adversarial in nature, all because you want to get paid &#8212; equal pay for equal work.</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And what that requires of that woman beyond doing a good job, to your point, I think that&#8217;s such a &#8212; it&#8217;s a subtle but incredibly important point.</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; Absolutely.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You were still striving for and achieving excellence in your job.&nbsp; And then it required superhuman excellence to endure litigation &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. SCURRY:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; to just get paid for the value of your work.</p>



<p>Talk to me about the next generation and what that &#8212; what it &#8212; let&#8217;s talk about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; we were talking &#8212; we were talking backstage about how &#8212; I shared &#8212; my mother had many sayings.&nbsp; One of them she would say to me, “Kamala, you may be the first to do many things, but make sure you&#8217;re not the last.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what I love about the conversation that we were having &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to bring Megan and Alex into this conversation.&nbsp; But I love how you all really do think about this in terms of the generational impact &#8212; those who kind of had to go with the machete and go and try and knock things down to achieve fairness, and then the next generation that has come through really appreciating that and then carrying it through and continuing with that work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So why don&#8217;t we talk a little bit about that?</p>



<p>MS. PURCE:&nbsp; A hundred percent.&nbsp; When you used the analogy of the machete, I was just thinking: I think that&#8217;s so accurate.&nbsp; You guys had the machete, you have a sword, and now I feel like I have these like scissors &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; that I&#8217;m like, “All right, let&#8217;s &#8211;”&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. O’HARA:&nbsp; They’re sharp.&nbsp; They’re sharp.</p>



<p>MS. PURCE:&nbsp; Yeah, let&#8217;s &#8212; they&#8217;re sharp, but like let&#8217;s try them &#8212; like, let&#8217;s get it done.</p>



<p>I really do think that the true power of this team doesn&#8217;t come from the fact that we&#8217;re able to accomplish change, but we&#8217;re able to embolden others to pursue change.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PURCE:&nbsp; It&#8217;s so evident that this progress is the result of women across generations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PURCE:&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s a lesson in possibility.&nbsp; It shows that when you pursue what is right, others will join you and it will continue on pass whatever you &#8212; you can imagine it&#8217;s going to do.</p>



<p>So yeah, I mean, I even think &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m not the youngest player in camp.&nbsp; And even when I look younger than me, I&#8217;m like, “Yeah, they&#8217;re going to be great,” on both sides of the coin &#8212; on the field and off the field.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I do agree the future is bright.&nbsp; And I &#8212; I&#8217;m really grateful to have had examples like this &#8212; you know, not just seeing it on television, but then practicing with it every day, being able to call it &#8212; I&#8217;m talking to Pinoe &#8212; after camp and see what&#8217;s going on.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s incredible the &#8212; the culture that you guys have created, and I&#8217;m just so grateful to be a part of it.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And I love that point.&nbsp; It is &#8212; if we see it for what we should, which is that it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s really a fight for something, not against something, and, yes, about equal pay and equity, but also possibility &#8212; right? &#8212; and encouraging people to see what is possible, even if it has never been.</p>



<p>Megan, coming to you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Coming to you.</p>



<p>Talk a little bit about where you think that there are lessons for women in other industries and professions, based on the experience that you all have had.&nbsp; What worked?&nbsp; What didn’t work?&nbsp; What’s the &#8212; how can you advise others about where maybe there are some hard knocks but where it was worth it because you saw some success?</p>



<p>MS. RAPINOE:&nbsp; (Inaudible.) (Audio on mute.)</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. RAPINOE:&nbsp; Oh, I’m so mad.&nbsp; I’m so upset right now.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s the theme of the last two years.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. RAPINOE:&nbsp; I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Take two.&nbsp; Take two.</p>



<p>MS. RAPINOE:&nbsp; That just really &#8212; okay, I deserved that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>I was going to say I’m not going to pass up this opportunity &#8212; certainly, for the first time in my life and the first time ever, hopefully not the last &#8212; to just say, &#8220;Madam Vice President.&#8221;&nbsp; Like, that’s &#8212; that’s incredible.&nbsp; And although it doesn’t have to do specifically with equal pay, I think it speaks to a changing landscape that we’re all part of.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the thing that I’ve &#8212; you know, it’s really settled with me &#8212; is that our freedom and our liberation and our equality is tied up in each other in the moment, but also generationally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, you’re seeing on the stage right now &#8212; you know, Madam Vice President, your mom, her famous quote about not being the last one, even though you&#8217;re the first &#8212; when we think of Billie Jean King; and Venus and Serena Williams; and WNBA players &#8212; obviously, my partner, Sue Bird, and Nneka Ogwumike.&nbsp; Like, all of these women are doing the same thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, even go wider.&nbsp; If I&#8217;m seeing myself in, you know, union workers in Alabama and they&#8217;re seeing themselves in us or our team, it&#8217;s all kind of the same thing because we&#8217;re all dealing with the same issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think for us, the more we connect our stories, the more we literally connect with each other, the more that we can kind of draft off each other, I think the more successful that we&#8217;ll be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know, for us &#8212; you know, our lawsuit &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t capture every single player and it doesn&#8217;t capture every single woman in all of America, but it is something and it&#8217;s our little part.</p>



<p>And I think when you start to string together the idea that all of our equality &#8212; I mean, frankly, across the entire spectrum of equality &#8212; but all of our liberation, all of our freedom, all of our worth is tied up in each other, now we have a movement.&nbsp; Now we have 50 percent of the country all fighting for the same thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, of course, you add, you know, allies and advocates and people who believe and feel the same thing.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where I think the biggest impact can come.&nbsp; Because, as you said, the little knocks &#8212; I mean, everything is a knock.&nbsp; Like, inequality is in the air that we breathe.&nbsp; And so, it is difficult at times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Kelley spoke to it.&nbsp; Being able to sign your name with 27 other people and being able to, at times, take a rest when you&#8217;re exhausted knowing that, you know, other women or other players or other people in your union are having your back and doing that work, I think, is essential, because it is difficult work and it is long work and the game has to be long.</p>



<p>So, I think, for all of us, you know, we sort of know it on the team just intrinsically because we know that we come from a long line of fighters and, you know, women who fought for equality and fought for freedoms for us and fought to make things better each generation.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s our goal, and now really trying to tie it to a larger sort of society movement is what I think will have the most impact over the shortest amount of time.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s great.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s right.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s about the coalition and &#8212; and I think the strength of coalition always is seeing the commonalities and then &#8212; and then building and growing off of that in a way that empowers everybody.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s right.</p>



<p>Alex, did you just get off the field?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. MORGAN:&nbsp; I’m very underdressed.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I literally ran in and my cleats are still on.&nbsp; So, yes.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know that, and I&#8217;m so glad that &#8212; because we were &#8212; we weren&#8217;t &#8212; we weren&#8217;t sure.&nbsp; And you hustled to get here, and I&#8217;m so glad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m thinking, given the circumstances in which you are here, that it might be best to ask you: What are the analogies between the fight for equal pay and the fight to win a game?</p>



<p>MS. MORGAN:&nbsp; Oh.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Like, what does it take?&nbsp; What does it take?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. MORGAN:&nbsp; I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Give me some analogies.&nbsp; Like, right?&nbsp; The rules of winning a game.</p>



<p>MS. MORGAN:&nbsp; What does it take?&nbsp; I mean, it takes everything.&nbsp; It &#8212; honestly, I feel it&#8217;s everything.&nbsp; Like Pinoe said, sometimes you have some women stepping up and some have to take a backseat because they’re exhausted.&nbsp; So, it’s everyone fighting for each other.&nbsp; It’s working as a team.&nbsp; It’s supporting each other.&nbsp; It’s raising questions and knowing in your heart that you’re doing the right thing.&nbsp; And it’s leaning on each other.</p>



<p>A fight for equal pay is a lot longer than a soccer game and a lot harder.&nbsp; But there is &#8212; there’s definitely some similarities to be had.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And good coaches, I imagine, help.&nbsp; Right?</p>



<p>MS. MORGAN:&nbsp; Definitely.&nbsp; Coaches, lawyers, publicists &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Fair umpires.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>MS. MORGAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Referees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. MORGAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All of that.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. MORGAN:&nbsp; Oh, it all &#8212; yeah, it all plays into it.&nbsp; Referees, judges, court decisions.&nbsp; Yep, it all plays into it.</p>



<p>MS. RAPINOE:&nbsp; That was good off the fly.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That was good off the fly, right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I knew there would be some &#8212; I mean, it’s &#8212; because also it really is about pacing yourself, for sure, and figuring out how do you define the win.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And the score is certainly one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think that on this point and to Megan’s point, anything that is about a fight for equality, the win includes that you fought.&nbsp; That’s part of defining the win &#8212; that you stood up for yourself.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Even in &#8212; when the odds were against you.&nbsp; Maybe it wasn’t popular.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, because in these kinds of processes &#8212; we were talking about the fact that I was in Selma last week, celebrating &#8212; or commemorating the 57th anniversary of the crossing of the Edmund Pettus Bridge, when those marchers &#8212; you know, they tried three times to cross that bridge and were beaten back, you know, shed blood on that bridge.&nbsp; But they didn&#8217;t give up.&nbsp; And every time they went, they were inspiring other people to know what was possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s a similar thing to have that kind of faith in yourself and your cause and to not give up.&nbsp; And you all have done that in a really extraordinary way &#8212; a really extraordinary way.</p>



<p>So, thank you all very much.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really &#8212; it&#8217;s wonderful to watch.&nbsp; And I know many of us watched it from afar, saw the images of, you know, the difference in terms of locker rooms and &#8212; and the equipment, in terms of &#8212; yeah.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s good to know that things are changing for the better.</p>



<p>So, thank you all very much.&nbsp; For all &#8212; all of us who are here and all of us who are watching and the folks you probably never meet who are going to benefit from the work that you all did: Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PARTICIPANTS:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Yay!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3:57 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden to Celebrate Women’s History&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-to-celebrate-womens-history-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 02:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The White House Looking around this room, at so many women who have blazed trails and shattered glass ceilings, I’m so grateful that you’ve joined us.  Yet I can’t help but think of a woman whose name isn’t in our history books: my mother.   She was a stay-at-home mom of five girls in a suburb of Philadelphia.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The White House</p>



<p>Looking around this room, at so many women who have blazed trails and shattered glass ceilings, I’m so grateful that you’ve joined us. <br> <br>Yet I can’t help but think of a woman whose name isn’t in our history books: my mother.  <br> <br>She was a stay-at-home mom of five girls in a suburb of Philadelphia. She spent her days trying to complete a to-do list that was never quite done.<br> <br>She was a terrible cook—we ate frozen fish sticks and boiled hotdogs—but she dressed the dinner table with fresh flowers and china each night to make it feel special.<br> <br>She was witty, and quick to laugh, and kind and she knew exactly what to say when my world was falling apart.<br> <br>That’s what I miss the most—how I could call her when I was hurt or angry, when I felt like I’d never live up to the person I wanted to be—and just the sound of her voice let me know that everything would be OK.                    <br> <br>She never asked me to follow in her footsteps—only made sure I knew I could find my own way and she’d be there to root for me.<br> <br>And though she left before I was done needing her, I feel her strength inside me. I see her fire in my daughter, Ashley. I know that she never stopped cheering me on.<br> <br>We are all here today because someone believed in us. Our mothers. Our nanas, and teachers, and mentors. Because someone taught us to be brave.<br> <br>And we are here to be those women for someone else. In big, historic ways—becoming, as the Vice President says, those “firsts, but not lasts”—and in small ways, too.<br> <br>Helping our daughters believe in a world we haven’t won yet, showing our sons that it’s their work too.<br> <br>Taking risks—even when we might fail—because we know that there is a young girl who needs to see us try.   <br> <br>Today, we honor the women who made us and the women we make.<br> <br>We know that there is still far to travel, but we keep moving, guided by the strong hands of the women who came before us, continuing the path they forged with sweat and pain and love.<br> <br>So thank you for being here. Thank you for celebrating this moment with us.<br> <br>May you never forget the women who are cheering you on. And may your voice be that ovation for the girls who come next. <br> <br>Thank you.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at an Event on Equal Pay Day to Celebrate Women&#8217;s History&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/15/remarks-by-president-biden-at-an-event-on-equal-pay-day-to-celebrate-womens-history-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[6:01 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, hello, everyone.&#160; Welcome to the White House.&#160; This is the biggest crowd we’ve had since we got here.&#160; (Applause.) I’m Joe Biden.&#160; I’m Jill Biden’s husband.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; And proud of it.&#160; Welcome to Women’s History Month celebration.&#160; We’re honored to have what may well be the most inspiring event&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>6:01 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, hello, everyone.&nbsp; Welcome to the White House.&nbsp; This is the biggest crowd we’ve had since we got here.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I’m Joe Biden.&nbsp; I’m Jill Biden’s husband.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And proud of it.&nbsp;<br><br>Welcome to Women’s History Month celebration.&nbsp; We’re honored to have what may well be the most inspiring event we’ve had at the White House so far.<br><br>I’ve often said that America’s strength is not just the example of our power, but the power of our example.&nbsp; And I mean that.&nbsp; Look at &#8212; I was going to say: Look at this stage, but that’s enough too.&nbsp; Look at this stage.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But there’s been a little change in the arrangement of who’s on the stage because of the First Lady’s husband contracting COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>But look at this room and what you see.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Pardon?<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; You said the First &#8212; anyways.&nbsp;&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s right.&nbsp; She’s fine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s me that’s not together.<br><br>The Second La- &#8212; the First Gentleman.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; How about that.<br><br>Anyway, an incredible group of members of Congress, led by Nancy Pelosi, the first woman Speaker &#8212; (applause) &#8212; who I believe will be considered one of the greatest Speakers in our history.&nbsp; And I mean that.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And she knows I mean it.&nbsp; I’ve been saying it for years.&nbsp;<br><br>And members of the most diverse Cabinet in the history of this country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And the first to have an equal number of women and men in the Cabinet.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>I’m enormously proud of this team.&nbsp; One person I’m particularly proud of is &#8212; was going to be introducing me &#8212; is Kamala Harris.&nbsp; But Kamala &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as I said, Kamala chose not to take a chance since her husband had contracted COVID, although he’s feeling very well, I’m told.<br><br>And, by the way, when he tested &#8212; he’s fine, but out of an abundance of caution, she decided she wasn’t going to join us today.&nbsp; But let’s send her our love because she’s something else.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I know how proud she is of our &#8212; our team:<br><br>Avril Haines &#8212; the first woman to lead our intelligence community as Director of National Intelligence.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Stand up, Avril.&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; Stand up.&nbsp; She does everything in secret.&nbsp; That’s why she doesn’t want to stand up.&nbsp;<br><br>Former governor Jennifer Granholm, the Energy Department.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I often kid her &#8212; and I wasn’t kidding early on when I seeking the nomination.&nbsp; Had she been born in America, she’d be standing here and I’d be sitting there.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She’s the former governor of the state of Michigan.&nbsp; Michigan.&nbsp; Wrong.&nbsp; She was a former sta- &#8212; she was a governor.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I’m teasing.&nbsp; But we often kidded about it.<br><br>And Isabel Guzman, the Small Business Administration.&nbsp; Where are you?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Katherine Tai, U.S. Trade Representative.&nbsp; And she knows how to cut a deal.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Cece Rouse, Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>A number of members are not here today because they&#8217;re out traveling on behalf of the administration:<br><br>Jale- &#8212; Janet Yellen, the first female Secretary of the Treasury.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Deb Haaland, the first Native American person in the Cabinet as Interior Secretary.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Gina Raimondo, former governor, leading the Commerce Department.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Marcia Fudge, Housing and Urban Development.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>If I stole any more members of Congress, I would’ve been in real trouble with Nancy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>And Shalanda Young, newly confirmed &#8212; (applause) &#8212; just minutes ago.&nbsp; Where is she?&nbsp; Shalanda, stand up.&nbsp; Where is Shalanda?&nbsp; Where &#8212; where are you?&nbsp; She &#8212; where is she?<br><br>I guess she&#8217;s not &#8212; okay.&nbsp; Lead the Office of Management and Budget.<br><br>And Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenhouse &#8212; -Greenfield, excuse me &#8212; who is at the United Nations and does an incredible job for us.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And it’s not just the Cabinet.&nbsp; We have women in senior roles in every level here at the White House, across the administration, many of whom are here today.<br><br>And something I’m very proud of: I kept my commitment to be &#8212; nominate the first Black woman to the Supreme Court.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And she&#8217;s really good.&nbsp;<br><br>And that’s not all.&nbsp; We have confirmed more Black women to the Circuit Court of Appeals than every previous administration combined.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As a matter of fact, 75 percent of my judicial nominees are women.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>It matters.&nbsp; It matters.<br><br>Above all, we see the power of each and every one of you in the example that they, in fact, give the whole country.<br><br>You know, I want to thank you all for being here &#8212; at home and all those who are helping me around &#8212; helping the administration around the world.<br><br>It &#8212; that includes a special guest of the First Lady &#8212; and the First Lady of Iceland, Eliza Reid.&nbsp; Eliza, where are you?&nbsp;&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Stand up.&nbsp; Give her a big hand.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>She is a real champion for gender equality.&nbsp; We had a nice long talk.<br><br>Women’s History Month is an opportunity to honor the legacy, the vision, and the achievements of trailblazing women and girls who’ve built, shaped, and strengthened the character &#8212; the very character of this nation.<br><br>And despite hardships and exclusion and discrimination, women run the right &#8212; won the right to vote, campaigned against injustice, shattered countless barriers, and expanded the possibilities for all Americans.&nbsp; I think you underestimate all you’ve done.<br><br>They came before us and they&#8217;re all here &#8212; here today from all across the country as well, especially everyone who has gotten through this pandemic &#8212; frontline workers and service members, researchers and teachers &#8212; (applause) &#8212; caregivers, leaders in their communities.<br><br>And today I&#8217;m honored to be with some of the world’s greatest soccer players who happen to be women &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the U.S. Women’s National Team, both past and present.&nbsp;<br><br>Please &#8212; if I can ask you, come up on the stage.<br><br>I was going to have them stand, but if they stood, you couldn’t seem them anyway because everyone else is standing.&nbsp;<br><br>This is &#8212; they’ve won World Cups, the Olympics Gold Medal &#8212; Gold Medals, and, you know, for &#8212; after much, much too long, equal pay.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Equal pay.<br><br>Today is Equal Pay Day.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And they just came from an event that discussed our administration’s effort to close the pay gap.&nbsp; So, thank you so much.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;And, by the way, you’re not only helping yourself, you’re helping us get it done for other women.</p>



<p>MS. CONE:&nbsp;&nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;Yes.&nbsp;&nbsp;And that’s (inaudible).</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp;All right. &nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)<br><br>And, look, we&#8217;re doing so by expanding access to good-paying jobs, lower costs for childcare and eldercare so women can get back to work and their families can have economic security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And earlier today, I signed an executive order to promote efforts to achieve pay equality and pay equity for employees of federal contractors.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s my hope that this sets an example for all private companies to follow as well.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the purpose of what I did.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Let me just close with this: Gender equality is not a woman&#8217;s issue alone; it benefits everybody.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp; It benefits everyone &#8212; our society, our economy, and our country.</p>



<p>And I hope you&#8217;re able to walk through the wonderful exhibit we have downstairs celebrating Women&#8217;s History Month and the history of the journey of America.</p>



<p>Back in Fer- &#8212; back in February, I was in Lorain, Ohio, outside of Cleveland, to talk about a new infrastructure law that was going to transform our nation.&nbsp; It was the day before the birthday of Lorain&#8217;s most famous &#8212; one of her most famous daughters, Nobel Prize, Pulitzer Prize, No- &#8212; Nobel Prize winner, Pulitzer Prize winner, and one of Jill&#8217;s favorite authors, Toni Morrison.&nbsp; Toni is also &#8212; was also the mother-in-law of Dr. Rouse, one of our nation&#8217;s top economic thinkers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ms. Morrison left us words to live by.&nbsp; She said, “We&#8217;ve got more yesterdays than anybody.&nbsp; We need some kind of tomorrow.”&nbsp; “We need some kind of tomorrow.”</p>



<p>Downstairs is a display honoring Toni Morrison and that singular belief in tomorrow &#8212; that singular belief that America &#8212; in America, anything is possible.</p>



<p>I was once asked by Xi Jinping in China how &#8212; could I define America.  I said, “Yes.  In one word.”  God’s truth &#8212; one word: “Possibilities.”  We believe anything is possible in this country. <br><br>And that singular power of example shows our daughters, our granddaughters there’s not a single thing a man can do that a woman can’t do as well or better.<br><br>And, by the way, I can honestly say without fear of contradiction: From the time my daughter was born &#8212; our daughter was born &#8212; so, the time our four granddaughters were born &#8212; I&#8217;ve told them every day they could listen that there&#8217;s not a single thing they can&#8217;t do.  And I mean that from the bottom of my heart.  And they are living proof of that truth.<br><br>I want to start talking about my granddaughters now, if I can.  But &#8212; (laughter).<br><br>You know, especially the women I&#8217;m honored to introduce and who has more influence on them and has set an example that I think I&#8217;m just fortunate and they&#8217;re fortunate to have witnessed and be part of.<br><br>And with that, let me introduce the First Lady of the United States.  Before she comes up, I want you to know: Everybody knows I love her more than she loves me.  (Laughter.) I&#8217;m going to tell the story, Jill. <br><br>THE FIRST LADY:  No.  (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m going to tell the story. <br><br>When we first got to the Vice President&#8217;s office, as those of you who are from Washington know, you walk down the steps of the Eisenhower Building, and you&#8217;re looking right into the Vice President&#8217;s office.  And the windows, I think, are 16 feet high and they have 12 big panes of glass, and four of them going across the office.  I think it&#8217;s four. <br><br>And &#8212; and so, Jill&#8217;s favorite day is &#8212; of the year is Valentine&#8217;s Day.  And so, she had gotten, as a professor &#8212; a teacher &#8212; she&#8217;s still teaching full-time &#8212; a teacher, she got that erasable paint you can, you know, use.  And she, on every window &#8212; every window &#8212; she got the maintenance guy to bring up a ladder.  And on every window, she put a big heart, and she said, “Joe loves Jill.”  (Laughter.)  Swear to God.  In every single window.  (Laughter.) <br><br>Well, my press person came to me &#8212; because she did it in the evening, and &#8212; and she &#8212; the night before Valentine&#8217;s Day.  And he said, “Look, they want you to go on CBS tomorrow morning and talk about Valentine&#8217;s Day.  We think you should do it.”  Now, her name &#8212; the interviewer is Juju Chang.  And Juju &#8212; we’re sitting there in the Vice President&#8217;s large office with all the shades pulled, in the dark, and just the lights on &#8212; you know, the Klieg lights.  And we&#8217;re about knee to knee.  And while we&#8217;re getting ready, Juju Chang looks at me and says, “You know, everybody says you and your wife have a great love affair going.”  I said, “I think so.”  I said, “But everybody knows I love her more than she loves me.”  And she looked at me straight in the eye &#8212; give you my word &#8212; and said, “That’s what they say.”  (Laughter.) <br><br>Ladies and gentlemen, the love of my life and the life of my love: Jill.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>6:16 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
