<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 21:00:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Appointments to Board of Advisors on Historically Black Colleges and&#160;Universities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/31/president-biden-announces-appointments-to-board-of-advisors-on-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint qualified and diverse leaders to the President’s Board of Advisors on Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs). The President’s Board will advance the goal of the HBCU Initiative, established by the Carter Administration, to increase the capacity of HBCUs to provide the highest-quality education to its&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to appoint qualified and diverse leaders to the President’s Board of Advisors on Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs). The President’s Board will advance the goal of the <a href="https://thehilltoponline.com/2021/09/03/exclusive-biden-harris-administration-announces-white-house-initiative-targeting-hbcus/">HBCU Initiative</a>, established by the Carter Administration, to increase the capacity of HBCUs to provide the highest-quality education to its students and continue serving as engines of opportunity.<br> </p>



<p>In 2021, President Biden appointed Drs. Tony Allen and Glenda Glover to serve as Chair and Vice Chair of the President’s Board of Advisors on HBCUs, respectively. In February, he appointed Dr. Dietra Trent as executive director of the White House HBCU Initiative.</p>



<p><br>The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to supporting the vital mission of HBCUs. Through the American Rescue Plan, grant funding, and by forgiving capital improvement debt of many these institutions, the Biden-Harris Administration has already committed more than <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-%E2%81%A0harris-administrations-historic-investments-and-support-for-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/">$5.8 billion in support</a>. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/09/03/executive-order-on-white-house-initiative-on-advancing-educational-equity-excellence-and-economic-opportunity-through-historically-black-colleges-and-universities/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Reestablishing the White House HBCU Initiative</a>&nbsp;– and appointing qualified and diverse individuals to the Board – will allow the administration to build on that financial commitment with continued institutional support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden announces his intent to appoint the following individuals to serve as members on the board:</p>



<ul><li>Makola M. Abdullah</li><li>Javaune Adams-Gaston</li><li>Paige Blake</li><li>Thasunda Brown Duckett</li><li>Willie A. Deese</li><li>Patrick Cokley</li><li>Monica Goldson</li><li>Brett J. Hart</li><li>Taraji P. Henson</li><li>Beverly W. Hogan</li><li>Lisa P. Jackson</li><li>Shevrin D. Jones</li><li>Walter M. Kimbrough</li><li>William F. L. Moses</li><li>Christopher E. Paul</li><li>Quinton T. Ross Jr.</li><li>Ruth J. Simmons</li><li>Janeen Uzzell</li></ul>



<p><strong>Makola M. Abdullah</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Makola M. Abdullah is the 14<sup>th</sup> President of Virginia State University (VSU). He is a member of numerous boards and committees including: Council of 1890s Presidents for Association of Public Land-Grant Universities (APLU); Board of Trustees for the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools Commission on College, and the Council of Presidents for Virginia Institutions of Higher Education, and Board member of Big Brothers Big Sisters of America. Prior to his appointment as President of Virginia State University, Dr. Abdullah served as provost and senior vice president at Bethune-Cookman University in Daytona Beach, provost and vice president for academic affairs at Florida Memorial University in Miami Gardens, and dean and director of 1890 land grant programs at Florida Agricultural and Mechanical University in Tallahassee. Dr. Abdullah is a Chicago native. He earned his undergraduate degree from Howard University in civil engineering and his doctorate and master’s degrees in civil engineering from Northwestern University. He is the youngest African American to receive a Ph.D. in engineering. He is a member of Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity. He and his wife, Ahkinyala Cobb-Abdullah, Ph.D., are the proud parents of a son, Mikaili, and a daughter, Sefiyetu, who both are college graduates.</p>



<p><strong>Javaune Adams-Gaston &nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Javaune Adams-Gaston, Ph.D., serves as the seventh President of Norfolk State University, the Commonwealth of Virginia’s largest Historically Black College and University in Norfolk, Virginia. Dr. Adams-Gaston is committed to the mission of Norfolk State University to transform the lives of students through access to higher education and excellence in scholarship, career preparation, and service. Dr. Adams-Gaston is committed to student success and the development of the student holistically through academic excellence, mentorship, mental and physical wellness, internships, and civic engagement. Since her arrival on campus in June 2019, Dr. Adams-Gaston has advocated for increased financial support for the benefit of students, faculty and staff and the stability of the institution. Dr. Adams-Gaston was pivotal in securing a $40 million gift from philanthropist MacKenzie Scott—the largest single gift in NSU’s history. She has led the university in successful efforts to secure grants and partnerships from corporations such as Microsoft, Netflix, Apple, IBM, Dominion Energy, and others. Under her tenure, NSU has been designated a Top 20 HBCU for consecutive years in U.S News and World Report Rankings. Prior to becoming President at Norfolk State University, Dr. Adams-Gaston served as Senior Vice President for Student Life at The Ohio State University. During her career at the University of Maryland, Dr. Adams-Gaston held numerous positions including psychologist, associate dean in academic affairs, assistant athletic director, equity administrator, and graduate faculty member. Dr. Adams-Gaston had a practice for 25 years as a licensed psychologist and as an educator, she is frequently asked to provide speeches, lectures, and to serve on panels regarding student success and leadership.</p>



<p><strong>Paige Blake</strong></p>



<p>Paige Blake is a 20-year-old native of Prince George’s County, Maryland. She is a junior at Bowie State University where she majors in Biology and is on the pre-med track. Paige plans to attend medical school to study Neurology to help others with Spina Bifida and other neurological conditions. Paige was diagnosed at age 4 with a rare form of Sacral Agenesis (a form of Spina Bifida). Over time she’s learned the importance of advocacy after having her own share of hardships in her life with her disability. Paige has used her personal experiences to advocate and help others in various ways, such as organizing donation drives with her Girl Scout troop where they sent medical supplies to countries overseas and working with The Congressional Black Caucus and President Obama’s White House Initiative on African American Excellence to advocate for disabled students. Currently, Paige has been named the 2021-2022 White House Initiative HBCU Competitiveness Scholar for Bowie State University. She also is working with The University System of Maryland Student Council as the Director of Student Affairs, where she advocates for students to ensure that present and future college students in the state of Maryland will have positive and equal opportunities.</p>



<p><strong>Thasunda Brown Duckett</strong></p>



<p>Thasunda Brown Duckett is President and Chief Executive Officer of TIAA, a Fortune 100 provider of secure retirements and outcome-focused investment solutions to millions of people working in higher education, healthcare and other mission-driven organizations. As TIAA’s CEO, Duckett leads a company whose mission is defined by financial inclusion and opportunity – goals and values she has upheld throughout her career. Duckett joined TIAA after serving as Chief Executive Officer of Chase Consumer Banking, where she oversaw a banking network with more than $600 billion in deposits and 50,000 employees. Duckett serves on the boards of NIKE, Inc., Brex Inc., Robert F. Kennedy Human Rights, Sesame Workshop, National Medal of Honor Museum, Economic Club of New York, University of Houston Board of Visitors and Dean’s Advisory Board for the Baylor University’s Hankamer School of Business. She’s a member of the Executive Leadership Council, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority Inc. and Jack and Jill of America Inc. She holds a Bachelor’s degree in Finance and Marketing from the University of Houston and an MBA from Baylor University.</p>



<p><strong>Willie A. Deese</strong></p>



<p>Willie A. Deese is a retired pharmaceutical executive and corporate board member whose career spans 5 decades.&nbsp; He most recently served as Executive Vice President of Manufacturing at Merck and Co. Inc.&nbsp; He is a graduate of North Carolina A&amp;T State University and credits his alma mater with providing him the foundational platform on which he was able to build a successful career.&nbsp; He is recognized for his expertise in manufacturing and supply chain management as well as his proactive contributions defining healthy, engaged corporate cultures, implementing environmental and sustainability standards, DEI practices and policies, and leadership development.&nbsp; He fervently believes that when we level the playing field by providing equitable resources and opportunities for all, it leads to positive outcomes that have an exponential impact on society.&nbsp; Recently, North Carolina A&amp;T named its College of Business and Economics in his honor.</p>



<p><strong>Patrick Cokley</strong></p>



<p>Patrick Cokley works to bring issues of inclusion to the forefront of all communities. In his role as Chief of Organizing Advocacy and Learning at Civic Influencers, Patrick believes in the importance of giving all young people the tools they need to be engaged citizens with the ability to bring positive change to their communities. Patrick’s dedication to service stems from the values he learned from his family as well as time at an HBCU. As a graduate of Howard University, Patrick believes that it is imperative that the disability and traditional diversity communities learn to work together as they both share the core values of inclusion. Only together can our communities realize the success of an America that is inclusive of all of its citizens. Originally from South Carolina, Patrick now makes his home in New Jersey. In addition to being a person who is low vision, Patrick is also the parent of two children with disabilities.</p>



<p><strong>Monica Goldson</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Monica Goldson, Chief Executive Officer for Prince George’s County Public Schools (PGCPS), is the dedicated and dynamic leader of the 20th largest school district in the nation. A three-time HBCU graduate, she is committed to creating transformative experiences that propel students to their highest levels of excellence. Dr. Goldson focuses on doing what is best for students and educators, especially amid the challenges of the COVID-19 pandemic. Her longtime advocacy for public education was key in mobilizing the PGCPS community to provide laptops, internet service and technology assistance to families in need while building virtual learning from the ground up. Beyond the schoolhouse, she is a member of Chiefs for Change, a graduate of Leadership Greater Washington, and a board member of Nonprofit Prince George’s and the Prince George’s Chamber of Commerce. Dr. Goldson holds a bachelor’s degree in Mathematics from Florida A&amp;M University, a master’s degree in Elementary and Secondary School Administration from Bowie State University, and a doctorate in Educational Administration and Policy from Howard University. She has two adult sons, both graduates of Prince George’s County Public Schools.</p>



<p><strong>Brett Hart</strong></p>



<p>Brett Hart is President of United Airlines and is responsible for leading the company’s external-facing teams as well as operational workgroups including Technical Operations, Airport Operations, Corporate Safety, United Ground Express and Network Operations. He also oversees business-critical functions such as the customer experience, government affairs, corporate real estate, human resources, and labor relations teams.&nbsp; Mr. Hart previously served as executive vice president and chief administrative officer for United.&nbsp; A longtime resident of Chicago, Mr. Hart has been extensively involved in social, cultural, and economic causes impacting his home community.&nbsp; Brett serves on the boards of World Business Chicago, the Herbie Hancock Institute of Jazz, Northwestern Medical Group, and the Obama Foundation Inclusion Council. Brett received his Bachelor of Arts in philosophy and English from the University of Michigan and a Juris Doctor from the University of Chicago Law School. He is married and has three sons.</p>



<p><strong>Taraji P. Henson</strong></p>



<p>Academy Award-nominated and SAG and Golden Globe-winning actor, filmmaker, and activist, Taraji P. Henson quickly rose to fame after her breakout performance in the critically acclaimed film <em>Hustle &amp; Flow.</em>&nbsp; In 2020, Henson wrapped her iconic run as “Cookie Lyon” in Fox’s hit musical drama <em>Empire</em>, which has earned her three Emmy nominations, a Golden Globe Award, a Critics Choice Award, and three BET Awards. Prior credits include <em>Hidden Figures</em>, which won her a SAG for Best Ensemble, and <em>The Curious Case of Benjamin Button </em>with Brad Pitt, for which she earned an Academy Award nomination.&nbsp; In Summer 2022, she has <em>Minions: The Rise of Gru</em> and is currently in production on Blitz Bazawule’s <em>The Color Purple</em>, where she will star as Shug Avery.&nbsp;Henson launched TPH Entertainment with upcoming projects including <em>Two-Faced</em> with Bron Entertainment, which will mark Henson’s feature film directorial debut, Alessandro Camon’s <em>Time Alone</em>, which Henson will also star in, and <em>Sorcerority</em>, which she will co-produce with Game Changer Films and Gabrielle Union’s I’ll Have Another Productions. In October 2016, Henson released her New York Times bestselling novel “Around The Way Girl.” Henson launched the Boris Lawrence Henson Foundation in 2018 in honor of her late father, which provides scholarships to African-American students majoring in mental health, offers mental health services to youth in urban schools, and works to lower the recidivism rates of African-American men and women. Henson recently co-hosted the Facebook Watch series on mental health called <em>Peace of Mind with Taraji</em>, for which she received a Daytime Emmy Award nomination. In 2019, Henson received her star on the Hollywood Walk of Fame.</p>



<p><strong>Beverly W. Hogan</strong></p>



<p>Beverly Wade Hogan has a long and distinguished career as a public administrator, educator, community leader and humanitarian. As the first woman to lead the historic institution, Hogan served as President at Tougaloo College for 17 years. She retired with the distinction of President Emerita. She had also served the College as the founding director of the George A. and Ruth B. Owens Health, Wellness and Human Resources Center, Vice President for Institutional Advancement and Interim President. During her presidential tenure, she and her team enhanced the college’s curricula with new undergraduate and graduate degree programs and&nbsp; expanded partnerships with major research institutions for three plus two degree programs in law, engineering, and public health; established the Undergraduate Research Center, the Center for International Studies and Global Change, the Institute for the Study of Modern Day Slavery, the Early College High School; and made significant improvements in campus physical and technological infrastructure. Prior to becoming a college president, Hogan served as Commissioner of the Workers’ Compensation Commission; Executive Director of the Governor’s Office of Federal State Programs; Executive Director of the Mental Health Association. She is a national voice for higher education, having served on the board of directors for the Council of Independent Colleges, National Association for Independent Colleges and Universities, NAFEO and UNCF. She was appointed by former President Barack Obama to the Board of Advisors for the White House Initiative on HBCUs.</p>



<p><strong>Lisa P. Jackson</strong></p>



<p>Lisa P. Jackson is Apple’s vice president of Environment, Policy and Social Initiatives, where she leads the company’s environmental initiatives, racial equity and justice initiative, global education policy programs, product accessibility efforts, corporate giving and philanthropic partnerships, and worldwide government affairs. Her work includes driving Apple’s support for HBCUs through coding initiatives, innovation partnerships and the launch of the Propel Center. Under President Barack Obama, she served as Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, becoming the first Black person to hold the position. She also served as Chief of Staff to New Jersey Governor Jon S. Corzine and as Commissioner of New Jersey’s Department of Environmental Protection, following nearly 20 years with the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency. Lisa has been recognized as a leader in business and sustainability by numerous publications, including Ebony’s Power 100, Black Enterprise’s Women of Power, Essence Magazine’s 40 Women Who Have Influenced the World lists, and Women of Color magazine. She is the recipient of Princeton’s James Madison Medal and Tulane University’s Distinguished Alumni Award, among others. Lisa holds a master’s degree in Chemical Engineering from Princeton University and a bachelor’s degree in Chemical Engineering from Tulane University. She also holds an honorary degree from Spelman College and maintains close ties to Xavier University in New Orleans. She serves on the boards of Tulane University, the American Film Institute, and Conservation International and is an honorary member of Delta Sigma Theta sorority. Lisa and her husband Kenneth reside in San Francisco.</p>



<p><strong>Shevrin Jones</strong></p>



<p>Florida State Senator Shevrin “Shev” Jones is an educator, public servant, and consensus builder who has dedicated his life to serving others and building pathways to opportunity. Thanks to the encouragement of his close-knit family and supportive teachers, Jones recognized from a young age the power of education as the great equalizer, a foundation that drove Shevrin into teaching to help students reach their full potential. A proud graduate of Florida A&amp;M University, Jones taught high school chemistry in Broward Public Schools before founding L.E.A.D. Nation, a South Florida nonprofit organization committed to youth leadership development and social entrepreneurship training. Jones’ firsthand look at the inequities in education and society at large propelled him to enter public service, and since 2013, he has served in the Florida legislature, championing meaningful bipartisan legislation including two consecutive bills to secure dignity for incarcerated women; statewide expansion of a clean syringe exchange program; safety and oversight for athletic coaches for youth athletic teams; increased investment in underserved communities; and greater transparency and accountability for law enforcement. The first LGBTQ State Senator elected in Florida history, Jones served on President Barack Obama’s College Promise Task Force and is an active member of the Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity Inc., Young Elected Officials Network, and Millennial Action Project’s Florida Future Caucus. Today, Jones is completing his Ph.D. in Educational Leadership at Florida Atlantic University.</p>



<p><strong>Walter M. Kimbrough</strong></p>



<p>A native of Atlanta, Dr. Walter M. Kimbrough was his high school salutatorian and student bodypresident, and went on to earn degrees from the University of Georgia, Miami University in Ohio, and a doctorate in higher education from Georgia State University. He has enjoyed a fulfilling career in student affairs, serving at Emory University, Georgia State University, Old Dominion University, and Albany State University. In October of 2004, at the age of 37, he was named the 12th President of Philander Smith College. In 2012, he became the 7th President of Dillard University in New Orleans, Louisiana. Kimbrough has been recognized for his research and writings on HBCUs and African American men in college. Recently he has emerged as one of the leaders discussing free speech on college campuses. Kimbrough also has been noted for his active use of social media. He was cited by Education Dive as one of 10 college presidents on Twitter who are doing it right and was profiled in the text, “Digital Leadership In Higher Education.” In 2020 he was named by College Cliffs as one of 50 Top U.S. College and University Presidents.</p>



<p><strong>William F. L. Moses</strong></p>



<p>William F. L. Moses serves as Managing Director for the Kresge Foundation’s Education Program, which supports postsecondary access and success for low-income, first-generation and underrepresented students in the United States and South Africa. The key architect of Kresge’s education programming, Bill leads the team’s continuum of grant activities and for more than 20 years has awarded grants to HBCUs and MSIs, including UNCF, Thurgood Marshall College Fund, Spelman College, Morehouse College, Paul Quinn College, Delaware State University, Jackson State University, and Xavier University, among others. Prior to joining Kresge, Bill served as Executive Director of the Thomas J. Watson Foundation, a Senior Analyst at the Investor Responsibility Research Center, a research officer at TechnoServe, and in various positions at the Alaska State Legislature, and the federal government, including the U.S. Embassy in Cape Town, South Africa. A graduate of Claremont McKenna College, Bill holds a master’s degree in international relations from Yale University, and is the author of <em>A Guide to American State and Local Laws on South Africa</em> and co-author of <em>Corporate Responsibility in a Changing South Africa</em>. &nbsp;Bill currently serves on the advisory committees or boards of the Africa Grantmakers’ Affinity Group, APIA Scholars, California Community Colleges Chancellor’s External Leadership Council, College Promise, Detroit College Access Network, and the Seal of Excelencia.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Christopher Paul</strong></p>



<p>Christopher “Chris” Paul is a twelve-time NBA All-Star with the Phoenix Suns, two-time Olympic Gold medalist and is listed as one of the NBA’s 75 greatest players in NBA history. Off the court, he’s a father, husband, entrepreneur, activist, and philanthropist. His leadership and impact are well noted in the sports industry as he recently ended an eight-year tenure as the President of the National Basketball Players Association. His advocacy for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) is extremely important and through his Chris Paul Family Foundation, he has actively expanded a Business of Entertainment Media and Sports special topics course at NC A&amp; T, Southern University, Winston Salem State and Clark Atlanta University.&nbsp; His production company, Ohh Dip!!! creates content across multiple platforms, which includes the Why Not Us franchise of shows with NC Central Men’s Basketball and FAMU Football. Paul co-launched the Social Change Fund United dedicated to investing in and supporting organizations focused on empowering communities of color and advocating for the human rights of all black lives. His philanthropic efforts have earned him the 2016 ESPYs “Humanitarian of the Year” award, 2016 Mannie Jackson Human Spirit Award, the NBA Community Assist Award five times, and most recently the inaugural Kobe and Gigi Bryant Advocacy Award for his significant contributions to the advancement of girls’ and women&#8217;s basketball and advocacy for the WNBA.</p>



<p><strong>Quinton T. Ross Jr.</strong></p>



<p>Dr. Quinton T. Ross, Jr.,&nbsp;is entering his fifth year as President of Alabama State University, having assumed the leadership role at his alma mater on October 3, 2017. His tenure has been marked by transformative and innovative leadership that has included a 130 percent increase in fundraising, expansion of national and global partnerships, advancement of strategic initiatives under the brand of “CommUniversity,” and an increased emphasis on student success. President Ross is a three-time graduate of Alabama State University, where he earned a Bachelor of Science degree in Political Science, a Master of Education degree in Secondary Education English, and a Doctorate of Education in Educational Leadership, Policy, and Law. Dr.&nbsp;Ross&nbsp;is a distinguished career educator with more than 28 years of experience in Higher and K-12 public education. Prior to becoming the University’s 15th&nbsp;President, Dr. Ross served with distinction as a senator in the Alabama Legislature for four terms.</p>



<p><strong>Ruth J. Simmons</strong></p>



<p>Ruth J. Simmons is President of Prairie View A&amp;M University. Prior to joining Prairie View, she served as President of Smith College from 1995 to 2001 and President of Brown University from 2001 to 2012. She holds a Bachelor’s degree from Dillard University and a Ph.D. in Romance Languages and Literatures from Harvard University. Simmons serves on the Council of the Smithsonian National Museum of History and Culture and the Board of the Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas, Houston Branch.</p>



<p><strong>Janeen Uzzell</strong></p>



<p>Janeen Uzzell is the Chief Executive Officer at the National Society of Black Engineers (NSBE), the largest Black STEM community impacting society and industry. In her former role as the Chief Operating Officer for the Wikimedia Foundation, which operates Wikipedia, Janeen drove process improvement and helped launch the Wikimedia Knowledge Equity Fund to address racial inequities in free knowledge. For nearly two decades, she held various roles at General Electric, working in healthcare technologies in some of the world’s most challenging environments. As the head of Women in Technology, she accelerated the number of women in technical roles. Her previous roles at GE included Global Director of External Affairs and Technology Programs, Director of Healthcare Programs at GE Africa (where Janeen lived for several years as an Ex-Pat in Accra, Ghana), Director of Global Healthcare Programs, Director of Healthcare Disparity Programs, and Director of Service Operations. She is a recipient of numerous awards, including the United Nations Global Leadership Award and one of ADWEEK’s Top Black Women Trailblazers in Tech. Janeen received her Bachelor of Science in mechanical engineering from North Carolina Agricultural and Technical State University, and an MBA in International Business from Fairleigh Dickinson University. Janeen fuses her passion for social justice and her leadership to shine light on inequality in tech spaces and forge opportunities for others. In her spare time, she enjoys playing tennis and spending time with her family and friends in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>###</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Second Chance Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-second-chance-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 19:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[April marks Second Chance Month, when we reaffirm the importance of helping people who were formerly incarcerated reenter society.&#160; America is a Nation of second chances, and it is critical that our criminal and juvenile justice systems provide meaningful opportunities for rehabilitation and redemption. &#160;It is also vital that we address both the root causes&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>April marks Second Chance Month, when we reaffirm the importance of helping people who were formerly incarcerated reenter society.&nbsp; America is a Nation of second chances, and it is critical that our criminal and juvenile justice systems provide meaningful opportunities for rehabilitation and redemption. &nbsp;It is also vital that we address both the root causes of crime and the underlying needs of returning citizens using resources devoted to prevention, diversion, reentry, trauma-informed care, culturally-specific services, and social support. &nbsp;By supporting people who are committed to rectifying their mistakes, redefining themselves, and making meaningful contributions to society, we help reduce recidivism and build safer communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every year, over 640,000 people are released from State and Federal prisons. &nbsp;More than 70 million Americans have a criminal record that creates significant barriers to employment, economic stability, and successful reentry into society. &nbsp;Thousands of legal and regulatory restrictions prevent these individuals from accessing employment, housing, voting, education, business licensing, and other basic opportunities. &nbsp;Because of these barriers, nearly 75 percent of people who were formerly incarcerated are still unemployed a year after being released.</p>



<p>     We must rethink the existing criminal justice system and whom we send to prison and for how long; how unaddressed trauma and abuse create pipelines to incarceration; how people are treated while incarcerated; how prepared they are to reenter society once they have served their time; and how the racial inequities that lead to disproportionate numbers of incarcerated people of color and other underserved groups.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration recognizes that making the criminal and juvenile justice systems more equitable, just, and effective requires a holistic approach.&nbsp; It requires eliminating exceedingly long sentences and mandatory minimums that keep people incarcerated longer than they should be. &nbsp;It requires quality job training and educational opportunities during incarceration. &nbsp;It requires providing formerly incarcerated individuals with opportunities to enter the workforce, reunite with their families, find stable and safe homes, and access health care.&nbsp; It requires expunging and sealing certain criminal records so that people&#8217;s futures are not defined by their past.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is why my Administration is working across Federal agencies to eliminate barriers to reentry. &nbsp;We are expanding avenues for employment, housing, education, health services, civic engagement, and other benefits. &nbsp;Last fall, the Department of Justice convened the Reentry Coordination Council in collaboration with the Departments of Housing and Urban Development, Agriculture, Education, Health and Human Services, Veterans Affairs, and Labor. &nbsp;I am confident that our collective efforts will help make our communities safer and stronger by reducing crime, recidivism, mass incarceration, and elements of the justice system that foster harmful disparate impacts on people of color and other historically disadvantaged communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But despite our progress, much more work remains.&nbsp; Our&nbsp;Federal, State, local, territorial, and Tribal governments, private employers, philanthropies, and community leaders play a significant role in preparing individuals returning to our communities for success.&nbsp; Together, let us recommit to empower Americans who have paid their debt to society and to provide them with a second chance to participate, contribute, and succeed.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United&nbsp;States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States, do hereby proclaim April&nbsp;2022 as Second Chance Month.&nbsp; I call upon all government officials, educators, volunteers, and all the people of the United States to observe the month with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Sexual Assault Awareness And Prevention Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-national-sexual-assault-awareness-and-prevention-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 19:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50216</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; I was raised to believe that one of the greatest sins is the abuse of power –- whether it is economic, psychological, or physical. &#160;The cruel fact is that people of every age, ability, race, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, national origin, socioeconomic background, and religion suffer the pain and trauma of the abuse&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was raised to believe that one of the greatest sins is the abuse of power –- whether it is economic, psychological, or physical. &nbsp;The cruel fact is that people of every age, ability, race, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation, national origin, socioeconomic background, and religion suffer the pain and trauma of the abuse of power that is sexual assault. &nbsp;Sexual violence can occur anywhere &#8212; and millions of assaults occur each year at the workplace, in the home, at school, and online. &nbsp;These assaults are an intolerable affront to our shared humanity.&nbsp; During National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month, we renew our commitment to ensuring that every person can live a life free from sexual violence.&nbsp; We continue in our commitment to stand with survivors, hold perpetrators accountable, and dismantle a culture that is complicit in allowing sexual violence to continue.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sexual assault is also a public health crisis.&nbsp; According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, nearly 1 in 5 women in America experiences a rape or attempted rape, and nearly 44 percent of women and about 25 percent of all men experience some form of sexual violence in their lifetime.&nbsp; Tragically, many of those assaulted are young, and research shows that these assaults can have lifelong effects on health and are linked to chronic illnesses. &nbsp;Too often, this trauma is compounded by lost productivity, the challenge of seeking accountability, and the ensuing costs of medical and mental health care.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is committed to supporting survivors and alleviating the public health crisis of sexual assault.&nbsp; That is&nbsp;why we included $450 million in the American Rescue Plan to&nbsp;provide funding for domestic violence and sexual assault services, including rape crisis centers.&nbsp; We also included a historic commitment to funding culturally-specific community-based organizations to address the needs of survivors who face systemic barriers to accessing support and resources, including survivors of color, survivors with disabilities, and LGBTQI+ survivors.&nbsp; My Administration continues to fund innovative programs to support sexual assault survivors in rural and remote communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am committed to addressing sexual violence wherever it occurs.&nbsp; Last year, I issued an Executive Order directing the Department of Education to review Title IX regulations and other agency actions to ensure that all students have an educational environment that is free from discrimination on the basis of sex.&nbsp; Because 1 in 3 women under the age of 35 has experienced sexual harassment online, I have made addressing online forms of sexual violence, harassment, and abuse a priority, and my Administration recently launched a new Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sexual violence is also a matter of national security and military readiness.&nbsp; To advance the goal of eliminating sexual assault in our Armed Forces, I signed the 2022 National Defense Authorization Act, which includes the historic shift of legal decisions in cases of sexual assault from commanders to independent, specialized military prosecutors. &nbsp;To implement the I Am Vanessa Guillén Act, I also issued an Executive Order to add sexual harassment as a specific offense under the Uniform Code of Military Justice.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was proud to support and sign into law the Ending Forced Arbitration of Sexual Assault and Sexual Harassment Act of 2021.&nbsp; This law advances efforts to prevent and address sexual harassment and sexual assault and promotes access to justice by guaranteeing that people who have experienced sexual assault and sexual harassment in the workplace are not forced into binding arbitration and are instead allowed to choose whether to go to court.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ending violence against women and eliminating sexual assault has been a priority for me throughout my life.&nbsp; It is why I wrote and championed the original Violence Against Women Act (VAWA), a law that has transformed how we respond to sexual assault and which I count as one of my proudest legislative accomplishments.&nbsp; I am proud to have recently signed into law the reauthorization of VAWA, which expands prevention efforts and protections for survivors of sexual assault and other forms of gender-based violence. &nbsp;The law will provide increased resources and training so that our law enforcement and our judicial systems are better able to appropriately handle these cases.&nbsp; It&nbsp;includes a new focus on addressing technology-facilitated abuse and establishes a Federal civil cause of action for victims of non-consensual distribution of intimate images.&nbsp; The&nbsp;Act will strengthen rape prevention and education efforts, support rape crisis centers, improve the training of sexual assault forensic examiners, reduce the backlog of untested DNA kits, and broaden access to legal services for all survivors.&nbsp; It will also expand recognition of the special criminal jurisdiction of Tribal courts to cover non-Native perpetrators of sexual assault, sex trafficking, child abuse, and stalking.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This month, we honor the bravery and leadership of survivors by rededicating ourselves to eliminating sexual violence.&nbsp; It will require care and commitment from each of us to realize an America where everyone is free from the threat and impact of sexual violence.</p>



<p>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month.  I urge all Americans to support sexual assault survivors including when survivors reach out and disclose abuse.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Child Abuse Prevention Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-national-child-abuse-prevention-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50208</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every child deserves to live in a safe and loving household; yet, for hundreds of thousands of children across our Nation, abuse and neglect are a tragic reality.&#160; During National Child Abuse Prevention Month, our country stands as one to condemn and combat child abuse in all of its forms &#8212; including physical, emotional, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every child deserves to live in a safe and loving household; yet, for hundreds of thousands of children across our Nation, abuse and neglect are a tragic reality.&nbsp; During National Child Abuse Prevention Month, our country stands as one to condemn and combat child abuse in all of its forms &#8212; including physical, emotional, and sexual abuse, as well as online sexual exploitation; we raise awareness about the risk factors that can lead to child abuse and neglect; and we highlight the importance of supporting families to prevent child maltreatment.&nbsp; As a Nation, we must work together to prevent and address child abuse and ensure that every child can grow up in a safe environment and live a happy, prosperous life.</p>



<p><strong>   </strong>  Child abuse crosses all socioeconomic and educational levels, religions, and ethnic and cultural backgrounds.  We know that abuse and neglect negatively impact every aspect and stage of a child&#8217;s life.  Child abuse impacts the ability of students to succeed in school and often hinders their ability to forge healthy relationships with their loved ones and peers.  It is associated with involvement in the juvenile justice system, especially for girls who have experienced sexual abuse.  One of the most important tools to break the cycle and eliminate the tragedy of child abuse and neglect is prevention.  This requires that we support and uplift our communities, families, and individuals so that our children can be raised in safe, loving, and healthy environments.  For those children and adolescents who do experience abuse, it is important to ensure access to trauma-informed services and healing.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In order to help prevent child abuse and neglect, my Administration is committed to providing high-quality and equitable support to all families that need it.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan provided cash assistance to millions of working families and expanded the Child Tax Credit &#8212; which lifted millions of children and families out of poverty.&nbsp; It supplied critical funding to support State and community child abuse prevention and response efforts and authorized an additional $250 million for community-based child abuse prevention programs. &nbsp;This additional funding has allowed communities to address the complex structural issues that contribute to families becoming involved in the child welfare system.&nbsp; At a&nbsp;time when families are experiencing elevated hardships, especially vulnerable families that have been disproportionately affected by COVID-19, this extra support is more important than ever. &nbsp;Also, I was proud to sign into law a bill to help sustain the Crime Victims Fund, which provides assistance for child advocacy centers and other programs to address child abuse.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was raised to believe that one of the greatest sins is the abuse of power, and there is no greater abuse of power than the abuse of a child. &nbsp;National Child Abuse Prevention Month is an opportunity to take bold action to better support parents and caregivers with access to resources to cope during challenging times.&nbsp; It is also a time to identify and take the necessary steps to address inequities experienced by those who have been historically underserved and adversely affected by continuous poverty and inequality.&nbsp; Reducing child poverty is critical to&nbsp;reducing the disproportional representation of low-income children and families &#8212; especially communities of color &#8212; in&nbsp;the child welfare system and foster care.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our Nation is also witnessing a cynical and dangerous campaign waged by some elected leaders who are attempting to weaponize the child welfare system against families just because they love and affirm their transgender children. &nbsp;These leaders have sought to direct child abuse investigations into families simply because they have provided access to affirming care for their children. &nbsp;These discriminatory actions threaten to hurt our Nation&#8217;s children and must stop.&nbsp; Affirming a transgender child&#8217;s identity is one of the best things that a parent, teacher, or doctor can do to keep children from harm. &nbsp;My Administration will continue to take actions to keep transgender children and their families safe. &nbsp;That is why the Department of Health and Human Services recently released new guidance to State child welfare agencies on how they can support and affirm LGBTQI+ children who are in foster care.</p>



<p>     During National Child Abuse Prevention Month and throughout the year, I call upon everyone to stand together against child abuse and neglect and show our appreciation of the hardworking child-welfare workforce and allies who are steadfast in their commitment to strengthening families, protecting children, and combating systemic inequities.  For more information on how professionals and communities are supporting families and to learn strategies to advance equity in child abuse prevention programs, please view the 2021/2022 Prevention Resource Guide, available at childwelfare.gov.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Child Abuse Prevention Month.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this month by joining together as a Nation to promote the safety and well-being of all children and families and to recognize the child-welfare workforce and allies who work tirelessly to protect our children. &nbsp;And we honor the strength and resilience of adult survivors of child abuse.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Cancer Control Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/national-cancer-control-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[    Since the Congress passed the landmark National Cancer Act in 1971, our Nation has made tremendous strides in preventing, detecting, and treating cancer.  But nearly all families &#8211;including my own and that of the Vice President&#8217;s &#8212; still know the pain a cancer diagnosis brings.  Despite our Nation&#8217;s progress over the last 50 years, cancer&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>    Since the Congress passed the landmark National Cancer Act in 1971, our Nation has made tremendous strides in preventing, detecting, and treating cancer.  But nearly all families &#8211;including my own and that of the Vice President&#8217;s &#8212; still know the pain a cancer diagnosis brings.  Despite our Nation&#8217;s progress over the last 50 years, cancer in its many forms is still the second leading cause of death in the United States, with more than 600,000 deaths and nearly 1.9 million new cancer diagnoses each year.  A cancer diagnosis remains a crushing blow to those diagnosed, as well as their loved ones.  In the name of all those we have lost and for all those still fighting, I believe we can end cancer as we know it.  <br><br>     During National Cancer Control Month, we renew our commitments to improve cancer prevention, promote early detection, enhance treatment, and support the needs of cancer patients, survivors, and caregivers.  We recognize that while the fight against cancer is often personal, the desire to make cancer more preventable, detectable, and treatable is one that has the potential to unite us as a Nation, inspiring us to stand together and work together.  <br><br>     In 2016, as Vice President, I led the Cancer Moonshot to accelerate our progress against cancer and take advantage of 21st century science and technology &#8212; an effort that has catalyzed change across the cancer community.  As President, I have reignited the Cancer Moonshot and set ambitious new goals to reduce the death rate from cancer by 50 percent over the next 25 years and to improve the experience of people and their families living with and surviving cancer.  We are creating the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA-H), with the singular purpose of expediting breakthroughs in the prevention, detection, and treatment of cancer and other deadly diseases.  <br><br>     As part of a recommitment to the Cancer Moonshot, the First Lady and I announced a call to action on cancer screening and early detection.  Our goal is to drive progress on potentially life-saving screenings that so many Americans have missed as a result of the pandemic and to help ensure that everyone in the United States benefits equitably from the technology we have to detect, diagnose, and treat cancer.  We urge every American to get back on track with their recommended screenings, and we implore the public and private sectors to increase access to early detection for individuals and communities.  To learn more about which cancer screenings are appropriate for you, talk to your healthcare provider, visit <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/cancer/dcpc/prevention/screening.htm">cdc.gov/cancerscreening</a> or <a href="https://www.cancer.gov/about-cancer/screening/screening-tests">cancer.gov/screeningtests</a>, or call 1-800-4-CANCER. <br><br>     We also encourage Americans to take the proven steps to lower their risk for many forms of cancer.  Experts agree that reducing tobacco use, eating healthily, engaging in regular physical activity and exercise, limiting alcohol consumption, and reducing exposure to the sun when it is at its peak can help reduce the risk of a cancer diagnosis.  Given that cigarette smoking is responsible for 30 percent of all cancer deaths, helping people quit smoking and limiting exposure to secondhand smoke can save lives.  Resources are available at <a href="http://www.smokefree.gov/">SmokeFree.gov</a>, by calling 1-800-QUIT-NOW, or by texting QUITNOW to 333888. <br><br>     Access to health coverage is critical to the fight against cancer, and we were proud to expand access to quality, affordable coverage through the American Rescue Plan.  Most health insurance plans are required to cover recommended cancer screenings with no out-of-pocket costs.  But for millions of Americans, the care they need is not within reach.  That is why I am committed to reducing prescription drug costs and health insurance premiums for millions of Americans and closing the Medicaid coverage gap in States that refuse to expand Medicaid.  This would allow millions more of our fellow Americans to access cancer screenings and tobacco cessation services.  <br><br>     We also thank the doctors, nurses, researchers, caregivers, and advocates who are dedicated to finding treatments and cures and reducing the pain and burden of cancer.  Our Nation&#8217;s health care workers continued to provide care and support to cancer patients and their loved ones, even as a global pandemic made their jobs more difficult and demanding, and our Nation is forever grateful.  <br><br>    During Cancer Control Month, we reaffirm our national commitment to meet the scourge of cancer with urgency and with all the tools and talent we can bring to bear.  For survivors and caregivers who carry the physical and mental scars of cancer treatment and recovery, for those who we have lost, and for those who we can save &#8212; let us end cancer as we know it. <br><br>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Cancer Control Month.  I encourage citizens, government agencies, private businesses, nonprofit organizations, and other interested groups to join in activities that will increase awareness of what Americans can do to prevent, detect, treat, and control cancer.<br><br>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Donate Life Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-national-donate-life-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, more than 100,000 men, women, and children in the United States need a life-saving organ transplant.  In many cases, an organ donation provides another chance to live a full life.  For those waiting for that gift of life &#8212; the uncertainty can be excruciating, exacting a physical and emotional toll on the potential recipient and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, more than 100,000 men, women, and children in the United States need a life-saving organ transplant.  In many cases, an organ donation provides another chance to live a full life.  For those waiting for that gift of life &#8212; the uncertainty can be excruciating, exacting a physical and emotional toll on the potential recipient and their loved ones.  During National Donate Life Month, we give thanks to the families and friends of donors who have supported their loved one&#8217;s decision to save lives by donating; we show our appreciation for the professionals who serve the transplantation community; and we encourage Americans who can to become organ, eye, tissue, marrow, and blood donors.  In so doing, we honor those who have given this most extraordinary of gifts.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, because of the charity and generosity of the American people, our Nation&#8217;s transplant experts performed more than 41,000 organ transplants &#8212; a record number. &nbsp;We saw organ donations from deceased donors set an annual record for the 11th consecutive year. &nbsp;Living donor transplants, which decreased significantly in 2020 due to the COVID-19 pandemic, increased with over 6,500 living donor transplants performed.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Despite our progress, our Nation continues to face a critical shortage of organ donors, and the number of people in need of a transplant is high, with 17 people dying every day while waiting for a transplant.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s transplant waitlist also includes more than 1,900 children under the age of 18 awaiting the gift of life.&nbsp; That is why during National Donate Life Month, we also recognize National Pediatric Transplant Week&nbsp;from April 24-30, a period dedicated to ending the pediatric transplant waiting list.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Waitlist data shows that people of color make up nearly 60&nbsp;percent of individuals awaiting an organ transplant. &nbsp;To increase access to transplantation for everyone, we recommit to promoting greater diversity in organ donation, as we continue to advance health equity for all communities, including those that have gone underserved, across our Nation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every year, nearly 18,000 people in America are diagnosed with life-threatening blood cancers or other diseases for which a blood stem cell transplant may be their best or only hope for a cure.&nbsp; Approximately 70 percent of these individuals need donors from outside their families. &nbsp;Although nearly 23 million adults in the United States are currently registered as blood stem cell donors, we need more registrants to help the many individuals who still have difficulty finding a suitably matched donor.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During National Donate Life Month, we thank the millions of&nbsp;individuals across America who are living or registered organ donors.&nbsp; We recognize and commend the researchers, advocates, volunteers, and medical professionals working to reduce the number of people awaiting vital organ transplants.&nbsp; Our Nation applauds the therapeutic innovations that have decreased rates of organ rejection and have extended the lifespan of transplanted organs.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; While transplantation continues to increase substantially and meet the needs of many people with organ failure, we must continue our efforts to shorten the waiting list and encourage organ donation. &nbsp;If you have not signed up as an organ donor, we&nbsp;can use your help.&nbsp; I encourage every American to help people in&nbsp;need by visiting <a href="https://www.organdonor.gov/sign-up">organdonor.gov</a> for organ, eye, and tissue donation, and <a href="https://bloodstemcell.hrsa.gov/">bloodstemcell.hrsa.gov</a> for marrow and blood donation.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the&nbsp;United States of America, by the authority vested in me by the&nbsp;Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as National Donate Life Month.&nbsp; I call upon every person who can to share the gift of life and hope by becoming organ, eye, tissue, marrow, and blood donors.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this</p>



<p>thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the Month Of The Military Child,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/a-proclamation-on-the-month-of-the-military-child-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each April, the Month of the Military Child provides a chance for us to recognize and thank the children of our service members and veterans. &#160;I have always believed that America has a sacred obligation to prepare our troops when we send them into harm&#8217;s way and to support them and their families both while&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Each April, the Month of the Military Child provides a chance for us to recognize and thank the children of our service members and veterans. &nbsp;I have always believed that America has a sacred obligation to prepare our troops when we send them into harm&#8217;s way and to support them and their families both while they are deployed and after they return home.&nbsp; The First Lady and I recognize that it is not only those who wear the uniform that serve our country &#8212; it is also their loved ones, and especially their children.&nbsp; In the timeless words of the poet John Milton, &#8220;They also serve who only stand and wait.&#8221;<br><br>Military-connected children shoulder the burdens of service, facing unique challenges from a young age. &nbsp;They move frequently with their families &#8212; leaving friends, schools, and communities behind. &nbsp;They say goodbye to deploying family members, not knowing when they will see them again.&nbsp; Some of these young people endure deployments and separations, spending months or even years away from their beloved parent. &nbsp;Birthdays, holidays, graduations, and other important milestones are celebrated with just a phone call or virtual hug. &nbsp;The First Lady and I witnessed these sacrifices firsthand, when our grandchildren experienced their father&#8217;s deployment to Iraq.<br><br>Even after their parent has left the military, children can continue to face challenges as their parent transitions to civilian life and they may be called on to care for wounds or injuries their parent suffered during their service. &nbsp;Too many live with the pain and loss of a parent or family member who made the ultimate sacrifice in service to our country.<br><br>This month &#8212; and every month &#8212; we share our gratitude for these children. &nbsp;We recognize the hardships they face and commit to supporting the physical, social, and emotional health and safety of their families. &nbsp;That is why the White House&#8217;s Joining Forces initiative, guided by the First Lady, is focused on supporting the military and veteran families, caregivers, and survivors. &nbsp;<br><br>As a symbol of our support and gratitude to our military children, during the Month of the Military Child, the Department of Defense uses the color purple &#8212; representing all services in the military community. &nbsp;I encourage Americans everywhere to find ways to support our military-connected children, including by wearing purple to honor their service.&nbsp; Let us recommit ourselves to our sacred obligation to provide our military children and their families with the full support of our communities and our Government.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 2022 as the Month of the Military Child. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to honor military children with appropriate ceremonies and activities.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirty-first day of March, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Finding of a Severe Energy Supply&#160;Interruption</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/memorandum-on-finding-of-a-severe-energy-supply-interruption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT:        Finding of a Severe Energy Supply Interruption The Russian Federation&#8217;s unjustified, unprovoked, and unconscionable war against Ukraine, including its further invasion in violation of international law and its ongoing destructive military campaign across Ukraine, has had a profound impact on global oil markets.  On March 1, 2022, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY<br> <br>SUBJECT:        Finding of a Severe Energy Supply Interruption</p>



<p>The Russian Federation&#8217;s unjustified, unprovoked, and unconscionable war against Ukraine, including its further invasion in violation of international law and its ongoing destructive military campaign across Ukraine, has had a profound impact on global oil markets.  On March 1, 2022, the International Energy Agency Governing Board agreed to a collective release of petroleum reserves and the United States committed to a drawdown and sale of 30 million barrels from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.  Since that time, the Russian Federation has escalated its attacks across broad swaths of Ukrainian territory and has devastated the civilian population.  The United States and its allies have imposed sanctions on the Russian Federation&#8217;s economy and financial system.  Public recognition of the gravity of the Russian Federation&#8217;s actions has precipitated a significant reduction in international economic engagement with Russian businesses, including with respect to transactions not currently subject to sanctions.<br><br>Based on information from and advice of the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) and on other information, I find and determine, in accordance with section 161(d) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (EPCA), 42 U.S.C. 6241(d), that a drawdown and sale of petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) is required by a severe energy supply interruption, as defined in 42 U.S.C. 6202(8), on the basis that there is a national energy supply shortage that:<br><br>     (A)  is, or is likely to be, of significant scope and duration, and of an emergency nature;<br><br>     (B)  may cause major adverse impact on national safety or the national economy; and<br><br>     (C)  results, or is likely to result, from an interruption in the supply of imported petroleum products.<br><br>For these reasons, the Secretary is authorized and directed to draw down and sell petroleum from the SPR at public sale to the highest qualified bidder at a rate the Secretary may determine, in accordance with section 161 of EPCA and the SPR competitive sales procedures in 10 CFR Part 625.  If the Secretary determines the circumstances leading to this finding no longer support initiation or continuation of a drawdown and sale of petroleum from the SPR, the Secretary is authorized to cancel in whole or in part any offer to sell petroleum as a part of any drawdown and sale pursuant to this finding. <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as&#160;amended</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/31/memorandum-on-presidential-determination-pursuant-to-section-303-of-the-defense-production-act-of-1950-as-amended/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50190</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential DeterminationNo.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;2022-11 MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act&#160;of 1950, as amended By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right">Presidential Determination<br>No.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;2022-11</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE<br><br>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act&nbsp;of 1950, as amended<br><br>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the &#8220;Act&#8221;) (50 U.S.C. 4533), it is hereby ordered:<br><br>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration that ensuring a robust, resilient, sustainable, and environmentally responsible domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy, such as the production of large-capacity batteries, is essential to our national security and the development and preservation of domestic critical infrastructure.<br><br>The United States depends on unreliable foreign sources for many of the strategic and critical materials necessary for the clean energy transition &#8212; such as lithium, nickel, cobalt, graphite, and manganese for large-capacity batteries.&nbsp; Demand for such materials is projected to increase exponentially as the world transitions to a clean energy economy.<br><br>To promote the national defense, the United States must secure a reliable and sustainable supply of such strategic and critical materials. &nbsp;The United States shall, to the extent consistent with the promotion of the national defense, secure the supply of such materials through environmentally responsible domestic mining and processing; recycling and reuse; and recovery from unconventional and secondary sources, such as mine waste.</p>



<p>These actions shall be conducted, to the extent consistent with the promotion of the national defense and applicable law, with strong environmental, sustainability, safety, labor, Tribal consultation, and impacted community engagement standards, to rebuild and maintain American expertise and productive capacity in these critical sectors.<br><br>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Determination.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;I hereby determine, pursuant to section 303(a)(5) of the Act, that:<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(1) &nbsp;sustainable and responsible domestic mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing of strategic and critical materials for the production of large-capacity batteries for the automotive, e-mobility, and stationary storage sectors are essential to the national defense;<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(2) &nbsp;without Presidential action under section 303 of the Act, United States industry cannot reasonably be expected to provide the capability for these needed industrial resources, materials, or critical technology items in a timely manner; and<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(3) &nbsp;purchases, purchase commitments, or other action pursuant to section 303 of the Act are the most cost-effective, expedient, and practical alternative method for meeting the need.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b) &nbsp;Consistent with section 303(a)(1) of the Act, the Secretary of Defense shall create, maintain, protect, expand, or restore sustainable and responsible domestic production capabilities of such strategic and critical materials by supporting feasibility studies for mature mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing projects; by-product and co-product production at existing mining, mine waste reclamation, and other industrial facilities; mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing modernization to increase productivity, environmental sustainability, and workforce safety; and any other such activities authorized under section 303(a)(1) of the Act.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c) &nbsp;In the execution of projects to create, maintain, protect, expand, or restore sustainable and responsible domestic production capabilities of such strategic and critical materials consistent with section 303(a)(1) of the Act, the Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, and the heads of other executive departments and agencies (agencies) as appropriate.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d) &nbsp;Further, pursuant to section 303(a)(7)(B) of the Act, I find that action to expand the domestic production capabilities for such strategic and critical materials is necessary to avert an industrial resource or critical technology item shortfall that would severely impair the national defense capability. &nbsp;Therefore, I waive the requirements of section&nbsp;303(a)(1)–(a)(6) of the Act for the purpose of expanding the sustainable and responsible domestic mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing of strategic and critical materials necessary for the production of large-capacity batteries for the automotive, e-mobility, and stationary storage sectors.<br><br>Sec. 3. &nbsp;Annual Report to the President and the Congress by the Secretary of Defense. &nbsp;(a)&nbsp; The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the heads of other agencies as appropriate, shall conduct a survey of the domestic industrial base for the mining, beneficiation, and value-added processing of strategic and critical materials for the production of large-capacity batteries for the automotive, e-mobility, and stationary storage sectors. &nbsp;Such survey shall assess whether conditions continue to warrant the use of the authority under section 303 of the Act.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b)&nbsp; Consistent with the designation under section 309 of Executive Order 13603 of March 16, 2012 (National Defense Resources Preparedness), the Secretary of Defense shall include the survey stated in section 3(a) of this determination in the annual report to the Congress required by section 304(f) of the Act, and also shall submit such report to the President.<br><br>Sec. 4.&nbsp; Limitations.&nbsp; Nothing in this determination shall be construed to waive or supersede the requirement for mines or other industrial facilities to comply with all Federal and State permitting requirements and environmental health and safety laws.<br><br>Sec. 5.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this determination shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(b)&nbsp; This determination shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(c)&nbsp; This determination is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(d)&nbsp; You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Plan to Respond to Putin&#8217;s Price Hike at the&#160;Pump</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/31/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-president-bidens-plan-to-respond-to-putins-price-hike-at-the-pump/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 18:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:51 A.M. EDT MS. SIMONS:&#160; Thank you so much for joining this call.&#160; As a reminder, this call is on background as “senior administration officials” and is not under embargo. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; On this call, our senior administration officials will provide an overview on President Biden’s plan to respond to Putin’s price hike at&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:51 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Thank you so much for joining this call.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call is on background as “senior administration officials” and is not under embargo.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this call, our senior administration officials will provide an overview on President Biden’s plan to respond to Putin’s price hike at the pump.&nbsp; We will take some questions at the end.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not for reporting but for your awareness, the speakers on the call today are [senior administration official], [senior administration official], and [senior administration official].<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With that, I will now turn it over to [senior administration official].<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks so much for everyone joining.&nbsp; The President will be speaking this afternoon on the effect of Putin’s price hike on gas prices for American families.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Prices at the pump right now are up almost $1 since Vladimir Putin accelerated his military buildup in January.&nbsp; That’s because Russian oil now is coming off the market.&nbsp; The United States banned the import of Russian oil, which Republicans and Democrats in Congress called for and supported.&nbsp; It was the right thing to do.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as the United States and others aren’t buying Russian oil, supply is dropping and the price has increased.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has said from the start that standing up to Putin’s aggression would never be painless, but he is committed to doing everything he can to help American families.&nbsp; That’s why today he is announcing a two-part plan to bring American families relief.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Part one involves immediately increasing the supply of oil as a wartime bridge to greater domestic production.&nbsp; Part two is charting a path towards real American energy independence by accelerating the clean energy transition so that we are no longer reliant on foreign oil.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Starting with part one, which is about immediately increasing supply: The fact is that there is nothing standing in the way of domestic oil production, which is expected to increase by a million barrels a day this year alone.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; U.S. oil companies are recording their largest profits in years and can put those profits toward productive use.&nbsp; While some companies have already announced they are increasing immediate production, too many are choosing right now to make extraordinary profits without investing in more supply.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why, today, the President is proposing a “use it or lose it” policy to incentivize companies to produce more in the short term with the resources they already have.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right now, the oil and gas industry is sitting on more than 9,000 unused but approved permits for production on federal lands and more than 12 million unused acres.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Congress should make companies pay fees on unused wells on federal lands and on acres of public land that they are sitting on without producing.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, the industry has indicated that they can get online an additional million barrels per day this year, as I said.&nbsp; That is something that we need, that they should be doing.&nbsp; But we know it will take months, not days, for that production to come online, including through the kinds of measures the President is laying out today to encourage additional production.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We need a bridge to that additional supply.&nbsp; That’s why the President is announcing a historic release of a million barrels a day for the next six months from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That release will immediately shore up global supplies.&nbsp; These barrels will be a wartime bridge to additional U.S. production and other production that we expect later this year.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Importantly, from rev- &#8212; with revenues from that sale, we’ll restock the reserve when prices are lower.&nbsp; And the Department of Energy already has that authority.&nbsp; That can also incentivize the additional production we need this year, knowing that those purchases will occur in the future at a lower price when we’re through this emergency.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This release is being coordinated with allies and partners around the world.&nbsp; Together, our combined efforts will supply well over 1 million barrels per day to the market.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This will be the largest release from reserves over time that has been done, so it is a historic release.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; These actions will increase our immediate supply and help us meet the immediate emergency and address the lack of supply as a result of Putin’s actions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The second part of President Biden’s plan is to declare real American energy independence for the long term so that Americans aren’t subject to the kind of volatility in the oil market and at the pump that we now see due to Putin’s actions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ll now turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk more about that.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everybody.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, President Biden knows that the path to real American energy independence depends on reducing our reliance on foreign oil and on fossil fuels, and that the path to that energy security runs through clean energy.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why President Biden is calling on Congress to pass his landmark plan to speed the transition to a cleaner energy future made here in the United States of America.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Implementing the President’s climate plans would save Americans more than $900 a year in gasoline from the adoption of electric and hydrogen vehicles.&nbsp; It would save Americans $500 a year by increasing the use of clean electricity to power homes, not only on the grid but in the household as well &#8212; technologies like heat pumps and solar and storage.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And altogether, this would create millions of good-paying union jobs &#8212; jobs that cannot be outsourced.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Together, these actions would move us towards freeing ourselves from dependence on fossil fuels and, certainly, on sourcing outside of North America.</p>



<p>And President Biden, of course, is not waiting on Congress to take action, and this week alone is illustrative of that push to achieve real American energy independence.</p>



<p>One example of that, that he will announce today, is taking the next step in using the Defense Production Act by issuing an authorization for use of the DPA to secure American supplies of the critical materials needed to boost our clean energy economy.&nbsp; That is specifically focused on the procurement of the tools needed to build batteries here in the United States &#8212; batteries that will go into electric vehicles, batteries that will help us support a cleaner electricity grid.&nbsp; And all of this to be done in a way that respects and really sets the best &#8212; the highest standards on labor, on environment, on engagement with communities, and with Tribal Nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, he will make $3.2 billion available to states, Tribes, and territories for the weatherization of homes through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; That&#8217;s 10x the amount of historic funding levels that will help electrify and make efficient homes all around the country.</p>



<p>The third is advancing a set of strong energy efficiency standards designed to lower consumer and small-business costs.&nbsp; These are the appliance efficiency and equipment efficiency standards set by the Department of Energy.&nbsp; The President will talk about the 100 actions that his administration will take by the end of this year that will save families $100 annually through more efficiency in these appliances and equipment.</p>



<p>And finally, he will talk about the upcoming finalization of new fuel economy standards for cars and trucks that will save drivers money at the pump through more efficient vehicles &#8212; combining more production here at home in the short run to meet the emergency situation that [senior administration official] described, with a strategy that drives a reduced dependence on fossil fuels and an increased production of homemade clean energy means more energy security.&nbsp; That is what real American energy independence is all about, and that&#8217;s the plan the President will speak to today.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you so much, [senior administration officials].&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ll now take some questions.&nbsp; If you can use the “raise hand” feature, we&#8217;ll try and get to as many of you as we can in our allotted time.</p>



<p>The first question will go to Justin Sink at Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, can you hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; So, I have two quick questions.&nbsp; The first was how you guys were planning to deal with the Jones Act to move this amount of product.&nbsp; And the second was if you had any more details on the partner release of strategic oil that would be part of this.&nbsp; Is it coordinated through the IEA?&nbsp; Do you have a sense of how much and how soon we would see those sort of additional releases from partners?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll take that &#8212; the first question and then turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>When it comes to the Jones Act, the administration is obviously releasing a historic amount of oil through this action by the President &#8212; over the next six months, a million barrels a day.&nbsp; We are also committed to fully complying with the Jones Act and the President&#8217;s Made in America commitment.</p>



<p>A sizable portion of the release of a million barrels a day will be carried by pipeline.&nbsp; In fact, in the most recent reserve drawdown, the vast majority of the sales, 85 percent, were delivered via pipeline, while 15 percent have been slated for shipment by sea.</p>



<p>However, shipping is likely to also be needed to transport oil to parts of the country not serviced by pipelines.&nbsp; Based upon the support offered by American carriers and labor unions, we expect the Jones Act-qualified vessels will be available to meet those needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, given the historic volumes we plan to release, it is also possible that Jones Act-qualified vessels may not always be available to carry additional shipments in a timely manner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When that is the case, the administration stands ready to promptly process Jones Act waiver requests to ensure orderly and timely delivery of oil.&nbsp; Several agencies have already coordinated to make this process work smoothly.&nbsp; We will be receiving requests seven days a week, and we will work to process any waiver requests quickly with the goal of providing a response within two days.</p>



<p>On your second question, I&#8217;ll now turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; I really appreciate the question.&nbsp; Regarding working with partners and allies, this is an effort and a cadence we&#8217;ve been doing for the last several weeks and months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just most recently, the President was in Europe, where he talked about the importance of energy supply with his G7 counterparts.&nbsp; And earlier this week, we gave a readout of the call he had with the Quint, where he again &#8212; once again, they discussed the importance of ensuring energy supply in the markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, regarding the collective action and actions taken with other countries, as you all know, the United States has a much larger reserve than other countries.&nbsp; And the President has said he would not hesitate to act to protect Americans from Putin&#8217;s price hike.</p>



<p>I will not speak to what other countries will do, but I will note that tomorrow there is a meeting of the International Energy Agency to further discuss collaborative efforts to address energy markets and supply, and we will not prejudge those outcomes.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Next question will go to Weijia Jiang from CBS News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, and thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; To better understand how this latest release is going to bring down gas prices, can you share what the deficit is in the global market supply of oil since the U.S. and other nations sanctioned Russian oil?&nbsp; In other words, every day, how many millions of oil &#8212; barrels of oil have been removed from the market supply?</p>



<p>And then, just more basically, you know, once this release is triggered, how quickly could that actually have an impact on U.S. gas prices?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, to take your question &#8212; so, thanks for the questions.</p>



<p>First, when it comes to the effect on global supply, what we know is that there is reduced global supply right now.&nbsp; Obviously, outside analysts have given us sort of a range of estimates of the reduction in supply.&nbsp; We know, for instance, that, you know, across points of last year, the United States was importing 700,000 barrels per day of crude and petroleum product from Russia; we obviously have now banned those imports.</p>



<p>What we know is that there is a lack of supply and that the kind of action that the President is taking today, this historic action &#8212; the million barrels per day that will be released from the reserve over the next six months as we see a ramp-up in U.S. production and production elsewhere &#8212; will be very important in helping to address that lack of supply.</p>



<p>When it comes to, you know, how quickly will this translate into relief: You know, obviously, we&#8217;ve seen, even overnight, markets responding to the initial news of a reserve release &#8212; where we&#8217;ve seen, you know, with a reduction in the oil price.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re not focused right now on sort of the immediate, short-term price movements.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re focused on is a real challenge we have.&nbsp; You know, looking ahead with Russian supply coming off the market, we want to address that lack of supply.&nbsp; We know and believe that that will then translate into helping to provide relief to American consumers.&nbsp; We think that this historic release from the reserve will be an important step in that direction, will have meaningful effects.&nbsp; And then, in combination with actions by other countries taken around the world, it will mean we will have well in excess of a million barrels per day being released from reserves around the world in response.</p>



<p>MR. SIMONS:&nbsp; Next, we&#8217;ll go to Jeremy Diamond.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks very much for doing this.&nbsp; Just to follow up on Weijia’s question, you just said that you think this release will be an important step in the direction of helping to reduce gas prices.&nbsp; But do you not have an estimate of how quickly that will happen or by how much Americans can expect to see their gas prices reduced, say in three months from now or six months from now?</p>



<p>And then secondly, what are your plans in terms of replenishing the Strategic Petroleum Reserve?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, what we &#8212; where we’re focused is a structural challenge right now in the oil market as a result of Putin’s actions.&nbsp; We know that there is too little supply to meet demand, as Russian oil was coming off the market.&nbsp; Obviously, United States banned Russian imports; others also are not purchasing.&nbsp; We know that there&#8217;s a reduction in supply.&nbsp; And we are focused on the difference, that deficit between supply and demand, and that this historic action &#8212; a million barrels per day &#8212; will help to address that in coordination with other countries around the world.</p>



<p>You know, when it comes to the particular price effects, there is good evidence from studies of prior reserve releases that it can have significant effects in that sort of interim period, that short-term period, in order to provide relief.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where we&#8217;re focused.&nbsp; This is a bridge towards greater supply coming on the market from production both in the United States and elsewhere.</p>



<p>When it comes to the refilling, restocking the reserves, all of the funds that will be attained by the Department of Energy as a result of the sale of this oil will then go to restocking the reserve.&nbsp; That is an authority that the Department of Energy already has; that&#8217;s how they can deploy those funds.&nbsp; We expect that to occur.&nbsp; Once the oil price has come down, we are no longer in an emergency.&nbsp; You know, I direct you to the Department of Energy for more details on that.</p>



<p>The final thing I would say: You know, our commitment to restocking the reserve in order for it to be ready for future emergencies also can have good effects right now.&nbsp; It can encourage the additional production we need right now in order to respond to Putin&#8217;s action.&nbsp; So there really is a double benefit, both making sure that we are ready for future emergencies and also encouraging the production we need immediately in order to respond to Putin&#8217;s actions.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Next, we&#8217;ll go to Josh Boak from the Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much again for doing this.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve released &#8212; you&#8217;ve had two prior releases from the Strategic Reserve.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re describing this release, which is much larger as a bridge.&nbsp; Has the administration had talks or conversations with oil companies to ensure that the increased production will be out there and that this will be a bridge, since this also would reduce prices and presumably some of the incentives to pump more?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, appreciate the question, Josh.&nbsp; So, the President has had discussions with leaders in the industry.&nbsp; Senior administration officials have been closely monitoring and also in discussions with the industry as well.</p>



<p>You know, as I said, we believe that the industry needs to step up, it needs to do more, it needs to be investing in additional production.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are companies out there that have said they are; that are doing the right thing right now in increasing production.&nbsp; You know, that&#8217;s where, for instance, the million barrels a day that we &#8212; in additional production that we expect this year comes from.</p>



<p>However, there are also companies out there that haven&#8217;t said that.&nbsp; And, in fact, you know, some leaders in the industry who have said that it doesn&#8217;t matter where the price point is, they&#8217;re not going to produce more; they’re instead focused on returning dividends and other distributions to shareholders and their owners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s the right thing.&nbsp; We think these companies need to be stepping up, given the moment that we are in.&nbsp; There are some that have.&nbsp; And obviously &#8212; and I think you&#8217;ll hear the President say today: There is nothing standing in their way.&nbsp; There are, you know, thousands of unused</p>



<p>permits right now out there.&nbsp; There are the acres that aren&#8217;t being developed and they should be, given the current moment.</p>



<p>When it comes to the reserve and its effect on incentives, we do think that this is a bridge.&nbsp; And this is a discussion we&#8217;re having with the industry, but we &#8212; and I want to focus on, you know, two aspects of it.&nbsp; It, obviously, can help address the real lack of supply that exists right now &#8212; that difference between supply and demand as a result of Putin’s actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are committed, as I said, to restocking the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; Once we&#8217;re through this emergency and prices are down, our commitment to do that then provides an important signal to the market that, you know, additional production should be coming online, in part because the government will be purchasing that oil to restock the reserve, looking ahead to prepare for future emergencies.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; And next we’ll go to Kayla Tausche from CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I just wanted to ask for a little bit of clarification on the 1 million barrels.&nbsp; It looks, from the release, like the 1 million barrel total is the U.S. and allies combined.&nbsp; But I know it was also just said that other allies and the IEA would be discussing this at a meeting tomorrow and that their policy positions might not be final.&nbsp; So, could you just clarify that the 1 million barrels is specifically from the U.S. reserves?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, the United States will be releasing 1 million barrels per day, on average, for the next six months, and that will come from U.S. reserves.&nbsp; In combination with releases from other countries around the world, we expect it to be well in excess of 1 million barrels per day.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; Next, James Politi from the Financial Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; I was just wondering, will there be any consequences for U.S. energy producers that don&#8217;t step up in this moment and produce more oil?&nbsp; What would those consequences be?</p>



<p>And in terms of the price for repurchasing and restocking the reserve, is that &#8212; you know, are you thinking a particular price where you could say, okay, well, it&#8217;s low enough now that we can buy; that it&#8217;s time to kind of shift?</p>



<p>And finally, what&#8217;s the state of the discussion with the Saudis?&nbsp; And should we be expecting them to increase production later this year as part of getting well over a million barrels per day?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, first, when it comes to the industry, we do think that there should be</p>



<p>consequences if you&#8217;re sitting on unused approved permits for production on federal lands and also undeveloped acres of land that have been leased. &nbsp;That&#8217;s why the President will today call for a “use it or lose it” policy that will charge companies if they&#8217;re sitting on &#8212; on wells that aren&#8217;t producing and leases that they&#8217;re not developing.&nbsp; We think that can help encourage additional production this year.</p>



<p>The &#8212; and I&#8217;m forgetting what your second question was.&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>We might’ve lo- &#8212; we can &#8212; and I can &#8212; I remember your last question was on the OPEC, and I can turn it over for &#8212; to [senior administration official] to respond to that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; So, regarding your OPEC/Saudi question, as you know, OPEC took a decision this morning, and we will not &#8212; you know, OPEC Plus will make the decisions as it always has, and we continue to be in touch with relevant OPEC Plus partners on energy security and supply.</p>



<p>The President has been clear that he will act, if needed, to provide additional oil supply to calm turbulent markets.&nbsp; And when there&#8217;s an oil disruption, such as the one that we&#8217;re facing today, we know that consumers need relief now and that&#8217;s why the President has acted.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m remembering the second question was on restocking the reserves.&nbsp; The bottom line is we are committed to doing so when the &#8212; when prices come down, both to prepare for future emergencies and also to provide the right signal to the market now.</p>



<p>We’ll defer to the Department of Energy on exactly how we&#8217;re going &#8212; on exactly the execution of that.&nbsp; But that is our strong commitment and an authority that the Department of Energy has.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; And we’ll do one final question.&nbsp; Timothy Gardner from Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, when exactly will we see the first million barrels of this release come to markets?&nbsp; And secondly, could you &#8212; obviously, with</p>



<p>Saudi Arabia and UAE and others playing a very important role in oil markets, can you say when this plan was communicated to them?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on the first question, the barrels will be coming to market very soon, so we&#8217;re already releasing barrels from the previous releases.&nbsp; We expect the Department of Energy to soon issue a notice, which would put additional &#8212; the additional barrels on the market starting in the month of May &#8212; for May delivery.&nbsp; And we’ll defer &#8212; we’ll refer you to them for additional operational details.&nbsp; But these barrels will be coming on the market very, very soon, and we expect a notice of sale that would begin making them available in the month of May.</p>



<p>And on the question around consultations, we&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; As we&#8217;ve always done, we&#8217;ve always been in touch with relevant OPEC partners on energy security and supply.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve had those conversations over the last several weeks.</p>



<p>MS. SIMONS:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks to everyone so much for joining.&nbsp; Please feel free to send me your questions.&nbsp; We will do our best to get you an answer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I hope everyone has a great day and tunes into the President&#8217;s remarks this afternoon.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p> 11:18 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
