<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 02:14:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Gun Violence in&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/02/remarks-by-president-biden-on-gun-violence-in-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 01:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cross Hall 7:32 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160;&#160;&#160; On Memorial Day this past Monday, Jill and I visited Arlington National Cemetery. As we entered those hallowed grounds, we saw rows and rows of crosses among the rows of headstones, with other emblems of belief, honoring those who paid the ultimate price on battlefields around the world.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cross Hall</p>



<p>7:32 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Memorial Day this past Monday, Jill and I visited Arlington National Cemetery.</p>



<p>As we entered those hallowed grounds, we saw rows and rows of crosses among the rows of headstones, with other emblems of belief, honoring those who paid the ultimate price on battlefields around the world.</p>



<p>The day before, we visited Uvalde &#8212; Uvalde, Texas.&nbsp; In front of Robb Elementary School, we stood before 21 crosses for 19 third and fourth graders and two teachers.&nbsp; On each cross, a name.&nbsp; And nearby, a photo of each victim that Jill and I reached out to touch.&nbsp; Innocent victims, murdered in a classroom that had been turned into a killing field.</p>



<p>Standing there in that small town, like so many other communities across America, I couldn’t help but think there are too many other schools, too many other everyday places that have become killing fields, battlefields here in America.</p>



<p><br>We stood at such a place just 12 days before, across from a grocery store in Buffalo, New York, memorializing 10 fellow Americans &#8212; a spouse, a parent, a grandparent, a sibling &#8212; gone forever.</p>



<p>At both places, we spent hours with hundreds of family members who were broken and whose lives will never be the same.&nbsp; And they had one message for all of us: Do something.&nbsp; Just do something.&nbsp; For God’s sake, do something.</p>



<p>After Columbine, after Sandy Hook, after Charleston, after Orlando, after Las Vegas, after Parkland, nothing has been done.</p>



<p>This time, that can’t be true.&nbsp; This time, we must actually do something.</p>



<p>The issue we face is one of conscience and common sense.</p>



<p>For so many of you at home, I want to be very clear: This is not about taking away anyone’s guns.&nbsp; It’s about vili- &#8212; not about vilifying gum [sic] &#8212; gun owners.&nbsp; In fact, we believe we should be treating responsible gun owners as an example of how every gun owner should behave.&nbsp; I respect the culture and the tradition and the concerns of lawful gun owners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, the Second Amendment, like all other rights, is not absolute.&nbsp; It was Jus- &#8212; it was Justice Scalia who wrote, and I quote, “Like most rights, the right…” &#8212; Second Amendment &#8212; the rights granted by the Second Amendment are “not unlimited.”&nbsp; Not unlimited.&nbsp; It never has been.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There have always been limitations on what weapons you can own in America.&nbsp; For example, machine guns have been federally regulated for nearly 90 years.&nbsp; And this is still a free country.</p>



<p>This isn’t about taking away anyone’s rights.&nbsp; It’s about protecting children.&nbsp; It’s about protecting families.&nbsp; It’s about protecting whole communities.&nbsp; It’s about protecting our freedoms to go to school, to a grocery store, and to a church without being shot and killed.</p>



<p>According to new data just released by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, guns are the number one killer of children in the United States of America.&nbsp; The number one killer.&nbsp; More than car accidents.&nbsp; More than cancer.</p>



<p>Over the last two decades, more school-aged children have died from guns than on-duty police officers and active-duty military combined.&nbsp; Think about that: more kids than on-duty cops killed by guns, more kids than soldiers killed by guns.</p>



<p>For God’s sake, how much more carnage are we willing to accept?&nbsp; How many more innocent American lives must be taken before we say “enough”?&nbsp; Enough.</p>



<p>I know that we can’t prevent every tragedy.&nbsp; But here’s what I believe we have to do.&nbsp; Here’s what the overwhelming majority of the American people believe we must do.&nbsp; Here’s what the families in Buffalo and Uvalde, in Texas, told us we must do.</p>



<p>We need to ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines.&nbsp; And if we can’t ban assault weapons, then we should raise the age to purchase them from 18 to 21.&nbsp; Strengthen background checks.&nbsp; Enact safe storage laws and red-flag laws.&nbsp; Repeal the immunity that protects gun manufacturers from liability.&nbsp; Address the mental health crisis deepening the trauma of gun violence and as a consequence of that violence.</p>



<p>These are rational, commonsense measures.&nbsp; And here’s what it all means.&nbsp; It all means this: We should reinstate the assault weapons ban and high-capacity magazines that we passed in 1994 with bipartisan support in Congress and the support of law enforcement.&nbsp; Nine categories of semi-automatic weapons were included in that ban, like AK-47s and AR-15s.</p>



<p>And in the 10 years it was law, mass shootings went down.&nbsp; But after Republicans let the law expire in 2004 and those weapons were allowed to be sold again, mass shootings tripled.&nbsp; Those are the facts.</p>



<p>A few years ago, the family of the inventor of the AR-15 said he would have been horrified to know that its design was being used to slaughter children and other innocent lives instead of being used as a military weapon on the battlefields, as it was designed &#8212; that’s what it was designed for.</p>



<p>Enough.&nbsp; Enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We should limit how many rounds a weapon can hold.&nbsp; Why in God’s name should an ordinary citizen be able to purchase an assault weapon that holds 30-round magazines that let mass shooters fire hundreds of bullets in a matter of minutes?</p>



<p>The damage was so devastating in Uvalde, parents had to do DNA swabs to identify the remains of their children &#8212; 9- and 10-year-old children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Enough.</p>



<p>We should expand background checks to be- &#8212; keep guns out of the hands of felons, fugitives, and those under restraining orders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Stronger background checks are something that the vast majority of Americans, including the majority of gun owners, agree on.</p>



<p>I also believe we should have safe storage laws and personal liability for not locking up your gun.</p>



<p>The shooter in Sandy Hook came from a home full of guns that were too easy to access.&nbsp; That’s how he got the weapons &#8212; the weapon he used to kill his mother and then murder 26 people, including 20 first graders.</p>



<p>If you own a weapon, you have a responsibility to secure it &#8212; every responsible gun owner agrees &#8212; to make sure no one else can have access to it, to lock it up, to have trigger locks.&nbsp; And if you don&#8217;t and something bad happens, you should be held responsible.</p>



<p>We should also have national red-flag laws so that a parent, a teacher, a counselor can flag for a court that a child, a student, a patient is exhibiting violent tendencies, threatening classmates, or experiencing suicidal thoughts that makes them a danger to themselves or to others.</p>



<p>Nineteen states and the District of Columbia have red-flag laws.&nbsp; The Delaware law is named after my son, Attorney General Beau Biden.</p>



<p>Fort Hood, Texas, 2009 &#8212; 13 dead and more than 30 injured.</p>



<p>Marjorie Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, 2018 &#8212; 17 dead, 17 injured.</p>



<p>In both places, countless others suffering with invisible wounds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Red-flag laws could have stopped both these shooters.</p>



<p>In Uvalde, the shooter was 17 when he asked his sister to buy him an assault weapon, knowing he’d be denied because he was too young to purchase one himself.&nbsp; She refused.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as soon as he turned 18, he purchased two assault weapons for himself.&nbsp; Because in Texas, you can be 18 years old and buy an assault weapon even though you can’t buy a pistol in Texas until you’re 21.<br><br>If we can’t ban assault weapons, as we should, we must at least raise the age to be able to purchase one to 21.</p>



<p>Look, I know some folks will say, “18-year-olds can serve in the military and fire those weapons.”&nbsp; But that’s with training and supervision by the best-trained experts in the world.&nbsp; Don’t tell me raising the age won’t make a difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Enough.</p>



<p>We should repeal the liability shield that often protects gun manufacturers from being sued for the death and destruction caused by their weapons.&nbsp; They’re the only industry in this country that has that kind of immunity.</p>



<p>Imagine &#8212; imagine if the tobacco industry had been immune from being sued &#8212; where we’d be today.&nbsp; The gun industry’s special protections are outrageous.&nbsp; It must end.</p>



<p>And let there be no mistake about the psychological trauma that gun violence leaves behind.</p>



<p>Imagine being that little girl &#8212; that brave little girl in Uvalde who smeared the blood off her murdered friend’s body onto her own face to lie still among the corpses in her classroom and pretend she was dead in order to stay alive.&nbsp; Imagine &#8212; imagine what it would it be like for her to walk down the hallway of any school again.</p>



<p>Imagine what it’s like for children who experience this kind of trauma every day in school, in the streets, in communities all across America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Imagine what it is like for so many parents to hug their children goodbye in the morning, not sure whether they’ll come back home.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, too many people don’t have to imagine that at all.</p>



<p>Even before the pandemic, young people were already hurting.&nbsp; There’s a serious youth mental health crisis in this country, and we have to do something about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why mental health is at the heart of my Unity Agenda that I laid out in the State of the Union Address this year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We must provide more school counselors, more school nurses, more mental health services for students and for teachers, more people volunteering as mentors to help young people succeed, more privacy protection and resources to keep kids safe from the harms of social media.</p>



<p>This Unity Agenda won’t fully heal the wounded souls, but it will help.&nbsp; It matters.</p>



<p><br>I just told you what I’d do.&nbsp; The question now is: What will the Congress do?</p>



<p>The House of Representatives has already passed key measures we need.&nbsp; Expanding background checks to cover nearly all gun sales, including at gun shows and online sales.&nbsp; Getting rid of the loophole that allows a gun sale to go through after three business days even if the background check has not been completed.</p>



<p>And the House is planning even more action next week.&nbsp; Safe storage requirements.&nbsp; The banning of high-cama- &#8212; -capacity magazines.&nbsp; Raising the age to buy an assault weapon to 21.&nbsp; Federal red-flag law.&nbsp; Codifying my ban on ghost guns that don’t have serial numbers and can’t be traced.&nbsp; And tougher laws to prevent gun trafficking and straw purchases.</p>



<p>This time, we have to take the time to do something.&nbsp; And this time, it’s time for the Senate to do something.<br><br>But, as we know, in order to do any- &#8212; get anything done in the Senate, we need a minimum of 10 Republican senators.</p>



<p>I support the bipartisan efforts that include a small group of Democrats and Republican senators trying to find a way.&nbsp; But my God, the fact that the majority of the Senate Republicans don’t want any of these proposals even to be debated or come up for a vote, I find unconscionable.</p>



<p>We can’t fail the American people again.<br><br>Since Uvalde, just over a week ago, there have been 20 other mass shootings in America, each with four or more people killed or injured, including yesterday at a hospital in Tulsa, Oklahoma.</p>



<p>A shooter deliberately targeted a surgeon using an assault weapon he bought just a few hours before his rampage that left the surgeon, another doctor, a receptionist, and a patient dead, and many more injured.</p>



<p>That doesn’t count the carnage we see every single day that doesn’t make the headlines.</p>



<p>I’ve been in this fight for a long time.&nbsp; I know how hard it is, but I’ll never give up.&nbsp; And if Congress fails, I believe this time a majority of the American people won’t give up either.&nbsp; I believe the majority of you will act to turn your outrage into making this issue central to your vote.</p>



<p>Enough.&nbsp; Enough.&nbsp; Enough.</p>



<p>Over the next 17 days, the families in Uvalde will continue burying their dead.</p>



<p>It will take that long in part because it’s a town where everyone knows everyone, and day by day they will honor each one they lost.</p>



<p>Jill and I met with the owner and staff of the funeral home that is being strong &#8212; strong, strong, strong &#8212; to take care of their own.</p>



<p>And the people of Uvalde mourn.&nbsp; As they do over the next 17 days, what will we be doing as a nation?</p>



<p>Jill and I met with the sister of the teacher who was murdered and whose husband died of a heart attack two days later, leaving behind four beautiful, orphaned children &#8212; and all now orphaned.</p>



<p>The sister asked us: What could she say?&nbsp; What could she tell her nieces and nephews?</p>



<p>It was one of the most heartbreaking moments that I can remember.&nbsp; All I could think to say was &#8212; I told her to hold them tight.&nbsp; Hold them tight.</p>



<p>After visiting the school, we attended mass at Sacred Heart Catholic Church with Father Eddie.</p>



<p>In the pews, families and friends held each other tightly.&nbsp; As Archbishop Gustavo spoke, he asked the children in attendance to come up on the altar and sit on the altar with him as he spoke.</p>



<p>There wasn’t enough room, so a mom and her young son sat next to Jill and me in the first pew.&nbsp; And as we left the church, a grandmother who had just lost her granddaughter passed me a handwritten letter.</p>



<p>It read, quote, “Erase the invisible line that is dividing our nation.&nbsp; Come up with a solution and fix what’s broken and make the changes that are necessary to prevent this from happening again.”&nbsp; End of quote.</p>



<p>My fellow Americans, enough.&nbsp; Enough.&nbsp; It’s time for each of us to do our part.&nbsp; It’s time to act.<br><br>For the children we’ve lost, for the children we can save, for the nation we love, let’s hear the call and the cry.&nbsp; Let’s meet the moment.&nbsp; Let us finally do something.</p>



<p>God bless the families who are hurting.&nbsp; God bless you all.</p>



<p>From a hymn based on the 91st Psalm sung in my church:<br><br><em>May He raise you up on eagle’s wings<br>and bear you on the breath of dawn<br>make you to shine like the sun<br>and hold you in the palm of His hand.</em></p>



<p>That’s my prayer for all of you.&nbsp; God bless you.<br><br>7:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Outlook for the Social Security and Medicare Trust&#160;Funds</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/02/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-outlook-for-the-social-security-and-medicare-trust-funds/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 21:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s report from the Trustees of the Social Security and Medicare trust funds shows that the strong economic recovery driven by my economic and vaccination plans has strengthened programs that millions of Americans rely on and has put our nation in a better fiscal position. The Social Security and Medicare Hospital Insurance Trust Funds will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s report from the Trustees of the Social Security and Medicare trust funds shows that the strong economic recovery driven by my economic and vaccination plans has strengthened programs that millions of Americans rely on and has put our nation in a better fiscal position. The Social Security and Medicare Hospital Insurance Trust Funds will be able to pay benefits on a timely basis for longer than previously projected before the American Rescue Plan passed. The Trustees report says that those improvements are a result in part of a faster recovery in employment, earnings, and economic growth than previously projected. Last month, the nonpartisan Congressional Budget Office projected that the deficit will fall by $1.7 trillion this year – the largest deficit reduction in a single year on record – and that the deficit this year will be lower than CBO projected before passage of the Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>While my economic agenda has put us in a better fiscal position – cutting the deficit by the largest amount in a single year on record and strengthening Social Security and Medicare – Congressional Republicans have put forward a different approach. Led by Chair Rick Scott, their plan would put these programs on the chopping block every five years. That’s not the way to strengthen these programs. I will work with anyone willing to have an open and honest conversation about growing our economy, bringing down inflation, improving our fiscal position, and strengthening the programs that millions of Americans rely on.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on Corinthian Student Loan Forgiveness</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/02/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-corinthian-student-loan-forgiveness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 19:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Department of EducationWashington, D.C. 1:38 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Hi, everyone.  Thank you, thank you.  Thank you.  Sit, sit, sit.  How about our great Secretary Cardona?  (Applause.)  We are quite glee-filled today, aren’t we?  We really are quite gleeful.  (Applause.)  I think we have good reason, all of us.  Sit, sit, sit.  Thank you. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Department of Education<br>Washington, D.C.</em></p>



<p>1:38 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Hi, everyone.  Thank you, thank you.  Thank you.  Sit, sit, sit.  How about our great Secretary Cardona?  (Applause.)  We are quite glee-filled today, aren’t we?  We really are quite gleeful.  (Applause.)  I think we have good reason, all of us.  Sit, sit, sit.  Thank you.  Sit.  Thank you.<br><br>It’s so good to be with &#8212; we have been doing this together for so long.  Isn’t it wonderful to see how we are bringing it to some conclusion?  Although there is still much more work to be done on the issue, as a general matter.<br><br>But I see Nick Akers there and I just want to say hello.  (Applause.)  Nick was in my office in the California Department of Justice and worked so hard.  And, Nick, it’s just so great to see you.  Thank you.  Thank you, thank you.  Can we pl- &#8212; (applause).  We spent a lot of time together on this one.<br><br>So, I will now get back to my talking points.  (Laughter.)<br><br>Thank you, Secretary Cardona, for your lifelong dedication to educating and protecting our students and, by extension, our communities and our country.  And thank you to your whole team and to all the advocates here with us in your relentless fight on behalf of those important, wonderful people who were needlessly and just so wrongfully targeted by the for-profit college scams.<br><br>Before I &#8212; I begin my comments, I do want to, however, speak for a moment about what happened yesterday in Tulsa, Oklahoma.  The President will be talking more about this later.  But we have been monitoring the situation quite closely.  And the latest report, of course, is that four innocent people lost their lives and many more were injured.<br><br>We, of course, all of us, hold the people of Tulsa in our hearts.  But we also reaffirm our commitment to passing commonsense gun safety laws.  (Applause.)<br><br>And I don’t have to tell anybody in this room, but President Biden has taken more executive action to combat gun violence than any other president at this point in their administration.<br><br>But we cannot, as an administration or those of us who are here, address this alone.  No more excuses.  Thoughts and prayers are important, but not enough.  We need Congress to act.<br><br>And so, with that, I will turn to the topic at hand, but I know that we all feel similarly about the importance of leaders leading on issues like this.<br><br>So, today &#8212; today, we are here to mark a milestone.  It is a milestone in a journey so many of us have been travelling for quite some time &#8212; a journey for justice for everyone who was defrauded by Corinthian Colleges.<br><br>Students who simply wanted to better their prospects in life and instead found themselves taken advantage of by a scam that took their money and gave them nothing in return except heartache.<br><br>I first became involved, as many of you know, in the fight to stop Corinthian nearly a decade ago.  As Attorney General of California, I led the California Department of Justice, and we sued Corinthian.<br><br>And we won because our investigation discovered that Corinthian had engaged in false and deceptive advertising.  They promoted programs that they did not offer.  They penalized their telemarketers if the telemarketers revealed the truth to prospective students.<br><br>Their ads falsely promised students that if they attended certain programs, they would be guaranteed a job after graduation, raising the hopes of people who worked so hard for the bit of money they had to pay to get in these programs.<br><br>Our investigation revealed that some of the degrees from Corinthian were so worthless that they didn’t help a single student get a job.<br><br>Moreover, the company went through great lengths to inflate its job placement numbers to mislead prospective students.<br><br>For example, in 2011, they paid a temporary employment agency to hire graduates for short-term jobs.  Some students told us they were placed in jobs that only lasted for two days.  Two days.  That, of course, is not gainful employment, but Corinthian counted it as a successful job placement.  Fraud.<br><br>We also learned that the company deliberately targeted specific populations of people, such as veterans, single mothers and single fathers, people living below the poverty line, people who lost jobs during the Great Recession, people who believed in the power of education to transform their lives, people who simply wanted to take control of their own future.<br><br>As part of our investigation, we also obtained Corinthian&#8217;s internal documents &#8212; and I remember the day we got those documents so well, and we read through them, Nick.  And these documents described the types of people that Corinthian sought to deceive.  So, they literally wrote this stuff down and printed it, and we read it.<br><br>And they called their target demographic &#8212; and I quote here &#8212; I’m quoting directly &#8212; they called their target &#8212; their targeted demographic “isolated.”  They referred to them as people with, quote, “low self-esteem.”  Men and women who were, quote, “stuck,” who were, quote &#8212; quote, “unable to plan well” for their own future; people who, quote, “few people in their lives who care about them.”  Targeting people who, according to them, have &#8220;few people in their lives who care about them.&#8221;<br><br>Talk about predatory. <br><br>Corinthian purposely and fraudulently went after the folks most in need, by their own definition.  The company believed they could get away with it because, as predators are want to do, they targeted people who they assumed wouldn&#8217;t fight back.  They targeted people who they assumed no one would be there to fight for. <br><br>And they were wrong.  Students came forward and shared their stories with us.  Advocates &#8212; many of you &#8212; and many members of Congress fought on their behalf.  And we sued.  And Corinthian was shut down, and we obtained more than $1 billion in a judgment against the company. <br><br>In the wake of our lawsuit, the company was no longer then able to receive federal funding and could no longer enroll students, and they declared bankruptcy.  It was a huge victory.<br><br>But the story, as we all know, didn&#8217;t end there.  Because even though it was a victory and all of that happened, it still didn’t provide financial relief to the students who had already been impacted. <br><br>So, it&#8217;s one thing to say &#8220;there should be accountability,&#8221; but when we think about and define &#8220;accountability&#8221; based on bad actors and bad deeds, part of our system of justice tells us that, yes, there should be serious, swift, and severe consequence, but also we must look to those who were harmed and ask, &#8220;Are we doing enough to allow them the ability to recover from that harm?&#8221;<br><br>So, that’s the topic of our conversation today.  What we did then is we continued our work to undo the damage that Corinthian had caused.<br><br>And, in 2015, I joined with eight other attorneys general &#8212; some of whom offices are represented here &#8212; and we petitioned the federal government &#8212; your department &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to provide relief &#8212; he wasn’t here at the time &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to provide relief for Corinthian student-loan borrowers. <br><br>In response, the Department of Education made some Corinthian students eligible for debt relief, but only those who applied.  Until today.  Thank you.<br><br>So, I am proud to announce, together with the leaders on this stage, that the Department of Education will cancel all remaining federal student loans for former Corinthian students.<br><br>So, to those that this directly impacts, what it means that &#8212; it means that if you attended Corinthian at any point in its existence, you will receive this relief automatically.  You do not need to apply for it.  All former students will soon receive notice that Corinthian College federal loans will be cancelled.  And this will benefit more than half a million people who still have loans.  And it will add up to almost $6 billion in debt relief for former students. <br><br>And, of course, we all know, that’s real money in the pockets of real people who have faced, over these years, significant debt, many of whom are still struggling to make ends meet as costs have gone up.<br><br>And I think we all know and have to acknowledge what these intervening years have meant for the folks that will now benefit from this announcement.  What it has meant is that they kept getting notices that they owed money. <br><br>And let’s remember who we’re talking about in terms of who the &#8212; the folks were who applied to go to Corinthian College.  We’re talking about people who are highly responsible, who decided they would save up some money to pay for an education to improve their life and the life of their family and contribute to their community. <br><br>Think about what kind of person does that.  And then think about that person receiving what is probably a monthly bill saying, “You owe money,” and how that makes that person feel and the pressure they are then under because they are a responsible person who does care about contributing.<br><br>I say all of that to say that these intervening years have meant something that is not good for the folks we are talking about.  I say that because, also, in terms of the significance of the passage of time, it is that, and also that for more than 20 years, Corinthian took advantage of people who only wanted a better life for themselves and their families. <br><br>In 2016, after we obtained the judgment against Corinthian, I said then that the least we could do was to give everyone Corinthian took advantage of the relief they deserve.  I said then that we would do everything in our power to help them.<br><br>Finally &#8212; and sadly it has taken this long &#8212; finally, that promise is fulfilled.  (Applause.) <br><br>So, in closing, I will say &#8212; where I started, I will say it again &#8212; thank you all.  Thank you for all of you who helped us deliver justice.  Thank you for all of you who could have &#8212; on the day that we got the judgment and got partial relief for the students &#8212; could have declared a victory and walked away onto the next thing, but you didn’t stop and you didn’t give up. <br><br>And because of your hard work and your dedication, we’re where we are today, also knowing that as a nation we still have a lot more work to do on these issues. <br><br>Thank you all very much.  (Applause.)    <br><br>END               1:52 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden and Vice President Harris’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/02/readout-of-president-biden-and-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 19:17:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to prepare for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid. The leaders discussed the implications of Russia’s war on Ukraine for Transatlantic security and the importance of strengthening NATO’s deterrence and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to prepare for the June 29-30 NATO Summit in Madrid. The leaders discussed the implications of Russia’s war on Ukraine for Transatlantic security and the importance of strengthening NATO’s deterrence and defense, in addition to ensuring NATO is properly resourced to address a wide range of challenges, from cyber to climate change. They also welcomed the applications by Finland and Sweden for NATO membership, and President Biden conveyed his strong support for efforts by Secretary General Stoltenberg to facilitate a rapid accession process that addresses the security concerns of all Allies. Additionally, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met separately with Secretary General Stoltenberg.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Meeting with Religious Denominational Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/02/readout-of-meeting-with-religious-denominational-leaders-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 16:47:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein and staff from the Office of the Vice President and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with a diverse group of national religious denominational leaders on reproductive rights.&#160;Attendees discussed the importance of protecting access to health care, including reproductive health care, with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein and staff from the Office of the Vice President and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with a diverse group of national religious denominational leaders on reproductive rights.&nbsp;Attendees discussed the importance of protecting access to health care, including reproductive health care, with a particular emphasis on the importance of equitable access for underserved communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Faith leaders also highlighted the importance of the&nbsp;constitutional rights affirmed in&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>, including the fundamental right to privacy.&nbsp;Participants underscored the importance in ensuring that health care decisions be made by women without the interference of politicians.&nbsp;They also cited fears about the challenges facing families in their congregations and communities as states pass extreme laws restricting access to critical health care, including reproductive health care.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Senior Administration officials highlighted the President’s commitment to reproductive rights.&nbsp;The Administration also&nbsp;committed to continued engagement and partnership with these groups.<br>&nbsp;<br>Participants included representatives from:</p>



<ul><li>Evangelical Lutheran Church in America</li><li>United Church of Christ&nbsp;</li><li>United Methodist Church&nbsp;</li><li>Presbyterian Church USA&nbsp;</li><li>The Fellowship of Affirming Ministries&nbsp;</li><li>Reconstructing Judaism</li><li>The Rabbinical Assembly</li><li>Yeshivat Chovevei Torah</li><li>Central Conference of American Rabbis<br></li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from the President on Unemployment Claims and Manufacturing&#160;Progress</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/02/statement-from-the-president-on-unemployment-claims-and-manufacturing-progress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 14:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today we received more data that, despite the global challenges we face, America is on the move. Unemployment benefits have reached historic lows.&#160;Since I took office,&#160;the number of Americans relying on unemployment benefits&#160; is now&#160;down 95%, and&#160; our economy has added 8.3 million jobs And,&#160;as we make the transition from an historic jobs recovery to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today we received more data that, despite the global challenges we face, America is on the move. Unemployment benefits have reached historic lows.&nbsp;Since I took office,&nbsp;the number of Americans relying on unemployment benefits&nbsp; is now&nbsp;down 95%, and&nbsp; our economy has added 8.3 million jobs</p>



<p>And,&nbsp;as we make the transition from an historic jobs recovery to steady, stable&nbsp;economic growth, companies are investing in manufacturing in America &#8212; strengthening supply chains, lowering costs for working families, and securing our energy independence. During my first year in office, the U.S. economy created more manufacturing jobs on average per month than any other President in the last 50 years.&nbsp;Two new announcements today will add to that historic manufacturing boom. Ford’s $3.7&nbsp;billion&nbsp;investment to create more than 6,000&nbsp;good-paying, union&nbsp;jobs in Michigan, Ohio,&nbsp;and Missouri&nbsp;building new electric vehicles is great news for American workers. Stellantis’ agreement to purchase up to 25,000 metric tons of lithium per year that CTR is producing from geothermal brine in California’s Imperial County sets the U.S. on a path to being a leading producer of sustainably sourced, low carbon lithium. This builds on announced investments by dozens of companies over the past year, from Intel’s $20 billion investment to build semiconductors in America to Tesla, America’s largest manufacturer of electric vehicles. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This isn’t an accident – it’s the result of my economic plan to grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out. My Bipartisan Infrastructure Law was a major step forward in making America a place where businesses invest and good jobs grow, including our national electric vehicle charging infrastructure and battery supply chain. I urge Congress to continue this transition toward steady and stable economic growth that benefits all Americans, extend and expand incentives for clean vehicles, chargers, batteries, and semi-conductors,&nbsp;and&nbsp;to&nbsp;pass the Bipartisan Innovation Act to catalyze even more domestic manufacturing.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Statement on the UN-Mediated Truce Extension in&#160;Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/02/president-biden-statement-on-the-un-mediated-truce-extension-in-yemen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 14:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54652</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I welcome the announcement today of a continuation of the truce in the Yemen conflict.&#160; The last two months in Yemen, thanks to the truce brokered in April, have been&#160;among the most peaceful periods since this terrible war began seven years ago.&#160; Thousands of lives have been saved as fighting receded.&#160; For the first time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I welcome the announcement today of a continuation of the truce in the Yemen conflict.&nbsp; The last two months in Yemen, thanks to the truce brokered in April, have been&nbsp;among the most peaceful periods since this terrible war began seven years ago.&nbsp; Thousands of lives have been saved as fighting receded.&nbsp; For the first time in seven years, Yemenis are able to fly from Sana’a to destinations outside Yemen.&nbsp;We have also seen&nbsp;additional fuel ships&nbsp;moving&nbsp;through the port of Hudaydah,&nbsp;helping ease Yemen’s fuel crisis. &nbsp;The parties to the conflict have now extended this truce for another two months, and it’s important that we work from here to make it permanent.</p>



<p>Ending the war in Yemen has been a priority of my administration.&nbsp; I am grateful for the tireless work of my Special Envoy Tim Lenderking, and the UN’s Envoy&nbsp;to&nbsp;Yemen, Hans Grundberg.&nbsp; Their work, however, is not finished.&nbsp; I urge all parties to move expeditiously towards a comprehensive and inclusive peace process.&nbsp; Our diplomacy will not rest until a permanent settlement is in place.</p>



<p>This truce also would not have been possible without cooperative diplomacy from across the region.&nbsp; Saudi Arabia demonstrated courageous leadership by taking initiatives early on to endorse and implement terms of the UN-led truce.&nbsp; Oman played a central role in hosting and facilitating&nbsp;dialogue.&nbsp; Egypt and Jordan opened their airports to flights from Yemen over the past month thereby enabling a key component of the truce process. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States will remain engaged in this process over the coming weeks and months.&nbsp; As we continue to support regional diplomacy to de-escalate tensions wherever possible in the Middle East region, the United States is also focused intensively on deterring threats to our friends and partners.&nbsp; Our friends can rely on the United States as the security partner of choice.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States Takes Further Actions to Counter Sanctions Evasion by&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/02/fact-sheet-united-states-takes-further-actions-to-counter-sanctions-evasion-by-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 14:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54649</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States, alongside over 30 partners around the world, has imposed unprecedented sanctions and export controls to hold President Putin to account for his war against Ukraine, restrict Russia’s access to critical technology it needs to fund its war machine, and turn Russia into a global financial pariah.&#160; The Russian economy is staggering under&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States, alongside over 30 partners around the world, has imposed unprecedented sanctions and export controls to hold President Putin to account for his war against Ukraine, restrict Russia’s access to critical technology it needs to fund its war machine, and turn Russia into a global financial pariah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Russian economy is staggering under the weight of financial and trade sanctions, export controls, and the exodus of approximately 1,000 U.S. and multinational businesses. Analysts are projecting a double-digit decline in Russian GDP in 2022, soaring inflation estimated near 20% in 2022, and Putin’s war is projected to wipe out the last 15 years of economic gains in Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States and our allies and partners are committed to supporting Ukraine and ensuring the Russian government feels the compounding effects of our economic actions. Today the United States took further action, several of which have also been targeted by partners and allies, to crack down on evasion and tighten our sanctions to enhance enforcement and increase pressure on Putin and his enablers:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of the Treasury is targeting prominent Russian government officials and business leaders, luxury property of elites, and luxury asset management and service companies key to Russian attempts to evade sanctions.&nbsp;</strong>This includes close Putin associate and money-manager of Putin’s offshore wealth, Sergei Roldugin and his family members; Putin-linked yachts and Kremlin aligned yacht brokerages including&nbsp;Imperial Yachts and its CEO which provide services for Vladimir Putin’s inner circle; government ministers overseeing key sectors integral to the Russian economy; and the President of United Aircraft Corporation, a state-owned company that plays a leading role in supporting the defense industry and supplying the military’s destructive activity in Ukraine.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of State is targeting additional Russian oligarchs and elites close to Putin.&nbsp;</strong>This includes God Nisanov, a close associate of Russian officials.; Maria Zakharova,&nbsp;spokesperson for the Russian Foreign Ministry; and Alexey Mordashov, one of Russia’s wealthiest billionaires, in addition to his family members and companies, including one of&nbsp;Russia’s leading domestic steel producers.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>The Department of Commerce is further restricting the Russian military’s ability to obtain technologies and other items it needs to sustain its aggression and project power.&nbsp;</strong>This includes adding 71 parties located in Russia and Belarus to the Entity List, effectively cutting them off from obtaining U.S.-origin items or foreign-made products derived from certain U.S. technology or software.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Today’s actions across the U.S. government continue to add to expansive economic measures imposed on Russia to hold it accountable for its unprovoked war in Ukraine. So far, the United States has added 1,000 parties to Treasury’s Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons List and over 300 parties have been added to Commerce’s Entity List. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces the First Session of the White&#160;House Internship Program, Administration Will Pay Interns for the First Time in&#160;History</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/02/biden-harris-administration-announces-the-first-session-of-the-white-house-internship-program-administration-will-pay-interns-for-the-first-time-in-history/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden and Vice President Harris are announcing the launch of the White House Internship Program and that, for the first time in recent history, White House interns will be paid. The first session will commence in Fall 2022.   Too often, unpaid federal internships have been a barrier to hardworking and talented students and professionals,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris are announcing the launch of the White House Internship Program and that, for the first time in recent history, White House interns will be paid. The first session will commence in Fall 2022.  </p>



<p>Too often, unpaid federal internships have been a barrier to hardworking and talented students and professionals, preventing them from contributing their talents and skills to the country and holding them back from federal career advancement opportunities. This significant milestone of paying White House interns will help remove barriers to equal opportunity for low-income students and first-generation professionals&nbsp;at the beginnings of their careers and help to ensure that those who receive internships at the White House—and who will be a significant part of the leadership pipeline across the entire federal government—reflect the diversity of America.</p>



<p>The funds for paying interns come from bipartisan legislation that the President was proud to sign earlier this year.</p>



<p>This funding provides for paid internships across the Executive Office of the President. Interns participating in the White House Internship Program will support the White House Office and the Office of the Vice President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The White House Internship Program is a public service leadership and development program that provides emerging leaders with an opportunity to gain valuable skills while supporting the work of the White House and furthering the priorities of the Biden-Harris Administration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Interested candidates can find the Program’s online application at&nbsp;<a href="http://wh.gov/intern">WH.gov/intern</a>. The website also features additional information about the Program, including a “Frequently Asked Questions” section. The application for the Fall 2022 session will open on Monday, June 6 and close on Friday, June 24.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each year, leaders from around the country participate in the White House Internship Program to dedicate their time, energy, and experience to serve the country through public service.</p>



<p>The Fall 2022 session will be hosted in-person on the White House campus. Program leadership will continue to monitor the public health landscape related to COVID-19 and will adapt the Program’s approach in order to ensure a safe and healthy work environment. All interns will be required to attest to their vaccination status and must adhere to any White House COVID-19 protocols.</p>



<p>The Fall 2022 session will be a 14-week program, beginning on Monday, September 12 and ending on Friday, December 16. Selected applicants will be notified the week of August 8.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Program participants must be U.S. citizens, at least 18 years or older before the first day of the Program, and meet at least one of the three following criteria:</p>



<ul><li>Currently enrolled in an accredited undergraduate or graduate degree program at a college, community college, or university (two- to four-year institution)</li><li>Graduated from an accredited undergraduate or graduate program at a college, community college, or university (two- to four-year institution) no more than two years prior to the first day of the Program</li><li>A veteran of the United States Armed Forces who possesses a high school diploma or its equivalent and has served on active duty, for any length of time, no more than two years prior to the first day of the Program</li></ul>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris have committed to building an Administration that looks like America, believing that qualified people from every background and walk of life should have equal opportunity to serve our Nation. That commitment is reflected in each White House Internship Program class, and all who are interested and meet the established criteria are highly encouraged to apply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The White House Internship Program application and additional information about the Program can be found at&nbsp;<a href="/Users/ASPuri/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/1SR44D5D/WH.gov/intern">WH.gov/intern</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Prospective candidates with questions about the Program, as well as college/university administrators, faculty, campus leadership, and others interested in more information to share with their communities can reach out to the White House Internship Program team at&nbsp;<a href="mailto:internship@who.eop.gov">internship@who.eop.gov</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s call with President Alberto Fernandez of the Argentine&#160;Republic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-alberto-fernandez-of-the-argentine-republic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 03:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Alberto Fernandez of the Argentine Republic in advance of the Summit of the Americas. The President invited President Fernandez to visit Washington in July to build upon active U.S.-Argentina engagement on bilateral, regional, and global issues, specifically human rights, food insecurity, climate change and energy, technological&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Alberto Fernandez of the Argentine Republic in advance of the Summit of the Americas. The President invited President Fernandez to visit Washington in July to build upon active U.S.-Argentina engagement on bilateral, regional, and global issues, specifically human rights, food insecurity, climate change and energy, technological innovation, and critical supply chains. The President also outlined his vision for a region that is secure, middle class, and democratic, which is fundamentally in the national security interest of the United States. The President reiterated that the U.S. relationship with the Americas is based on partnership, mutual respect, and a shared objective of promoting a green and equitable recovery from the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
