<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 15:47:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Declaration of Emergency and Authorization for Temporary Extensions of Time and Duty-Free Importation of Solar Cells and Modules from Southeast&#160;Asia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/declaration-of-emergency-and-authorization-for-temporary-extensions-of-time-and-duty-free-importation-of-solar-cells-and-modules-from-southeast-asia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 15:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Electricity is an essential part of modern life that powers homes, business, and industry.&#160; It is critical to the function of major sectors of the economy, including hospitals, schools, public transportation systems, and the defense industrial base.&#160; Even isolated interruptions in electric service can have catastrophic health and economic consequences. &#160;A robust and reliable electric&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Electricity is an essential part of modern life that powers homes, business, and industry.&nbsp; It is critical to the function of major sectors of the economy, including hospitals, schools, public transportation systems, and the defense industrial base.&nbsp; Even isolated interruptions in electric service can have catastrophic health and economic consequences. &nbsp;A robust and reliable electric power system is therefore not only a basic human necessity, but is also critical to national security and national defense.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Multiple factors are threatening the ability of the United&nbsp;States to provide sufficient electricity generation to serve expected customer demand.&nbsp; These factors include disruptions to energy markets caused by Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine and extreme weather events exacerbated by climate change. &nbsp;For example, in parts of the country, drought conditions coupled with heatwaves are simultaneously causing projected electricity supply shortfalls and record electricity demand. &nbsp;As a result, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and the North American Electric Reliability Corporation have both warned of near-term electricity reliability concerns in their recent summer reliability assessments.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In order to ensure electric resource adequacy, utilities and grid operators must engage in advance planning to build new capacity now to serve expected customer demand.&nbsp; Solar energy is among the fastest growing sources of new electric generation in the United States. &nbsp;Utilities and grid operators are increasingly relying on new solar installations to ensure that there are sufficient resources on the grid to maintain reliable service.&nbsp; Additions of solar capacity and batteries were expected to account for over half of new electric sector capacity in 2022 and 2023.&nbsp; The unavailability of solar cells and modules jeopardizes those planned additions, which in turn threatens the availability of sufficient electricity generation capacity to serve expected customer demand.&nbsp; Electricity produced through solar energy is also critical to reducing our dependence on electricity produced by the burning of fossil fuels, which drives climate change.&nbsp; The Department of Defense has recognized climate change as a threat to our national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In recent years, the vast majority of solar modules installed in the United States were imported, with those from Southeast Asia making up approximately three-quarters of imported modules in 2020.&nbsp; Recently, however, the United States has been unable to import solar modules in sufficient quantities to ensure solar capacity additions necessary to achieve our climate and clean energy goals, ensure electricity grid resource adequacy, and help combat rising energy prices.&nbsp; This acute shortage of solar modules and module components has abruptly put at risk near-term solar capacity additions that could otherwise have the potential to help ensure the sufficiency of electricity generation to meet customer demand.&nbsp; Roughly half of the domestic deployment of solar modules that had been anticipated over the next year is currently in jeopardy as a result of insufficient supply.&nbsp; Across the country, solar projects are being postponed or canceled.</p>



<p>     The Federal Government is working with the private sector to promote the expansion of domestic solar manufacturing capacity, including our capacity to manufacture modules and other inputs in the solar supply chain, but building that capacity will take time.  Immediate action is needed to ensure in the interim that the United States has access to a sufficient supply of solar modules to assist in meeting our electricity generation needs.</p>



<p>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States, by the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including by section 318(a) of the Tariff Act of 1930, as amended, 19 U.S.C. 1318(a), do hereby declare an emergency to exist with respect to the threats to the availability of sufficient electricity generation capacity to meet expected customer demand.  Pursuant to this declaration, I hereby direct as follows:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Section 1.<strong> </strong>&nbsp;Emergency Authority.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;To provide additional authority to the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) to respond to the emergency herein declared, the authority under section 1318(a) of title 19, United States Code, is invoked and made available, according to its terms, to the Secretary.</p>



<p>     (b)  To provide relief from the emergency, the Secretary shall consider taking appropriate action under section 1318(a) of title 19, United States Code, to permit, until 24 months after the date of this proclamation or until the emergency declared herein has terminated, whichever occurs first, under such regulations and under such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, the importation, free of the collection of duties and estimated duties, if applicable, under sections 1671, 1673, 1675, and 1677j of title 19, United States Code, of certain solar cells and modules, exported from the Kingdom of Cambodia, Malaysia, the Kingdom of Thailand, and the Socialist Republic of Vietnam, and that are not already subject to an antidumping or countervailing duty order as of the date of this proclamation, and to temporarily extend during the course of the emergency the time therein prescribed for the performance of any act related to such imports.   </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (c) &nbsp;The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security, or their designees, before exercising, as invoked and made available under this proclamation, any of the authorities set forth in section 1318(a) of title 19, United States Code.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sec. 2.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Nothing in this proclamation shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b) &nbsp;This proclamation shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (c) &nbsp;This proclamation is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this sixth day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;4426</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/06/bill-signed-h-r-4426/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 15:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, June 6, 2022, the President signed into law:  H.R. 4426, the &#8220;Homeland Security for Children Act,&#8221; which requires the Department of Homeland Security to ensure that the needs of children are considered in homeland security planning. Thank you to Representatives Donald Payne Jr. and Bennie G. Thompson for their leadership.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, June 6, 2022, the President signed into law:<br> <br> H.R. 4426, the &#8220;Homeland Security for Children Act,&#8221; which requires the Department of Homeland Security to ensure that the needs of children are considered in homeland security planning.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Donald Payne Jr. and Bennie G. Thompson for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Takes Bold Executive Action to Spur Domestic Clean Energy&#160;Manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/fact-sheet-president-biden-takes-bold-executive-action-to-spur-domestic-clean-energy-manufacturing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 13:39:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54772</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Historic Actions Include Authorizing Defense Production Act to Lower Energy Costs, Strengthen Power Grid, and Create Good-Paying Jobs Today’s clean energy technologies are a critical part of the arsenal we must harness to lower energy costs for families, reduce risks to our power grid, and tackle the urgent crisis of a changing climate. From day&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Historic Actions Include Authorizing Defense Production Act to Lower Energy Costs, Strengthen Power Grid, and Create Good-Paying Jobs</em></p>



<p>Today’s clean energy technologies are a critical part of the arsenal we must harness to lower energy costs for families, reduce risks to our power grid, and tackle the urgent crisis of a changing climate. From day one, President Biden has mobilized investment in these critical technologies. Thanks to his clean energy and climate agenda, last year marked the largest deployment of solar, wind, and batteries in United States history, and our nation is now a magnet for investment in clean energy manufacturing.</p>



<p>Since President Biden took office, the private sector has committed over $100 billion in new private capital to make electric vehicles and batteries in the United States. We have made historic investments in clean hydrogen, nuclear, and other cutting-edge technologies. And companies are investing billions more to grow a new domestic offshore wind industry.</p>



<p>We are also now on track to triple domestic solar manufacturing capacity by 2024. The expansions to domestic solar manufacturing capacity announced since President Biden took office will grow the current base capacity of 7.5 gigawatts by an additional 15 gigawatts. This would total 22.5 gigawatts by the end of his first term – enough to enable more than 3.3 million homes to switch to clean solar energy each year.</p>



<p>While President Biden continues pushing Congress to pass clean energy investments and tax cuts, he is taking bold action to rapidly build on this progress and create a bridge to this American-made clean energy future. Today, President Biden is taking action to:</p>



<ul><li>Authorize use of the Defense Production Act (DPA) to accelerate domestic production of clean energy technologies, including solar panel parts;</li><li>Put the full power of federal procurement to work spurring additional domestic solar manufacturing capacity by directing the development of master supply agreements, including “super preference” status; and</li><li>Create a 24-month bridge as domestic manufacturing rapidly scales up to ensure the reliable supply of components that U.S. solar deployers need to construct clean energy projects and an electric grid for the 21<sup>st</sup> century, while reinforcing the integrity of our trade laws and processes.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Together, these actions will spur domestic manufacturing, construction projects, and good-paying jobs – all while cutting energy costs for families, strengthening our grid, and tackling climate change and environmental injustice. With a stronger clean energy arsenal, the United States can be an even stronger partner to our allies, especially in the face of Putin’s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>The stakes could not be higher. That is why President Biden also continues to urge Congress to quickly pass tax cuts and additional investments that advance U.S. clean energy manufacturing and deployment. Failing to take these actions would deny consumers access to cost-cutting clean energy options, add risks to our power grid, and stall domestic clean energy construction projects that are critical to tackling the climate crisis. At the same time, President Biden will keep using his executive authority to take bold action to build an American-made clean energy future.</p>



<p><strong><u>INVOKING THE DEFENSE PRODUCTION ACT FOR CLEAN ENERGY</u></strong></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is authorizing the use of the Defense Production Act (DPA) to accelerate domestic production of clean energy technologies – unlocking new powers to meet this moment. Specifically, the President is authorizing the Department of Energy to use the DPA to rapidly expand American manufacturing of five critical clean energy technologies:</p>



<ul><li>Solar panel parts like photovoltaic modules and module components;</li><li>Building insulation;</li><li>Heat pumps, which heat and cool buildings super efficiently;</li><li>Equipment for making and using clean electricity-generated fuels, including electrolyzers, fuel cells, and related platinum group metals; and</li><li>Critical power grid infrastructure like transformers.</li></ul>



<p>In deploying the DPA, the Biden-Harris Administration will strongly encourage the use of strong labor standards, including project labor agreements and community benefits agreements that offer wages at or above the prevailing rate and include local hire provisions. The Administration also will strongly encourage projects with environmental justice outcomes that empower the clean energy transition in low-income communities historically overburdened by legacy pollution.</p>



<p>Following this announcement, the White House and the Department of Energy will convene relevant industry, labor, environmental justice, and other key stakeholders as we maximize the impact of the DPA tools made available by President Biden’s actions and strengthen domestic clean energy manufacturing.</p>



<p><strong><u>BOOSTING MADE-IN-AMERICA CLEAN ENERGY WITH FEDERAL PROCUREMENT</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden is also putting the full power of federal procurement to work spurring additional domestic solar manufacturing capacity. Today, the President directed the development of two innovative tools to accelerate Made-in-America clean energy:</p>



<ul><li>Master Supply Agreements for domestically manufactured solar systems to increase the speed and efficiency with which domestic clean electricity providers can sell their products to the U.S. Government; and</li><li>So-called “Super Preferences” to apply domestic content standards for federal procurement of solar systems, including domestically manufactured solar photovoltaic components, consistent with the Buy American Act.</li></ul>



<p>These federal procurement measures can stimulate demand for up to a gigawatt of domestically produced solar modules in the near term, and up to 10 gigawatts over the next decade from U.S. government demand alone. To further increase the impact of these actions, the Administration will also partner with state and local governments and municipal utilities in these innovative arrangements – increasing the potential market impact over the next decade to as much as over 100 gigawatts. These procurement actions will provide a significant demand anchor for a revitalized domestic solar manufacturing industry.</p>



<p><strong><u>SUPPORT FOR U.S. GRID-STRENGTHENING, CLEAN ENERGY CONSTRUCTION PROJECTS </u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Because of private investor confidence in President Biden’s leadership and our national commitment to a clean energy future, the United States is now on track to triple its solar manufacturing capacity by 2024. The expansions to domestic solar manufacturing capacity announced since the President took office will grow the current 7.5 gigawatts of capacity by an additional 15 gigawatts of capacity, for a total of 22.5 gigawatts by the end of his first term – enough to enable more than 3.3 million homes to switch to clean solar energy every year. To rapidly build on this progress and create a bridge to this American-made clean energy future, we need to boost short-term solar panel supply to support construction projects in the United States right now. This is because grid operators around the country are relying on planned solar projects to come online to ensure there is sufficient power to meet demand, and to ensure we can continue to deploy solar at the rates needed to keep us on track to meet the President’s climate goals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is using his powers to create a 24-month bridge for certain solar imports while reinforcing the integrity of our trade laws and processes. Specifically, the President is:</p>



<ul><li>Temporarily facilitating U.S. solar deployers’ ability to source solar modules and cells from Cambodia, Malaysia, Thailand, and Vietnam by providing that those components can be imported free of certain duties for 24 months in order to ensure the U.S. has access to a sufficient supply of solar modules to meet electricity generation needs while domestic manufacturing scales up; and</li><li>Reinforcing his commitment to safeguarding the integrity and independence of all ongoing trade investigations by career officials at the Department of Commerce and recognizing the vital role these processes play in strengthening our economy.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>ADDITIONAL STEPS TO CUT COSTS, SUPPORT GOOD-PAYING JOBS, AND ADVANCE ENVIRONMENTAL JUSTICE</u></strong></p>



<p>Today’s actions build on this Administration’s existing initiatives to grow domestic clean energy innovation and manufacturing and to lower energy costs for Americans, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Permitting More Clean Energy on Public Lands.</strong> As part of the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-permitting-action-plan-to-accelerate-and-deliver-infrastructure-projects-on-time-on-task-and-on-budget/">Biden-Harris Permitting Action Plan</a>, a new five-agency collaboration is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/12/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-races-to-deploy-clean-energy-that-creates-jobs-and-lowers-costs/">expediting reviews of clean energy projects on public lands</a> through the Department of the Interior, helping us race ahead toward permitting at least 25 gigawatts by 2025&nbsp;–&nbsp;enough to power around five million homes. These actions have already <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-outlines-roadmap-continued-renewable-energy-progress-public-lands">increased</a> clean energy permitting activities by 35 percent, including major solar <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-advances-three-solar-projects-california-marking-significant">project approvals</a> and <a href="https://www.blm.gov/press-release/bureau-land-management-utah-issues-first-competitive-solar-leases">leases</a>. We have also launched five new Renewable Energy Coordination Offices and reduced rents and fees by more than 50 percent for solar and wind projects on public lands.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Boosting Community-Based Clean Energy in Cities and Rural Areas. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration is helping 17 local communities remove red tape with the <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-kicks-summer-solar-2021-tool-fast-tracks-solar-power-communities-nationwide">SolarAPP+ online tool</a> to enable same-day approvals for residential solar installation permits, and an additional 400 interested communities are in the pipeline. The National Climate Task Force launched new initiatives on increasing deployment of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-creates-cost-saving-clean-energy-opportunities-to-combat-climate-crisis/">Distributed Energy Resources</a>, including rooftop solar, with a focus on bringing the benefits of these projects to underserved communities. The United States Department of Agriculture provided the largest-ever investment in rural renewable energy last year. In addition, the Department of Energy and the Department of Health and Human Services are partnering to develop and pilot a digital platform that will connect customers who are eligible for the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program with community solar subscriptions, to further reduce customer energy costs. Likewise, the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development is working with municipalities to enable residents of affordable housing to directly benefit from low-cost community solar power without seeing a rent increase or adjustment to their utility allowance.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting a Diverse Solar Workforce with Good-Paying Jobs, including pathways to stable careers with the free and fair choice to join a union.</strong>&nbsp;Solar industry jobs consistently rank among the top fastest-growing in the nation, and many require only a high school education or GED. The Economic Development Administration recently awarded funding to support solar employment training in tribal and coal-impacted communities. In addition, the Department of Energy has issued a Request for Information&nbsp;and hosted six workshops&nbsp;to&nbsp;determine common goals and needs from&nbsp;stakeholders, including industry,&nbsp;unions, and&nbsp;training organizations. DOE will continue to explore these issues, including by providing funding, new collaborations with industry, other federal agencies, and state-based job boards to develop&nbsp;equitable&nbsp;worker-centric training and education programs, work-based learning opportunities, and support services such as career counseling, mentorship, and job readiness programs.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Developing</strong><strong> Clean Energy Domestic Manufacturing for Export and Building Capacity in Allied Nations. </strong>The Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM) Make More in America Initiative, approved by the EXIM board in April, will prioritize investments to expand clean energy manufacturing. The U.S. International Development Finance Corporation supports building resilient clean energy manufacturing supply chains in allied nations around the world, reducing global dependence on China.</li><li><strong>Investing in Clean Energy for Resilience in Puerto Rico: </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration joined forces with the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico to advance dozens of solar energy projects that will enable Puerto Rico to meet its target of 100%&nbsp;renewable&nbsp;electricity, while improving power sector resilience and increasing access to more affordable energy and cleaner air.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Health Policy and Advocacy&#160;Groups</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-health-policy-and-advocacy-groups/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 13:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54764</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week, the White House Gender Policy Council, the White House Domestic Policy Council, and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with national health policy and advocacy groups on protecting access to health care, including access to abortion.&#160; Participants discussed the health care crisis that the nation will face if&#160;Roe v.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Last week, the White House Gender Policy Council, the White House Domestic Policy Council, and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with national health policy and advocacy groups on protecting access to health care, including access to abortion.&nbsp; Participants discussed the health care crisis that the nation will face if&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>&nbsp;is overturned and underscored that all individuals have a right to make decisions about their health and well-being. &nbsp;They also discussed access to reproductive health care as an issue of health equity and economic security and highlighted the disproportionate impact that restrictions have on underserved communities.&nbsp;Administration officials affirmed the President’s strong commitment to reproductive rights and committed to continued engagement and partnership with these groups.Participants included representatives from:</p>



<ul><li>Center for American Progress </li><li>Community Catalyst </li><li>Families USA </li><li>Protect Our Care </li><li>Young Invincibles</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Air Force Two&#160;Departure </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-air-force-two-departure-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reno-Tahoe International AirportReno, Nevada Q    Do you have any confidence Congress can get something real done on guns? THE VICE PRESIDENT:  I really hope and pray that they do.  And I have a great deal of confidence in people like Chris Murphy.  And I know that &#8212; that he is sincerely working at this in a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Reno-Tahoe International Airport<br><em>Reno, Nevada</em></em></p>



<p>Q    Do you have any confidence Congress can get something real done on guns?<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  I really hope and pray that they do.  And I have a great deal of confidence in people like Chris Murphy.  And I know that &#8212; that he is sincerely working at this in a bipartisan way, which is really the only way we&#8217;re going to be able to get anything done.<br><br>You know, I temper my optimism with, you know, knowing that when Sandy Hook happened, nothing happened.  But, you know, I &#8212; I do believe that people can learn, and I do believe that people can revisit an issue like this and perhaps have a change of heart and mind.  So, I remain optimistic. <br> <br>So, thank you.<br><br>                                END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the 90th Annual Meeting of the U.S. Conference of&#160;Mayors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/03/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-90th-annual-meeting-of-the-u-s-conference-of-mayors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Peppermill ResortReno, Nevada 12:52 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon. Thank you, Mayor Suarez, for your introduction, for your work.  It is good to see you again.  You have been an extraordinary leader not only for your city, but in our country.  So, thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Peppermill Resort<br><em>Reno, Nevada</em></em></p>



<p>12:52 P.M. PDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.<br> <br>Thank you, Mayor Suarez, for your introduction, for your work.  It is good to see you again.  You have been an extraordinary leader not only for your city, but in our country.  So, thank you. <br> <br>Mayor Schieve, thank you for hosting us.  It is so good to be back in Reno. <br> <br>And to everyone, it is my honor to be with you this afternoon. <br> <br>You, our mayors &#8212; you are leaders not only for the constituents that elected you, but, I think if weren’t clear before the last couple of years, it is clear to everyone now you are not only local leaders, you are national leaders who show such courage, conviction, and fortitude during some of the most difficult times.<br> <br>And so, I’m here, most of all, to thank you all for what you do, what you have been doing, and what you are committed to do. <br> <br>As many of you probably know, I spent the first 20 years of my career in local government.  And throughout the years, I have partnered with mayors in every public office I’ve held &#8212; from my time as the elected District Attorney of San Francisco, to being Attorney General of California, and a United States Senator, and, now, of course, as Vice President.<br> <br>In fact, since first becoming Vice President a little over a year ago, I have met with &#8212; as I have counted it, roughly &#8212; so far, I’ve met with nearly 60 mayors.<br> <br>All that to say: I know what you all do and I know how important it is.  And I know how personal it is.  As a mayor, your work does not stop at the end of the day when you walk out of City Hall.  Your work is full time. <br> <br>It finds you at the grocery store &#8212; I know &#8212; (laughs) &#8211;when a retiree may come up to you to tell you about that streetlight that’s out on his block.  (Applause.)  I know.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>Your work finds you at your child or your grandchild’s basketball game when the assistant coach wants to know when his neighborhood is getting high-speed Internet.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>Your work finds you at your place of worship when a young mother will ask you how to get guns out of the wrong hands.<br> <br>People look to you to solve problems.  And because you are so present where you work and lead, you often have the experience of people literally searching your eyes to figure out if everything is going to be okay &#8212; even when sometimes you may not be sure.  But you still keep getting up and getting out there and making it work.<br> <br>And that is why President Joe Biden and I are honored to partner with America’s mayors to continue to build our nation.<br> <br>When we took office, as many of you remember, our economy and the pandemic &#8212; well, things weren’t looking good; in fact, in many ways, heading in the wrong direction. <br> <br>But our administration worked with you to get our country back on track.  We worked together to help millions of people who, at the time, were facing eviction to stay in their homes. <br> <br>We worked together to make sure families had enough food to eat.  We worked together to help small businesses stay open or reopen their doors and retain their employees. <br> <br>And because of our work together, since the President and I took office, we have seen record job creation, record declines in unemployment, and a record increase in labor participation.  (Applause.)   <br> <br>Just yesterday, in fact, we learned that the long-term health of our Medicare and Social Security programs is stronger than it was a year ago.  And, of course, the jobs report that came out today proves that we continue to move in the right direction. <br> <br>Last month alone, we added 390,000 jobs, which is tremendous progress &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and happening as we see a shift from recovery to sustainable economic growth. <br> <br>All together, we have created nearly 9 million new jobs since taking office, which is a record-setting pace of job creation.  Unemployment is down to 3.6 percent.  And small business creation is growing at an historic rate &#8212; which means, of course, at a local level, more folks are starting a new business in your community than ever before.<br> <br>The backstory on this is that, within our first month in office, many of you will remember, the President and I asked you all to meet with us and to meet with us in the White House.  It was virtual, but it was a meeting in the White House; you were there.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>And we asked you &#8212; there was a reason for that meeting, and those meetings, because there were many.  We asked you what you needed.  Because, you see, as many of you know, the President and I, as I said &#8212; I did and he also started at local government.  So we know you all are &#8212; are &#8212; you &#8212; you got your finger on the pulse.  You’re right there on the ground.  So we knew you, our mayors, were some of the folks that could be most informative and helpful to us to ensure that we would do the right thing.<br> <br>And through those meetings, you told us exactly what it would take to help your communities get through the pandemic.  The result of that and that work together, that partnership was the American Rescue Plan.  (Applause.)<br> <br>The ARP &#8212; you know I’ve spent time in D.C.; we now got a lot of acronyms &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; so I’m going to say “ARP,” but it’s the American Rescue Plan.  One of the things that we talked about with you and we knew has, in many policy initiatives, been an issue and we needed to deal with it &#8212; the ARP dealt with one of these issues, which is the need to make sure there would be direct funding to cities.  (Applause.)  So we did that. <br> <br>And we did that because we also knew why it is important.  It is important because then you all, at a local level, could put that money to work immediately, which you did.  Because after the ARP passed, you used this money to get people vaccinated.  You used it to support frontline workers, to keep small businesses open, to address crime and keep communities safe, to re-open schools so that children could return to the classroom and parents could return to work. <br> <br>None of this would have happened without your work to craft and implement the ARP.  And so, I’m here to say, for so many reasons, again: Thank you.  Thank you for all you have done to enable the progress that we have made.<br> <br>Together, we are heading in the right direction &#8212; toward steady and stable growth.  But while our economy has recovered faster than anyone thought possible, it is also a fact, as we all are living and know, that supply has struggled to keep up with the demand for new goods and products.<br> <br>We have seen the global supply chain slow down because of the pandemic.  And we have seen the economic impact of Putin’s unprovoked war in Ukraine ripple across the world. <br> <br>Both of these factors have resulted in rising costs.  And people in your cities, in your towns are feeling the pinch and seeing higher prices from the pump &#8212; gas pump to the grocery store.<br> <br>The President and I are doing everything in our power to lower the cost of the things that matter most for American families, and that includes the work that we still, together, must fight to achieve, such as bringing down the cost of childcare.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We believe strongly if we are to have a strong workforce, we must recognize that we must support working parents and their ability to parent.  So we have been fighting to say that for parents making a certain income and less than a certain income, they should not have to pay more than 7 percent of their income in child support.<br> <br>We are fighting for eldercare and affordable eldercare &#8212; bringing down the cost of eldercare.  And we are for fighting to make sure that we lower the cost of prescription drugs like insulin, which we should cap at $35 a month.  (Applause.) <br> <br>We are fighting to lower the cost of gas, including an historic step to blunt the increase in gas prices by releasing 1 million barrels a day from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve. <br> <br>We are already lowering the cost of high-speed Internet.  In fact, just last month, I announced that nearly 40 percent of American households are now eligible to receive a discount of $30 off their Internet bill each month.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And I will note that this happened, getting that in the infrastructure law happened because you all joined our fight to include bipartisan work around having high-speed Internet and affordable broadband in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.  And in so doing, you all helped put real money in the pockets of Americans. <br> <br>As a mayor, you understand how much rising costs impact members of your community because, again, you are deeply connected to the day-to-day lives of your constituents.  You see firsthand how these costs create uncertainty about the future for many people. <br> <br>This uncertainty is made worse by the existential challenges that societies around the world right now are grappling with. <br> <br>As Vice President, I have met with dozens of world leaders and have traveled to many places to sit down and meet with our allies and our partners.  And I can tell you this: There is a sense among all that we currently live in an unsettled world.   <br> <br>We see this most clearly in Ukraine, where the long-established principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity now rest on shaky ground, and we also see it here at home.  We also see it here at home where we are once again forced to defend fundamental principles that we hoped were well established.  Principles like the freedom to vote; the rights of women to make decisions about their own bodies &#8212; (applause); even &#8212; even questioning what constitutes the truth.<br> <br>The American people are grappling with these issues at a time when they also face immediate concerns about safety and security and about attacks on their communities that keep happening again and again. <br> <br>Mayors, you step up when horrific acts of violence shake us to our core, and you see firsthand how the hate that fuels these acts is manifesting itself in our communities.  There’s a through-line from what happened at Tops Market in Buffalo to what happened at those spas and parlors across Atlanta, at Pulse nightclub in Orlando, at the Tree of Life synagogue in Pittsburgh. <br> <br>Our country is facing what might be considered an epidemic of hate where people are being targeted just because of who they are &#8212; because of their race, because of their ethnicity, their gender, their religion, their sexual orientation. <br> <br>This then is a moment that requires all of us &#8212; as leaders, as citizens of a society &#8212; a civil society &#8212; to stand up and say: Enough is enough.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And we must speak truth and be honest as mayors &#8212; because your work does not allow you to be anything but practical.  No.  Well, we must speak honestly about what is happening and agree that the hate we see is &#8212; is not new.  There have always been those who see diversity and inclusion not as the strength we know it to be, but as a weakness. <br> <br>But we also cannot deny that this moment feels different and that data shows us, in the last couple of years, more hate incidents have happened now than at any other point in the last 20 years. <br> <br>Our interconnected world has now meant that bad actors can find each other online.  It has given space for hate to flourish and provided demagogues with a megaphone to inflame these tensions. <br> <br>Let us not allow those who are motivated by hate to separate us or to make us feel fear.  (Applause.)  Let us not allow that. <br> <br>Instead, as we all know, it is a time to renew our commitment to fight for unity; to remind our communities that we all have so much more in common than what separates us; that if we are to maximize our strength as a nation, we must find a way to commit to come together with a principle that includes believing that a harm against any one of us is a harm against all of us and, therefore, that no one should be made to fight alone.<br> <br>To combat hate, we cannot be silent and we must have the courage to speak truth about what fuels these crimes as we work to come together as a society. <br> <br>And so let us speak out.  No 86-year-old should fear for her safety to go to the grocery store.  No nine-year-old should be afraid to go to school.  And no 18-year-old should be able to buy a weapon of war.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, the President &#8212; the President spoke last night, and he said &#8212; and I think many of us know and agree: We need to pass  commonsense gun safety laws &#8212; common sense.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We need to take action.  And we know it is even more clear this day, just after the massacre of those 19 babies in Uvalde, after the killing just two days ago in Tulsa of 4 people, and after the countless lives lost to gun violence every day on streets across America.<br> <br>So, it’s clear that we must renew the assault weapons ban.  We must expand &#8212; (applause) &#8212; background checks.  We must repeal the liability shield that prote- &#8212; protects gun manufacturers.   And we must pass &#8212; (applause) &#8212; red-flag laws to prevent people from possessing firearms if they are a danger to themselves or others.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And finally, the United States Senate must confirm a permanent Director to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobi- &#8212; Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives &#8212; ATF.  (Applause.)  Because it’s been a long time, guys, since there’s been a permanent director there.  And that organization knows best how these steps will protect our communities.<br> <br>So here’s the thing.  The U.S. Conference of Mayors has been a strong advocate on so many of these issues &#8212; on sensible gun laws, by my count, for well over half a century.<br> <br>And so, again, I thank you.  And, in conclusion, I ask you: Please continue to make your voices heard.  Please continue to use your bully pulpit to fight for safer communities, for more economic opportunity, and for all the things that you so uniquely understand and know that our families need to succeed and to thrive.<br> <br>And I know that each of you is up to this challenge, because you are “The Mayor.”  (Laughter and applause.)  You deliver each and every day, and you always get the job done. <br> <br>God bless our mayors.  And God bless America.  Thank you.  <br> <br>                          END                 1:14 P.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with State Legislative Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/03/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-state-legislative-leaders-on-reproductive-rights-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 21:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, hosted a meeting with state legislative leaders in Kansas, Louisiana, and North Carolina on efforts to defend reproductive health and rights. Legislative leaders discussed the status of ongoing attacks in these states on reproductive rights, as well&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, hosted a meeting with state legislative leaders in Kansas, Louisiana, and North Carolina on efforts to defend reproductive health and rights.</p>



<p>Legislative leaders discussed the status of ongoing attacks in these states on reproductive rights, as well as their efforts to protect access to critical reproductive health care. On August 2, 2022, Kansans will vote on a ballot measure that would strip the right to abortion from the state constitution. The Kansas Supreme Court has twice ruled that the Kansas state constitution guarantees the fundamental right to abortion. Louisiana’s legislature will adjourn in a matter of days, and multiple bills are currently circulating that would undercut women’s rights. In North Carolina, ongoing work is required to protect access to care. &nbsp;White House Senior Officials thanked participants for their leadership and efforts to defend reproductive freedom.</p>



<p>Today’s engagement follows <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/24/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-state-legislative-leaders-on-reproductive-rights/">a meeting senior White House officials held last week</a> with legislators who are advancing&nbsp; legislation to protect reproductive rights.</p>



<p>State legislative leaders from today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>North Carolina House Democratic Leader Robert Reives</li><li>North Carolina Representative Julie Von Haefen</li><li>Kansas Senate Minority Leader Dinah Sykes</li><li>Kansas House Minority Whip Stephanie Clayton</li><li>Kansas Senate Minority Whip Pat Pettey</li><li>Kansas House Minority Caucus Chair Barbara Ballard</li><li>Kansas Senate Agenda Chair Marci Francisco</li><li>Kansas Representative Sydney Carlin</li><li>Kansas Representative Gail Finney</li><li>Kansas Representative Christina Haswood</li><li>Louisiana Representative Mandie Landry</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Sections 1209 and 1236 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015, as&#160;Amended</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/03/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-sections-1209-and-1236-of-the-national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2015-as-amended/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 19:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Sections 1209 and 1236 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015, as Amended By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;301 of title 3, United States Code,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Sections 1209 and 1236 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015, as Amended</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of Defense the authority and functions vested in the President by sections 1209(l)(3) and 1236(o) of the Carl&nbsp;Levin and Howard P. &#8220;Buck&#8221; McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 (Public Law 113-291, 128 Stat. 3292), as amended, to waive certain limitations on the cost of construction and repair projects in support of the Counter-ISIS campaign in Iraq and Syria, including making any determinations and submitting any congressional notifications required for such waivers.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/03/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54726</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:  Nate Fick, Nominee for Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy Daniel N. Rosenblum, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Kazakhstan Kathleen Ann Kavalec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration: </p>



<ul><li>Nate Fick, Nominee for Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy</li><li>Daniel N. Rosenblum, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Kazakhstan</li><li>Kathleen Ann Kavalec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Romania</li><li>Richard K. Delmar, Nominee for the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury</li><li>Karla Gilbride, Nominee for General Counsel of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</li><li>Terrence Edwards, Nominee for Inspector General for the National Reconnaissance Office</li><li>Richard E. DiZinno, Nominee for Member of the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</li><li>Adam Wade White, Nominee for Member of the Tennessee Valley Authority Board of Directors</li><li>William Renick Sr., Nominee for Member of the Tennessee Valley Authority Board of Directors</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Nate Fick, Nominee for Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy</u></strong></p>



<p>Nate Fick leads Elastic’s information security business globally as Vice President, Security Strategy.&nbsp;Previously, he was CEO of Endgame, a cybersecurity software company, from 2012 through its acquisition by Elastic in 2019.&nbsp;He also led Endgame’s professional services business through its acquisition by Accenture in 2017.&nbsp;Fick spent nearly a decade as an operating partner at Bessemer Venture Partners, where he worked with management teams to build technology businesses.&nbsp;He writes and speaks regularly on leadership, corporate governance, security and technology issues.&nbsp;Fick was named by Fast Company magazine as one of the “100 Most Creative People in Business” and Endgame was selected by Forbes as one of the “100 Best Cloud Companies in the World.”&nbsp;From 2009-2012, Fick was CEO of the Center for a New American Security (CNAS). While at CNAS, he launched the Center’s program on technology and national security, and oversaw work related to NATO readiness, diplomacy in the Indo-Pacific, and support for veterans and military families.&nbsp;Fick served as a Marine Corps infantry and reconnaissance officer, including combat tours in Afghanistan and Iraq.&nbsp;Fick graduated with high honors in Classics from Dartmouth College and holds an MPA from the Harvard Kennedy School and an MBA from the Harvard Business School.&nbsp; He serves as a board member of the Council on Foreign Relations, and on the Military and Veterans Advisory Council at JPMorgan Chase &amp; Co.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Daniel N. Rosenblum, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Kazakhstan</u></strong></p>



<p>Daniel N. Rosenblum, a career member of the Senior Executive Service, has served as U.S. Ambassador to Uzbekistan since 2019.&nbsp;Prior to that, he was a Deputy Assistant Secretary in the State Department’s Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs where he managed U.S. policy and diplomatic relations with the five Central Asian states.&nbsp;Previously, Rosenblum served as Coordinator of U.S. Assistance to Europe, Eurasia and Central Asia, where he was responsible for ensuring the strategic and efficient expenditure of foreign aid budgets averaging over $1 billion annually.&nbsp;He also served as the primary U.S. government liaison with other international donors, including the European Union and multilateral development banks.&nbsp;Earlier, Rosenblum held the positions of Deputy Coordinator, Director of the Eurasia Division, and Special Advisor for Economic Programs in the Assistance Coordinator’s office.&nbsp;Before joining the State Department, Rosenblum spent six years at the Free Trade Union Institute (FTUI), where he managed U.S. government grants related to the post-Communist transition in Eastern Europe and the former Soviet Union.&nbsp;He managed the operation of field offices in Russia, Ukraine, Kazakhstan, and Poland. Rosenblum also worked as a legislative assistant to U.S. Senator Carl Levin, where he advised on foreign affairs and trade policy.&nbsp;Rosenblum received his B.A. in History from Yale University and an M.A. in Soviet Studies and International Economics from the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies.&nbsp;He speaks Russian.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kathleen Ann Kavalec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Romania</u></strong></p>



<p>Kathleen Ann Kavalec, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the Head of Mission at the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe (OSCE) Mission to Bosnia and Herzegovina, on detail from the Department of State since 2019. Previously, she served as Deputy Assistant Secretary in the State Department’s Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs.&nbsp;Prior to that, Kavalec was the Director of the Office of Russian Affairs and the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Mission UNESCO in Paris, France.&nbsp;Kavalec oversaw major U.S. foreign assistance programs as Deputy Coordinator for Assistance in the European Bureau, and as Director for Conflict Prevention in the Office of the Coordinator for Reconstruction and Stabilization.&nbsp;Kavalec’s other overseas assignments include service as Cultural Affairs Officer, U.S. Embassy Bucharest, Romania; Political Counselor, U.S. Embassy Kyiv, Ukraine; and Political Officer, U.S. Embassy Moscow, Russia (twice).&nbsp;In Washington, she served as a Legislative Management Officer in the Bureau of Legislative Affairs, and as Director of the Economic Unit in the Office of the Coordinator for Assistance for the New Independent States.&nbsp;A native of California, Kavalec earned her A.B. in Political Science from the University of California at Berkeley and a Master of Science in Foreign Service from Georgetown University in Washington, D.C.&nbsp;Kavalec is the recipient of numerous State Department awards, as well as the Presidential Rank Award.&nbsp;She speaks Romanian, Spanish, Portuguese, French, and Russian.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Richard K. Delmar, Nominee for the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Richard K. Delmar is the Deputy Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury.&nbsp;He has served as Acting Inspector General and as Counsel.&nbsp;Earlier in his career, Delmar served on active duty in the U.S. Navy Judge Advocate General’s Corps, as a trial attorney in the Department of Justice Tax Division, and as a tax litigator and criminal tax program manager with the Office of Chief Counsel at the Internal Revenue Service. Delmar is a graduate of Georgetown University, the New York University School of Law, and the Naval War College Off-Campus Graduate Program.&nbsp;He is a member of the District of Columbia Bar.</p>



<p><strong><u>Karla Gilbride, Nominee for General Counsel of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Karla Gilbride has litigated on behalf of workers and others denied an equal opportunity because of discriminatory barriers since graduating from Georgetown Law School in 2007. After clerking for Judge Ronald Gould on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, she spent three years at Disability Rights Advocates in Berkeley, CA, where she sought to ensure that people with disabilities received the accommodations they needed on professional licensing exams, and that disabled residents of Los Angeles had access to shelter, transportation and other governmental services in the event of a natural disaster. Gilbride formerly served as an Associate at Mehri &amp; Skalet PLLC in Washington, DC representing workers in discrimination and wage and hour cases, and also worked on a case under the Fair Housing Act to ensure that multi-family housing in Florida was accessible to residents with mobility disabilities.</p>



<p>Gilbride currently works at Public Justice, litigating cases and appeals on behalf of low-wage workers and others who are disproportionately harmed by procedural barriers. Her cases at Public Justice have focused on mandatory, pre-dispute arbitration provisions that prevent workers and consumers from using the public courts when they experience unfair pay, on-the-job harassment or other violations of law. She has successfully argued appeals in U.S. Courts of Appeals on the topic of arbitration, and recently won a unanimous Supreme Court decision involving arbitration. During the COVID-19 pandemic, she represented meatpacking workers at a Smithfield processing plant in Missouri and Amazon workers at a warehouse in New York.</p>



<p><strong><u>Terrence Edwards, Nominee for Inspector General for the National Reconnaissance Office</u></strong></p>



<p>Terrence Edwards is currently the Chief of Staff to the Principal Deputy Director of National Intelligence. Prior to serving in this position, Edwards was the Deputy General Counsel for Management in the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, where he oversaw the provisioning of legal advice on a wide array of national security issues. Since 2005, Edwards has held a number of other legal positions within the federal government, including Senior Attorney at the National Security Agency, Senior Acquisition Attorney at the Communications Electronics Command and Attorney-Advisor at the Army Sustainment Command. Edwards has received several awards during his career, including the Presidential Rank Award.&nbsp;Edwards holds a J.D. from The Ohio State University, an M.S.B.A from Texas A&amp;M University Texarkana, and a B.S. from McNeese State University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Richard E. DiZinno, Nominee for Member of the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Richard E. DiZinno currently serves as the Vice President for Strategy, Policy, and Government Affairs at the National Insurance Crime Bureau (NICB). DiZinno oversees the formulation and implementation of NICB policy positions, coordinates strategic planning, and manages the government affairs team. Prior to NICB, DiZinno served as Associate Deputy Attorney General at the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ), where he advised the Deputy Attorney General on significant national security matters. Before DOJ, he was Chief Counsel for National Security and Crime for the U.S. Senate’s Judiciary Committee. In that role, DiZinno helped shepherd the reauthorization of Section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act in 2018; passage of the CLOUD Act, which established a process for law enforcement to request data in other countries; and Senate passage of the USA FREEDOM Act reauthorization in 2020.</p>



<p>DiZinno formerly served as an Assistant U.S. Attorney in the U.S. Attorney’s Office in the District of Columbia. While in the National Security section, he led investigations involving terrorist financing through large financial institutions, illegal exports of U.S.-origin goods, counterintelligence investigations of classified material, and international human smuggling operations. He tried over fifty cases to verdict over eight years. DiZinno spent four years as an Associate at Howrey LLP, a specialty litigation firm in D.C. DiZinno received a B.A. from the College of the Holy Cross, and attended the George Washington University School of Law. After law school, he served as a Judicial Assistant for Chief Judge Thomas Hogan of the U.S. District Court in D.C.</p>



<p><strong><u>Adam Wade White, Nominee for Member of the Tennessee Valley Authority Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>Adam “Wade” White, a Lyon County native, is currently serving his 12th year as Lyon County Judge Executive. During his tenure as Judge Executive, Wade has been a recipient of multiple awards, such as the Kentucky Elected Official Ripple Effect issued by Keep the Tennessee River Beautiful Group. He was inducted into the Freshwater Fishing Hall of Fame in 2016 and in 2018, Wade initiated the “War on Carp” as Asian Carp were having a negative impact on Kentucky Lake and Lake Barkley. Wade graduated from the University of Kentucky in 1995.&nbsp;He currently lives in Lyon County, Kentucky, with his wife.</p>



<p><strong><u>William Renick Sr., Nominee for Member of the Tennessee Valley Authority Board of Directors</u></strong></p>



<p>William J. “Bill” Renick is currently the Chairman of the Commission on the Future of Northeast Mississippi. For the past 13 years, until June 30, 2021, he served as the Workforce Division Director at Three Rivers Planning and Development District in Pontotoc, leading the Mississippi Partnership Local Workforce Area which covers 27 counties in North Mississippi. Renick entered public service at the age of 18, when he was elected to the Board of Aldermen in Ashland, Mississippi and later was elected Mayor. He also previously served on the Benton County Board of Supervisors, and eventually the State Senate. Renick served as Chief-of-Staff to Lt. Governor Eddie Briggs (R-Mississippi) and later as Chief-of-Staff to Governor Ronnie Musgrove (D-Mississippi). In between those years of public service, Renick was Administrator of Holly Springs Memorial Hospital, President of the Retail Association of Mississippi, and Executive Director of the Marshall County Industrial Development Authority. Renick is a native of Ashland, Mississippi.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the May Jobs&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/03/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-may-jobs-report-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 16:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54723</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rehoboth Beach Convention CenterRehoboth Beach, Delaware 10:48 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; With today’s excellent jobs report and unemployment remaining at a near-historic low of 3.6 percent, I want to speak very briefly today about our economy and what we’re doing to lower the costs for American families. I know that even with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rehoboth Beach Convention Center<br>Rehoboth Beach, Delaware</p>



<p>10:48 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; With today’s excellent jobs report and unemployment remaining at a near-historic low of 3.6 percent, I want to speak very briefly today about our economy and what we’re doing to lower the costs for American families.</p>



<p>I know that even with today’s good news, a lot of Americans remain anxious, and I understand the feeling.&nbsp; I grew up in a family about 100 miles from here that if &#8212; where if the price of gas went up, you felt it.&nbsp; It was a discussion at the kitchen table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is no denying that high prices, particularly around gasoline and food, are a real problem for people</p>



<p>But there is every reason for the American people to feel confident that we’ll meet these challenges.&nbsp; Because of the enormous progress we’ve made on the economy, the Americans can tackle inflation from a position of strength.&nbsp; Still a problem, but we can tackle it from a position of strength.</p>



<p>That purpose that we’ve set out to accomplish and the progress we’ve made, I think, is critical.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the time I took office, about 16 months ago, the economy had stalled and COVID was out of control.</p>



<p>Today, thanks to the economic plan and the vaccination plan that my administration put into action, America has achieved the most robust recovery in modern history just two years removed from the worst economic crisis since the Great Depression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The job market is the strongest it’s been since just after World War Two.&nbsp; We’ve got more evidence of that today.&nbsp; We learned that in May the economy added another 390,000 new jobs, bringing the total since I took office to 8.7 million new jobs &#8212; an all-time record.</p>



<p>We learned that more Americans entered the labor force in May.&nbsp; In fact, working-age people have come back into the workforce at a faster rate in this recovery than at any point in the last 40 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That means that the unemployment rate is near historic lows.&nbsp; And the number of Americans on unemployment benefits has gone from record highs to record lows, with millions of Americans moving up to better jobs, with better pay.</p>



<p>And Amer- &#8212; and American manufacturing is booming: 600,000 new manufacturing jobs created since I took office.</p>



<p>But it isn’t only about jobs.&nbsp; Since I took office, families are carrying less debt; their average savings are up.</p>



<p>A recent survey from the Federal Reserve found that more Americans feel financially comfortable than at any time since the survey began in 2013.</p>



<p>That confidence and comfortability is part of the reason why Americans applied to start more new small businesses last year than ever before in American history.</p>



<p>And because of our historically strong growth, we have strengthened Medicare and Social Security programs that millions of American families rely on.</p>



<p>Yesterday, I learned that Social Security and Medicare trust funds will be able to pay benefits for longer than previously projected before we passed the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>The reason?&nbsp; A faster-than-expected recovery in jobs, earnings, economic growth has all strengthened the financial prospects for these bedrock programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, America is stronger economic &#8212; in a stronger economic position today than just about any other country in the world.</p>



<p>Independent experts have projected that the U.S. economy could grow faster than China’s economy this year.&nbsp; That hasn’t happened since 1976, nearly one half century ago.</p>



<p>The point is this: We’ve laid an economic foundation that’s historically strong.&nbsp; And now, we’re moving forward to a new moment where we can build on that foundation, build a future of stable, steady growth so we can bring down inflation without sacrificing all the historic gains we’ve made.&nbsp; And that’s what we’re beginning to see in today’s jobs report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With today’s numbers, the jobs over the last three months have averaged about 400,000 jobs per month.&nbsp; That’s historically robust and a sign we’re beginning a shift to steady growth after rapidly recovering 600,000 jobs per month over the prior six months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as we move to a new period of stable, steady growth, we should expect to see more moderation.&nbsp; We aren’t likely to see the kind of blockbuster job reports month after month like we had over this past year, but that’s a good thing.&nbsp; That’s a sign of a healthy economy with steady growth, rising wages for working families, everyday costs easing up, and shrinking the deficit.</p>



<p>That stability puts us in a strong position to tackle what is clearly a problem: inflation.</p>



<p>I’ve been very clear that fighting inflation is my top economic priority.&nbsp; On Tuesday, I spoke about one element of my inflation plan: giving the Federal Reserve the space they need to operate.</p>



<p>Today, I’d like to address the two additional elements of my plan to tackle inflation:</p>



<p>One, bringing down the cost of everyday goods for families.</p>



<p>And two, bringing down the federal deficit at the same time.</p>



<p>Bringing down the costs &#8212; here’s where we stand: The two challenges on the minds of most working families are prices at the pump and prices at the grocery store.&nbsp; Both of these challenges have been directly exacerbated by Putin’s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>The price of gas is up $1.40 since the beginning of the year when Putin began amassing troops at the Ukrainian border.&nbsp; This is the “Putin price hike.”</p>



<p>Putin’s war has raised the price of food because Ukraine and Russia are two of the world’s major breadbaskets for wheat and corn &#8212; the basic product for so many foods around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ukraine has 20 million tons of grain in storage right now, and it’s been in storage since the last harvest.&nbsp; Normally, that would have already been exported into the world market.&nbsp; But because of Putin’s invasion and a blockade of the port at which they could take that grain out for the rest of the world, it’s not.&nbsp; It’s not.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And look, I understand that families who are struggling probably don’t care why the prices are up.&nbsp; They just want them to go down.&nbsp; “Joe, what are you going to do to bring them down?”&nbsp; But it’s important that we understand the root of the problem so we can take steps to solve it.</p>



<p>I’ve been up front with the American people from the outset that there would be a cost here at home of Putin’s decision to brutally and savagely invade a sovereign nation.</p>



<p>But as your President, I remain committed to doing everything in my power to blunt the impact on American families, and that’s exactly what I’m doing.</p>



<p>I led the world to coordinate the largest release of global oil reserves in history &#8212; 240 million barrels &#8212; to boost global supply and keep prices from rising even more.</p>



<p>I directed the sale of gasoline using homegrown biofuels this summer.</p>



<p>And I’m working closely with our European partners to get more of the grain locked in Ukraine right now out into the world market, which could help bring down prices.&nbsp; There’s ways to do that over land, which we could talk about at another time.</p>



<p>But actions have already helped to blunt that &#8212; what would have been an even larger Putin price hike.</p>



<p>And as I said, I’m going to continue to use every tool available to me to further blunt those price hikes as we move forward.</p>



<p>But the fact is this: There’s more than one way to solve this problem.&nbsp; If food and gas prices are going to be elevated by Putin’s price hike, one way we can make things a little better for families is by helping them save on other basic items their family needs on a monthly basis, like their utility bills, their Internet bills, their prescription drug bills, and other costs like housing.</p>



<p>My goal is to make sure that at the end of the month families have a little more breathing room than they &#8212; than they have now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, here’s something we can do right now: Congress could help ease the costs for families right away by passing my clean energy investment proposal that I’ve proposed that’s been sitting there.&nbsp; Things like tax credits for businesses to produce clean energy and tax cuts for families to make their homes more energy efficient.&nbsp; That’s what it results in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I met with nearly a dozen CEOs of America’s largest utility companies, such as Southern Company and American Electric Power.&nbsp; They told me that if we pass the investments, they will make immediately lower &#8212; they’ll immediately lower the average family’s energy costs by about $500 a year.&nbsp; That would help a lot.&nbsp; That’d make up for a lot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the long run, it would help families make America truly energy independent so, in the future, American families are no longer subject to the whims of a dictator half a world away, controlling oil.</p>



<p>It’s not just utility bills, though.&nbsp; I’ve laid out a plan to lower prescription drug costs by giving Medicare the power to negotiate with the pharmaceutical companies and how much they can charge, just like they do with the Veterans Administration.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, they say, “We’re not going to pay X &#8212; more than X amount of dollars for your insulin.”&nbsp; Well, they can decide not to sell it all &#8212; or they can sell it at the price that the government says they’ll pay for it, bringing down the average cost of prescription drugs.</p>



<p>By capping that cost of insulin, by the way, at no more than $35 a month.&nbsp; It costs them less than 10 bucks to make it.&nbsp; And some &#8212; in some families, it means hundreds of dollars a month and sometimes hundreds of dollars a year, depending on what the &#8212; what ailment they’re trying to deal with.<br><br>Someone with diab- &#8212; diabetes, for example, it’s hundreds of dollars per year.&nbsp; Someone with arthritis, it could be thousands of dollars per year.</p>



<p>I’ve laid out a plan to lower rent and mortgage costs &#8212; the largest cost most families face; around a third of a typical family’s budget &#8212; because we have a shortage of housing.&nbsp; Building more than a million more housing units and closing the shortfall in affordable housing in this country will do that.</p>



<p>I’ve laid out a plan to lower the cost of high-speed Internet by working with the 20 leading Internet service providers to cut their prices and raise their speeds.</p>



<p>For tens of millions of households, this could lower what they have to pay for high-speed Internet by $50 a month or more.&nbsp; And nearly 40 percent of households in America qualify for these savings.</p>



<p>And by the way, you can find out if you’d be eligible by visiting &#8212; by vi- &#8212; GetInternet.gov.&nbsp; GetInternet.gov.&nbsp; I’ll say it again: GetInternet.gov.&nbsp; See if you qualify.</p>



<p>I’ve laid out a plan to lower the cost of everyday goods that move through our supply chains to stores and families’ doorsteps.</p>



<p>For example, at the State of the Union, I called on Congress to crack down on foreign-owned shipping companies that have raised their prices to transport goods by as much as 1,000 percent.&nbsp; One thousand percent.&nbsp; And that obviously raises the cost of the goods on those ships to consumers.</p>



<p>The Senate has passed legislation, and I am hopeful the House can do the same to send me legislation in the coming weeks to crack down on these companies and help lower overall costs.</p>



<p>And my plan does all this without raising a penny in taxes on people making less than $400,000 a year and without raising the deficit at all by taxing the super wealthy and big corporations, like the 55 major corporations that don’t pay a single penny in taxes, even though they had a &#8212; $40 billion in profits.</p>



<p>The point is this: I’m doing everything I can on my own to help working families during this stretch of higher prices.&nbsp; And I’m going to &#8212; I’m going to continue to do that.</p>



<p>But Congress needs to act as well.&nbsp; We can do so much more if we come together to lower the costs for American families.</p>



<p>But my congressional Republican friends, led by Rick Scott, have a different approach.&nbsp; He’s actually introduced a plan.&nbsp; He wants to raise taxes on working families by an average of $1,500 a year; put Medicare and Social Security &#8212; Medicaid &#8212; excuse me &#8212; Social Security and Medicaid on the chopping block every five years.&nbsp; In other words: Every five years, they’re &#8212; they’re going no longer exist unless they vote them back into existence.</p>



<p>I disagree with that.&nbsp; What in God’s name are they doing?</p>



<p>And I’ll work with anyone &#8212; Democrat, Republican, independent &#8212; to deliver real solutions and real savings for the American people, not take money out of their pockets.</p>



<p>Now, the other melem- &#8212; other element I’d like to address that has impacts on inflation is to lower the deficit.&nbsp; The reason this matters to families is because reducing the deficit is another way to ease inflation.</p>



<p>My friends on the Republican side like to paint me as the “big spender.”&nbsp; But let’s look at the facts.&nbsp; Facts matter.&nbsp;<br><br>Under my predecessor, the deficit exploded, rising every single year he was in office.&nbsp; Under my plan, we’re on track to cut the federal deficit this year by $1.7 trillion.&nbsp; You hear me now?&nbsp; This year by $1.7 trillion.&nbsp; That’s a fact.&nbsp; The largest decline in American history.</p>



<p>And by the way, those aren’t White House projections.&nbsp; They come from the nonpartisan Congressional Budget Office that you in the press and everybody around the country legitimately quotes all the time.</p>



<p>That progress on tackling the deficit was not pre-ordained.&nbsp; It was my economic strategy built into our historic recovery.&nbsp; That we didn’t anticipate a war in Ukraine at the time.&nbsp; Historic economic growth that not only helped tens of millions of families move up, it has helped our federal deficit come down.</p>



<p>And now, because of that strategy, we’re on track for a deficit to take up a lower share of our economy than it did before the pandemic.</p>



<p>In fact, the Treasury Department is planning to pay down &#8212; pay down &#8212; the national debt this quarter, which never happened under my predecessor.&nbsp; Not once.&nbsp; Not once.&nbsp; Because, unlike my predecessor, the deficit has come down both years I’ve been here.<br><br>I’ve proposed a plan to keep shrinking that deficit by making commonsense reforms to our tax code, leveling the playing field internationally so that the biggest companies no longer have an incentive to shift jobs overseas &#8212; to shift them overseas to make their product because they get charged less in taxes and avoid paying their fair share of taxes here at home.&nbsp; We put together a multi-nation initiative that I’m hopeful will come into play at the G7.&nbsp;<br><br>And ending the outrageous unfairness of our tax system that allows billionaires &#8212; look, if you can make a billion dollars, I’m all for it.&nbsp; Just pay a little bit of your fair share, you know?&nbsp; Just pay your fair share.&nbsp; Billionaires pay a lower rate than a teacher or a firefighter.</p>



<p>The bottom line is this: Part of the reason I ran for President is because I was tired of trickle-down economics.&nbsp; It doesn’t work.</p>



<p>My plans have produced the strongest, fastest, most widespread economic recovery America has ever experienced, with record jobs, a new record of small businesses, and wages rising.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s the foundation for an economy that works for working families.</p>



<p>And because of that foundation, we’re better positioned than any country in the world to overcome the global inflation that we’re seeing and reach a new chapter of stable and steady growth.</p>



<p>So, let’s come together and focus on what’s the matter &#8212; on what matters.&nbsp; Let’s build on the extraordinary progress we’ve made.&nbsp; And let’s continue to build this economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; When that happens, everybody does well, including the very wealthy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And God bless you.&nbsp; And I &#8212; God &#8212; may God protect our troops.</p>



<p>I’ll take a few questions.</p>



<p>Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you going to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Saudi Arabia, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me answer her &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, Elon Musk has asked &#8212; has said that he has a “super bad feeling” about the U.S. economy.&nbsp; He is laying off 10 percent of his workforce.&nbsp; What do you say to Elon Musk about his feeling about the economy?&nbsp; Jamie Dimon has said similar things.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, let me tell you.&nbsp; While Elon Musk is talking about that, Ford is increasing their investment overwhelmingly.&nbsp; I think Ford is increasing the investment in building new electric vehicles: 6,000 new employees &#8212; union employees, I might add &#8212; in the Midwest.</p>



<p>The former Chrysler Corporation, Stellantis, they&#8217;re also making similar investments in electric vehicles.</p>



<p>Intel is adding 20,000 new jobs for making computer chips.</p>



<p>So, you know, lots of luck on his trip to the Moon.&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I mean, you know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212; are you going to go to Saudi Arabia, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not sure whether I’m going.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I have no direct plans at the moment.&nbsp; But let me tell you that I have been engaged in trying to work with how we can bring more stability and peace to the Middle East.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is a possibility that I would be going to meet with both the Israelis and the Ara- &#8212; some Arab countries at the time &#8212; including, I expect, would be Saudi Arabia &#8212; would be included in that if I did go.</p>



<p>But I have no direct plans at the moment.&nbsp; We’re looking at it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the Kingdom still a pariah, in your eyes?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to change my view on human rights.&nbsp; But as President of the United States, my job is to bring peace if I can &#8212; peace if I can.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what I&#8217;m going to try to do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, would you be open to meeting with the Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman if you do end up going to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, we&#8217;re getting way ahead of ourselves here.&nbsp; What I want to do is see to it that we diminish the likelihood that there&#8217;s a continuation of this &#8212; some of the senseless wars between Israel and the Arab nations.&nbsp; And that’s what I’m focused on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is OPEC doing enough on oil production?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, what I recently read and talking to my team that &#8212; they acknowledge that there is an oil shortage, and they have made an announcement, of late, that they&#8217;re going to increase production.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t know enough to know whether it&#8217;s enough, but I know it&#8217;s positive.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, does Ukraine have to cede territory to achieve some peace?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, you’ve been always fair with me. The &#8212; from the beginning, I&#8217;ve said and I&#8217;ve been &#8212; not everyone has agreed with me &#8212; nothing about Ukraine without Ukraine.&nbsp; It’s their territory.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to tell them what they should and shouldn&#8217;t do.</p>



<p>But it appears to me that, at some point along the line, there&#8217;s going to have to be a negotiated settlement here.&nbsp; And what that entails, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; I don’t think anybody knows at the time.</p>



<p>But in the meantime, we&#8217;re going to continue to put the &#8212; the Ukrainians in a position where they can defend themselves.</p>



<p>Thank you all so very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, will you go to the Hill next week on guns to meet with lawmakers?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My staff is &#8212; my staff is dealing &#8212; and have been dealing constantly with every member of the House and Senate who is wanting to talk about guns.&nbsp; It’s been a constant interchange.&nbsp; And I’ve been constantly briefed.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll do what I can to try to see if we have some real progress.</p>



<p>Thank you. </p>



<p>11:08 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
